<filme>
 <id>
  307
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118971
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Advogado do Diabo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A hotshot lawyer gets more than he bargained for when he learns his new boss is Lucifer himself.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Based on a book by Andrew Neiderman, the film centers on a young lawyer who joins a New York firm only to discover that his boss has an increasingly bizarre personality.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   lawyer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   law
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   law firm
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   florida
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   vanity
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Taylor Hackford
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Andrew Neiderman
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jonathan Lemkin
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Keanu Reeves
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Al Pacino
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Charlize Theron
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary, Thought Provoking, Just Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mediapeertime
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films about Satan. Great at deceiving, full of power, loses in the end - as the devil should! This was altogether a great lawyer film. In this film, we get to see one of Pacino's best performances. He wasn't that usual character that we'r5e so used to seeing. Also tremendous performances by Charlize Theron, Connie Nielson, Jeffrey Jones, Tamara Tunie, and Craig T. Nelson. Couldn't buy Keaneau Reeves in the best lawyer role. he was adequate at best. Watch the train scene with Al Pacino - just tremendous! Taylor Hackford, great work (except casting of Reeves, but that mau not have been his choice????)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Brilliant!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elif490
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exceptional. Simply perfect. I watched without blinking my eye for a moment until the end of the film, and the final literally shocked me. As it tells us the relationship between us and satisfaction & sins, it shows us our biggest weaknesses as people. This film makes you terrify and at the same time it makes you learn a lot. Acting is even better than 'magnificent'. Legendary is a way less description for Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are fantastic!! Excellent and unique. Anyone who doesn't watch this movie loses a lot. It just blows your mind! Seriously. It's one of the bests. Once you watch it, you will never forget about this movie. Ten out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keanu Reeves as a bad-ass lawyer from hell.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tess van Brummelen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting (Keanu Reeves, Al Pacino and Charlize Theron) was brilliant. This film is scary as hell. Favorite quotes: "It's not a dream if it's true." "Your belly's too full, your dick is sore, your eyes are bloodshot, and you're screaming for someone to help!" "It's the goof of all time. Look but don't touch. Touch, but don't taste. Taste, don't swallow. Ahaha." "Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. The virtue of the devil is in his loins." "Vanity, definitely my favorite sin."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a stylish supernatural thriller about the temptation of evil for a young lawyer from the South. When he is offered a big time job in New York by big time lawyer played by Al Pacino, he finds there is a price to pay. The cast is good. Al Pacino before he got really devilish looking is good except for the silly dance at the end. Connie Nielsen is sophisticated and elegant. Charlize Theron is moving and convincing as the young wife sacrificing her looks for a standout performance. Even Keanu acts quite well as the young lawyer and you can't say that about too many of his movies. They didn't make it over the top horror - it's clever and frightening without much gore or in your face violence. Along with Rosemary's Baby this is the best NYC supernatural horror movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demonic thriller full of tension and pain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    4rch 4ng3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The figure of the devil posted in a contemporaney time, with a great Keanu Reeves and a really appreciable Al Pacino as the mysterious figure of the hided evil. Charlize Theron is absorbed by the pain and the sufference caused, a trap filled with an articoulate labyrinth of lies and bad actions. The screenplay, not even need to talk, is fantastic and avvolving at all, withal an adrenalinic envelopment an a huge tale of twists and questions. The way out is difficoult to find and the easy decisions are not part of the dialogues or the plot. The evil is so high and so showed, without fear, is unstoppable and known at the same time. The conseguences are so many and impossible to predict.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't really live up to its hype
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one film I had been wanting to watch for quite some time now, and I got around to it just a while back. I had some really good expectations from this movie, as I had read about it on IMDb and other movie sites, and I had thought it would be a courtroom thriller filled with suspense. But I have to say I was a bit disappointed with what I saw. The film is about a hotshot Florida lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves) who has never lost a case in his entire career. A New York law firm enlists his help to select a jury for a case and recognizing his talent, offers him a job. Lomax accepts and becomes quite close to his boss, John Milton (Al Pacino) during the course of his work. But he gradually begins to uncover some strange facets of Milton's personality and finally realizes that he is none other than Satan himself. Now, such a premise should surely set the stage for a riveting thriller filled with suspense and mystery. But sadly, it doesn't. I think the main reason is Keanu Reeves' performance. I couldn't really buy the idea of him being an argumentative lawyer who could acquit a rapist in spite of the pile of evidence staring him in the face, especially as this is what is shown in the first scene of the film. If the scene is supposed to convince the viewer of the talent of this young lawyer, it doesn't really pass the test. The only thing it does is invariably draw comparisons to the courtroom scenes in "A Few good Men", which had fabulous dialogues, coupled with one of Tom Cruise's finest performances ever. So it is asking a lot to make the audience believe that Lomax hasn't yet lost a case. Apart from this, the film does have a few things going for it. The pace is fast and well set, and for a first time viewing, there is no scene which makes you feel bored, irksome or irritable. And, of course, there's Al Pacino. His thunderous voice and arrogant demeanour are enough to make the viewer feel uncomfortable about him, and it isn't really hard to associate his character with that of the Devil. The other characters merely serve as pretexts for Lomax's wife to lose control over herself and imagine things related to hell, Satan and all that stuff. All in all, I wouldn't recommend this as a must-see, but probably something you might just rent at a DVD store when your other choices aren't that appealing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Night of the world"- uncreated by fable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yughred
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt that Kevin is familiar with the Bible, this is the weapon of the debate in his court in "Mo Yizi case, he resorted to the freedom of religious belief of the party days India with eloquence eloquent Mo Yizi acquitted on the charges, plus Mo Yizi assistant prosecutor Arnold Modu facilities witchcraft, it coughing, unable to speak, and Kevin got his wish to obtain another victory. Famous football coach Vince Lombardi once behalf of Kevin shouted his voice: "Winning is not everything, but only! Bible or religion or in the creation of four 60-game winning streak myth The young lawyer Kevin's eyes, but the tools to win the victory. The United States is a respect for the success of the nation, "the exclusive worship of successfully goddess bitch" overwhelm everything, including God. Xu Kaiwen court numerous times to praise the name of the Lord, in his heart, God is but a trite illusory value symbol. This era is the era of man and the world is completely lost. The maze of free will Make free will answer the philosophers who believe that God create people are born with free will - are born with the ability to act in accordance with their own wishes. The face of the world, people can be free to make a choice. Therefore, evil and suffering in the world, is the result of the abuse of free will, this responsibility should be by the people themselves to provide us with. God is not interfered. From the words of the Bible, we can infer that: God created Adam and Eve when, inevitably given their free will - the event that obey the spell of the snake Tousijinguo this crime, is not based on the free will to make autonomous decision, while is responsible for the crimes they have committed a pre-determined by God no choice behavior, then, God, what is the reason to make Adam and Eve it? The philosophical insights is the one held by the "devil's advocate". Summit in New York, in the face of the nations bustling, Kevin chose an opposite road with Jesus Christ, step-by-step into the trap of the devil - based on the free will. Yes, free will! Kevin's mother and wife successively abduction by Satan, the same is based on the free will of independent decision. Satan never force others to comply with his will. God, he respects the free will of the people. "I don't make things happen", he was just with a charming smile, charm by saying, to induce the people inside the original sin. He does not directly make any demands. He even twice put the persuasion attitude demagogue mending their ways. Free will, this is a wonderful word! In the eyes of the people, it embodied the pride and glory of the man. And Satan said: "Free will, it is a bitch." Bitch Italian English word "bitch, slut, nasty stuff", full of humble and despicable mean. Sadly, if Satan is not wrong. Bear the original sin of the people, given human nature and the dark background. Night of the world ", dumping large town of Babylon, God-given free will of light in this dark human nature, it has been alienated to slut who gaudy jeweled. "I'm a fan of man. I'm a humanist, maybe the last humanist." Satan wanton interpretation of the words of Montaigne: "anything that can occur in the human body and it was not inhuman." His "humanitarian doctrine "is to distort the true meaning of free will along the dark humanity, his definition of" freedom "is an absolute and unfettered freedom, one to do whatever they want to meet the desire of freedom. The paradox is that the absolute freedom, being mean absolute enslavement. "Man is born free, but no go without chains. Precisely the desire, only the desire of the human heart, is the real shackles, people become prisoners under the order shall not be free. Conspiracy of Satan took advantage of the free will of the people of the world - which lost in the sea of ​​desire free will, step by step, to lure the world turned away from God and become degenerate. "The 20th century was entirely mine", at the moment, Satan winner complacent. So, what is truly "free"? Jesus as early as "John." Provides us with the answer: "You shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free." Face of the unexpected defeat of Satan desperately shouting: "No! Damn you! Enough! Have not I given enough?" Ezekiel book describes the scene in an instant staged: "Are you proud because of the beautiful hearts corrupted your wisdom because of glory, I have sent thee to the ground you down before kings, good that they may behold thee. sins of many, unfair trade defiled thy sanctuary. therefore will I bring fire from you issue the middle, devour thee, and upon the earth in the sight of all people watch ashes "in a raging fire, Satan revealed a proud Blazing Angels Lucifer Mami. Satan carefully constructed dream collapsed in an instant. Out from the sea of ​​desire meditation from Kevin, the court did not hesitate to refuse to act as the spokesperson of the devil, the hearts of the people think: a hero was born, God, after all, to get the victory. However, Satan is everywhere. He was the embodiment of the snake, and also the embodiment of the law firm boss, he can transform himself into a tabloid reporter. Kevin's body, after all, keep the pride and vanity of the blood of Lucifer. Marian also as her ancestor Eve, enticed her husband swallowed sinking attractive fruit. The temptation is everywhere. Free will still trapped in the maze. The night of the world is still long. The dawn of being buried. "Alas, Babylon the great! Moment between your judgment come ... never again shining light in the midst of thee ..."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Devil's Avocate, an interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waltyeresdesousa (waltyeresdesousa@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate A movie of mystery and suspense, where people left their normal lives to live a story that since its beginning is surreal. That is how rolls The Devil's Advocate. Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reevens) is a lawyer that began his carrier at Florida and his principal characteristics are: He's never lost a court case before; He wins cases whether the accused is innocent or not; He is an excellent professional and it calls much attention of a millionaire - John Milton (Al Pacino), an owner of largest law firm in New York. John makes a proposal that cannot be refused by Kevin: if he wins the cases, he would work with him and have a good job and house. So he passed to live better in New York- the city that already wished for many peoples- with his wife Mary Ann Lomax (Charlize Theron), who had worked a lot before, since she was 13. Kevin unfortunately accepts this proposal even being advised by his mother Alice Lomax (Judith Ivev) that New York was the big Babylon, as descriptive on Apocalypse. He was a religious man when he was a child, Kevin knew this prophecy but he thought would only practice his religiosity again in his old age. By not listening to the prophecy, his life changes radically from that. He starts to work in this new company and his wife stays at home because she doesn't work anymore. Her function was only to take care of the house. But strange things start to happen in her life, she begins to see strange shapes in the people and they pass to have some aspects of demons and they are trying to scare her. The most interesting fact is that the boss of Kevin, Mr. John, always knows everything that happens in his married life. After many events, the movie ends with secrets revealed; Kevin finds out that his boss and his own mother are the center of the secret that could transform his life totally. When the movie ends, it scions about vanity and reinterpret the habitual concept about it and take this concept to Spiritual life. The movie sin in last scenes because it ends in a messy and the movie didn't make clear the real surreal. Can call your attention in a way that you forget the world, it try to exit you of the simple world where your mind can open to others' understanding. This movie is directed by Taylor Hackford, lasts 2:23:34. It was produced in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For watching, it is a good film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damn-eth
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate is one of the best films in the history of cinema. Both players and cues make the film charming. When you watch the film, you can't understand how it finishes since it progresses fluently. When people decide wrong decisions and choices, it is too late for turning back. This film dealt with them very well. Also, actors and actress have a impact on watching the film with integrating the roles of their.Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are leading roles. The film explains life of a successful lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves ) that his life changes after he meets rich businessman John Milton (Al Pacino). Kevin is an ambitious lawyer, his only aim is to succeed in his career and he saves them from even they are guilty. Kevin meets John and moves to New York. He affects from him but essentially, he makes an agreement with devil. In the beginning, everything is better. But after that, his wife faces to psychological problems. So, lawyer notices some realities and he tries to change something. I like cues of film so much. Especially, "Vanity is definitely my favorite sin." I think, the film doesn't lose ıt's beauty even the years passes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The devil has a son...called Kevin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is truly an oddity. There's the usual series of gruesome deaths lifted from The Omen and many another supernatural yarn accompanied by the now standard choral music. There's nothing much in the way of originality about any of this, but it does at least hold the attention. The most interesting thing are the bravura speeches from the villain John Milton (AKA The Devil) delivered with great gusto by Al Pacino, but some of the gravitas is undermined by his son's rather bathetic name 'Kevin'. 'Beelzebub and Kevin' does not quite have a demonic ring to it. The formulaic script is written more for melodramatic impact than sense, with people wandering onto busy roads for no apparent reason only to be mowed down by cars and such like. One strange and inexplicable scene has a blood drenched Kevin after just seeing his wife die by slitting her own throat meet his mother. Rather than her saying "why are you covered in blood, Kevin?" or "My God! what happened to my daughter-in-law?" instead she launches into a longwinded exposition (but one telegraphed at least an hour earlier in the film) that Milton is his father. All this is gory and faintly ludicrous but is carried out with Hollywood slickness and would perhaps deserve a better score were it not for the unforgivable finale where this house of cards collapses. Kevin is tempted to join his satanic father by having sex with his own sister. Instead of this Kevin chooses to shoot himself at which point any sense the script had disappears. Kevin's sister for some unexplained reason dies. The devil's (and the emperor's new) clothes fall off, he starts to burn while shouting "No! No!" The only way this comically bad scene could have been improved would have been to have Pacino say, "HE'S NOT THE ANTICHRIST! HE'S A VERY NAUGHTY BOY!" All this makes little sense dramatically or theologically. How can you defeat the devil by committing suicide? Isn't that expressly forbidden in the scriptures? Still you could argue that the point is that Kevin makes an act of self-sacrifice and had it ended there it perhaps would not have been so bad. BUT THEN HE WAKES UP! Seriously, he is then back at the very start of the film before any of the bad stuff happened. In other words the whole thing was an extended dream sequence. This is the sort of thing that first year English students are told to avoid. To cap it all Kevin then refuses to defend his client, something than is strangely presented as a moral stance when it is actually morally and legally dubious. Isn't it a lawyer's duty to defend his client even if he knows his client is guilty? A pointless re-appearance of Al Pacino right at the end just adds to the incoherence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary, Thought Provoking, Just Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mediapeertime
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films about Satan. Great at deceiving, full of power, loses in the end - as the devil should! This was altogether a great lawyer film. In this film, we get to see one of Pacino's best performances. He wasn't that usual character that we'r5e so used to seeing. Also tremendous performances by Charlize Theron, Connie Nielson, Jeffrey Jones, Tamara Tunie, and Craig T. Nelson. Couldn't buy Keaneau Reeves in the best lawyer role. he was adequate at best. Watch the train scene with Al Pacino - just tremendous! Taylor Hackford, great work (except casting of Reeves, but that mau not have been his choice????)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Brilliant!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elif490
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exceptional. Simply perfect. I watched without blinking my eye for a moment until the end of the film, and the final literally shocked me. As it tells us the relationship between us and satisfaction & sins, it shows us our biggest weaknesses as people. This film makes you terrify and at the same time it makes you learn a lot. Acting is even better than 'magnificent'. Legendary is a way less description for Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are fantastic!! Excellent and unique. Anyone who doesn't watch this movie loses a lot. It just blows your mind! Seriously. It's one of the bests. Once you watch it, you will never forget about this movie. Ten out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keanu Reeves as a bad-ass lawyer from hell.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tess van Brummelen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting (Keanu Reeves, Al Pacino and Charlize Theron) was brilliant. This film is scary as hell. Favorite quotes: "It's not a dream if it's true." "Your belly's too full, your dick is sore, your eyes are bloodshot, and you're screaming for someone to help!" "It's the goof of all time. Look but don't touch. Touch, but don't taste. Taste, don't swallow. Ahaha." "Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. The virtue of the devil is in his loins." "Vanity, definitely my favorite sin."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a stylish supernatural thriller about the temptation of evil for a young lawyer from the South. When he is offered a big time job in New York by big time lawyer played by Al Pacino, he finds there is a price to pay. The cast is good. Al Pacino before he got really devilish looking is good except for the silly dance at the end. Connie Nielsen is sophisticated and elegant. Charlize Theron is moving and convincing as the young wife sacrificing her looks for a standout performance. Even Keanu acts quite well as the young lawyer and you can't say that about too many of his movies. They didn't make it over the top horror - it's clever and frightening without much gore or in your face violence. Along with Rosemary's Baby this is the best NYC supernatural horror movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demonic thriller full of tension and pain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    4rch 4ng3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The figure of the devil posted in a contemporaney time, with a great Keanu Reeves and a really appreciable Al Pacino as the mysterious figure of the hided evil. Charlize Theron is absorbed by the pain and the sufference caused, a trap filled with an articoulate labyrinth of lies and bad actions. The screenplay, not even need to talk, is fantastic and avvolving at all, withal an adrenalinic envelopment an a huge tale of twists and questions. The way out is difficoult to find and the easy decisions are not part of the dialogues or the plot. The evil is so high and so showed, without fear, is unstoppable and known at the same time. The conseguences are so many and impossible to predict.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't really live up to its hype
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one film I had been wanting to watch for quite some time now, and I got around to it just a while back. I had some really good expectations from this movie, as I had read about it on IMDb and other movie sites, and I had thought it would be a courtroom thriller filled with suspense. But I have to say I was a bit disappointed with what I saw. The film is about a hotshot Florida lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves) who has never lost a case in his entire career. A New York law firm enlists his help to select a jury for a case and recognizing his talent, offers him a job. Lomax accepts and becomes quite close to his boss, John Milton (Al Pacino) during the course of his work. But he gradually begins to uncover some strange facets of Milton's personality and finally realizes that he is none other than Satan himself. Now, such a premise should surely set the stage for a riveting thriller filled with suspense and mystery. But sadly, it doesn't. I think the main reason is Keanu Reeves' performance. I couldn't really buy the idea of him being an argumentative lawyer who could acquit a rapist in spite of the pile of evidence staring him in the face, especially as this is what is shown in the first scene of the film. If the scene is supposed to convince the viewer of the talent of this young lawyer, it doesn't really pass the test. The only thing it does is invariably draw comparisons to the courtroom scenes in "A Few good Men", which had fabulous dialogues, coupled with one of Tom Cruise's finest performances ever. So it is asking a lot to make the audience believe that Lomax hasn't yet lost a case. Apart from this, the film does have a few things going for it. The pace is fast and well set, and for a first time viewing, there is no scene which makes you feel bored, irksome or irritable. And, of course, there's Al Pacino. His thunderous voice and arrogant demeanour are enough to make the viewer feel uncomfortable about him, and it isn't really hard to associate his character with that of the Devil. The other characters merely serve as pretexts for Lomax's wife to lose control over herself and imagine things related to hell, Satan and all that stuff. All in all, I wouldn't recommend this as a must-see, but probably something you might just rent at a DVD store when your other choices aren't that appealing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Night of the world"- uncreated by fable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yughred
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt that Kevin is familiar with the Bible, this is the weapon of the debate in his court in "Mo Yizi case, he resorted to the freedom of religious belief of the party days India with eloquence eloquent Mo Yizi acquitted on the charges, plus Mo Yizi assistant prosecutor Arnold Modu facilities witchcraft, it coughing, unable to speak, and Kevin got his wish to obtain another victory. Famous football coach Vince Lombardi once behalf of Kevin shouted his voice: "Winning is not everything, but only! Bible or religion or in the creation of four 60-game winning streak myth The young lawyer Kevin's eyes, but the tools to win the victory. The United States is a respect for the success of the nation, "the exclusive worship of successfully goddess bitch" overwhelm everything, including God. Xu Kaiwen court numerous times to praise the name of the Lord, in his heart, God is but a trite illusory value symbol. This era is the era of man and the world is completely lost. The maze of free will Make free will answer the philosophers who believe that God create people are born with free will - are born with the ability to act in accordance with their own wishes. The face of the world, people can be free to make a choice. Therefore, evil and suffering in the world, is the result of the abuse of free will, this responsibility should be by the people themselves to provide us with. God is not interfered. From the words of the Bible, we can infer that: God created Adam and Eve when, inevitably given their free will - the event that obey the spell of the snake Tousijinguo this crime, is not based on the free will to make autonomous decision, while is responsible for the crimes they have committed a pre-determined by God no choice behavior, then, God, what is the reason to make Adam and Eve it? The philosophical insights is the one held by the "devil's advocate". Summit in New York, in the face of the nations bustling, Kevin chose an opposite road with Jesus Christ, step-by-step into the trap of the devil - based on the free will. Yes, free will! Kevin's mother and wife successively abduction by Satan, the same is based on the free will of independent decision. Satan never force others to comply with his will. God, he respects the free will of the people. "I don't make things happen", he was just with a charming smile, charm by saying, to induce the people inside the original sin. He does not directly make any demands. He even twice put the persuasion attitude demagogue mending their ways. Free will, this is a wonderful word! In the eyes of the people, it embodied the pride and glory of the man. And Satan said: "Free will, it is a bitch." Bitch Italian English word "bitch, slut, nasty stuff", full of humble and despicable mean. Sadly, if Satan is not wrong. Bear the original sin of the people, given human nature and the dark background. Night of the world ", dumping large town of Babylon, God-given free will of light in this dark human nature, it has been alienated to slut who gaudy jeweled. "I'm a fan of man. I'm a humanist, maybe the last humanist." Satan wanton interpretation of the words of Montaigne: "anything that can occur in the human body and it was not inhuman." His "humanitarian doctrine "is to distort the true meaning of free will along the dark humanity, his definition of" freedom "is an absolute and unfettered freedom, one to do whatever they want to meet the desire of freedom. The paradox is that the absolute freedom, being mean absolute enslavement. "Man is born free, but no go without chains. Precisely the desire, only the desire of the human heart, is the real shackles, people become prisoners under the order shall not be free. Conspiracy of Satan took advantage of the free will of the people of the world - which lost in the sea of ​​desire free will, step by step, to lure the world turned away from God and become degenerate. "The 20th century was entirely mine", at the moment, Satan winner complacent. So, what is truly "free"? Jesus as early as "John." Provides us with the answer: "You shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free." Face of the unexpected defeat of Satan desperately shouting: "No! Damn you! Enough! Have not I given enough?" Ezekiel book describes the scene in an instant staged: "Are you proud because of the beautiful hearts corrupted your wisdom because of glory, I have sent thee to the ground you down before kings, good that they may behold thee. sins of many, unfair trade defiled thy sanctuary. therefore will I bring fire from you issue the middle, devour thee, and upon the earth in the sight of all people watch ashes "in a raging fire, Satan revealed a proud Blazing Angels Lucifer Mami. Satan carefully constructed dream collapsed in an instant. Out from the sea of ​​desire meditation from Kevin, the court did not hesitate to refuse to act as the spokesperson of the devil, the hearts of the people think: a hero was born, God, after all, to get the victory. However, Satan is everywhere. He was the embodiment of the snake, and also the embodiment of the law firm boss, he can transform himself into a tabloid reporter. Kevin's body, after all, keep the pride and vanity of the blood of Lucifer. Marian also as her ancestor Eve, enticed her husband swallowed sinking attractive fruit. The temptation is everywhere. Free will still trapped in the maze. The night of the world is still long. The dawn of being buried. "Alas, Babylon the great! Moment between your judgment come ... never again shining light in the midst of thee ..."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Devil's Avocate, an interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waltyeresdesousa (waltyeresdesousa@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate A movie of mystery and suspense, where people left their normal lives to live a story that since its beginning is surreal. That is how rolls The Devil's Advocate. Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reevens) is a lawyer that began his carrier at Florida and his principal characteristics are: He's never lost a court case before; He wins cases whether the accused is innocent or not; He is an excellent professional and it calls much attention of a millionaire - John Milton (Al Pacino), an owner of largest law firm in New York. John makes a proposal that cannot be refused by Kevin: if he wins the cases, he would work with him and have a good job and house. So he passed to live better in New York- the city that already wished for many peoples- with his wife Mary Ann Lomax (Charlize Theron), who had worked a lot before, since she was 13. Kevin unfortunately accepts this proposal even being advised by his mother Alice Lomax (Judith Ivev) that New York was the big Babylon, as descriptive on Apocalypse. He was a religious man when he was a child, Kevin knew this prophecy but he thought would only practice his religiosity again in his old age. By not listening to the prophecy, his life changes radically from that. He starts to work in this new company and his wife stays at home because she doesn't work anymore. Her function was only to take care of the house. But strange things start to happen in her life, she begins to see strange shapes in the people and they pass to have some aspects of demons and they are trying to scare her. The most interesting fact is that the boss of Kevin, Mr. John, always knows everything that happens in his married life. After many events, the movie ends with secrets revealed; Kevin finds out that his boss and his own mother are the center of the secret that could transform his life totally. When the movie ends, it scions about vanity and reinterpret the habitual concept about it and take this concept to Spiritual life. The movie sin in last scenes because it ends in a messy and the movie didn't make clear the real surreal. Can call your attention in a way that you forget the world, it try to exit you of the simple world where your mind can open to others' understanding. This movie is directed by Taylor Hackford, lasts 2:23:34. It was produced in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For watching, it is a good film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damn-eth
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate is one of the best films in the history of cinema. Both players and cues make the film charming. When you watch the film, you can't understand how it finishes since it progresses fluently. When people decide wrong decisions and choices, it is too late for turning back. This film dealt with them very well. Also, actors and actress have a impact on watching the film with integrating the roles of their.Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are leading roles. The film explains life of a successful lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves ) that his life changes after he meets rich businessman John Milton (Al Pacino). Kevin is an ambitious lawyer, his only aim is to succeed in his career and he saves them from even they are guilty. Kevin meets John and moves to New York. He affects from him but essentially, he makes an agreement with devil. In the beginning, everything is better. But after that, his wife faces to psychological problems. So, lawyer notices some realities and he tries to change something. I like cues of film so much. Especially, "Vanity is definitely my favorite sin." I think, the film doesn't lose ıt's beauty even the years passes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The devil has a son...called Kevin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is truly an oddity. There's the usual series of gruesome deaths lifted from The Omen and many another supernatural yarn accompanied by the now standard choral music. There's nothing much in the way of originality about any of this, but it does at least hold the attention. The most interesting thing are the bravura speeches from the villain John Milton (AKA The Devil) delivered with great gusto by Al Pacino, but some of the gravitas is undermined by his son's rather bathetic name 'Kevin'. 'Beelzebub and Kevin' does not quite have a demonic ring to it. The formulaic script is written more for melodramatic impact than sense, with people wandering onto busy roads for no apparent reason only to be mowed down by cars and such like. One strange and inexplicable scene has a blood drenched Kevin after just seeing his wife die by slitting her own throat meet his mother. Rather than her saying "why are you covered in blood, Kevin?" or "My God! what happened to my daughter-in-law?" instead she launches into a longwinded exposition (but one telegraphed at least an hour earlier in the film) that Milton is his father. All this is gory and faintly ludicrous but is carried out with Hollywood slickness and would perhaps deserve a better score were it not for the unforgivable finale where this house of cards collapses. Kevin is tempted to join his satanic father by having sex with his own sister. Instead of this Kevin chooses to shoot himself at which point any sense the script had disappears. Kevin's sister for some unexplained reason dies. The devil's (and the emperor's new) clothes fall off, he starts to burn while shouting "No! No!" The only way this comically bad scene could have been improved would have been to have Pacino say, "HE'S NOT THE ANTICHRIST! HE'S A VERY NAUGHTY BOY!" All this makes little sense dramatically or theologically. How can you defeat the devil by committing suicide? Isn't that expressly forbidden in the scriptures? Still you could argue that the point is that Kevin makes an act of self-sacrifice and had it ended there it perhaps would not have been so bad. BUT THEN HE WAKES UP! Seriously, he is then back at the very start of the film before any of the bad stuff happened. In other words the whole thing was an extended dream sequence. This is the sort of thing that first year English students are told to avoid. To cap it all Kevin then refuses to defend his client, something than is strangely presented as a moral stance when it is actually morally and legally dubious. Isn't it a lawyer's duty to defend his client even if he knows his client is guilty? A pointless re-appearance of Al Pacino right at the end just adds to the incoherence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary, Thought Provoking, Just Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mediapeertime
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films about Satan. Great at deceiving, full of power, loses in the end - as the devil should! This was altogether a great lawyer film. In this film, we get to see one of Pacino's best performances. He wasn't that usual character that we'r5e so used to seeing. Also tremendous performances by Charlize Theron, Connie Nielson, Jeffrey Jones, Tamara Tunie, and Craig T. Nelson. Couldn't buy Keaneau Reeves in the best lawyer role. he was adequate at best. Watch the train scene with Al Pacino - just tremendous! Taylor Hackford, great work (except casting of Reeves, but that mau not have been his choice????)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Brilliant!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elif490
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exceptional. Simply perfect. I watched without blinking my eye for a moment until the end of the film, and the final literally shocked me. As it tells us the relationship between us and satisfaction & sins, it shows us our biggest weaknesses as people. This film makes you terrify and at the same time it makes you learn a lot. Acting is even better than 'magnificent'. Legendary is a way less description for Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are fantastic!! Excellent and unique. Anyone who doesn't watch this movie loses a lot. It just blows your mind! Seriously. It's one of the bests. Once you watch it, you will never forget about this movie. Ten out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keanu Reeves as a bad-ass lawyer from hell.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tess van Brummelen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting (Keanu Reeves, Al Pacino and Charlize Theron) was brilliant. This film is scary as hell. Favorite quotes: "It's not a dream if it's true." "Your belly's too full, your dick is sore, your eyes are bloodshot, and you're screaming for someone to help!" "It's the goof of all time. Look but don't touch. Touch, but don't taste. Taste, don't swallow. Ahaha." "Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. The virtue of the devil is in his loins." "Vanity, definitely my favorite sin."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a stylish supernatural thriller about the temptation of evil for a young lawyer from the South. When he is offered a big time job in New York by big time lawyer played by Al Pacino, he finds there is a price to pay. The cast is good. Al Pacino before he got really devilish looking is good except for the silly dance at the end. Connie Nielsen is sophisticated and elegant. Charlize Theron is moving and convincing as the young wife sacrificing her looks for a standout performance. Even Keanu acts quite well as the young lawyer and you can't say that about too many of his movies. They didn't make it over the top horror - it's clever and frightening without much gore or in your face violence. Along with Rosemary's Baby this is the best NYC supernatural horror movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demonic thriller full of tension and pain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    4rch 4ng3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The figure of the devil posted in a contemporaney time, with a great Keanu Reeves and a really appreciable Al Pacino as the mysterious figure of the hided evil. Charlize Theron is absorbed by the pain and the sufference caused, a trap filled with an articoulate labyrinth of lies and bad actions. The screenplay, not even need to talk, is fantastic and avvolving at all, withal an adrenalinic envelopment an a huge tale of twists and questions. The way out is difficoult to find and the easy decisions are not part of the dialogues or the plot. The evil is so high and so showed, without fear, is unstoppable and known at the same time. The conseguences are so many and impossible to predict.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't really live up to its hype
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one film I had been wanting to watch for quite some time now, and I got around to it just a while back. I had some really good expectations from this movie, as I had read about it on IMDb and other movie sites, and I had thought it would be a courtroom thriller filled with suspense. But I have to say I was a bit disappointed with what I saw. The film is about a hotshot Florida lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves) who has never lost a case in his entire career. A New York law firm enlists his help to select a jury for a case and recognizing his talent, offers him a job. Lomax accepts and becomes quite close to his boss, John Milton (Al Pacino) during the course of his work. But he gradually begins to uncover some strange facets of Milton's personality and finally realizes that he is none other than Satan himself. Now, such a premise should surely set the stage for a riveting thriller filled with suspense and mystery. But sadly, it doesn't. I think the main reason is Keanu Reeves' performance. I couldn't really buy the idea of him being an argumentative lawyer who could acquit a rapist in spite of the pile of evidence staring him in the face, especially as this is what is shown in the first scene of the film. If the scene is supposed to convince the viewer of the talent of this young lawyer, it doesn't really pass the test. The only thing it does is invariably draw comparisons to the courtroom scenes in "A Few good Men", which had fabulous dialogues, coupled with one of Tom Cruise's finest performances ever. So it is asking a lot to make the audience believe that Lomax hasn't yet lost a case. Apart from this, the film does have a few things going for it. The pace is fast and well set, and for a first time viewing, there is no scene which makes you feel bored, irksome or irritable. And, of course, there's Al Pacino. His thunderous voice and arrogant demeanour are enough to make the viewer feel uncomfortable about him, and it isn't really hard to associate his character with that of the Devil. The other characters merely serve as pretexts for Lomax's wife to lose control over herself and imagine things related to hell, Satan and all that stuff. All in all, I wouldn't recommend this as a must-see, but probably something you might just rent at a DVD store when your other choices aren't that appealing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Night of the world"- uncreated by fable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yughred
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt that Kevin is familiar with the Bible, this is the weapon of the debate in his court in "Mo Yizi case, he resorted to the freedom of religious belief of the party days India with eloquence eloquent Mo Yizi acquitted on the charges, plus Mo Yizi assistant prosecutor Arnold Modu facilities witchcraft, it coughing, unable to speak, and Kevin got his wish to obtain another victory. Famous football coach Vince Lombardi once behalf of Kevin shouted his voice: "Winning is not everything, but only! Bible or religion or in the creation of four 60-game winning streak myth The young lawyer Kevin's eyes, but the tools to win the victory. The United States is a respect for the success of the nation, "the exclusive worship of successfully goddess bitch" overwhelm everything, including God. Xu Kaiwen court numerous times to praise the name of the Lord, in his heart, God is but a trite illusory value symbol. This era is the era of man and the world is completely lost. The maze of free will Make free will answer the philosophers who believe that God create people are born with free will - are born with the ability to act in accordance with their own wishes. The face of the world, people can be free to make a choice. Therefore, evil and suffering in the world, is the result of the abuse of free will, this responsibility should be by the people themselves to provide us with. God is not interfered. From the words of the Bible, we can infer that: God created Adam and Eve when, inevitably given their free will - the event that obey the spell of the snake Tousijinguo this crime, is not based on the free will to make autonomous decision, while is responsible for the crimes they have committed a pre-determined by God no choice behavior, then, God, what is the reason to make Adam and Eve it? The philosophical insights is the one held by the "devil's advocate". Summit in New York, in the face of the nations bustling, Kevin chose an opposite road with Jesus Christ, step-by-step into the trap of the devil - based on the free will. Yes, free will! Kevin's mother and wife successively abduction by Satan, the same is based on the free will of independent decision. Satan never force others to comply with his will. God, he respects the free will of the people. "I don't make things happen", he was just with a charming smile, charm by saying, to induce the people inside the original sin. He does not directly make any demands. He even twice put the persuasion attitude demagogue mending their ways. Free will, this is a wonderful word! In the eyes of the people, it embodied the pride and glory of the man. And Satan said: "Free will, it is a bitch." Bitch Italian English word "bitch, slut, nasty stuff", full of humble and despicable mean. Sadly, if Satan is not wrong. Bear the original sin of the people, given human nature and the dark background. Night of the world ", dumping large town of Babylon, God-given free will of light in this dark human nature, it has been alienated to slut who gaudy jeweled. "I'm a fan of man. I'm a humanist, maybe the last humanist." Satan wanton interpretation of the words of Montaigne: "anything that can occur in the human body and it was not inhuman." His "humanitarian doctrine "is to distort the true meaning of free will along the dark humanity, his definition of" freedom "is an absolute and unfettered freedom, one to do whatever they want to meet the desire of freedom. The paradox is that the absolute freedom, being mean absolute enslavement. "Man is born free, but no go without chains. Precisely the desire, only the desire of the human heart, is the real shackles, people become prisoners under the order shall not be free. Conspiracy of Satan took advantage of the free will of the people of the world - which lost in the sea of ​​desire free will, step by step, to lure the world turned away from God and become degenerate. "The 20th century was entirely mine", at the moment, Satan winner complacent. So, what is truly "free"? Jesus as early as "John." Provides us with the answer: "You shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free." Face of the unexpected defeat of Satan desperately shouting: "No! Damn you! Enough! Have not I given enough?" Ezekiel book describes the scene in an instant staged: "Are you proud because of the beautiful hearts corrupted your wisdom because of glory, I have sent thee to the ground you down before kings, good that they may behold thee. sins of many, unfair trade defiled thy sanctuary. therefore will I bring fire from you issue the middle, devour thee, and upon the earth in the sight of all people watch ashes "in a raging fire, Satan revealed a proud Blazing Angels Lucifer Mami. Satan carefully constructed dream collapsed in an instant. Out from the sea of ​​desire meditation from Kevin, the court did not hesitate to refuse to act as the spokesperson of the devil, the hearts of the people think: a hero was born, God, after all, to get the victory. However, Satan is everywhere. He was the embodiment of the snake, and also the embodiment of the law firm boss, he can transform himself into a tabloid reporter. Kevin's body, after all, keep the pride and vanity of the blood of Lucifer. Marian also as her ancestor Eve, enticed her husband swallowed sinking attractive fruit. The temptation is everywhere. Free will still trapped in the maze. The night of the world is still long. The dawn of being buried. "Alas, Babylon the great! Moment between your judgment come ... never again shining light in the midst of thee ..."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Devil's Avocate, an interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waltyeresdesousa (waltyeresdesousa@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate A movie of mystery and suspense, where people left their normal lives to live a story that since its beginning is surreal. That is how rolls The Devil's Advocate. Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reevens) is a lawyer that began his carrier at Florida and his principal characteristics are: He's never lost a court case before; He wins cases whether the accused is innocent or not; He is an excellent professional and it calls much attention of a millionaire - John Milton (Al Pacino), an owner of largest law firm in New York. John makes a proposal that cannot be refused by Kevin: if he wins the cases, he would work with him and have a good job and house. So he passed to live better in New York- the city that already wished for many peoples- with his wife Mary Ann Lomax (Charlize Theron), who had worked a lot before, since she was 13. Kevin unfortunately accepts this proposal even being advised by his mother Alice Lomax (Judith Ivev) that New York was the big Babylon, as descriptive on Apocalypse. He was a religious man when he was a child, Kevin knew this prophecy but he thought would only practice his religiosity again in his old age. By not listening to the prophecy, his life changes radically from that. He starts to work in this new company and his wife stays at home because she doesn't work anymore. Her function was only to take care of the house. But strange things start to happen in her life, she begins to see strange shapes in the people and they pass to have some aspects of demons and they are trying to scare her. The most interesting fact is that the boss of Kevin, Mr. John, always knows everything that happens in his married life. After many events, the movie ends with secrets revealed; Kevin finds out that his boss and his own mother are the center of the secret that could transform his life totally. When the movie ends, it scions about vanity and reinterpret the habitual concept about it and take this concept to Spiritual life. The movie sin in last scenes because it ends in a messy and the movie didn't make clear the real surreal. Can call your attention in a way that you forget the world, it try to exit you of the simple world where your mind can open to others' understanding. This movie is directed by Taylor Hackford, lasts 2:23:34. It was produced in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For watching, it is a good film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damn-eth
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate is one of the best films in the history of cinema. Both players and cues make the film charming. When you watch the film, you can't understand how it finishes since it progresses fluently. When people decide wrong decisions and choices, it is too late for turning back. This film dealt with them very well. Also, actors and actress have a impact on watching the film with integrating the roles of their.Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are leading roles. The film explains life of a successful lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves ) that his life changes after he meets rich businessman John Milton (Al Pacino). Kevin is an ambitious lawyer, his only aim is to succeed in his career and he saves them from even they are guilty. Kevin meets John and moves to New York. He affects from him but essentially, he makes an agreement with devil. In the beginning, everything is better. But after that, his wife faces to psychological problems. So, lawyer notices some realities and he tries to change something. I like cues of film so much. Especially, "Vanity is definitely my favorite sin." I think, the film doesn't lose ıt's beauty even the years passes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The devil has a son...called Kevin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is truly an oddity. There's the usual series of gruesome deaths lifted from The Omen and many another supernatural yarn accompanied by the now standard choral music. There's nothing much in the way of originality about any of this, but it does at least hold the attention. The most interesting thing are the bravura speeches from the villain John Milton (AKA The Devil) delivered with great gusto by Al Pacino, but some of the gravitas is undermined by his son's rather bathetic name 'Kevin'. 'Beelzebub and Kevin' does not quite have a demonic ring to it. The formulaic script is written more for melodramatic impact than sense, with people wandering onto busy roads for no apparent reason only to be mowed down by cars and such like. One strange and inexplicable scene has a blood drenched Kevin after just seeing his wife die by slitting her own throat meet his mother. Rather than her saying "why are you covered in blood, Kevin?" or "My God! what happened to my daughter-in-law?" instead she launches into a longwinded exposition (but one telegraphed at least an hour earlier in the film) that Milton is his father. All this is gory and faintly ludicrous but is carried out with Hollywood slickness and would perhaps deserve a better score were it not for the unforgivable finale where this house of cards collapses. Kevin is tempted to join his satanic father by having sex with his own sister. Instead of this Kevin chooses to shoot himself at which point any sense the script had disappears. Kevin's sister for some unexplained reason dies. The devil's (and the emperor's new) clothes fall off, he starts to burn while shouting "No! No!" The only way this comically bad scene could have been improved would have been to have Pacino say, "HE'S NOT THE ANTICHRIST! HE'S A VERY NAUGHTY BOY!" All this makes little sense dramatically or theologically. How can you defeat the devil by committing suicide? Isn't that expressly forbidden in the scriptures? Still you could argue that the point is that Kevin makes an act of self-sacrifice and had it ended there it perhaps would not have been so bad. BUT THEN HE WAKES UP! Seriously, he is then back at the very start of the film before any of the bad stuff happened. In other words the whole thing was an extended dream sequence. This is the sort of thing that first year English students are told to avoid. To cap it all Kevin then refuses to defend his client, something than is strangely presented as a moral stance when it is actually morally and legally dubious. Isn't it a lawyer's duty to defend his client even if he knows his client is guilty? A pointless re-appearance of Al Pacino right at the end just adds to the incoherence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary, Thought Provoking, Just Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mediapeertime
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films about Satan. Great at deceiving, full of power, loses in the end - as the devil should! This was altogether a great lawyer film. In this film, we get to see one of Pacino's best performances. He wasn't that usual character that we'r5e so used to seeing. Also tremendous performances by Charlize Theron, Connie Nielson, Jeffrey Jones, Tamara Tunie, and Craig T. Nelson. Couldn't buy Keaneau Reeves in the best lawyer role. he was adequate at best. Watch the train scene with Al Pacino - just tremendous! Taylor Hackford, great work (except casting of Reeves, but that mau not have been his choice????)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Brilliant!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elif490
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exceptional. Simply perfect. I watched without blinking my eye for a moment until the end of the film, and the final literally shocked me. As it tells us the relationship between us and satisfaction & sins, it shows us our biggest weaknesses as people. This film makes you terrify and at the same time it makes you learn a lot. Acting is even better than 'magnificent'. Legendary is a way less description for Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are fantastic!! Excellent and unique. Anyone who doesn't watch this movie loses a lot. It just blows your mind! Seriously. It's one of the bests. Once you watch it, you will never forget about this movie. Ten out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keanu Reeves as a bad-ass lawyer from hell.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tess van Brummelen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting (Keanu Reeves, Al Pacino and Charlize Theron) was brilliant. This film is scary as hell. Favorite quotes: "It's not a dream if it's true." "Your belly's too full, your dick is sore, your eyes are bloodshot, and you're screaming for someone to help!" "It's the goof of all time. Look but don't touch. Touch, but don't taste. Taste, don't swallow. Ahaha." "Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. The virtue of the devil is in his loins." "Vanity, definitely my favorite sin."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a stylish supernatural thriller about the temptation of evil for a young lawyer from the South. When he is offered a big time job in New York by big time lawyer played by Al Pacino, he finds there is a price to pay. The cast is good. Al Pacino before he got really devilish looking is good except for the silly dance at the end. Connie Nielsen is sophisticated and elegant. Charlize Theron is moving and convincing as the young wife sacrificing her looks for a standout performance. Even Keanu acts quite well as the young lawyer and you can't say that about too many of his movies. They didn't make it over the top horror - it's clever and frightening without much gore or in your face violence. Along with Rosemary's Baby this is the best NYC supernatural horror movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demonic thriller full of tension and pain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    4rch 4ng3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The figure of the devil posted in a contemporaney time, with a great Keanu Reeves and a really appreciable Al Pacino as the mysterious figure of the hided evil. Charlize Theron is absorbed by the pain and the sufference caused, a trap filled with an articoulate labyrinth of lies and bad actions. The screenplay, not even need to talk, is fantastic and avvolving at all, withal an adrenalinic envelopment an a huge tale of twists and questions. The way out is difficoult to find and the easy decisions are not part of the dialogues or the plot. The evil is so high and so showed, without fear, is unstoppable and known at the same time. The conseguences are so many and impossible to predict.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't really live up to its hype
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one film I had been wanting to watch for quite some time now, and I got around to it just a while back. I had some really good expectations from this movie, as I had read about it on IMDb and other movie sites, and I had thought it would be a courtroom thriller filled with suspense. But I have to say I was a bit disappointed with what I saw. The film is about a hotshot Florida lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves) who has never lost a case in his entire career. A New York law firm enlists his help to select a jury for a case and recognizing his talent, offers him a job. Lomax accepts and becomes quite close to his boss, John Milton (Al Pacino) during the course of his work. But he gradually begins to uncover some strange facets of Milton's personality and finally realizes that he is none other than Satan himself. Now, such a premise should surely set the stage for a riveting thriller filled with suspense and mystery. But sadly, it doesn't. I think the main reason is Keanu Reeves' performance. I couldn't really buy the idea of him being an argumentative lawyer who could acquit a rapist in spite of the pile of evidence staring him in the face, especially as this is what is shown in the first scene of the film. If the scene is supposed to convince the viewer of the talent of this young lawyer, it doesn't really pass the test. The only thing it does is invariably draw comparisons to the courtroom scenes in "A Few good Men", which had fabulous dialogues, coupled with one of Tom Cruise's finest performances ever. So it is asking a lot to make the audience believe that Lomax hasn't yet lost a case. Apart from this, the film does have a few things going for it. The pace is fast and well set, and for a first time viewing, there is no scene which makes you feel bored, irksome or irritable. And, of course, there's Al Pacino. His thunderous voice and arrogant demeanour are enough to make the viewer feel uncomfortable about him, and it isn't really hard to associate his character with that of the Devil. The other characters merely serve as pretexts for Lomax's wife to lose control over herself and imagine things related to hell, Satan and all that stuff. All in all, I wouldn't recommend this as a must-see, but probably something you might just rent at a DVD store when your other choices aren't that appealing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Night of the world"- uncreated by fable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yughred
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt that Kevin is familiar with the Bible, this is the weapon of the debate in his court in "Mo Yizi case, he resorted to the freedom of religious belief of the party days India with eloquence eloquent Mo Yizi acquitted on the charges, plus Mo Yizi assistant prosecutor Arnold Modu facilities witchcraft, it coughing, unable to speak, and Kevin got his wish to obtain another victory. Famous football coach Vince Lombardi once behalf of Kevin shouted his voice: "Winning is not everything, but only! Bible or religion or in the creation of four 60-game winning streak myth The young lawyer Kevin's eyes, but the tools to win the victory. The United States is a respect for the success of the nation, "the exclusive worship of successfully goddess bitch" overwhelm everything, including God. Xu Kaiwen court numerous times to praise the name of the Lord, in his heart, God is but a trite illusory value symbol. This era is the era of man and the world is completely lost. The maze of free will Make free will answer the philosophers who believe that God create people are born with free will - are born with the ability to act in accordance with their own wishes. The face of the world, people can be free to make a choice. Therefore, evil and suffering in the world, is the result of the abuse of free will, this responsibility should be by the people themselves to provide us with. God is not interfered. From the words of the Bible, we can infer that: God created Adam and Eve when, inevitably given their free will - the event that obey the spell of the snake Tousijinguo this crime, is not based on the free will to make autonomous decision, while is responsible for the crimes they have committed a pre-determined by God no choice behavior, then, God, what is the reason to make Adam and Eve it? The philosophical insights is the one held by the "devil's advocate". Summit in New York, in the face of the nations bustling, Kevin chose an opposite road with Jesus Christ, step-by-step into the trap of the devil - based on the free will. Yes, free will! Kevin's mother and wife successively abduction by Satan, the same is based on the free will of independent decision. Satan never force others to comply with his will. God, he respects the free will of the people. "I don't make things happen", he was just with a charming smile, charm by saying, to induce the people inside the original sin. He does not directly make any demands. He even twice put the persuasion attitude demagogue mending their ways. Free will, this is a wonderful word! In the eyes of the people, it embodied the pride and glory of the man. And Satan said: "Free will, it is a bitch." Bitch Italian English word "bitch, slut, nasty stuff", full of humble and despicable mean. Sadly, if Satan is not wrong. Bear the original sin of the people, given human nature and the dark background. Night of the world ", dumping large town of Babylon, God-given free will of light in this dark human nature, it has been alienated to slut who gaudy jeweled. "I'm a fan of man. I'm a humanist, maybe the last humanist." Satan wanton interpretation of the words of Montaigne: "anything that can occur in the human body and it was not inhuman." His "humanitarian doctrine "is to distort the true meaning of free will along the dark humanity, his definition of" freedom "is an absolute and unfettered freedom, one to do whatever they want to meet the desire of freedom. The paradox is that the absolute freedom, being mean absolute enslavement. "Man is born free, but no go without chains. Precisely the desire, only the desire of the human heart, is the real shackles, people become prisoners under the order shall not be free. Conspiracy of Satan took advantage of the free will of the people of the world - which lost in the sea of ​​desire free will, step by step, to lure the world turned away from God and become degenerate. "The 20th century was entirely mine", at the moment, Satan winner complacent. So, what is truly "free"? Jesus as early as "John." Provides us with the answer: "You shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free." Face of the unexpected defeat of Satan desperately shouting: "No! Damn you! Enough! Have not I given enough?" Ezekiel book describes the scene in an instant staged: "Are you proud because of the beautiful hearts corrupted your wisdom because of glory, I have sent thee to the ground you down before kings, good that they may behold thee. sins of many, unfair trade defiled thy sanctuary. therefore will I bring fire from you issue the middle, devour thee, and upon the earth in the sight of all people watch ashes "in a raging fire, Satan revealed a proud Blazing Angels Lucifer Mami. Satan carefully constructed dream collapsed in an instant. Out from the sea of ​​desire meditation from Kevin, the court did not hesitate to refuse to act as the spokesperson of the devil, the hearts of the people think: a hero was born, God, after all, to get the victory. However, Satan is everywhere. He was the embodiment of the snake, and also the embodiment of the law firm boss, he can transform himself into a tabloid reporter. Kevin's body, after all, keep the pride and vanity of the blood of Lucifer. Marian also as her ancestor Eve, enticed her husband swallowed sinking attractive fruit. The temptation is everywhere. Free will still trapped in the maze. The night of the world is still long. The dawn of being buried. "Alas, Babylon the great! Moment between your judgment come ... never again shining light in the midst of thee ..."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Devil's Avocate, an interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waltyeresdesousa (waltyeresdesousa@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate A movie of mystery and suspense, where people left their normal lives to live a story that since its beginning is surreal. That is how rolls The Devil's Advocate. Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reevens) is a lawyer that began his carrier at Florida and his principal characteristics are: He's never lost a court case before; He wins cases whether the accused is innocent or not; He is an excellent professional and it calls much attention of a millionaire - John Milton (Al Pacino), an owner of largest law firm in New York. John makes a proposal that cannot be refused by Kevin: if he wins the cases, he would work with him and have a good job and house. So he passed to live better in New York- the city that already wished for many peoples- with his wife Mary Ann Lomax (Charlize Theron), who had worked a lot before, since she was 13. Kevin unfortunately accepts this proposal even being advised by his mother Alice Lomax (Judith Ivev) that New York was the big Babylon, as descriptive on Apocalypse. He was a religious man when he was a child, Kevin knew this prophecy but he thought would only practice his religiosity again in his old age. By not listening to the prophecy, his life changes radically from that. He starts to work in this new company and his wife stays at home because she doesn't work anymore. Her function was only to take care of the house. But strange things start to happen in her life, she begins to see strange shapes in the people and they pass to have some aspects of demons and they are trying to scare her. The most interesting fact is that the boss of Kevin, Mr. John, always knows everything that happens in his married life. After many events, the movie ends with secrets revealed; Kevin finds out that his boss and his own mother are the center of the secret that could transform his life totally. When the movie ends, it scions about vanity and reinterpret the habitual concept about it and take this concept to Spiritual life. The movie sin in last scenes because it ends in a messy and the movie didn't make clear the real surreal. Can call your attention in a way that you forget the world, it try to exit you of the simple world where your mind can open to others' understanding. This movie is directed by Taylor Hackford, lasts 2:23:34. It was produced in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For watching, it is a good film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damn-eth
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate is one of the best films in the history of cinema. Both players and cues make the film charming. When you watch the film, you can't understand how it finishes since it progresses fluently. When people decide wrong decisions and choices, it is too late for turning back. This film dealt with them very well. Also, actors and actress have a impact on watching the film with integrating the roles of their.Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are leading roles. The film explains life of a successful lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves ) that his life changes after he meets rich businessman John Milton (Al Pacino). Kevin is an ambitious lawyer, his only aim is to succeed in his career and he saves them from even they are guilty. Kevin meets John and moves to New York. He affects from him but essentially, he makes an agreement with devil. In the beginning, everything is better. But after that, his wife faces to psychological problems. So, lawyer notices some realities and he tries to change something. I like cues of film so much. Especially, "Vanity is definitely my favorite sin." I think, the film doesn't lose ıt's beauty even the years passes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The devil has a son...called Kevin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is truly an oddity. There's the usual series of gruesome deaths lifted from The Omen and many another supernatural yarn accompanied by the now standard choral music. There's nothing much in the way of originality about any of this, but it does at least hold the attention. The most interesting thing are the bravura speeches from the villain John Milton (AKA The Devil) delivered with great gusto by Al Pacino, but some of the gravitas is undermined by his son's rather bathetic name 'Kevin'. 'Beelzebub and Kevin' does not quite have a demonic ring to it. The formulaic script is written more for melodramatic impact than sense, with people wandering onto busy roads for no apparent reason only to be mowed down by cars and such like. One strange and inexplicable scene has a blood drenched Kevin after just seeing his wife die by slitting her own throat meet his mother. Rather than her saying "why are you covered in blood, Kevin?" or "My God! what happened to my daughter-in-law?" instead she launches into a longwinded exposition (but one telegraphed at least an hour earlier in the film) that Milton is his father. All this is gory and faintly ludicrous but is carried out with Hollywood slickness and would perhaps deserve a better score were it not for the unforgivable finale where this house of cards collapses. Kevin is tempted to join his satanic father by having sex with his own sister. Instead of this Kevin chooses to shoot himself at which point any sense the script had disappears. Kevin's sister for some unexplained reason dies. The devil's (and the emperor's new) clothes fall off, he starts to burn while shouting "No! No!" The only way this comically bad scene could have been improved would have been to have Pacino say, "HE'S NOT THE ANTICHRIST! HE'S A VERY NAUGHTY BOY!" All this makes little sense dramatically or theologically. How can you defeat the devil by committing suicide? Isn't that expressly forbidden in the scriptures? Still you could argue that the point is that Kevin makes an act of self-sacrifice and had it ended there it perhaps would not have been so bad. BUT THEN HE WAKES UP! Seriously, he is then back at the very start of the film before any of the bad stuff happened. In other words the whole thing was an extended dream sequence. This is the sort of thing that first year English students are told to avoid. To cap it all Kevin then refuses to defend his client, something than is strangely presented as a moral stance when it is actually morally and legally dubious. Isn't it a lawyer's duty to defend his client even if he knows his client is guilty? A pointless re-appearance of Al Pacino right at the end just adds to the incoherence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary, Thought Provoking, Just Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mediapeertime
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films about Satan. Great at deceiving, full of power, loses in the end - as the devil should! This was altogether a great lawyer film. In this film, we get to see one of Pacino's best performances. He wasn't that usual character that we'r5e so used to seeing. Also tremendous performances by Charlize Theron, Connie Nielson, Jeffrey Jones, Tamara Tunie, and Craig T. Nelson. Couldn't buy Keaneau Reeves in the best lawyer role. he was adequate at best. Watch the train scene with Al Pacino - just tremendous! Taylor Hackford, great work (except casting of Reeves, but that mau not have been his choice????)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Brilliant!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elif490
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exceptional. Simply perfect. I watched without blinking my eye for a moment until the end of the film, and the final literally shocked me. As it tells us the relationship between us and satisfaction & sins, it shows us our biggest weaknesses as people. This film makes you terrify and at the same time it makes you learn a lot. Acting is even better than 'magnificent'. Legendary is a way less description for Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are fantastic!! Excellent and unique. Anyone who doesn't watch this movie loses a lot. It just blows your mind! Seriously. It's one of the bests. Once you watch it, you will never forget about this movie. Ten out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keanu Reeves as a bad-ass lawyer from hell.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tess van Brummelen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting (Keanu Reeves, Al Pacino and Charlize Theron) was brilliant. This film is scary as hell. Favorite quotes: "It's not a dream if it's true." "Your belly's too full, your dick is sore, your eyes are bloodshot, and you're screaming for someone to help!" "It's the goof of all time. Look but don't touch. Touch, but don't taste. Taste, don't swallow. Ahaha." "Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. The virtue of the devil is in his loins." "Vanity, definitely my favorite sin."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a stylish supernatural thriller about the temptation of evil for a young lawyer from the South. When he is offered a big time job in New York by big time lawyer played by Al Pacino, he finds there is a price to pay. The cast is good. Al Pacino before he got really devilish looking is good except for the silly dance at the end. Connie Nielsen is sophisticated and elegant. Charlize Theron is moving and convincing as the young wife sacrificing her looks for a standout performance. Even Keanu acts quite well as the young lawyer and you can't say that about too many of his movies. They didn't make it over the top horror - it's clever and frightening without much gore or in your face violence. Along with Rosemary's Baby this is the best NYC supernatural horror movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demonic thriller full of tension and pain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    4rch 4ng3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The figure of the devil posted in a contemporaney time, with a great Keanu Reeves and a really appreciable Al Pacino as the mysterious figure of the hided evil. Charlize Theron is absorbed by the pain and the sufference caused, a trap filled with an articoulate labyrinth of lies and bad actions. The screenplay, not even need to talk, is fantastic and avvolving at all, withal an adrenalinic envelopment an a huge tale of twists and questions. The way out is difficoult to find and the easy decisions are not part of the dialogues or the plot. The evil is so high and so showed, without fear, is unstoppable and known at the same time. The conseguences are so many and impossible to predict.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't really live up to its hype
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one film I had been wanting to watch for quite some time now, and I got around to it just a while back. I had some really good expectations from this movie, as I had read about it on IMDb and other movie sites, and I had thought it would be a courtroom thriller filled with suspense. But I have to say I was a bit disappointed with what I saw. The film is about a hotshot Florida lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves) who has never lost a case in his entire career. A New York law firm enlists his help to select a jury for a case and recognizing his talent, offers him a job. Lomax accepts and becomes quite close to his boss, John Milton (Al Pacino) during the course of his work. But he gradually begins to uncover some strange facets of Milton's personality and finally realizes that he is none other than Satan himself. Now, such a premise should surely set the stage for a riveting thriller filled with suspense and mystery. But sadly, it doesn't. I think the main reason is Keanu Reeves' performance. I couldn't really buy the idea of him being an argumentative lawyer who could acquit a rapist in spite of the pile of evidence staring him in the face, especially as this is what is shown in the first scene of the film. If the scene is supposed to convince the viewer of the talent of this young lawyer, it doesn't really pass the test. The only thing it does is invariably draw comparisons to the courtroom scenes in "A Few good Men", which had fabulous dialogues, coupled with one of Tom Cruise's finest performances ever. So it is asking a lot to make the audience believe that Lomax hasn't yet lost a case. Apart from this, the film does have a few things going for it. The pace is fast and well set, and for a first time viewing, there is no scene which makes you feel bored, irksome or irritable. And, of course, there's Al Pacino. His thunderous voice and arrogant demeanour are enough to make the viewer feel uncomfortable about him, and it isn't really hard to associate his character with that of the Devil. The other characters merely serve as pretexts for Lomax's wife to lose control over herself and imagine things related to hell, Satan and all that stuff. All in all, I wouldn't recommend this as a must-see, but probably something you might just rent at a DVD store when your other choices aren't that appealing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Night of the world"- uncreated by fable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yughred
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt that Kevin is familiar with the Bible, this is the weapon of the debate in his court in "Mo Yizi case, he resorted to the freedom of religious belief of the party days India with eloquence eloquent Mo Yizi acquitted on the charges, plus Mo Yizi assistant prosecutor Arnold Modu facilities witchcraft, it coughing, unable to speak, and Kevin got his wish to obtain another victory. Famous football coach Vince Lombardi once behalf of Kevin shouted his voice: "Winning is not everything, but only! Bible or religion or in the creation of four 60-game winning streak myth The young lawyer Kevin's eyes, but the tools to win the victory. The United States is a respect for the success of the nation, "the exclusive worship of successfully goddess bitch" overwhelm everything, including God. Xu Kaiwen court numerous times to praise the name of the Lord, in his heart, God is but a trite illusory value symbol. This era is the era of man and the world is completely lost. The maze of free will Make free will answer the philosophers who believe that God create people are born with free will - are born with the ability to act in accordance with their own wishes. The face of the world, people can be free to make a choice. Therefore, evil and suffering in the world, is the result of the abuse of free will, this responsibility should be by the people themselves to provide us with. God is not interfered. From the words of the Bible, we can infer that: God created Adam and Eve when, inevitably given their free will - the event that obey the spell of the snake Tousijinguo this crime, is not based on the free will to make autonomous decision, while is responsible for the crimes they have committed a pre-determined by God no choice behavior, then, God, what is the reason to make Adam and Eve it? The philosophical insights is the one held by the "devil's advocate". Summit in New York, in the face of the nations bustling, Kevin chose an opposite road with Jesus Christ, step-by-step into the trap of the devil - based on the free will. Yes, free will! Kevin's mother and wife successively abduction by Satan, the same is based on the free will of independent decision. Satan never force others to comply with his will. God, he respects the free will of the people. "I don't make things happen", he was just with a charming smile, charm by saying, to induce the people inside the original sin. He does not directly make any demands. He even twice put the persuasion attitude demagogue mending their ways. Free will, this is a wonderful word! In the eyes of the people, it embodied the pride and glory of the man. And Satan said: "Free will, it is a bitch." Bitch Italian English word "bitch, slut, nasty stuff", full of humble and despicable mean. Sadly, if Satan is not wrong. Bear the original sin of the people, given human nature and the dark background. Night of the world ", dumping large town of Babylon, God-given free will of light in this dark human nature, it has been alienated to slut who gaudy jeweled. "I'm a fan of man. I'm a humanist, maybe the last humanist." Satan wanton interpretation of the words of Montaigne: "anything that can occur in the human body and it was not inhuman." His "humanitarian doctrine "is to distort the true meaning of free will along the dark humanity, his definition of" freedom "is an absolute and unfettered freedom, one to do whatever they want to meet the desire of freedom. The paradox is that the absolute freedom, being mean absolute enslavement. "Man is born free, but no go without chains. Precisely the desire, only the desire of the human heart, is the real shackles, people become prisoners under the order shall not be free. Conspiracy of Satan took advantage of the free will of the people of the world - which lost in the sea of ​​desire free will, step by step, to lure the world turned away from God and become degenerate. "The 20th century was entirely mine", at the moment, Satan winner complacent. So, what is truly "free"? Jesus as early as "John." Provides us with the answer: "You shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free." Face of the unexpected defeat of Satan desperately shouting: "No! Damn you! Enough! Have not I given enough?" Ezekiel book describes the scene in an instant staged: "Are you proud because of the beautiful hearts corrupted your wisdom because of glory, I have sent thee to the ground you down before kings, good that they may behold thee. sins of many, unfair trade defiled thy sanctuary. therefore will I bring fire from you issue the middle, devour thee, and upon the earth in the sight of all people watch ashes "in a raging fire, Satan revealed a proud Blazing Angels Lucifer Mami. Satan carefully constructed dream collapsed in an instant. Out from the sea of ​​desire meditation from Kevin, the court did not hesitate to refuse to act as the spokesperson of the devil, the hearts of the people think: a hero was born, God, after all, to get the victory. However, Satan is everywhere. He was the embodiment of the snake, and also the embodiment of the law firm boss, he can transform himself into a tabloid reporter. Kevin's body, after all, keep the pride and vanity of the blood of Lucifer. Marian also as her ancestor Eve, enticed her husband swallowed sinking attractive fruit. The temptation is everywhere. Free will still trapped in the maze. The night of the world is still long. The dawn of being buried. "Alas, Babylon the great! Moment between your judgment come ... never again shining light in the midst of thee ..."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Devil's Avocate, an interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waltyeresdesousa (waltyeresdesousa@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate A movie of mystery and suspense, where people left their normal lives to live a story that since its beginning is surreal. That is how rolls The Devil's Advocate. Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reevens) is a lawyer that began his carrier at Florida and his principal characteristics are: He's never lost a court case before; He wins cases whether the accused is innocent or not; He is an excellent professional and it calls much attention of a millionaire - John Milton (Al Pacino), an owner of largest law firm in New York. John makes a proposal that cannot be refused by Kevin: if he wins the cases, he would work with him and have a good job and house. So he passed to live better in New York- the city that already wished for many peoples- with his wife Mary Ann Lomax (Charlize Theron), who had worked a lot before, since she was 13. Kevin unfortunately accepts this proposal even being advised by his mother Alice Lomax (Judith Ivev) that New York was the big Babylon, as descriptive on Apocalypse. He was a religious man when he was a child, Kevin knew this prophecy but he thought would only practice his religiosity again in his old age. By not listening to the prophecy, his life changes radically from that. He starts to work in this new company and his wife stays at home because she doesn't work anymore. Her function was only to take care of the house. But strange things start to happen in her life, she begins to see strange shapes in the people and they pass to have some aspects of demons and they are trying to scare her. The most interesting fact is that the boss of Kevin, Mr. John, always knows everything that happens in his married life. After many events, the movie ends with secrets revealed; Kevin finds out that his boss and his own mother are the center of the secret that could transform his life totally. When the movie ends, it scions about vanity and reinterpret the habitual concept about it and take this concept to Spiritual life. The movie sin in last scenes because it ends in a messy and the movie didn't make clear the real surreal. Can call your attention in a way that you forget the world, it try to exit you of the simple world where your mind can open to others' understanding. This movie is directed by Taylor Hackford, lasts 2:23:34. It was produced in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For watching, it is a good film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damn-eth
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate is one of the best films in the history of cinema. Both players and cues make the film charming. When you watch the film, you can't understand how it finishes since it progresses fluently. When people decide wrong decisions and choices, it is too late for turning back. This film dealt with them very well. Also, actors and actress have a impact on watching the film with integrating the roles of their.Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are leading roles. The film explains life of a successful lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves ) that his life changes after he meets rich businessman John Milton (Al Pacino). Kevin is an ambitious lawyer, his only aim is to succeed in his career and he saves them from even they are guilty. Kevin meets John and moves to New York. He affects from him but essentially, he makes an agreement with devil. In the beginning, everything is better. But after that, his wife faces to psychological problems. So, lawyer notices some realities and he tries to change something. I like cues of film so much. Especially, "Vanity is definitely my favorite sin." I think, the film doesn't lose ıt's beauty even the years passes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The devil has a son...called Kevin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is truly an oddity. There's the usual series of gruesome deaths lifted from The Omen and many another supernatural yarn accompanied by the now standard choral music. There's nothing much in the way of originality about any of this, but it does at least hold the attention. The most interesting thing are the bravura speeches from the villain John Milton (AKA The Devil) delivered with great gusto by Al Pacino, but some of the gravitas is undermined by his son's rather bathetic name 'Kevin'. 'Beelzebub and Kevin' does not quite have a demonic ring to it. The formulaic script is written more for melodramatic impact than sense, with people wandering onto busy roads for no apparent reason only to be mowed down by cars and such like. One strange and inexplicable scene has a blood drenched Kevin after just seeing his wife die by slitting her own throat meet his mother. Rather than her saying "why are you covered in blood, Kevin?" or "My God! what happened to my daughter-in-law?" instead she launches into a longwinded exposition (but one telegraphed at least an hour earlier in the film) that Milton is his father. All this is gory and faintly ludicrous but is carried out with Hollywood slickness and would perhaps deserve a better score were it not for the unforgivable finale where this house of cards collapses. Kevin is tempted to join his satanic father by having sex with his own sister. Instead of this Kevin chooses to shoot himself at which point any sense the script had disappears. Kevin's sister for some unexplained reason dies. The devil's (and the emperor's new) clothes fall off, he starts to burn while shouting "No! No!" The only way this comically bad scene could have been improved would have been to have Pacino say, "HE'S NOT THE ANTICHRIST! HE'S A VERY NAUGHTY BOY!" All this makes little sense dramatically or theologically. How can you defeat the devil by committing suicide? Isn't that expressly forbidden in the scriptures? Still you could argue that the point is that Kevin makes an act of self-sacrifice and had it ended there it perhaps would not have been so bad. BUT THEN HE WAKES UP! Seriously, he is then back at the very start of the film before any of the bad stuff happened. In other words the whole thing was an extended dream sequence. This is the sort of thing that first year English students are told to avoid. To cap it all Kevin then refuses to defend his client, something than is strangely presented as a moral stance when it is actually morally and legally dubious. Isn't it a lawyer's duty to defend his client even if he knows his client is guilty? A pointless re-appearance of Al Pacino right at the end just adds to the incoherence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary, Thought Provoking, Just Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mediapeertime
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films about Satan. Great at deceiving, full of power, loses in the end - as the devil should! This was altogether a great lawyer film. In this film, we get to see one of Pacino's best performances. He wasn't that usual character that we'r5e so used to seeing. Also tremendous performances by Charlize Theron, Connie Nielson, Jeffrey Jones, Tamara Tunie, and Craig T. Nelson. Couldn't buy Keaneau Reeves in the best lawyer role. he was adequate at best. Watch the train scene with Al Pacino - just tremendous! Taylor Hackford, great work (except casting of Reeves, but that mau not have been his choice????)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Brilliant!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elif490
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exceptional. Simply perfect. I watched without blinking my eye for a moment until the end of the film, and the final literally shocked me. As it tells us the relationship between us and satisfaction & sins, it shows us our biggest weaknesses as people. This film makes you terrify and at the same time it makes you learn a lot. Acting is even better than 'magnificent'. Legendary is a way less description for Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are fantastic!! Excellent and unique. Anyone who doesn't watch this movie loses a lot. It just blows your mind! Seriously. It's one of the bests. Once you watch it, you will never forget about this movie. Ten out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keanu Reeves as a bad-ass lawyer from hell.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tess van Brummelen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting (Keanu Reeves, Al Pacino and Charlize Theron) was brilliant. This film is scary as hell. Favorite quotes: "It's not a dream if it's true." "Your belly's too full, your dick is sore, your eyes are bloodshot, and you're screaming for someone to help!" "It's the goof of all time. Look but don't touch. Touch, but don't taste. Taste, don't swallow. Ahaha." "Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. The virtue of the devil is in his loins." "Vanity, definitely my favorite sin."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a stylish supernatural thriller about the temptation of evil for a young lawyer from the South. When he is offered a big time job in New York by big time lawyer played by Al Pacino, he finds there is a price to pay. The cast is good. Al Pacino before he got really devilish looking is good except for the silly dance at the end. Connie Nielsen is sophisticated and elegant. Charlize Theron is moving and convincing as the young wife sacrificing her looks for a standout performance. Even Keanu acts quite well as the young lawyer and you can't say that about too many of his movies. They didn't make it over the top horror - it's clever and frightening without much gore or in your face violence. Along with Rosemary's Baby this is the best NYC supernatural horror movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demonic thriller full of tension and pain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    4rch 4ng3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The figure of the devil posted in a contemporaney time, with a great Keanu Reeves and a really appreciable Al Pacino as the mysterious figure of the hided evil. Charlize Theron is absorbed by the pain and the sufference caused, a trap filled with an articoulate labyrinth of lies and bad actions. The screenplay, not even need to talk, is fantastic and avvolving at all, withal an adrenalinic envelopment an a huge tale of twists and questions. The way out is difficoult to find and the easy decisions are not part of the dialogues or the plot. The evil is so high and so showed, without fear, is unstoppable and known at the same time. The conseguences are so many and impossible to predict.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't really live up to its hype
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one film I had been wanting to watch for quite some time now, and I got around to it just a while back. I had some really good expectations from this movie, as I had read about it on IMDb and other movie sites, and I had thought it would be a courtroom thriller filled with suspense. But I have to say I was a bit disappointed with what I saw. The film is about a hotshot Florida lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves) who has never lost a case in his entire career. A New York law firm enlists his help to select a jury for a case and recognizing his talent, offers him a job. Lomax accepts and becomes quite close to his boss, John Milton (Al Pacino) during the course of his work. But he gradually begins to uncover some strange facets of Milton's personality and finally realizes that he is none other than Satan himself. Now, such a premise should surely set the stage for a riveting thriller filled with suspense and mystery. But sadly, it doesn't. I think the main reason is Keanu Reeves' performance. I couldn't really buy the idea of him being an argumentative lawyer who could acquit a rapist in spite of the pile of evidence staring him in the face, especially as this is what is shown in the first scene of the film. If the scene is supposed to convince the viewer of the talent of this young lawyer, it doesn't really pass the test. The only thing it does is invariably draw comparisons to the courtroom scenes in "A Few good Men", which had fabulous dialogues, coupled with one of Tom Cruise's finest performances ever. So it is asking a lot to make the audience believe that Lomax hasn't yet lost a case. Apart from this, the film does have a few things going for it. The pace is fast and well set, and for a first time viewing, there is no scene which makes you feel bored, irksome or irritable. And, of course, there's Al Pacino. His thunderous voice and arrogant demeanour are enough to make the viewer feel uncomfortable about him, and it isn't really hard to associate his character with that of the Devil. The other characters merely serve as pretexts for Lomax's wife to lose control over herself and imagine things related to hell, Satan and all that stuff. All in all, I wouldn't recommend this as a must-see, but probably something you might just rent at a DVD store when your other choices aren't that appealing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Night of the world"- uncreated by fable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yughred
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt that Kevin is familiar with the Bible, this is the weapon of the debate in his court in "Mo Yizi case, he resorted to the freedom of religious belief of the party days India with eloquence eloquent Mo Yizi acquitted on the charges, plus Mo Yizi assistant prosecutor Arnold Modu facilities witchcraft, it coughing, unable to speak, and Kevin got his wish to obtain another victory. Famous football coach Vince Lombardi once behalf of Kevin shouted his voice: "Winning is not everything, but only! Bible or religion or in the creation of four 60-game winning streak myth The young lawyer Kevin's eyes, but the tools to win the victory. The United States is a respect for the success of the nation, "the exclusive worship of successfully goddess bitch" overwhelm everything, including God. Xu Kaiwen court numerous times to praise the name of the Lord, in his heart, God is but a trite illusory value symbol. This era is the era of man and the world is completely lost. The maze of free will Make free will answer the philosophers who believe that God create people are born with free will - are born with the ability to act in accordance with their own wishes. The face of the world, people can be free to make a choice. Therefore, evil and suffering in the world, is the result of the abuse of free will, this responsibility should be by the people themselves to provide us with. God is not interfered. From the words of the Bible, we can infer that: God created Adam and Eve when, inevitably given their free will - the event that obey the spell of the snake Tousijinguo this crime, is not based on the free will to make autonomous decision, while is responsible for the crimes they have committed a pre-determined by God no choice behavior, then, God, what is the reason to make Adam and Eve it? The philosophical insights is the one held by the "devil's advocate". Summit in New York, in the face of the nations bustling, Kevin chose an opposite road with Jesus Christ, step-by-step into the trap of the devil - based on the free will. Yes, free will! Kevin's mother and wife successively abduction by Satan, the same is based on the free will of independent decision. Satan never force others to comply with his will. God, he respects the free will of the people. "I don't make things happen", he was just with a charming smile, charm by saying, to induce the people inside the original sin. He does not directly make any demands. He even twice put the persuasion attitude demagogue mending their ways. Free will, this is a wonderful word! In the eyes of the people, it embodied the pride and glory of the man. And Satan said: "Free will, it is a bitch." Bitch Italian English word "bitch, slut, nasty stuff", full of humble and despicable mean. Sadly, if Satan is not wrong. Bear the original sin of the people, given human nature and the dark background. Night of the world ", dumping large town of Babylon, God-given free will of light in this dark human nature, it has been alienated to slut who gaudy jeweled. "I'm a fan of man. I'm a humanist, maybe the last humanist." Satan wanton interpretation of the words of Montaigne: "anything that can occur in the human body and it was not inhuman." His "humanitarian doctrine "is to distort the true meaning of free will along the dark humanity, his definition of" freedom "is an absolute and unfettered freedom, one to do whatever they want to meet the desire of freedom. The paradox is that the absolute freedom, being mean absolute enslavement. "Man is born free, but no go without chains. Precisely the desire, only the desire of the human heart, is the real shackles, people become prisoners under the order shall not be free. Conspiracy of Satan took advantage of the free will of the people of the world - which lost in the sea of ​​desire free will, step by step, to lure the world turned away from God and become degenerate. "The 20th century was entirely mine", at the moment, Satan winner complacent. So, what is truly "free"? Jesus as early as "John." Provides us with the answer: "You shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free." Face of the unexpected defeat of Satan desperately shouting: "No! Damn you! Enough! Have not I given enough?" Ezekiel book describes the scene in an instant staged: "Are you proud because of the beautiful hearts corrupted your wisdom because of glory, I have sent thee to the ground you down before kings, good that they may behold thee. sins of many, unfair trade defiled thy sanctuary. therefore will I bring fire from you issue the middle, devour thee, and upon the earth in the sight of all people watch ashes "in a raging fire, Satan revealed a proud Blazing Angels Lucifer Mami. Satan carefully constructed dream collapsed in an instant. Out from the sea of ​​desire meditation from Kevin, the court did not hesitate to refuse to act as the spokesperson of the devil, the hearts of the people think: a hero was born, God, after all, to get the victory. However, Satan is everywhere. He was the embodiment of the snake, and also the embodiment of the law firm boss, he can transform himself into a tabloid reporter. Kevin's body, after all, keep the pride and vanity of the blood of Lucifer. Marian also as her ancestor Eve, enticed her husband swallowed sinking attractive fruit. The temptation is everywhere. Free will still trapped in the maze. The night of the world is still long. The dawn of being buried. "Alas, Babylon the great! Moment between your judgment come ... never again shining light in the midst of thee ..."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Devil's Avocate, an interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waltyeresdesousa (waltyeresdesousa@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate A movie of mystery and suspense, where people left their normal lives to live a story that since its beginning is surreal. That is how rolls The Devil's Advocate. Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reevens) is a lawyer that began his carrier at Florida and his principal characteristics are: He's never lost a court case before; He wins cases whether the accused is innocent or not; He is an excellent professional and it calls much attention of a millionaire - John Milton (Al Pacino), an owner of largest law firm in New York. John makes a proposal that cannot be refused by Kevin: if he wins the cases, he would work with him and have a good job and house. So he passed to live better in New York- the city that already wished for many peoples- with his wife Mary Ann Lomax (Charlize Theron), who had worked a lot before, since she was 13. Kevin unfortunately accepts this proposal even being advised by his mother Alice Lomax (Judith Ivev) that New York was the big Babylon, as descriptive on Apocalypse. He was a religious man when he was a child, Kevin knew this prophecy but he thought would only practice his religiosity again in his old age. By not listening to the prophecy, his life changes radically from that. He starts to work in this new company and his wife stays at home because she doesn't work anymore. Her function was only to take care of the house. But strange things start to happen in her life, she begins to see strange shapes in the people and they pass to have some aspects of demons and they are trying to scare her. The most interesting fact is that the boss of Kevin, Mr. John, always knows everything that happens in his married life. After many events, the movie ends with secrets revealed; Kevin finds out that his boss and his own mother are the center of the secret that could transform his life totally. When the movie ends, it scions about vanity and reinterpret the habitual concept about it and take this concept to Spiritual life. The movie sin in last scenes because it ends in a messy and the movie didn't make clear the real surreal. Can call your attention in a way that you forget the world, it try to exit you of the simple world where your mind can open to others' understanding. This movie is directed by Taylor Hackford, lasts 2:23:34. It was produced in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For watching, it is a good film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damn-eth
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate is one of the best films in the history of cinema. Both players and cues make the film charming. When you watch the film, you can't understand how it finishes since it progresses fluently. When people decide wrong decisions and choices, it is too late for turning back. This film dealt with them very well. Also, actors and actress have a impact on watching the film with integrating the roles of their.Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are leading roles. The film explains life of a successful lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves ) that his life changes after he meets rich businessman John Milton (Al Pacino). Kevin is an ambitious lawyer, his only aim is to succeed in his career and he saves them from even they are guilty. Kevin meets John and moves to New York. He affects from him but essentially, he makes an agreement with devil. In the beginning, everything is better. But after that, his wife faces to psychological problems. So, lawyer notices some realities and he tries to change something. I like cues of film so much. Especially, "Vanity is definitely my favorite sin." I think, the film doesn't lose ıt's beauty even the years passes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The devil has a son...called Kevin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is truly an oddity. There's the usual series of gruesome deaths lifted from The Omen and many another supernatural yarn accompanied by the now standard choral music. There's nothing much in the way of originality about any of this, but it does at least hold the attention. The most interesting thing are the bravura speeches from the villain John Milton (AKA The Devil) delivered with great gusto by Al Pacino, but some of the gravitas is undermined by his son's rather bathetic name 'Kevin'. 'Beelzebub and Kevin' does not quite have a demonic ring to it. The formulaic script is written more for melodramatic impact than sense, with people wandering onto busy roads for no apparent reason only to be mowed down by cars and such like. One strange and inexplicable scene has a blood drenched Kevin after just seeing his wife die by slitting her own throat meet his mother. Rather than her saying "why are you covered in blood, Kevin?" or "My God! what happened to my daughter-in-law?" instead she launches into a longwinded exposition (but one telegraphed at least an hour earlier in the film) that Milton is his father. All this is gory and faintly ludicrous but is carried out with Hollywood slickness and would perhaps deserve a better score were it not for the unforgivable finale where this house of cards collapses. Kevin is tempted to join his satanic father by having sex with his own sister. Instead of this Kevin chooses to shoot himself at which point any sense the script had disappears. Kevin's sister for some unexplained reason dies. The devil's (and the emperor's new) clothes fall off, he starts to burn while shouting "No! No!" The only way this comically bad scene could have been improved would have been to have Pacino say, "HE'S NOT THE ANTICHRIST! HE'S A VERY NAUGHTY BOY!" All this makes little sense dramatically or theologically. How can you defeat the devil by committing suicide? Isn't that expressly forbidden in the scriptures? Still you could argue that the point is that Kevin makes an act of self-sacrifice and had it ended there it perhaps would not have been so bad. BUT THEN HE WAKES UP! Seriously, he is then back at the very start of the film before any of the bad stuff happened. In other words the whole thing was an extended dream sequence. This is the sort of thing that first year English students are told to avoid. To cap it all Kevin then refuses to defend his client, something than is strangely presented as a moral stance when it is actually morally and legally dubious. Isn't it a lawyer's duty to defend his client even if he knows his client is guilty? A pointless re-appearance of Al Pacino right at the end just adds to the incoherence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary, Thought Provoking, Just Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mediapeertime
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films about Satan. Great at deceiving, full of power, loses in the end - as the devil should! This was altogether a great lawyer film. In this film, we get to see one of Pacino's best performances. He wasn't that usual character that we'r5e so used to seeing. Also tremendous performances by Charlize Theron, Connie Nielson, Jeffrey Jones, Tamara Tunie, and Craig T. Nelson. Couldn't buy Keaneau Reeves in the best lawyer role. he was adequate at best. Watch the train scene with Al Pacino - just tremendous! Taylor Hackford, great work (except casting of Reeves, but that mau not have been his choice????)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Brilliant!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elif490
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exceptional. Simply perfect. I watched without blinking my eye for a moment until the end of the film, and the final literally shocked me. As it tells us the relationship between us and satisfaction & sins, it shows us our biggest weaknesses as people. This film makes you terrify and at the same time it makes you learn a lot. Acting is even better than 'magnificent'. Legendary is a way less description for Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are fantastic!! Excellent and unique. Anyone who doesn't watch this movie loses a lot. It just blows your mind! Seriously. It's one of the bests. Once you watch it, you will never forget about this movie. Ten out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keanu Reeves as a bad-ass lawyer from hell.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tess van Brummelen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting (Keanu Reeves, Al Pacino and Charlize Theron) was brilliant. This film is scary as hell. Favorite quotes: "It's not a dream if it's true." "Your belly's too full, your dick is sore, your eyes are bloodshot, and you're screaming for someone to help!" "It's the goof of all time. Look but don't touch. Touch, but don't taste. Taste, don't swallow. Ahaha." "Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. The virtue of the devil is in his loins." "Vanity, definitely my favorite sin."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a stylish supernatural thriller about the temptation of evil for a young lawyer from the South. When he is offered a big time job in New York by big time lawyer played by Al Pacino, he finds there is a price to pay. The cast is good. Al Pacino before he got really devilish looking is good except for the silly dance at the end. Connie Nielsen is sophisticated and elegant. Charlize Theron is moving and convincing as the young wife sacrificing her looks for a standout performance. Even Keanu acts quite well as the young lawyer and you can't say that about too many of his movies. They didn't make it over the top horror - it's clever and frightening without much gore or in your face violence. Along with Rosemary's Baby this is the best NYC supernatural horror movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demonic thriller full of tension and pain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    4rch 4ng3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The figure of the devil posted in a contemporaney time, with a great Keanu Reeves and a really appreciable Al Pacino as the mysterious figure of the hided evil. Charlize Theron is absorbed by the pain and the sufference caused, a trap filled with an articoulate labyrinth of lies and bad actions. The screenplay, not even need to talk, is fantastic and avvolving at all, withal an adrenalinic envelopment an a huge tale of twists and questions. The way out is difficoult to find and the easy decisions are not part of the dialogues or the plot. The evil is so high and so showed, without fear, is unstoppable and known at the same time. The conseguences are so many and impossible to predict.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't really live up to its hype
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one film I had been wanting to watch for quite some time now, and I got around to it just a while back. I had some really good expectations from this movie, as I had read about it on IMDb and other movie sites, and I had thought it would be a courtroom thriller filled with suspense. But I have to say I was a bit disappointed with what I saw. The film is about a hotshot Florida lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves) who has never lost a case in his entire career. A New York law firm enlists his help to select a jury for a case and recognizing his talent, offers him a job. Lomax accepts and becomes quite close to his boss, John Milton (Al Pacino) during the course of his work. But he gradually begins to uncover some strange facets of Milton's personality and finally realizes that he is none other than Satan himself. Now, such a premise should surely set the stage for a riveting thriller filled with suspense and mystery. But sadly, it doesn't. I think the main reason is Keanu Reeves' performance. I couldn't really buy the idea of him being an argumentative lawyer who could acquit a rapist in spite of the pile of evidence staring him in the face, especially as this is what is shown in the first scene of the film. If the scene is supposed to convince the viewer of the talent of this young lawyer, it doesn't really pass the test. The only thing it does is invariably draw comparisons to the courtroom scenes in "A Few good Men", which had fabulous dialogues, coupled with one of Tom Cruise's finest performances ever. So it is asking a lot to make the audience believe that Lomax hasn't yet lost a case. Apart from this, the film does have a few things going for it. The pace is fast and well set, and for a first time viewing, there is no scene which makes you feel bored, irksome or irritable. And, of course, there's Al Pacino. His thunderous voice and arrogant demeanour are enough to make the viewer feel uncomfortable about him, and it isn't really hard to associate his character with that of the Devil. The other characters merely serve as pretexts for Lomax's wife to lose control over herself and imagine things related to hell, Satan and all that stuff. All in all, I wouldn't recommend this as a must-see, but probably something you might just rent at a DVD store when your other choices aren't that appealing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Night of the world"- uncreated by fable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yughred
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt that Kevin is familiar with the Bible, this is the weapon of the debate in his court in "Mo Yizi case, he resorted to the freedom of religious belief of the party days India with eloquence eloquent Mo Yizi acquitted on the charges, plus Mo Yizi assistant prosecutor Arnold Modu facilities witchcraft, it coughing, unable to speak, and Kevin got his wish to obtain another victory. Famous football coach Vince Lombardi once behalf of Kevin shouted his voice: "Winning is not everything, but only! Bible or religion or in the creation of four 60-game winning streak myth The young lawyer Kevin's eyes, but the tools to win the victory. The United States is a respect for the success of the nation, "the exclusive worship of successfully goddess bitch" overwhelm everything, including God. Xu Kaiwen court numerous times to praise the name of the Lord, in his heart, God is but a trite illusory value symbol. This era is the era of man and the world is completely lost. The maze of free will Make free will answer the philosophers who believe that God create people are born with free will - are born with the ability to act in accordance with their own wishes. The face of the world, people can be free to make a choice. Therefore, evil and suffering in the world, is the result of the abuse of free will, this responsibility should be by the people themselves to provide us with. God is not interfered. From the words of the Bible, we can infer that: God created Adam and Eve when, inevitably given their free will - the event that obey the spell of the snake Tousijinguo this crime, is not based on the free will to make autonomous decision, while is responsible for the crimes they have committed a pre-determined by God no choice behavior, then, God, what is the reason to make Adam and Eve it? The philosophical insights is the one held by the "devil's advocate". Summit in New York, in the face of the nations bustling, Kevin chose an opposite road with Jesus Christ, step-by-step into the trap of the devil - based on the free will. Yes, free will! Kevin's mother and wife successively abduction by Satan, the same is based on the free will of independent decision. Satan never force others to comply with his will. God, he respects the free will of the people. "I don't make things happen", he was just with a charming smile, charm by saying, to induce the people inside the original sin. He does not directly make any demands. He even twice put the persuasion attitude demagogue mending their ways. Free will, this is a wonderful word! In the eyes of the people, it embodied the pride and glory of the man. And Satan said: "Free will, it is a bitch." Bitch Italian English word "bitch, slut, nasty stuff", full of humble and despicable mean. Sadly, if Satan is not wrong. Bear the original sin of the people, given human nature and the dark background. Night of the world ", dumping large town of Babylon, God-given free will of light in this dark human nature, it has been alienated to slut who gaudy jeweled. "I'm a fan of man. I'm a humanist, maybe the last humanist." Satan wanton interpretation of the words of Montaigne: "anything that can occur in the human body and it was not inhuman." His "humanitarian doctrine "is to distort the true meaning of free will along the dark humanity, his definition of" freedom "is an absolute and unfettered freedom, one to do whatever they want to meet the desire of freedom. The paradox is that the absolute freedom, being mean absolute enslavement. "Man is born free, but no go without chains. Precisely the desire, only the desire of the human heart, is the real shackles, people become prisoners under the order shall not be free. Conspiracy of Satan took advantage of the free will of the people of the world - which lost in the sea of ​​desire free will, step by step, to lure the world turned away from God and become degenerate. "The 20th century was entirely mine", at the moment, Satan winner complacent. So, what is truly "free"? Jesus as early as "John." Provides us with the answer: "You shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free." Face of the unexpected defeat of Satan desperately shouting: "No! Damn you! Enough! Have not I given enough?" Ezekiel book describes the scene in an instant staged: "Are you proud because of the beautiful hearts corrupted your wisdom because of glory, I have sent thee to the ground you down before kings, good that they may behold thee. sins of many, unfair trade defiled thy sanctuary. therefore will I bring fire from you issue the middle, devour thee, and upon the earth in the sight of all people watch ashes "in a raging fire, Satan revealed a proud Blazing Angels Lucifer Mami. Satan carefully constructed dream collapsed in an instant. Out from the sea of ​​desire meditation from Kevin, the court did not hesitate to refuse to act as the spokesperson of the devil, the hearts of the people think: a hero was born, God, after all, to get the victory. However, Satan is everywhere. He was the embodiment of the snake, and also the embodiment of the law firm boss, he can transform himself into a tabloid reporter. Kevin's body, after all, keep the pride and vanity of the blood of Lucifer. Marian also as her ancestor Eve, enticed her husband swallowed sinking attractive fruit. The temptation is everywhere. Free will still trapped in the maze. The night of the world is still long. The dawn of being buried. "Alas, Babylon the great! Moment between your judgment come ... never again shining light in the midst of thee ..."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Devil's Avocate, an interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waltyeresdesousa (waltyeresdesousa@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate A movie of mystery and suspense, where people left their normal lives to live a story that since its beginning is surreal. That is how rolls The Devil's Advocate. Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reevens) is a lawyer that began his carrier at Florida and his principal characteristics are: He's never lost a court case before; He wins cases whether the accused is innocent or not; He is an excellent professional and it calls much attention of a millionaire - John Milton (Al Pacino), an owner of largest law firm in New York. John makes a proposal that cannot be refused by Kevin: if he wins the cases, he would work with him and have a good job and house. So he passed to live better in New York- the city that already wished for many peoples- with his wife Mary Ann Lomax (Charlize Theron), who had worked a lot before, since she was 13. Kevin unfortunately accepts this proposal even being advised by his mother Alice Lomax (Judith Ivev) that New York was the big Babylon, as descriptive on Apocalypse. He was a religious man when he was a child, Kevin knew this prophecy but he thought would only practice his religiosity again in his old age. By not listening to the prophecy, his life changes radically from that. He starts to work in this new company and his wife stays at home because she doesn't work anymore. Her function was only to take care of the house. But strange things start to happen in her life, she begins to see strange shapes in the people and they pass to have some aspects of demons and they are trying to scare her. The most interesting fact is that the boss of Kevin, Mr. John, always knows everything that happens in his married life. After many events, the movie ends with secrets revealed; Kevin finds out that his boss and his own mother are the center of the secret that could transform his life totally. When the movie ends, it scions about vanity and reinterpret the habitual concept about it and take this concept to Spiritual life. The movie sin in last scenes because it ends in a messy and the movie didn't make clear the real surreal. Can call your attention in a way that you forget the world, it try to exit you of the simple world where your mind can open to others' understanding. This movie is directed by Taylor Hackford, lasts 2:23:34. It was produced in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For watching, it is a good film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damn-eth
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate is one of the best films in the history of cinema. Both players and cues make the film charming. When you watch the film, you can't understand how it finishes since it progresses fluently. When people decide wrong decisions and choices, it is too late for turning back. This film dealt with them very well. Also, actors and actress have a impact on watching the film with integrating the roles of their.Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are leading roles. The film explains life of a successful lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves ) that his life changes after he meets rich businessman John Milton (Al Pacino). Kevin is an ambitious lawyer, his only aim is to succeed in his career and he saves them from even they are guilty. Kevin meets John and moves to New York. He affects from him but essentially, he makes an agreement with devil. In the beginning, everything is better. But after that, his wife faces to psychological problems. So, lawyer notices some realities and he tries to change something. I like cues of film so much. Especially, "Vanity is definitely my favorite sin." I think, the film doesn't lose ıt's beauty even the years passes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The devil has a son...called Kevin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is truly an oddity. There's the usual series of gruesome deaths lifted from The Omen and many another supernatural yarn accompanied by the now standard choral music. There's nothing much in the way of originality about any of this, but it does at least hold the attention. The most interesting thing are the bravura speeches from the villain John Milton (AKA The Devil) delivered with great gusto by Al Pacino, but some of the gravitas is undermined by his son's rather bathetic name 'Kevin'. 'Beelzebub and Kevin' does not quite have a demonic ring to it. The formulaic script is written more for melodramatic impact than sense, with people wandering onto busy roads for no apparent reason only to be mowed down by cars and such like. One strange and inexplicable scene has a blood drenched Kevin after just seeing his wife die by slitting her own throat meet his mother. Rather than her saying "why are you covered in blood, Kevin?" or "My God! what happened to my daughter-in-law?" instead she launches into a longwinded exposition (but one telegraphed at least an hour earlier in the film) that Milton is his father. All this is gory and faintly ludicrous but is carried out with Hollywood slickness and would perhaps deserve a better score were it not for the unforgivable finale where this house of cards collapses. Kevin is tempted to join his satanic father by having sex with his own sister. Instead of this Kevin chooses to shoot himself at which point any sense the script had disappears. Kevin's sister for some unexplained reason dies. The devil's (and the emperor's new) clothes fall off, he starts to burn while shouting "No! No!" The only way this comically bad scene could have been improved would have been to have Pacino say, "HE'S NOT THE ANTICHRIST! HE'S A VERY NAUGHTY BOY!" All this makes little sense dramatically or theologically. How can you defeat the devil by committing suicide? Isn't that expressly forbidden in the scriptures? Still you could argue that the point is that Kevin makes an act of self-sacrifice and had it ended there it perhaps would not have been so bad. BUT THEN HE WAKES UP! Seriously, he is then back at the very start of the film before any of the bad stuff happened. In other words the whole thing was an extended dream sequence. This is the sort of thing that first year English students are told to avoid. To cap it all Kevin then refuses to defend his client, something than is strangely presented as a moral stance when it is actually morally and legally dubious. Isn't it a lawyer's duty to defend his client even if he knows his client is guilty? A pointless re-appearance of Al Pacino right at the end just adds to the incoherence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary, Thought Provoking, Just Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mediapeertime
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films about Satan. Great at deceiving, full of power, loses in the end - as the devil should! This was altogether a great lawyer film. In this film, we get to see one of Pacino's best performances. He wasn't that usual character that we'r5e so used to seeing. Also tremendous performances by Charlize Theron, Connie Nielson, Jeffrey Jones, Tamara Tunie, and Craig T. Nelson. Couldn't buy Keaneau Reeves in the best lawyer role. he was adequate at best. Watch the train scene with Al Pacino - just tremendous! Taylor Hackford, great work (except casting of Reeves, but that mau not have been his choice????)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Brilliant!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elif490
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exceptional. Simply perfect. I watched without blinking my eye for a moment until the end of the film, and the final literally shocked me. As it tells us the relationship between us and satisfaction & sins, it shows us our biggest weaknesses as people. This film makes you terrify and at the same time it makes you learn a lot. Acting is even better than 'magnificent'. Legendary is a way less description for Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are fantastic!! Excellent and unique. Anyone who doesn't watch this movie loses a lot. It just blows your mind! Seriously. It's one of the bests. Once you watch it, you will never forget about this movie. Ten out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keanu Reeves as a bad-ass lawyer from hell.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tess van Brummelen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting (Keanu Reeves, Al Pacino and Charlize Theron) was brilliant. This film is scary as hell. Favorite quotes: "It's not a dream if it's true." "Your belly's too full, your dick is sore, your eyes are bloodshot, and you're screaming for someone to help!" "It's the goof of all time. Look but don't touch. Touch, but don't taste. Taste, don't swallow. Ahaha." "Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. The virtue of the devil is in his loins." "Vanity, definitely my favorite sin."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a stylish supernatural thriller about the temptation of evil for a young lawyer from the South. When he is offered a big time job in New York by big time lawyer played by Al Pacino, he finds there is a price to pay. The cast is good. Al Pacino before he got really devilish looking is good except for the silly dance at the end. Connie Nielsen is sophisticated and elegant. Charlize Theron is moving and convincing as the young wife sacrificing her looks for a standout performance. Even Keanu acts quite well as the young lawyer and you can't say that about too many of his movies. They didn't make it over the top horror - it's clever and frightening without much gore or in your face violence. Along with Rosemary's Baby this is the best NYC supernatural horror movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demonic thriller full of tension and pain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    4rch 4ng3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The figure of the devil posted in a contemporaney time, with a great Keanu Reeves and a really appreciable Al Pacino as the mysterious figure of the hided evil. Charlize Theron is absorbed by the pain and the sufference caused, a trap filled with an articoulate labyrinth of lies and bad actions. The screenplay, not even need to talk, is fantastic and avvolving at all, withal an adrenalinic envelopment an a huge tale of twists and questions. The way out is difficoult to find and the easy decisions are not part of the dialogues or the plot. The evil is so high and so showed, without fear, is unstoppable and known at the same time. The conseguences are so many and impossible to predict.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't really live up to its hype
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one film I had been wanting to watch for quite some time now, and I got around to it just a while back. I had some really good expectations from this movie, as I had read about it on IMDb and other movie sites, and I had thought it would be a courtroom thriller filled with suspense. But I have to say I was a bit disappointed with what I saw. The film is about a hotshot Florida lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves) who has never lost a case in his entire career. A New York law firm enlists his help to select a jury for a case and recognizing his talent, offers him a job. Lomax accepts and becomes quite close to his boss, John Milton (Al Pacino) during the course of his work. But he gradually begins to uncover some strange facets of Milton's personality and finally realizes that he is none other than Satan himself. Now, such a premise should surely set the stage for a riveting thriller filled with suspense and mystery. But sadly, it doesn't. I think the main reason is Keanu Reeves' performance. I couldn't really buy the idea of him being an argumentative lawyer who could acquit a rapist in spite of the pile of evidence staring him in the face, especially as this is what is shown in the first scene of the film. If the scene is supposed to convince the viewer of the talent of this young lawyer, it doesn't really pass the test. The only thing it does is invariably draw comparisons to the courtroom scenes in "A Few good Men", which had fabulous dialogues, coupled with one of Tom Cruise's finest performances ever. So it is asking a lot to make the audience believe that Lomax hasn't yet lost a case. Apart from this, the film does have a few things going for it. The pace is fast and well set, and for a first time viewing, there is no scene which makes you feel bored, irksome or irritable. And, of course, there's Al Pacino. His thunderous voice and arrogant demeanour are enough to make the viewer feel uncomfortable about him, and it isn't really hard to associate his character with that of the Devil. The other characters merely serve as pretexts for Lomax's wife to lose control over herself and imagine things related to hell, Satan and all that stuff. All in all, I wouldn't recommend this as a must-see, but probably something you might just rent at a DVD store when your other choices aren't that appealing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Night of the world"- uncreated by fable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yughred
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt that Kevin is familiar with the Bible, this is the weapon of the debate in his court in "Mo Yizi case, he resorted to the freedom of religious belief of the party days India with eloquence eloquent Mo Yizi acquitted on the charges, plus Mo Yizi assistant prosecutor Arnold Modu facilities witchcraft, it coughing, unable to speak, and Kevin got his wish to obtain another victory. Famous football coach Vince Lombardi once behalf of Kevin shouted his voice: "Winning is not everything, but only! Bible or religion or in the creation of four 60-game winning streak myth The young lawyer Kevin's eyes, but the tools to win the victory. The United States is a respect for the success of the nation, "the exclusive worship of successfully goddess bitch" overwhelm everything, including God. Xu Kaiwen court numerous times to praise the name of the Lord, in his heart, God is but a trite illusory value symbol. This era is the era of man and the world is completely lost. The maze of free will Make free will answer the philosophers who believe that God create people are born with free will - are born with the ability to act in accordance with their own wishes. The face of the world, people can be free to make a choice. Therefore, evil and suffering in the world, is the result of the abuse of free will, this responsibility should be by the people themselves to provide us with. God is not interfered. From the words of the Bible, we can infer that: God created Adam and Eve when, inevitably given their free will - the event that obey the spell of the snake Tousijinguo this crime, is not based on the free will to make autonomous decision, while is responsible for the crimes they have committed a pre-determined by God no choice behavior, then, God, what is the reason to make Adam and Eve it? The philosophical insights is the one held by the "devil's advocate". Summit in New York, in the face of the nations bustling, Kevin chose an opposite road with Jesus Christ, step-by-step into the trap of the devil - based on the free will. Yes, free will! Kevin's mother and wife successively abduction by Satan, the same is based on the free will of independent decision. Satan never force others to comply with his will. God, he respects the free will of the people. "I don't make things happen", he was just with a charming smile, charm by saying, to induce the people inside the original sin. He does not directly make any demands. He even twice put the persuasion attitude demagogue mending their ways. Free will, this is a wonderful word! In the eyes of the people, it embodied the pride and glory of the man. And Satan said: "Free will, it is a bitch." Bitch Italian English word "bitch, slut, nasty stuff", full of humble and despicable mean. Sadly, if Satan is not wrong. Bear the original sin of the people, given human nature and the dark background. Night of the world ", dumping large town of Babylon, God-given free will of light in this dark human nature, it has been alienated to slut who gaudy jeweled. "I'm a fan of man. I'm a humanist, maybe the last humanist." Satan wanton interpretation of the words of Montaigne: "anything that can occur in the human body and it was not inhuman." His "humanitarian doctrine "is to distort the true meaning of free will along the dark humanity, his definition of" freedom "is an absolute and unfettered freedom, one to do whatever they want to meet the desire of freedom. The paradox is that the absolute freedom, being mean absolute enslavement. "Man is born free, but no go without chains. Precisely the desire, only the desire of the human heart, is the real shackles, people become prisoners under the order shall not be free. Conspiracy of Satan took advantage of the free will of the people of the world - which lost in the sea of ​​desire free will, step by step, to lure the world turned away from God and become degenerate. "The 20th century was entirely mine", at the moment, Satan winner complacent. So, what is truly "free"? Jesus as early as "John." Provides us with the answer: "You shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free." Face of the unexpected defeat of Satan desperately shouting: "No! Damn you! Enough! Have not I given enough?" Ezekiel book describes the scene in an instant staged: "Are you proud because of the beautiful hearts corrupted your wisdom because of glory, I have sent thee to the ground you down before kings, good that they may behold thee. sins of many, unfair trade defiled thy sanctuary. therefore will I bring fire from you issue the middle, devour thee, and upon the earth in the sight of all people watch ashes "in a raging fire, Satan revealed a proud Blazing Angels Lucifer Mami. Satan carefully constructed dream collapsed in an instant. Out from the sea of ​​desire meditation from Kevin, the court did not hesitate to refuse to act as the spokesperson of the devil, the hearts of the people think: a hero was born, God, after all, to get the victory. However, Satan is everywhere. He was the embodiment of the snake, and also the embodiment of the law firm boss, he can transform himself into a tabloid reporter. Kevin's body, after all, keep the pride and vanity of the blood of Lucifer. Marian also as her ancestor Eve, enticed her husband swallowed sinking attractive fruit. The temptation is everywhere. Free will still trapped in the maze. The night of the world is still long. The dawn of being buried. "Alas, Babylon the great! Moment between your judgment come ... never again shining light in the midst of thee ..."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Devil's Avocate, an interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waltyeresdesousa (waltyeresdesousa@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate A movie of mystery and suspense, where people left their normal lives to live a story that since its beginning is surreal. That is how rolls The Devil's Advocate. Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reevens) is a lawyer that began his carrier at Florida and his principal characteristics are: He's never lost a court case before; He wins cases whether the accused is innocent or not; He is an excellent professional and it calls much attention of a millionaire - John Milton (Al Pacino), an owner of largest law firm in New York. John makes a proposal that cannot be refused by Kevin: if he wins the cases, he would work with him and have a good job and house. So he passed to live better in New York- the city that already wished for many peoples- with his wife Mary Ann Lomax (Charlize Theron), who had worked a lot before, since she was 13. Kevin unfortunately accepts this proposal even being advised by his mother Alice Lomax (Judith Ivev) that New York was the big Babylon, as descriptive on Apocalypse. He was a religious man when he was a child, Kevin knew this prophecy but he thought would only practice his religiosity again in his old age. By not listening to the prophecy, his life changes radically from that. He starts to work in this new company and his wife stays at home because she doesn't work anymore. Her function was only to take care of the house. But strange things start to happen in her life, she begins to see strange shapes in the people and they pass to have some aspects of demons and they are trying to scare her. The most interesting fact is that the boss of Kevin, Mr. John, always knows everything that happens in his married life. After many events, the movie ends with secrets revealed; Kevin finds out that his boss and his own mother are the center of the secret that could transform his life totally. When the movie ends, it scions about vanity and reinterpret the habitual concept about it and take this concept to Spiritual life. The movie sin in last scenes because it ends in a messy and the movie didn't make clear the real surreal. Can call your attention in a way that you forget the world, it try to exit you of the simple world where your mind can open to others' understanding. This movie is directed by Taylor Hackford, lasts 2:23:34. It was produced in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For watching, it is a good film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damn-eth
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate is one of the best films in the history of cinema. Both players and cues make the film charming. When you watch the film, you can't understand how it finishes since it progresses fluently. When people decide wrong decisions and choices, it is too late for turning back. This film dealt with them very well. Also, actors and actress have a impact on watching the film with integrating the roles of their.Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are leading roles. The film explains life of a successful lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves ) that his life changes after he meets rich businessman John Milton (Al Pacino). Kevin is an ambitious lawyer, his only aim is to succeed in his career and he saves them from even they are guilty. Kevin meets John and moves to New York. He affects from him but essentially, he makes an agreement with devil. In the beginning, everything is better. But after that, his wife faces to psychological problems. So, lawyer notices some realities and he tries to change something. I like cues of film so much. Especially, "Vanity is definitely my favorite sin." I think, the film doesn't lose ıt's beauty even the years passes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The devil has a son...called Kevin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is truly an oddity. There's the usual series of gruesome deaths lifted from The Omen and many another supernatural yarn accompanied by the now standard choral music. There's nothing much in the way of originality about any of this, but it does at least hold the attention. The most interesting thing are the bravura speeches from the villain John Milton (AKA The Devil) delivered with great gusto by Al Pacino, but some of the gravitas is undermined by his son's rather bathetic name 'Kevin'. 'Beelzebub and Kevin' does not quite have a demonic ring to it. The formulaic script is written more for melodramatic impact than sense, with people wandering onto busy roads for no apparent reason only to be mowed down by cars and such like. One strange and inexplicable scene has a blood drenched Kevin after just seeing his wife die by slitting her own throat meet his mother. Rather than her saying "why are you covered in blood, Kevin?" or "My God! what happened to my daughter-in-law?" instead she launches into a longwinded exposition (but one telegraphed at least an hour earlier in the film) that Milton is his father. All this is gory and faintly ludicrous but is carried out with Hollywood slickness and would perhaps deserve a better score were it not for the unforgivable finale where this house of cards collapses. Kevin is tempted to join his satanic father by having sex with his own sister. Instead of this Kevin chooses to shoot himself at which point any sense the script had disappears. Kevin's sister for some unexplained reason dies. The devil's (and the emperor's new) clothes fall off, he starts to burn while shouting "No! No!" The only way this comically bad scene could have been improved would have been to have Pacino say, "HE'S NOT THE ANTICHRIST! HE'S A VERY NAUGHTY BOY!" All this makes little sense dramatically or theologically. How can you defeat the devil by committing suicide? Isn't that expressly forbidden in the scriptures? Still you could argue that the point is that Kevin makes an act of self-sacrifice and had it ended there it perhaps would not have been so bad. BUT THEN HE WAKES UP! Seriously, he is then back at the very start of the film before any of the bad stuff happened. In other words the whole thing was an extended dream sequence. This is the sort of thing that first year English students are told to avoid. To cap it all Kevin then refuses to defend his client, something than is strangely presented as a moral stance when it is actually morally and legally dubious. Isn't it a lawyer's duty to defend his client even if he knows his client is guilty? A pointless re-appearance of Al Pacino right at the end just adds to the incoherence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary, Thought Provoking, Just Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mediapeertime
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films about Satan. Great at deceiving, full of power, loses in the end - as the devil should! This was altogether a great lawyer film. In this film, we get to see one of Pacino's best performances. He wasn't that usual character that we'r5e so used to seeing. Also tremendous performances by Charlize Theron, Connie Nielson, Jeffrey Jones, Tamara Tunie, and Craig T. Nelson. Couldn't buy Keaneau Reeves in the best lawyer role. he was adequate at best. Watch the train scene with Al Pacino - just tremendous! Taylor Hackford, great work (except casting of Reeves, but that mau not have been his choice????)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Brilliant!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elif490
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exceptional. Simply perfect. I watched without blinking my eye for a moment until the end of the film, and the final literally shocked me. As it tells us the relationship between us and satisfaction & sins, it shows us our biggest weaknesses as people. This film makes you terrify and at the same time it makes you learn a lot. Acting is even better than 'magnificent'. Legendary is a way less description for Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are fantastic!! Excellent and unique. Anyone who doesn't watch this movie loses a lot. It just blows your mind! Seriously. It's one of the bests. Once you watch it, you will never forget about this movie. Ten out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keanu Reeves as a bad-ass lawyer from hell.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tess van Brummelen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting (Keanu Reeves, Al Pacino and Charlize Theron) was brilliant. This film is scary as hell. Favorite quotes: "It's not a dream if it's true." "Your belly's too full, your dick is sore, your eyes are bloodshot, and you're screaming for someone to help!" "It's the goof of all time. Look but don't touch. Touch, but don't taste. Taste, don't swallow. Ahaha." "Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. The virtue of the devil is in his loins." "Vanity, definitely my favorite sin."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a stylish supernatural thriller about the temptation of evil for a young lawyer from the South. When he is offered a big time job in New York by big time lawyer played by Al Pacino, he finds there is a price to pay. The cast is good. Al Pacino before he got really devilish looking is good except for the silly dance at the end. Connie Nielsen is sophisticated and elegant. Charlize Theron is moving and convincing as the young wife sacrificing her looks for a standout performance. Even Keanu acts quite well as the young lawyer and you can't say that about too many of his movies. They didn't make it over the top horror - it's clever and frightening without much gore or in your face violence. Along with Rosemary's Baby this is the best NYC supernatural horror movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demonic thriller full of tension and pain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    4rch 4ng3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The figure of the devil posted in a contemporaney time, with a great Keanu Reeves and a really appreciable Al Pacino as the mysterious figure of the hided evil. Charlize Theron is absorbed by the pain and the sufference caused, a trap filled with an articoulate labyrinth of lies and bad actions. The screenplay, not even need to talk, is fantastic and avvolving at all, withal an adrenalinic envelopment an a huge tale of twists and questions. The way out is difficoult to find and the easy decisions are not part of the dialogues or the plot. The evil is so high and so showed, without fear, is unstoppable and known at the same time. The conseguences are so many and impossible to predict.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't really live up to its hype
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one film I had been wanting to watch for quite some time now, and I got around to it just a while back. I had some really good expectations from this movie, as I had read about it on IMDb and other movie sites, and I had thought it would be a courtroom thriller filled with suspense. But I have to say I was a bit disappointed with what I saw. The film is about a hotshot Florida lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves) who has never lost a case in his entire career. A New York law firm enlists his help to select a jury for a case and recognizing his talent, offers him a job. Lomax accepts and becomes quite close to his boss, John Milton (Al Pacino) during the course of his work. But he gradually begins to uncover some strange facets of Milton's personality and finally realizes that he is none other than Satan himself. Now, such a premise should surely set the stage for a riveting thriller filled with suspense and mystery. But sadly, it doesn't. I think the main reason is Keanu Reeves' performance. I couldn't really buy the idea of him being an argumentative lawyer who could acquit a rapist in spite of the pile of evidence staring him in the face, especially as this is what is shown in the first scene of the film. If the scene is supposed to convince the viewer of the talent of this young lawyer, it doesn't really pass the test. The only thing it does is invariably draw comparisons to the courtroom scenes in "A Few good Men", which had fabulous dialogues, coupled with one of Tom Cruise's finest performances ever. So it is asking a lot to make the audience believe that Lomax hasn't yet lost a case. Apart from this, the film does have a few things going for it. The pace is fast and well set, and for a first time viewing, there is no scene which makes you feel bored, irksome or irritable. And, of course, there's Al Pacino. His thunderous voice and arrogant demeanour are enough to make the viewer feel uncomfortable about him, and it isn't really hard to associate his character with that of the Devil. The other characters merely serve as pretexts for Lomax's wife to lose control over herself and imagine things related to hell, Satan and all that stuff. All in all, I wouldn't recommend this as a must-see, but probably something you might just rent at a DVD store when your other choices aren't that appealing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Night of the world"- uncreated by fable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yughred
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt that Kevin is familiar with the Bible, this is the weapon of the debate in his court in "Mo Yizi case, he resorted to the freedom of religious belief of the party days India with eloquence eloquent Mo Yizi acquitted on the charges, plus Mo Yizi assistant prosecutor Arnold Modu facilities witchcraft, it coughing, unable to speak, and Kevin got his wish to obtain another victory. Famous football coach Vince Lombardi once behalf of Kevin shouted his voice: "Winning is not everything, but only! Bible or religion or in the creation of four 60-game winning streak myth The young lawyer Kevin's eyes, but the tools to win the victory. The United States is a respect for the success of the nation, "the exclusive worship of successfully goddess bitch" overwhelm everything, including God. Xu Kaiwen court numerous times to praise the name of the Lord, in his heart, God is but a trite illusory value symbol. This era is the era of man and the world is completely lost. The maze of free will Make free will answer the philosophers who believe that God create people are born with free will - are born with the ability to act in accordance with their own wishes. The face of the world, people can be free to make a choice. Therefore, evil and suffering in the world, is the result of the abuse of free will, this responsibility should be by the people themselves to provide us with. God is not interfered. From the words of the Bible, we can infer that: God created Adam and Eve when, inevitably given their free will - the event that obey the spell of the snake Tousijinguo this crime, is not based on the free will to make autonomous decision, while is responsible for the crimes they have committed a pre-determined by God no choice behavior, then, God, what is the reason to make Adam and Eve it? The philosophical insights is the one held by the "devil's advocate". Summit in New York, in the face of the nations bustling, Kevin chose an opposite road with Jesus Christ, step-by-step into the trap of the devil - based on the free will. Yes, free will! Kevin's mother and wife successively abduction by Satan, the same is based on the free will of independent decision. Satan never force others to comply with his will. God, he respects the free will of the people. "I don't make things happen", he was just with a charming smile, charm by saying, to induce the people inside the original sin. He does not directly make any demands. He even twice put the persuasion attitude demagogue mending their ways. Free will, this is a wonderful word! In the eyes of the people, it embodied the pride and glory of the man. And Satan said: "Free will, it is a bitch." Bitch Italian English word "bitch, slut, nasty stuff", full of humble and despicable mean. Sadly, if Satan is not wrong. Bear the original sin of the people, given human nature and the dark background. Night of the world ", dumping large town of Babylon, God-given free will of light in this dark human nature, it has been alienated to slut who gaudy jeweled. "I'm a fan of man. I'm a humanist, maybe the last humanist." Satan wanton interpretation of the words of Montaigne: "anything that can occur in the human body and it was not inhuman." His "humanitarian doctrine "is to distort the true meaning of free will along the dark humanity, his definition of" freedom "is an absolute and unfettered freedom, one to do whatever they want to meet the desire of freedom. The paradox is that the absolute freedom, being mean absolute enslavement. "Man is born free, but no go without chains. Precisely the desire, only the desire of the human heart, is the real shackles, people become prisoners under the order shall not be free. Conspiracy of Satan took advantage of the free will of the people of the world - which lost in the sea of ​​desire free will, step by step, to lure the world turned away from God and become degenerate. "The 20th century was entirely mine", at the moment, Satan winner complacent. So, what is truly "free"? Jesus as early as "John." Provides us with the answer: "You shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free." Face of the unexpected defeat of Satan desperately shouting: "No! Damn you! Enough! Have not I given enough?" Ezekiel book describes the scene in an instant staged: "Are you proud because of the beautiful hearts corrupted your wisdom because of glory, I have sent thee to the ground you down before kings, good that they may behold thee. sins of many, unfair trade defiled thy sanctuary. therefore will I bring fire from you issue the middle, devour thee, and upon the earth in the sight of all people watch ashes "in a raging fire, Satan revealed a proud Blazing Angels Lucifer Mami. Satan carefully constructed dream collapsed in an instant. Out from the sea of ​​desire meditation from Kevin, the court did not hesitate to refuse to act as the spokesperson of the devil, the hearts of the people think: a hero was born, God, after all, to get the victory. However, Satan is everywhere. He was the embodiment of the snake, and also the embodiment of the law firm boss, he can transform himself into a tabloid reporter. Kevin's body, after all, keep the pride and vanity of the blood of Lucifer. Marian also as her ancestor Eve, enticed her husband swallowed sinking attractive fruit. The temptation is everywhere. Free will still trapped in the maze. The night of the world is still long. The dawn of being buried. "Alas, Babylon the great! Moment between your judgment come ... never again shining light in the midst of thee ..."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Devil's Avocate, an interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waltyeresdesousa (waltyeresdesousa@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate A movie of mystery and suspense, where people left their normal lives to live a story that since its beginning is surreal. That is how rolls The Devil's Advocate. Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reevens) is a lawyer that began his carrier at Florida and his principal characteristics are: He's never lost a court case before; He wins cases whether the accused is innocent or not; He is an excellent professional and it calls much attention of a millionaire - John Milton (Al Pacino), an owner of largest law firm in New York. John makes a proposal that cannot be refused by Kevin: if he wins the cases, he would work with him and have a good job and house. So he passed to live better in New York- the city that already wished for many peoples- with his wife Mary Ann Lomax (Charlize Theron), who had worked a lot before, since she was 13. Kevin unfortunately accepts this proposal even being advised by his mother Alice Lomax (Judith Ivev) that New York was the big Babylon, as descriptive on Apocalypse. He was a religious man when he was a child, Kevin knew this prophecy but he thought would only practice his religiosity again in his old age. By not listening to the prophecy, his life changes radically from that. He starts to work in this new company and his wife stays at home because she doesn't work anymore. Her function was only to take care of the house. But strange things start to happen in her life, she begins to see strange shapes in the people and they pass to have some aspects of demons and they are trying to scare her. The most interesting fact is that the boss of Kevin, Mr. John, always knows everything that happens in his married life. After many events, the movie ends with secrets revealed; Kevin finds out that his boss and his own mother are the center of the secret that could transform his life totally. When the movie ends, it scions about vanity and reinterpret the habitual concept about it and take this concept to Spiritual life. The movie sin in last scenes because it ends in a messy and the movie didn't make clear the real surreal. Can call your attention in a way that you forget the world, it try to exit you of the simple world where your mind can open to others' understanding. This movie is directed by Taylor Hackford, lasts 2:23:34. It was produced in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For watching, it is a good film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damn-eth
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate is one of the best films in the history of cinema. Both players and cues make the film charming. When you watch the film, you can't understand how it finishes since it progresses fluently. When people decide wrong decisions and choices, it is too late for turning back. This film dealt with them very well. Also, actors and actress have a impact on watching the film with integrating the roles of their.Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are leading roles. The film explains life of a successful lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves ) that his life changes after he meets rich businessman John Milton (Al Pacino). Kevin is an ambitious lawyer, his only aim is to succeed in his career and he saves them from even they are guilty. Kevin meets John and moves to New York. He affects from him but essentially, he makes an agreement with devil. In the beginning, everything is better. But after that, his wife faces to psychological problems. So, lawyer notices some realities and he tries to change something. I like cues of film so much. Especially, "Vanity is definitely my favorite sin." I think, the film doesn't lose ıt's beauty even the years passes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The devil has a son...called Kevin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is truly an oddity. There's the usual series of gruesome deaths lifted from The Omen and many another supernatural yarn accompanied by the now standard choral music. There's nothing much in the way of originality about any of this, but it does at least hold the attention. The most interesting thing are the bravura speeches from the villain John Milton (AKA The Devil) delivered with great gusto by Al Pacino, but some of the gravitas is undermined by his son's rather bathetic name 'Kevin'. 'Beelzebub and Kevin' does not quite have a demonic ring to it. The formulaic script is written more for melodramatic impact than sense, with people wandering onto busy roads for no apparent reason only to be mowed down by cars and such like. One strange and inexplicable scene has a blood drenched Kevin after just seeing his wife die by slitting her own throat meet his mother. Rather than her saying "why are you covered in blood, Kevin?" or "My God! what happened to my daughter-in-law?" instead she launches into a longwinded exposition (but one telegraphed at least an hour earlier in the film) that Milton is his father. All this is gory and faintly ludicrous but is carried out with Hollywood slickness and would perhaps deserve a better score were it not for the unforgivable finale where this house of cards collapses. Kevin is tempted to join his satanic father by having sex with his own sister. Instead of this Kevin chooses to shoot himself at which point any sense the script had disappears. Kevin's sister for some unexplained reason dies. The devil's (and the emperor's new) clothes fall off, he starts to burn while shouting "No! No!" The only way this comically bad scene could have been improved would have been to have Pacino say, "HE'S NOT THE ANTICHRIST! HE'S A VERY NAUGHTY BOY!" All this makes little sense dramatically or theologically. How can you defeat the devil by committing suicide? Isn't that expressly forbidden in the scriptures? Still you could argue that the point is that Kevin makes an act of self-sacrifice and had it ended there it perhaps would not have been so bad. BUT THEN HE WAKES UP! Seriously, he is then back at the very start of the film before any of the bad stuff happened. In other words the whole thing was an extended dream sequence. This is the sort of thing that first year English students are told to avoid. To cap it all Kevin then refuses to defend his client, something than is strangely presented as a moral stance when it is actually morally and legally dubious. Isn't it a lawyer's duty to defend his client even if he knows his client is guilty? A pointless re-appearance of Al Pacino right at the end just adds to the incoherence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary, Thought Provoking, Just Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mediapeertime
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films about Satan. Great at deceiving, full of power, loses in the end - as the devil should! This was altogether a great lawyer film. In this film, we get to see one of Pacino's best performances. He wasn't that usual character that we'r5e so used to seeing. Also tremendous performances by Charlize Theron, Connie Nielson, Jeffrey Jones, Tamara Tunie, and Craig T. Nelson. Couldn't buy Keaneau Reeves in the best lawyer role. he was adequate at best. Watch the train scene with Al Pacino - just tremendous! Taylor Hackford, great work (except casting of Reeves, but that mau not have been his choice????)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely Brilliant!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elif490
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exceptional. Simply perfect. I watched without blinking my eye for a moment until the end of the film, and the final literally shocked me. As it tells us the relationship between us and satisfaction & sins, it shows us our biggest weaknesses as people. This film makes you terrify and at the same time it makes you learn a lot. Acting is even better than 'magnificent'. Legendary is a way less description for Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are fantastic!! Excellent and unique. Anyone who doesn't watch this movie loses a lot. It just blows your mind! Seriously. It's one of the bests. Once you watch it, you will never forget about this movie. Ten out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keanu Reeves as a bad-ass lawyer from hell.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tess van Brummelen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The acting (Keanu Reeves, Al Pacino and Charlize Theron) was brilliant. This film is scary as hell. Favorite quotes: "It's not a dream if it's true." "Your belly's too full, your dick is sore, your eyes are bloodshot, and you're screaming for someone to help!" "It's the goof of all time. Look but don't touch. Touch, but don't taste. Taste, don't swallow. Ahaha." "Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. Diaboli virtus in lumbis est. The virtue of the devil is in his loins." "Vanity, definitely my favorite sin."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a stylish supernatural thriller about the temptation of evil for a young lawyer from the South. When he is offered a big time job in New York by big time lawyer played by Al Pacino, he finds there is a price to pay. The cast is good. Al Pacino before he got really devilish looking is good except for the silly dance at the end. Connie Nielsen is sophisticated and elegant. Charlize Theron is moving and convincing as the young wife sacrificing her looks for a standout performance. Even Keanu acts quite well as the young lawyer and you can't say that about too many of his movies. They didn't make it over the top horror - it's clever and frightening without much gore or in your face violence. Along with Rosemary's Baby this is the best NYC supernatural horror movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demonic thriller full of tension and pain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    4rch 4ng3l
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The figure of the devil posted in a contemporaney time, with a great Keanu Reeves and a really appreciable Al Pacino as the mysterious figure of the hided evil. Charlize Theron is absorbed by the pain and the sufference caused, a trap filled with an articoulate labyrinth of lies and bad actions. The screenplay, not even need to talk, is fantastic and avvolving at all, withal an adrenalinic envelopment an a huge tale of twists and questions. The way out is difficoult to find and the easy decisions are not part of the dialogues or the plot. The evil is so high and so showed, without fear, is unstoppable and known at the same time. The conseguences are so many and impossible to predict.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't really live up to its hype
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one film I had been wanting to watch for quite some time now, and I got around to it just a while back. I had some really good expectations from this movie, as I had read about it on IMDb and other movie sites, and I had thought it would be a courtroom thriller filled with suspense. But I have to say I was a bit disappointed with what I saw. The film is about a hotshot Florida lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves) who has never lost a case in his entire career. A New York law firm enlists his help to select a jury for a case and recognizing his talent, offers him a job. Lomax accepts and becomes quite close to his boss, John Milton (Al Pacino) during the course of his work. But he gradually begins to uncover some strange facets of Milton's personality and finally realizes that he is none other than Satan himself. Now, such a premise should surely set the stage for a riveting thriller filled with suspense and mystery. But sadly, it doesn't. I think the main reason is Keanu Reeves' performance. I couldn't really buy the idea of him being an argumentative lawyer who could acquit a rapist in spite of the pile of evidence staring him in the face, especially as this is what is shown in the first scene of the film. If the scene is supposed to convince the viewer of the talent of this young lawyer, it doesn't really pass the test. The only thing it does is invariably draw comparisons to the courtroom scenes in "A Few good Men", which had fabulous dialogues, coupled with one of Tom Cruise's finest performances ever. So it is asking a lot to make the audience believe that Lomax hasn't yet lost a case. Apart from this, the film does have a few things going for it. The pace is fast and well set, and for a first time viewing, there is no scene which makes you feel bored, irksome or irritable. And, of course, there's Al Pacino. His thunderous voice and arrogant demeanour are enough to make the viewer feel uncomfortable about him, and it isn't really hard to associate his character with that of the Devil. The other characters merely serve as pretexts for Lomax's wife to lose control over herself and imagine things related to hell, Satan and all that stuff. All in all, I wouldn't recommend this as a must-see, but probably something you might just rent at a DVD store when your other choices aren't that appealing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Night of the world"- uncreated by fable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yughred
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt that Kevin is familiar with the Bible, this is the weapon of the debate in his court in "Mo Yizi case, he resorted to the freedom of religious belief of the party days India with eloquence eloquent Mo Yizi acquitted on the charges, plus Mo Yizi assistant prosecutor Arnold Modu facilities witchcraft, it coughing, unable to speak, and Kevin got his wish to obtain another victory. Famous football coach Vince Lombardi once behalf of Kevin shouted his voice: "Winning is not everything, but only! Bible or religion or in the creation of four 60-game winning streak myth The young lawyer Kevin's eyes, but the tools to win the victory. The United States is a respect for the success of the nation, "the exclusive worship of successfully goddess bitch" overwhelm everything, including God. Xu Kaiwen court numerous times to praise the name of the Lord, in his heart, God is but a trite illusory value symbol. This era is the era of man and the world is completely lost. The maze of free will Make free will answer the philosophers who believe that God create people are born with free will - are born with the ability to act in accordance with their own wishes. The face of the world, people can be free to make a choice. Therefore, evil and suffering in the world, is the result of the abuse of free will, this responsibility should be by the people themselves to provide us with. God is not interfered. From the words of the Bible, we can infer that: God created Adam and Eve when, inevitably given their free will - the event that obey the spell of the snake Tousijinguo this crime, is not based on the free will to make autonomous decision, while is responsible for the crimes they have committed a pre-determined by God no choice behavior, then, God, what is the reason to make Adam and Eve it? The philosophical insights is the one held by the "devil's advocate". Summit in New York, in the face of the nations bustling, Kevin chose an opposite road with Jesus Christ, step-by-step into the trap of the devil - based on the free will. Yes, free will! Kevin's mother and wife successively abduction by Satan, the same is based on the free will of independent decision. Satan never force others to comply with his will. God, he respects the free will of the people. "I don't make things happen", he was just with a charming smile, charm by saying, to induce the people inside the original sin. He does not directly make any demands. He even twice put the persuasion attitude demagogue mending their ways. Free will, this is a wonderful word! In the eyes of the people, it embodied the pride and glory of the man. And Satan said: "Free will, it is a bitch." Bitch Italian English word "bitch, slut, nasty stuff", full of humble and despicable mean. Sadly, if Satan is not wrong. Bear the original sin of the people, given human nature and the dark background. Night of the world ", dumping large town of Babylon, God-given free will of light in this dark human nature, it has been alienated to slut who gaudy jeweled. "I'm a fan of man. I'm a humanist, maybe the last humanist." Satan wanton interpretation of the words of Montaigne: "anything that can occur in the human body and it was not inhuman." His "humanitarian doctrine "is to distort the true meaning of free will along the dark humanity, his definition of" freedom "is an absolute and unfettered freedom, one to do whatever they want to meet the desire of freedom. The paradox is that the absolute freedom, being mean absolute enslavement. "Man is born free, but no go without chains. Precisely the desire, only the desire of the human heart, is the real shackles, people become prisoners under the order shall not be free. Conspiracy of Satan took advantage of the free will of the people of the world - which lost in the sea of ​​desire free will, step by step, to lure the world turned away from God and become degenerate. "The 20th century was entirely mine", at the moment, Satan winner complacent. So, what is truly "free"? Jesus as early as "John." Provides us with the answer: "You shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free." Face of the unexpected defeat of Satan desperately shouting: "No! Damn you! Enough! Have not I given enough?" Ezekiel book describes the scene in an instant staged: "Are you proud because of the beautiful hearts corrupted your wisdom because of glory, I have sent thee to the ground you down before kings, good that they may behold thee. sins of many, unfair trade defiled thy sanctuary. therefore will I bring fire from you issue the middle, devour thee, and upon the earth in the sight of all people watch ashes "in a raging fire, Satan revealed a proud Blazing Angels Lucifer Mami. Satan carefully constructed dream collapsed in an instant. Out from the sea of ​​desire meditation from Kevin, the court did not hesitate to refuse to act as the spokesperson of the devil, the hearts of the people think: a hero was born, God, after all, to get the victory. However, Satan is everywhere. He was the embodiment of the snake, and also the embodiment of the law firm boss, he can transform himself into a tabloid reporter. Kevin's body, after all, keep the pride and vanity of the blood of Lucifer. Marian also as her ancestor Eve, enticed her husband swallowed sinking attractive fruit. The temptation is everywhere. Free will still trapped in the maze. The night of the world is still long. The dawn of being buried. "Alas, Babylon the great! Moment between your judgment come ... never again shining light in the midst of thee ..."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Devil's Avocate, an interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    waltyeresdesousa (waltyeresdesousa@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate A movie of mystery and suspense, where people left their normal lives to live a story that since its beginning is surreal. That is how rolls The Devil's Advocate. Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reevens) is a lawyer that began his carrier at Florida and his principal characteristics are: He's never lost a court case before; He wins cases whether the accused is innocent or not; He is an excellent professional and it calls much attention of a millionaire - John Milton (Al Pacino), an owner of largest law firm in New York. John makes a proposal that cannot be refused by Kevin: if he wins the cases, he would work with him and have a good job and house. So he passed to live better in New York- the city that already wished for many peoples- with his wife Mary Ann Lomax (Charlize Theron), who had worked a lot before, since she was 13. Kevin unfortunately accepts this proposal even being advised by his mother Alice Lomax (Judith Ivev) that New York was the big Babylon, as descriptive on Apocalypse. He was a religious man when he was a child, Kevin knew this prophecy but he thought would only practice his religiosity again in his old age. By not listening to the prophecy, his life changes radically from that. He starts to work in this new company and his wife stays at home because she doesn't work anymore. Her function was only to take care of the house. But strange things start to happen in her life, she begins to see strange shapes in the people and they pass to have some aspects of demons and they are trying to scare her. The most interesting fact is that the boss of Kevin, Mr. John, always knows everything that happens in his married life. After many events, the movie ends with secrets revealed; Kevin finds out that his boss and his own mother are the center of the secret that could transform his life totally. When the movie ends, it scions about vanity and reinterpret the habitual concept about it and take this concept to Spiritual life. The movie sin in last scenes because it ends in a messy and the movie didn't make clear the real surreal. Can call your attention in a way that you forget the world, it try to exit you of the simple world where your mind can open to others' understanding. This movie is directed by Taylor Hackford, lasts 2:23:34. It was produced in 1997.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For watching, it is a good film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    damn-eth
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Devil's Advocate is one of the best films in the history of cinema. Both players and cues make the film charming. When you watch the film, you can't understand how it finishes since it progresses fluently. When people decide wrong decisions and choices, it is too late for turning back. This film dealt with them very well. Also, actors and actress have a impact on watching the film with integrating the roles of their.Al Pacino, Keanu Reeves and Charlize Theron are leading roles. The film explains life of a successful lawyer Kevin Lomax (Keanu Reeves ) that his life changes after he meets rich businessman John Milton (Al Pacino). Kevin is an ambitious lawyer, his only aim is to succeed in his career and he saves them from even they are guilty. Kevin meets John and moves to New York. He affects from him but essentially, he makes an agreement with devil. In the beginning, everything is better. But after that, his wife faces to psychological problems. So, lawyer notices some realities and he tries to change something. I like cues of film so much. Especially, "Vanity is definitely my favorite sin." I think, the film doesn't lose ıt's beauty even the years passes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The devil has a son...called Kevin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is truly an oddity. There's the usual series of gruesome deaths lifted from The Omen and many another supernatural yarn accompanied by the now standard choral music. There's nothing much in the way of originality about any of this, but it does at least hold the attention. The most interesting thing are the bravura speeches from the villain John Milton (AKA The Devil) delivered with great gusto by Al Pacino, but some of the gravitas is undermined by his son's rather bathetic name 'Kevin'. 'Beelzebub and Kevin' does not quite have a demonic ring to it. The formulaic script is written more for melodramatic impact than sense, with people wandering onto busy roads for no apparent reason only to be mowed down by cars and such like. One strange and inexplicable scene has a blood drenched Kevin after just seeing his wife die by slitting her own throat meet his mother. Rather than her saying "why are you covered in blood, Kevin?" or "My God! what happened to my daughter-in-law?" instead she launches into a longwinded exposition (but one telegraphed at least an hour earlier in the film) that Milton is his father. All this is gory and faintly ludicrous but is carried out with Hollywood slickness and would perhaps deserve a better score were it not for the unforgivable finale where this house of cards collapses. Kevin is tempted to join his satanic father by having sex with his own sister. Instead of this Kevin chooses to shoot himself at which point any sense the script had disappears. Kevin's sister for some unexplained reason dies. The devil's (and the emperor's new) clothes fall off, he starts to burn while shouting "No! No!" The only way this comically bad scene could have been improved would have been to have Pacino say, "HE'S NOT THE ANTICHRIST! HE'S A VERY NAUGHTY BOY!" All this makes little sense dramatically or theologically. How can you defeat the devil by committing suicide? Isn't that expressly forbidden in the scriptures? Still you could argue that the point is that Kevin makes an act of self-sacrifice and had it ended there it perhaps would not have been so bad. BUT THEN HE WAKES UP! Seriously, he is then back at the very start of the film before any of the bad stuff happened. In other words the whole thing was an extended dream sequence. This is the sort of thing that first year English students are told to avoid. To cap it all Kevin then refuses to defend his client, something than is strangely presented as a moral stance when it is actually morally and legally dubious. Isn't it a lawyer's duty to defend his client even if he knows his client is guilty? A pointless re-appearance of Al Pacino right at the end just adds to the incoherence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
