<filme>
 <id>
  308
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119095
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Encanto das Fadas
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Two children in 1917 take a photograph, believed by some to be the first scientific evidence of the existence of fairies. Based on a true story.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Based on factual accounts, this is the story of two young girls that, somehow, have the ability to take pictures of winged beings... which certainly causes quite a stir throughout England during the time of the first World War. Everyone, except the girls who think it's quite normal, are excited about this "photographic proof" that fairies exist... even the great Sir Arthur Conan Doyle and Harry Houdini pay the girls a visit.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   girl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fairy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   children
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   photograph
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   billiards
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Charles Sturridge
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Albert Ash
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Tom McLoughlin
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Paul McGann
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Florence Hoath
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Elizabeth Earl
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imaginary Playmate Comes Out Of The Wood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two little girls -- eight and twelve years old -- in rural Yorkshire get hold of their Dad's camera and return with pictures of stereotypical tiny fairies during World War One. The photos get into the hands of the Theosophical Society and then the press and cause a great to-do. Sir Arthur Conan-Doyle (O'Toole) and Houdini (Keitel) are swept up in the investigation. First things first. The two little girls are as cute as all get out. The older one is thoughtful and reserved. The younger one is expressive and whimsical. (The first will grow up loving wisely; the second will love too well.) The younger girl has even features and may grow up to be quite beautiful and well known if she decides to pursue an acting career. I can't remember the names of the actresses but both are splendid in their roles. How do you get kids that young to act so well on screen? At the same time, we have to be careful about believing the tales that kids bring us. Joan of Arc was only a teen ager, and St. Bernadette was fourteen when she had her visions. And let's not forget that the witch hunts of Salem, Massachusetts, were begun because of the fairy tales spun by a handful of girls the same age as the ones in this movie. So watch out. Okay. The second thing that impressed me is the location. Rarely has West (or North) Yorkshire looked so ravishing. It's summer and the hills are like slight sea swells, criss-crossed by stone walls. And the place where the girls claim to have found the fairies! It's tranquil, placid, languorous, bewitching. There's a trickling rill that spreads out and runs a few inches deep across flat gray rocks, in some spots forming miniature pools. Overhead are drooping branches. And it's all surrounded by light forests and fields of pale purple flowers. I'm telling you, if you lie too long next to that brook, especially in the light of a full moon, you too will be overcome by your collective unconscious and the sprites and elves will come fluttering forth. Of course the two little girls are frauds, but consider the times. For Europe, unlike America, the first war was a horrendous bloody catastrophe that accomplished nothing in the long run and had little cause in the first place. And in the previous generation, science seemed to have made great advances and offered up a challenge to belief in the supernatural -- meaning no afterlife, no heaven or hell, no nothing. Damned Darwin and Freud and their acolytes and bulldogs. Conan-Doyle had just lost a son pointlessly. It's no wonder the two little liars became sensations. Like the magic of the fairy home, mysticism was in the air. For a similar story from the same period, see "Miss Morrison's Ghosts." It's a slow movie, especially if you've recently been fed a diet of slam-bang action movies. It's done in a classical ("old-fashioned") style with a mostly still camera. Yet there are moments of tension and drama. And the acting is superb. Peter O'Toole is a very gentlemanly and sad Conan-Doyle. And Keitel -- who looks great in his stage make up as Houdini -- is the friendliest of skeptics. Supporting parts are well done and, as I say, it would be hard to improve upon the two girls. The only sour note is the villainous reporter (McInernny), a gawky and ambitious character with a long neck and tiny jaw who undergoes his own comic conversion. It all ends, appropriately, with dozens of fairies buzzing around like dragonflies, although they're all fakes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fairy Tale" Is a Movie Come True
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kgny309
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it comes to family movies, it has to be thoughtful, entertaining and capable enough to hold on to the audience between age 1 and 101. "Fairy Tale: A True Story" takes that challenge and it really succeeds. In 1917 England, two girls, Elsie {Florence Hoath} and her cousin Frances {Elizabeth Earl} discover real fairies in a garden. Later, they take photographs to give proof that the fairies are real. Soon, they become famous when Arthur Conan Doyle {Peter O'Toole} publishes the photos in Strand magazine. "Fairy Tale" has the conflict of Human vs. Fantasy. The conflict connects with the film's theme, which is you must believe it unless you see the real thing. The center of the film's story is Elsie and Frances. They're two girls who really see things as it happen. They grab our attention along with the story. Ernie Contreras's unpredictable script makes the characters feel as human beings, not as cardboard people. There's even a clich&eacute; in the film with a reporter trying to get the real story behind the photographs, but it never gets annoying. Plus, there's a subplot with Frances's missing father which is handled well. Hoath and Earl each give fine performances. The supporting roles are handled nicely with O'Toole as Doyle and Harvey Keitel as magician Harry Houdini. Zbigniew Preisner's score gives a dreamy feel to the proceedings and Shirley Russell's World War period costumes are luscious. Delightfully photographed and wonderfully acted, Charles Sturridge's film is a charming, perfect and winning family film. This is a movie come true for all ages. Rating: ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FairyTale: A True Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the title says, this film is apparently, loosely anyway, based on the real life story of Cottingley Fairies, this story of course turned out to be fake, but this film at least creates the sense of realism felt at the time by many people, from director Charles Sturridge (Lassie). Basically, set in the early 20th Century, England, during the time that electricity and photography had been invented, many people have their own particular beliefs and become fascinated with phenomenas, including writer and Sherlock Holmes creator Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (Peter O'Toole) and magician, escapologist and stunt performer Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel). The daughter of devoted father Arthur (Paul McGann) and mother Polly (Phoebe Nicholls) who is grieving for the death of the son, twelve year old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath), has kept her dead brother Joseph's scrapbooks and stuff that relate to fairies. She is joined by her cousin Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) who has come from abroad while her father goes into action during World War I, and the two of them become close friends, spending much of their time at the brook and near the stream. It is there that they supposedly occasionally see actual fairies, and borrowing Elsie's father's camera they capture two photographs of them together with these fairies, and these are meant as gifts for Polly. However she takes them to Theosophist lecturer Edward L. Gardner (Bill Nighy), who gets them analysed by a photography professional who can determine whether they are fake or not, and they are pronounced genuine, due to fairy wings moving. Many adults say that the girls could have faked the photographs, but more say that they may be real, including Conan-Doyle, and Houdini sees them too, and two more photographs taken allow publication in The Strand, creating a big buzz. The attention however comes from some unwanted sources, with hundreds of people crowding the village looking for fairies themselves, or the girls interacting with them, such as reporters, like John Ferret (Tim McInnerny). The girls have become celebrities when they travel to London, and they get to meet Houdini again, and see his water tank escape performance, and the film ends with him telling Elsie not to reveal anything, only to leave people to make their own minds up, there is a brief return from the fairies, and Frances' Father (Mel Gibson in a cameo) returns from war. Also starring Jurassic Park's Bob Peck as Harry Briggs, War Horse's Peter Mullan as Sergeant Farmer and Four Weddings and a Funeral's Anna Chancellor as Peter Pan. The acting is as good as you are going to get from terrific actors like Keitel, O'Toole and Nighy, and it is a pleasant story, obviously if you knew that the five captured photographs from the real girls were faked it would technically ruin your belief, but either way it is a nice tale that works with the fantasy element, and obviously the small special effects to create the fairies supposedly captured, of course in real life they were gift book cutouts LOL, a worthwhile period drama based on a true story. It won the BAFTA Children's Award for Best Children's Film. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a Photograph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I watched this movie I was so tired that I slept through a part of it and didn't take in much of the other but from what I saw and from listening to others I picked up enough to comment on it. From what I heard this movie is based on some photographs taken in 1915 of some fairies. The photos could not be proved that they were faked and baffled a lot of people. What this movie has done is made the fairies real so as to create a child's movie. The plot is very thin but it is about people believing in fairies. The end comes with everybody seeing the evidence of the existence of fairies and believing in them. The thing is that the fairies play very little part in this movie and it is more focused on the children. The fairies never speak and interact with the children very rarely. This also seems to be an excuse to parade famous identities in the movie. We have Sir Arthur Conan Doyle and Harry Houdini as major characters in the movie and even show Houdini performing some of his escapes. Doyle is said to have written a book on fairies which my friend wanted to look for. He also said that the soundtrack was relaxing. They liked it but I slept and really had little interest in this movie. These fairies were the beautiful children fairies which I do not like, when it comes to fairies I like Faeries. What is the difference? Faeries are the more adult versions and appear in Mid-summer Night's Dream and Faerie Tale. These are much more vicious and hostile, especially Titania and Oberon in Midsummer Night's Dream. Those I love, Fairy Tale I don't. Oh well, each to his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enchanting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emswan2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie. I first learned of this story while studying the history of photography in college. The story is true, except... well- watch the movie. :) While by today's standards we would not be fooled by the photos, still the healing impact this news event had on society back then after the horrors of WWI and the peoples' willingness to believe it are certainly understandable and wonderful. The film is perfectly cast and perfectly acted and expertly edited. The girls are delightful. All characters are well expressed, including the parents, and the stories within the story are so very real, and touching. The is a lovely looking movie, with special effects that look convincingly real and made me wish they were. :-D Gather your loved ones around you and ENJOY this movie together!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undeniably charming; an absolutely delightful film for the whole family!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fairytale: A True Story is a truly charming and delightful film, that has all the charm of the enchanting Secret Garden and the equally wonderful Little Princess. The screenplay was very solid, and the film does look very, very beautiful, with perfect camera-work and splendid period detail. The simple but well-told story tells of two young girls who find and photograph fairies, and they manage to convince even Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (marvellously played by Peter O'Toole) that the fairies are real. The music was really lovely to listen to, and director Charles Sturridge manages to draw spirited (and exemplary) performances from his two leads Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl. The supporting cast include Paul McGann, Pheobe Nicolls and Harvey Keital, and all do more than a respectable job. Overall, a very pleasing and charming film, that does certainly leave you wanting fairies at the bottom of your garden, like the back of the video box promised. 10/10 Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made film about the two girls who claimed to have taken pictures of fairies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Enchanting and well acted,Fairytale A True Story tells the real life story of two cousins Elsie Wright(Florence Hoath)and Frances Griffiths(Elizabeth Earl)who in 1917 took some pictures that captivated the world and had England divided in discussion of their authenticity. Even more attention was drawn to them and their home when two very high profile and well known figures took an interest.They are Sir Arthur Conan Doyle(Peter O'Toole)the author best known for creating the character of Sherlock Holmes and his close friend the illusionist Harry Houdini(Harvey Keitel).Conan Doyle believes in what he sees 100 percent whereas Houdini is a little more sceptical(probably as he was the greatest illusionist the world had seen and wanted to see how they created the illusion of fairies).However tests on the photos proved them to be genuine.To this day people are still divided about whether they are pictures of real fairies or a clever and very impressive hoax.With a great cast including Paul MGann as Arthur Elsies father and Phoebe Nicholls as her mother who is grieving for her dead son(who claimed to have seen the fairies as well)moving and uplifting this is well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly Recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aimless-46
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Masters of illusion never reveal their secrets" says Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel) in the lyrical fantasy ''Fairytale--A True Story'' (1997). And pay attention to the things Houdini says like: "Never try to fool children. They expect nothing and therefore see everything", because his character exists to articulate the film's themes. These revolve around the need for many people to believe in the existence of spiritual concepts, the wisdom of not challenging these beliefs if they give sustenance, and how loss of the ability to see much that is hidden goes along with our loss of innocence. The innocence is stressed early in the film when an 8 year-old girl fearlessly seeks out a horribly scarred veteran on the train and gets "her corporal's" help to play a game of cat's cradle. In its best montage the film moves between, Houdini's fabled "The Chinese Water Torture Cell" illusion, a chess match, and the first-hand spiritual education of an investigative reporter. The film loosely documents the "Cottingley fairies" incident in 1917 when two English girls produced photographs that showed themselves in the presence of fairies. Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (insert Sherlock Holmes here) published the photographs when he and various experts became convinced they were authentic. Many years later the girls would confess that they had faked all but one of the photos, but they continued to claim that their fairies actually exist. 12-year-old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath) and 8-year-old Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) are the girls. It is late in WW1 and Francis has come to live with her Aunt and Uncle because her father is missing in action on the front lines. The Wright's too are dealing with a recent loss as Elsie's brother has passed away. So both children and Mrs. Wright (Phoebe Nicholls) are primed for belief in the other world. Yes there are fairies, the viewer sees them when no people are around and we see them leaving the area when Doyle's revelations cause the property to be trampled by a hoard of both believers and skeptics. The production design and the special effects are impressive and the film is absorbing from scene to scene. The target audience is a little hard to pin down as the subject is geared to children but much of the story a bit confusing if you are not already familiar with historical figures like Houdini and Doyle. The film utilizes the tried and true device for connecting with children by giving them a story about young people who know stuff is real, even though adults don't get it. In the film the age gap between the two girls is slightly less than it was in real life, which gives their relationship a bit more believability. Even more impressive is how successful the director was in the subtle creation two very distinct personalities. Elsie is shy and artistic. Frances is confident and social. Their interplay is the film's real strength; apparently the director sensed this dynamic and worked very hard in his acting for the camera direction of the two young actresses. He kept them in character and added behavioral elements they give their characters considerable depth and dimensionality. Then again, what do I know? I'm only a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A magical story behind the poorly directed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Efenstor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone who's deeply interested in folklore, as I dare to say I am, knows the story of the Fairies of Cottingley, it's one nearly-epic story of the two girls who inadvertently made a half of the world actually believe in magical creatures (I don't count children, for they did, they do and they will believe, and that's wondrous), and the best part of the epic is that they had never straightforwardly confessed that they've forged it just not to ruin people's glimpse of faith in magical. If that's what this movie should have been telling about then it certainly does not the job. Despite the wonderful and believable acting of Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl, the incoherent screenplay and direction ruin everything and only a shadow of the childhood magic remains in the dark corner pushed away by the social-drama clich&eacute;s (they even managed to insert there a villain and the goddammit comic relief!). And the top-notch CGI doesn't help out. There's more magic even in ghost-story movies, such as 'Lady in White' or 'The Changeling'. Worth watching, but only once. I deeply hope that some day someone will make a movie worthy of this story's spiritual background, so you'd understand why some perfectly sane people believe in fairies, even without the photographs. One of my favorite books is the collection of narrative tales, recorded in the middle of the 20th century among the Siberian villagers, mostly in the Chita region, by V.P. Zinovyev, and the thing I really love and adore in those stories is that those people actually believe all the folklore things they're speaking about! It's grievous that there are less and less such people live in this world, of that kind who believe because of the purity of the heart, not because of fear or passion. Some call those people dark and unenlightened, some laugh at them, but the thing they actually have is the faith, whilst everyone else have only a ghost of it. That who knows cannot believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It was simply a lovely, moving film. Tears flowed down my cheeks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjhan2
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd seen this film on DVD when it first came to the States,I saw it again last weekend on TV. I'd forgotten how much I loved it, I'm so glad I saw it again. It was so moving, I felt I wanted to believe in fairies and after seeing this film and the websites with pictures of them, who's to say there aren't any? I recommend this film to anyone, just keep an open mind and a box of tissues handy. The girls are so sweet, if only children were like that today, we would be so lucky! Harvey Keitel was a bit hard to believe as Houdini but he wasn't terrible and Peter O'Toole was wonderful as Sir Arthur Conan Doyle. The mother and father were just the ticket, I believed their performances entirely. If only we could make a film as lovely as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imaginary Playmate Comes Out Of The Wood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two little girls -- eight and twelve years old -- in rural Yorkshire get hold of their Dad's camera and return with pictures of stereotypical tiny fairies during World War One. The photos get into the hands of the Theosophical Society and then the press and cause a great to-do. Sir Arthur Conan-Doyle (O'Toole) and Houdini (Keitel) are swept up in the investigation. First things first. The two little girls are as cute as all get out. The older one is thoughtful and reserved. The younger one is expressive and whimsical. (The first will grow up loving wisely; the second will love too well.) The younger girl has even features and may grow up to be quite beautiful and well known if she decides to pursue an acting career. I can't remember the names of the actresses but both are splendid in their roles. How do you get kids that young to act so well on screen? At the same time, we have to be careful about believing the tales that kids bring us. Joan of Arc was only a teen ager, and St. Bernadette was fourteen when she had her visions. And let's not forget that the witch hunts of Salem, Massachusetts, were begun because of the fairy tales spun by a handful of girls the same age as the ones in this movie. So watch out. Okay. The second thing that impressed me is the location. Rarely has West (or North) Yorkshire looked so ravishing. It's summer and the hills are like slight sea swells, criss-crossed by stone walls. And the place where the girls claim to have found the fairies! It's tranquil, placid, languorous, bewitching. There's a trickling rill that spreads out and runs a few inches deep across flat gray rocks, in some spots forming miniature pools. Overhead are drooping branches. And it's all surrounded by light forests and fields of pale purple flowers. I'm telling you, if you lie too long next to that brook, especially in the light of a full moon, you too will be overcome by your collective unconscious and the sprites and elves will come fluttering forth. Of course the two little girls are frauds, but consider the times. For Europe, unlike America, the first war was a horrendous bloody catastrophe that accomplished nothing in the long run and had little cause in the first place. And in the previous generation, science seemed to have made great advances and offered up a challenge to belief in the supernatural -- meaning no afterlife, no heaven or hell, no nothing. Damned Darwin and Freud and their acolytes and bulldogs. Conan-Doyle had just lost a son pointlessly. It's no wonder the two little liars became sensations. Like the magic of the fairy home, mysticism was in the air. For a similar story from the same period, see "Miss Morrison's Ghosts." It's a slow movie, especially if you've recently been fed a diet of slam-bang action movies. It's done in a classical ("old-fashioned") style with a mostly still camera. Yet there are moments of tension and drama. And the acting is superb. Peter O'Toole is a very gentlemanly and sad Conan-Doyle. And Keitel -- who looks great in his stage make up as Houdini -- is the friendliest of skeptics. Supporting parts are well done and, as I say, it would be hard to improve upon the two girls. The only sour note is the villainous reporter (McInernny), a gawky and ambitious character with a long neck and tiny jaw who undergoes his own comic conversion. It all ends, appropriately, with dozens of fairies buzzing around like dragonflies, although they're all fakes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fairy Tale" Is a Movie Come True
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kgny309
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it comes to family movies, it has to be thoughtful, entertaining and capable enough to hold on to the audience between age 1 and 101. "Fairy Tale: A True Story" takes that challenge and it really succeeds. In 1917 England, two girls, Elsie {Florence Hoath} and her cousin Frances {Elizabeth Earl} discover real fairies in a garden. Later, they take photographs to give proof that the fairies are real. Soon, they become famous when Arthur Conan Doyle {Peter O'Toole} publishes the photos in Strand magazine. "Fairy Tale" has the conflict of Human vs. Fantasy. The conflict connects with the film's theme, which is you must believe it unless you see the real thing. The center of the film's story is Elsie and Frances. They're two girls who really see things as it happen. They grab our attention along with the story. Ernie Contreras's unpredictable script makes the characters feel as human beings, not as cardboard people. There's even a clich&eacute; in the film with a reporter trying to get the real story behind the photographs, but it never gets annoying. Plus, there's a subplot with Frances's missing father which is handled well. Hoath and Earl each give fine performances. The supporting roles are handled nicely with O'Toole as Doyle and Harvey Keitel as magician Harry Houdini. Zbigniew Preisner's score gives a dreamy feel to the proceedings and Shirley Russell's World War period costumes are luscious. Delightfully photographed and wonderfully acted, Charles Sturridge's film is a charming, perfect and winning family film. This is a movie come true for all ages. Rating: ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FairyTale: A True Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the title says, this film is apparently, loosely anyway, based on the real life story of Cottingley Fairies, this story of course turned out to be fake, but this film at least creates the sense of realism felt at the time by many people, from director Charles Sturridge (Lassie). Basically, set in the early 20th Century, England, during the time that electricity and photography had been invented, many people have their own particular beliefs and become fascinated with phenomenas, including writer and Sherlock Holmes creator Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (Peter O'Toole) and magician, escapologist and stunt performer Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel). The daughter of devoted father Arthur (Paul McGann) and mother Polly (Phoebe Nicholls) who is grieving for the death of the son, twelve year old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath), has kept her dead brother Joseph's scrapbooks and stuff that relate to fairies. She is joined by her cousin Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) who has come from abroad while her father goes into action during World War I, and the two of them become close friends, spending much of their time at the brook and near the stream. It is there that they supposedly occasionally see actual fairies, and borrowing Elsie's father's camera they capture two photographs of them together with these fairies, and these are meant as gifts for Polly. However she takes them to Theosophist lecturer Edward L. Gardner (Bill Nighy), who gets them analysed by a photography professional who can determine whether they are fake or not, and they are pronounced genuine, due to fairy wings moving. Many adults say that the girls could have faked the photographs, but more say that they may be real, including Conan-Doyle, and Houdini sees them too, and two more photographs taken allow publication in The Strand, creating a big buzz. The attention however comes from some unwanted sources, with hundreds of people crowding the village looking for fairies themselves, or the girls interacting with them, such as reporters, like John Ferret (Tim McInnerny). The girls have become celebrities when they travel to London, and they get to meet Houdini again, and see his water tank escape performance, and the film ends with him telling Elsie not to reveal anything, only to leave people to make their own minds up, there is a brief return from the fairies, and Frances' Father (Mel Gibson in a cameo) returns from war. Also starring Jurassic Park's Bob Peck as Harry Briggs, War Horse's Peter Mullan as Sergeant Farmer and Four Weddings and a Funeral's Anna Chancellor as Peter Pan. The acting is as good as you are going to get from terrific actors like Keitel, O'Toole and Nighy, and it is a pleasant story, obviously if you knew that the five captured photographs from the real girls were faked it would technically ruin your belief, but either way it is a nice tale that works with the fantasy element, and obviously the small special effects to create the fairies supposedly captured, of course in real life they were gift book cutouts LOL, a worthwhile period drama based on a true story. It won the BAFTA Children's Award for Best Children's Film. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a Photograph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I watched this movie I was so tired that I slept through a part of it and didn't take in much of the other but from what I saw and from listening to others I picked up enough to comment on it. From what I heard this movie is based on some photographs taken in 1915 of some fairies. The photos could not be proved that they were faked and baffled a lot of people. What this movie has done is made the fairies real so as to create a child's movie. The plot is very thin but it is about people believing in fairies. The end comes with everybody seeing the evidence of the existence of fairies and believing in them. The thing is that the fairies play very little part in this movie and it is more focused on the children. The fairies never speak and interact with the children very rarely. This also seems to be an excuse to parade famous identities in the movie. We have Sir Arthur Conan Doyle and Harry Houdini as major characters in the movie and even show Houdini performing some of his escapes. Doyle is said to have written a book on fairies which my friend wanted to look for. He also said that the soundtrack was relaxing. They liked it but I slept and really had little interest in this movie. These fairies were the beautiful children fairies which I do not like, when it comes to fairies I like Faeries. What is the difference? Faeries are the more adult versions and appear in Mid-summer Night's Dream and Faerie Tale. These are much more vicious and hostile, especially Titania and Oberon in Midsummer Night's Dream. Those I love, Fairy Tale I don't. Oh well, each to his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enchanting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emswan2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie. I first learned of this story while studying the history of photography in college. The story is true, except... well- watch the movie. :) While by today's standards we would not be fooled by the photos, still the healing impact this news event had on society back then after the horrors of WWI and the peoples' willingness to believe it are certainly understandable and wonderful. The film is perfectly cast and perfectly acted and expertly edited. The girls are delightful. All characters are well expressed, including the parents, and the stories within the story are so very real, and touching. The is a lovely looking movie, with special effects that look convincingly real and made me wish they were. :-D Gather your loved ones around you and ENJOY this movie together!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undeniably charming; an absolutely delightful film for the whole family!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fairytale: A True Story is a truly charming and delightful film, that has all the charm of the enchanting Secret Garden and the equally wonderful Little Princess. The screenplay was very solid, and the film does look very, very beautiful, with perfect camera-work and splendid period detail. The simple but well-told story tells of two young girls who find and photograph fairies, and they manage to convince even Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (marvellously played by Peter O'Toole) that the fairies are real. The music was really lovely to listen to, and director Charles Sturridge manages to draw spirited (and exemplary) performances from his two leads Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl. The supporting cast include Paul McGann, Pheobe Nicolls and Harvey Keital, and all do more than a respectable job. Overall, a very pleasing and charming film, that does certainly leave you wanting fairies at the bottom of your garden, like the back of the video box promised. 10/10 Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made film about the two girls who claimed to have taken pictures of fairies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Enchanting and well acted,Fairytale A True Story tells the real life story of two cousins Elsie Wright(Florence Hoath)and Frances Griffiths(Elizabeth Earl)who in 1917 took some pictures that captivated the world and had England divided in discussion of their authenticity. Even more attention was drawn to them and their home when two very high profile and well known figures took an interest.They are Sir Arthur Conan Doyle(Peter O'Toole)the author best known for creating the character of Sherlock Holmes and his close friend the illusionist Harry Houdini(Harvey Keitel).Conan Doyle believes in what he sees 100 percent whereas Houdini is a little more sceptical(probably as he was the greatest illusionist the world had seen and wanted to see how they created the illusion of fairies).However tests on the photos proved them to be genuine.To this day people are still divided about whether they are pictures of real fairies or a clever and very impressive hoax.With a great cast including Paul MGann as Arthur Elsies father and Phoebe Nicholls as her mother who is grieving for her dead son(who claimed to have seen the fairies as well)moving and uplifting this is well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly Recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aimless-46
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Masters of illusion never reveal their secrets" says Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel) in the lyrical fantasy ''Fairytale--A True Story'' (1997). And pay attention to the things Houdini says like: "Never try to fool children. They expect nothing and therefore see everything", because his character exists to articulate the film's themes. These revolve around the need for many people to believe in the existence of spiritual concepts, the wisdom of not challenging these beliefs if they give sustenance, and how loss of the ability to see much that is hidden goes along with our loss of innocence. The innocence is stressed early in the film when an 8 year-old girl fearlessly seeks out a horribly scarred veteran on the train and gets "her corporal's" help to play a game of cat's cradle. In its best montage the film moves between, Houdini's fabled "The Chinese Water Torture Cell" illusion, a chess match, and the first-hand spiritual education of an investigative reporter. The film loosely documents the "Cottingley fairies" incident in 1917 when two English girls produced photographs that showed themselves in the presence of fairies. Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (insert Sherlock Holmes here) published the photographs when he and various experts became convinced they were authentic. Many years later the girls would confess that they had faked all but one of the photos, but they continued to claim that their fairies actually exist. 12-year-old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath) and 8-year-old Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) are the girls. It is late in WW1 and Francis has come to live with her Aunt and Uncle because her father is missing in action on the front lines. The Wright's too are dealing with a recent loss as Elsie's brother has passed away. So both children and Mrs. Wright (Phoebe Nicholls) are primed for belief in the other world. Yes there are fairies, the viewer sees them when no people are around and we see them leaving the area when Doyle's revelations cause the property to be trampled by a hoard of both believers and skeptics. The production design and the special effects are impressive and the film is absorbing from scene to scene. The target audience is a little hard to pin down as the subject is geared to children but much of the story a bit confusing if you are not already familiar with historical figures like Houdini and Doyle. The film utilizes the tried and true device for connecting with children by giving them a story about young people who know stuff is real, even though adults don't get it. In the film the age gap between the two girls is slightly less than it was in real life, which gives their relationship a bit more believability. Even more impressive is how successful the director was in the subtle creation two very distinct personalities. Elsie is shy and artistic. Frances is confident and social. Their interplay is the film's real strength; apparently the director sensed this dynamic and worked very hard in his acting for the camera direction of the two young actresses. He kept them in character and added behavioral elements they give their characters considerable depth and dimensionality. Then again, what do I know? I'm only a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A magical story behind the poorly directed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Efenstor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone who's deeply interested in folklore, as I dare to say I am, knows the story of the Fairies of Cottingley, it's one nearly-epic story of the two girls who inadvertently made a half of the world actually believe in magical creatures (I don't count children, for they did, they do and they will believe, and that's wondrous), and the best part of the epic is that they had never straightforwardly confessed that they've forged it just not to ruin people's glimpse of faith in magical. If that's what this movie should have been telling about then it certainly does not the job. Despite the wonderful and believable acting of Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl, the incoherent screenplay and direction ruin everything and only a shadow of the childhood magic remains in the dark corner pushed away by the social-drama clich&eacute;s (they even managed to insert there a villain and the goddammit comic relief!). And the top-notch CGI doesn't help out. There's more magic even in ghost-story movies, such as 'Lady in White' or 'The Changeling'. Worth watching, but only once. I deeply hope that some day someone will make a movie worthy of this story's spiritual background, so you'd understand why some perfectly sane people believe in fairies, even without the photographs. One of my favorite books is the collection of narrative tales, recorded in the middle of the 20th century among the Siberian villagers, mostly in the Chita region, by V.P. Zinovyev, and the thing I really love and adore in those stories is that those people actually believe all the folklore things they're speaking about! It's grievous that there are less and less such people live in this world, of that kind who believe because of the purity of the heart, not because of fear or passion. Some call those people dark and unenlightened, some laugh at them, but the thing they actually have is the faith, whilst everyone else have only a ghost of it. That who knows cannot believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It was simply a lovely, moving film. Tears flowed down my cheeks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjhan2
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd seen this film on DVD when it first came to the States,I saw it again last weekend on TV. I'd forgotten how much I loved it, I'm so glad I saw it again. It was so moving, I felt I wanted to believe in fairies and after seeing this film and the websites with pictures of them, who's to say there aren't any? I recommend this film to anyone, just keep an open mind and a box of tissues handy. The girls are so sweet, if only children were like that today, we would be so lucky! Harvey Keitel was a bit hard to believe as Houdini but he wasn't terrible and Peter O'Toole was wonderful as Sir Arthur Conan Doyle. The mother and father were just the ticket, I believed their performances entirely. If only we could make a film as lovely as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imaginary Playmate Comes Out Of The Wood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two little girls -- eight and twelve years old -- in rural Yorkshire get hold of their Dad's camera and return with pictures of stereotypical tiny fairies during World War One. The photos get into the hands of the Theosophical Society and then the press and cause a great to-do. Sir Arthur Conan-Doyle (O'Toole) and Houdini (Keitel) are swept up in the investigation. First things first. The two little girls are as cute as all get out. The older one is thoughtful and reserved. The younger one is expressive and whimsical. (The first will grow up loving wisely; the second will love too well.) The younger girl has even features and may grow up to be quite beautiful and well known if she decides to pursue an acting career. I can't remember the names of the actresses but both are splendid in their roles. How do you get kids that young to act so well on screen? At the same time, we have to be careful about believing the tales that kids bring us. Joan of Arc was only a teen ager, and St. Bernadette was fourteen when she had her visions. And let's not forget that the witch hunts of Salem, Massachusetts, were begun because of the fairy tales spun by a handful of girls the same age as the ones in this movie. So watch out. Okay. The second thing that impressed me is the location. Rarely has West (or North) Yorkshire looked so ravishing. It's summer and the hills are like slight sea swells, criss-crossed by stone walls. And the place where the girls claim to have found the fairies! It's tranquil, placid, languorous, bewitching. There's a trickling rill that spreads out and runs a few inches deep across flat gray rocks, in some spots forming miniature pools. Overhead are drooping branches. And it's all surrounded by light forests and fields of pale purple flowers. I'm telling you, if you lie too long next to that brook, especially in the light of a full moon, you too will be overcome by your collective unconscious and the sprites and elves will come fluttering forth. Of course the two little girls are frauds, but consider the times. For Europe, unlike America, the first war was a horrendous bloody catastrophe that accomplished nothing in the long run and had little cause in the first place. And in the previous generation, science seemed to have made great advances and offered up a challenge to belief in the supernatural -- meaning no afterlife, no heaven or hell, no nothing. Damned Darwin and Freud and their acolytes and bulldogs. Conan-Doyle had just lost a son pointlessly. It's no wonder the two little liars became sensations. Like the magic of the fairy home, mysticism was in the air. For a similar story from the same period, see "Miss Morrison's Ghosts." It's a slow movie, especially if you've recently been fed a diet of slam-bang action movies. It's done in a classical ("old-fashioned") style with a mostly still camera. Yet there are moments of tension and drama. And the acting is superb. Peter O'Toole is a very gentlemanly and sad Conan-Doyle. And Keitel -- who looks great in his stage make up as Houdini -- is the friendliest of skeptics. Supporting parts are well done and, as I say, it would be hard to improve upon the two girls. The only sour note is the villainous reporter (McInernny), a gawky and ambitious character with a long neck and tiny jaw who undergoes his own comic conversion. It all ends, appropriately, with dozens of fairies buzzing around like dragonflies, although they're all fakes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fairy Tale" Is a Movie Come True
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kgny309
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it comes to family movies, it has to be thoughtful, entertaining and capable enough to hold on to the audience between age 1 and 101. "Fairy Tale: A True Story" takes that challenge and it really succeeds. In 1917 England, two girls, Elsie {Florence Hoath} and her cousin Frances {Elizabeth Earl} discover real fairies in a garden. Later, they take photographs to give proof that the fairies are real. Soon, they become famous when Arthur Conan Doyle {Peter O'Toole} publishes the photos in Strand magazine. "Fairy Tale" has the conflict of Human vs. Fantasy. The conflict connects with the film's theme, which is you must believe it unless you see the real thing. The center of the film's story is Elsie and Frances. They're two girls who really see things as it happen. They grab our attention along with the story. Ernie Contreras's unpredictable script makes the characters feel as human beings, not as cardboard people. There's even a clich&eacute; in the film with a reporter trying to get the real story behind the photographs, but it never gets annoying. Plus, there's a subplot with Frances's missing father which is handled well. Hoath and Earl each give fine performances. The supporting roles are handled nicely with O'Toole as Doyle and Harvey Keitel as magician Harry Houdini. Zbigniew Preisner's score gives a dreamy feel to the proceedings and Shirley Russell's World War period costumes are luscious. Delightfully photographed and wonderfully acted, Charles Sturridge's film is a charming, perfect and winning family film. This is a movie come true for all ages. Rating: ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FairyTale: A True Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the title says, this film is apparently, loosely anyway, based on the real life story of Cottingley Fairies, this story of course turned out to be fake, but this film at least creates the sense of realism felt at the time by many people, from director Charles Sturridge (Lassie). Basically, set in the early 20th Century, England, during the time that electricity and photography had been invented, many people have their own particular beliefs and become fascinated with phenomenas, including writer and Sherlock Holmes creator Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (Peter O'Toole) and magician, escapologist and stunt performer Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel). The daughter of devoted father Arthur (Paul McGann) and mother Polly (Phoebe Nicholls) who is grieving for the death of the son, twelve year old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath), has kept her dead brother Joseph's scrapbooks and stuff that relate to fairies. She is joined by her cousin Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) who has come from abroad while her father goes into action during World War I, and the two of them become close friends, spending much of their time at the brook and near the stream. It is there that they supposedly occasionally see actual fairies, and borrowing Elsie's father's camera they capture two photographs of them together with these fairies, and these are meant as gifts for Polly. However she takes them to Theosophist lecturer Edward L. Gardner (Bill Nighy), who gets them analysed by a photography professional who can determine whether they are fake or not, and they are pronounced genuine, due to fairy wings moving. Many adults say that the girls could have faked the photographs, but more say that they may be real, including Conan-Doyle, and Houdini sees them too, and two more photographs taken allow publication in The Strand, creating a big buzz. The attention however comes from some unwanted sources, with hundreds of people crowding the village looking for fairies themselves, or the girls interacting with them, such as reporters, like John Ferret (Tim McInnerny). The girls have become celebrities when they travel to London, and they get to meet Houdini again, and see his water tank escape performance, and the film ends with him telling Elsie not to reveal anything, only to leave people to make their own minds up, there is a brief return from the fairies, and Frances' Father (Mel Gibson in a cameo) returns from war. Also starring Jurassic Park's Bob Peck as Harry Briggs, War Horse's Peter Mullan as Sergeant Farmer and Four Weddings and a Funeral's Anna Chancellor as Peter Pan. The acting is as good as you are going to get from terrific actors like Keitel, O'Toole and Nighy, and it is a pleasant story, obviously if you knew that the five captured photographs from the real girls were faked it would technically ruin your belief, but either way it is a nice tale that works with the fantasy element, and obviously the small special effects to create the fairies supposedly captured, of course in real life they were gift book cutouts LOL, a worthwhile period drama based on a true story. It won the BAFTA Children's Award for Best Children's Film. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a Photograph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I watched this movie I was so tired that I slept through a part of it and didn't take in much of the other but from what I saw and from listening to others I picked up enough to comment on it. From what I heard this movie is based on some photographs taken in 1915 of some fairies. The photos could not be proved that they were faked and baffled a lot of people. What this movie has done is made the fairies real so as to create a child's movie. The plot is very thin but it is about people believing in fairies. The end comes with everybody seeing the evidence of the existence of fairies and believing in them. The thing is that the fairies play very little part in this movie and it is more focused on the children. The fairies never speak and interact with the children very rarely. This also seems to be an excuse to parade famous identities in the movie. We have Sir Arthur Conan Doyle and Harry Houdini as major characters in the movie and even show Houdini performing some of his escapes. Doyle is said to have written a book on fairies which my friend wanted to look for. He also said that the soundtrack was relaxing. They liked it but I slept and really had little interest in this movie. These fairies were the beautiful children fairies which I do not like, when it comes to fairies I like Faeries. What is the difference? Faeries are the more adult versions and appear in Mid-summer Night's Dream and Faerie Tale. These are much more vicious and hostile, especially Titania and Oberon in Midsummer Night's Dream. Those I love, Fairy Tale I don't. Oh well, each to his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enchanting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emswan2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie. I first learned of this story while studying the history of photography in college. The story is true, except... well- watch the movie. :) While by today's standards we would not be fooled by the photos, still the healing impact this news event had on society back then after the horrors of WWI and the peoples' willingness to believe it are certainly understandable and wonderful. The film is perfectly cast and perfectly acted and expertly edited. The girls are delightful. All characters are well expressed, including the parents, and the stories within the story are so very real, and touching. The is a lovely looking movie, with special effects that look convincingly real and made me wish they were. :-D Gather your loved ones around you and ENJOY this movie together!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undeniably charming; an absolutely delightful film for the whole family!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fairytale: A True Story is a truly charming and delightful film, that has all the charm of the enchanting Secret Garden and the equally wonderful Little Princess. The screenplay was very solid, and the film does look very, very beautiful, with perfect camera-work and splendid period detail. The simple but well-told story tells of two young girls who find and photograph fairies, and they manage to convince even Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (marvellously played by Peter O'Toole) that the fairies are real. The music was really lovely to listen to, and director Charles Sturridge manages to draw spirited (and exemplary) performances from his two leads Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl. The supporting cast include Paul McGann, Pheobe Nicolls and Harvey Keital, and all do more than a respectable job. Overall, a very pleasing and charming film, that does certainly leave you wanting fairies at the bottom of your garden, like the back of the video box promised. 10/10 Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made film about the two girls who claimed to have taken pictures of fairies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Enchanting and well acted,Fairytale A True Story tells the real life story of two cousins Elsie Wright(Florence Hoath)and Frances Griffiths(Elizabeth Earl)who in 1917 took some pictures that captivated the world and had England divided in discussion of their authenticity. Even more attention was drawn to them and their home when two very high profile and well known figures took an interest.They are Sir Arthur Conan Doyle(Peter O'Toole)the author best known for creating the character of Sherlock Holmes and his close friend the illusionist Harry Houdini(Harvey Keitel).Conan Doyle believes in what he sees 100 percent whereas Houdini is a little more sceptical(probably as he was the greatest illusionist the world had seen and wanted to see how they created the illusion of fairies).However tests on the photos proved them to be genuine.To this day people are still divided about whether they are pictures of real fairies or a clever and very impressive hoax.With a great cast including Paul MGann as Arthur Elsies father and Phoebe Nicholls as her mother who is grieving for her dead son(who claimed to have seen the fairies as well)moving and uplifting this is well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly Recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aimless-46
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Masters of illusion never reveal their secrets" says Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel) in the lyrical fantasy ''Fairytale--A True Story'' (1997). And pay attention to the things Houdini says like: "Never try to fool children. They expect nothing and therefore see everything", because his character exists to articulate the film's themes. These revolve around the need for many people to believe in the existence of spiritual concepts, the wisdom of not challenging these beliefs if they give sustenance, and how loss of the ability to see much that is hidden goes along with our loss of innocence. The innocence is stressed early in the film when an 8 year-old girl fearlessly seeks out a horribly scarred veteran on the train and gets "her corporal's" help to play a game of cat's cradle. In its best montage the film moves between, Houdini's fabled "The Chinese Water Torture Cell" illusion, a chess match, and the first-hand spiritual education of an investigative reporter. The film loosely documents the "Cottingley fairies" incident in 1917 when two English girls produced photographs that showed themselves in the presence of fairies. Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (insert Sherlock Holmes here) published the photographs when he and various experts became convinced they were authentic. Many years later the girls would confess that they had faked all but one of the photos, but they continued to claim that their fairies actually exist. 12-year-old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath) and 8-year-old Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) are the girls. It is late in WW1 and Francis has come to live with her Aunt and Uncle because her father is missing in action on the front lines. The Wright's too are dealing with a recent loss as Elsie's brother has passed away. So both children and Mrs. Wright (Phoebe Nicholls) are primed for belief in the other world. Yes there are fairies, the viewer sees them when no people are around and we see them leaving the area when Doyle's revelations cause the property to be trampled by a hoard of both believers and skeptics. The production design and the special effects are impressive and the film is absorbing from scene to scene. The target audience is a little hard to pin down as the subject is geared to children but much of the story a bit confusing if you are not already familiar with historical figures like Houdini and Doyle. The film utilizes the tried and true device for connecting with children by giving them a story about young people who know stuff is real, even though adults don't get it. In the film the age gap between the two girls is slightly less than it was in real life, which gives their relationship a bit more believability. Even more impressive is how successful the director was in the subtle creation two very distinct personalities. Elsie is shy and artistic. Frances is confident and social. Their interplay is the film's real strength; apparently the director sensed this dynamic and worked very hard in his acting for the camera direction of the two young actresses. He kept them in character and added behavioral elements they give their characters considerable depth and dimensionality. Then again, what do I know? I'm only a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A magical story behind the poorly directed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Efenstor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone who's deeply interested in folklore, as I dare to say I am, knows the story of the Fairies of Cottingley, it's one nearly-epic story of the two girls who inadvertently made a half of the world actually believe in magical creatures (I don't count children, for they did, they do and they will believe, and that's wondrous), and the best part of the epic is that they had never straightforwardly confessed that they've forged it just not to ruin people's glimpse of faith in magical. If that's what this movie should have been telling about then it certainly does not the job. Despite the wonderful and believable acting of Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl, the incoherent screenplay and direction ruin everything and only a shadow of the childhood magic remains in the dark corner pushed away by the social-drama clich&eacute;s (they even managed to insert there a villain and the goddammit comic relief!). And the top-notch CGI doesn't help out. There's more magic even in ghost-story movies, such as 'Lady in White' or 'The Changeling'. Worth watching, but only once. I deeply hope that some day someone will make a movie worthy of this story's spiritual background, so you'd understand why some perfectly sane people believe in fairies, even without the photographs. One of my favorite books is the collection of narrative tales, recorded in the middle of the 20th century among the Siberian villagers, mostly in the Chita region, by V.P. Zinovyev, and the thing I really love and adore in those stories is that those people actually believe all the folklore things they're speaking about! It's grievous that there are less and less such people live in this world, of that kind who believe because of the purity of the heart, not because of fear or passion. Some call those people dark and unenlightened, some laugh at them, but the thing they actually have is the faith, whilst everyone else have only a ghost of it. That who knows cannot believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It was simply a lovely, moving film. Tears flowed down my cheeks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjhan2
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd seen this film on DVD when it first came to the States,I saw it again last weekend on TV. I'd forgotten how much I loved it, I'm so glad I saw it again. It was so moving, I felt I wanted to believe in fairies and after seeing this film and the websites with pictures of them, who's to say there aren't any? I recommend this film to anyone, just keep an open mind and a box of tissues handy. The girls are so sweet, if only children were like that today, we would be so lucky! Harvey Keitel was a bit hard to believe as Houdini but he wasn't terrible and Peter O'Toole was wonderful as Sir Arthur Conan Doyle. The mother and father were just the ticket, I believed their performances entirely. If only we could make a film as lovely as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imaginary Playmate Comes Out Of The Wood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two little girls -- eight and twelve years old -- in rural Yorkshire get hold of their Dad's camera and return with pictures of stereotypical tiny fairies during World War One. The photos get into the hands of the Theosophical Society and then the press and cause a great to-do. Sir Arthur Conan-Doyle (O'Toole) and Houdini (Keitel) are swept up in the investigation. First things first. The two little girls are as cute as all get out. The older one is thoughtful and reserved. The younger one is expressive and whimsical. (The first will grow up loving wisely; the second will love too well.) The younger girl has even features and may grow up to be quite beautiful and well known if she decides to pursue an acting career. I can't remember the names of the actresses but both are splendid in their roles. How do you get kids that young to act so well on screen? At the same time, we have to be careful about believing the tales that kids bring us. Joan of Arc was only a teen ager, and St. Bernadette was fourteen when she had her visions. And let's not forget that the witch hunts of Salem, Massachusetts, were begun because of the fairy tales spun by a handful of girls the same age as the ones in this movie. So watch out. Okay. The second thing that impressed me is the location. Rarely has West (or North) Yorkshire looked so ravishing. It's summer and the hills are like slight sea swells, criss-crossed by stone walls. And the place where the girls claim to have found the fairies! It's tranquil, placid, languorous, bewitching. There's a trickling rill that spreads out and runs a few inches deep across flat gray rocks, in some spots forming miniature pools. Overhead are drooping branches. And it's all surrounded by light forests and fields of pale purple flowers. I'm telling you, if you lie too long next to that brook, especially in the light of a full moon, you too will be overcome by your collective unconscious and the sprites and elves will come fluttering forth. Of course the two little girls are frauds, but consider the times. For Europe, unlike America, the first war was a horrendous bloody catastrophe that accomplished nothing in the long run and had little cause in the first place. And in the previous generation, science seemed to have made great advances and offered up a challenge to belief in the supernatural -- meaning no afterlife, no heaven or hell, no nothing. Damned Darwin and Freud and their acolytes and bulldogs. Conan-Doyle had just lost a son pointlessly. It's no wonder the two little liars became sensations. Like the magic of the fairy home, mysticism was in the air. For a similar story from the same period, see "Miss Morrison's Ghosts." It's a slow movie, especially if you've recently been fed a diet of slam-bang action movies. It's done in a classical ("old-fashioned") style with a mostly still camera. Yet there are moments of tension and drama. And the acting is superb. Peter O'Toole is a very gentlemanly and sad Conan-Doyle. And Keitel -- who looks great in his stage make up as Houdini -- is the friendliest of skeptics. Supporting parts are well done and, as I say, it would be hard to improve upon the two girls. The only sour note is the villainous reporter (McInernny), a gawky and ambitious character with a long neck and tiny jaw who undergoes his own comic conversion. It all ends, appropriately, with dozens of fairies buzzing around like dragonflies, although they're all fakes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fairy Tale" Is a Movie Come True
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kgny309
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it comes to family movies, it has to be thoughtful, entertaining and capable enough to hold on to the audience between age 1 and 101. "Fairy Tale: A True Story" takes that challenge and it really succeeds. In 1917 England, two girls, Elsie {Florence Hoath} and her cousin Frances {Elizabeth Earl} discover real fairies in a garden. Later, they take photographs to give proof that the fairies are real. Soon, they become famous when Arthur Conan Doyle {Peter O'Toole} publishes the photos in Strand magazine. "Fairy Tale" has the conflict of Human vs. Fantasy. The conflict connects with the film's theme, which is you must believe it unless you see the real thing. The center of the film's story is Elsie and Frances. They're two girls who really see things as it happen. They grab our attention along with the story. Ernie Contreras's unpredictable script makes the characters feel as human beings, not as cardboard people. There's even a clich&eacute; in the film with a reporter trying to get the real story behind the photographs, but it never gets annoying. Plus, there's a subplot with Frances's missing father which is handled well. Hoath and Earl each give fine performances. The supporting roles are handled nicely with O'Toole as Doyle and Harvey Keitel as magician Harry Houdini. Zbigniew Preisner's score gives a dreamy feel to the proceedings and Shirley Russell's World War period costumes are luscious. Delightfully photographed and wonderfully acted, Charles Sturridge's film is a charming, perfect and winning family film. This is a movie come true for all ages. Rating: ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FairyTale: A True Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the title says, this film is apparently, loosely anyway, based on the real life story of Cottingley Fairies, this story of course turned out to be fake, but this film at least creates the sense of realism felt at the time by many people, from director Charles Sturridge (Lassie). Basically, set in the early 20th Century, England, during the time that electricity and photography had been invented, many people have their own particular beliefs and become fascinated with phenomenas, including writer and Sherlock Holmes creator Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (Peter O'Toole) and magician, escapologist and stunt performer Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel). The daughter of devoted father Arthur (Paul McGann) and mother Polly (Phoebe Nicholls) who is grieving for the death of the son, twelve year old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath), has kept her dead brother Joseph's scrapbooks and stuff that relate to fairies. She is joined by her cousin Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) who has come from abroad while her father goes into action during World War I, and the two of them become close friends, spending much of their time at the brook and near the stream. It is there that they supposedly occasionally see actual fairies, and borrowing Elsie's father's camera they capture two photographs of them together with these fairies, and these are meant as gifts for Polly. However she takes them to Theosophist lecturer Edward L. Gardner (Bill Nighy), who gets them analysed by a photography professional who can determine whether they are fake or not, and they are pronounced genuine, due to fairy wings moving. Many adults say that the girls could have faked the photographs, but more say that they may be real, including Conan-Doyle, and Houdini sees them too, and two more photographs taken allow publication in The Strand, creating a big buzz. The attention however comes from some unwanted sources, with hundreds of people crowding the village looking for fairies themselves, or the girls interacting with them, such as reporters, like John Ferret (Tim McInnerny). The girls have become celebrities when they travel to London, and they get to meet Houdini again, and see his water tank escape performance, and the film ends with him telling Elsie not to reveal anything, only to leave people to make their own minds up, there is a brief return from the fairies, and Frances' Father (Mel Gibson in a cameo) returns from war. Also starring Jurassic Park's Bob Peck as Harry Briggs, War Horse's Peter Mullan as Sergeant Farmer and Four Weddings and a Funeral's Anna Chancellor as Peter Pan. The acting is as good as you are going to get from terrific actors like Keitel, O'Toole and Nighy, and it is a pleasant story, obviously if you knew that the five captured photographs from the real girls were faked it would technically ruin your belief, but either way it is a nice tale that works with the fantasy element, and obviously the small special effects to create the fairies supposedly captured, of course in real life they were gift book cutouts LOL, a worthwhile period drama based on a true story. It won the BAFTA Children's Award for Best Children's Film. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a Photograph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I watched this movie I was so tired that I slept through a part of it and didn't take in much of the other but from what I saw and from listening to others I picked up enough to comment on it. From what I heard this movie is based on some photographs taken in 1915 of some fairies. The photos could not be proved that they were faked and baffled a lot of people. What this movie has done is made the fairies real so as to create a child's movie. The plot is very thin but it is about people believing in fairies. The end comes with everybody seeing the evidence of the existence of fairies and believing in them. The thing is that the fairies play very little part in this movie and it is more focused on the children. The fairies never speak and interact with the children very rarely. This also seems to be an excuse to parade famous identities in the movie. We have Sir Arthur Conan Doyle and Harry Houdini as major characters in the movie and even show Houdini performing some of his escapes. Doyle is said to have written a book on fairies which my friend wanted to look for. He also said that the soundtrack was relaxing. They liked it but I slept and really had little interest in this movie. These fairies were the beautiful children fairies which I do not like, when it comes to fairies I like Faeries. What is the difference? Faeries are the more adult versions and appear in Mid-summer Night's Dream and Faerie Tale. These are much more vicious and hostile, especially Titania and Oberon in Midsummer Night's Dream. Those I love, Fairy Tale I don't. Oh well, each to his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enchanting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emswan2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie. I first learned of this story while studying the history of photography in college. The story is true, except... well- watch the movie. :) While by today's standards we would not be fooled by the photos, still the healing impact this news event had on society back then after the horrors of WWI and the peoples' willingness to believe it are certainly understandable and wonderful. The film is perfectly cast and perfectly acted and expertly edited. The girls are delightful. All characters are well expressed, including the parents, and the stories within the story are so very real, and touching. The is a lovely looking movie, with special effects that look convincingly real and made me wish they were. :-D Gather your loved ones around you and ENJOY this movie together!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undeniably charming; an absolutely delightful film for the whole family!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fairytale: A True Story is a truly charming and delightful film, that has all the charm of the enchanting Secret Garden and the equally wonderful Little Princess. The screenplay was very solid, and the film does look very, very beautiful, with perfect camera-work and splendid period detail. The simple but well-told story tells of two young girls who find and photograph fairies, and they manage to convince even Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (marvellously played by Peter O'Toole) that the fairies are real. The music was really lovely to listen to, and director Charles Sturridge manages to draw spirited (and exemplary) performances from his two leads Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl. The supporting cast include Paul McGann, Pheobe Nicolls and Harvey Keital, and all do more than a respectable job. Overall, a very pleasing and charming film, that does certainly leave you wanting fairies at the bottom of your garden, like the back of the video box promised. 10/10 Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made film about the two girls who claimed to have taken pictures of fairies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Enchanting and well acted,Fairytale A True Story tells the real life story of two cousins Elsie Wright(Florence Hoath)and Frances Griffiths(Elizabeth Earl)who in 1917 took some pictures that captivated the world and had England divided in discussion of their authenticity. Even more attention was drawn to them and their home when two very high profile and well known figures took an interest.They are Sir Arthur Conan Doyle(Peter O'Toole)the author best known for creating the character of Sherlock Holmes and his close friend the illusionist Harry Houdini(Harvey Keitel).Conan Doyle believes in what he sees 100 percent whereas Houdini is a little more sceptical(probably as he was the greatest illusionist the world had seen and wanted to see how they created the illusion of fairies).However tests on the photos proved them to be genuine.To this day people are still divided about whether they are pictures of real fairies or a clever and very impressive hoax.With a great cast including Paul MGann as Arthur Elsies father and Phoebe Nicholls as her mother who is grieving for her dead son(who claimed to have seen the fairies as well)moving and uplifting this is well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly Recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aimless-46
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Masters of illusion never reveal their secrets" says Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel) in the lyrical fantasy ''Fairytale--A True Story'' (1997). And pay attention to the things Houdini says like: "Never try to fool children. They expect nothing and therefore see everything", because his character exists to articulate the film's themes. These revolve around the need for many people to believe in the existence of spiritual concepts, the wisdom of not challenging these beliefs if they give sustenance, and how loss of the ability to see much that is hidden goes along with our loss of innocence. The innocence is stressed early in the film when an 8 year-old girl fearlessly seeks out a horribly scarred veteran on the train and gets "her corporal's" help to play a game of cat's cradle. In its best montage the film moves between, Houdini's fabled "The Chinese Water Torture Cell" illusion, a chess match, and the first-hand spiritual education of an investigative reporter. The film loosely documents the "Cottingley fairies" incident in 1917 when two English girls produced photographs that showed themselves in the presence of fairies. Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (insert Sherlock Holmes here) published the photographs when he and various experts became convinced they were authentic. Many years later the girls would confess that they had faked all but one of the photos, but they continued to claim that their fairies actually exist. 12-year-old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath) and 8-year-old Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) are the girls. It is late in WW1 and Francis has come to live with her Aunt and Uncle because her father is missing in action on the front lines. The Wright's too are dealing with a recent loss as Elsie's brother has passed away. So both children and Mrs. Wright (Phoebe Nicholls) are primed for belief in the other world. Yes there are fairies, the viewer sees them when no people are around and we see them leaving the area when Doyle's revelations cause the property to be trampled by a hoard of both believers and skeptics. The production design and the special effects are impressive and the film is absorbing from scene to scene. The target audience is a little hard to pin down as the subject is geared to children but much of the story a bit confusing if you are not already familiar with historical figures like Houdini and Doyle. The film utilizes the tried and true device for connecting with children by giving them a story about young people who know stuff is real, even though adults don't get it. In the film the age gap between the two girls is slightly less than it was in real life, which gives their relationship a bit more believability. Even more impressive is how successful the director was in the subtle creation two very distinct personalities. Elsie is shy and artistic. Frances is confident and social. Their interplay is the film's real strength; apparently the director sensed this dynamic and worked very hard in his acting for the camera direction of the two young actresses. He kept them in character and added behavioral elements they give their characters considerable depth and dimensionality. Then again, what do I know? I'm only a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A magical story behind the poorly directed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Efenstor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone who's deeply interested in folklore, as I dare to say I am, knows the story of the Fairies of Cottingley, it's one nearly-epic story of the two girls who inadvertently made a half of the world actually believe in magical creatures (I don't count children, for they did, they do and they will believe, and that's wondrous), and the best part of the epic is that they had never straightforwardly confessed that they've forged it just not to ruin people's glimpse of faith in magical. If that's what this movie should have been telling about then it certainly does not the job. Despite the wonderful and believable acting of Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl, the incoherent screenplay and direction ruin everything and only a shadow of the childhood magic remains in the dark corner pushed away by the social-drama clich&eacute;s (they even managed to insert there a villain and the goddammit comic relief!). And the top-notch CGI doesn't help out. There's more magic even in ghost-story movies, such as 'Lady in White' or 'The Changeling'. Worth watching, but only once. I deeply hope that some day someone will make a movie worthy of this story's spiritual background, so you'd understand why some perfectly sane people believe in fairies, even without the photographs. One of my favorite books is the collection of narrative tales, recorded in the middle of the 20th century among the Siberian villagers, mostly in the Chita region, by V.P. Zinovyev, and the thing I really love and adore in those stories is that those people actually believe all the folklore things they're speaking about! It's grievous that there are less and less such people live in this world, of that kind who believe because of the purity of the heart, not because of fear or passion. Some call those people dark and unenlightened, some laugh at them, but the thing they actually have is the faith, whilst everyone else have only a ghost of it. That who knows cannot believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It was simply a lovely, moving film. Tears flowed down my cheeks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjhan2
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd seen this film on DVD when it first came to the States,I saw it again last weekend on TV. I'd forgotten how much I loved it, I'm so glad I saw it again. It was so moving, I felt I wanted to believe in fairies and after seeing this film and the websites with pictures of them, who's to say there aren't any? I recommend this film to anyone, just keep an open mind and a box of tissues handy. The girls are so sweet, if only children were like that today, we would be so lucky! Harvey Keitel was a bit hard to believe as Houdini but he wasn't terrible and Peter O'Toole was wonderful as Sir Arthur Conan Doyle. The mother and father were just the ticket, I believed their performances entirely. If only we could make a film as lovely as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imaginary Playmate Comes Out Of The Wood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two little girls -- eight and twelve years old -- in rural Yorkshire get hold of their Dad's camera and return with pictures of stereotypical tiny fairies during World War One. The photos get into the hands of the Theosophical Society and then the press and cause a great to-do. Sir Arthur Conan-Doyle (O'Toole) and Houdini (Keitel) are swept up in the investigation. First things first. The two little girls are as cute as all get out. The older one is thoughtful and reserved. The younger one is expressive and whimsical. (The first will grow up loving wisely; the second will love too well.) The younger girl has even features and may grow up to be quite beautiful and well known if she decides to pursue an acting career. I can't remember the names of the actresses but both are splendid in their roles. How do you get kids that young to act so well on screen? At the same time, we have to be careful about believing the tales that kids bring us. Joan of Arc was only a teen ager, and St. Bernadette was fourteen when she had her visions. And let's not forget that the witch hunts of Salem, Massachusetts, were begun because of the fairy tales spun by a handful of girls the same age as the ones in this movie. So watch out. Okay. The second thing that impressed me is the location. Rarely has West (or North) Yorkshire looked so ravishing. It's summer and the hills are like slight sea swells, criss-crossed by stone walls. And the place where the girls claim to have found the fairies! It's tranquil, placid, languorous, bewitching. There's a trickling rill that spreads out and runs a few inches deep across flat gray rocks, in some spots forming miniature pools. Overhead are drooping branches. And it's all surrounded by light forests and fields of pale purple flowers. I'm telling you, if you lie too long next to that brook, especially in the light of a full moon, you too will be overcome by your collective unconscious and the sprites and elves will come fluttering forth. Of course the two little girls are frauds, but consider the times. For Europe, unlike America, the first war was a horrendous bloody catastrophe that accomplished nothing in the long run and had little cause in the first place. And in the previous generation, science seemed to have made great advances and offered up a challenge to belief in the supernatural -- meaning no afterlife, no heaven or hell, no nothing. Damned Darwin and Freud and their acolytes and bulldogs. Conan-Doyle had just lost a son pointlessly. It's no wonder the two little liars became sensations. Like the magic of the fairy home, mysticism was in the air. For a similar story from the same period, see "Miss Morrison's Ghosts." It's a slow movie, especially if you've recently been fed a diet of slam-bang action movies. It's done in a classical ("old-fashioned") style with a mostly still camera. Yet there are moments of tension and drama. And the acting is superb. Peter O'Toole is a very gentlemanly and sad Conan-Doyle. And Keitel -- who looks great in his stage make up as Houdini -- is the friendliest of skeptics. Supporting parts are well done and, as I say, it would be hard to improve upon the two girls. The only sour note is the villainous reporter (McInernny), a gawky and ambitious character with a long neck and tiny jaw who undergoes his own comic conversion. It all ends, appropriately, with dozens of fairies buzzing around like dragonflies, although they're all fakes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fairy Tale" Is a Movie Come True
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kgny309
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it comes to family movies, it has to be thoughtful, entertaining and capable enough to hold on to the audience between age 1 and 101. "Fairy Tale: A True Story" takes that challenge and it really succeeds. In 1917 England, two girls, Elsie {Florence Hoath} and her cousin Frances {Elizabeth Earl} discover real fairies in a garden. Later, they take photographs to give proof that the fairies are real. Soon, they become famous when Arthur Conan Doyle {Peter O'Toole} publishes the photos in Strand magazine. "Fairy Tale" has the conflict of Human vs. Fantasy. The conflict connects with the film's theme, which is you must believe it unless you see the real thing. The center of the film's story is Elsie and Frances. They're two girls who really see things as it happen. They grab our attention along with the story. Ernie Contreras's unpredictable script makes the characters feel as human beings, not as cardboard people. There's even a clich&eacute; in the film with a reporter trying to get the real story behind the photographs, but it never gets annoying. Plus, there's a subplot with Frances's missing father which is handled well. Hoath and Earl each give fine performances. The supporting roles are handled nicely with O'Toole as Doyle and Harvey Keitel as magician Harry Houdini. Zbigniew Preisner's score gives a dreamy feel to the proceedings and Shirley Russell's World War period costumes are luscious. Delightfully photographed and wonderfully acted, Charles Sturridge's film is a charming, perfect and winning family film. This is a movie come true for all ages. Rating: ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FairyTale: A True Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the title says, this film is apparently, loosely anyway, based on the real life story of Cottingley Fairies, this story of course turned out to be fake, but this film at least creates the sense of realism felt at the time by many people, from director Charles Sturridge (Lassie). Basically, set in the early 20th Century, England, during the time that electricity and photography had been invented, many people have their own particular beliefs and become fascinated with phenomenas, including writer and Sherlock Holmes creator Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (Peter O'Toole) and magician, escapologist and stunt performer Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel). The daughter of devoted father Arthur (Paul McGann) and mother Polly (Phoebe Nicholls) who is grieving for the death of the son, twelve year old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath), has kept her dead brother Joseph's scrapbooks and stuff that relate to fairies. She is joined by her cousin Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) who has come from abroad while her father goes into action during World War I, and the two of them become close friends, spending much of their time at the brook and near the stream. It is there that they supposedly occasionally see actual fairies, and borrowing Elsie's father's camera they capture two photographs of them together with these fairies, and these are meant as gifts for Polly. However she takes them to Theosophist lecturer Edward L. Gardner (Bill Nighy), who gets them analysed by a photography professional who can determine whether they are fake or not, and they are pronounced genuine, due to fairy wings moving. Many adults say that the girls could have faked the photographs, but more say that they may be real, including Conan-Doyle, and Houdini sees them too, and two more photographs taken allow publication in The Strand, creating a big buzz. The attention however comes from some unwanted sources, with hundreds of people crowding the village looking for fairies themselves, or the girls interacting with them, such as reporters, like John Ferret (Tim McInnerny). The girls have become celebrities when they travel to London, and they get to meet Houdini again, and see his water tank escape performance, and the film ends with him telling Elsie not to reveal anything, only to leave people to make their own minds up, there is a brief return from the fairies, and Frances' Father (Mel Gibson in a cameo) returns from war. Also starring Jurassic Park's Bob Peck as Harry Briggs, War Horse's Peter Mullan as Sergeant Farmer and Four Weddings and a Funeral's Anna Chancellor as Peter Pan. The acting is as good as you are going to get from terrific actors like Keitel, O'Toole and Nighy, and it is a pleasant story, obviously if you knew that the five captured photographs from the real girls were faked it would technically ruin your belief, but either way it is a nice tale that works with the fantasy element, and obviously the small special effects to create the fairies supposedly captured, of course in real life they were gift book cutouts LOL, a worthwhile period drama based on a true story. It won the BAFTA Children's Award for Best Children's Film. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a Photograph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I watched this movie I was so tired that I slept through a part of it and didn't take in much of the other but from what I saw and from listening to others I picked up enough to comment on it. From what I heard this movie is based on some photographs taken in 1915 of some fairies. The photos could not be proved that they were faked and baffled a lot of people. What this movie has done is made the fairies real so as to create a child's movie. The plot is very thin but it is about people believing in fairies. The end comes with everybody seeing the evidence of the existence of fairies and believing in them. The thing is that the fairies play very little part in this movie and it is more focused on the children. The fairies never speak and interact with the children very rarely. This also seems to be an excuse to parade famous identities in the movie. We have Sir Arthur Conan Doyle and Harry Houdini as major characters in the movie and even show Houdini performing some of his escapes. Doyle is said to have written a book on fairies which my friend wanted to look for. He also said that the soundtrack was relaxing. They liked it but I slept and really had little interest in this movie. These fairies were the beautiful children fairies which I do not like, when it comes to fairies I like Faeries. What is the difference? Faeries are the more adult versions and appear in Mid-summer Night's Dream and Faerie Tale. These are much more vicious and hostile, especially Titania and Oberon in Midsummer Night's Dream. Those I love, Fairy Tale I don't. Oh well, each to his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enchanting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emswan2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie. I first learned of this story while studying the history of photography in college. The story is true, except... well- watch the movie. :) While by today's standards we would not be fooled by the photos, still the healing impact this news event had on society back then after the horrors of WWI and the peoples' willingness to believe it are certainly understandable and wonderful. The film is perfectly cast and perfectly acted and expertly edited. The girls are delightful. All characters are well expressed, including the parents, and the stories within the story are so very real, and touching. The is a lovely looking movie, with special effects that look convincingly real and made me wish they were. :-D Gather your loved ones around you and ENJOY this movie together!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undeniably charming; an absolutely delightful film for the whole family!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fairytale: A True Story is a truly charming and delightful film, that has all the charm of the enchanting Secret Garden and the equally wonderful Little Princess. The screenplay was very solid, and the film does look very, very beautiful, with perfect camera-work and splendid period detail. The simple but well-told story tells of two young girls who find and photograph fairies, and they manage to convince even Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (marvellously played by Peter O'Toole) that the fairies are real. The music was really lovely to listen to, and director Charles Sturridge manages to draw spirited (and exemplary) performances from his two leads Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl. The supporting cast include Paul McGann, Pheobe Nicolls and Harvey Keital, and all do more than a respectable job. Overall, a very pleasing and charming film, that does certainly leave you wanting fairies at the bottom of your garden, like the back of the video box promised. 10/10 Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made film about the two girls who claimed to have taken pictures of fairies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Enchanting and well acted,Fairytale A True Story tells the real life story of two cousins Elsie Wright(Florence Hoath)and Frances Griffiths(Elizabeth Earl)who in 1917 took some pictures that captivated the world and had England divided in discussion of their authenticity. Even more attention was drawn to them and their home when two very high profile and well known figures took an interest.They are Sir Arthur Conan Doyle(Peter O'Toole)the author best known for creating the character of Sherlock Holmes and his close friend the illusionist Harry Houdini(Harvey Keitel).Conan Doyle believes in what he sees 100 percent whereas Houdini is a little more sceptical(probably as he was the greatest illusionist the world had seen and wanted to see how they created the illusion of fairies).However tests on the photos proved them to be genuine.To this day people are still divided about whether they are pictures of real fairies or a clever and very impressive hoax.With a great cast including Paul MGann as Arthur Elsies father and Phoebe Nicholls as her mother who is grieving for her dead son(who claimed to have seen the fairies as well)moving and uplifting this is well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly Recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aimless-46
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Masters of illusion never reveal their secrets" says Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel) in the lyrical fantasy ''Fairytale--A True Story'' (1997). And pay attention to the things Houdini says like: "Never try to fool children. They expect nothing and therefore see everything", because his character exists to articulate the film's themes. These revolve around the need for many people to believe in the existence of spiritual concepts, the wisdom of not challenging these beliefs if they give sustenance, and how loss of the ability to see much that is hidden goes along with our loss of innocence. The innocence is stressed early in the film when an 8 year-old girl fearlessly seeks out a horribly scarred veteran on the train and gets "her corporal's" help to play a game of cat's cradle. In its best montage the film moves between, Houdini's fabled "The Chinese Water Torture Cell" illusion, a chess match, and the first-hand spiritual education of an investigative reporter. The film loosely documents the "Cottingley fairies" incident in 1917 when two English girls produced photographs that showed themselves in the presence of fairies. Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (insert Sherlock Holmes here) published the photographs when he and various experts became convinced they were authentic. Many years later the girls would confess that they had faked all but one of the photos, but they continued to claim that their fairies actually exist. 12-year-old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath) and 8-year-old Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) are the girls. It is late in WW1 and Francis has come to live with her Aunt and Uncle because her father is missing in action on the front lines. The Wright's too are dealing with a recent loss as Elsie's brother has passed away. So both children and Mrs. Wright (Phoebe Nicholls) are primed for belief in the other world. Yes there are fairies, the viewer sees them when no people are around and we see them leaving the area when Doyle's revelations cause the property to be trampled by a hoard of both believers and skeptics. The production design and the special effects are impressive and the film is absorbing from scene to scene. The target audience is a little hard to pin down as the subject is geared to children but much of the story a bit confusing if you are not already familiar with historical figures like Houdini and Doyle. The film utilizes the tried and true device for connecting with children by giving them a story about young people who know stuff is real, even though adults don't get it. In the film the age gap between the two girls is slightly less than it was in real life, which gives their relationship a bit more believability. Even more impressive is how successful the director was in the subtle creation two very distinct personalities. Elsie is shy and artistic. Frances is confident and social. Their interplay is the film's real strength; apparently the director sensed this dynamic and worked very hard in his acting for the camera direction of the two young actresses. He kept them in character and added behavioral elements they give their characters considerable depth and dimensionality. Then again, what do I know? I'm only a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A magical story behind the poorly directed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Efenstor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone who's deeply interested in folklore, as I dare to say I am, knows the story of the Fairies of Cottingley, it's one nearly-epic story of the two girls who inadvertently made a half of the world actually believe in magical creatures (I don't count children, for they did, they do and they will believe, and that's wondrous), and the best part of the epic is that they had never straightforwardly confessed that they've forged it just not to ruin people's glimpse of faith in magical. If that's what this movie should have been telling about then it certainly does not the job. Despite the wonderful and believable acting of Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl, the incoherent screenplay and direction ruin everything and only a shadow of the childhood magic remains in the dark corner pushed away by the social-drama clich&eacute;s (they even managed to insert there a villain and the goddammit comic relief!). And the top-notch CGI doesn't help out. There's more magic even in ghost-story movies, such as 'Lady in White' or 'The Changeling'. Worth watching, but only once. I deeply hope that some day someone will make a movie worthy of this story's spiritual background, so you'd understand why some perfectly sane people believe in fairies, even without the photographs. One of my favorite books is the collection of narrative tales, recorded in the middle of the 20th century among the Siberian villagers, mostly in the Chita region, by V.P. Zinovyev, and the thing I really love and adore in those stories is that those people actually believe all the folklore things they're speaking about! It's grievous that there are less and less such people live in this world, of that kind who believe because of the purity of the heart, not because of fear or passion. Some call those people dark and unenlightened, some laugh at them, but the thing they actually have is the faith, whilst everyone else have only a ghost of it. That who knows cannot believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It was simply a lovely, moving film. Tears flowed down my cheeks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjhan2
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd seen this film on DVD when it first came to the States,I saw it again last weekend on TV. I'd forgotten how much I loved it, I'm so glad I saw it again. It was so moving, I felt I wanted to believe in fairies and after seeing this film and the websites with pictures of them, who's to say there aren't any? I recommend this film to anyone, just keep an open mind and a box of tissues handy. The girls are so sweet, if only children were like that today, we would be so lucky! Harvey Keitel was a bit hard to believe as Houdini but he wasn't terrible and Peter O'Toole was wonderful as Sir Arthur Conan Doyle. The mother and father were just the ticket, I believed their performances entirely. If only we could make a film as lovely as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imaginary Playmate Comes Out Of The Wood.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two little girls -- eight and twelve years old -- in rural Yorkshire get hold of their Dad's camera and return with pictures of stereotypical tiny fairies during World War One. The photos get into the hands of the Theosophical Society and then the press and cause a great to-do. Sir Arthur Conan-Doyle (O'Toole) and Houdini (Keitel) are swept up in the investigation. First things first. The two little girls are as cute as all get out. The older one is thoughtful and reserved. The younger one is expressive and whimsical. (The first will grow up loving wisely; the second will love too well.) The younger girl has even features and may grow up to be quite beautiful and well known if she decides to pursue an acting career. I can't remember the names of the actresses but both are splendid in their roles. How do you get kids that young to act so well on screen? At the same time, we have to be careful about believing the tales that kids bring us. Joan of Arc was only a teen ager, and St. Bernadette was fourteen when she had her visions. And let's not forget that the witch hunts of Salem, Massachusetts, were begun because of the fairy tales spun by a handful of girls the same age as the ones in this movie. So watch out. Okay. The second thing that impressed me is the location. Rarely has West (or North) Yorkshire looked so ravishing. It's summer and the hills are like slight sea swells, criss-crossed by stone walls. And the place where the girls claim to have found the fairies! It's tranquil, placid, languorous, bewitching. There's a trickling rill that spreads out and runs a few inches deep across flat gray rocks, in some spots forming miniature pools. Overhead are drooping branches. And it's all surrounded by light forests and fields of pale purple flowers. I'm telling you, if you lie too long next to that brook, especially in the light of a full moon, you too will be overcome by your collective unconscious and the sprites and elves will come fluttering forth. Of course the two little girls are frauds, but consider the times. For Europe, unlike America, the first war was a horrendous bloody catastrophe that accomplished nothing in the long run and had little cause in the first place. And in the previous generation, science seemed to have made great advances and offered up a challenge to belief in the supernatural -- meaning no afterlife, no heaven or hell, no nothing. Damned Darwin and Freud and their acolytes and bulldogs. Conan-Doyle had just lost a son pointlessly. It's no wonder the two little liars became sensations. Like the magic of the fairy home, mysticism was in the air. For a similar story from the same period, see "Miss Morrison's Ghosts." It's a slow movie, especially if you've recently been fed a diet of slam-bang action movies. It's done in a classical ("old-fashioned") style with a mostly still camera. Yet there are moments of tension and drama. And the acting is superb. Peter O'Toole is a very gentlemanly and sad Conan-Doyle. And Keitel -- who looks great in his stage make up as Houdini -- is the friendliest of skeptics. Supporting parts are well done and, as I say, it would be hard to improve upon the two girls. The only sour note is the villainous reporter (McInernny), a gawky and ambitious character with a long neck and tiny jaw who undergoes his own comic conversion. It all ends, appropriately, with dozens of fairies buzzing around like dragonflies, although they're all fakes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fairy Tale" Is a Movie Come True
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kgny309
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it comes to family movies, it has to be thoughtful, entertaining and capable enough to hold on to the audience between age 1 and 101. "Fairy Tale: A True Story" takes that challenge and it really succeeds. In 1917 England, two girls, Elsie {Florence Hoath} and her cousin Frances {Elizabeth Earl} discover real fairies in a garden. Later, they take photographs to give proof that the fairies are real. Soon, they become famous when Arthur Conan Doyle {Peter O'Toole} publishes the photos in Strand magazine. "Fairy Tale" has the conflict of Human vs. Fantasy. The conflict connects with the film's theme, which is you must believe it unless you see the real thing. The center of the film's story is Elsie and Frances. They're two girls who really see things as it happen. They grab our attention along with the story. Ernie Contreras's unpredictable script makes the characters feel as human beings, not as cardboard people. There's even a clich&eacute; in the film with a reporter trying to get the real story behind the photographs, but it never gets annoying. Plus, there's a subplot with Frances's missing father which is handled well. Hoath and Earl each give fine performances. The supporting roles are handled nicely with O'Toole as Doyle and Harvey Keitel as magician Harry Houdini. Zbigniew Preisner's score gives a dreamy feel to the proceedings and Shirley Russell's World War period costumes are luscious. Delightfully photographed and wonderfully acted, Charles Sturridge's film is a charming, perfect and winning family film. This is a movie come true for all ages. Rating: ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FairyTale: A True Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the title says, this film is apparently, loosely anyway, based on the real life story of Cottingley Fairies, this story of course turned out to be fake, but this film at least creates the sense of realism felt at the time by many people, from director Charles Sturridge (Lassie). Basically, set in the early 20th Century, England, during the time that electricity and photography had been invented, many people have their own particular beliefs and become fascinated with phenomenas, including writer and Sherlock Holmes creator Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (Peter O'Toole) and magician, escapologist and stunt performer Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel). The daughter of devoted father Arthur (Paul McGann) and mother Polly (Phoebe Nicholls) who is grieving for the death of the son, twelve year old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath), has kept her dead brother Joseph's scrapbooks and stuff that relate to fairies. She is joined by her cousin Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) who has come from abroad while her father goes into action during World War I, and the two of them become close friends, spending much of their time at the brook and near the stream. It is there that they supposedly occasionally see actual fairies, and borrowing Elsie's father's camera they capture two photographs of them together with these fairies, and these are meant as gifts for Polly. However she takes them to Theosophist lecturer Edward L. Gardner (Bill Nighy), who gets them analysed by a photography professional who can determine whether they are fake or not, and they are pronounced genuine, due to fairy wings moving. Many adults say that the girls could have faked the photographs, but more say that they may be real, including Conan-Doyle, and Houdini sees them too, and two more photographs taken allow publication in The Strand, creating a big buzz. The attention however comes from some unwanted sources, with hundreds of people crowding the village looking for fairies themselves, or the girls interacting with them, such as reporters, like John Ferret (Tim McInnerny). The girls have become celebrities when they travel to London, and they get to meet Houdini again, and see his water tank escape performance, and the film ends with him telling Elsie not to reveal anything, only to leave people to make their own minds up, there is a brief return from the fairies, and Frances' Father (Mel Gibson in a cameo) returns from war. Also starring Jurassic Park's Bob Peck as Harry Briggs, War Horse's Peter Mullan as Sergeant Farmer and Four Weddings and a Funeral's Anna Chancellor as Peter Pan. The acting is as good as you are going to get from terrific actors like Keitel, O'Toole and Nighy, and it is a pleasant story, obviously if you knew that the five captured photographs from the real girls were faked it would technically ruin your belief, but either way it is a nice tale that works with the fantasy element, and obviously the small special effects to create the fairies supposedly captured, of course in real life they were gift book cutouts LOL, a worthwhile period drama based on a true story. It won the BAFTA Children's Award for Best Children's Film. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a Photograph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I watched this movie I was so tired that I slept through a part of it and didn't take in much of the other but from what I saw and from listening to others I picked up enough to comment on it. From what I heard this movie is based on some photographs taken in 1915 of some fairies. The photos could not be proved that they were faked and baffled a lot of people. What this movie has done is made the fairies real so as to create a child's movie. The plot is very thin but it is about people believing in fairies. The end comes with everybody seeing the evidence of the existence of fairies and believing in them. The thing is that the fairies play very little part in this movie and it is more focused on the children. The fairies never speak and interact with the children very rarely. This also seems to be an excuse to parade famous identities in the movie. We have Sir Arthur Conan Doyle and Harry Houdini as major characters in the movie and even show Houdini performing some of his escapes. Doyle is said to have written a book on fairies which my friend wanted to look for. He also said that the soundtrack was relaxing. They liked it but I slept and really had little interest in this movie. These fairies were the beautiful children fairies which I do not like, when it comes to fairies I like Faeries. What is the difference? Faeries are the more adult versions and appear in Mid-summer Night's Dream and Faerie Tale. These are much more vicious and hostile, especially Titania and Oberon in Midsummer Night's Dream. Those I love, Fairy Tale I don't. Oh well, each to his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enchanting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emswan2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie. I first learned of this story while studying the history of photography in college. The story is true, except... well- watch the movie. :) While by today's standards we would not be fooled by the photos, still the healing impact this news event had on society back then after the horrors of WWI and the peoples' willingness to believe it are certainly understandable and wonderful. The film is perfectly cast and perfectly acted and expertly edited. The girls are delightful. All characters are well expressed, including the parents, and the stories within the story are so very real, and touching. The is a lovely looking movie, with special effects that look convincingly real and made me wish they were. :-D Gather your loved ones around you and ENJOY this movie together!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undeniably charming; an absolutely delightful film for the whole family!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fairytale: A True Story is a truly charming and delightful film, that has all the charm of the enchanting Secret Garden and the equally wonderful Little Princess. The screenplay was very solid, and the film does look very, very beautiful, with perfect camera-work and splendid period detail. The simple but well-told story tells of two young girls who find and photograph fairies, and they manage to convince even Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (marvellously played by Peter O'Toole) that the fairies are real. The music was really lovely to listen to, and director Charles Sturridge manages to draw spirited (and exemplary) performances from his two leads Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl. The supporting cast include Paul McGann, Pheobe Nicolls and Harvey Keital, and all do more than a respectable job. Overall, a very pleasing and charming film, that does certainly leave you wanting fairies at the bottom of your garden, like the back of the video box promised. 10/10 Bethany Cox.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made film about the two girls who claimed to have taken pictures of fairies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Enchanting and well acted,Fairytale A True Story tells the real life story of two cousins Elsie Wright(Florence Hoath)and Frances Griffiths(Elizabeth Earl)who in 1917 took some pictures that captivated the world and had England divided in discussion of their authenticity. Even more attention was drawn to them and their home when two very high profile and well known figures took an interest.They are Sir Arthur Conan Doyle(Peter O'Toole)the author best known for creating the character of Sherlock Holmes and his close friend the illusionist Harry Houdini(Harvey Keitel).Conan Doyle believes in what he sees 100 percent whereas Houdini is a little more sceptical(probably as he was the greatest illusionist the world had seen and wanted to see how they created the illusion of fairies).However tests on the photos proved them to be genuine.To this day people are still divided about whether they are pictures of real fairies or a clever and very impressive hoax.With a great cast including Paul MGann as Arthur Elsies father and Phoebe Nicholls as her mother who is grieving for her dead son(who claimed to have seen the fairies as well)moving and uplifting this is well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly Recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aimless-46
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Masters of illusion never reveal their secrets" says Harry Houdini (Harvey Keitel) in the lyrical fantasy ''Fairytale--A True Story'' (1997). And pay attention to the things Houdini says like: "Never try to fool children. They expect nothing and therefore see everything", because his character exists to articulate the film's themes. These revolve around the need for many people to believe in the existence of spiritual concepts, the wisdom of not challenging these beliefs if they give sustenance, and how loss of the ability to see much that is hidden goes along with our loss of innocence. The innocence is stressed early in the film when an 8 year-old girl fearlessly seeks out a horribly scarred veteran on the train and gets "her corporal's" help to play a game of cat's cradle. In its best montage the film moves between, Houdini's fabled "The Chinese Water Torture Cell" illusion, a chess match, and the first-hand spiritual education of an investigative reporter. The film loosely documents the "Cottingley fairies" incident in 1917 when two English girls produced photographs that showed themselves in the presence of fairies. Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (insert Sherlock Holmes here) published the photographs when he and various experts became convinced they were authentic. Many years later the girls would confess that they had faked all but one of the photos, but they continued to claim that their fairies actually exist. 12-year-old Elsie Wright (Florence Hoath) and 8-year-old Frances Griffiths (Elizabeth Earl) are the girls. It is late in WW1 and Francis has come to live with her Aunt and Uncle because her father is missing in action on the front lines. The Wright's too are dealing with a recent loss as Elsie's brother has passed away. So both children and Mrs. Wright (Phoebe Nicholls) are primed for belief in the other world. Yes there are fairies, the viewer sees them when no people are around and we see them leaving the area when Doyle's revelations cause the property to be trampled by a hoard of both believers and skeptics. The production design and the special effects are impressive and the film is absorbing from scene to scene. The target audience is a little hard to pin down as the subject is geared to children but much of the story a bit confusing if you are not already familiar with historical figures like Houdini and Doyle. The film utilizes the tried and true device for connecting with children by giving them a story about young people who know stuff is real, even though adults don't get it. In the film the age gap between the two girls is slightly less than it was in real life, which gives their relationship a bit more believability. Even more impressive is how successful the director was in the subtle creation two very distinct personalities. Elsie is shy and artistic. Frances is confident and social. Their interplay is the film's real strength; apparently the director sensed this dynamic and worked very hard in his acting for the camera direction of the two young actresses. He kept them in character and added behavioral elements they give their characters considerable depth and dimensionality. Then again, what do I know? I'm only a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A magical story behind the poorly directed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Efenstor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone who's deeply interested in folklore, as I dare to say I am, knows the story of the Fairies of Cottingley, it's one nearly-epic story of the two girls who inadvertently made a half of the world actually believe in magical creatures (I don't count children, for they did, they do and they will believe, and that's wondrous), and the best part of the epic is that they had never straightforwardly confessed that they've forged it just not to ruin people's glimpse of faith in magical. If that's what this movie should have been telling about then it certainly does not the job. Despite the wonderful and believable acting of Florence Hoath and Elizabeth Earl, the incoherent screenplay and direction ruin everything and only a shadow of the childhood magic remains in the dark corner pushed away by the social-drama clich&eacute;s (they even managed to insert there a villain and the goddammit comic relief!). And the top-notch CGI doesn't help out. There's more magic even in ghost-story movies, such as 'Lady in White' or 'The Changeling'. Worth watching, but only once. I deeply hope that some day someone will make a movie worthy of this story's spiritual background, so you'd understand why some perfectly sane people believe in fairies, even without the photographs. One of my favorite books is the collection of narrative tales, recorded in the middle of the 20th century among the Siberian villagers, mostly in the Chita region, by V.P. Zinovyev, and the thing I really love and adore in those stories is that those people actually believe all the folklore things they're speaking about! It's grievous that there are less and less such people live in this world, of that kind who believe because of the purity of the heart, not because of fear or passion. Some call those people dark and unenlightened, some laugh at them, but the thing they actually have is the faith, whilst everyone else have only a ghost of it. That who knows cannot believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It was simply a lovely, moving film. Tears flowed down my cheeks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjhan2
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd seen this film on DVD when it first came to the States,I saw it again last weekend on TV. I'd forgotten how much I loved it, I'm so glad I saw it again. It was so moving, I felt I wanted to believe in fairies and after seeing this film and the websites with pictures of them, who's to say there aren't any? I recommend this film to anyone, just keep an open mind and a box of tissues handy. The girls are so sweet, if only children were like that today, we would be so lucky! Harvey Keitel was a bit hard to believe as Houdini but he wasn't terrible and Peter O'Toole was wonderful as Sir Arthur Conan Doyle. The mother and father were just the ticket, I believed their performances entirely. If only we could make a film as lovely as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
