<filme>
 <id>
  311
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120520
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Asas do Amor
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An impoverished woman who has been forced to choose between a privileged life with her wealthy aunt and her journalist lover, befriends an American heiress. When she discovers the heiress is attracted to her own lover and is dying, she sees a chance to have both the privileged life she cannot give up and the lover she cannot live without.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Kate Croy's mother was born to wealth and privilege, but she threw it all away to marry Kate's father, a penniless opium addict who admits to having stolen from his wife. After her mother's death, Kate is offered an opportunity to return to the life her mother gave up. There is a condition, however: Kate must sever all of her old ties, not only to her father, but also to her lover, the muck-raking journalist Merton Densher, whom she has promised marriage. Kate reluctantly agrees to this, and in the meantime becomes friendly with "the world's richest orphan," Millie Theale, an American making the Grand Tour. Desperate to see Kate, Merton crashes a party that she and Millie are attending, and Millie is attracted to him. When Kate learns that Millie is dying, she comes up with a plan to have her cake and eat it too...but all does not go as planned.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   american
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   journalist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   heiress
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   party
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   poverty
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Iain Softley
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Henry James
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Hossein Amini
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Helena Bonham Carter
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Linus Roache
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Alex Jennings
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Corrupt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Henry James novel, Kate Croy (Helena Bonham Carter)'s mother was born to wealth, but she threw it all away to marry Kate's opium addicted father. After her mother's death, Kate is offered a return to privilege. Of course, she must abandon her father, and her fianc&eacute;, journalist Merton Densher (Linus Roache). When she becomes friend with sick wealthy orphan Millie Theale (Alison Elliott), Kate sees an opportunity to get back with Merton and keep her position. It's a real murky portrait of the London class system, and how money corrupts the characters in this movie. The scheming is heart breaking. It's moral ambiguity is delicious. Helena Bonham Carter puts in a multi-dimensional performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kaleko
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great film to watch when you are feeling a little melancholy and want to be taken away somewhere else- Somewhere far away, and subdued. It was a slow yet enjoyable film. I would say that some might find it boring. It is true that the plot is fairly simple, and you have to wait a while for the few twists and turns it has. Though, it does always have something interesting going on, and the pace is decent for what it is. But if you don't enjoy long cerebral romances and period films, you probably won't enjoy this. I have to say it was visually appealing. This helps the film from becoming boring. Also the two leading ladies are gorgeous. You see the beauty of darkness in Kate and the beauty of sunshine in Millie- like night and day. I must agree fully with Lord Mark's comment about Kate's eyes. What was great about this film was the acting, presentation, mood, and lesson. Okay spoiler time, because I'd like to share my opinions on what happened. What I took away from this film is that it is not a good idea to persuade your love, for whatever reason, to be with another, even if it seems like a good idea at the time! Ha. Though I fully sympathized with Kate. She wasn't the sociopath that you often see in stories like this. She actually did care for Millie, and it seemed that she tried to convince herself that it would actually be good for Millie, at first. Although, the way she did try to break them up was a little heartless to her friend. But you can understand how it would be difficult for her to find any other way to do it. I suppose she could have admitted it to Millie herself, but I would think she might be too ashamed to do this. And anyways, she did say "this is the first time I didn't feel bad for her." She was jealous, and whilst at first she may not have expected herself to feel jealous, I think we can all understand the lack of sympathy we might have for someone if we did truly become jealous of them. So it is a little understandable that she would have hurt her friend. Besides, her friend would have been hurt anyway if she knew the truth with whatever way she found out, and she did deserve to know it. The best part for me was the ending where she was turned away by Merton. (By the way, did anyone else notice how at the end, Kate laid in the same position as the woman in the painting she asked Millie to look at?) I didn't fully expect her to be rejected. But it did make sense afterwards, as he was faced with a truly good human being, and felt so wretched about what he and Kate did to Millie, and finally realized that Kate wasn't such a great person after all. I think he was put off by the selfishness in Kate's final demand. I think if she hadn't requested that, he might have let bygones be bygones. But seriously, one can understand why she felt hurt and worried about throwing away so much to pursue this "true" love that she wasn't sure still existed. She was worried she already lost him to another woman and missed his undying singular commitment to her. But I can see why Merton would be so offended. Her request really did speak of an ignorance and uncaring about his feelings which may have developed, which were all her fault to begin with. I honestly thought it was a little silly for Kate to make her final demand. I mean honestly, she loved Millie and she should have realized that it was only natural to love such a great person. Besides, it's not like she would truly be a threat any more, 6 feet under! All things fade with time. Kate was honest with him about her feelings and intentions, so I don't think that Merton should have turned her away due to a lack of trust. Especially since she did change her mind in the end about going through with the plan. But I do suppose he could have resented the fact that she wanted money so badly, or acted so selfishly, or lied at all, and would have never known whether she was with him for his money after he got it. I suppose that was where his demand came from. But the fact she agreed to marry him should have been enough. He should have called her silly when she brought up her side of the bargain, and admitted that yes he loved the memory of Millie, just as Kate found herself loving her. I mean come on, Millie was an easy person to love, and Kate should have understood that. Besides, if Kate truly just wanted Merton for the money, she wouldn't have made her request. But really, they probably did need some time apart. I think that later on, they probably would find themselves back together after they had healed from the experience. One last thing I wanted to mention - The scene where Merton was crying was amazing. I don't think I've ever seen such a realistic portrayal of a man crying on screen before. He really nailed that one, and I felt very sympathetic to the feelings he was portraying. Anyway, it really was a wonderful film. It was very grey in its portrayal of the goodness and badness of the characters, which I like, and which isn't easy to do. It also made you think. I only downgraded it a bit because the storyline, while nicely portrayed, wasn't anything really spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wings of the Dove
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British period drama cannot be a bad alternative for a flushing upsurge of my Febiofest movie-goers' schedule. Nominated for 4 Oscars (Leading Actress, Cinematography, Costume and Adapted Screenplay), TWOTD represents a paradigmatic melodrama study of love, conspiracy, betrayal and passion, meanwhile mildly bashes the mercenary vanity then, all converges to a superior satisfactory coda. Venice part is memorably shot as an enchanting last journey to enjoy the fullest of one's life, an engaging score from Edward Shearmur firstly accompanies the film with a soothing pace, then adheres to the dramatic rotation aptly all the way along. The most striking caliber of the film is indisputably the acting stretch, Helena Bonham Carter is magnetically absorbing in her puberty of mixing brisk gal, smart aleck manipulator and sophisticated lovelorn victim, her career-best so far. A terrifically undervalued Alison Elliott radiates an unassumingly captivating rendition with both vulnerability and playfulness (she and Helena currently end up No. 2 and No. 1 in my Oscar chart for supporting and leading actress respectively). To juggle with these two vehement lovebirds, Linus Roache (the alien form THE FORGOTTEN 2005) may be tread the water a little bit frivolously, with a moral criterion swinging back and forth ambiguously, he tackles the most tricky part heedfully. The nudity scene near its finale is theatrically robust in delivering a love-lost denouement and generates poignant pathos. The minor satellites revolving around are all British old hands, Rampling. Gambon are too skimpy on screen, while McGovern's sedately elegant attendance is never histrionic. Adapted from Henry James' novel of the the same name, this Neo-classical piece has an imposing buzz on its own merit, some might deem it a shad mawkish, but I'm confidently not among that breed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich, beautiful, subtle, special--Henry James not far from where he'd like it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove (1997) Yes, this is a quite, indirect, thoughtful movie. But it is never slow. And the acting is incredible, almost as incredible as all the dresses and interior sets, which will blow anyone's mind. The story, by Henry James (the master of indirect but probing feelings), is about love of all kinds. And about being a good person, really. Three of the four main leads struggle with doing the right thing (and they do the right thing). The fourth struggles, falters, then comes forward again, then falters, finally, by making a demand that can never be met. It's unfair to compare this kind of period movie (set around 1910 even though James's book was published in 1902) to "A Room with a View" (set in the same decade) but the reason this happens is that the 1985 Merchant-Ivory masterpiece seemed to open up a new way of making period films, filled with beauty and lingering thoughts and, well, feeling. Not the feeling two people have for each other, but a feeling of a time and place. It so happens the star of this 1997 film, Helena Bonham Carter, also starred (magnificently) in the first one. The other star is a man, Linus Roache, who almost overplays his understated character by making him dry and deadpan and polite. But it works, over time, to help make the final few seconds of the film (which are so important) succeed. The third lead, really, in this lopsided triangle, is Alison Elliott, who puts in an equally subtle performance. So much of the movie is about little changes in facial expression, the acting had to rise to the needs of the plot. Bonham Carter, above all, does this with chilling perfection. But those dresses! This is what is called Edwardian England, the first decade of the 20th Century, a time when modernity swept Europe with a passion (Picasso and Klimt) and when cars and other new technologies were surging. The styles of the dresses are part Art Nouveau, with its Asian influences, and part European excess, a showing off of style and wealth and material sensibility. Thank god! It's just breathtaking. The interiors are likewise brimming with tiles and flowers and paintings and light of all kinds. All of this is handled with a cinematic control that reminds me of the color coordination of mid-century Technicolor films, where the palette of a scene is often limited to a pair of colors. You'll see many scenes where a mix of blue and rusty orange are the only two colors in various guises (and these are most common because of the hair and eyes of Elliott). The cinematography is by Eduardo Serra, one of a handful of the most sumptuous contemporary shooters in film ("Girl with the Pearl Earring" and "What Dreams May Come"). And he lets the light and color inhabit every scene, never letting the photography get in the way. Just beautiful. So what does it mean to be a good person? Who cares with all this great acting and beautiful filming? But really, you do care, and it's a touching and provoking film in all its quietness. And it's not a bit obscure. Henry James never quite liked the book, but I think it's because he expected more from it, the themes and characters are so promising. Critics have come to see it as one of his great late novels, and that much is here. Director Iain Softley takes a couple of turns that the book avoids--a little sensational talk toward the beginning, and a frank and sex scene at the end--and both are okay in the film but not actually in keeping with the tone of the rest of it, which is about never quite showing your hand even to your closest friends. It's about waiting to speak, and hiding even good intentions for fear of seeming good when in fact part of being good is simply being good, not merely seeming it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and tragic beyond measure, put it on your view list right this very minute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kate (Helena Bonham Carter) is a young woman in love with a poor journalist, Merton (Linus Roache). Its Edwardian England and, having no money of her own, Kate lives with a wealthy aunt (Charlotte Rampling) who is avid to marry Kate well. Thus, the beautiful lady will not be free to wed Merton or any man of her choosing, if he doesn't have the goods. They meet secretly and passionately, even arranging a clandestine trip to Italy. Once there, the two cross paths with an extremely wealthy American, Millie (Alison Elliott) who casts her eye on Merton. Since neither Kate nor Merton have revealed that they are a couple, a difficult triangle is created, for Millie also chooses Kate as a friend. This becomes even more complex when the British duo learn that Millie, despite being young and beautiful, is incredibly ill with a respiratory ailment. Temptation arrives. What would happen, Kate asks Merton, if HE romances Millie, marries her and inherits her wealth upon her death? Why, the secret lovers would be set for life! Merton is appalled at the idea of making advances on a dying girl but, eventually, gives in. What neither Kate or Merton count on is the young gentleman's growing attraction to Millie, for she is sweet and funny as well as very lovely. Is tragedy in the future for this trio? Unfortunately, yes. This stunningly gorgeous film, based on the novel of Henry James, is a superior piece of movie making that cannot be denied. The three actors, Bonham Carter, Roache, and Elliott are extremely compelling in their difficult roles and all of the lesser cast members do fine work, too. Then, the setting in Italy, mostly, is lovely, with cinematography of the very finest. Costumes, too, are gorgeous, especially Elliott's garments and accessories. But, naturally, it is the powerful story of love and deception, with tragic results, that is the strongest asset of all. It should be stated that there are a couple of explicitly sexual scenes that might upset a few viewers. But, for the majority of film fans, they will be accepted as a necessary part of the story's elements. If you have never picked up this film, don't delay! Wings of the Dove is a soaring achievement that should be seen by everyone who loves great cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unforgettable story of love and desire set in Edwardian England.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the classic novel by Henry James,Iain Softley's 1997 adaptation features one of Helena Bonham Carters best performances,an ending that will stick in your memory long after the films finished and breathtaking period costumes designed by Sandy Powell.A timeless love story blighted by restrictions of class and money which will move you like no other. London 1910,spirited and beautiful Kate Croy(Helena Bonham Carter)is deeply in love with kind hearted but penniless journalist Merton Densher(Linus Roache).However since Kate became the ward of her wealthy aunt Maude(Charlotte Rampling)she now has no choice but to consider her financial position at all times.Especially as her aunt sends money to her alcoholic father Lionel(Michael Gambon).This drives a wedge between Kate and Merton and she soon finds herself being courted by the wealthy Lord Mark(Alex Jennings). When Kate befriends the outgoing yet fragile Millie Theale(Alison Elliott)she hatches a plan to get her to leave her fortune to Merton by bringing the two together knowing Millie is seriously ill and may die.However the plan backfires when Milton visits the women in Venice and really does come to care for Millie and falls in love with her. And so begins Kates quest to try and reclaim Mertons heart even though it may now completely belong to Millie.A haunting love story with beautiful location work and memorable performances,Wings Of The Dove will stay with you long after it's over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deception, Love, Jealousy in 1910
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove is a sinister, fascinating love story. Helena Bonham Carter plays Kate Croy, an ambitious but poor young woman who lives on the generosity of a rich aunt. Unable to live poor but not wanting to surrender to the husband her aunt is trying to find for her, she hatches a genius and simple plan: to let her boyfriend, Merton Densher (Linus Roache) seduce the rich and dying American millionaire Millie (Alison Elliott) so that she will leave all her money to him. Carter shines in this movie and her performance is one of the main reasons to watch it. It's one of those rare performances in which all the character's thoughts and feelings are transmitted by the eyes; Carter's eyes are always expressive, she barely needs any dialogue. And yet Hossein Amini's screenplay is also one of the brighter aspects of the movie. I cannot judge ho well he adapted the novel since I haven't yet read it, but as a movie it's a joy: each dialogue is essential, precise and enjoyable; no words are wasted or out of place. The movie's pacing is constant, deceptively calm but always filled with tension, for deception is pretty much the theme of the movie: how far will someone go to deceive another, and what effect will it have on them? For Merton the moral consequences of the deception haunt him as he realizes he may be falling in love with Millie, whereas Kate fears she may be losing her beloved's affection. Between this strange dynamic we have the innocent, cheerful Millie. The movie is also a fine period piece: Sandy Powell got a a much-deserved Oscar nomination for the costume design, but in truth all aspects of the movie deserve merit for their recreation of England in 1910. This movie takes us to places period movies seldom do: the underground system; the interior of bookshops and opium-dens; the interior of museums (in a wonderful sequence the characters attend a Klimt exhibition). And then there's the way Eduardo Serra's cinematography captures Venice in 1910. Serra is an under-appreciated director of cinematography, although he's left his mark in many memorable movies. His best work perhaps remains this movie, in particular the segment taking place in Venice. The way he captures the old canals, the gondolas, the colors at night during Carnival, the decay of the buildings, the beauty of the monuments, perhaps surpass the classic Death In Venice. The Wings of the Dove was a pleasant surprise, an underrated movie that caught me completely by surprise with its perfection. Although it was nominated for several Oscars back in 1998, it seems time has forgotten it. That's a pity, but for those who dare to give it a look, it'll be a huge source of joy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Did Someone Say Henry James -- Please Wait While I Shoot Myself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inevitable question will be: is "The Wings of the Dove" faithful to its source material? I, alas, can't answer that question for you, because to me Henry James's novel was 800 pages of random words strung together in ways that resembled sentences but made absolutely no other kind of sense. I'd rather be bludgeoned to death with one of his books than ever have to read another one -- the movie version could have featured transvestite cyborgs for all I cared; as long as I wasn't actually having to read it, I was a happy boy. The film is pretty good, about what you'd expect from a period piece based on a famous literary classic. It's got more pizazz than a Merchant-Ivory production, and boasts a great performance from a Merchant-Ivory regular, Helena Bonham Carter. It's nothing special, but probably worth a watch. Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helena Bonham Carter's Best Received Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although neither of them had anything to do with "Wings of the Dove," it reminded me strongly of the string of Merchant-Ivory films. It's a period film, based on a famous novel (by Henry James), set in gorgeous locations (London and Venice), with magnificent costuming and a largely English cast led by Helena Bonham Carter, who graced many a Merchant-Ivory film. "Wings of the Dove" is widely regarded as her finest performance. It earned an Oscar nomination. Although she lost out to Helen Hunt, many critics thought she deserved the honor more. Here she plays Kate Croy, the impoverished niece of her wealthy Aunt Maude (Charlotte Rampling) in love with a handsome, impecunious radical (Linus Roache) and decidedly not in love with her Aunt's choice, Lord Mark (Alex Jennings). I won't give away the scheme that is at the root of the story but Bonham Carter is both distinctively beautiful and a powerful actress. Only Rampling holds her own -- in a much less prominent role, although Michael Gambon in a small part as Kate's ne'er do well father is excellent (as always). Subsequent to "Wings of the Dove," Bonham Carter drifted in the direction of films (the Harry Potter series, for example) that failed to utilize her enormous talent or take full advantage of her slightly unusual but distinctive beauty. She's still young enough to make a big splash at some point in the future but she seems to have lost the urge to make the most of her considerable talent. If so, this film, which she made at the age of 31, may turn out in retrospect to have been her career high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You think love is sexual chemistry, think again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (zfiany@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie which might be overlooked for the romantic side of it because some people tend to judge a movie as trash if it is about romance. Well, I agree but not all romantic movies are the same. There are romantic movies that have messages which go beyond the emotion of love to the twin emotions jealousy, envy, sexual desires, respect, humanity, sacred love, pain and many others. All these feelings you can still experience in a romantic movie cooked well. Wings of dove is a movie with a plot and actually there is a part in the middle of the movie where if you pay attention carefully you might be able to understand what's going on before the story starts revealing its chapters. Actors are great; Helena Bonham Carter is indeed good in this role and Alison Elliotte is just as good and even better. Linus Roache also knows how to exhibit his transmitting emotions in a brilliant way. He knew how to play the difference which is a thin line between love and desire. You only have to guess whom he loved and whom he desired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Corrupt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Henry James novel, Kate Croy (Helena Bonham Carter)'s mother was born to wealth, but she threw it all away to marry Kate's opium addicted father. After her mother's death, Kate is offered a return to privilege. Of course, she must abandon her father, and her fianc&eacute;, journalist Merton Densher (Linus Roache). When she becomes friend with sick wealthy orphan Millie Theale (Alison Elliott), Kate sees an opportunity to get back with Merton and keep her position. It's a real murky portrait of the London class system, and how money corrupts the characters in this movie. The scheming is heart breaking. It's moral ambiguity is delicious. Helena Bonham Carter puts in a multi-dimensional performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kaleko
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great film to watch when you are feeling a little melancholy and want to be taken away somewhere else- Somewhere far away, and subdued. It was a slow yet enjoyable film. I would say that some might find it boring. It is true that the plot is fairly simple, and you have to wait a while for the few twists and turns it has. Though, it does always have something interesting going on, and the pace is decent for what it is. But if you don't enjoy long cerebral romances and period films, you probably won't enjoy this. I have to say it was visually appealing. This helps the film from becoming boring. Also the two leading ladies are gorgeous. You see the beauty of darkness in Kate and the beauty of sunshine in Millie- like night and day. I must agree fully with Lord Mark's comment about Kate's eyes. What was great about this film was the acting, presentation, mood, and lesson. Okay spoiler time, because I'd like to share my opinions on what happened. What I took away from this film is that it is not a good idea to persuade your love, for whatever reason, to be with another, even if it seems like a good idea at the time! Ha. Though I fully sympathized with Kate. She wasn't the sociopath that you often see in stories like this. She actually did care for Millie, and it seemed that she tried to convince herself that it would actually be good for Millie, at first. Although, the way she did try to break them up was a little heartless to her friend. But you can understand how it would be difficult for her to find any other way to do it. I suppose she could have admitted it to Millie herself, but I would think she might be too ashamed to do this. And anyways, she did say "this is the first time I didn't feel bad for her." She was jealous, and whilst at first she may not have expected herself to feel jealous, I think we can all understand the lack of sympathy we might have for someone if we did truly become jealous of them. So it is a little understandable that she would have hurt her friend. Besides, her friend would have been hurt anyway if she knew the truth with whatever way she found out, and she did deserve to know it. The best part for me was the ending where she was turned away by Merton. (By the way, did anyone else notice how at the end, Kate laid in the same position as the woman in the painting she asked Millie to look at?) I didn't fully expect her to be rejected. But it did make sense afterwards, as he was faced with a truly good human being, and felt so wretched about what he and Kate did to Millie, and finally realized that Kate wasn't such a great person after all. I think he was put off by the selfishness in Kate's final demand. I think if she hadn't requested that, he might have let bygones be bygones. But seriously, one can understand why she felt hurt and worried about throwing away so much to pursue this "true" love that she wasn't sure still existed. She was worried she already lost him to another woman and missed his undying singular commitment to her. But I can see why Merton would be so offended. Her request really did speak of an ignorance and uncaring about his feelings which may have developed, which were all her fault to begin with. I honestly thought it was a little silly for Kate to make her final demand. I mean honestly, she loved Millie and she should have realized that it was only natural to love such a great person. Besides, it's not like she would truly be a threat any more, 6 feet under! All things fade with time. Kate was honest with him about her feelings and intentions, so I don't think that Merton should have turned her away due to a lack of trust. Especially since she did change her mind in the end about going through with the plan. But I do suppose he could have resented the fact that she wanted money so badly, or acted so selfishly, or lied at all, and would have never known whether she was with him for his money after he got it. I suppose that was where his demand came from. But the fact she agreed to marry him should have been enough. He should have called her silly when she brought up her side of the bargain, and admitted that yes he loved the memory of Millie, just as Kate found herself loving her. I mean come on, Millie was an easy person to love, and Kate should have understood that. Besides, if Kate truly just wanted Merton for the money, she wouldn't have made her request. But really, they probably did need some time apart. I think that later on, they probably would find themselves back together after they had healed from the experience. One last thing I wanted to mention - The scene where Merton was crying was amazing. I don't think I've ever seen such a realistic portrayal of a man crying on screen before. He really nailed that one, and I felt very sympathetic to the feelings he was portraying. Anyway, it really was a wonderful film. It was very grey in its portrayal of the goodness and badness of the characters, which I like, and which isn't easy to do. It also made you think. I only downgraded it a bit because the storyline, while nicely portrayed, wasn't anything really spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wings of the Dove
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British period drama cannot be a bad alternative for a flushing upsurge of my Febiofest movie-goers' schedule. Nominated for 4 Oscars (Leading Actress, Cinematography, Costume and Adapted Screenplay), TWOTD represents a paradigmatic melodrama study of love, conspiracy, betrayal and passion, meanwhile mildly bashes the mercenary vanity then, all converges to a superior satisfactory coda. Venice part is memorably shot as an enchanting last journey to enjoy the fullest of one's life, an engaging score from Edward Shearmur firstly accompanies the film with a soothing pace, then adheres to the dramatic rotation aptly all the way along. The most striking caliber of the film is indisputably the acting stretch, Helena Bonham Carter is magnetically absorbing in her puberty of mixing brisk gal, smart aleck manipulator and sophisticated lovelorn victim, her career-best so far. A terrifically undervalued Alison Elliott radiates an unassumingly captivating rendition with both vulnerability and playfulness (she and Helena currently end up No. 2 and No. 1 in my Oscar chart for supporting and leading actress respectively). To juggle with these two vehement lovebirds, Linus Roache (the alien form THE FORGOTTEN 2005) may be tread the water a little bit frivolously, with a moral criterion swinging back and forth ambiguously, he tackles the most tricky part heedfully. The nudity scene near its finale is theatrically robust in delivering a love-lost denouement and generates poignant pathos. The minor satellites revolving around are all British old hands, Rampling. Gambon are too skimpy on screen, while McGovern's sedately elegant attendance is never histrionic. Adapted from Henry James' novel of the the same name, this Neo-classical piece has an imposing buzz on its own merit, some might deem it a shad mawkish, but I'm confidently not among that breed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich, beautiful, subtle, special--Henry James not far from where he'd like it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove (1997) Yes, this is a quite, indirect, thoughtful movie. But it is never slow. And the acting is incredible, almost as incredible as all the dresses and interior sets, which will blow anyone's mind. The story, by Henry James (the master of indirect but probing feelings), is about love of all kinds. And about being a good person, really. Three of the four main leads struggle with doing the right thing (and they do the right thing). The fourth struggles, falters, then comes forward again, then falters, finally, by making a demand that can never be met. It's unfair to compare this kind of period movie (set around 1910 even though James's book was published in 1902) to "A Room with a View" (set in the same decade) but the reason this happens is that the 1985 Merchant-Ivory masterpiece seemed to open up a new way of making period films, filled with beauty and lingering thoughts and, well, feeling. Not the feeling two people have for each other, but a feeling of a time and place. It so happens the star of this 1997 film, Helena Bonham Carter, also starred (magnificently) in the first one. The other star is a man, Linus Roache, who almost overplays his understated character by making him dry and deadpan and polite. But it works, over time, to help make the final few seconds of the film (which are so important) succeed. The third lead, really, in this lopsided triangle, is Alison Elliott, who puts in an equally subtle performance. So much of the movie is about little changes in facial expression, the acting had to rise to the needs of the plot. Bonham Carter, above all, does this with chilling perfection. But those dresses! This is what is called Edwardian England, the first decade of the 20th Century, a time when modernity swept Europe with a passion (Picasso and Klimt) and when cars and other new technologies were surging. The styles of the dresses are part Art Nouveau, with its Asian influences, and part European excess, a showing off of style and wealth and material sensibility. Thank god! It's just breathtaking. The interiors are likewise brimming with tiles and flowers and paintings and light of all kinds. All of this is handled with a cinematic control that reminds me of the color coordination of mid-century Technicolor films, where the palette of a scene is often limited to a pair of colors. You'll see many scenes where a mix of blue and rusty orange are the only two colors in various guises (and these are most common because of the hair and eyes of Elliott). The cinematography is by Eduardo Serra, one of a handful of the most sumptuous contemporary shooters in film ("Girl with the Pearl Earring" and "What Dreams May Come"). And he lets the light and color inhabit every scene, never letting the photography get in the way. Just beautiful. So what does it mean to be a good person? Who cares with all this great acting and beautiful filming? But really, you do care, and it's a touching and provoking film in all its quietness. And it's not a bit obscure. Henry James never quite liked the book, but I think it's because he expected more from it, the themes and characters are so promising. Critics have come to see it as one of his great late novels, and that much is here. Director Iain Softley takes a couple of turns that the book avoids--a little sensational talk toward the beginning, and a frank and sex scene at the end--and both are okay in the film but not actually in keeping with the tone of the rest of it, which is about never quite showing your hand even to your closest friends. It's about waiting to speak, and hiding even good intentions for fear of seeming good when in fact part of being good is simply being good, not merely seeming it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and tragic beyond measure, put it on your view list right this very minute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kate (Helena Bonham Carter) is a young woman in love with a poor journalist, Merton (Linus Roache). Its Edwardian England and, having no money of her own, Kate lives with a wealthy aunt (Charlotte Rampling) who is avid to marry Kate well. Thus, the beautiful lady will not be free to wed Merton or any man of her choosing, if he doesn't have the goods. They meet secretly and passionately, even arranging a clandestine trip to Italy. Once there, the two cross paths with an extremely wealthy American, Millie (Alison Elliott) who casts her eye on Merton. Since neither Kate nor Merton have revealed that they are a couple, a difficult triangle is created, for Millie also chooses Kate as a friend. This becomes even more complex when the British duo learn that Millie, despite being young and beautiful, is incredibly ill with a respiratory ailment. Temptation arrives. What would happen, Kate asks Merton, if HE romances Millie, marries her and inherits her wealth upon her death? Why, the secret lovers would be set for life! Merton is appalled at the idea of making advances on a dying girl but, eventually, gives in. What neither Kate or Merton count on is the young gentleman's growing attraction to Millie, for she is sweet and funny as well as very lovely. Is tragedy in the future for this trio? Unfortunately, yes. This stunningly gorgeous film, based on the novel of Henry James, is a superior piece of movie making that cannot be denied. The three actors, Bonham Carter, Roache, and Elliott are extremely compelling in their difficult roles and all of the lesser cast members do fine work, too. Then, the setting in Italy, mostly, is lovely, with cinematography of the very finest. Costumes, too, are gorgeous, especially Elliott's garments and accessories. But, naturally, it is the powerful story of love and deception, with tragic results, that is the strongest asset of all. It should be stated that there are a couple of explicitly sexual scenes that might upset a few viewers. But, for the majority of film fans, they will be accepted as a necessary part of the story's elements. If you have never picked up this film, don't delay! Wings of the Dove is a soaring achievement that should be seen by everyone who loves great cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unforgettable story of love and desire set in Edwardian England.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the classic novel by Henry James,Iain Softley's 1997 adaptation features one of Helena Bonham Carters best performances,an ending that will stick in your memory long after the films finished and breathtaking period costumes designed by Sandy Powell.A timeless love story blighted by restrictions of class and money which will move you like no other. London 1910,spirited and beautiful Kate Croy(Helena Bonham Carter)is deeply in love with kind hearted but penniless journalist Merton Densher(Linus Roache).However since Kate became the ward of her wealthy aunt Maude(Charlotte Rampling)she now has no choice but to consider her financial position at all times.Especially as her aunt sends money to her alcoholic father Lionel(Michael Gambon).This drives a wedge between Kate and Merton and she soon finds herself being courted by the wealthy Lord Mark(Alex Jennings). When Kate befriends the outgoing yet fragile Millie Theale(Alison Elliott)she hatches a plan to get her to leave her fortune to Merton by bringing the two together knowing Millie is seriously ill and may die.However the plan backfires when Milton visits the women in Venice and really does come to care for Millie and falls in love with her. And so begins Kates quest to try and reclaim Mertons heart even though it may now completely belong to Millie.A haunting love story with beautiful location work and memorable performances,Wings Of The Dove will stay with you long after it's over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deception, Love, Jealousy in 1910
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove is a sinister, fascinating love story. Helena Bonham Carter plays Kate Croy, an ambitious but poor young woman who lives on the generosity of a rich aunt. Unable to live poor but not wanting to surrender to the husband her aunt is trying to find for her, she hatches a genius and simple plan: to let her boyfriend, Merton Densher (Linus Roache) seduce the rich and dying American millionaire Millie (Alison Elliott) so that she will leave all her money to him. Carter shines in this movie and her performance is one of the main reasons to watch it. It's one of those rare performances in which all the character's thoughts and feelings are transmitted by the eyes; Carter's eyes are always expressive, she barely needs any dialogue. And yet Hossein Amini's screenplay is also one of the brighter aspects of the movie. I cannot judge ho well he adapted the novel since I haven't yet read it, but as a movie it's a joy: each dialogue is essential, precise and enjoyable; no words are wasted or out of place. The movie's pacing is constant, deceptively calm but always filled with tension, for deception is pretty much the theme of the movie: how far will someone go to deceive another, and what effect will it have on them? For Merton the moral consequences of the deception haunt him as he realizes he may be falling in love with Millie, whereas Kate fears she may be losing her beloved's affection. Between this strange dynamic we have the innocent, cheerful Millie. The movie is also a fine period piece: Sandy Powell got a a much-deserved Oscar nomination for the costume design, but in truth all aspects of the movie deserve merit for their recreation of England in 1910. This movie takes us to places period movies seldom do: the underground system; the interior of bookshops and opium-dens; the interior of museums (in a wonderful sequence the characters attend a Klimt exhibition). And then there's the way Eduardo Serra's cinematography captures Venice in 1910. Serra is an under-appreciated director of cinematography, although he's left his mark in many memorable movies. His best work perhaps remains this movie, in particular the segment taking place in Venice. The way he captures the old canals, the gondolas, the colors at night during Carnival, the decay of the buildings, the beauty of the monuments, perhaps surpass the classic Death In Venice. The Wings of the Dove was a pleasant surprise, an underrated movie that caught me completely by surprise with its perfection. Although it was nominated for several Oscars back in 1998, it seems time has forgotten it. That's a pity, but for those who dare to give it a look, it'll be a huge source of joy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Did Someone Say Henry James -- Please Wait While I Shoot Myself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inevitable question will be: is "The Wings of the Dove" faithful to its source material? I, alas, can't answer that question for you, because to me Henry James's novel was 800 pages of random words strung together in ways that resembled sentences but made absolutely no other kind of sense. I'd rather be bludgeoned to death with one of his books than ever have to read another one -- the movie version could have featured transvestite cyborgs for all I cared; as long as I wasn't actually having to read it, I was a happy boy. The film is pretty good, about what you'd expect from a period piece based on a famous literary classic. It's got more pizazz than a Merchant-Ivory production, and boasts a great performance from a Merchant-Ivory regular, Helena Bonham Carter. It's nothing special, but probably worth a watch. Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helena Bonham Carter's Best Received Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although neither of them had anything to do with "Wings of the Dove," it reminded me strongly of the string of Merchant-Ivory films. It's a period film, based on a famous novel (by Henry James), set in gorgeous locations (London and Venice), with magnificent costuming and a largely English cast led by Helena Bonham Carter, who graced many a Merchant-Ivory film. "Wings of the Dove" is widely regarded as her finest performance. It earned an Oscar nomination. Although she lost out to Helen Hunt, many critics thought she deserved the honor more. Here she plays Kate Croy, the impoverished niece of her wealthy Aunt Maude (Charlotte Rampling) in love with a handsome, impecunious radical (Linus Roache) and decidedly not in love with her Aunt's choice, Lord Mark (Alex Jennings). I won't give away the scheme that is at the root of the story but Bonham Carter is both distinctively beautiful and a powerful actress. Only Rampling holds her own -- in a much less prominent role, although Michael Gambon in a small part as Kate's ne'er do well father is excellent (as always). Subsequent to "Wings of the Dove," Bonham Carter drifted in the direction of films (the Harry Potter series, for example) that failed to utilize her enormous talent or take full advantage of her slightly unusual but distinctive beauty. She's still young enough to make a big splash at some point in the future but she seems to have lost the urge to make the most of her considerable talent. If so, this film, which she made at the age of 31, may turn out in retrospect to have been her career high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You think love is sexual chemistry, think again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (zfiany@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie which might be overlooked for the romantic side of it because some people tend to judge a movie as trash if it is about romance. Well, I agree but not all romantic movies are the same. There are romantic movies that have messages which go beyond the emotion of love to the twin emotions jealousy, envy, sexual desires, respect, humanity, sacred love, pain and many others. All these feelings you can still experience in a romantic movie cooked well. Wings of dove is a movie with a plot and actually there is a part in the middle of the movie where if you pay attention carefully you might be able to understand what's going on before the story starts revealing its chapters. Actors are great; Helena Bonham Carter is indeed good in this role and Alison Elliotte is just as good and even better. Linus Roache also knows how to exhibit his transmitting emotions in a brilliant way. He knew how to play the difference which is a thin line between love and desire. You only have to guess whom he loved and whom he desired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Corrupt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Henry James novel, Kate Croy (Helena Bonham Carter)'s mother was born to wealth, but she threw it all away to marry Kate's opium addicted father. After her mother's death, Kate is offered a return to privilege. Of course, she must abandon her father, and her fianc&eacute;, journalist Merton Densher (Linus Roache). When she becomes friend with sick wealthy orphan Millie Theale (Alison Elliott), Kate sees an opportunity to get back with Merton and keep her position. It's a real murky portrait of the London class system, and how money corrupts the characters in this movie. The scheming is heart breaking. It's moral ambiguity is delicious. Helena Bonham Carter puts in a multi-dimensional performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kaleko
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great film to watch when you are feeling a little melancholy and want to be taken away somewhere else- Somewhere far away, and subdued. It was a slow yet enjoyable film. I would say that some might find it boring. It is true that the plot is fairly simple, and you have to wait a while for the few twists and turns it has. Though, it does always have something interesting going on, and the pace is decent for what it is. But if you don't enjoy long cerebral romances and period films, you probably won't enjoy this. I have to say it was visually appealing. This helps the film from becoming boring. Also the two leading ladies are gorgeous. You see the beauty of darkness in Kate and the beauty of sunshine in Millie- like night and day. I must agree fully with Lord Mark's comment about Kate's eyes. What was great about this film was the acting, presentation, mood, and lesson. Okay spoiler time, because I'd like to share my opinions on what happened. What I took away from this film is that it is not a good idea to persuade your love, for whatever reason, to be with another, even if it seems like a good idea at the time! Ha. Though I fully sympathized with Kate. She wasn't the sociopath that you often see in stories like this. She actually did care for Millie, and it seemed that she tried to convince herself that it would actually be good for Millie, at first. Although, the way she did try to break them up was a little heartless to her friend. But you can understand how it would be difficult for her to find any other way to do it. I suppose she could have admitted it to Millie herself, but I would think she might be too ashamed to do this. And anyways, she did say "this is the first time I didn't feel bad for her." She was jealous, and whilst at first she may not have expected herself to feel jealous, I think we can all understand the lack of sympathy we might have for someone if we did truly become jealous of them. So it is a little understandable that she would have hurt her friend. Besides, her friend would have been hurt anyway if she knew the truth with whatever way she found out, and she did deserve to know it. The best part for me was the ending where she was turned away by Merton. (By the way, did anyone else notice how at the end, Kate laid in the same position as the woman in the painting she asked Millie to look at?) I didn't fully expect her to be rejected. But it did make sense afterwards, as he was faced with a truly good human being, and felt so wretched about what he and Kate did to Millie, and finally realized that Kate wasn't such a great person after all. I think he was put off by the selfishness in Kate's final demand. I think if she hadn't requested that, he might have let bygones be bygones. But seriously, one can understand why she felt hurt and worried about throwing away so much to pursue this "true" love that she wasn't sure still existed. She was worried she already lost him to another woman and missed his undying singular commitment to her. But I can see why Merton would be so offended. Her request really did speak of an ignorance and uncaring about his feelings which may have developed, which were all her fault to begin with. I honestly thought it was a little silly for Kate to make her final demand. I mean honestly, she loved Millie and she should have realized that it was only natural to love such a great person. Besides, it's not like she would truly be a threat any more, 6 feet under! All things fade with time. Kate was honest with him about her feelings and intentions, so I don't think that Merton should have turned her away due to a lack of trust. Especially since she did change her mind in the end about going through with the plan. But I do suppose he could have resented the fact that she wanted money so badly, or acted so selfishly, or lied at all, and would have never known whether she was with him for his money after he got it. I suppose that was where his demand came from. But the fact she agreed to marry him should have been enough. He should have called her silly when she brought up her side of the bargain, and admitted that yes he loved the memory of Millie, just as Kate found herself loving her. I mean come on, Millie was an easy person to love, and Kate should have understood that. Besides, if Kate truly just wanted Merton for the money, she wouldn't have made her request. But really, they probably did need some time apart. I think that later on, they probably would find themselves back together after they had healed from the experience. One last thing I wanted to mention - The scene where Merton was crying was amazing. I don't think I've ever seen such a realistic portrayal of a man crying on screen before. He really nailed that one, and I felt very sympathetic to the feelings he was portraying. Anyway, it really was a wonderful film. It was very grey in its portrayal of the goodness and badness of the characters, which I like, and which isn't easy to do. It also made you think. I only downgraded it a bit because the storyline, while nicely portrayed, wasn't anything really spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wings of the Dove
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British period drama cannot be a bad alternative for a flushing upsurge of my Febiofest movie-goers' schedule. Nominated for 4 Oscars (Leading Actress, Cinematography, Costume and Adapted Screenplay), TWOTD represents a paradigmatic melodrama study of love, conspiracy, betrayal and passion, meanwhile mildly bashes the mercenary vanity then, all converges to a superior satisfactory coda. Venice part is memorably shot as an enchanting last journey to enjoy the fullest of one's life, an engaging score from Edward Shearmur firstly accompanies the film with a soothing pace, then adheres to the dramatic rotation aptly all the way along. The most striking caliber of the film is indisputably the acting stretch, Helena Bonham Carter is magnetically absorbing in her puberty of mixing brisk gal, smart aleck manipulator and sophisticated lovelorn victim, her career-best so far. A terrifically undervalued Alison Elliott radiates an unassumingly captivating rendition with both vulnerability and playfulness (she and Helena currently end up No. 2 and No. 1 in my Oscar chart for supporting and leading actress respectively). To juggle with these two vehement lovebirds, Linus Roache (the alien form THE FORGOTTEN 2005) may be tread the water a little bit frivolously, with a moral criterion swinging back and forth ambiguously, he tackles the most tricky part heedfully. The nudity scene near its finale is theatrically robust in delivering a love-lost denouement and generates poignant pathos. The minor satellites revolving around are all British old hands, Rampling. Gambon are too skimpy on screen, while McGovern's sedately elegant attendance is never histrionic. Adapted from Henry James' novel of the the same name, this Neo-classical piece has an imposing buzz on its own merit, some might deem it a shad mawkish, but I'm confidently not among that breed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich, beautiful, subtle, special--Henry James not far from where he'd like it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove (1997) Yes, this is a quite, indirect, thoughtful movie. But it is never slow. And the acting is incredible, almost as incredible as all the dresses and interior sets, which will blow anyone's mind. The story, by Henry James (the master of indirect but probing feelings), is about love of all kinds. And about being a good person, really. Three of the four main leads struggle with doing the right thing (and they do the right thing). The fourth struggles, falters, then comes forward again, then falters, finally, by making a demand that can never be met. It's unfair to compare this kind of period movie (set around 1910 even though James's book was published in 1902) to "A Room with a View" (set in the same decade) but the reason this happens is that the 1985 Merchant-Ivory masterpiece seemed to open up a new way of making period films, filled with beauty and lingering thoughts and, well, feeling. Not the feeling two people have for each other, but a feeling of a time and place. It so happens the star of this 1997 film, Helena Bonham Carter, also starred (magnificently) in the first one. The other star is a man, Linus Roache, who almost overplays his understated character by making him dry and deadpan and polite. But it works, over time, to help make the final few seconds of the film (which are so important) succeed. The third lead, really, in this lopsided triangle, is Alison Elliott, who puts in an equally subtle performance. So much of the movie is about little changes in facial expression, the acting had to rise to the needs of the plot. Bonham Carter, above all, does this with chilling perfection. But those dresses! This is what is called Edwardian England, the first decade of the 20th Century, a time when modernity swept Europe with a passion (Picasso and Klimt) and when cars and other new technologies were surging. The styles of the dresses are part Art Nouveau, with its Asian influences, and part European excess, a showing off of style and wealth and material sensibility. Thank god! It's just breathtaking. The interiors are likewise brimming with tiles and flowers and paintings and light of all kinds. All of this is handled with a cinematic control that reminds me of the color coordination of mid-century Technicolor films, where the palette of a scene is often limited to a pair of colors. You'll see many scenes where a mix of blue and rusty orange are the only two colors in various guises (and these are most common because of the hair and eyes of Elliott). The cinematography is by Eduardo Serra, one of a handful of the most sumptuous contemporary shooters in film ("Girl with the Pearl Earring" and "What Dreams May Come"). And he lets the light and color inhabit every scene, never letting the photography get in the way. Just beautiful. So what does it mean to be a good person? Who cares with all this great acting and beautiful filming? But really, you do care, and it's a touching and provoking film in all its quietness. And it's not a bit obscure. Henry James never quite liked the book, but I think it's because he expected more from it, the themes and characters are so promising. Critics have come to see it as one of his great late novels, and that much is here. Director Iain Softley takes a couple of turns that the book avoids--a little sensational talk toward the beginning, and a frank and sex scene at the end--and both are okay in the film but not actually in keeping with the tone of the rest of it, which is about never quite showing your hand even to your closest friends. It's about waiting to speak, and hiding even good intentions for fear of seeming good when in fact part of being good is simply being good, not merely seeming it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and tragic beyond measure, put it on your view list right this very minute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kate (Helena Bonham Carter) is a young woman in love with a poor journalist, Merton (Linus Roache). Its Edwardian England and, having no money of her own, Kate lives with a wealthy aunt (Charlotte Rampling) who is avid to marry Kate well. Thus, the beautiful lady will not be free to wed Merton or any man of her choosing, if he doesn't have the goods. They meet secretly and passionately, even arranging a clandestine trip to Italy. Once there, the two cross paths with an extremely wealthy American, Millie (Alison Elliott) who casts her eye on Merton. Since neither Kate nor Merton have revealed that they are a couple, a difficult triangle is created, for Millie also chooses Kate as a friend. This becomes even more complex when the British duo learn that Millie, despite being young and beautiful, is incredibly ill with a respiratory ailment. Temptation arrives. What would happen, Kate asks Merton, if HE romances Millie, marries her and inherits her wealth upon her death? Why, the secret lovers would be set for life! Merton is appalled at the idea of making advances on a dying girl but, eventually, gives in. What neither Kate or Merton count on is the young gentleman's growing attraction to Millie, for she is sweet and funny as well as very lovely. Is tragedy in the future for this trio? Unfortunately, yes. This stunningly gorgeous film, based on the novel of Henry James, is a superior piece of movie making that cannot be denied. The three actors, Bonham Carter, Roache, and Elliott are extremely compelling in their difficult roles and all of the lesser cast members do fine work, too. Then, the setting in Italy, mostly, is lovely, with cinematography of the very finest. Costumes, too, are gorgeous, especially Elliott's garments and accessories. But, naturally, it is the powerful story of love and deception, with tragic results, that is the strongest asset of all. It should be stated that there are a couple of explicitly sexual scenes that might upset a few viewers. But, for the majority of film fans, they will be accepted as a necessary part of the story's elements. If you have never picked up this film, don't delay! Wings of the Dove is a soaring achievement that should be seen by everyone who loves great cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unforgettable story of love and desire set in Edwardian England.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the classic novel by Henry James,Iain Softley's 1997 adaptation features one of Helena Bonham Carters best performances,an ending that will stick in your memory long after the films finished and breathtaking period costumes designed by Sandy Powell.A timeless love story blighted by restrictions of class and money which will move you like no other. London 1910,spirited and beautiful Kate Croy(Helena Bonham Carter)is deeply in love with kind hearted but penniless journalist Merton Densher(Linus Roache).However since Kate became the ward of her wealthy aunt Maude(Charlotte Rampling)she now has no choice but to consider her financial position at all times.Especially as her aunt sends money to her alcoholic father Lionel(Michael Gambon).This drives a wedge between Kate and Merton and she soon finds herself being courted by the wealthy Lord Mark(Alex Jennings). When Kate befriends the outgoing yet fragile Millie Theale(Alison Elliott)she hatches a plan to get her to leave her fortune to Merton by bringing the two together knowing Millie is seriously ill and may die.However the plan backfires when Milton visits the women in Venice and really does come to care for Millie and falls in love with her. And so begins Kates quest to try and reclaim Mertons heart even though it may now completely belong to Millie.A haunting love story with beautiful location work and memorable performances,Wings Of The Dove will stay with you long after it's over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deception, Love, Jealousy in 1910
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove is a sinister, fascinating love story. Helena Bonham Carter plays Kate Croy, an ambitious but poor young woman who lives on the generosity of a rich aunt. Unable to live poor but not wanting to surrender to the husband her aunt is trying to find for her, she hatches a genius and simple plan: to let her boyfriend, Merton Densher (Linus Roache) seduce the rich and dying American millionaire Millie (Alison Elliott) so that she will leave all her money to him. Carter shines in this movie and her performance is one of the main reasons to watch it. It's one of those rare performances in which all the character's thoughts and feelings are transmitted by the eyes; Carter's eyes are always expressive, she barely needs any dialogue. And yet Hossein Amini's screenplay is also one of the brighter aspects of the movie. I cannot judge ho well he adapted the novel since I haven't yet read it, but as a movie it's a joy: each dialogue is essential, precise and enjoyable; no words are wasted or out of place. The movie's pacing is constant, deceptively calm but always filled with tension, for deception is pretty much the theme of the movie: how far will someone go to deceive another, and what effect will it have on them? For Merton the moral consequences of the deception haunt him as he realizes he may be falling in love with Millie, whereas Kate fears she may be losing her beloved's affection. Between this strange dynamic we have the innocent, cheerful Millie. The movie is also a fine period piece: Sandy Powell got a a much-deserved Oscar nomination for the costume design, but in truth all aspects of the movie deserve merit for their recreation of England in 1910. This movie takes us to places period movies seldom do: the underground system; the interior of bookshops and opium-dens; the interior of museums (in a wonderful sequence the characters attend a Klimt exhibition). And then there's the way Eduardo Serra's cinematography captures Venice in 1910. Serra is an under-appreciated director of cinematography, although he's left his mark in many memorable movies. His best work perhaps remains this movie, in particular the segment taking place in Venice. The way he captures the old canals, the gondolas, the colors at night during Carnival, the decay of the buildings, the beauty of the monuments, perhaps surpass the classic Death In Venice. The Wings of the Dove was a pleasant surprise, an underrated movie that caught me completely by surprise with its perfection. Although it was nominated for several Oscars back in 1998, it seems time has forgotten it. That's a pity, but for those who dare to give it a look, it'll be a huge source of joy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Did Someone Say Henry James -- Please Wait While I Shoot Myself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inevitable question will be: is "The Wings of the Dove" faithful to its source material? I, alas, can't answer that question for you, because to me Henry James's novel was 800 pages of random words strung together in ways that resembled sentences but made absolutely no other kind of sense. I'd rather be bludgeoned to death with one of his books than ever have to read another one -- the movie version could have featured transvestite cyborgs for all I cared; as long as I wasn't actually having to read it, I was a happy boy. The film is pretty good, about what you'd expect from a period piece based on a famous literary classic. It's got more pizazz than a Merchant-Ivory production, and boasts a great performance from a Merchant-Ivory regular, Helena Bonham Carter. It's nothing special, but probably worth a watch. Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helena Bonham Carter's Best Received Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although neither of them had anything to do with "Wings of the Dove," it reminded me strongly of the string of Merchant-Ivory films. It's a period film, based on a famous novel (by Henry James), set in gorgeous locations (London and Venice), with magnificent costuming and a largely English cast led by Helena Bonham Carter, who graced many a Merchant-Ivory film. "Wings of the Dove" is widely regarded as her finest performance. It earned an Oscar nomination. Although she lost out to Helen Hunt, many critics thought she deserved the honor more. Here she plays Kate Croy, the impoverished niece of her wealthy Aunt Maude (Charlotte Rampling) in love with a handsome, impecunious radical (Linus Roache) and decidedly not in love with her Aunt's choice, Lord Mark (Alex Jennings). I won't give away the scheme that is at the root of the story but Bonham Carter is both distinctively beautiful and a powerful actress. Only Rampling holds her own -- in a much less prominent role, although Michael Gambon in a small part as Kate's ne'er do well father is excellent (as always). Subsequent to "Wings of the Dove," Bonham Carter drifted in the direction of films (the Harry Potter series, for example) that failed to utilize her enormous talent or take full advantage of her slightly unusual but distinctive beauty. She's still young enough to make a big splash at some point in the future but she seems to have lost the urge to make the most of her considerable talent. If so, this film, which she made at the age of 31, may turn out in retrospect to have been her career high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You think love is sexual chemistry, think again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (zfiany@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie which might be overlooked for the romantic side of it because some people tend to judge a movie as trash if it is about romance. Well, I agree but not all romantic movies are the same. There are romantic movies that have messages which go beyond the emotion of love to the twin emotions jealousy, envy, sexual desires, respect, humanity, sacred love, pain and many others. All these feelings you can still experience in a romantic movie cooked well. Wings of dove is a movie with a plot and actually there is a part in the middle of the movie where if you pay attention carefully you might be able to understand what's going on before the story starts revealing its chapters. Actors are great; Helena Bonham Carter is indeed good in this role and Alison Elliotte is just as good and even better. Linus Roache also knows how to exhibit his transmitting emotions in a brilliant way. He knew how to play the difference which is a thin line between love and desire. You only have to guess whom he loved and whom he desired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Corrupt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Henry James novel, Kate Croy (Helena Bonham Carter)'s mother was born to wealth, but she threw it all away to marry Kate's opium addicted father. After her mother's death, Kate is offered a return to privilege. Of course, she must abandon her father, and her fianc&eacute;, journalist Merton Densher (Linus Roache). When she becomes friend with sick wealthy orphan Millie Theale (Alison Elliott), Kate sees an opportunity to get back with Merton and keep her position. It's a real murky portrait of the London class system, and how money corrupts the characters in this movie. The scheming is heart breaking. It's moral ambiguity is delicious. Helena Bonham Carter puts in a multi-dimensional performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kaleko
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great film to watch when you are feeling a little melancholy and want to be taken away somewhere else- Somewhere far away, and subdued. It was a slow yet enjoyable film. I would say that some might find it boring. It is true that the plot is fairly simple, and you have to wait a while for the few twists and turns it has. Though, it does always have something interesting going on, and the pace is decent for what it is. But if you don't enjoy long cerebral romances and period films, you probably won't enjoy this. I have to say it was visually appealing. This helps the film from becoming boring. Also the two leading ladies are gorgeous. You see the beauty of darkness in Kate and the beauty of sunshine in Millie- like night and day. I must agree fully with Lord Mark's comment about Kate's eyes. What was great about this film was the acting, presentation, mood, and lesson. Okay spoiler time, because I'd like to share my opinions on what happened. What I took away from this film is that it is not a good idea to persuade your love, for whatever reason, to be with another, even if it seems like a good idea at the time! Ha. Though I fully sympathized with Kate. She wasn't the sociopath that you often see in stories like this. She actually did care for Millie, and it seemed that she tried to convince herself that it would actually be good for Millie, at first. Although, the way she did try to break them up was a little heartless to her friend. But you can understand how it would be difficult for her to find any other way to do it. I suppose she could have admitted it to Millie herself, but I would think she might be too ashamed to do this. And anyways, she did say "this is the first time I didn't feel bad for her." She was jealous, and whilst at first she may not have expected herself to feel jealous, I think we can all understand the lack of sympathy we might have for someone if we did truly become jealous of them. So it is a little understandable that she would have hurt her friend. Besides, her friend would have been hurt anyway if she knew the truth with whatever way she found out, and she did deserve to know it. The best part for me was the ending where she was turned away by Merton. (By the way, did anyone else notice how at the end, Kate laid in the same position as the woman in the painting she asked Millie to look at?) I didn't fully expect her to be rejected. But it did make sense afterwards, as he was faced with a truly good human being, and felt so wretched about what he and Kate did to Millie, and finally realized that Kate wasn't such a great person after all. I think he was put off by the selfishness in Kate's final demand. I think if she hadn't requested that, he might have let bygones be bygones. But seriously, one can understand why she felt hurt and worried about throwing away so much to pursue this "true" love that she wasn't sure still existed. She was worried she already lost him to another woman and missed his undying singular commitment to her. But I can see why Merton would be so offended. Her request really did speak of an ignorance and uncaring about his feelings which may have developed, which were all her fault to begin with. I honestly thought it was a little silly for Kate to make her final demand. I mean honestly, she loved Millie and she should have realized that it was only natural to love such a great person. Besides, it's not like she would truly be a threat any more, 6 feet under! All things fade with time. Kate was honest with him about her feelings and intentions, so I don't think that Merton should have turned her away due to a lack of trust. Especially since she did change her mind in the end about going through with the plan. But I do suppose he could have resented the fact that she wanted money so badly, or acted so selfishly, or lied at all, and would have never known whether she was with him for his money after he got it. I suppose that was where his demand came from. But the fact she agreed to marry him should have been enough. He should have called her silly when she brought up her side of the bargain, and admitted that yes he loved the memory of Millie, just as Kate found herself loving her. I mean come on, Millie was an easy person to love, and Kate should have understood that. Besides, if Kate truly just wanted Merton for the money, she wouldn't have made her request. But really, they probably did need some time apart. I think that later on, they probably would find themselves back together after they had healed from the experience. One last thing I wanted to mention - The scene where Merton was crying was amazing. I don't think I've ever seen such a realistic portrayal of a man crying on screen before. He really nailed that one, and I felt very sympathetic to the feelings he was portraying. Anyway, it really was a wonderful film. It was very grey in its portrayal of the goodness and badness of the characters, which I like, and which isn't easy to do. It also made you think. I only downgraded it a bit because the storyline, while nicely portrayed, wasn't anything really spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wings of the Dove
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British period drama cannot be a bad alternative for a flushing upsurge of my Febiofest movie-goers' schedule. Nominated for 4 Oscars (Leading Actress, Cinematography, Costume and Adapted Screenplay), TWOTD represents a paradigmatic melodrama study of love, conspiracy, betrayal and passion, meanwhile mildly bashes the mercenary vanity then, all converges to a superior satisfactory coda. Venice part is memorably shot as an enchanting last journey to enjoy the fullest of one's life, an engaging score from Edward Shearmur firstly accompanies the film with a soothing pace, then adheres to the dramatic rotation aptly all the way along. The most striking caliber of the film is indisputably the acting stretch, Helena Bonham Carter is magnetically absorbing in her puberty of mixing brisk gal, smart aleck manipulator and sophisticated lovelorn victim, her career-best so far. A terrifically undervalued Alison Elliott radiates an unassumingly captivating rendition with both vulnerability and playfulness (she and Helena currently end up No. 2 and No. 1 in my Oscar chart for supporting and leading actress respectively). To juggle with these two vehement lovebirds, Linus Roache (the alien form THE FORGOTTEN 2005) may be tread the water a little bit frivolously, with a moral criterion swinging back and forth ambiguously, he tackles the most tricky part heedfully. The nudity scene near its finale is theatrically robust in delivering a love-lost denouement and generates poignant pathos. The minor satellites revolving around are all British old hands, Rampling. Gambon are too skimpy on screen, while McGovern's sedately elegant attendance is never histrionic. Adapted from Henry James' novel of the the same name, this Neo-classical piece has an imposing buzz on its own merit, some might deem it a shad mawkish, but I'm confidently not among that breed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich, beautiful, subtle, special--Henry James not far from where he'd like it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove (1997) Yes, this is a quite, indirect, thoughtful movie. But it is never slow. And the acting is incredible, almost as incredible as all the dresses and interior sets, which will blow anyone's mind. The story, by Henry James (the master of indirect but probing feelings), is about love of all kinds. And about being a good person, really. Three of the four main leads struggle with doing the right thing (and they do the right thing). The fourth struggles, falters, then comes forward again, then falters, finally, by making a demand that can never be met. It's unfair to compare this kind of period movie (set around 1910 even though James's book was published in 1902) to "A Room with a View" (set in the same decade) but the reason this happens is that the 1985 Merchant-Ivory masterpiece seemed to open up a new way of making period films, filled with beauty and lingering thoughts and, well, feeling. Not the feeling two people have for each other, but a feeling of a time and place. It so happens the star of this 1997 film, Helena Bonham Carter, also starred (magnificently) in the first one. The other star is a man, Linus Roache, who almost overplays his understated character by making him dry and deadpan and polite. But it works, over time, to help make the final few seconds of the film (which are so important) succeed. The third lead, really, in this lopsided triangle, is Alison Elliott, who puts in an equally subtle performance. So much of the movie is about little changes in facial expression, the acting had to rise to the needs of the plot. Bonham Carter, above all, does this with chilling perfection. But those dresses! This is what is called Edwardian England, the first decade of the 20th Century, a time when modernity swept Europe with a passion (Picasso and Klimt) and when cars and other new technologies were surging. The styles of the dresses are part Art Nouveau, with its Asian influences, and part European excess, a showing off of style and wealth and material sensibility. Thank god! It's just breathtaking. The interiors are likewise brimming with tiles and flowers and paintings and light of all kinds. All of this is handled with a cinematic control that reminds me of the color coordination of mid-century Technicolor films, where the palette of a scene is often limited to a pair of colors. You'll see many scenes where a mix of blue and rusty orange are the only two colors in various guises (and these are most common because of the hair and eyes of Elliott). The cinematography is by Eduardo Serra, one of a handful of the most sumptuous contemporary shooters in film ("Girl with the Pearl Earring" and "What Dreams May Come"). And he lets the light and color inhabit every scene, never letting the photography get in the way. Just beautiful. So what does it mean to be a good person? Who cares with all this great acting and beautiful filming? But really, you do care, and it's a touching and provoking film in all its quietness. And it's not a bit obscure. Henry James never quite liked the book, but I think it's because he expected more from it, the themes and characters are so promising. Critics have come to see it as one of his great late novels, and that much is here. Director Iain Softley takes a couple of turns that the book avoids--a little sensational talk toward the beginning, and a frank and sex scene at the end--and both are okay in the film but not actually in keeping with the tone of the rest of it, which is about never quite showing your hand even to your closest friends. It's about waiting to speak, and hiding even good intentions for fear of seeming good when in fact part of being good is simply being good, not merely seeming it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and tragic beyond measure, put it on your view list right this very minute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kate (Helena Bonham Carter) is a young woman in love with a poor journalist, Merton (Linus Roache). Its Edwardian England and, having no money of her own, Kate lives with a wealthy aunt (Charlotte Rampling) who is avid to marry Kate well. Thus, the beautiful lady will not be free to wed Merton or any man of her choosing, if he doesn't have the goods. They meet secretly and passionately, even arranging a clandestine trip to Italy. Once there, the two cross paths with an extremely wealthy American, Millie (Alison Elliott) who casts her eye on Merton. Since neither Kate nor Merton have revealed that they are a couple, a difficult triangle is created, for Millie also chooses Kate as a friend. This becomes even more complex when the British duo learn that Millie, despite being young and beautiful, is incredibly ill with a respiratory ailment. Temptation arrives. What would happen, Kate asks Merton, if HE romances Millie, marries her and inherits her wealth upon her death? Why, the secret lovers would be set for life! Merton is appalled at the idea of making advances on a dying girl but, eventually, gives in. What neither Kate or Merton count on is the young gentleman's growing attraction to Millie, for she is sweet and funny as well as very lovely. Is tragedy in the future for this trio? Unfortunately, yes. This stunningly gorgeous film, based on the novel of Henry James, is a superior piece of movie making that cannot be denied. The three actors, Bonham Carter, Roache, and Elliott are extremely compelling in their difficult roles and all of the lesser cast members do fine work, too. Then, the setting in Italy, mostly, is lovely, with cinematography of the very finest. Costumes, too, are gorgeous, especially Elliott's garments and accessories. But, naturally, it is the powerful story of love and deception, with tragic results, that is the strongest asset of all. It should be stated that there are a couple of explicitly sexual scenes that might upset a few viewers. But, for the majority of film fans, they will be accepted as a necessary part of the story's elements. If you have never picked up this film, don't delay! Wings of the Dove is a soaring achievement that should be seen by everyone who loves great cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unforgettable story of love and desire set in Edwardian England.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the classic novel by Henry James,Iain Softley's 1997 adaptation features one of Helena Bonham Carters best performances,an ending that will stick in your memory long after the films finished and breathtaking period costumes designed by Sandy Powell.A timeless love story blighted by restrictions of class and money which will move you like no other. London 1910,spirited and beautiful Kate Croy(Helena Bonham Carter)is deeply in love with kind hearted but penniless journalist Merton Densher(Linus Roache).However since Kate became the ward of her wealthy aunt Maude(Charlotte Rampling)she now has no choice but to consider her financial position at all times.Especially as her aunt sends money to her alcoholic father Lionel(Michael Gambon).This drives a wedge between Kate and Merton and she soon finds herself being courted by the wealthy Lord Mark(Alex Jennings). When Kate befriends the outgoing yet fragile Millie Theale(Alison Elliott)she hatches a plan to get her to leave her fortune to Merton by bringing the two together knowing Millie is seriously ill and may die.However the plan backfires when Milton visits the women in Venice and really does come to care for Millie and falls in love with her. And so begins Kates quest to try and reclaim Mertons heart even though it may now completely belong to Millie.A haunting love story with beautiful location work and memorable performances,Wings Of The Dove will stay with you long after it's over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deception, Love, Jealousy in 1910
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove is a sinister, fascinating love story. Helena Bonham Carter plays Kate Croy, an ambitious but poor young woman who lives on the generosity of a rich aunt. Unable to live poor but not wanting to surrender to the husband her aunt is trying to find for her, she hatches a genius and simple plan: to let her boyfriend, Merton Densher (Linus Roache) seduce the rich and dying American millionaire Millie (Alison Elliott) so that she will leave all her money to him. Carter shines in this movie and her performance is one of the main reasons to watch it. It's one of those rare performances in which all the character's thoughts and feelings are transmitted by the eyes; Carter's eyes are always expressive, she barely needs any dialogue. And yet Hossein Amini's screenplay is also one of the brighter aspects of the movie. I cannot judge ho well he adapted the novel since I haven't yet read it, but as a movie it's a joy: each dialogue is essential, precise and enjoyable; no words are wasted or out of place. The movie's pacing is constant, deceptively calm but always filled with tension, for deception is pretty much the theme of the movie: how far will someone go to deceive another, and what effect will it have on them? For Merton the moral consequences of the deception haunt him as he realizes he may be falling in love with Millie, whereas Kate fears she may be losing her beloved's affection. Between this strange dynamic we have the innocent, cheerful Millie. The movie is also a fine period piece: Sandy Powell got a a much-deserved Oscar nomination for the costume design, but in truth all aspects of the movie deserve merit for their recreation of England in 1910. This movie takes us to places period movies seldom do: the underground system; the interior of bookshops and opium-dens; the interior of museums (in a wonderful sequence the characters attend a Klimt exhibition). And then there's the way Eduardo Serra's cinematography captures Venice in 1910. Serra is an under-appreciated director of cinematography, although he's left his mark in many memorable movies. His best work perhaps remains this movie, in particular the segment taking place in Venice. The way he captures the old canals, the gondolas, the colors at night during Carnival, the decay of the buildings, the beauty of the monuments, perhaps surpass the classic Death In Venice. The Wings of the Dove was a pleasant surprise, an underrated movie that caught me completely by surprise with its perfection. Although it was nominated for several Oscars back in 1998, it seems time has forgotten it. That's a pity, but for those who dare to give it a look, it'll be a huge source of joy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Did Someone Say Henry James -- Please Wait While I Shoot Myself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inevitable question will be: is "The Wings of the Dove" faithful to its source material? I, alas, can't answer that question for you, because to me Henry James's novel was 800 pages of random words strung together in ways that resembled sentences but made absolutely no other kind of sense. I'd rather be bludgeoned to death with one of his books than ever have to read another one -- the movie version could have featured transvestite cyborgs for all I cared; as long as I wasn't actually having to read it, I was a happy boy. The film is pretty good, about what you'd expect from a period piece based on a famous literary classic. It's got more pizazz than a Merchant-Ivory production, and boasts a great performance from a Merchant-Ivory regular, Helena Bonham Carter. It's nothing special, but probably worth a watch. Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helena Bonham Carter's Best Received Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although neither of them had anything to do with "Wings of the Dove," it reminded me strongly of the string of Merchant-Ivory films. It's a period film, based on a famous novel (by Henry James), set in gorgeous locations (London and Venice), with magnificent costuming and a largely English cast led by Helena Bonham Carter, who graced many a Merchant-Ivory film. "Wings of the Dove" is widely regarded as her finest performance. It earned an Oscar nomination. Although she lost out to Helen Hunt, many critics thought she deserved the honor more. Here she plays Kate Croy, the impoverished niece of her wealthy Aunt Maude (Charlotte Rampling) in love with a handsome, impecunious radical (Linus Roache) and decidedly not in love with her Aunt's choice, Lord Mark (Alex Jennings). I won't give away the scheme that is at the root of the story but Bonham Carter is both distinctively beautiful and a powerful actress. Only Rampling holds her own -- in a much less prominent role, although Michael Gambon in a small part as Kate's ne'er do well father is excellent (as always). Subsequent to "Wings of the Dove," Bonham Carter drifted in the direction of films (the Harry Potter series, for example) that failed to utilize her enormous talent or take full advantage of her slightly unusual but distinctive beauty. She's still young enough to make a big splash at some point in the future but she seems to have lost the urge to make the most of her considerable talent. If so, this film, which she made at the age of 31, may turn out in retrospect to have been her career high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You think love is sexual chemistry, think again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (zfiany@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie which might be overlooked for the romantic side of it because some people tend to judge a movie as trash if it is about romance. Well, I agree but not all romantic movies are the same. There are romantic movies that have messages which go beyond the emotion of love to the twin emotions jealousy, envy, sexual desires, respect, humanity, sacred love, pain and many others. All these feelings you can still experience in a romantic movie cooked well. Wings of dove is a movie with a plot and actually there is a part in the middle of the movie where if you pay attention carefully you might be able to understand what's going on before the story starts revealing its chapters. Actors are great; Helena Bonham Carter is indeed good in this role and Alison Elliotte is just as good and even better. Linus Roache also knows how to exhibit his transmitting emotions in a brilliant way. He knew how to play the difference which is a thin line between love and desire. You only have to guess whom he loved and whom he desired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Corrupt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Henry James novel, Kate Croy (Helena Bonham Carter)'s mother was born to wealth, but she threw it all away to marry Kate's opium addicted father. After her mother's death, Kate is offered a return to privilege. Of course, she must abandon her father, and her fianc&eacute;, journalist Merton Densher (Linus Roache). When she becomes friend with sick wealthy orphan Millie Theale (Alison Elliott), Kate sees an opportunity to get back with Merton and keep her position. It's a real murky portrait of the London class system, and how money corrupts the characters in this movie. The scheming is heart breaking. It's moral ambiguity is delicious. Helena Bonham Carter puts in a multi-dimensional performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kaleko
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great film to watch when you are feeling a little melancholy and want to be taken away somewhere else- Somewhere far away, and subdued. It was a slow yet enjoyable film. I would say that some might find it boring. It is true that the plot is fairly simple, and you have to wait a while for the few twists and turns it has. Though, it does always have something interesting going on, and the pace is decent for what it is. But if you don't enjoy long cerebral romances and period films, you probably won't enjoy this. I have to say it was visually appealing. This helps the film from becoming boring. Also the two leading ladies are gorgeous. You see the beauty of darkness in Kate and the beauty of sunshine in Millie- like night and day. I must agree fully with Lord Mark's comment about Kate's eyes. What was great about this film was the acting, presentation, mood, and lesson. Okay spoiler time, because I'd like to share my opinions on what happened. What I took away from this film is that it is not a good idea to persuade your love, for whatever reason, to be with another, even if it seems like a good idea at the time! Ha. Though I fully sympathized with Kate. She wasn't the sociopath that you often see in stories like this. She actually did care for Millie, and it seemed that she tried to convince herself that it would actually be good for Millie, at first. Although, the way she did try to break them up was a little heartless to her friend. But you can understand how it would be difficult for her to find any other way to do it. I suppose she could have admitted it to Millie herself, but I would think she might be too ashamed to do this. And anyways, she did say "this is the first time I didn't feel bad for her." She was jealous, and whilst at first she may not have expected herself to feel jealous, I think we can all understand the lack of sympathy we might have for someone if we did truly become jealous of them. So it is a little understandable that she would have hurt her friend. Besides, her friend would have been hurt anyway if she knew the truth with whatever way she found out, and she did deserve to know it. The best part for me was the ending where she was turned away by Merton. (By the way, did anyone else notice how at the end, Kate laid in the same position as the woman in the painting she asked Millie to look at?) I didn't fully expect her to be rejected. But it did make sense afterwards, as he was faced with a truly good human being, and felt so wretched about what he and Kate did to Millie, and finally realized that Kate wasn't such a great person after all. I think he was put off by the selfishness in Kate's final demand. I think if she hadn't requested that, he might have let bygones be bygones. But seriously, one can understand why she felt hurt and worried about throwing away so much to pursue this "true" love that she wasn't sure still existed. She was worried she already lost him to another woman and missed his undying singular commitment to her. But I can see why Merton would be so offended. Her request really did speak of an ignorance and uncaring about his feelings which may have developed, which were all her fault to begin with. I honestly thought it was a little silly for Kate to make her final demand. I mean honestly, she loved Millie and she should have realized that it was only natural to love such a great person. Besides, it's not like she would truly be a threat any more, 6 feet under! All things fade with time. Kate was honest with him about her feelings and intentions, so I don't think that Merton should have turned her away due to a lack of trust. Especially since she did change her mind in the end about going through with the plan. But I do suppose he could have resented the fact that she wanted money so badly, or acted so selfishly, or lied at all, and would have never known whether she was with him for his money after he got it. I suppose that was where his demand came from. But the fact she agreed to marry him should have been enough. He should have called her silly when she brought up her side of the bargain, and admitted that yes he loved the memory of Millie, just as Kate found herself loving her. I mean come on, Millie was an easy person to love, and Kate should have understood that. Besides, if Kate truly just wanted Merton for the money, she wouldn't have made her request. But really, they probably did need some time apart. I think that later on, they probably would find themselves back together after they had healed from the experience. One last thing I wanted to mention - The scene where Merton was crying was amazing. I don't think I've ever seen such a realistic portrayal of a man crying on screen before. He really nailed that one, and I felt very sympathetic to the feelings he was portraying. Anyway, it really was a wonderful film. It was very grey in its portrayal of the goodness and badness of the characters, which I like, and which isn't easy to do. It also made you think. I only downgraded it a bit because the storyline, while nicely portrayed, wasn't anything really spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wings of the Dove
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British period drama cannot be a bad alternative for a flushing upsurge of my Febiofest movie-goers' schedule. Nominated for 4 Oscars (Leading Actress, Cinematography, Costume and Adapted Screenplay), TWOTD represents a paradigmatic melodrama study of love, conspiracy, betrayal and passion, meanwhile mildly bashes the mercenary vanity then, all converges to a superior satisfactory coda. Venice part is memorably shot as an enchanting last journey to enjoy the fullest of one's life, an engaging score from Edward Shearmur firstly accompanies the film with a soothing pace, then adheres to the dramatic rotation aptly all the way along. The most striking caliber of the film is indisputably the acting stretch, Helena Bonham Carter is magnetically absorbing in her puberty of mixing brisk gal, smart aleck manipulator and sophisticated lovelorn victim, her career-best so far. A terrifically undervalued Alison Elliott radiates an unassumingly captivating rendition with both vulnerability and playfulness (she and Helena currently end up No. 2 and No. 1 in my Oscar chart for supporting and leading actress respectively). To juggle with these two vehement lovebirds, Linus Roache (the alien form THE FORGOTTEN 2005) may be tread the water a little bit frivolously, with a moral criterion swinging back and forth ambiguously, he tackles the most tricky part heedfully. The nudity scene near its finale is theatrically robust in delivering a love-lost denouement and generates poignant pathos. The minor satellites revolving around are all British old hands, Rampling. Gambon are too skimpy on screen, while McGovern's sedately elegant attendance is never histrionic. Adapted from Henry James' novel of the the same name, this Neo-classical piece has an imposing buzz on its own merit, some might deem it a shad mawkish, but I'm confidently not among that breed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich, beautiful, subtle, special--Henry James not far from where he'd like it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove (1997) Yes, this is a quite, indirect, thoughtful movie. But it is never slow. And the acting is incredible, almost as incredible as all the dresses and interior sets, which will blow anyone's mind. The story, by Henry James (the master of indirect but probing feelings), is about love of all kinds. And about being a good person, really. Three of the four main leads struggle with doing the right thing (and they do the right thing). The fourth struggles, falters, then comes forward again, then falters, finally, by making a demand that can never be met. It's unfair to compare this kind of period movie (set around 1910 even though James's book was published in 1902) to "A Room with a View" (set in the same decade) but the reason this happens is that the 1985 Merchant-Ivory masterpiece seemed to open up a new way of making period films, filled with beauty and lingering thoughts and, well, feeling. Not the feeling two people have for each other, but a feeling of a time and place. It so happens the star of this 1997 film, Helena Bonham Carter, also starred (magnificently) in the first one. The other star is a man, Linus Roache, who almost overplays his understated character by making him dry and deadpan and polite. But it works, over time, to help make the final few seconds of the film (which are so important) succeed. The third lead, really, in this lopsided triangle, is Alison Elliott, who puts in an equally subtle performance. So much of the movie is about little changes in facial expression, the acting had to rise to the needs of the plot. Bonham Carter, above all, does this with chilling perfection. But those dresses! This is what is called Edwardian England, the first decade of the 20th Century, a time when modernity swept Europe with a passion (Picasso and Klimt) and when cars and other new technologies were surging. The styles of the dresses are part Art Nouveau, with its Asian influences, and part European excess, a showing off of style and wealth and material sensibility. Thank god! It's just breathtaking. The interiors are likewise brimming with tiles and flowers and paintings and light of all kinds. All of this is handled with a cinematic control that reminds me of the color coordination of mid-century Technicolor films, where the palette of a scene is often limited to a pair of colors. You'll see many scenes where a mix of blue and rusty orange are the only two colors in various guises (and these are most common because of the hair and eyes of Elliott). The cinematography is by Eduardo Serra, one of a handful of the most sumptuous contemporary shooters in film ("Girl with the Pearl Earring" and "What Dreams May Come"). And he lets the light and color inhabit every scene, never letting the photography get in the way. Just beautiful. So what does it mean to be a good person? Who cares with all this great acting and beautiful filming? But really, you do care, and it's a touching and provoking film in all its quietness. And it's not a bit obscure. Henry James never quite liked the book, but I think it's because he expected more from it, the themes and characters are so promising. Critics have come to see it as one of his great late novels, and that much is here. Director Iain Softley takes a couple of turns that the book avoids--a little sensational talk toward the beginning, and a frank and sex scene at the end--and both are okay in the film but not actually in keeping with the tone of the rest of it, which is about never quite showing your hand even to your closest friends. It's about waiting to speak, and hiding even good intentions for fear of seeming good when in fact part of being good is simply being good, not merely seeming it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and tragic beyond measure, put it on your view list right this very minute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kate (Helena Bonham Carter) is a young woman in love with a poor journalist, Merton (Linus Roache). Its Edwardian England and, having no money of her own, Kate lives with a wealthy aunt (Charlotte Rampling) who is avid to marry Kate well. Thus, the beautiful lady will not be free to wed Merton or any man of her choosing, if he doesn't have the goods. They meet secretly and passionately, even arranging a clandestine trip to Italy. Once there, the two cross paths with an extremely wealthy American, Millie (Alison Elliott) who casts her eye on Merton. Since neither Kate nor Merton have revealed that they are a couple, a difficult triangle is created, for Millie also chooses Kate as a friend. This becomes even more complex when the British duo learn that Millie, despite being young and beautiful, is incredibly ill with a respiratory ailment. Temptation arrives. What would happen, Kate asks Merton, if HE romances Millie, marries her and inherits her wealth upon her death? Why, the secret lovers would be set for life! Merton is appalled at the idea of making advances on a dying girl but, eventually, gives in. What neither Kate or Merton count on is the young gentleman's growing attraction to Millie, for she is sweet and funny as well as very lovely. Is tragedy in the future for this trio? Unfortunately, yes. This stunningly gorgeous film, based on the novel of Henry James, is a superior piece of movie making that cannot be denied. The three actors, Bonham Carter, Roache, and Elliott are extremely compelling in their difficult roles and all of the lesser cast members do fine work, too. Then, the setting in Italy, mostly, is lovely, with cinematography of the very finest. Costumes, too, are gorgeous, especially Elliott's garments and accessories. But, naturally, it is the powerful story of love and deception, with tragic results, that is the strongest asset of all. It should be stated that there are a couple of explicitly sexual scenes that might upset a few viewers. But, for the majority of film fans, they will be accepted as a necessary part of the story's elements. If you have never picked up this film, don't delay! Wings of the Dove is a soaring achievement that should be seen by everyone who loves great cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unforgettable story of love and desire set in Edwardian England.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the classic novel by Henry James,Iain Softley's 1997 adaptation features one of Helena Bonham Carters best performances,an ending that will stick in your memory long after the films finished and breathtaking period costumes designed by Sandy Powell.A timeless love story blighted by restrictions of class and money which will move you like no other. London 1910,spirited and beautiful Kate Croy(Helena Bonham Carter)is deeply in love with kind hearted but penniless journalist Merton Densher(Linus Roache).However since Kate became the ward of her wealthy aunt Maude(Charlotte Rampling)she now has no choice but to consider her financial position at all times.Especially as her aunt sends money to her alcoholic father Lionel(Michael Gambon).This drives a wedge between Kate and Merton and she soon finds herself being courted by the wealthy Lord Mark(Alex Jennings). When Kate befriends the outgoing yet fragile Millie Theale(Alison Elliott)she hatches a plan to get her to leave her fortune to Merton by bringing the two together knowing Millie is seriously ill and may die.However the plan backfires when Milton visits the women in Venice and really does come to care for Millie and falls in love with her. And so begins Kates quest to try and reclaim Mertons heart even though it may now completely belong to Millie.A haunting love story with beautiful location work and memorable performances,Wings Of The Dove will stay with you long after it's over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deception, Love, Jealousy in 1910
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove is a sinister, fascinating love story. Helena Bonham Carter plays Kate Croy, an ambitious but poor young woman who lives on the generosity of a rich aunt. Unable to live poor but not wanting to surrender to the husband her aunt is trying to find for her, she hatches a genius and simple plan: to let her boyfriend, Merton Densher (Linus Roache) seduce the rich and dying American millionaire Millie (Alison Elliott) so that she will leave all her money to him. Carter shines in this movie and her performance is one of the main reasons to watch it. It's one of those rare performances in which all the character's thoughts and feelings are transmitted by the eyes; Carter's eyes are always expressive, she barely needs any dialogue. And yet Hossein Amini's screenplay is also one of the brighter aspects of the movie. I cannot judge ho well he adapted the novel since I haven't yet read it, but as a movie it's a joy: each dialogue is essential, precise and enjoyable; no words are wasted or out of place. The movie's pacing is constant, deceptively calm but always filled with tension, for deception is pretty much the theme of the movie: how far will someone go to deceive another, and what effect will it have on them? For Merton the moral consequences of the deception haunt him as he realizes he may be falling in love with Millie, whereas Kate fears she may be losing her beloved's affection. Between this strange dynamic we have the innocent, cheerful Millie. The movie is also a fine period piece: Sandy Powell got a a much-deserved Oscar nomination for the costume design, but in truth all aspects of the movie deserve merit for their recreation of England in 1910. This movie takes us to places period movies seldom do: the underground system; the interior of bookshops and opium-dens; the interior of museums (in a wonderful sequence the characters attend a Klimt exhibition). And then there's the way Eduardo Serra's cinematography captures Venice in 1910. Serra is an under-appreciated director of cinematography, although he's left his mark in many memorable movies. His best work perhaps remains this movie, in particular the segment taking place in Venice. The way he captures the old canals, the gondolas, the colors at night during Carnival, the decay of the buildings, the beauty of the monuments, perhaps surpass the classic Death In Venice. The Wings of the Dove was a pleasant surprise, an underrated movie that caught me completely by surprise with its perfection. Although it was nominated for several Oscars back in 1998, it seems time has forgotten it. That's a pity, but for those who dare to give it a look, it'll be a huge source of joy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Did Someone Say Henry James -- Please Wait While I Shoot Myself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inevitable question will be: is "The Wings of the Dove" faithful to its source material? I, alas, can't answer that question for you, because to me Henry James's novel was 800 pages of random words strung together in ways that resembled sentences but made absolutely no other kind of sense. I'd rather be bludgeoned to death with one of his books than ever have to read another one -- the movie version could have featured transvestite cyborgs for all I cared; as long as I wasn't actually having to read it, I was a happy boy. The film is pretty good, about what you'd expect from a period piece based on a famous literary classic. It's got more pizazz than a Merchant-Ivory production, and boasts a great performance from a Merchant-Ivory regular, Helena Bonham Carter. It's nothing special, but probably worth a watch. Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helena Bonham Carter's Best Received Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although neither of them had anything to do with "Wings of the Dove," it reminded me strongly of the string of Merchant-Ivory films. It's a period film, based on a famous novel (by Henry James), set in gorgeous locations (London and Venice), with magnificent costuming and a largely English cast led by Helena Bonham Carter, who graced many a Merchant-Ivory film. "Wings of the Dove" is widely regarded as her finest performance. It earned an Oscar nomination. Although she lost out to Helen Hunt, many critics thought she deserved the honor more. Here she plays Kate Croy, the impoverished niece of her wealthy Aunt Maude (Charlotte Rampling) in love with a handsome, impecunious radical (Linus Roache) and decidedly not in love with her Aunt's choice, Lord Mark (Alex Jennings). I won't give away the scheme that is at the root of the story but Bonham Carter is both distinctively beautiful and a powerful actress. Only Rampling holds her own -- in a much less prominent role, although Michael Gambon in a small part as Kate's ne'er do well father is excellent (as always). Subsequent to "Wings of the Dove," Bonham Carter drifted in the direction of films (the Harry Potter series, for example) that failed to utilize her enormous talent or take full advantage of her slightly unusual but distinctive beauty. She's still young enough to make a big splash at some point in the future but she seems to have lost the urge to make the most of her considerable talent. If so, this film, which she made at the age of 31, may turn out in retrospect to have been her career high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You think love is sexual chemistry, think again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (zfiany@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie which might be overlooked for the romantic side of it because some people tend to judge a movie as trash if it is about romance. Well, I agree but not all romantic movies are the same. There are romantic movies that have messages which go beyond the emotion of love to the twin emotions jealousy, envy, sexual desires, respect, humanity, sacred love, pain and many others. All these feelings you can still experience in a romantic movie cooked well. Wings of dove is a movie with a plot and actually there is a part in the middle of the movie where if you pay attention carefully you might be able to understand what's going on before the story starts revealing its chapters. Actors are great; Helena Bonham Carter is indeed good in this role and Alison Elliotte is just as good and even better. Linus Roache also knows how to exhibit his transmitting emotions in a brilliant way. He knew how to play the difference which is a thin line between love and desire. You only have to guess whom he loved and whom he desired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Corrupt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Henry James novel, Kate Croy (Helena Bonham Carter)'s mother was born to wealth, but she threw it all away to marry Kate's opium addicted father. After her mother's death, Kate is offered a return to privilege. Of course, she must abandon her father, and her fianc&eacute;, journalist Merton Densher (Linus Roache). When she becomes friend with sick wealthy orphan Millie Theale (Alison Elliott), Kate sees an opportunity to get back with Merton and keep her position. It's a real murky portrait of the London class system, and how money corrupts the characters in this movie. The scheming is heart breaking. It's moral ambiguity is delicious. Helena Bonham Carter puts in a multi-dimensional performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kaleko
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great film to watch when you are feeling a little melancholy and want to be taken away somewhere else- Somewhere far away, and subdued. It was a slow yet enjoyable film. I would say that some might find it boring. It is true that the plot is fairly simple, and you have to wait a while for the few twists and turns it has. Though, it does always have something interesting going on, and the pace is decent for what it is. But if you don't enjoy long cerebral romances and period films, you probably won't enjoy this. I have to say it was visually appealing. This helps the film from becoming boring. Also the two leading ladies are gorgeous. You see the beauty of darkness in Kate and the beauty of sunshine in Millie- like night and day. I must agree fully with Lord Mark's comment about Kate's eyes. What was great about this film was the acting, presentation, mood, and lesson. Okay spoiler time, because I'd like to share my opinions on what happened. What I took away from this film is that it is not a good idea to persuade your love, for whatever reason, to be with another, even if it seems like a good idea at the time! Ha. Though I fully sympathized with Kate. She wasn't the sociopath that you often see in stories like this. She actually did care for Millie, and it seemed that she tried to convince herself that it would actually be good for Millie, at first. Although, the way she did try to break them up was a little heartless to her friend. But you can understand how it would be difficult for her to find any other way to do it. I suppose she could have admitted it to Millie herself, but I would think she might be too ashamed to do this. And anyways, she did say "this is the first time I didn't feel bad for her." She was jealous, and whilst at first she may not have expected herself to feel jealous, I think we can all understand the lack of sympathy we might have for someone if we did truly become jealous of them. So it is a little understandable that she would have hurt her friend. Besides, her friend would have been hurt anyway if she knew the truth with whatever way she found out, and she did deserve to know it. The best part for me was the ending where she was turned away by Merton. (By the way, did anyone else notice how at the end, Kate laid in the same position as the woman in the painting she asked Millie to look at?) I didn't fully expect her to be rejected. But it did make sense afterwards, as he was faced with a truly good human being, and felt so wretched about what he and Kate did to Millie, and finally realized that Kate wasn't such a great person after all. I think he was put off by the selfishness in Kate's final demand. I think if she hadn't requested that, he might have let bygones be bygones. But seriously, one can understand why she felt hurt and worried about throwing away so much to pursue this "true" love that she wasn't sure still existed. She was worried she already lost him to another woman and missed his undying singular commitment to her. But I can see why Merton would be so offended. Her request really did speak of an ignorance and uncaring about his feelings which may have developed, which were all her fault to begin with. I honestly thought it was a little silly for Kate to make her final demand. I mean honestly, she loved Millie and she should have realized that it was only natural to love such a great person. Besides, it's not like she would truly be a threat any more, 6 feet under! All things fade with time. Kate was honest with him about her feelings and intentions, so I don't think that Merton should have turned her away due to a lack of trust. Especially since she did change her mind in the end about going through with the plan. But I do suppose he could have resented the fact that she wanted money so badly, or acted so selfishly, or lied at all, and would have never known whether she was with him for his money after he got it. I suppose that was where his demand came from. But the fact she agreed to marry him should have been enough. He should have called her silly when she brought up her side of the bargain, and admitted that yes he loved the memory of Millie, just as Kate found herself loving her. I mean come on, Millie was an easy person to love, and Kate should have understood that. Besides, if Kate truly just wanted Merton for the money, she wouldn't have made her request. But really, they probably did need some time apart. I think that later on, they probably would find themselves back together after they had healed from the experience. One last thing I wanted to mention - The scene where Merton was crying was amazing. I don't think I've ever seen such a realistic portrayal of a man crying on screen before. He really nailed that one, and I felt very sympathetic to the feelings he was portraying. Anyway, it really was a wonderful film. It was very grey in its portrayal of the goodness and badness of the characters, which I like, and which isn't easy to do. It also made you think. I only downgraded it a bit because the storyline, while nicely portrayed, wasn't anything really spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wings of the Dove
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British period drama cannot be a bad alternative for a flushing upsurge of my Febiofest movie-goers' schedule. Nominated for 4 Oscars (Leading Actress, Cinematography, Costume and Adapted Screenplay), TWOTD represents a paradigmatic melodrama study of love, conspiracy, betrayal and passion, meanwhile mildly bashes the mercenary vanity then, all converges to a superior satisfactory coda. Venice part is memorably shot as an enchanting last journey to enjoy the fullest of one's life, an engaging score from Edward Shearmur firstly accompanies the film with a soothing pace, then adheres to the dramatic rotation aptly all the way along. The most striking caliber of the film is indisputably the acting stretch, Helena Bonham Carter is magnetically absorbing in her puberty of mixing brisk gal, smart aleck manipulator and sophisticated lovelorn victim, her career-best so far. A terrifically undervalued Alison Elliott radiates an unassumingly captivating rendition with both vulnerability and playfulness (she and Helena currently end up No. 2 and No. 1 in my Oscar chart for supporting and leading actress respectively). To juggle with these two vehement lovebirds, Linus Roache (the alien form THE FORGOTTEN 2005) may be tread the water a little bit frivolously, with a moral criterion swinging back and forth ambiguously, he tackles the most tricky part heedfully. The nudity scene near its finale is theatrically robust in delivering a love-lost denouement and generates poignant pathos. The minor satellites revolving around are all British old hands, Rampling. Gambon are too skimpy on screen, while McGovern's sedately elegant attendance is never histrionic. Adapted from Henry James' novel of the the same name, this Neo-classical piece has an imposing buzz on its own merit, some might deem it a shad mawkish, but I'm confidently not among that breed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich, beautiful, subtle, special--Henry James not far from where he'd like it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove (1997) Yes, this is a quite, indirect, thoughtful movie. But it is never slow. And the acting is incredible, almost as incredible as all the dresses and interior sets, which will blow anyone's mind. The story, by Henry James (the master of indirect but probing feelings), is about love of all kinds. And about being a good person, really. Three of the four main leads struggle with doing the right thing (and they do the right thing). The fourth struggles, falters, then comes forward again, then falters, finally, by making a demand that can never be met. It's unfair to compare this kind of period movie (set around 1910 even though James's book was published in 1902) to "A Room with a View" (set in the same decade) but the reason this happens is that the 1985 Merchant-Ivory masterpiece seemed to open up a new way of making period films, filled with beauty and lingering thoughts and, well, feeling. Not the feeling two people have for each other, but a feeling of a time and place. It so happens the star of this 1997 film, Helena Bonham Carter, also starred (magnificently) in the first one. The other star is a man, Linus Roache, who almost overplays his understated character by making him dry and deadpan and polite. But it works, over time, to help make the final few seconds of the film (which are so important) succeed. The third lead, really, in this lopsided triangle, is Alison Elliott, who puts in an equally subtle performance. So much of the movie is about little changes in facial expression, the acting had to rise to the needs of the plot. Bonham Carter, above all, does this with chilling perfection. But those dresses! This is what is called Edwardian England, the first decade of the 20th Century, a time when modernity swept Europe with a passion (Picasso and Klimt) and when cars and other new technologies were surging. The styles of the dresses are part Art Nouveau, with its Asian influences, and part European excess, a showing off of style and wealth and material sensibility. Thank god! It's just breathtaking. The interiors are likewise brimming with tiles and flowers and paintings and light of all kinds. All of this is handled with a cinematic control that reminds me of the color coordination of mid-century Technicolor films, where the palette of a scene is often limited to a pair of colors. You'll see many scenes where a mix of blue and rusty orange are the only two colors in various guises (and these are most common because of the hair and eyes of Elliott). The cinematography is by Eduardo Serra, one of a handful of the most sumptuous contemporary shooters in film ("Girl with the Pearl Earring" and "What Dreams May Come"). And he lets the light and color inhabit every scene, never letting the photography get in the way. Just beautiful. So what does it mean to be a good person? Who cares with all this great acting and beautiful filming? But really, you do care, and it's a touching and provoking film in all its quietness. And it's not a bit obscure. Henry James never quite liked the book, but I think it's because he expected more from it, the themes and characters are so promising. Critics have come to see it as one of his great late novels, and that much is here. Director Iain Softley takes a couple of turns that the book avoids--a little sensational talk toward the beginning, and a frank and sex scene at the end--and both are okay in the film but not actually in keeping with the tone of the rest of it, which is about never quite showing your hand even to your closest friends. It's about waiting to speak, and hiding even good intentions for fear of seeming good when in fact part of being good is simply being good, not merely seeming it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and tragic beyond measure, put it on your view list right this very minute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kate (Helena Bonham Carter) is a young woman in love with a poor journalist, Merton (Linus Roache). Its Edwardian England and, having no money of her own, Kate lives with a wealthy aunt (Charlotte Rampling) who is avid to marry Kate well. Thus, the beautiful lady will not be free to wed Merton or any man of her choosing, if he doesn't have the goods. They meet secretly and passionately, even arranging a clandestine trip to Italy. Once there, the two cross paths with an extremely wealthy American, Millie (Alison Elliott) who casts her eye on Merton. Since neither Kate nor Merton have revealed that they are a couple, a difficult triangle is created, for Millie also chooses Kate as a friend. This becomes even more complex when the British duo learn that Millie, despite being young and beautiful, is incredibly ill with a respiratory ailment. Temptation arrives. What would happen, Kate asks Merton, if HE romances Millie, marries her and inherits her wealth upon her death? Why, the secret lovers would be set for life! Merton is appalled at the idea of making advances on a dying girl but, eventually, gives in. What neither Kate or Merton count on is the young gentleman's growing attraction to Millie, for she is sweet and funny as well as very lovely. Is tragedy in the future for this trio? Unfortunately, yes. This stunningly gorgeous film, based on the novel of Henry James, is a superior piece of movie making that cannot be denied. The three actors, Bonham Carter, Roache, and Elliott are extremely compelling in their difficult roles and all of the lesser cast members do fine work, too. Then, the setting in Italy, mostly, is lovely, with cinematography of the very finest. Costumes, too, are gorgeous, especially Elliott's garments and accessories. But, naturally, it is the powerful story of love and deception, with tragic results, that is the strongest asset of all. It should be stated that there are a couple of explicitly sexual scenes that might upset a few viewers. But, for the majority of film fans, they will be accepted as a necessary part of the story's elements. If you have never picked up this film, don't delay! Wings of the Dove is a soaring achievement that should be seen by everyone who loves great cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unforgettable story of love and desire set in Edwardian England.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the classic novel by Henry James,Iain Softley's 1997 adaptation features one of Helena Bonham Carters best performances,an ending that will stick in your memory long after the films finished and breathtaking period costumes designed by Sandy Powell.A timeless love story blighted by restrictions of class and money which will move you like no other. London 1910,spirited and beautiful Kate Croy(Helena Bonham Carter)is deeply in love with kind hearted but penniless journalist Merton Densher(Linus Roache).However since Kate became the ward of her wealthy aunt Maude(Charlotte Rampling)she now has no choice but to consider her financial position at all times.Especially as her aunt sends money to her alcoholic father Lionel(Michael Gambon).This drives a wedge between Kate and Merton and she soon finds herself being courted by the wealthy Lord Mark(Alex Jennings). When Kate befriends the outgoing yet fragile Millie Theale(Alison Elliott)she hatches a plan to get her to leave her fortune to Merton by bringing the two together knowing Millie is seriously ill and may die.However the plan backfires when Milton visits the women in Venice and really does come to care for Millie and falls in love with her. And so begins Kates quest to try and reclaim Mertons heart even though it may now completely belong to Millie.A haunting love story with beautiful location work and memorable performances,Wings Of The Dove will stay with you long after it's over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deception, Love, Jealousy in 1910
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove is a sinister, fascinating love story. Helena Bonham Carter plays Kate Croy, an ambitious but poor young woman who lives on the generosity of a rich aunt. Unable to live poor but not wanting to surrender to the husband her aunt is trying to find for her, she hatches a genius and simple plan: to let her boyfriend, Merton Densher (Linus Roache) seduce the rich and dying American millionaire Millie (Alison Elliott) so that she will leave all her money to him. Carter shines in this movie and her performance is one of the main reasons to watch it. It's one of those rare performances in which all the character's thoughts and feelings are transmitted by the eyes; Carter's eyes are always expressive, she barely needs any dialogue. And yet Hossein Amini's screenplay is also one of the brighter aspects of the movie. I cannot judge ho well he adapted the novel since I haven't yet read it, but as a movie it's a joy: each dialogue is essential, precise and enjoyable; no words are wasted or out of place. The movie's pacing is constant, deceptively calm but always filled with tension, for deception is pretty much the theme of the movie: how far will someone go to deceive another, and what effect will it have on them? For Merton the moral consequences of the deception haunt him as he realizes he may be falling in love with Millie, whereas Kate fears she may be losing her beloved's affection. Between this strange dynamic we have the innocent, cheerful Millie. The movie is also a fine period piece: Sandy Powell got a a much-deserved Oscar nomination for the costume design, but in truth all aspects of the movie deserve merit for their recreation of England in 1910. This movie takes us to places period movies seldom do: the underground system; the interior of bookshops and opium-dens; the interior of museums (in a wonderful sequence the characters attend a Klimt exhibition). And then there's the way Eduardo Serra's cinematography captures Venice in 1910. Serra is an under-appreciated director of cinematography, although he's left his mark in many memorable movies. His best work perhaps remains this movie, in particular the segment taking place in Venice. The way he captures the old canals, the gondolas, the colors at night during Carnival, the decay of the buildings, the beauty of the monuments, perhaps surpass the classic Death In Venice. The Wings of the Dove was a pleasant surprise, an underrated movie that caught me completely by surprise with its perfection. Although it was nominated for several Oscars back in 1998, it seems time has forgotten it. That's a pity, but for those who dare to give it a look, it'll be a huge source of joy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Did Someone Say Henry James -- Please Wait While I Shoot Myself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inevitable question will be: is "The Wings of the Dove" faithful to its source material? I, alas, can't answer that question for you, because to me Henry James's novel was 800 pages of random words strung together in ways that resembled sentences but made absolutely no other kind of sense. I'd rather be bludgeoned to death with one of his books than ever have to read another one -- the movie version could have featured transvestite cyborgs for all I cared; as long as I wasn't actually having to read it, I was a happy boy. The film is pretty good, about what you'd expect from a period piece based on a famous literary classic. It's got more pizazz than a Merchant-Ivory production, and boasts a great performance from a Merchant-Ivory regular, Helena Bonham Carter. It's nothing special, but probably worth a watch. Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helena Bonham Carter's Best Received Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although neither of them had anything to do with "Wings of the Dove," it reminded me strongly of the string of Merchant-Ivory films. It's a period film, based on a famous novel (by Henry James), set in gorgeous locations (London and Venice), with magnificent costuming and a largely English cast led by Helena Bonham Carter, who graced many a Merchant-Ivory film. "Wings of the Dove" is widely regarded as her finest performance. It earned an Oscar nomination. Although she lost out to Helen Hunt, many critics thought she deserved the honor more. Here she plays Kate Croy, the impoverished niece of her wealthy Aunt Maude (Charlotte Rampling) in love with a handsome, impecunious radical (Linus Roache) and decidedly not in love with her Aunt's choice, Lord Mark (Alex Jennings). I won't give away the scheme that is at the root of the story but Bonham Carter is both distinctively beautiful and a powerful actress. Only Rampling holds her own -- in a much less prominent role, although Michael Gambon in a small part as Kate's ne'er do well father is excellent (as always). Subsequent to "Wings of the Dove," Bonham Carter drifted in the direction of films (the Harry Potter series, for example) that failed to utilize her enormous talent or take full advantage of her slightly unusual but distinctive beauty. She's still young enough to make a big splash at some point in the future but she seems to have lost the urge to make the most of her considerable talent. If so, this film, which she made at the age of 31, may turn out in retrospect to have been her career high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You think love is sexual chemistry, think again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (zfiany@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie which might be overlooked for the romantic side of it because some people tend to judge a movie as trash if it is about romance. Well, I agree but not all romantic movies are the same. There are romantic movies that have messages which go beyond the emotion of love to the twin emotions jealousy, envy, sexual desires, respect, humanity, sacred love, pain and many others. All these feelings you can still experience in a romantic movie cooked well. Wings of dove is a movie with a plot and actually there is a part in the middle of the movie where if you pay attention carefully you might be able to understand what's going on before the story starts revealing its chapters. Actors are great; Helena Bonham Carter is indeed good in this role and Alison Elliotte is just as good and even better. Linus Roache also knows how to exhibit his transmitting emotions in a brilliant way. He knew how to play the difference which is a thin line between love and desire. You only have to guess whom he loved and whom he desired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Corrupt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Henry James novel, Kate Croy (Helena Bonham Carter)'s mother was born to wealth, but she threw it all away to marry Kate's opium addicted father. After her mother's death, Kate is offered a return to privilege. Of course, she must abandon her father, and her fianc&eacute;, journalist Merton Densher (Linus Roache). When she becomes friend with sick wealthy orphan Millie Theale (Alison Elliott), Kate sees an opportunity to get back with Merton and keep her position. It's a real murky portrait of the London class system, and how money corrupts the characters in this movie. The scheming is heart breaking. It's moral ambiguity is delicious. Helena Bonham Carter puts in a multi-dimensional performance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kaleko
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great film to watch when you are feeling a little melancholy and want to be taken away somewhere else- Somewhere far away, and subdued. It was a slow yet enjoyable film. I would say that some might find it boring. It is true that the plot is fairly simple, and you have to wait a while for the few twists and turns it has. Though, it does always have something interesting going on, and the pace is decent for what it is. But if you don't enjoy long cerebral romances and period films, you probably won't enjoy this. I have to say it was visually appealing. This helps the film from becoming boring. Also the two leading ladies are gorgeous. You see the beauty of darkness in Kate and the beauty of sunshine in Millie- like night and day. I must agree fully with Lord Mark's comment about Kate's eyes. What was great about this film was the acting, presentation, mood, and lesson. Okay spoiler time, because I'd like to share my opinions on what happened. What I took away from this film is that it is not a good idea to persuade your love, for whatever reason, to be with another, even if it seems like a good idea at the time! Ha. Though I fully sympathized with Kate. She wasn't the sociopath that you often see in stories like this. She actually did care for Millie, and it seemed that she tried to convince herself that it would actually be good for Millie, at first. Although, the way she did try to break them up was a little heartless to her friend. But you can understand how it would be difficult for her to find any other way to do it. I suppose she could have admitted it to Millie herself, but I would think she might be too ashamed to do this. And anyways, she did say "this is the first time I didn't feel bad for her." She was jealous, and whilst at first she may not have expected herself to feel jealous, I think we can all understand the lack of sympathy we might have for someone if we did truly become jealous of them. So it is a little understandable that she would have hurt her friend. Besides, her friend would have been hurt anyway if she knew the truth with whatever way she found out, and she did deserve to know it. The best part for me was the ending where she was turned away by Merton. (By the way, did anyone else notice how at the end, Kate laid in the same position as the woman in the painting she asked Millie to look at?) I didn't fully expect her to be rejected. But it did make sense afterwards, as he was faced with a truly good human being, and felt so wretched about what he and Kate did to Millie, and finally realized that Kate wasn't such a great person after all. I think he was put off by the selfishness in Kate's final demand. I think if she hadn't requested that, he might have let bygones be bygones. But seriously, one can understand why she felt hurt and worried about throwing away so much to pursue this "true" love that she wasn't sure still existed. She was worried she already lost him to another woman and missed his undying singular commitment to her. But I can see why Merton would be so offended. Her request really did speak of an ignorance and uncaring about his feelings which may have developed, which were all her fault to begin with. I honestly thought it was a little silly for Kate to make her final demand. I mean honestly, she loved Millie and she should have realized that it was only natural to love such a great person. Besides, it's not like she would truly be a threat any more, 6 feet under! All things fade with time. Kate was honest with him about her feelings and intentions, so I don't think that Merton should have turned her away due to a lack of trust. Especially since she did change her mind in the end about going through with the plan. But I do suppose he could have resented the fact that she wanted money so badly, or acted so selfishly, or lied at all, and would have never known whether she was with him for his money after he got it. I suppose that was where his demand came from. But the fact she agreed to marry him should have been enough. He should have called her silly when she brought up her side of the bargain, and admitted that yes he loved the memory of Millie, just as Kate found herself loving her. I mean come on, Millie was an easy person to love, and Kate should have understood that. Besides, if Kate truly just wanted Merton for the money, she wouldn't have made her request. But really, they probably did need some time apart. I think that later on, they probably would find themselves back together after they had healed from the experience. One last thing I wanted to mention - The scene where Merton was crying was amazing. I don't think I've ever seen such a realistic portrayal of a man crying on screen before. He really nailed that one, and I felt very sympathetic to the feelings he was portraying. Anyway, it really was a wonderful film. It was very grey in its portrayal of the goodness and badness of the characters, which I like, and which isn't easy to do. It also made you think. I only downgraded it a bit because the storyline, while nicely portrayed, wasn't anything really spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Wings of the Dove
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British period drama cannot be a bad alternative for a flushing upsurge of my Febiofest movie-goers' schedule. Nominated for 4 Oscars (Leading Actress, Cinematography, Costume and Adapted Screenplay), TWOTD represents a paradigmatic melodrama study of love, conspiracy, betrayal and passion, meanwhile mildly bashes the mercenary vanity then, all converges to a superior satisfactory coda. Venice part is memorably shot as an enchanting last journey to enjoy the fullest of one's life, an engaging score from Edward Shearmur firstly accompanies the film with a soothing pace, then adheres to the dramatic rotation aptly all the way along. The most striking caliber of the film is indisputably the acting stretch, Helena Bonham Carter is magnetically absorbing in her puberty of mixing brisk gal, smart aleck manipulator and sophisticated lovelorn victim, her career-best so far. A terrifically undervalued Alison Elliott radiates an unassumingly captivating rendition with both vulnerability and playfulness (she and Helena currently end up No. 2 and No. 1 in my Oscar chart for supporting and leading actress respectively). To juggle with these two vehement lovebirds, Linus Roache (the alien form THE FORGOTTEN 2005) may be tread the water a little bit frivolously, with a moral criterion swinging back and forth ambiguously, he tackles the most tricky part heedfully. The nudity scene near its finale is theatrically robust in delivering a love-lost denouement and generates poignant pathos. The minor satellites revolving around are all British old hands, Rampling. Gambon are too skimpy on screen, while McGovern's sedately elegant attendance is never histrionic. Adapted from Henry James' novel of the the same name, this Neo-classical piece has an imposing buzz on its own merit, some might deem it a shad mawkish, but I'm confidently not among that breed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich, beautiful, subtle, special--Henry James not far from where he'd like it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove (1997) Yes, this is a quite, indirect, thoughtful movie. But it is never slow. And the acting is incredible, almost as incredible as all the dresses and interior sets, which will blow anyone's mind. The story, by Henry James (the master of indirect but probing feelings), is about love of all kinds. And about being a good person, really. Three of the four main leads struggle with doing the right thing (and they do the right thing). The fourth struggles, falters, then comes forward again, then falters, finally, by making a demand that can never be met. It's unfair to compare this kind of period movie (set around 1910 even though James's book was published in 1902) to "A Room with a View" (set in the same decade) but the reason this happens is that the 1985 Merchant-Ivory masterpiece seemed to open up a new way of making period films, filled with beauty and lingering thoughts and, well, feeling. Not the feeling two people have for each other, but a feeling of a time and place. It so happens the star of this 1997 film, Helena Bonham Carter, also starred (magnificently) in the first one. The other star is a man, Linus Roache, who almost overplays his understated character by making him dry and deadpan and polite. But it works, over time, to help make the final few seconds of the film (which are so important) succeed. The third lead, really, in this lopsided triangle, is Alison Elliott, who puts in an equally subtle performance. So much of the movie is about little changes in facial expression, the acting had to rise to the needs of the plot. Bonham Carter, above all, does this with chilling perfection. But those dresses! This is what is called Edwardian England, the first decade of the 20th Century, a time when modernity swept Europe with a passion (Picasso and Klimt) and when cars and other new technologies were surging. The styles of the dresses are part Art Nouveau, with its Asian influences, and part European excess, a showing off of style and wealth and material sensibility. Thank god! It's just breathtaking. The interiors are likewise brimming with tiles and flowers and paintings and light of all kinds. All of this is handled with a cinematic control that reminds me of the color coordination of mid-century Technicolor films, where the palette of a scene is often limited to a pair of colors. You'll see many scenes where a mix of blue and rusty orange are the only two colors in various guises (and these are most common because of the hair and eyes of Elliott). The cinematography is by Eduardo Serra, one of a handful of the most sumptuous contemporary shooters in film ("Girl with the Pearl Earring" and "What Dreams May Come"). And he lets the light and color inhabit every scene, never letting the photography get in the way. Just beautiful. So what does it mean to be a good person? Who cares with all this great acting and beautiful filming? But really, you do care, and it's a touching and provoking film in all its quietness. And it's not a bit obscure. Henry James never quite liked the book, but I think it's because he expected more from it, the themes and characters are so promising. Critics have come to see it as one of his great late novels, and that much is here. Director Iain Softley takes a couple of turns that the book avoids--a little sensational talk toward the beginning, and a frank and sex scene at the end--and both are okay in the film but not actually in keeping with the tone of the rest of it, which is about never quite showing your hand even to your closest friends. It's about waiting to speak, and hiding even good intentions for fear of seeming good when in fact part of being good is simply being good, not merely seeming it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and tragic beyond measure, put it on your view list right this very minute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kate (Helena Bonham Carter) is a young woman in love with a poor journalist, Merton (Linus Roache). Its Edwardian England and, having no money of her own, Kate lives with a wealthy aunt (Charlotte Rampling) who is avid to marry Kate well. Thus, the beautiful lady will not be free to wed Merton or any man of her choosing, if he doesn't have the goods. They meet secretly and passionately, even arranging a clandestine trip to Italy. Once there, the two cross paths with an extremely wealthy American, Millie (Alison Elliott) who casts her eye on Merton. Since neither Kate nor Merton have revealed that they are a couple, a difficult triangle is created, for Millie also chooses Kate as a friend. This becomes even more complex when the British duo learn that Millie, despite being young and beautiful, is incredibly ill with a respiratory ailment. Temptation arrives. What would happen, Kate asks Merton, if HE romances Millie, marries her and inherits her wealth upon her death? Why, the secret lovers would be set for life! Merton is appalled at the idea of making advances on a dying girl but, eventually, gives in. What neither Kate or Merton count on is the young gentleman's growing attraction to Millie, for she is sweet and funny as well as very lovely. Is tragedy in the future for this trio? Unfortunately, yes. This stunningly gorgeous film, based on the novel of Henry James, is a superior piece of movie making that cannot be denied. The three actors, Bonham Carter, Roache, and Elliott are extremely compelling in their difficult roles and all of the lesser cast members do fine work, too. Then, the setting in Italy, mostly, is lovely, with cinematography of the very finest. Costumes, too, are gorgeous, especially Elliott's garments and accessories. But, naturally, it is the powerful story of love and deception, with tragic results, that is the strongest asset of all. It should be stated that there are a couple of explicitly sexual scenes that might upset a few viewers. But, for the majority of film fans, they will be accepted as a necessary part of the story's elements. If you have never picked up this film, don't delay! Wings of the Dove is a soaring achievement that should be seen by everyone who loves great cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unforgettable story of love and desire set in Edwardian England.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the classic novel by Henry James,Iain Softley's 1997 adaptation features one of Helena Bonham Carters best performances,an ending that will stick in your memory long after the films finished and breathtaking period costumes designed by Sandy Powell.A timeless love story blighted by restrictions of class and money which will move you like no other. London 1910,spirited and beautiful Kate Croy(Helena Bonham Carter)is deeply in love with kind hearted but penniless journalist Merton Densher(Linus Roache).However since Kate became the ward of her wealthy aunt Maude(Charlotte Rampling)she now has no choice but to consider her financial position at all times.Especially as her aunt sends money to her alcoholic father Lionel(Michael Gambon).This drives a wedge between Kate and Merton and she soon finds herself being courted by the wealthy Lord Mark(Alex Jennings). When Kate befriends the outgoing yet fragile Millie Theale(Alison Elliott)she hatches a plan to get her to leave her fortune to Merton by bringing the two together knowing Millie is seriously ill and may die.However the plan backfires when Milton visits the women in Venice and really does come to care for Millie and falls in love with her. And so begins Kates quest to try and reclaim Mertons heart even though it may now completely belong to Millie.A haunting love story with beautiful location work and memorable performances,Wings Of The Dove will stay with you long after it's over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deception, Love, Jealousy in 1910
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wings of the Dove is a sinister, fascinating love story. Helena Bonham Carter plays Kate Croy, an ambitious but poor young woman who lives on the generosity of a rich aunt. Unable to live poor but not wanting to surrender to the husband her aunt is trying to find for her, she hatches a genius and simple plan: to let her boyfriend, Merton Densher (Linus Roache) seduce the rich and dying American millionaire Millie (Alison Elliott) so that she will leave all her money to him. Carter shines in this movie and her performance is one of the main reasons to watch it. It's one of those rare performances in which all the character's thoughts and feelings are transmitted by the eyes; Carter's eyes are always expressive, she barely needs any dialogue. And yet Hossein Amini's screenplay is also one of the brighter aspects of the movie. I cannot judge ho well he adapted the novel since I haven't yet read it, but as a movie it's a joy: each dialogue is essential, precise and enjoyable; no words are wasted or out of place. The movie's pacing is constant, deceptively calm but always filled with tension, for deception is pretty much the theme of the movie: how far will someone go to deceive another, and what effect will it have on them? For Merton the moral consequences of the deception haunt him as he realizes he may be falling in love with Millie, whereas Kate fears she may be losing her beloved's affection. Between this strange dynamic we have the innocent, cheerful Millie. The movie is also a fine period piece: Sandy Powell got a a much-deserved Oscar nomination for the costume design, but in truth all aspects of the movie deserve merit for their recreation of England in 1910. This movie takes us to places period movies seldom do: the underground system; the interior of bookshops and opium-dens; the interior of museums (in a wonderful sequence the characters attend a Klimt exhibition). And then there's the way Eduardo Serra's cinematography captures Venice in 1910. Serra is an under-appreciated director of cinematography, although he's left his mark in many memorable movies. His best work perhaps remains this movie, in particular the segment taking place in Venice. The way he captures the old canals, the gondolas, the colors at night during Carnival, the decay of the buildings, the beauty of the monuments, perhaps surpass the classic Death In Venice. The Wings of the Dove was a pleasant surprise, an underrated movie that caught me completely by surprise with its perfection. Although it was nominated for several Oscars back in 1998, it seems time has forgotten it. That's a pity, but for those who dare to give it a look, it'll be a huge source of joy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Did Someone Say Henry James -- Please Wait While I Shoot Myself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inevitable question will be: is "The Wings of the Dove" faithful to its source material? I, alas, can't answer that question for you, because to me Henry James's novel was 800 pages of random words strung together in ways that resembled sentences but made absolutely no other kind of sense. I'd rather be bludgeoned to death with one of his books than ever have to read another one -- the movie version could have featured transvestite cyborgs for all I cared; as long as I wasn't actually having to read it, I was a happy boy. The film is pretty good, about what you'd expect from a period piece based on a famous literary classic. It's got more pizazz than a Merchant-Ivory production, and boasts a great performance from a Merchant-Ivory regular, Helena Bonham Carter. It's nothing special, but probably worth a watch. Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Helena Bonham Carter's Best Received Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although neither of them had anything to do with "Wings of the Dove," it reminded me strongly of the string of Merchant-Ivory films. It's a period film, based on a famous novel (by Henry James), set in gorgeous locations (London and Venice), with magnificent costuming and a largely English cast led by Helena Bonham Carter, who graced many a Merchant-Ivory film. "Wings of the Dove" is widely regarded as her finest performance. It earned an Oscar nomination. Although she lost out to Helen Hunt, many critics thought she deserved the honor more. Here she plays Kate Croy, the impoverished niece of her wealthy Aunt Maude (Charlotte Rampling) in love with a handsome, impecunious radical (Linus Roache) and decidedly not in love with her Aunt's choice, Lord Mark (Alex Jennings). I won't give away the scheme that is at the root of the story but Bonham Carter is both distinctively beautiful and a powerful actress. Only Rampling holds her own -- in a much less prominent role, although Michael Gambon in a small part as Kate's ne'er do well father is excellent (as always). Subsequent to "Wings of the Dove," Bonham Carter drifted in the direction of films (the Harry Potter series, for example) that failed to utilize her enormous talent or take full advantage of her slightly unusual but distinctive beauty. She's still young enough to make a big splash at some point in the future but she seems to have lost the urge to make the most of her considerable talent. If so, this film, which she made at the age of 31, may turn out in retrospect to have been her career high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You think love is sexual chemistry, think again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (zfiany@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie which might be overlooked for the romantic side of it because some people tend to judge a movie as trash if it is about romance. Well, I agree but not all romantic movies are the same. There are romantic movies that have messages which go beyond the emotion of love to the twin emotions jealousy, envy, sexual desires, respect, humanity, sacred love, pain and many others. All these feelings you can still experience in a romantic movie cooked well. Wings of dove is a movie with a plot and actually there is a part in the middle of the movie where if you pay attention carefully you might be able to understand what's going on before the story starts revealing its chapters. Actors are great; Helena Bonham Carter is indeed good in this role and Alison Elliotte is just as good and even better. Linus Roache also knows how to exhibit his transmitting emotions in a brilliant way. He knew how to play the difference which is a thin line between love and desire. You only have to guess whom he loved and whom he desired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
