<filme>
 <id>
  316
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119822
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Melhor &Eacute; Imposs&iacute;vel
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A single mother/waitress, a misanthropic author, and a gay artist form an unlikely friendship after the artist is in an accident.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  New York City. Melvin Udall, a cranky, bigoted, obsessive-compulsive writer, finds his life turned upside down when neighboring gay artist Simon is hospitalized and his dog is entrusted to Melvin. In addition, Carol, the only waitress who will tolerate him, must leave work to care for her sick son, making it impossible for Melvin to eat breakfast.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   artist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dog
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   waitress
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   neighbor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   writer
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   James L. Brooks
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Mark Andrus
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   James L. Brooks
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jack Nicholson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Helen Hunt
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Greg Kinnear
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jack you makes my 20 bucks valuable!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Honestly at beginning I spent my 20 bucks for Helen, she is beautiful, elegant and adorable. In addition, Hunt got Oscar via this movie. However, after watching it, I think I am more lucky than before when I only went for Hunt but Jack. It is perfect for me to pay money getting a film of which both the leading actor and actress make me excited. Initially, I don't like Jack, as the most time I saw him is not in movies but on the first row of Staples Center where is the host court of L.A. Lakers. His crazy applause for Kobe Bryant annoyed as I don't like the showoffer - No.24 of Lakers. However after this movie one thing I clearly understand is you can't ignore the merits by the defects of a person. Also the guy Jack playing also make me sick, but this guy gets something making me feel good as well. Once again, it gets proof that the annoying guy also gets merits. The movie helps the communities create a harmony neighbourhood. How can you image that an annoying neighbour like Mr Udall can find his true love and the precious friendship. That's it people must get some merits no matter how badass they are. And another important thing is people are changing, so please do not judge them with your old prejudice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The name says it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blacksheep241
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's no need to talk about plot or characters as there's enough reviews already doing that so Ill start off by saying As good As It Gets is Simply one of my favourite movies ever, Melvin is my hero. So much more than a typical romantic comedy. The humour is subtle but perfect with some real laugh out loud moments mixed into the general smooth quirkiness, the pace of the movie is perfect, the acting is sublime. Nicholson deservedly gets most of the plaudits for the acting in this, but every character in it could not be better portrayed, even the dog Verdell could teach lassie a thing or two about acting. I've grown really fond of every character in it. I smile from start to finish each time I've watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fantastic film with a great lead performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jafar Iqbal
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A friendship starts to develop between a gay artist, a single mother working as a waitress, and a misanthropist, when the artist is left hospitalised after an attack. The three start to become somewhat dependent on one another, against their own expectations. 'As Good As It Gets' is one of those movies that I remember seeing the trailer of, but never felt the need to see. Just seemed like a boring rom-com with actors I didn't really care about. 'As Good As It Gets' is, in fact, an incredibly funny and quirky movie that was fully deserving of the Oscars that it won. The script is the strong-point of the movie. Issues of homophobia, racism, misogyny and countless other prejudices are touched with a sharp, cynical twang. Emotional moments are slapped in the face by cutting jokes, never letting the audience settle in. A script is only as good as the people who recite it, though, and there's a reason why Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt both won Oscars for their performances. Sure, everyone is else as just as good, but the two leads are magnetic. Nicholson does a perfect job of playing the grumpy Melvin Udall, and he never really stops being grumpy; and this works excellently in response to Helen Hunt's exhausted but ever-optimistic Carol Connelly. The chemistry between the two is top-notch. You could argue that, perhaps, that the film goes on too long. It's over two hours long, when ninety minutes would have been absolutely fine. That extra time allows the film-makers to populate the film with other slightly bizarre characters, all adding to the general acerbic aura of the film. However, it's two hours of excellent acting, breathing beautiful life into some excellently written dialogue. Definitely worth a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You make me want to be a better man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets positions itself from the get-go as the romantic comedy to recommend to people who don't like romantic comedies. The first scene establishes Melvin (Jack Nicholson) as a cold asshole, the second reveals his OCD, establishing him altogether as a guy you wouldn't normally find in a romcom, while also getting people who are bummed about being forced to see the film on board. In the third, however, we find Melvin writing romantic literature, pointing out the direction of the film. Shot from behind some shelves, we are told that his sensitive side is hidden only deep beneath, but as the camera moves to the other side of the shelves for the next shot, we also know that this side will be uncovered eventually. The grittiness of the film is pretty much limited to Nicholson's unusually bad behavior and allowing the actors to curse, which is hardy enough to subvert genre conventions. Other than that, there's not much originality in the "unlikely love" trope or the gay supporting characters. But as always, just because we know A and B does not mean there isn't any fun to be had getting there. There's a really weird pacing to this film. As described above, the protagonist is presented very economically, as is his counterpart Carol (Helen Hunt), but then it feels like the film noodles around for like an hour, which only feels partly necessary for developing the characters and their relations further. In any case there is really no need for this film to be more than two hours long. Once the unlikely trio Melvin, Carol, and Melvin's gay neighbor Simon go on their trip, though, the film becomes a lot of fun. Comedies rarely make me laugh when I'm alone but both "I'm afraid he might pull the stiff one-eye on me" and something about "whether crabs were in season now" made me lose it. The film also delivers in the sweetness and romance department; "You make me want to be a better man" is one of the most heartwarming lines ever. I think one of the measures of success is if you want the lead characters to get together at the end of the film. As an incurable cynic, I wouldn't have minded if the only victory was the suggestion that Melvin's ailment was improving (by him forgetting to lock his door and finally stepping on some tiles), but the mere fact that I wasn't bothered by the happy ending was a small victory in itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this a romantic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callielovespink
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow the misogynist falls in love with a woman 20 years younger than him. That is the plot to this movie "How do you write women so well?" "I take away reason and accountability." How does someone who says that have the capability to care for a woman while hating women? I get that he is a curmudgeon. But it was so poorly done and inauthentic. The OCD did not seem authentic authentic either. An attempt at Beauty and the Beast becomes Beauty and the Creepy-50-year-old. Not a metamorphosis that I would sit through again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!... But too long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very well scripted with some really great one-liners; mostly delivered by Jack Nicholson; although there is one point where Greg Kinnear does a rather good impression. Both Jack and Helen Hunt put in great performances that were worthy of praise. My main niggle is that it is way too long; it could have easily been shortened by at least 20 minutes and that would have maybe given it a little more punch. Not that I was bored you understand, far from it, I just felt it would have benefited from being a little shorter. Enough of that; it's a very well made film with some excellent performances and a touching, well written, script. Well worth a look. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.7/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Do this Won Anything?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets is a romantic comedy that rocked the 1998 Oscar ceremony but nobody really cares or even remembers it. Yes, there are some good lines, the actors are really likable and the performances gel together well for a romantic comedy about misfits. But is this really a classic romantic comedy with unforgettable performances and iconic scenes that will keep on living inn our popular culture? The answer is no, hell no. It's way too long, very simplistic and absolutely unremarkable in every way you look at it. Jack Nicholson gives his usual crazy, over the top performance you have seen before and it rivals his work in Departed at being cartoonshly silly. This isn't a good performance and not in the same league as his work in Chinatown or One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest. Helen Hunt does her usual performance too and it's a shame, since she can do much better. There was hardly any Academy award winning material here. Yeah, the actors did do a good job playing the simplistic script and elevated the mediocre material. I don't hate this this film or even dislike it. I liked it just fine but it way too long and tries way too hard at being a Woody Allen film. If you like the cast and enjoy watching something like this, go see it. It's not bad just painfully overrated in its time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Likable movie about an unlikable guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very interesting movie in that it immediately establishes Jack Nicholson as a terrible person and then spends the rest of the movie trying to convince you he's better than you'd think. Nicholson is up to the challenge, being monstrous in the beginning and then slowly softening, but never flattening out, the rough edges. Hunt is equally excellent with his very convincing portrayal of a Brooklyn waitress, catching the spirit of someone leading a very ordinary life. Like most James L. Brooks movies, this one is quite amusing. It's also rather touching, so much so that I was willing to forgive it for its utter unlikeliness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Good as It Get defines this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chester Ruminski (Chet@callchet.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably my most favorite movie. The only difficulty I personally have Is watching the graphic beating of Simom. But I derived a somewhat relieving observation the last time I watched it. In the middle of the furor of the horrible beating of Simon, one of the thugs said excuse me to another thug as he passed by him. I thought that was hilarious and it softened the effect for me. I have seen the movie at least twenty times and don't remember hearing that before. I was wondering if the dialog was different in subsequent released versions. The part that helps make the movie so important is Melvin defending himself to Carol. He tells her about his medicine and his new resolve to take it. She makes him want to be a better man. That humanizes his recognition of his cold logical compulsive behavior. That he wants to do something about it is a tribute to him and a challenge to everybody else. Tthanks for the great "As Good as It Gets". Chet Ruminski
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breaking Habits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good As It Gets is one of the few examples of a movie that even though it directly comes from the modern Hollywood traditions, it works. Directed by James L. Brooks, the film won 2 Oscars, for the two leading roles: Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt. It was acclaimed fairly well by American audiences and critics. Melvin is a successful writer as well as an obsessive-compulsive misanthropist. He drives himself through a very strict daily routine, building around himself a world of patterns and neat organization. When his gay neighbor is severely hurt, his dog passes on to Melvin's custody for a few weeks: from there, the writer's life will be changed, as he also tries to get closer to the waitress of the diner he goes to every morning. His incredibly rude behavior though will be in the way of his good will. What the main character experiences in the movie is the most predictable trick in Hollywood when it comes to character development: that is, turning a bad man into a good man. Character change is an important part of any kind of fiction storytelling, but in mainstream movies, it's usually an overly-used technique exploited to the max. Although this is exactly what happens in As Good As It Gets, it's not as drastic as it might seem: if in the beginning of the film, Melvin is mean and misanthropic to the extreme, he still keeps it in him throughout the whole movie, and it never quite disappears, even though he's found love. Nicholson, who plays the main character, does a wonderful job in depicting Marvin so bitterly; Helen Hunt also seems very comfortable in her role as Carol. The dialogue has memorable quotes and sparks some laughs and smiles, but also dares to enter into the melodrama, which surprisingly never exceeds in sentimentality. Basically, it's a Romantic comedy without the "I Love You" punch-line, one that is funny and entertaining all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jack you makes my 20 bucks valuable!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Honestly at beginning I spent my 20 bucks for Helen, she is beautiful, elegant and adorable. In addition, Hunt got Oscar via this movie. However, after watching it, I think I am more lucky than before when I only went for Hunt but Jack. It is perfect for me to pay money getting a film of which both the leading actor and actress make me excited. Initially, I don't like Jack, as the most time I saw him is not in movies but on the first row of Staples Center where is the host court of L.A. Lakers. His crazy applause for Kobe Bryant annoyed as I don't like the showoffer - No.24 of Lakers. However after this movie one thing I clearly understand is you can't ignore the merits by the defects of a person. Also the guy Jack playing also make me sick, but this guy gets something making me feel good as well. Once again, it gets proof that the annoying guy also gets merits. The movie helps the communities create a harmony neighbourhood. How can you image that an annoying neighbour like Mr Udall can find his true love and the precious friendship. That's it people must get some merits no matter how badass they are. And another important thing is people are changing, so please do not judge them with your old prejudice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The name says it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blacksheep241
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's no need to talk about plot or characters as there's enough reviews already doing that so Ill start off by saying As good As It Gets is Simply one of my favourite movies ever, Melvin is my hero. So much more than a typical romantic comedy. The humour is subtle but perfect with some real laugh out loud moments mixed into the general smooth quirkiness, the pace of the movie is perfect, the acting is sublime. Nicholson deservedly gets most of the plaudits for the acting in this, but every character in it could not be better portrayed, even the dog Verdell could teach lassie a thing or two about acting. I've grown really fond of every character in it. I smile from start to finish each time I've watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fantastic film with a great lead performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jafar Iqbal
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A friendship starts to develop between a gay artist, a single mother working as a waitress, and a misanthropist, when the artist is left hospitalised after an attack. The three start to become somewhat dependent on one another, against their own expectations. 'As Good As It Gets' is one of those movies that I remember seeing the trailer of, but never felt the need to see. Just seemed like a boring rom-com with actors I didn't really care about. 'As Good As It Gets' is, in fact, an incredibly funny and quirky movie that was fully deserving of the Oscars that it won. The script is the strong-point of the movie. Issues of homophobia, racism, misogyny and countless other prejudices are touched with a sharp, cynical twang. Emotional moments are slapped in the face by cutting jokes, never letting the audience settle in. A script is only as good as the people who recite it, though, and there's a reason why Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt both won Oscars for their performances. Sure, everyone is else as just as good, but the two leads are magnetic. Nicholson does a perfect job of playing the grumpy Melvin Udall, and he never really stops being grumpy; and this works excellently in response to Helen Hunt's exhausted but ever-optimistic Carol Connelly. The chemistry between the two is top-notch. You could argue that, perhaps, that the film goes on too long. It's over two hours long, when ninety minutes would have been absolutely fine. That extra time allows the film-makers to populate the film with other slightly bizarre characters, all adding to the general acerbic aura of the film. However, it's two hours of excellent acting, breathing beautiful life into some excellently written dialogue. Definitely worth a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You make me want to be a better man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets positions itself from the get-go as the romantic comedy to recommend to people who don't like romantic comedies. The first scene establishes Melvin (Jack Nicholson) as a cold asshole, the second reveals his OCD, establishing him altogether as a guy you wouldn't normally find in a romcom, while also getting people who are bummed about being forced to see the film on board. In the third, however, we find Melvin writing romantic literature, pointing out the direction of the film. Shot from behind some shelves, we are told that his sensitive side is hidden only deep beneath, but as the camera moves to the other side of the shelves for the next shot, we also know that this side will be uncovered eventually. The grittiness of the film is pretty much limited to Nicholson's unusually bad behavior and allowing the actors to curse, which is hardy enough to subvert genre conventions. Other than that, there's not much originality in the "unlikely love" trope or the gay supporting characters. But as always, just because we know A and B does not mean there isn't any fun to be had getting there. There's a really weird pacing to this film. As described above, the protagonist is presented very economically, as is his counterpart Carol (Helen Hunt), but then it feels like the film noodles around for like an hour, which only feels partly necessary for developing the characters and their relations further. In any case there is really no need for this film to be more than two hours long. Once the unlikely trio Melvin, Carol, and Melvin's gay neighbor Simon go on their trip, though, the film becomes a lot of fun. Comedies rarely make me laugh when I'm alone but both "I'm afraid he might pull the stiff one-eye on me" and something about "whether crabs were in season now" made me lose it. The film also delivers in the sweetness and romance department; "You make me want to be a better man" is one of the most heartwarming lines ever. I think one of the measures of success is if you want the lead characters to get together at the end of the film. As an incurable cynic, I wouldn't have minded if the only victory was the suggestion that Melvin's ailment was improving (by him forgetting to lock his door and finally stepping on some tiles), but the mere fact that I wasn't bothered by the happy ending was a small victory in itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this a romantic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callielovespink
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow the misogynist falls in love with a woman 20 years younger than him. That is the plot to this movie "How do you write women so well?" "I take away reason and accountability." How does someone who says that have the capability to care for a woman while hating women? I get that he is a curmudgeon. But it was so poorly done and inauthentic. The OCD did not seem authentic authentic either. An attempt at Beauty and the Beast becomes Beauty and the Creepy-50-year-old. Not a metamorphosis that I would sit through again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!... But too long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very well scripted with some really great one-liners; mostly delivered by Jack Nicholson; although there is one point where Greg Kinnear does a rather good impression. Both Jack and Helen Hunt put in great performances that were worthy of praise. My main niggle is that it is way too long; it could have easily been shortened by at least 20 minutes and that would have maybe given it a little more punch. Not that I was bored you understand, far from it, I just felt it would have benefited from being a little shorter. Enough of that; it's a very well made film with some excellent performances and a touching, well written, script. Well worth a look. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.7/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Do this Won Anything?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets is a romantic comedy that rocked the 1998 Oscar ceremony but nobody really cares or even remembers it. Yes, there are some good lines, the actors are really likable and the performances gel together well for a romantic comedy about misfits. But is this really a classic romantic comedy with unforgettable performances and iconic scenes that will keep on living inn our popular culture? The answer is no, hell no. It's way too long, very simplistic and absolutely unremarkable in every way you look at it. Jack Nicholson gives his usual crazy, over the top performance you have seen before and it rivals his work in Departed at being cartoonshly silly. This isn't a good performance and not in the same league as his work in Chinatown or One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest. Helen Hunt does her usual performance too and it's a shame, since she can do much better. There was hardly any Academy award winning material here. Yeah, the actors did do a good job playing the simplistic script and elevated the mediocre material. I don't hate this this film or even dislike it. I liked it just fine but it way too long and tries way too hard at being a Woody Allen film. If you like the cast and enjoy watching something like this, go see it. It's not bad just painfully overrated in its time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Likable movie about an unlikable guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very interesting movie in that it immediately establishes Jack Nicholson as a terrible person and then spends the rest of the movie trying to convince you he's better than you'd think. Nicholson is up to the challenge, being monstrous in the beginning and then slowly softening, but never flattening out, the rough edges. Hunt is equally excellent with his very convincing portrayal of a Brooklyn waitress, catching the spirit of someone leading a very ordinary life. Like most James L. Brooks movies, this one is quite amusing. It's also rather touching, so much so that I was willing to forgive it for its utter unlikeliness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Good as It Get defines this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chester Ruminski (Chet@callchet.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably my most favorite movie. The only difficulty I personally have Is watching the graphic beating of Simom. But I derived a somewhat relieving observation the last time I watched it. In the middle of the furor of the horrible beating of Simon, one of the thugs said excuse me to another thug as he passed by him. I thought that was hilarious and it softened the effect for me. I have seen the movie at least twenty times and don't remember hearing that before. I was wondering if the dialog was different in subsequent released versions. The part that helps make the movie so important is Melvin defending himself to Carol. He tells her about his medicine and his new resolve to take it. She makes him want to be a better man. That humanizes his recognition of his cold logical compulsive behavior. That he wants to do something about it is a tribute to him and a challenge to everybody else. Tthanks for the great "As Good as It Gets". Chet Ruminski
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breaking Habits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good As It Gets is one of the few examples of a movie that even though it directly comes from the modern Hollywood traditions, it works. Directed by James L. Brooks, the film won 2 Oscars, for the two leading roles: Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt. It was acclaimed fairly well by American audiences and critics. Melvin is a successful writer as well as an obsessive-compulsive misanthropist. He drives himself through a very strict daily routine, building around himself a world of patterns and neat organization. When his gay neighbor is severely hurt, his dog passes on to Melvin's custody for a few weeks: from there, the writer's life will be changed, as he also tries to get closer to the waitress of the diner he goes to every morning. His incredibly rude behavior though will be in the way of his good will. What the main character experiences in the movie is the most predictable trick in Hollywood when it comes to character development: that is, turning a bad man into a good man. Character change is an important part of any kind of fiction storytelling, but in mainstream movies, it's usually an overly-used technique exploited to the max. Although this is exactly what happens in As Good As It Gets, it's not as drastic as it might seem: if in the beginning of the film, Melvin is mean and misanthropic to the extreme, he still keeps it in him throughout the whole movie, and it never quite disappears, even though he's found love. Nicholson, who plays the main character, does a wonderful job in depicting Marvin so bitterly; Helen Hunt also seems very comfortable in her role as Carol. The dialogue has memorable quotes and sparks some laughs and smiles, but also dares to enter into the melodrama, which surprisingly never exceeds in sentimentality. Basically, it's a Romantic comedy without the "I Love You" punch-line, one that is funny and entertaining all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jack you makes my 20 bucks valuable!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Honestly at beginning I spent my 20 bucks for Helen, she is beautiful, elegant and adorable. In addition, Hunt got Oscar via this movie. However, after watching it, I think I am more lucky than before when I only went for Hunt but Jack. It is perfect for me to pay money getting a film of which both the leading actor and actress make me excited. Initially, I don't like Jack, as the most time I saw him is not in movies but on the first row of Staples Center where is the host court of L.A. Lakers. His crazy applause for Kobe Bryant annoyed as I don't like the showoffer - No.24 of Lakers. However after this movie one thing I clearly understand is you can't ignore the merits by the defects of a person. Also the guy Jack playing also make me sick, but this guy gets something making me feel good as well. Once again, it gets proof that the annoying guy also gets merits. The movie helps the communities create a harmony neighbourhood. How can you image that an annoying neighbour like Mr Udall can find his true love and the precious friendship. That's it people must get some merits no matter how badass they are. And another important thing is people are changing, so please do not judge them with your old prejudice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The name says it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blacksheep241
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's no need to talk about plot or characters as there's enough reviews already doing that so Ill start off by saying As good As It Gets is Simply one of my favourite movies ever, Melvin is my hero. So much more than a typical romantic comedy. The humour is subtle but perfect with some real laugh out loud moments mixed into the general smooth quirkiness, the pace of the movie is perfect, the acting is sublime. Nicholson deservedly gets most of the plaudits for the acting in this, but every character in it could not be better portrayed, even the dog Verdell could teach lassie a thing or two about acting. I've grown really fond of every character in it. I smile from start to finish each time I've watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fantastic film with a great lead performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jafar Iqbal
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A friendship starts to develop between a gay artist, a single mother working as a waitress, and a misanthropist, when the artist is left hospitalised after an attack. The three start to become somewhat dependent on one another, against their own expectations. 'As Good As It Gets' is one of those movies that I remember seeing the trailer of, but never felt the need to see. Just seemed like a boring rom-com with actors I didn't really care about. 'As Good As It Gets' is, in fact, an incredibly funny and quirky movie that was fully deserving of the Oscars that it won. The script is the strong-point of the movie. Issues of homophobia, racism, misogyny and countless other prejudices are touched with a sharp, cynical twang. Emotional moments are slapped in the face by cutting jokes, never letting the audience settle in. A script is only as good as the people who recite it, though, and there's a reason why Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt both won Oscars for their performances. Sure, everyone is else as just as good, but the two leads are magnetic. Nicholson does a perfect job of playing the grumpy Melvin Udall, and he never really stops being grumpy; and this works excellently in response to Helen Hunt's exhausted but ever-optimistic Carol Connelly. The chemistry between the two is top-notch. You could argue that, perhaps, that the film goes on too long. It's over two hours long, when ninety minutes would have been absolutely fine. That extra time allows the film-makers to populate the film with other slightly bizarre characters, all adding to the general acerbic aura of the film. However, it's two hours of excellent acting, breathing beautiful life into some excellently written dialogue. Definitely worth a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You make me want to be a better man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets positions itself from the get-go as the romantic comedy to recommend to people who don't like romantic comedies. The first scene establishes Melvin (Jack Nicholson) as a cold asshole, the second reveals his OCD, establishing him altogether as a guy you wouldn't normally find in a romcom, while also getting people who are bummed about being forced to see the film on board. In the third, however, we find Melvin writing romantic literature, pointing out the direction of the film. Shot from behind some shelves, we are told that his sensitive side is hidden only deep beneath, but as the camera moves to the other side of the shelves for the next shot, we also know that this side will be uncovered eventually. The grittiness of the film is pretty much limited to Nicholson's unusually bad behavior and allowing the actors to curse, which is hardy enough to subvert genre conventions. Other than that, there's not much originality in the "unlikely love" trope or the gay supporting characters. But as always, just because we know A and B does not mean there isn't any fun to be had getting there. There's a really weird pacing to this film. As described above, the protagonist is presented very economically, as is his counterpart Carol (Helen Hunt), but then it feels like the film noodles around for like an hour, which only feels partly necessary for developing the characters and their relations further. In any case there is really no need for this film to be more than two hours long. Once the unlikely trio Melvin, Carol, and Melvin's gay neighbor Simon go on their trip, though, the film becomes a lot of fun. Comedies rarely make me laugh when I'm alone but both "I'm afraid he might pull the stiff one-eye on me" and something about "whether crabs were in season now" made me lose it. The film also delivers in the sweetness and romance department; "You make me want to be a better man" is one of the most heartwarming lines ever. I think one of the measures of success is if you want the lead characters to get together at the end of the film. As an incurable cynic, I wouldn't have minded if the only victory was the suggestion that Melvin's ailment was improving (by him forgetting to lock his door and finally stepping on some tiles), but the mere fact that I wasn't bothered by the happy ending was a small victory in itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this a romantic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callielovespink
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow the misogynist falls in love with a woman 20 years younger than him. That is the plot to this movie "How do you write women so well?" "I take away reason and accountability." How does someone who says that have the capability to care for a woman while hating women? I get that he is a curmudgeon. But it was so poorly done and inauthentic. The OCD did not seem authentic authentic either. An attempt at Beauty and the Beast becomes Beauty and the Creepy-50-year-old. Not a metamorphosis that I would sit through again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!... But too long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very well scripted with some really great one-liners; mostly delivered by Jack Nicholson; although there is one point where Greg Kinnear does a rather good impression. Both Jack and Helen Hunt put in great performances that were worthy of praise. My main niggle is that it is way too long; it could have easily been shortened by at least 20 minutes and that would have maybe given it a little more punch. Not that I was bored you understand, far from it, I just felt it would have benefited from being a little shorter. Enough of that; it's a very well made film with some excellent performances and a touching, well written, script. Well worth a look. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.7/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Do this Won Anything?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets is a romantic comedy that rocked the 1998 Oscar ceremony but nobody really cares or even remembers it. Yes, there are some good lines, the actors are really likable and the performances gel together well for a romantic comedy about misfits. But is this really a classic romantic comedy with unforgettable performances and iconic scenes that will keep on living inn our popular culture? The answer is no, hell no. It's way too long, very simplistic and absolutely unremarkable in every way you look at it. Jack Nicholson gives his usual crazy, over the top performance you have seen before and it rivals his work in Departed at being cartoonshly silly. This isn't a good performance and not in the same league as his work in Chinatown or One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest. Helen Hunt does her usual performance too and it's a shame, since she can do much better. There was hardly any Academy award winning material here. Yeah, the actors did do a good job playing the simplistic script and elevated the mediocre material. I don't hate this this film or even dislike it. I liked it just fine but it way too long and tries way too hard at being a Woody Allen film. If you like the cast and enjoy watching something like this, go see it. It's not bad just painfully overrated in its time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Likable movie about an unlikable guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very interesting movie in that it immediately establishes Jack Nicholson as a terrible person and then spends the rest of the movie trying to convince you he's better than you'd think. Nicholson is up to the challenge, being monstrous in the beginning and then slowly softening, but never flattening out, the rough edges. Hunt is equally excellent with his very convincing portrayal of a Brooklyn waitress, catching the spirit of someone leading a very ordinary life. Like most James L. Brooks movies, this one is quite amusing. It's also rather touching, so much so that I was willing to forgive it for its utter unlikeliness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Good as It Get defines this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chester Ruminski (Chet@callchet.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably my most favorite movie. The only difficulty I personally have Is watching the graphic beating of Simom. But I derived a somewhat relieving observation the last time I watched it. In the middle of the furor of the horrible beating of Simon, one of the thugs said excuse me to another thug as he passed by him. I thought that was hilarious and it softened the effect for me. I have seen the movie at least twenty times and don't remember hearing that before. I was wondering if the dialog was different in subsequent released versions. The part that helps make the movie so important is Melvin defending himself to Carol. He tells her about his medicine and his new resolve to take it. She makes him want to be a better man. That humanizes his recognition of his cold logical compulsive behavior. That he wants to do something about it is a tribute to him and a challenge to everybody else. Tthanks for the great "As Good as It Gets". Chet Ruminski
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breaking Habits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good As It Gets is one of the few examples of a movie that even though it directly comes from the modern Hollywood traditions, it works. Directed by James L. Brooks, the film won 2 Oscars, for the two leading roles: Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt. It was acclaimed fairly well by American audiences and critics. Melvin is a successful writer as well as an obsessive-compulsive misanthropist. He drives himself through a very strict daily routine, building around himself a world of patterns and neat organization. When his gay neighbor is severely hurt, his dog passes on to Melvin's custody for a few weeks: from there, the writer's life will be changed, as he also tries to get closer to the waitress of the diner he goes to every morning. His incredibly rude behavior though will be in the way of his good will. What the main character experiences in the movie is the most predictable trick in Hollywood when it comes to character development: that is, turning a bad man into a good man. Character change is an important part of any kind of fiction storytelling, but in mainstream movies, it's usually an overly-used technique exploited to the max. Although this is exactly what happens in As Good As It Gets, it's not as drastic as it might seem: if in the beginning of the film, Melvin is mean and misanthropic to the extreme, he still keeps it in him throughout the whole movie, and it never quite disappears, even though he's found love. Nicholson, who plays the main character, does a wonderful job in depicting Marvin so bitterly; Helen Hunt also seems very comfortable in her role as Carol. The dialogue has memorable quotes and sparks some laughs and smiles, but also dares to enter into the melodrama, which surprisingly never exceeds in sentimentality. Basically, it's a Romantic comedy without the "I Love You" punch-line, one that is funny and entertaining all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jack you makes my 20 bucks valuable!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Honestly at beginning I spent my 20 bucks for Helen, she is beautiful, elegant and adorable. In addition, Hunt got Oscar via this movie. However, after watching it, I think I am more lucky than before when I only went for Hunt but Jack. It is perfect for me to pay money getting a film of which both the leading actor and actress make me excited. Initially, I don't like Jack, as the most time I saw him is not in movies but on the first row of Staples Center where is the host court of L.A. Lakers. His crazy applause for Kobe Bryant annoyed as I don't like the showoffer - No.24 of Lakers. However after this movie one thing I clearly understand is you can't ignore the merits by the defects of a person. Also the guy Jack playing also make me sick, but this guy gets something making me feel good as well. Once again, it gets proof that the annoying guy also gets merits. The movie helps the communities create a harmony neighbourhood. How can you image that an annoying neighbour like Mr Udall can find his true love and the precious friendship. That's it people must get some merits no matter how badass they are. And another important thing is people are changing, so please do not judge them with your old prejudice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The name says it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blacksheep241
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's no need to talk about plot or characters as there's enough reviews already doing that so Ill start off by saying As good As It Gets is Simply one of my favourite movies ever, Melvin is my hero. So much more than a typical romantic comedy. The humour is subtle but perfect with some real laugh out loud moments mixed into the general smooth quirkiness, the pace of the movie is perfect, the acting is sublime. Nicholson deservedly gets most of the plaudits for the acting in this, but every character in it could not be better portrayed, even the dog Verdell could teach lassie a thing or two about acting. I've grown really fond of every character in it. I smile from start to finish each time I've watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fantastic film with a great lead performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jafar Iqbal
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A friendship starts to develop between a gay artist, a single mother working as a waitress, and a misanthropist, when the artist is left hospitalised after an attack. The three start to become somewhat dependent on one another, against their own expectations. 'As Good As It Gets' is one of those movies that I remember seeing the trailer of, but never felt the need to see. Just seemed like a boring rom-com with actors I didn't really care about. 'As Good As It Gets' is, in fact, an incredibly funny and quirky movie that was fully deserving of the Oscars that it won. The script is the strong-point of the movie. Issues of homophobia, racism, misogyny and countless other prejudices are touched with a sharp, cynical twang. Emotional moments are slapped in the face by cutting jokes, never letting the audience settle in. A script is only as good as the people who recite it, though, and there's a reason why Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt both won Oscars for their performances. Sure, everyone is else as just as good, but the two leads are magnetic. Nicholson does a perfect job of playing the grumpy Melvin Udall, and he never really stops being grumpy; and this works excellently in response to Helen Hunt's exhausted but ever-optimistic Carol Connelly. The chemistry between the two is top-notch. You could argue that, perhaps, that the film goes on too long. It's over two hours long, when ninety minutes would have been absolutely fine. That extra time allows the film-makers to populate the film with other slightly bizarre characters, all adding to the general acerbic aura of the film. However, it's two hours of excellent acting, breathing beautiful life into some excellently written dialogue. Definitely worth a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You make me want to be a better man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets positions itself from the get-go as the romantic comedy to recommend to people who don't like romantic comedies. The first scene establishes Melvin (Jack Nicholson) as a cold asshole, the second reveals his OCD, establishing him altogether as a guy you wouldn't normally find in a romcom, while also getting people who are bummed about being forced to see the film on board. In the third, however, we find Melvin writing romantic literature, pointing out the direction of the film. Shot from behind some shelves, we are told that his sensitive side is hidden only deep beneath, but as the camera moves to the other side of the shelves for the next shot, we also know that this side will be uncovered eventually. The grittiness of the film is pretty much limited to Nicholson's unusually bad behavior and allowing the actors to curse, which is hardy enough to subvert genre conventions. Other than that, there's not much originality in the "unlikely love" trope or the gay supporting characters. But as always, just because we know A and B does not mean there isn't any fun to be had getting there. There's a really weird pacing to this film. As described above, the protagonist is presented very economically, as is his counterpart Carol (Helen Hunt), but then it feels like the film noodles around for like an hour, which only feels partly necessary for developing the characters and their relations further. In any case there is really no need for this film to be more than two hours long. Once the unlikely trio Melvin, Carol, and Melvin's gay neighbor Simon go on their trip, though, the film becomes a lot of fun. Comedies rarely make me laugh when I'm alone but both "I'm afraid he might pull the stiff one-eye on me" and something about "whether crabs were in season now" made me lose it. The film also delivers in the sweetness and romance department; "You make me want to be a better man" is one of the most heartwarming lines ever. I think one of the measures of success is if you want the lead characters to get together at the end of the film. As an incurable cynic, I wouldn't have minded if the only victory was the suggestion that Melvin's ailment was improving (by him forgetting to lock his door and finally stepping on some tiles), but the mere fact that I wasn't bothered by the happy ending was a small victory in itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this a romantic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callielovespink
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow the misogynist falls in love with a woman 20 years younger than him. That is the plot to this movie "How do you write women so well?" "I take away reason and accountability." How does someone who says that have the capability to care for a woman while hating women? I get that he is a curmudgeon. But it was so poorly done and inauthentic. The OCD did not seem authentic authentic either. An attempt at Beauty and the Beast becomes Beauty and the Creepy-50-year-old. Not a metamorphosis that I would sit through again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!... But too long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very well scripted with some really great one-liners; mostly delivered by Jack Nicholson; although there is one point where Greg Kinnear does a rather good impression. Both Jack and Helen Hunt put in great performances that were worthy of praise. My main niggle is that it is way too long; it could have easily been shortened by at least 20 minutes and that would have maybe given it a little more punch. Not that I was bored you understand, far from it, I just felt it would have benefited from being a little shorter. Enough of that; it's a very well made film with some excellent performances and a touching, well written, script. Well worth a look. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.7/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Do this Won Anything?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets is a romantic comedy that rocked the 1998 Oscar ceremony but nobody really cares or even remembers it. Yes, there are some good lines, the actors are really likable and the performances gel together well for a romantic comedy about misfits. But is this really a classic romantic comedy with unforgettable performances and iconic scenes that will keep on living inn our popular culture? The answer is no, hell no. It's way too long, very simplistic and absolutely unremarkable in every way you look at it. Jack Nicholson gives his usual crazy, over the top performance you have seen before and it rivals his work in Departed at being cartoonshly silly. This isn't a good performance and not in the same league as his work in Chinatown or One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest. Helen Hunt does her usual performance too and it's a shame, since she can do much better. There was hardly any Academy award winning material here. Yeah, the actors did do a good job playing the simplistic script and elevated the mediocre material. I don't hate this this film or even dislike it. I liked it just fine but it way too long and tries way too hard at being a Woody Allen film. If you like the cast and enjoy watching something like this, go see it. It's not bad just painfully overrated in its time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Likable movie about an unlikable guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very interesting movie in that it immediately establishes Jack Nicholson as a terrible person and then spends the rest of the movie trying to convince you he's better than you'd think. Nicholson is up to the challenge, being monstrous in the beginning and then slowly softening, but never flattening out, the rough edges. Hunt is equally excellent with his very convincing portrayal of a Brooklyn waitress, catching the spirit of someone leading a very ordinary life. Like most James L. Brooks movies, this one is quite amusing. It's also rather touching, so much so that I was willing to forgive it for its utter unlikeliness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Good as It Get defines this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chester Ruminski (Chet@callchet.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably my most favorite movie. The only difficulty I personally have Is watching the graphic beating of Simom. But I derived a somewhat relieving observation the last time I watched it. In the middle of the furor of the horrible beating of Simon, one of the thugs said excuse me to another thug as he passed by him. I thought that was hilarious and it softened the effect for me. I have seen the movie at least twenty times and don't remember hearing that before. I was wondering if the dialog was different in subsequent released versions. The part that helps make the movie so important is Melvin defending himself to Carol. He tells her about his medicine and his new resolve to take it. She makes him want to be a better man. That humanizes his recognition of his cold logical compulsive behavior. That he wants to do something about it is a tribute to him and a challenge to everybody else. Tthanks for the great "As Good as It Gets". Chet Ruminski
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breaking Habits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good As It Gets is one of the few examples of a movie that even though it directly comes from the modern Hollywood traditions, it works. Directed by James L. Brooks, the film won 2 Oscars, for the two leading roles: Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt. It was acclaimed fairly well by American audiences and critics. Melvin is a successful writer as well as an obsessive-compulsive misanthropist. He drives himself through a very strict daily routine, building around himself a world of patterns and neat organization. When his gay neighbor is severely hurt, his dog passes on to Melvin's custody for a few weeks: from there, the writer's life will be changed, as he also tries to get closer to the waitress of the diner he goes to every morning. His incredibly rude behavior though will be in the way of his good will. What the main character experiences in the movie is the most predictable trick in Hollywood when it comes to character development: that is, turning a bad man into a good man. Character change is an important part of any kind of fiction storytelling, but in mainstream movies, it's usually an overly-used technique exploited to the max. Although this is exactly what happens in As Good As It Gets, it's not as drastic as it might seem: if in the beginning of the film, Melvin is mean and misanthropic to the extreme, he still keeps it in him throughout the whole movie, and it never quite disappears, even though he's found love. Nicholson, who plays the main character, does a wonderful job in depicting Marvin so bitterly; Helen Hunt also seems very comfortable in her role as Carol. The dialogue has memorable quotes and sparks some laughs and smiles, but also dares to enter into the melodrama, which surprisingly never exceeds in sentimentality. Basically, it's a Romantic comedy without the "I Love You" punch-line, one that is funny and entertaining all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jack you makes my 20 bucks valuable!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Honestly at beginning I spent my 20 bucks for Helen, she is beautiful, elegant and adorable. In addition, Hunt got Oscar via this movie. However, after watching it, I think I am more lucky than before when I only went for Hunt but Jack. It is perfect for me to pay money getting a film of which both the leading actor and actress make me excited. Initially, I don't like Jack, as the most time I saw him is not in movies but on the first row of Staples Center where is the host court of L.A. Lakers. His crazy applause for Kobe Bryant annoyed as I don't like the showoffer - No.24 of Lakers. However after this movie one thing I clearly understand is you can't ignore the merits by the defects of a person. Also the guy Jack playing also make me sick, but this guy gets something making me feel good as well. Once again, it gets proof that the annoying guy also gets merits. The movie helps the communities create a harmony neighbourhood. How can you image that an annoying neighbour like Mr Udall can find his true love and the precious friendship. That's it people must get some merits no matter how badass they are. And another important thing is people are changing, so please do not judge them with your old prejudice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The name says it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blacksheep241
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's no need to talk about plot or characters as there's enough reviews already doing that so Ill start off by saying As good As It Gets is Simply one of my favourite movies ever, Melvin is my hero. So much more than a typical romantic comedy. The humour is subtle but perfect with some real laugh out loud moments mixed into the general smooth quirkiness, the pace of the movie is perfect, the acting is sublime. Nicholson deservedly gets most of the plaudits for the acting in this, but every character in it could not be better portrayed, even the dog Verdell could teach lassie a thing or two about acting. I've grown really fond of every character in it. I smile from start to finish each time I've watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fantastic film with a great lead performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jafar Iqbal
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A friendship starts to develop between a gay artist, a single mother working as a waitress, and a misanthropist, when the artist is left hospitalised after an attack. The three start to become somewhat dependent on one another, against their own expectations. 'As Good As It Gets' is one of those movies that I remember seeing the trailer of, but never felt the need to see. Just seemed like a boring rom-com with actors I didn't really care about. 'As Good As It Gets' is, in fact, an incredibly funny and quirky movie that was fully deserving of the Oscars that it won. The script is the strong-point of the movie. Issues of homophobia, racism, misogyny and countless other prejudices are touched with a sharp, cynical twang. Emotional moments are slapped in the face by cutting jokes, never letting the audience settle in. A script is only as good as the people who recite it, though, and there's a reason why Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt both won Oscars for their performances. Sure, everyone is else as just as good, but the two leads are magnetic. Nicholson does a perfect job of playing the grumpy Melvin Udall, and he never really stops being grumpy; and this works excellently in response to Helen Hunt's exhausted but ever-optimistic Carol Connelly. The chemistry between the two is top-notch. You could argue that, perhaps, that the film goes on too long. It's over two hours long, when ninety minutes would have been absolutely fine. That extra time allows the film-makers to populate the film with other slightly bizarre characters, all adding to the general acerbic aura of the film. However, it's two hours of excellent acting, breathing beautiful life into some excellently written dialogue. Definitely worth a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You make me want to be a better man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets positions itself from the get-go as the romantic comedy to recommend to people who don't like romantic comedies. The first scene establishes Melvin (Jack Nicholson) as a cold asshole, the second reveals his OCD, establishing him altogether as a guy you wouldn't normally find in a romcom, while also getting people who are bummed about being forced to see the film on board. In the third, however, we find Melvin writing romantic literature, pointing out the direction of the film. Shot from behind some shelves, we are told that his sensitive side is hidden only deep beneath, but as the camera moves to the other side of the shelves for the next shot, we also know that this side will be uncovered eventually. The grittiness of the film is pretty much limited to Nicholson's unusually bad behavior and allowing the actors to curse, which is hardy enough to subvert genre conventions. Other than that, there's not much originality in the "unlikely love" trope or the gay supporting characters. But as always, just because we know A and B does not mean there isn't any fun to be had getting there. There's a really weird pacing to this film. As described above, the protagonist is presented very economically, as is his counterpart Carol (Helen Hunt), but then it feels like the film noodles around for like an hour, which only feels partly necessary for developing the characters and their relations further. In any case there is really no need for this film to be more than two hours long. Once the unlikely trio Melvin, Carol, and Melvin's gay neighbor Simon go on their trip, though, the film becomes a lot of fun. Comedies rarely make me laugh when I'm alone but both "I'm afraid he might pull the stiff one-eye on me" and something about "whether crabs were in season now" made me lose it. The film also delivers in the sweetness and romance department; "You make me want to be a better man" is one of the most heartwarming lines ever. I think one of the measures of success is if you want the lead characters to get together at the end of the film. As an incurable cynic, I wouldn't have minded if the only victory was the suggestion that Melvin's ailment was improving (by him forgetting to lock his door and finally stepping on some tiles), but the mere fact that I wasn't bothered by the happy ending was a small victory in itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this a romantic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callielovespink
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow the misogynist falls in love with a woman 20 years younger than him. That is the plot to this movie "How do you write women so well?" "I take away reason and accountability." How does someone who says that have the capability to care for a woman while hating women? I get that he is a curmudgeon. But it was so poorly done and inauthentic. The OCD did not seem authentic authentic either. An attempt at Beauty and the Beast becomes Beauty and the Creepy-50-year-old. Not a metamorphosis that I would sit through again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!... But too long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very well scripted with some really great one-liners; mostly delivered by Jack Nicholson; although there is one point where Greg Kinnear does a rather good impression. Both Jack and Helen Hunt put in great performances that were worthy of praise. My main niggle is that it is way too long; it could have easily been shortened by at least 20 minutes and that would have maybe given it a little more punch. Not that I was bored you understand, far from it, I just felt it would have benefited from being a little shorter. Enough of that; it's a very well made film with some excellent performances and a touching, well written, script. Well worth a look. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.7/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Do this Won Anything?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets is a romantic comedy that rocked the 1998 Oscar ceremony but nobody really cares or even remembers it. Yes, there are some good lines, the actors are really likable and the performances gel together well for a romantic comedy about misfits. But is this really a classic romantic comedy with unforgettable performances and iconic scenes that will keep on living inn our popular culture? The answer is no, hell no. It's way too long, very simplistic and absolutely unremarkable in every way you look at it. Jack Nicholson gives his usual crazy, over the top performance you have seen before and it rivals his work in Departed at being cartoonshly silly. This isn't a good performance and not in the same league as his work in Chinatown or One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest. Helen Hunt does her usual performance too and it's a shame, since she can do much better. There was hardly any Academy award winning material here. Yeah, the actors did do a good job playing the simplistic script and elevated the mediocre material. I don't hate this this film or even dislike it. I liked it just fine but it way too long and tries way too hard at being a Woody Allen film. If you like the cast and enjoy watching something like this, go see it. It's not bad just painfully overrated in its time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Likable movie about an unlikable guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very interesting movie in that it immediately establishes Jack Nicholson as a terrible person and then spends the rest of the movie trying to convince you he's better than you'd think. Nicholson is up to the challenge, being monstrous in the beginning and then slowly softening, but never flattening out, the rough edges. Hunt is equally excellent with his very convincing portrayal of a Brooklyn waitress, catching the spirit of someone leading a very ordinary life. Like most James L. Brooks movies, this one is quite amusing. It's also rather touching, so much so that I was willing to forgive it for its utter unlikeliness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Good as It Get defines this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chester Ruminski (Chet@callchet.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably my most favorite movie. The only difficulty I personally have Is watching the graphic beating of Simom. But I derived a somewhat relieving observation the last time I watched it. In the middle of the furor of the horrible beating of Simon, one of the thugs said excuse me to another thug as he passed by him. I thought that was hilarious and it softened the effect for me. I have seen the movie at least twenty times and don't remember hearing that before. I was wondering if the dialog was different in subsequent released versions. The part that helps make the movie so important is Melvin defending himself to Carol. He tells her about his medicine and his new resolve to take it. She makes him want to be a better man. That humanizes his recognition of his cold logical compulsive behavior. That he wants to do something about it is a tribute to him and a challenge to everybody else. Tthanks for the great "As Good as It Gets". Chet Ruminski
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breaking Habits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good As It Gets is one of the few examples of a movie that even though it directly comes from the modern Hollywood traditions, it works. Directed by James L. Brooks, the film won 2 Oscars, for the two leading roles: Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt. It was acclaimed fairly well by American audiences and critics. Melvin is a successful writer as well as an obsessive-compulsive misanthropist. He drives himself through a very strict daily routine, building around himself a world of patterns and neat organization. When his gay neighbor is severely hurt, his dog passes on to Melvin's custody for a few weeks: from there, the writer's life will be changed, as he also tries to get closer to the waitress of the diner he goes to every morning. His incredibly rude behavior though will be in the way of his good will. What the main character experiences in the movie is the most predictable trick in Hollywood when it comes to character development: that is, turning a bad man into a good man. Character change is an important part of any kind of fiction storytelling, but in mainstream movies, it's usually an overly-used technique exploited to the max. Although this is exactly what happens in As Good As It Gets, it's not as drastic as it might seem: if in the beginning of the film, Melvin is mean and misanthropic to the extreme, he still keeps it in him throughout the whole movie, and it never quite disappears, even though he's found love. Nicholson, who plays the main character, does a wonderful job in depicting Marvin so bitterly; Helen Hunt also seems very comfortable in her role as Carol. The dialogue has memorable quotes and sparks some laughs and smiles, but also dares to enter into the melodrama, which surprisingly never exceeds in sentimentality. Basically, it's a Romantic comedy without the "I Love You" punch-line, one that is funny and entertaining all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jack you makes my 20 bucks valuable!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Honestly at beginning I spent my 20 bucks for Helen, she is beautiful, elegant and adorable. In addition, Hunt got Oscar via this movie. However, after watching it, I think I am more lucky than before when I only went for Hunt but Jack. It is perfect for me to pay money getting a film of which both the leading actor and actress make me excited. Initially, I don't like Jack, as the most time I saw him is not in movies but on the first row of Staples Center where is the host court of L.A. Lakers. His crazy applause for Kobe Bryant annoyed as I don't like the showoffer - No.24 of Lakers. However after this movie one thing I clearly understand is you can't ignore the merits by the defects of a person. Also the guy Jack playing also make me sick, but this guy gets something making me feel good as well. Once again, it gets proof that the annoying guy also gets merits. The movie helps the communities create a harmony neighbourhood. How can you image that an annoying neighbour like Mr Udall can find his true love and the precious friendship. That's it people must get some merits no matter how badass they are. And another important thing is people are changing, so please do not judge them with your old prejudice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The name says it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blacksheep241
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's no need to talk about plot or characters as there's enough reviews already doing that so Ill start off by saying As good As It Gets is Simply one of my favourite movies ever, Melvin is my hero. So much more than a typical romantic comedy. The humour is subtle but perfect with some real laugh out loud moments mixed into the general smooth quirkiness, the pace of the movie is perfect, the acting is sublime. Nicholson deservedly gets most of the plaudits for the acting in this, but every character in it could not be better portrayed, even the dog Verdell could teach lassie a thing or two about acting. I've grown really fond of every character in it. I smile from start to finish each time I've watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fantastic film with a great lead performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jafar Iqbal
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A friendship starts to develop between a gay artist, a single mother working as a waitress, and a misanthropist, when the artist is left hospitalised after an attack. The three start to become somewhat dependent on one another, against their own expectations. 'As Good As It Gets' is one of those movies that I remember seeing the trailer of, but never felt the need to see. Just seemed like a boring rom-com with actors I didn't really care about. 'As Good As It Gets' is, in fact, an incredibly funny and quirky movie that was fully deserving of the Oscars that it won. The script is the strong-point of the movie. Issues of homophobia, racism, misogyny and countless other prejudices are touched with a sharp, cynical twang. Emotional moments are slapped in the face by cutting jokes, never letting the audience settle in. A script is only as good as the people who recite it, though, and there's a reason why Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt both won Oscars for their performances. Sure, everyone is else as just as good, but the two leads are magnetic. Nicholson does a perfect job of playing the grumpy Melvin Udall, and he never really stops being grumpy; and this works excellently in response to Helen Hunt's exhausted but ever-optimistic Carol Connelly. The chemistry between the two is top-notch. You could argue that, perhaps, that the film goes on too long. It's over two hours long, when ninety minutes would have been absolutely fine. That extra time allows the film-makers to populate the film with other slightly bizarre characters, all adding to the general acerbic aura of the film. However, it's two hours of excellent acting, breathing beautiful life into some excellently written dialogue. Definitely worth a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You make me want to be a better man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets positions itself from the get-go as the romantic comedy to recommend to people who don't like romantic comedies. The first scene establishes Melvin (Jack Nicholson) as a cold asshole, the second reveals his OCD, establishing him altogether as a guy you wouldn't normally find in a romcom, while also getting people who are bummed about being forced to see the film on board. In the third, however, we find Melvin writing romantic literature, pointing out the direction of the film. Shot from behind some shelves, we are told that his sensitive side is hidden only deep beneath, but as the camera moves to the other side of the shelves for the next shot, we also know that this side will be uncovered eventually. The grittiness of the film is pretty much limited to Nicholson's unusually bad behavior and allowing the actors to curse, which is hardy enough to subvert genre conventions. Other than that, there's not much originality in the "unlikely love" trope or the gay supporting characters. But as always, just because we know A and B does not mean there isn't any fun to be had getting there. There's a really weird pacing to this film. As described above, the protagonist is presented very economically, as is his counterpart Carol (Helen Hunt), but then it feels like the film noodles around for like an hour, which only feels partly necessary for developing the characters and their relations further. In any case there is really no need for this film to be more than two hours long. Once the unlikely trio Melvin, Carol, and Melvin's gay neighbor Simon go on their trip, though, the film becomes a lot of fun. Comedies rarely make me laugh when I'm alone but both "I'm afraid he might pull the stiff one-eye on me" and something about "whether crabs were in season now" made me lose it. The film also delivers in the sweetness and romance department; "You make me want to be a better man" is one of the most heartwarming lines ever. I think one of the measures of success is if you want the lead characters to get together at the end of the film. As an incurable cynic, I wouldn't have minded if the only victory was the suggestion that Melvin's ailment was improving (by him forgetting to lock his door and finally stepping on some tiles), but the mere fact that I wasn't bothered by the happy ending was a small victory in itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this a romantic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callielovespink
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow the misogynist falls in love with a woman 20 years younger than him. That is the plot to this movie "How do you write women so well?" "I take away reason and accountability." How does someone who says that have the capability to care for a woman while hating women? I get that he is a curmudgeon. But it was so poorly done and inauthentic. The OCD did not seem authentic authentic either. An attempt at Beauty and the Beast becomes Beauty and the Creepy-50-year-old. Not a metamorphosis that I would sit through again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!... But too long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very well scripted with some really great one-liners; mostly delivered by Jack Nicholson; although there is one point where Greg Kinnear does a rather good impression. Both Jack and Helen Hunt put in great performances that were worthy of praise. My main niggle is that it is way too long; it could have easily been shortened by at least 20 minutes and that would have maybe given it a little more punch. Not that I was bored you understand, far from it, I just felt it would have benefited from being a little shorter. Enough of that; it's a very well made film with some excellent performances and a touching, well written, script. Well worth a look. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.7/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Do this Won Anything?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets is a romantic comedy that rocked the 1998 Oscar ceremony but nobody really cares or even remembers it. Yes, there are some good lines, the actors are really likable and the performances gel together well for a romantic comedy about misfits. But is this really a classic romantic comedy with unforgettable performances and iconic scenes that will keep on living inn our popular culture? The answer is no, hell no. It's way too long, very simplistic and absolutely unremarkable in every way you look at it. Jack Nicholson gives his usual crazy, over the top performance you have seen before and it rivals his work in Departed at being cartoonshly silly. This isn't a good performance and not in the same league as his work in Chinatown or One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest. Helen Hunt does her usual performance too and it's a shame, since she can do much better. There was hardly any Academy award winning material here. Yeah, the actors did do a good job playing the simplistic script and elevated the mediocre material. I don't hate this this film or even dislike it. I liked it just fine but it way too long and tries way too hard at being a Woody Allen film. If you like the cast and enjoy watching something like this, go see it. It's not bad just painfully overrated in its time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Likable movie about an unlikable guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very interesting movie in that it immediately establishes Jack Nicholson as a terrible person and then spends the rest of the movie trying to convince you he's better than you'd think. Nicholson is up to the challenge, being monstrous in the beginning and then slowly softening, but never flattening out, the rough edges. Hunt is equally excellent with his very convincing portrayal of a Brooklyn waitress, catching the spirit of someone leading a very ordinary life. Like most James L. Brooks movies, this one is quite amusing. It's also rather touching, so much so that I was willing to forgive it for its utter unlikeliness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Good as It Get defines this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chester Ruminski (Chet@callchet.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably my most favorite movie. The only difficulty I personally have Is watching the graphic beating of Simom. But I derived a somewhat relieving observation the last time I watched it. In the middle of the furor of the horrible beating of Simon, one of the thugs said excuse me to another thug as he passed by him. I thought that was hilarious and it softened the effect for me. I have seen the movie at least twenty times and don't remember hearing that before. I was wondering if the dialog was different in subsequent released versions. The part that helps make the movie so important is Melvin defending himself to Carol. He tells her about his medicine and his new resolve to take it. She makes him want to be a better man. That humanizes his recognition of his cold logical compulsive behavior. That he wants to do something about it is a tribute to him and a challenge to everybody else. Tthanks for the great "As Good as It Gets". Chet Ruminski
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breaking Habits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good As It Gets is one of the few examples of a movie that even though it directly comes from the modern Hollywood traditions, it works. Directed by James L. Brooks, the film won 2 Oscars, for the two leading roles: Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt. It was acclaimed fairly well by American audiences and critics. Melvin is a successful writer as well as an obsessive-compulsive misanthropist. He drives himself through a very strict daily routine, building around himself a world of patterns and neat organization. When his gay neighbor is severely hurt, his dog passes on to Melvin's custody for a few weeks: from there, the writer's life will be changed, as he also tries to get closer to the waitress of the diner he goes to every morning. His incredibly rude behavior though will be in the way of his good will. What the main character experiences in the movie is the most predictable trick in Hollywood when it comes to character development: that is, turning a bad man into a good man. Character change is an important part of any kind of fiction storytelling, but in mainstream movies, it's usually an overly-used technique exploited to the max. Although this is exactly what happens in As Good As It Gets, it's not as drastic as it might seem: if in the beginning of the film, Melvin is mean and misanthropic to the extreme, he still keeps it in him throughout the whole movie, and it never quite disappears, even though he's found love. Nicholson, who plays the main character, does a wonderful job in depicting Marvin so bitterly; Helen Hunt also seems very comfortable in her role as Carol. The dialogue has memorable quotes and sparks some laughs and smiles, but also dares to enter into the melodrama, which surprisingly never exceeds in sentimentality. Basically, it's a Romantic comedy without the "I Love You" punch-line, one that is funny and entertaining all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jack you makes my 20 bucks valuable!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Honestly at beginning I spent my 20 bucks for Helen, she is beautiful, elegant and adorable. In addition, Hunt got Oscar via this movie. However, after watching it, I think I am more lucky than before when I only went for Hunt but Jack. It is perfect for me to pay money getting a film of which both the leading actor and actress make me excited. Initially, I don't like Jack, as the most time I saw him is not in movies but on the first row of Staples Center where is the host court of L.A. Lakers. His crazy applause for Kobe Bryant annoyed as I don't like the showoffer - No.24 of Lakers. However after this movie one thing I clearly understand is you can't ignore the merits by the defects of a person. Also the guy Jack playing also make me sick, but this guy gets something making me feel good as well. Once again, it gets proof that the annoying guy also gets merits. The movie helps the communities create a harmony neighbourhood. How can you image that an annoying neighbour like Mr Udall can find his true love and the precious friendship. That's it people must get some merits no matter how badass they are. And another important thing is people are changing, so please do not judge them with your old prejudice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The name says it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blacksheep241
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's no need to talk about plot or characters as there's enough reviews already doing that so Ill start off by saying As good As It Gets is Simply one of my favourite movies ever, Melvin is my hero. So much more than a typical romantic comedy. The humour is subtle but perfect with some real laugh out loud moments mixed into the general smooth quirkiness, the pace of the movie is perfect, the acting is sublime. Nicholson deservedly gets most of the plaudits for the acting in this, but every character in it could not be better portrayed, even the dog Verdell could teach lassie a thing or two about acting. I've grown really fond of every character in it. I smile from start to finish each time I've watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fantastic film with a great lead performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jafar Iqbal
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A friendship starts to develop between a gay artist, a single mother working as a waitress, and a misanthropist, when the artist is left hospitalised after an attack. The three start to become somewhat dependent on one another, against their own expectations. 'As Good As It Gets' is one of those movies that I remember seeing the trailer of, but never felt the need to see. Just seemed like a boring rom-com with actors I didn't really care about. 'As Good As It Gets' is, in fact, an incredibly funny and quirky movie that was fully deserving of the Oscars that it won. The script is the strong-point of the movie. Issues of homophobia, racism, misogyny and countless other prejudices are touched with a sharp, cynical twang. Emotional moments are slapped in the face by cutting jokes, never letting the audience settle in. A script is only as good as the people who recite it, though, and there's a reason why Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt both won Oscars for their performances. Sure, everyone is else as just as good, but the two leads are magnetic. Nicholson does a perfect job of playing the grumpy Melvin Udall, and he never really stops being grumpy; and this works excellently in response to Helen Hunt's exhausted but ever-optimistic Carol Connelly. The chemistry between the two is top-notch. You could argue that, perhaps, that the film goes on too long. It's over two hours long, when ninety minutes would have been absolutely fine. That extra time allows the film-makers to populate the film with other slightly bizarre characters, all adding to the general acerbic aura of the film. However, it's two hours of excellent acting, breathing beautiful life into some excellently written dialogue. Definitely worth a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You make me want to be a better man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets positions itself from the get-go as the romantic comedy to recommend to people who don't like romantic comedies. The first scene establishes Melvin (Jack Nicholson) as a cold asshole, the second reveals his OCD, establishing him altogether as a guy you wouldn't normally find in a romcom, while also getting people who are bummed about being forced to see the film on board. In the third, however, we find Melvin writing romantic literature, pointing out the direction of the film. Shot from behind some shelves, we are told that his sensitive side is hidden only deep beneath, but as the camera moves to the other side of the shelves for the next shot, we also know that this side will be uncovered eventually. The grittiness of the film is pretty much limited to Nicholson's unusually bad behavior and allowing the actors to curse, which is hardy enough to subvert genre conventions. Other than that, there's not much originality in the "unlikely love" trope or the gay supporting characters. But as always, just because we know A and B does not mean there isn't any fun to be had getting there. There's a really weird pacing to this film. As described above, the protagonist is presented very economically, as is his counterpart Carol (Helen Hunt), but then it feels like the film noodles around for like an hour, which only feels partly necessary for developing the characters and their relations further. In any case there is really no need for this film to be more than two hours long. Once the unlikely trio Melvin, Carol, and Melvin's gay neighbor Simon go on their trip, though, the film becomes a lot of fun. Comedies rarely make me laugh when I'm alone but both "I'm afraid he might pull the stiff one-eye on me" and something about "whether crabs were in season now" made me lose it. The film also delivers in the sweetness and romance department; "You make me want to be a better man" is one of the most heartwarming lines ever. I think one of the measures of success is if you want the lead characters to get together at the end of the film. As an incurable cynic, I wouldn't have minded if the only victory was the suggestion that Melvin's ailment was improving (by him forgetting to lock his door and finally stepping on some tiles), but the mere fact that I wasn't bothered by the happy ending was a small victory in itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this a romantic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callielovespink
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow the misogynist falls in love with a woman 20 years younger than him. That is the plot to this movie "How do you write women so well?" "I take away reason and accountability." How does someone who says that have the capability to care for a woman while hating women? I get that he is a curmudgeon. But it was so poorly done and inauthentic. The OCD did not seem authentic authentic either. An attempt at Beauty and the Beast becomes Beauty and the Creepy-50-year-old. Not a metamorphosis that I would sit through again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!... But too long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very well scripted with some really great one-liners; mostly delivered by Jack Nicholson; although there is one point where Greg Kinnear does a rather good impression. Both Jack and Helen Hunt put in great performances that were worthy of praise. My main niggle is that it is way too long; it could have easily been shortened by at least 20 minutes and that would have maybe given it a little more punch. Not that I was bored you understand, far from it, I just felt it would have benefited from being a little shorter. Enough of that; it's a very well made film with some excellent performances and a touching, well written, script. Well worth a look. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.7/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Do this Won Anything?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets is a romantic comedy that rocked the 1998 Oscar ceremony but nobody really cares or even remembers it. Yes, there are some good lines, the actors are really likable and the performances gel together well for a romantic comedy about misfits. But is this really a classic romantic comedy with unforgettable performances and iconic scenes that will keep on living inn our popular culture? The answer is no, hell no. It's way too long, very simplistic and absolutely unremarkable in every way you look at it. Jack Nicholson gives his usual crazy, over the top performance you have seen before and it rivals his work in Departed at being cartoonshly silly. This isn't a good performance and not in the same league as his work in Chinatown or One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest. Helen Hunt does her usual performance too and it's a shame, since she can do much better. There was hardly any Academy award winning material here. Yeah, the actors did do a good job playing the simplistic script and elevated the mediocre material. I don't hate this this film or even dislike it. I liked it just fine but it way too long and tries way too hard at being a Woody Allen film. If you like the cast and enjoy watching something like this, go see it. It's not bad just painfully overrated in its time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Likable movie about an unlikable guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very interesting movie in that it immediately establishes Jack Nicholson as a terrible person and then spends the rest of the movie trying to convince you he's better than you'd think. Nicholson is up to the challenge, being monstrous in the beginning and then slowly softening, but never flattening out, the rough edges. Hunt is equally excellent with his very convincing portrayal of a Brooklyn waitress, catching the spirit of someone leading a very ordinary life. Like most James L. Brooks movies, this one is quite amusing. It's also rather touching, so much so that I was willing to forgive it for its utter unlikeliness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Good as It Get defines this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chester Ruminski (Chet@callchet.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably my most favorite movie. The only difficulty I personally have Is watching the graphic beating of Simom. But I derived a somewhat relieving observation the last time I watched it. In the middle of the furor of the horrible beating of Simon, one of the thugs said excuse me to another thug as he passed by him. I thought that was hilarious and it softened the effect for me. I have seen the movie at least twenty times and don't remember hearing that before. I was wondering if the dialog was different in subsequent released versions. The part that helps make the movie so important is Melvin defending himself to Carol. He tells her about his medicine and his new resolve to take it. She makes him want to be a better man. That humanizes his recognition of his cold logical compulsive behavior. That he wants to do something about it is a tribute to him and a challenge to everybody else. Tthanks for the great "As Good as It Gets". Chet Ruminski
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breaking Habits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good As It Gets is one of the few examples of a movie that even though it directly comes from the modern Hollywood traditions, it works. Directed by James L. Brooks, the film won 2 Oscars, for the two leading roles: Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt. It was acclaimed fairly well by American audiences and critics. Melvin is a successful writer as well as an obsessive-compulsive misanthropist. He drives himself through a very strict daily routine, building around himself a world of patterns and neat organization. When his gay neighbor is severely hurt, his dog passes on to Melvin's custody for a few weeks: from there, the writer's life will be changed, as he also tries to get closer to the waitress of the diner he goes to every morning. His incredibly rude behavior though will be in the way of his good will. What the main character experiences in the movie is the most predictable trick in Hollywood when it comes to character development: that is, turning a bad man into a good man. Character change is an important part of any kind of fiction storytelling, but in mainstream movies, it's usually an overly-used technique exploited to the max. Although this is exactly what happens in As Good As It Gets, it's not as drastic as it might seem: if in the beginning of the film, Melvin is mean and misanthropic to the extreme, he still keeps it in him throughout the whole movie, and it never quite disappears, even though he's found love. Nicholson, who plays the main character, does a wonderful job in depicting Marvin so bitterly; Helen Hunt also seems very comfortable in her role as Carol. The dialogue has memorable quotes and sparks some laughs and smiles, but also dares to enter into the melodrama, which surprisingly never exceeds in sentimentality. Basically, it's a Romantic comedy without the "I Love You" punch-line, one that is funny and entertaining all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jack you makes my 20 bucks valuable!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Honestly at beginning I spent my 20 bucks for Helen, she is beautiful, elegant and adorable. In addition, Hunt got Oscar via this movie. However, after watching it, I think I am more lucky than before when I only went for Hunt but Jack. It is perfect for me to pay money getting a film of which both the leading actor and actress make me excited. Initially, I don't like Jack, as the most time I saw him is not in movies but on the first row of Staples Center where is the host court of L.A. Lakers. His crazy applause for Kobe Bryant annoyed as I don't like the showoffer - No.24 of Lakers. However after this movie one thing I clearly understand is you can't ignore the merits by the defects of a person. Also the guy Jack playing also make me sick, but this guy gets something making me feel good as well. Once again, it gets proof that the annoying guy also gets merits. The movie helps the communities create a harmony neighbourhood. How can you image that an annoying neighbour like Mr Udall can find his true love and the precious friendship. That's it people must get some merits no matter how badass they are. And another important thing is people are changing, so please do not judge them with your old prejudice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The name says it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blacksheep241
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's no need to talk about plot or characters as there's enough reviews already doing that so Ill start off by saying As good As It Gets is Simply one of my favourite movies ever, Melvin is my hero. So much more than a typical romantic comedy. The humour is subtle but perfect with some real laugh out loud moments mixed into the general smooth quirkiness, the pace of the movie is perfect, the acting is sublime. Nicholson deservedly gets most of the plaudits for the acting in this, but every character in it could not be better portrayed, even the dog Verdell could teach lassie a thing or two about acting. I've grown really fond of every character in it. I smile from start to finish each time I've watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fantastic film with a great lead performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jafar Iqbal
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A friendship starts to develop between a gay artist, a single mother working as a waitress, and a misanthropist, when the artist is left hospitalised after an attack. The three start to become somewhat dependent on one another, against their own expectations. 'As Good As It Gets' is one of those movies that I remember seeing the trailer of, but never felt the need to see. Just seemed like a boring rom-com with actors I didn't really care about. 'As Good As It Gets' is, in fact, an incredibly funny and quirky movie that was fully deserving of the Oscars that it won. The script is the strong-point of the movie. Issues of homophobia, racism, misogyny and countless other prejudices are touched with a sharp, cynical twang. Emotional moments are slapped in the face by cutting jokes, never letting the audience settle in. A script is only as good as the people who recite it, though, and there's a reason why Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt both won Oscars for their performances. Sure, everyone is else as just as good, but the two leads are magnetic. Nicholson does a perfect job of playing the grumpy Melvin Udall, and he never really stops being grumpy; and this works excellently in response to Helen Hunt's exhausted but ever-optimistic Carol Connelly. The chemistry between the two is top-notch. You could argue that, perhaps, that the film goes on too long. It's over two hours long, when ninety minutes would have been absolutely fine. That extra time allows the film-makers to populate the film with other slightly bizarre characters, all adding to the general acerbic aura of the film. However, it's two hours of excellent acting, breathing beautiful life into some excellently written dialogue. Definitely worth a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You make me want to be a better man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets positions itself from the get-go as the romantic comedy to recommend to people who don't like romantic comedies. The first scene establishes Melvin (Jack Nicholson) as a cold asshole, the second reveals his OCD, establishing him altogether as a guy you wouldn't normally find in a romcom, while also getting people who are bummed about being forced to see the film on board. In the third, however, we find Melvin writing romantic literature, pointing out the direction of the film. Shot from behind some shelves, we are told that his sensitive side is hidden only deep beneath, but as the camera moves to the other side of the shelves for the next shot, we also know that this side will be uncovered eventually. The grittiness of the film is pretty much limited to Nicholson's unusually bad behavior and allowing the actors to curse, which is hardy enough to subvert genre conventions. Other than that, there's not much originality in the "unlikely love" trope or the gay supporting characters. But as always, just because we know A and B does not mean there isn't any fun to be had getting there. There's a really weird pacing to this film. As described above, the protagonist is presented very economically, as is his counterpart Carol (Helen Hunt), but then it feels like the film noodles around for like an hour, which only feels partly necessary for developing the characters and their relations further. In any case there is really no need for this film to be more than two hours long. Once the unlikely trio Melvin, Carol, and Melvin's gay neighbor Simon go on their trip, though, the film becomes a lot of fun. Comedies rarely make me laugh when I'm alone but both "I'm afraid he might pull the stiff one-eye on me" and something about "whether crabs were in season now" made me lose it. The film also delivers in the sweetness and romance department; "You make me want to be a better man" is one of the most heartwarming lines ever. I think one of the measures of success is if you want the lead characters to get together at the end of the film. As an incurable cynic, I wouldn't have minded if the only victory was the suggestion that Melvin's ailment was improving (by him forgetting to lock his door and finally stepping on some tiles), but the mere fact that I wasn't bothered by the happy ending was a small victory in itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this a romantic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callielovespink
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow the misogynist falls in love with a woman 20 years younger than him. That is the plot to this movie "How do you write women so well?" "I take away reason and accountability." How does someone who says that have the capability to care for a woman while hating women? I get that he is a curmudgeon. But it was so poorly done and inauthentic. The OCD did not seem authentic authentic either. An attempt at Beauty and the Beast becomes Beauty and the Creepy-50-year-old. Not a metamorphosis that I would sit through again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!... But too long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very well scripted with some really great one-liners; mostly delivered by Jack Nicholson; although there is one point where Greg Kinnear does a rather good impression. Both Jack and Helen Hunt put in great performances that were worthy of praise. My main niggle is that it is way too long; it could have easily been shortened by at least 20 minutes and that would have maybe given it a little more punch. Not that I was bored you understand, far from it, I just felt it would have benefited from being a little shorter. Enough of that; it's a very well made film with some excellent performances and a touching, well written, script. Well worth a look. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.7/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Do this Won Anything?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets is a romantic comedy that rocked the 1998 Oscar ceremony but nobody really cares or even remembers it. Yes, there are some good lines, the actors are really likable and the performances gel together well for a romantic comedy about misfits. But is this really a classic romantic comedy with unforgettable performances and iconic scenes that will keep on living inn our popular culture? The answer is no, hell no. It's way too long, very simplistic and absolutely unremarkable in every way you look at it. Jack Nicholson gives his usual crazy, over the top performance you have seen before and it rivals his work in Departed at being cartoonshly silly. This isn't a good performance and not in the same league as his work in Chinatown or One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest. Helen Hunt does her usual performance too and it's a shame, since she can do much better. There was hardly any Academy award winning material here. Yeah, the actors did do a good job playing the simplistic script and elevated the mediocre material. I don't hate this this film or even dislike it. I liked it just fine but it way too long and tries way too hard at being a Woody Allen film. If you like the cast and enjoy watching something like this, go see it. It's not bad just painfully overrated in its time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Likable movie about an unlikable guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very interesting movie in that it immediately establishes Jack Nicholson as a terrible person and then spends the rest of the movie trying to convince you he's better than you'd think. Nicholson is up to the challenge, being monstrous in the beginning and then slowly softening, but never flattening out, the rough edges. Hunt is equally excellent with his very convincing portrayal of a Brooklyn waitress, catching the spirit of someone leading a very ordinary life. Like most James L. Brooks movies, this one is quite amusing. It's also rather touching, so much so that I was willing to forgive it for its utter unlikeliness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Good as It Get defines this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chester Ruminski (Chet@callchet.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably my most favorite movie. The only difficulty I personally have Is watching the graphic beating of Simom. But I derived a somewhat relieving observation the last time I watched it. In the middle of the furor of the horrible beating of Simon, one of the thugs said excuse me to another thug as he passed by him. I thought that was hilarious and it softened the effect for me. I have seen the movie at least twenty times and don't remember hearing that before. I was wondering if the dialog was different in subsequent released versions. The part that helps make the movie so important is Melvin defending himself to Carol. He tells her about his medicine and his new resolve to take it. She makes him want to be a better man. That humanizes his recognition of his cold logical compulsive behavior. That he wants to do something about it is a tribute to him and a challenge to everybody else. Tthanks for the great "As Good as It Gets". Chet Ruminski
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breaking Habits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good As It Gets is one of the few examples of a movie that even though it directly comes from the modern Hollywood traditions, it works. Directed by James L. Brooks, the film won 2 Oscars, for the two leading roles: Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt. It was acclaimed fairly well by American audiences and critics. Melvin is a successful writer as well as an obsessive-compulsive misanthropist. He drives himself through a very strict daily routine, building around himself a world of patterns and neat organization. When his gay neighbor is severely hurt, his dog passes on to Melvin's custody for a few weeks: from there, the writer's life will be changed, as he also tries to get closer to the waitress of the diner he goes to every morning. His incredibly rude behavior though will be in the way of his good will. What the main character experiences in the movie is the most predictable trick in Hollywood when it comes to character development: that is, turning a bad man into a good man. Character change is an important part of any kind of fiction storytelling, but in mainstream movies, it's usually an overly-used technique exploited to the max. Although this is exactly what happens in As Good As It Gets, it's not as drastic as it might seem: if in the beginning of the film, Melvin is mean and misanthropic to the extreme, he still keeps it in him throughout the whole movie, and it never quite disappears, even though he's found love. Nicholson, who plays the main character, does a wonderful job in depicting Marvin so bitterly; Helen Hunt also seems very comfortable in her role as Carol. The dialogue has memorable quotes and sparks some laughs and smiles, but also dares to enter into the melodrama, which surprisingly never exceeds in sentimentality. Basically, it's a Romantic comedy without the "I Love You" punch-line, one that is funny and entertaining all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jack you makes my 20 bucks valuable!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Honestly at beginning I spent my 20 bucks for Helen, she is beautiful, elegant and adorable. In addition, Hunt got Oscar via this movie. However, after watching it, I think I am more lucky than before when I only went for Hunt but Jack. It is perfect for me to pay money getting a film of which both the leading actor and actress make me excited. Initially, I don't like Jack, as the most time I saw him is not in movies but on the first row of Staples Center where is the host court of L.A. Lakers. His crazy applause for Kobe Bryant annoyed as I don't like the showoffer - No.24 of Lakers. However after this movie one thing I clearly understand is you can't ignore the merits by the defects of a person. Also the guy Jack playing also make me sick, but this guy gets something making me feel good as well. Once again, it gets proof that the annoying guy also gets merits. The movie helps the communities create a harmony neighbourhood. How can you image that an annoying neighbour like Mr Udall can find his true love and the precious friendship. That's it people must get some merits no matter how badass they are. And another important thing is people are changing, so please do not judge them with your old prejudice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The name says it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blacksheep241
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's no need to talk about plot or characters as there's enough reviews already doing that so Ill start off by saying As good As It Gets is Simply one of my favourite movies ever, Melvin is my hero. So much more than a typical romantic comedy. The humour is subtle but perfect with some real laugh out loud moments mixed into the general smooth quirkiness, the pace of the movie is perfect, the acting is sublime. Nicholson deservedly gets most of the plaudits for the acting in this, but every character in it could not be better portrayed, even the dog Verdell could teach lassie a thing or two about acting. I've grown really fond of every character in it. I smile from start to finish each time I've watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fantastic film with a great lead performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jafar Iqbal
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A friendship starts to develop between a gay artist, a single mother working as a waitress, and a misanthropist, when the artist is left hospitalised after an attack. The three start to become somewhat dependent on one another, against their own expectations. 'As Good As It Gets' is one of those movies that I remember seeing the trailer of, but never felt the need to see. Just seemed like a boring rom-com with actors I didn't really care about. 'As Good As It Gets' is, in fact, an incredibly funny and quirky movie that was fully deserving of the Oscars that it won. The script is the strong-point of the movie. Issues of homophobia, racism, misogyny and countless other prejudices are touched with a sharp, cynical twang. Emotional moments are slapped in the face by cutting jokes, never letting the audience settle in. A script is only as good as the people who recite it, though, and there's a reason why Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt both won Oscars for their performances. Sure, everyone is else as just as good, but the two leads are magnetic. Nicholson does a perfect job of playing the grumpy Melvin Udall, and he never really stops being grumpy; and this works excellently in response to Helen Hunt's exhausted but ever-optimistic Carol Connelly. The chemistry between the two is top-notch. You could argue that, perhaps, that the film goes on too long. It's over two hours long, when ninety minutes would have been absolutely fine. That extra time allows the film-makers to populate the film with other slightly bizarre characters, all adding to the general acerbic aura of the film. However, it's two hours of excellent acting, breathing beautiful life into some excellently written dialogue. Definitely worth a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You make me want to be a better man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets positions itself from the get-go as the romantic comedy to recommend to people who don't like romantic comedies. The first scene establishes Melvin (Jack Nicholson) as a cold asshole, the second reveals his OCD, establishing him altogether as a guy you wouldn't normally find in a romcom, while also getting people who are bummed about being forced to see the film on board. In the third, however, we find Melvin writing romantic literature, pointing out the direction of the film. Shot from behind some shelves, we are told that his sensitive side is hidden only deep beneath, but as the camera moves to the other side of the shelves for the next shot, we also know that this side will be uncovered eventually. The grittiness of the film is pretty much limited to Nicholson's unusually bad behavior and allowing the actors to curse, which is hardy enough to subvert genre conventions. Other than that, there's not much originality in the "unlikely love" trope or the gay supporting characters. But as always, just because we know A and B does not mean there isn't any fun to be had getting there. There's a really weird pacing to this film. As described above, the protagonist is presented very economically, as is his counterpart Carol (Helen Hunt), but then it feels like the film noodles around for like an hour, which only feels partly necessary for developing the characters and their relations further. In any case there is really no need for this film to be more than two hours long. Once the unlikely trio Melvin, Carol, and Melvin's gay neighbor Simon go on their trip, though, the film becomes a lot of fun. Comedies rarely make me laugh when I'm alone but both "I'm afraid he might pull the stiff one-eye on me" and something about "whether crabs were in season now" made me lose it. The film also delivers in the sweetness and romance department; "You make me want to be a better man" is one of the most heartwarming lines ever. I think one of the measures of success is if you want the lead characters to get together at the end of the film. As an incurable cynic, I wouldn't have minded if the only victory was the suggestion that Melvin's ailment was improving (by him forgetting to lock his door and finally stepping on some tiles), but the mere fact that I wasn't bothered by the happy ending was a small victory in itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this a romantic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callielovespink
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow the misogynist falls in love with a woman 20 years younger than him. That is the plot to this movie "How do you write women so well?" "I take away reason and accountability." How does someone who says that have the capability to care for a woman while hating women? I get that he is a curmudgeon. But it was so poorly done and inauthentic. The OCD did not seem authentic authentic either. An attempt at Beauty and the Beast becomes Beauty and the Creepy-50-year-old. Not a metamorphosis that I would sit through again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!... But too long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very well scripted with some really great one-liners; mostly delivered by Jack Nicholson; although there is one point where Greg Kinnear does a rather good impression. Both Jack and Helen Hunt put in great performances that were worthy of praise. My main niggle is that it is way too long; it could have easily been shortened by at least 20 minutes and that would have maybe given it a little more punch. Not that I was bored you understand, far from it, I just felt it would have benefited from being a little shorter. Enough of that; it's a very well made film with some excellent performances and a touching, well written, script. Well worth a look. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.7/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Do this Won Anything?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets is a romantic comedy that rocked the 1998 Oscar ceremony but nobody really cares or even remembers it. Yes, there are some good lines, the actors are really likable and the performances gel together well for a romantic comedy about misfits. But is this really a classic romantic comedy with unforgettable performances and iconic scenes that will keep on living inn our popular culture? The answer is no, hell no. It's way too long, very simplistic and absolutely unremarkable in every way you look at it. Jack Nicholson gives his usual crazy, over the top performance you have seen before and it rivals his work in Departed at being cartoonshly silly. This isn't a good performance and not in the same league as his work in Chinatown or One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest. Helen Hunt does her usual performance too and it's a shame, since she can do much better. There was hardly any Academy award winning material here. Yeah, the actors did do a good job playing the simplistic script and elevated the mediocre material. I don't hate this this film or even dislike it. I liked it just fine but it way too long and tries way too hard at being a Woody Allen film. If you like the cast and enjoy watching something like this, go see it. It's not bad just painfully overrated in its time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Likable movie about an unlikable guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very interesting movie in that it immediately establishes Jack Nicholson as a terrible person and then spends the rest of the movie trying to convince you he's better than you'd think. Nicholson is up to the challenge, being monstrous in the beginning and then slowly softening, but never flattening out, the rough edges. Hunt is equally excellent with his very convincing portrayal of a Brooklyn waitress, catching the spirit of someone leading a very ordinary life. Like most James L. Brooks movies, this one is quite amusing. It's also rather touching, so much so that I was willing to forgive it for its utter unlikeliness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Good as It Get defines this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chester Ruminski (Chet@callchet.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably my most favorite movie. The only difficulty I personally have Is watching the graphic beating of Simom. But I derived a somewhat relieving observation the last time I watched it. In the middle of the furor of the horrible beating of Simon, one of the thugs said excuse me to another thug as he passed by him. I thought that was hilarious and it softened the effect for me. I have seen the movie at least twenty times and don't remember hearing that before. I was wondering if the dialog was different in subsequent released versions. The part that helps make the movie so important is Melvin defending himself to Carol. He tells her about his medicine and his new resolve to take it. She makes him want to be a better man. That humanizes his recognition of his cold logical compulsive behavior. That he wants to do something about it is a tribute to him and a challenge to everybody else. Tthanks for the great "As Good as It Gets". Chet Ruminski
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breaking Habits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good As It Gets is one of the few examples of a movie that even though it directly comes from the modern Hollywood traditions, it works. Directed by James L. Brooks, the film won 2 Oscars, for the two leading roles: Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt. It was acclaimed fairly well by American audiences and critics. Melvin is a successful writer as well as an obsessive-compulsive misanthropist. He drives himself through a very strict daily routine, building around himself a world of patterns and neat organization. When his gay neighbor is severely hurt, his dog passes on to Melvin's custody for a few weeks: from there, the writer's life will be changed, as he also tries to get closer to the waitress of the diner he goes to every morning. His incredibly rude behavior though will be in the way of his good will. What the main character experiences in the movie is the most predictable trick in Hollywood when it comes to character development: that is, turning a bad man into a good man. Character change is an important part of any kind of fiction storytelling, but in mainstream movies, it's usually an overly-used technique exploited to the max. Although this is exactly what happens in As Good As It Gets, it's not as drastic as it might seem: if in the beginning of the film, Melvin is mean and misanthropic to the extreme, he still keeps it in him throughout the whole movie, and it never quite disappears, even though he's found love. Nicholson, who plays the main character, does a wonderful job in depicting Marvin so bitterly; Helen Hunt also seems very comfortable in her role as Carol. The dialogue has memorable quotes and sparks some laughs and smiles, but also dares to enter into the melodrama, which surprisingly never exceeds in sentimentality. Basically, it's a Romantic comedy without the "I Love You" punch-line, one that is funny and entertaining all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jack you makes my 20 bucks valuable!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Honestly at beginning I spent my 20 bucks for Helen, she is beautiful, elegant and adorable. In addition, Hunt got Oscar via this movie. However, after watching it, I think I am more lucky than before when I only went for Hunt but Jack. It is perfect for me to pay money getting a film of which both the leading actor and actress make me excited. Initially, I don't like Jack, as the most time I saw him is not in movies but on the first row of Staples Center where is the host court of L.A. Lakers. His crazy applause for Kobe Bryant annoyed as I don't like the showoffer - No.24 of Lakers. However after this movie one thing I clearly understand is you can't ignore the merits by the defects of a person. Also the guy Jack playing also make me sick, but this guy gets something making me feel good as well. Once again, it gets proof that the annoying guy also gets merits. The movie helps the communities create a harmony neighbourhood. How can you image that an annoying neighbour like Mr Udall can find his true love and the precious friendship. That's it people must get some merits no matter how badass they are. And another important thing is people are changing, so please do not judge them with your old prejudice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The name says it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blacksheep241
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's no need to talk about plot or characters as there's enough reviews already doing that so Ill start off by saying As good As It Gets is Simply one of my favourite movies ever, Melvin is my hero. So much more than a typical romantic comedy. The humour is subtle but perfect with some real laugh out loud moments mixed into the general smooth quirkiness, the pace of the movie is perfect, the acting is sublime. Nicholson deservedly gets most of the plaudits for the acting in this, but every character in it could not be better portrayed, even the dog Verdell could teach lassie a thing or two about acting. I've grown really fond of every character in it. I smile from start to finish each time I've watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fantastic film with a great lead performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jafar Iqbal
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A friendship starts to develop between a gay artist, a single mother working as a waitress, and a misanthropist, when the artist is left hospitalised after an attack. The three start to become somewhat dependent on one another, against their own expectations. 'As Good As It Gets' is one of those movies that I remember seeing the trailer of, but never felt the need to see. Just seemed like a boring rom-com with actors I didn't really care about. 'As Good As It Gets' is, in fact, an incredibly funny and quirky movie that was fully deserving of the Oscars that it won. The script is the strong-point of the movie. Issues of homophobia, racism, misogyny and countless other prejudices are touched with a sharp, cynical twang. Emotional moments are slapped in the face by cutting jokes, never letting the audience settle in. A script is only as good as the people who recite it, though, and there's a reason why Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt both won Oscars for their performances. Sure, everyone is else as just as good, but the two leads are magnetic. Nicholson does a perfect job of playing the grumpy Melvin Udall, and he never really stops being grumpy; and this works excellently in response to Helen Hunt's exhausted but ever-optimistic Carol Connelly. The chemistry between the two is top-notch. You could argue that, perhaps, that the film goes on too long. It's over two hours long, when ninety minutes would have been absolutely fine. That extra time allows the film-makers to populate the film with other slightly bizarre characters, all adding to the general acerbic aura of the film. However, it's two hours of excellent acting, breathing beautiful life into some excellently written dialogue. Definitely worth a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You make me want to be a better man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets positions itself from the get-go as the romantic comedy to recommend to people who don't like romantic comedies. The first scene establishes Melvin (Jack Nicholson) as a cold asshole, the second reveals his OCD, establishing him altogether as a guy you wouldn't normally find in a romcom, while also getting people who are bummed about being forced to see the film on board. In the third, however, we find Melvin writing romantic literature, pointing out the direction of the film. Shot from behind some shelves, we are told that his sensitive side is hidden only deep beneath, but as the camera moves to the other side of the shelves for the next shot, we also know that this side will be uncovered eventually. The grittiness of the film is pretty much limited to Nicholson's unusually bad behavior and allowing the actors to curse, which is hardy enough to subvert genre conventions. Other than that, there's not much originality in the "unlikely love" trope or the gay supporting characters. But as always, just because we know A and B does not mean there isn't any fun to be had getting there. There's a really weird pacing to this film. As described above, the protagonist is presented very economically, as is his counterpart Carol (Helen Hunt), but then it feels like the film noodles around for like an hour, which only feels partly necessary for developing the characters and their relations further. In any case there is really no need for this film to be more than two hours long. Once the unlikely trio Melvin, Carol, and Melvin's gay neighbor Simon go on their trip, though, the film becomes a lot of fun. Comedies rarely make me laugh when I'm alone but both "I'm afraid he might pull the stiff one-eye on me" and something about "whether crabs were in season now" made me lose it. The film also delivers in the sweetness and romance department; "You make me want to be a better man" is one of the most heartwarming lines ever. I think one of the measures of success is if you want the lead characters to get together at the end of the film. As an incurable cynic, I wouldn't have minded if the only victory was the suggestion that Melvin's ailment was improving (by him forgetting to lock his door and finally stepping on some tiles), but the mere fact that I wasn't bothered by the happy ending was a small victory in itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How is this a romantic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callielovespink
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow the misogynist falls in love with a woman 20 years younger than him. That is the plot to this movie "How do you write women so well?" "I take away reason and accountability." How does someone who says that have the capability to care for a woman while hating women? I get that he is a curmudgeon. But it was so poorly done and inauthentic. The OCD did not seem authentic authentic either. An attempt at Beauty and the Beast becomes Beauty and the Creepy-50-year-old. Not a metamorphosis that I would sit through again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!... But too long...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Steel
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very well scripted with some really great one-liners; mostly delivered by Jack Nicholson; although there is one point where Greg Kinnear does a rather good impression. Both Jack and Helen Hunt put in great performances that were worthy of praise. My main niggle is that it is way too long; it could have easily been shortened by at least 20 minutes and that would have maybe given it a little more punch. Not that I was bored you understand, far from it, I just felt it would have benefited from being a little shorter. Enough of that; it's a very well made film with some excellent performances and a touching, well written, script. Well worth a look. SteelMonster's verdict: RECOMMENDED My score: 7.7/10. You can find an expanded version of this review on my blog: Thoughts of a SteelMonster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why Do this Won Anything?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good as It Gets is a romantic comedy that rocked the 1998 Oscar ceremony but nobody really cares or even remembers it. Yes, there are some good lines, the actors are really likable and the performances gel together well for a romantic comedy about misfits. But is this really a classic romantic comedy with unforgettable performances and iconic scenes that will keep on living inn our popular culture? The answer is no, hell no. It's way too long, very simplistic and absolutely unremarkable in every way you look at it. Jack Nicholson gives his usual crazy, over the top performance you have seen before and it rivals his work in Departed at being cartoonshly silly. This isn't a good performance and not in the same league as his work in Chinatown or One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest. Helen Hunt does her usual performance too and it's a shame, since she can do much better. There was hardly any Academy award winning material here. Yeah, the actors did do a good job playing the simplistic script and elevated the mediocre material. I don't hate this this film or even dislike it. I liked it just fine but it way too long and tries way too hard at being a Woody Allen film. If you like the cast and enjoy watching something like this, go see it. It's not bad just painfully overrated in its time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Likable movie about an unlikable guy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very interesting movie in that it immediately establishes Jack Nicholson as a terrible person and then spends the rest of the movie trying to convince you he's better than you'd think. Nicholson is up to the challenge, being monstrous in the beginning and then slowly softening, but never flattening out, the rough edges. Hunt is equally excellent with his very convincing portrayal of a Brooklyn waitress, catching the spirit of someone leading a very ordinary life. Like most James L. Brooks movies, this one is quite amusing. It's also rather touching, so much so that I was willing to forgive it for its utter unlikeliness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Good as It Get defines this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chester Ruminski (Chet@callchet.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably my most favorite movie. The only difficulty I personally have Is watching the graphic beating of Simom. But I derived a somewhat relieving observation the last time I watched it. In the middle of the furor of the horrible beating of Simon, one of the thugs said excuse me to another thug as he passed by him. I thought that was hilarious and it softened the effect for me. I have seen the movie at least twenty times and don't remember hearing that before. I was wondering if the dialog was different in subsequent released versions. The part that helps make the movie so important is Melvin defending himself to Carol. He tells her about his medicine and his new resolve to take it. She makes him want to be a better man. That humanizes his recognition of his cold logical compulsive behavior. That he wants to do something about it is a tribute to him and a challenge to everybody else. Tthanks for the great "As Good as It Gets". Chet Ruminski
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breaking Habits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Good As It Gets is one of the few examples of a movie that even though it directly comes from the modern Hollywood traditions, it works. Directed by James L. Brooks, the film won 2 Oscars, for the two leading roles: Jack Nicholson and Helen Hunt. It was acclaimed fairly well by American audiences and critics. Melvin is a successful writer as well as an obsessive-compulsive misanthropist. He drives himself through a very strict daily routine, building around himself a world of patterns and neat organization. When his gay neighbor is severely hurt, his dog passes on to Melvin's custody for a few weeks: from there, the writer's life will be changed, as he also tries to get closer to the waitress of the diner he goes to every morning. His incredibly rude behavior though will be in the way of his good will. What the main character experiences in the movie is the most predictable trick in Hollywood when it comes to character development: that is, turning a bad man into a good man. Character change is an important part of any kind of fiction storytelling, but in mainstream movies, it's usually an overly-used technique exploited to the max. Although this is exactly what happens in As Good As It Gets, it's not as drastic as it might seem: if in the beginning of the film, Melvin is mean and misanthropic to the extreme, he still keeps it in him throughout the whole movie, and it never quite disappears, even though he's found love. Nicholson, who plays the main character, does a wonderful job in depicting Marvin so bitterly; Helen Hunt also seems very comfortable in her role as Carol. The dialogue has memorable quotes and sparks some laughs and smiles, but also dares to enter into the melodrama, which surprisingly never exceeds in sentimentality. Basically, it's a Romantic comedy without the "I Love You" punch-line, one that is funny and entertaining all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
