<filme>
 <id>
  319
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116242
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Todos Dizem Eu Te Amo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A New York girl sets her father up with a beautiful woman in a shaky marriage while her half sister gets engaged.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Holden and Skylar are in love with each other. Skylar lives with a large and extended family on Manhattan. Her parents, Bob and Steffi have been married to each other for many years. Joe, a friend of theirs, who has a daughter, DJ, with Steffi. After yet another relationship, Joe is alone again. He flees to Venice, and meets Von, and makes her believe that he is the man of her dreams. However, their happiness is fake all the way, and she returns to her previous husband. Steffi spends her time with charity work, and manages to break up Skylars and Holdens relation when she introduces Skylar to a released jailbird, Charles Ferry.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Musical
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   liberal
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   song
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   engagement
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   opposites attract
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Woody Allen
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Woody Allen
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Woody Allen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Goldie Hawn
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Julia Roberts
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did I miss this Woody Allen movie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gottlieb.cindy@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! An all star cast singing and dancing in between the dialog. It has the usual Woody Allen premise of love lost angst on Woody's part. The plot twists and turns with love as its theme. The little nuances that are classic Woody Allen in the background, like the teenagers drinking hard liquor that no one is noticing, the stereo-typing of ethnic peoples, playing stick hockey in the fancy foyer, to name a few that have you looking for the absurd as if a game within the movie watching. Everyone is looking for ideal love except maybe not Alan Alda who has already found his in Goldie Hawn. The actual singing by the actors was not so good but that's what made the movie so perfect. The musical numbers and dancing were so campy it was excellent and entertaining. At times like watching the June Taylor Dancers including the over head camera shots. BRILLIANT! The Groucho Marx routine and party to follow was the best! A Great movie and should be up there with the top 10 Best Movies of all Times.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable musical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now I did like the old school style direction when it came to this musical. And the musical numbers is good and even cute in some cases. But despite how it tries to go in that sweet and meaningful direction of it all, it just didn't work all together. This has multiple different subplots going but it just wasn't all that effective. Even if it does kinda tie together in the end for the most part. With Woody Allen's character story as the primary. Although I didn't really watch this for Woody Allen but for Edward Norton, who is almost impossible to dislike. This just wasn't all that absorbing despite it trying to be sweet and charming, I just didn't fall for it. The plot is about characters trying to find there path, which revolves around love, sex, fantasies, politics, enjoying life, Christian and atheist views. It even tries to be witty and edgy but wasn't feeling it. Like I said it does tie together in the end but not all that well. Fans of Woody Allen might like this film, it does have a lot of his trademarks in this. Woody Allen put a lot of ideas into this movie, but everything just seemed so rushed and poorly developed. It seem to lack heart and goes more towards opinionated life views, which isn't even all that deep. Edward Norton is always cool though. And the musical number and choreography is good but also forgettable. This movie is about a hour and a half long but felt longer. It's disappointing since this has a good cast. 3.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    god when is it over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rob0352002
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed Norton, Barrymore, Roberts, Hawn, Alda, Portman... what's not to love? Well the boring, plodding, banal and mind numbingly worked story line that is as intricate as a cereal box. How can anyone like this? Did they get awards because of the cast? This proves to me that pretentious nits make a good market for an inane movie a college student could have composed. It reminds me of those self-indulgent "I am melancholy pay attention to my deep thoughts" of the 70s genre, which is how old you have to be to find this mildly entertaining. Woody Allen should just give it up. Then again, people will pretend he has talent because they are suppose to. Kind of like people paid a zillion dollars a ticket to see washed up Streisand in concert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm through with love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There came a point when the trademark opening to Woody Allen movies - plain white text on black backgrounds accompanied by a jazz song - went from classy and charming to twee and self conscious. That point really seemed to hit home around his lacklustre 90s period, largely due to the indifferent quality of most of the product. If your jazz opening is ironic juxtaposition to a genuinely funny film, or a more museful one, then it works. If it presages a mediocre offering with Larry David then it can look a little self congratulatory and pretentious. That feeling extends throughout the whole of Everyone Says I Love You, a film that doesn't seem to know what it wants to be... a genuine musical homage or pastiche. If seeing hospital patients or the ghosts of the dead dancing to show tunes is your thing, then it's ideal. But this kind of humour would work more in the full-on hands of a Mel Brooks, not a nebbish pseudo intellectual. And I say that as a fan of Woody. One thing that surprises is how almost everyone can hold a reasonable note in the cast, even Woody himself, with Hawn and Norton reputedly told to sing worse to make it more realistic. And technically there's no faulting the skill behind this piece, Allen's first picture in over ten years to be shot outside New York. But there's a twee, self-amused feel throughout, something made even worse by the character Allen plays in the film. I'm a huge Woody Allen fan, but I would never claim he has a great number of strings to his acting bow. Here he plays Woody Allen - this time called "Joe Berlin" - as a man who psychologically manipulates Julia Roberts into bed with him. Using spied knowledge of her intimate psychological secrets, Allen says and does the right thing at all time to procure a physical relationship... sorry, but isn't that practically rape? This unsettling subtext to the movie unbalances it still further, a dispiriting turn of events in a film that never seems to know quite what it wants to be. It's nice to see Woody trying something new thirty years into his movie career, but Everyone Says I Love You really needs to be filed under "inessential Allen".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody says they love this movie -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaaber-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - but I'm here to complain. I find the film embarrassing. Its slipshod dramaturgy (not foreign to Allen) makes "Meet Me in St. Louis" look like Shakespeare. The voice-over babbles on and on so as to make you think that Woody Allen ought to have written a novel instead. The film as such seems like a sorry excuse for the musical numbers which are few and far between. And then, as often with Allen, I feel like having to listen to a guy who goes on and on about his affairs with beautiful women and what a great lover he is. This time he's taking Julia Roberts and Goldie Hawn hostages. I wish I could believe that it's all tongue-in-cheek, but I can't. I give it two stars for the music only.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Still A "Can't Miss" Woody Allen Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen produced,wrote and directed an All-Star cast musical comedy set in modern day New York,Venice and Paris in this film,Everyone Says I Love You.The ensemble cast includes Alan Alda,Drew Barrymore,Lukas Haas,Goldie Hawn,Gaby Hoffmann,Natasha Lyonne,Edward Norton,Natalie Portman,Julia Roberts,Tim Roth,David Ogden Stiers and Woody Allen himself. The story centered on a polite and comfortably well-off group of people and their romantic difficulties.DJ (Natasha Lyonne), who narrates the picture, is the daughter of divorced couple Steffi (Goldie Hawn) and Joe (Woody Allen). Since the break-up, Steffi has married Bob (Alan Alda); their children, DJ's half-sister and half-brother, are Skyler (Drew Barrymore) and Scott (Lukas Haas). Skyler is about to be married to a likable chap named Holden (Edward Norton). However, her mother Steffi, a wealthy liberal, cultivates people as "projects." Her latest project is ex-con Charles (Tim Roth), an extremely rude and crude customer. At family gatherings, everyone politely ignores his lapses in manners and good taste until Skyler postpones her wedding to have an affair with him. In a parallel storyline, we see that DJ is convinced that her unmarried dad would find a perfect mate in Von (Julia Roberts), and she contrives an elaborate (and successful) scheme to bring them together. Overall,this is one of the best musicals made in the 90's although it does not compared to those done in the past especially when it tries to emulate typical of '30s musicals.But nevertheless,it still passes as one of the best film features made since the performances of the actors are great.Also,the love story involved is told with sincerity and honesty.Aside from that,it also presented great songs such as songs such as "Just You, Just Me" and "My Baby Just Cares for Me,".In summary,this is a "can't miss" Woody Allen film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssgv
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a beautiful movie about family ,love and forgiveness. This musical proved to me once again that Woody Allen is one of the best directors alive. Before I watched this film I never thought about Julia Roberts as a good actress but she proved me wrong her performance had entertained me. Edward Norton and Drew Barrymore relationship was the most entertaining to me ,Edward Norton was funny ,my favorite character in this film is Tim Roth's character he was great. Truly entertaining musical. my rating 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love - something to make a song and dance about.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone Says I Love You is, not to beat about the bush, Woody Allen's musical. And a delightful confection it is too. Revolving around the life and loves of one family unit, the movie hasn't really got anything to say but presents itself with such style, warmth and wit that you can't help but enjoy it anyway. The cast, as is usual for a Woody Allen movie, is superb. Natasha Lyonne is the sassy teenage girl narrating the events while Goldie Hawn, Alan Alda and Woody Allen himself portray the parental figures. Drew Barrymore and Ed Norton are the young, courting couple who have their world disturbed by a crooked Tim Roth. Then we have Lukas Haas, Natalie Portman and Gaby Hoffmann playing the other teen-aged siblings. Oh, and I almost forgot to mention Julia Roberts as a woman plagued with problems who may end up being the one woman who stays with Woody Allen's character. Or she may not. There are plenty of enjoyable lines in the script, as per usual, but this is mainly about getting from one song to the next and the musical numbers are enjoyable enough. The big plus for this movie, though, is how Allen beautifully mixes the unreal with the real and this is demonstrated perfectly in a song and dance moment he has with Goldie Hawn near the end of the movie. In fact, when it gets to that scene you really get behind the movie and realise that it's been playing around all this time to get to that place where magic can seep into the mundanity of the real world. It's a beautiful and moving sequence that ranks up there with the very best work that Allen has ever put on film. For that one scene alone, I recommend that people check this film out. Don't worry though, there's plenty more to enjoy en route with superb turns from all of the actors involved, some nice moments that remind you of the gloriously bedazzling musicals of old and numerous little touches that should bring a smile to your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, this time, I said it (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not a fan of Woody. Among 325 movies i watched so far, only one comes from him and it was terribly dull. Beyond, i don't like the buzz heard each year about his new movie because he seems to be a industrial brand. However, Stephen King who faces the same critic has a good answer : if they can release so much, it's because they work the same. Nevertheless, i couldn't stand also that his movies star the most talked actress of the moment. But there, he has himself the perfect answer: he paid them. Finally, I picked up this movie because Natalie plays in it, and i must say this was an excellent moment. The movie is split between three romantic cities (New York, Paris and Venise) and the choice for a daily diary is always interesting. Woody is really funny here as an anguished but sweet father (i was one day compared to him for that). His romance with Julia is depicted with truth. Natalie and her big family are attaching. As the movie is a musical, I suppose i have to speak my opinion about it. For me, the songs and dance suck because they are not classic tunes (at last for me)and they just stop the story. However, the ballet at the Seine banks is poetic. In conclusion, if this wealthy family is faraway of most people life, they form a united one and they bring us an happy moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Professionally amateur
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pyrocitor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As an incredible affinity with nostalgic populism has been a recurring theme throughout his expansive career, the melding of a 1930s inspired musical and Woody Allen does not seem to be as unorthodox an idea as one might expect. However, in typical form, Allen proves far more interested in pursuing his own whimsical train of thought and interest than pursuing a topic along conventional expectations, opting for a 'musical' more reflexive about the role of the musical as a genre than concentrating on itself as a new entry into the genre. The result, Everyone Says I Love You, subsequently proves to be one of Allen's most silly, experimental, self-indulgent, and yet delightfully enjoyable films. While initial inspection would find criticism in the lacklustre singing and dancing efforts of his primary cast, it becomes clear over time than Allen's film attempts to harness the inspirational impact of the musical and the role it plays within the lives of the general public, particularly as a tool for inner expression. Through intentionally casting 'non-singers' (rumour has it than Allen neglected to inform any of the cast the film was a musical until after they were cast), the film achieves a naturalistic feel, as if providing real people with the sudden opportunity for cathartic song and dance in a way excluded from 'real life', thus exposing them and their inner workings as characters. And it is this methodology that brings the film to life, providing a unique spin on an otherwise familiar Allen narrative of a web of quirky yet credible individuals weaving in and out of each other's lives and relationships, suggesting the fluidity of romance and human nature. However, as always, Allen is less interested in ascribing judgement on his characters as simply observing them in action (although there is an amusingly tongue-in-cheek subplot satirizing the film's young republican character which unwinds in a hilariously contentious fashion). Everyone Says I Love You ends up exploring the inevitability of the contradictions and lapses in judgement of human nature, leaving each new weave of the plot largely bereft of directorial moral guiding and all the more human because of it. Though the title may suggest a comment on the devaluing of emotional excesses regarding love, Allen's film never trivializes or languishes on love, but merely presents it as a universal human concern, his fluffy approach belying a more credibly sweet interior (the film's ending riverside dance sequence stands out as one of the more quiet, poignant and beautiful climaxes in recent cinema). That said, the film at heart remains more of an experimental exploration than firmly quality film, as Allen's script lacks the zing and wit of many of his more assured works, lagging somewhat midway through, and the entire film has a highly cobbled together, incohesive and somewhat amateurish feel (whether or not this fits with Allen's intent at naturalism remains up for debate). In addition, Allen sometimes gets a little too silly for his own good (a song and dance number with ghosts in a funeral home is really pushing it), though he never quite gets carried away enough to lose track of his intent or film as a singular entity. Regardless of what they may lack in vocal credentials, the film's cast certainly excels in terms of performance. Drew Barrymore masters the sweetness, innocence yet unpredictability of a somewhat na&iuml;ve young woman in love, and Edward Norton is a scream as her thoroughly wholesome yet vaguely self-centred fianc&eacute; (their prospective engagement scene in a restaurant, with Norton essaying his best neurotic Allen impression in the midst of growing chaos, is likely the film's most hilarious moment). Allen himself finds an entirely appropriate role for himself without taking over the narrative, toning down his eccentricities for the role of a man attempting to reconstruct his entire life in the image of his prospective lover's ideals, and is fully convincing and lovably pathetic in the process. As said romantic interest, Julia Roberts is left with little material to work with, but channels a fitting sense of grounded yearning nonetheless. Alan Alda is hilarious as the central family's sweetly outspoken patriarch, threatening to steal the show on multiple occasions, Goldie Hawn is somewhat underused yet both witty and touching as his wife (and Allen's ex-wife). Tim Roth steals the show with a far too brief part as an unbalanced, recently released convict, and a young Natalie Portman excels at credibly conveying teenage yearning for love without lapsing into clich&eacute;. While an undeniably whimsical entry into the Allen canon, Everyone Says I Love You remains a thought-provoking and thoroughly charming (albeit somewhat clumsy) film easily worth experiencing for those beguiled by musicals as much as musical lovers. -7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did I miss this Woody Allen movie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gottlieb.cindy@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! An all star cast singing and dancing in between the dialog. It has the usual Woody Allen premise of love lost angst on Woody's part. The plot twists and turns with love as its theme. The little nuances that are classic Woody Allen in the background, like the teenagers drinking hard liquor that no one is noticing, the stereo-typing of ethnic peoples, playing stick hockey in the fancy foyer, to name a few that have you looking for the absurd as if a game within the movie watching. Everyone is looking for ideal love except maybe not Alan Alda who has already found his in Goldie Hawn. The actual singing by the actors was not so good but that's what made the movie so perfect. The musical numbers and dancing were so campy it was excellent and entertaining. At times like watching the June Taylor Dancers including the over head camera shots. BRILLIANT! The Groucho Marx routine and party to follow was the best! A Great movie and should be up there with the top 10 Best Movies of all Times.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable musical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now I did like the old school style direction when it came to this musical. And the musical numbers is good and even cute in some cases. But despite how it tries to go in that sweet and meaningful direction of it all, it just didn't work all together. This has multiple different subplots going but it just wasn't all that effective. Even if it does kinda tie together in the end for the most part. With Woody Allen's character story as the primary. Although I didn't really watch this for Woody Allen but for Edward Norton, who is almost impossible to dislike. This just wasn't all that absorbing despite it trying to be sweet and charming, I just didn't fall for it. The plot is about characters trying to find there path, which revolves around love, sex, fantasies, politics, enjoying life, Christian and atheist views. It even tries to be witty and edgy but wasn't feeling it. Like I said it does tie together in the end but not all that well. Fans of Woody Allen might like this film, it does have a lot of his trademarks in this. Woody Allen put a lot of ideas into this movie, but everything just seemed so rushed and poorly developed. It seem to lack heart and goes more towards opinionated life views, which isn't even all that deep. Edward Norton is always cool though. And the musical number and choreography is good but also forgettable. This movie is about a hour and a half long but felt longer. It's disappointing since this has a good cast. 3.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    god when is it over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rob0352002
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed Norton, Barrymore, Roberts, Hawn, Alda, Portman... what's not to love? Well the boring, plodding, banal and mind numbingly worked story line that is as intricate as a cereal box. How can anyone like this? Did they get awards because of the cast? This proves to me that pretentious nits make a good market for an inane movie a college student could have composed. It reminds me of those self-indulgent "I am melancholy pay attention to my deep thoughts" of the 70s genre, which is how old you have to be to find this mildly entertaining. Woody Allen should just give it up. Then again, people will pretend he has talent because they are suppose to. Kind of like people paid a zillion dollars a ticket to see washed up Streisand in concert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm through with love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There came a point when the trademark opening to Woody Allen movies - plain white text on black backgrounds accompanied by a jazz song - went from classy and charming to twee and self conscious. That point really seemed to hit home around his lacklustre 90s period, largely due to the indifferent quality of most of the product. If your jazz opening is ironic juxtaposition to a genuinely funny film, or a more museful one, then it works. If it presages a mediocre offering with Larry David then it can look a little self congratulatory and pretentious. That feeling extends throughout the whole of Everyone Says I Love You, a film that doesn't seem to know what it wants to be... a genuine musical homage or pastiche. If seeing hospital patients or the ghosts of the dead dancing to show tunes is your thing, then it's ideal. But this kind of humour would work more in the full-on hands of a Mel Brooks, not a nebbish pseudo intellectual. And I say that as a fan of Woody. One thing that surprises is how almost everyone can hold a reasonable note in the cast, even Woody himself, with Hawn and Norton reputedly told to sing worse to make it more realistic. And technically there's no faulting the skill behind this piece, Allen's first picture in over ten years to be shot outside New York. But there's a twee, self-amused feel throughout, something made even worse by the character Allen plays in the film. I'm a huge Woody Allen fan, but I would never claim he has a great number of strings to his acting bow. Here he plays Woody Allen - this time called "Joe Berlin" - as a man who psychologically manipulates Julia Roberts into bed with him. Using spied knowledge of her intimate psychological secrets, Allen says and does the right thing at all time to procure a physical relationship... sorry, but isn't that practically rape? This unsettling subtext to the movie unbalances it still further, a dispiriting turn of events in a film that never seems to know quite what it wants to be. It's nice to see Woody trying something new thirty years into his movie career, but Everyone Says I Love You really needs to be filed under "inessential Allen".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody says they love this movie -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaaber-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - but I'm here to complain. I find the film embarrassing. Its slipshod dramaturgy (not foreign to Allen) makes "Meet Me in St. Louis" look like Shakespeare. The voice-over babbles on and on so as to make you think that Woody Allen ought to have written a novel instead. The film as such seems like a sorry excuse for the musical numbers which are few and far between. And then, as often with Allen, I feel like having to listen to a guy who goes on and on about his affairs with beautiful women and what a great lover he is. This time he's taking Julia Roberts and Goldie Hawn hostages. I wish I could believe that it's all tongue-in-cheek, but I can't. I give it two stars for the music only.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Still A "Can't Miss" Woody Allen Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen produced,wrote and directed an All-Star cast musical comedy set in modern day New York,Venice and Paris in this film,Everyone Says I Love You.The ensemble cast includes Alan Alda,Drew Barrymore,Lukas Haas,Goldie Hawn,Gaby Hoffmann,Natasha Lyonne,Edward Norton,Natalie Portman,Julia Roberts,Tim Roth,David Ogden Stiers and Woody Allen himself. The story centered on a polite and comfortably well-off group of people and their romantic difficulties.DJ (Natasha Lyonne), who narrates the picture, is the daughter of divorced couple Steffi (Goldie Hawn) and Joe (Woody Allen). Since the break-up, Steffi has married Bob (Alan Alda); their children, DJ's half-sister and half-brother, are Skyler (Drew Barrymore) and Scott (Lukas Haas). Skyler is about to be married to a likable chap named Holden (Edward Norton). However, her mother Steffi, a wealthy liberal, cultivates people as "projects." Her latest project is ex-con Charles (Tim Roth), an extremely rude and crude customer. At family gatherings, everyone politely ignores his lapses in manners and good taste until Skyler postpones her wedding to have an affair with him. In a parallel storyline, we see that DJ is convinced that her unmarried dad would find a perfect mate in Von (Julia Roberts), and she contrives an elaborate (and successful) scheme to bring them together. Overall,this is one of the best musicals made in the 90's although it does not compared to those done in the past especially when it tries to emulate typical of '30s musicals.But nevertheless,it still passes as one of the best film features made since the performances of the actors are great.Also,the love story involved is told with sincerity and honesty.Aside from that,it also presented great songs such as songs such as "Just You, Just Me" and "My Baby Just Cares for Me,".In summary,this is a "can't miss" Woody Allen film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssgv
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a beautiful movie about family ,love and forgiveness. This musical proved to me once again that Woody Allen is one of the best directors alive. Before I watched this film I never thought about Julia Roberts as a good actress but she proved me wrong her performance had entertained me. Edward Norton and Drew Barrymore relationship was the most entertaining to me ,Edward Norton was funny ,my favorite character in this film is Tim Roth's character he was great. Truly entertaining musical. my rating 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love - something to make a song and dance about.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone Says I Love You is, not to beat about the bush, Woody Allen's musical. And a delightful confection it is too. Revolving around the life and loves of one family unit, the movie hasn't really got anything to say but presents itself with such style, warmth and wit that you can't help but enjoy it anyway. The cast, as is usual for a Woody Allen movie, is superb. Natasha Lyonne is the sassy teenage girl narrating the events while Goldie Hawn, Alan Alda and Woody Allen himself portray the parental figures. Drew Barrymore and Ed Norton are the young, courting couple who have their world disturbed by a crooked Tim Roth. Then we have Lukas Haas, Natalie Portman and Gaby Hoffmann playing the other teen-aged siblings. Oh, and I almost forgot to mention Julia Roberts as a woman plagued with problems who may end up being the one woman who stays with Woody Allen's character. Or she may not. There are plenty of enjoyable lines in the script, as per usual, but this is mainly about getting from one song to the next and the musical numbers are enjoyable enough. The big plus for this movie, though, is how Allen beautifully mixes the unreal with the real and this is demonstrated perfectly in a song and dance moment he has with Goldie Hawn near the end of the movie. In fact, when it gets to that scene you really get behind the movie and realise that it's been playing around all this time to get to that place where magic can seep into the mundanity of the real world. It's a beautiful and moving sequence that ranks up there with the very best work that Allen has ever put on film. For that one scene alone, I recommend that people check this film out. Don't worry though, there's plenty more to enjoy en route with superb turns from all of the actors involved, some nice moments that remind you of the gloriously bedazzling musicals of old and numerous little touches that should bring a smile to your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, this time, I said it (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not a fan of Woody. Among 325 movies i watched so far, only one comes from him and it was terribly dull. Beyond, i don't like the buzz heard each year about his new movie because he seems to be a industrial brand. However, Stephen King who faces the same critic has a good answer : if they can release so much, it's because they work the same. Nevertheless, i couldn't stand also that his movies star the most talked actress of the moment. But there, he has himself the perfect answer: he paid them. Finally, I picked up this movie because Natalie plays in it, and i must say this was an excellent moment. The movie is split between three romantic cities (New York, Paris and Venise) and the choice for a daily diary is always interesting. Woody is really funny here as an anguished but sweet father (i was one day compared to him for that). His romance with Julia is depicted with truth. Natalie and her big family are attaching. As the movie is a musical, I suppose i have to speak my opinion about it. For me, the songs and dance suck because they are not classic tunes (at last for me)and they just stop the story. However, the ballet at the Seine banks is poetic. In conclusion, if this wealthy family is faraway of most people life, they form a united one and they bring us an happy moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Professionally amateur
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pyrocitor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As an incredible affinity with nostalgic populism has been a recurring theme throughout his expansive career, the melding of a 1930s inspired musical and Woody Allen does not seem to be as unorthodox an idea as one might expect. However, in typical form, Allen proves far more interested in pursuing his own whimsical train of thought and interest than pursuing a topic along conventional expectations, opting for a 'musical' more reflexive about the role of the musical as a genre than concentrating on itself as a new entry into the genre. The result, Everyone Says I Love You, subsequently proves to be one of Allen's most silly, experimental, self-indulgent, and yet delightfully enjoyable films. While initial inspection would find criticism in the lacklustre singing and dancing efforts of his primary cast, it becomes clear over time than Allen's film attempts to harness the inspirational impact of the musical and the role it plays within the lives of the general public, particularly as a tool for inner expression. Through intentionally casting 'non-singers' (rumour has it than Allen neglected to inform any of the cast the film was a musical until after they were cast), the film achieves a naturalistic feel, as if providing real people with the sudden opportunity for cathartic song and dance in a way excluded from 'real life', thus exposing them and their inner workings as characters. And it is this methodology that brings the film to life, providing a unique spin on an otherwise familiar Allen narrative of a web of quirky yet credible individuals weaving in and out of each other's lives and relationships, suggesting the fluidity of romance and human nature. However, as always, Allen is less interested in ascribing judgement on his characters as simply observing them in action (although there is an amusingly tongue-in-cheek subplot satirizing the film's young republican character which unwinds in a hilariously contentious fashion). Everyone Says I Love You ends up exploring the inevitability of the contradictions and lapses in judgement of human nature, leaving each new weave of the plot largely bereft of directorial moral guiding and all the more human because of it. Though the title may suggest a comment on the devaluing of emotional excesses regarding love, Allen's film never trivializes or languishes on love, but merely presents it as a universal human concern, his fluffy approach belying a more credibly sweet interior (the film's ending riverside dance sequence stands out as one of the more quiet, poignant and beautiful climaxes in recent cinema). That said, the film at heart remains more of an experimental exploration than firmly quality film, as Allen's script lacks the zing and wit of many of his more assured works, lagging somewhat midway through, and the entire film has a highly cobbled together, incohesive and somewhat amateurish feel (whether or not this fits with Allen's intent at naturalism remains up for debate). In addition, Allen sometimes gets a little too silly for his own good (a song and dance number with ghosts in a funeral home is really pushing it), though he never quite gets carried away enough to lose track of his intent or film as a singular entity. Regardless of what they may lack in vocal credentials, the film's cast certainly excels in terms of performance. Drew Barrymore masters the sweetness, innocence yet unpredictability of a somewhat na&iuml;ve young woman in love, and Edward Norton is a scream as her thoroughly wholesome yet vaguely self-centred fianc&eacute; (their prospective engagement scene in a restaurant, with Norton essaying his best neurotic Allen impression in the midst of growing chaos, is likely the film's most hilarious moment). Allen himself finds an entirely appropriate role for himself without taking over the narrative, toning down his eccentricities for the role of a man attempting to reconstruct his entire life in the image of his prospective lover's ideals, and is fully convincing and lovably pathetic in the process. As said romantic interest, Julia Roberts is left with little material to work with, but channels a fitting sense of grounded yearning nonetheless. Alan Alda is hilarious as the central family's sweetly outspoken patriarch, threatening to steal the show on multiple occasions, Goldie Hawn is somewhat underused yet both witty and touching as his wife (and Allen's ex-wife). Tim Roth steals the show with a far too brief part as an unbalanced, recently released convict, and a young Natalie Portman excels at credibly conveying teenage yearning for love without lapsing into clich&eacute;. While an undeniably whimsical entry into the Allen canon, Everyone Says I Love You remains a thought-provoking and thoroughly charming (albeit somewhat clumsy) film easily worth experiencing for those beguiled by musicals as much as musical lovers. -7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did I miss this Woody Allen movie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gottlieb.cindy@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! An all star cast singing and dancing in between the dialog. It has the usual Woody Allen premise of love lost angst on Woody's part. The plot twists and turns with love as its theme. The little nuances that are classic Woody Allen in the background, like the teenagers drinking hard liquor that no one is noticing, the stereo-typing of ethnic peoples, playing stick hockey in the fancy foyer, to name a few that have you looking for the absurd as if a game within the movie watching. Everyone is looking for ideal love except maybe not Alan Alda who has already found his in Goldie Hawn. The actual singing by the actors was not so good but that's what made the movie so perfect. The musical numbers and dancing were so campy it was excellent and entertaining. At times like watching the June Taylor Dancers including the over head camera shots. BRILLIANT! The Groucho Marx routine and party to follow was the best! A Great movie and should be up there with the top 10 Best Movies of all Times.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable musical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now I did like the old school style direction when it came to this musical. And the musical numbers is good and even cute in some cases. But despite how it tries to go in that sweet and meaningful direction of it all, it just didn't work all together. This has multiple different subplots going but it just wasn't all that effective. Even if it does kinda tie together in the end for the most part. With Woody Allen's character story as the primary. Although I didn't really watch this for Woody Allen but for Edward Norton, who is almost impossible to dislike. This just wasn't all that absorbing despite it trying to be sweet and charming, I just didn't fall for it. The plot is about characters trying to find there path, which revolves around love, sex, fantasies, politics, enjoying life, Christian and atheist views. It even tries to be witty and edgy but wasn't feeling it. Like I said it does tie together in the end but not all that well. Fans of Woody Allen might like this film, it does have a lot of his trademarks in this. Woody Allen put a lot of ideas into this movie, but everything just seemed so rushed and poorly developed. It seem to lack heart and goes more towards opinionated life views, which isn't even all that deep. Edward Norton is always cool though. And the musical number and choreography is good but also forgettable. This movie is about a hour and a half long but felt longer. It's disappointing since this has a good cast. 3.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    god when is it over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rob0352002
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed Norton, Barrymore, Roberts, Hawn, Alda, Portman... what's not to love? Well the boring, plodding, banal and mind numbingly worked story line that is as intricate as a cereal box. How can anyone like this? Did they get awards because of the cast? This proves to me that pretentious nits make a good market for an inane movie a college student could have composed. It reminds me of those self-indulgent "I am melancholy pay attention to my deep thoughts" of the 70s genre, which is how old you have to be to find this mildly entertaining. Woody Allen should just give it up. Then again, people will pretend he has talent because they are suppose to. Kind of like people paid a zillion dollars a ticket to see washed up Streisand in concert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm through with love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There came a point when the trademark opening to Woody Allen movies - plain white text on black backgrounds accompanied by a jazz song - went from classy and charming to twee and self conscious. That point really seemed to hit home around his lacklustre 90s period, largely due to the indifferent quality of most of the product. If your jazz opening is ironic juxtaposition to a genuinely funny film, or a more museful one, then it works. If it presages a mediocre offering with Larry David then it can look a little self congratulatory and pretentious. That feeling extends throughout the whole of Everyone Says I Love You, a film that doesn't seem to know what it wants to be... a genuine musical homage or pastiche. If seeing hospital patients or the ghosts of the dead dancing to show tunes is your thing, then it's ideal. But this kind of humour would work more in the full-on hands of a Mel Brooks, not a nebbish pseudo intellectual. And I say that as a fan of Woody. One thing that surprises is how almost everyone can hold a reasonable note in the cast, even Woody himself, with Hawn and Norton reputedly told to sing worse to make it more realistic. And technically there's no faulting the skill behind this piece, Allen's first picture in over ten years to be shot outside New York. But there's a twee, self-amused feel throughout, something made even worse by the character Allen plays in the film. I'm a huge Woody Allen fan, but I would never claim he has a great number of strings to his acting bow. Here he plays Woody Allen - this time called "Joe Berlin" - as a man who psychologically manipulates Julia Roberts into bed with him. Using spied knowledge of her intimate psychological secrets, Allen says and does the right thing at all time to procure a physical relationship... sorry, but isn't that practically rape? This unsettling subtext to the movie unbalances it still further, a dispiriting turn of events in a film that never seems to know quite what it wants to be. It's nice to see Woody trying something new thirty years into his movie career, but Everyone Says I Love You really needs to be filed under "inessential Allen".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody says they love this movie -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaaber-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - but I'm here to complain. I find the film embarrassing. Its slipshod dramaturgy (not foreign to Allen) makes "Meet Me in St. Louis" look like Shakespeare. The voice-over babbles on and on so as to make you think that Woody Allen ought to have written a novel instead. The film as such seems like a sorry excuse for the musical numbers which are few and far between. And then, as often with Allen, I feel like having to listen to a guy who goes on and on about his affairs with beautiful women and what a great lover he is. This time he's taking Julia Roberts and Goldie Hawn hostages. I wish I could believe that it's all tongue-in-cheek, but I can't. I give it two stars for the music only.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Still A "Can't Miss" Woody Allen Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen produced,wrote and directed an All-Star cast musical comedy set in modern day New York,Venice and Paris in this film,Everyone Says I Love You.The ensemble cast includes Alan Alda,Drew Barrymore,Lukas Haas,Goldie Hawn,Gaby Hoffmann,Natasha Lyonne,Edward Norton,Natalie Portman,Julia Roberts,Tim Roth,David Ogden Stiers and Woody Allen himself. The story centered on a polite and comfortably well-off group of people and their romantic difficulties.DJ (Natasha Lyonne), who narrates the picture, is the daughter of divorced couple Steffi (Goldie Hawn) and Joe (Woody Allen). Since the break-up, Steffi has married Bob (Alan Alda); their children, DJ's half-sister and half-brother, are Skyler (Drew Barrymore) and Scott (Lukas Haas). Skyler is about to be married to a likable chap named Holden (Edward Norton). However, her mother Steffi, a wealthy liberal, cultivates people as "projects." Her latest project is ex-con Charles (Tim Roth), an extremely rude and crude customer. At family gatherings, everyone politely ignores his lapses in manners and good taste until Skyler postpones her wedding to have an affair with him. In a parallel storyline, we see that DJ is convinced that her unmarried dad would find a perfect mate in Von (Julia Roberts), and she contrives an elaborate (and successful) scheme to bring them together. Overall,this is one of the best musicals made in the 90's although it does not compared to those done in the past especially when it tries to emulate typical of '30s musicals.But nevertheless,it still passes as one of the best film features made since the performances of the actors are great.Also,the love story involved is told with sincerity and honesty.Aside from that,it also presented great songs such as songs such as "Just You, Just Me" and "My Baby Just Cares for Me,".In summary,this is a "can't miss" Woody Allen film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssgv
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a beautiful movie about family ,love and forgiveness. This musical proved to me once again that Woody Allen is one of the best directors alive. Before I watched this film I never thought about Julia Roberts as a good actress but she proved me wrong her performance had entertained me. Edward Norton and Drew Barrymore relationship was the most entertaining to me ,Edward Norton was funny ,my favorite character in this film is Tim Roth's character he was great. Truly entertaining musical. my rating 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love - something to make a song and dance about.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone Says I Love You is, not to beat about the bush, Woody Allen's musical. And a delightful confection it is too. Revolving around the life and loves of one family unit, the movie hasn't really got anything to say but presents itself with such style, warmth and wit that you can't help but enjoy it anyway. The cast, as is usual for a Woody Allen movie, is superb. Natasha Lyonne is the sassy teenage girl narrating the events while Goldie Hawn, Alan Alda and Woody Allen himself portray the parental figures. Drew Barrymore and Ed Norton are the young, courting couple who have their world disturbed by a crooked Tim Roth. Then we have Lukas Haas, Natalie Portman and Gaby Hoffmann playing the other teen-aged siblings. Oh, and I almost forgot to mention Julia Roberts as a woman plagued with problems who may end up being the one woman who stays with Woody Allen's character. Or she may not. There are plenty of enjoyable lines in the script, as per usual, but this is mainly about getting from one song to the next and the musical numbers are enjoyable enough. The big plus for this movie, though, is how Allen beautifully mixes the unreal with the real and this is demonstrated perfectly in a song and dance moment he has with Goldie Hawn near the end of the movie. In fact, when it gets to that scene you really get behind the movie and realise that it's been playing around all this time to get to that place where magic can seep into the mundanity of the real world. It's a beautiful and moving sequence that ranks up there with the very best work that Allen has ever put on film. For that one scene alone, I recommend that people check this film out. Don't worry though, there's plenty more to enjoy en route with superb turns from all of the actors involved, some nice moments that remind you of the gloriously bedazzling musicals of old and numerous little touches that should bring a smile to your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, this time, I said it (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not a fan of Woody. Among 325 movies i watched so far, only one comes from him and it was terribly dull. Beyond, i don't like the buzz heard each year about his new movie because he seems to be a industrial brand. However, Stephen King who faces the same critic has a good answer : if they can release so much, it's because they work the same. Nevertheless, i couldn't stand also that his movies star the most talked actress of the moment. But there, he has himself the perfect answer: he paid them. Finally, I picked up this movie because Natalie plays in it, and i must say this was an excellent moment. The movie is split between three romantic cities (New York, Paris and Venise) and the choice for a daily diary is always interesting. Woody is really funny here as an anguished but sweet father (i was one day compared to him for that). His romance with Julia is depicted with truth. Natalie and her big family are attaching. As the movie is a musical, I suppose i have to speak my opinion about it. For me, the songs and dance suck because they are not classic tunes (at last for me)and they just stop the story. However, the ballet at the Seine banks is poetic. In conclusion, if this wealthy family is faraway of most people life, they form a united one and they bring us an happy moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Professionally amateur
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pyrocitor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As an incredible affinity with nostalgic populism has been a recurring theme throughout his expansive career, the melding of a 1930s inspired musical and Woody Allen does not seem to be as unorthodox an idea as one might expect. However, in typical form, Allen proves far more interested in pursuing his own whimsical train of thought and interest than pursuing a topic along conventional expectations, opting for a 'musical' more reflexive about the role of the musical as a genre than concentrating on itself as a new entry into the genre. The result, Everyone Says I Love You, subsequently proves to be one of Allen's most silly, experimental, self-indulgent, and yet delightfully enjoyable films. While initial inspection would find criticism in the lacklustre singing and dancing efforts of his primary cast, it becomes clear over time than Allen's film attempts to harness the inspirational impact of the musical and the role it plays within the lives of the general public, particularly as a tool for inner expression. Through intentionally casting 'non-singers' (rumour has it than Allen neglected to inform any of the cast the film was a musical until after they were cast), the film achieves a naturalistic feel, as if providing real people with the sudden opportunity for cathartic song and dance in a way excluded from 'real life', thus exposing them and their inner workings as characters. And it is this methodology that brings the film to life, providing a unique spin on an otherwise familiar Allen narrative of a web of quirky yet credible individuals weaving in and out of each other's lives and relationships, suggesting the fluidity of romance and human nature. However, as always, Allen is less interested in ascribing judgement on his characters as simply observing them in action (although there is an amusingly tongue-in-cheek subplot satirizing the film's young republican character which unwinds in a hilariously contentious fashion). Everyone Says I Love You ends up exploring the inevitability of the contradictions and lapses in judgement of human nature, leaving each new weave of the plot largely bereft of directorial moral guiding and all the more human because of it. Though the title may suggest a comment on the devaluing of emotional excesses regarding love, Allen's film never trivializes or languishes on love, but merely presents it as a universal human concern, his fluffy approach belying a more credibly sweet interior (the film's ending riverside dance sequence stands out as one of the more quiet, poignant and beautiful climaxes in recent cinema). That said, the film at heart remains more of an experimental exploration than firmly quality film, as Allen's script lacks the zing and wit of many of his more assured works, lagging somewhat midway through, and the entire film has a highly cobbled together, incohesive and somewhat amateurish feel (whether or not this fits with Allen's intent at naturalism remains up for debate). In addition, Allen sometimes gets a little too silly for his own good (a song and dance number with ghosts in a funeral home is really pushing it), though he never quite gets carried away enough to lose track of his intent or film as a singular entity. Regardless of what they may lack in vocal credentials, the film's cast certainly excels in terms of performance. Drew Barrymore masters the sweetness, innocence yet unpredictability of a somewhat na&iuml;ve young woman in love, and Edward Norton is a scream as her thoroughly wholesome yet vaguely self-centred fianc&eacute; (their prospective engagement scene in a restaurant, with Norton essaying his best neurotic Allen impression in the midst of growing chaos, is likely the film's most hilarious moment). Allen himself finds an entirely appropriate role for himself without taking over the narrative, toning down his eccentricities for the role of a man attempting to reconstruct his entire life in the image of his prospective lover's ideals, and is fully convincing and lovably pathetic in the process. As said romantic interest, Julia Roberts is left with little material to work with, but channels a fitting sense of grounded yearning nonetheless. Alan Alda is hilarious as the central family's sweetly outspoken patriarch, threatening to steal the show on multiple occasions, Goldie Hawn is somewhat underused yet both witty and touching as his wife (and Allen's ex-wife). Tim Roth steals the show with a far too brief part as an unbalanced, recently released convict, and a young Natalie Portman excels at credibly conveying teenage yearning for love without lapsing into clich&eacute;. While an undeniably whimsical entry into the Allen canon, Everyone Says I Love You remains a thought-provoking and thoroughly charming (albeit somewhat clumsy) film easily worth experiencing for those beguiled by musicals as much as musical lovers. -7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did I miss this Woody Allen movie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gottlieb.cindy@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! An all star cast singing and dancing in between the dialog. It has the usual Woody Allen premise of love lost angst on Woody's part. The plot twists and turns with love as its theme. The little nuances that are classic Woody Allen in the background, like the teenagers drinking hard liquor that no one is noticing, the stereo-typing of ethnic peoples, playing stick hockey in the fancy foyer, to name a few that have you looking for the absurd as if a game within the movie watching. Everyone is looking for ideal love except maybe not Alan Alda who has already found his in Goldie Hawn. The actual singing by the actors was not so good but that's what made the movie so perfect. The musical numbers and dancing were so campy it was excellent and entertaining. At times like watching the June Taylor Dancers including the over head camera shots. BRILLIANT! The Groucho Marx routine and party to follow was the best! A Great movie and should be up there with the top 10 Best Movies of all Times.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable musical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now I did like the old school style direction when it came to this musical. And the musical numbers is good and even cute in some cases. But despite how it tries to go in that sweet and meaningful direction of it all, it just didn't work all together. This has multiple different subplots going but it just wasn't all that effective. Even if it does kinda tie together in the end for the most part. With Woody Allen's character story as the primary. Although I didn't really watch this for Woody Allen but for Edward Norton, who is almost impossible to dislike. This just wasn't all that absorbing despite it trying to be sweet and charming, I just didn't fall for it. The plot is about characters trying to find there path, which revolves around love, sex, fantasies, politics, enjoying life, Christian and atheist views. It even tries to be witty and edgy but wasn't feeling it. Like I said it does tie together in the end but not all that well. Fans of Woody Allen might like this film, it does have a lot of his trademarks in this. Woody Allen put a lot of ideas into this movie, but everything just seemed so rushed and poorly developed. It seem to lack heart and goes more towards opinionated life views, which isn't even all that deep. Edward Norton is always cool though. And the musical number and choreography is good but also forgettable. This movie is about a hour and a half long but felt longer. It's disappointing since this has a good cast. 3.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    god when is it over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rob0352002
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed Norton, Barrymore, Roberts, Hawn, Alda, Portman... what's not to love? Well the boring, plodding, banal and mind numbingly worked story line that is as intricate as a cereal box. How can anyone like this? Did they get awards because of the cast? This proves to me that pretentious nits make a good market for an inane movie a college student could have composed. It reminds me of those self-indulgent "I am melancholy pay attention to my deep thoughts" of the 70s genre, which is how old you have to be to find this mildly entertaining. Woody Allen should just give it up. Then again, people will pretend he has talent because they are suppose to. Kind of like people paid a zillion dollars a ticket to see washed up Streisand in concert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm through with love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There came a point when the trademark opening to Woody Allen movies - plain white text on black backgrounds accompanied by a jazz song - went from classy and charming to twee and self conscious. That point really seemed to hit home around his lacklustre 90s period, largely due to the indifferent quality of most of the product. If your jazz opening is ironic juxtaposition to a genuinely funny film, or a more museful one, then it works. If it presages a mediocre offering with Larry David then it can look a little self congratulatory and pretentious. That feeling extends throughout the whole of Everyone Says I Love You, a film that doesn't seem to know what it wants to be... a genuine musical homage or pastiche. If seeing hospital patients or the ghosts of the dead dancing to show tunes is your thing, then it's ideal. But this kind of humour would work more in the full-on hands of a Mel Brooks, not a nebbish pseudo intellectual. And I say that as a fan of Woody. One thing that surprises is how almost everyone can hold a reasonable note in the cast, even Woody himself, with Hawn and Norton reputedly told to sing worse to make it more realistic. And technically there's no faulting the skill behind this piece, Allen's first picture in over ten years to be shot outside New York. But there's a twee, self-amused feel throughout, something made even worse by the character Allen plays in the film. I'm a huge Woody Allen fan, but I would never claim he has a great number of strings to his acting bow. Here he plays Woody Allen - this time called "Joe Berlin" - as a man who psychologically manipulates Julia Roberts into bed with him. Using spied knowledge of her intimate psychological secrets, Allen says and does the right thing at all time to procure a physical relationship... sorry, but isn't that practically rape? This unsettling subtext to the movie unbalances it still further, a dispiriting turn of events in a film that never seems to know quite what it wants to be. It's nice to see Woody trying something new thirty years into his movie career, but Everyone Says I Love You really needs to be filed under "inessential Allen".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody says they love this movie -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaaber-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - but I'm here to complain. I find the film embarrassing. Its slipshod dramaturgy (not foreign to Allen) makes "Meet Me in St. Louis" look like Shakespeare. The voice-over babbles on and on so as to make you think that Woody Allen ought to have written a novel instead. The film as such seems like a sorry excuse for the musical numbers which are few and far between. And then, as often with Allen, I feel like having to listen to a guy who goes on and on about his affairs with beautiful women and what a great lover he is. This time he's taking Julia Roberts and Goldie Hawn hostages. I wish I could believe that it's all tongue-in-cheek, but I can't. I give it two stars for the music only.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Still A "Can't Miss" Woody Allen Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen produced,wrote and directed an All-Star cast musical comedy set in modern day New York,Venice and Paris in this film,Everyone Says I Love You.The ensemble cast includes Alan Alda,Drew Barrymore,Lukas Haas,Goldie Hawn,Gaby Hoffmann,Natasha Lyonne,Edward Norton,Natalie Portman,Julia Roberts,Tim Roth,David Ogden Stiers and Woody Allen himself. The story centered on a polite and comfortably well-off group of people and their romantic difficulties.DJ (Natasha Lyonne), who narrates the picture, is the daughter of divorced couple Steffi (Goldie Hawn) and Joe (Woody Allen). Since the break-up, Steffi has married Bob (Alan Alda); their children, DJ's half-sister and half-brother, are Skyler (Drew Barrymore) and Scott (Lukas Haas). Skyler is about to be married to a likable chap named Holden (Edward Norton). However, her mother Steffi, a wealthy liberal, cultivates people as "projects." Her latest project is ex-con Charles (Tim Roth), an extremely rude and crude customer. At family gatherings, everyone politely ignores his lapses in manners and good taste until Skyler postpones her wedding to have an affair with him. In a parallel storyline, we see that DJ is convinced that her unmarried dad would find a perfect mate in Von (Julia Roberts), and she contrives an elaborate (and successful) scheme to bring them together. Overall,this is one of the best musicals made in the 90's although it does not compared to those done in the past especially when it tries to emulate typical of '30s musicals.But nevertheless,it still passes as one of the best film features made since the performances of the actors are great.Also,the love story involved is told with sincerity and honesty.Aside from that,it also presented great songs such as songs such as "Just You, Just Me" and "My Baby Just Cares for Me,".In summary,this is a "can't miss" Woody Allen film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssgv
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a beautiful movie about family ,love and forgiveness. This musical proved to me once again that Woody Allen is one of the best directors alive. Before I watched this film I never thought about Julia Roberts as a good actress but she proved me wrong her performance had entertained me. Edward Norton and Drew Barrymore relationship was the most entertaining to me ,Edward Norton was funny ,my favorite character in this film is Tim Roth's character he was great. Truly entertaining musical. my rating 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love - something to make a song and dance about.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone Says I Love You is, not to beat about the bush, Woody Allen's musical. And a delightful confection it is too. Revolving around the life and loves of one family unit, the movie hasn't really got anything to say but presents itself with such style, warmth and wit that you can't help but enjoy it anyway. The cast, as is usual for a Woody Allen movie, is superb. Natasha Lyonne is the sassy teenage girl narrating the events while Goldie Hawn, Alan Alda and Woody Allen himself portray the parental figures. Drew Barrymore and Ed Norton are the young, courting couple who have their world disturbed by a crooked Tim Roth. Then we have Lukas Haas, Natalie Portman and Gaby Hoffmann playing the other teen-aged siblings. Oh, and I almost forgot to mention Julia Roberts as a woman plagued with problems who may end up being the one woman who stays with Woody Allen's character. Or she may not. There are plenty of enjoyable lines in the script, as per usual, but this is mainly about getting from one song to the next and the musical numbers are enjoyable enough. The big plus for this movie, though, is how Allen beautifully mixes the unreal with the real and this is demonstrated perfectly in a song and dance moment he has with Goldie Hawn near the end of the movie. In fact, when it gets to that scene you really get behind the movie and realise that it's been playing around all this time to get to that place where magic can seep into the mundanity of the real world. It's a beautiful and moving sequence that ranks up there with the very best work that Allen has ever put on film. For that one scene alone, I recommend that people check this film out. Don't worry though, there's plenty more to enjoy en route with superb turns from all of the actors involved, some nice moments that remind you of the gloriously bedazzling musicals of old and numerous little touches that should bring a smile to your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, this time, I said it (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not a fan of Woody. Among 325 movies i watched so far, only one comes from him and it was terribly dull. Beyond, i don't like the buzz heard each year about his new movie because he seems to be a industrial brand. However, Stephen King who faces the same critic has a good answer : if they can release so much, it's because they work the same. Nevertheless, i couldn't stand also that his movies star the most talked actress of the moment. But there, he has himself the perfect answer: he paid them. Finally, I picked up this movie because Natalie plays in it, and i must say this was an excellent moment. The movie is split between three romantic cities (New York, Paris and Venise) and the choice for a daily diary is always interesting. Woody is really funny here as an anguished but sweet father (i was one day compared to him for that). His romance with Julia is depicted with truth. Natalie and her big family are attaching. As the movie is a musical, I suppose i have to speak my opinion about it. For me, the songs and dance suck because they are not classic tunes (at last for me)and they just stop the story. However, the ballet at the Seine banks is poetic. In conclusion, if this wealthy family is faraway of most people life, they form a united one and they bring us an happy moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Professionally amateur
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pyrocitor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As an incredible affinity with nostalgic populism has been a recurring theme throughout his expansive career, the melding of a 1930s inspired musical and Woody Allen does not seem to be as unorthodox an idea as one might expect. However, in typical form, Allen proves far more interested in pursuing his own whimsical train of thought and interest than pursuing a topic along conventional expectations, opting for a 'musical' more reflexive about the role of the musical as a genre than concentrating on itself as a new entry into the genre. The result, Everyone Says I Love You, subsequently proves to be one of Allen's most silly, experimental, self-indulgent, and yet delightfully enjoyable films. While initial inspection would find criticism in the lacklustre singing and dancing efforts of his primary cast, it becomes clear over time than Allen's film attempts to harness the inspirational impact of the musical and the role it plays within the lives of the general public, particularly as a tool for inner expression. Through intentionally casting 'non-singers' (rumour has it than Allen neglected to inform any of the cast the film was a musical until after they were cast), the film achieves a naturalistic feel, as if providing real people with the sudden opportunity for cathartic song and dance in a way excluded from 'real life', thus exposing them and their inner workings as characters. And it is this methodology that brings the film to life, providing a unique spin on an otherwise familiar Allen narrative of a web of quirky yet credible individuals weaving in and out of each other's lives and relationships, suggesting the fluidity of romance and human nature. However, as always, Allen is less interested in ascribing judgement on his characters as simply observing them in action (although there is an amusingly tongue-in-cheek subplot satirizing the film's young republican character which unwinds in a hilariously contentious fashion). Everyone Says I Love You ends up exploring the inevitability of the contradictions and lapses in judgement of human nature, leaving each new weave of the plot largely bereft of directorial moral guiding and all the more human because of it. Though the title may suggest a comment on the devaluing of emotional excesses regarding love, Allen's film never trivializes or languishes on love, but merely presents it as a universal human concern, his fluffy approach belying a more credibly sweet interior (the film's ending riverside dance sequence stands out as one of the more quiet, poignant and beautiful climaxes in recent cinema). That said, the film at heart remains more of an experimental exploration than firmly quality film, as Allen's script lacks the zing and wit of many of his more assured works, lagging somewhat midway through, and the entire film has a highly cobbled together, incohesive and somewhat amateurish feel (whether or not this fits with Allen's intent at naturalism remains up for debate). In addition, Allen sometimes gets a little too silly for his own good (a song and dance number with ghosts in a funeral home is really pushing it), though he never quite gets carried away enough to lose track of his intent or film as a singular entity. Regardless of what they may lack in vocal credentials, the film's cast certainly excels in terms of performance. Drew Barrymore masters the sweetness, innocence yet unpredictability of a somewhat na&iuml;ve young woman in love, and Edward Norton is a scream as her thoroughly wholesome yet vaguely self-centred fianc&eacute; (their prospective engagement scene in a restaurant, with Norton essaying his best neurotic Allen impression in the midst of growing chaos, is likely the film's most hilarious moment). Allen himself finds an entirely appropriate role for himself without taking over the narrative, toning down his eccentricities for the role of a man attempting to reconstruct his entire life in the image of his prospective lover's ideals, and is fully convincing and lovably pathetic in the process. As said romantic interest, Julia Roberts is left with little material to work with, but channels a fitting sense of grounded yearning nonetheless. Alan Alda is hilarious as the central family's sweetly outspoken patriarch, threatening to steal the show on multiple occasions, Goldie Hawn is somewhat underused yet both witty and touching as his wife (and Allen's ex-wife). Tim Roth steals the show with a far too brief part as an unbalanced, recently released convict, and a young Natalie Portman excels at credibly conveying teenage yearning for love without lapsing into clich&eacute;. While an undeniably whimsical entry into the Allen canon, Everyone Says I Love You remains a thought-provoking and thoroughly charming (albeit somewhat clumsy) film easily worth experiencing for those beguiled by musicals as much as musical lovers. -7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did I miss this Woody Allen movie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gottlieb.cindy@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! An all star cast singing and dancing in between the dialog. It has the usual Woody Allen premise of love lost angst on Woody's part. The plot twists and turns with love as its theme. The little nuances that are classic Woody Allen in the background, like the teenagers drinking hard liquor that no one is noticing, the stereo-typing of ethnic peoples, playing stick hockey in the fancy foyer, to name a few that have you looking for the absurd as if a game within the movie watching. Everyone is looking for ideal love except maybe not Alan Alda who has already found his in Goldie Hawn. The actual singing by the actors was not so good but that's what made the movie so perfect. The musical numbers and dancing were so campy it was excellent and entertaining. At times like watching the June Taylor Dancers including the over head camera shots. BRILLIANT! The Groucho Marx routine and party to follow was the best! A Great movie and should be up there with the top 10 Best Movies of all Times.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable musical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now I did like the old school style direction when it came to this musical. And the musical numbers is good and even cute in some cases. But despite how it tries to go in that sweet and meaningful direction of it all, it just didn't work all together. This has multiple different subplots going but it just wasn't all that effective. Even if it does kinda tie together in the end for the most part. With Woody Allen's character story as the primary. Although I didn't really watch this for Woody Allen but for Edward Norton, who is almost impossible to dislike. This just wasn't all that absorbing despite it trying to be sweet and charming, I just didn't fall for it. The plot is about characters trying to find there path, which revolves around love, sex, fantasies, politics, enjoying life, Christian and atheist views. It even tries to be witty and edgy but wasn't feeling it. Like I said it does tie together in the end but not all that well. Fans of Woody Allen might like this film, it does have a lot of his trademarks in this. Woody Allen put a lot of ideas into this movie, but everything just seemed so rushed and poorly developed. It seem to lack heart and goes more towards opinionated life views, which isn't even all that deep. Edward Norton is always cool though. And the musical number and choreography is good but also forgettable. This movie is about a hour and a half long but felt longer. It's disappointing since this has a good cast. 3.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    god when is it over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rob0352002
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed Norton, Barrymore, Roberts, Hawn, Alda, Portman... what's not to love? Well the boring, plodding, banal and mind numbingly worked story line that is as intricate as a cereal box. How can anyone like this? Did they get awards because of the cast? This proves to me that pretentious nits make a good market for an inane movie a college student could have composed. It reminds me of those self-indulgent "I am melancholy pay attention to my deep thoughts" of the 70s genre, which is how old you have to be to find this mildly entertaining. Woody Allen should just give it up. Then again, people will pretend he has talent because they are suppose to. Kind of like people paid a zillion dollars a ticket to see washed up Streisand in concert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm through with love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There came a point when the trademark opening to Woody Allen movies - plain white text on black backgrounds accompanied by a jazz song - went from classy and charming to twee and self conscious. That point really seemed to hit home around his lacklustre 90s period, largely due to the indifferent quality of most of the product. If your jazz opening is ironic juxtaposition to a genuinely funny film, or a more museful one, then it works. If it presages a mediocre offering with Larry David then it can look a little self congratulatory and pretentious. That feeling extends throughout the whole of Everyone Says I Love You, a film that doesn't seem to know what it wants to be... a genuine musical homage or pastiche. If seeing hospital patients or the ghosts of the dead dancing to show tunes is your thing, then it's ideal. But this kind of humour would work more in the full-on hands of a Mel Brooks, not a nebbish pseudo intellectual. And I say that as a fan of Woody. One thing that surprises is how almost everyone can hold a reasonable note in the cast, even Woody himself, with Hawn and Norton reputedly told to sing worse to make it more realistic. And technically there's no faulting the skill behind this piece, Allen's first picture in over ten years to be shot outside New York. But there's a twee, self-amused feel throughout, something made even worse by the character Allen plays in the film. I'm a huge Woody Allen fan, but I would never claim he has a great number of strings to his acting bow. Here he plays Woody Allen - this time called "Joe Berlin" - as a man who psychologically manipulates Julia Roberts into bed with him. Using spied knowledge of her intimate psychological secrets, Allen says and does the right thing at all time to procure a physical relationship... sorry, but isn't that practically rape? This unsettling subtext to the movie unbalances it still further, a dispiriting turn of events in a film that never seems to know quite what it wants to be. It's nice to see Woody trying something new thirty years into his movie career, but Everyone Says I Love You really needs to be filed under "inessential Allen".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody says they love this movie -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaaber-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - but I'm here to complain. I find the film embarrassing. Its slipshod dramaturgy (not foreign to Allen) makes "Meet Me in St. Louis" look like Shakespeare. The voice-over babbles on and on so as to make you think that Woody Allen ought to have written a novel instead. The film as such seems like a sorry excuse for the musical numbers which are few and far between. And then, as often with Allen, I feel like having to listen to a guy who goes on and on about his affairs with beautiful women and what a great lover he is. This time he's taking Julia Roberts and Goldie Hawn hostages. I wish I could believe that it's all tongue-in-cheek, but I can't. I give it two stars for the music only.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Still A "Can't Miss" Woody Allen Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen produced,wrote and directed an All-Star cast musical comedy set in modern day New York,Venice and Paris in this film,Everyone Says I Love You.The ensemble cast includes Alan Alda,Drew Barrymore,Lukas Haas,Goldie Hawn,Gaby Hoffmann,Natasha Lyonne,Edward Norton,Natalie Portman,Julia Roberts,Tim Roth,David Ogden Stiers and Woody Allen himself. The story centered on a polite and comfortably well-off group of people and their romantic difficulties.DJ (Natasha Lyonne), who narrates the picture, is the daughter of divorced couple Steffi (Goldie Hawn) and Joe (Woody Allen). Since the break-up, Steffi has married Bob (Alan Alda); their children, DJ's half-sister and half-brother, are Skyler (Drew Barrymore) and Scott (Lukas Haas). Skyler is about to be married to a likable chap named Holden (Edward Norton). However, her mother Steffi, a wealthy liberal, cultivates people as "projects." Her latest project is ex-con Charles (Tim Roth), an extremely rude and crude customer. At family gatherings, everyone politely ignores his lapses in manners and good taste until Skyler postpones her wedding to have an affair with him. In a parallel storyline, we see that DJ is convinced that her unmarried dad would find a perfect mate in Von (Julia Roberts), and she contrives an elaborate (and successful) scheme to bring them together. Overall,this is one of the best musicals made in the 90's although it does not compared to those done in the past especially when it tries to emulate typical of '30s musicals.But nevertheless,it still passes as one of the best film features made since the performances of the actors are great.Also,the love story involved is told with sincerity and honesty.Aside from that,it also presented great songs such as songs such as "Just You, Just Me" and "My Baby Just Cares for Me,".In summary,this is a "can't miss" Woody Allen film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssgv
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a beautiful movie about family ,love and forgiveness. This musical proved to me once again that Woody Allen is one of the best directors alive. Before I watched this film I never thought about Julia Roberts as a good actress but she proved me wrong her performance had entertained me. Edward Norton and Drew Barrymore relationship was the most entertaining to me ,Edward Norton was funny ,my favorite character in this film is Tim Roth's character he was great. Truly entertaining musical. my rating 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love - something to make a song and dance about.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone Says I Love You is, not to beat about the bush, Woody Allen's musical. And a delightful confection it is too. Revolving around the life and loves of one family unit, the movie hasn't really got anything to say but presents itself with such style, warmth and wit that you can't help but enjoy it anyway. The cast, as is usual for a Woody Allen movie, is superb. Natasha Lyonne is the sassy teenage girl narrating the events while Goldie Hawn, Alan Alda and Woody Allen himself portray the parental figures. Drew Barrymore and Ed Norton are the young, courting couple who have their world disturbed by a crooked Tim Roth. Then we have Lukas Haas, Natalie Portman and Gaby Hoffmann playing the other teen-aged siblings. Oh, and I almost forgot to mention Julia Roberts as a woman plagued with problems who may end up being the one woman who stays with Woody Allen's character. Or she may not. There are plenty of enjoyable lines in the script, as per usual, but this is mainly about getting from one song to the next and the musical numbers are enjoyable enough. The big plus for this movie, though, is how Allen beautifully mixes the unreal with the real and this is demonstrated perfectly in a song and dance moment he has with Goldie Hawn near the end of the movie. In fact, when it gets to that scene you really get behind the movie and realise that it's been playing around all this time to get to that place where magic can seep into the mundanity of the real world. It's a beautiful and moving sequence that ranks up there with the very best work that Allen has ever put on film. For that one scene alone, I recommend that people check this film out. Don't worry though, there's plenty more to enjoy en route with superb turns from all of the actors involved, some nice moments that remind you of the gloriously bedazzling musicals of old and numerous little touches that should bring a smile to your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, this time, I said it (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not a fan of Woody. Among 325 movies i watched so far, only one comes from him and it was terribly dull. Beyond, i don't like the buzz heard each year about his new movie because he seems to be a industrial brand. However, Stephen King who faces the same critic has a good answer : if they can release so much, it's because they work the same. Nevertheless, i couldn't stand also that his movies star the most talked actress of the moment. But there, he has himself the perfect answer: he paid them. Finally, I picked up this movie because Natalie plays in it, and i must say this was an excellent moment. The movie is split between three romantic cities (New York, Paris and Venise) and the choice for a daily diary is always interesting. Woody is really funny here as an anguished but sweet father (i was one day compared to him for that). His romance with Julia is depicted with truth. Natalie and her big family are attaching. As the movie is a musical, I suppose i have to speak my opinion about it. For me, the songs and dance suck because they are not classic tunes (at last for me)and they just stop the story. However, the ballet at the Seine banks is poetic. In conclusion, if this wealthy family is faraway of most people life, they form a united one and they bring us an happy moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Professionally amateur
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pyrocitor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As an incredible affinity with nostalgic populism has been a recurring theme throughout his expansive career, the melding of a 1930s inspired musical and Woody Allen does not seem to be as unorthodox an idea as one might expect. However, in typical form, Allen proves far more interested in pursuing his own whimsical train of thought and interest than pursuing a topic along conventional expectations, opting for a 'musical' more reflexive about the role of the musical as a genre than concentrating on itself as a new entry into the genre. The result, Everyone Says I Love You, subsequently proves to be one of Allen's most silly, experimental, self-indulgent, and yet delightfully enjoyable films. While initial inspection would find criticism in the lacklustre singing and dancing efforts of his primary cast, it becomes clear over time than Allen's film attempts to harness the inspirational impact of the musical and the role it plays within the lives of the general public, particularly as a tool for inner expression. Through intentionally casting 'non-singers' (rumour has it than Allen neglected to inform any of the cast the film was a musical until after they were cast), the film achieves a naturalistic feel, as if providing real people with the sudden opportunity for cathartic song and dance in a way excluded from 'real life', thus exposing them and their inner workings as characters. And it is this methodology that brings the film to life, providing a unique spin on an otherwise familiar Allen narrative of a web of quirky yet credible individuals weaving in and out of each other's lives and relationships, suggesting the fluidity of romance and human nature. However, as always, Allen is less interested in ascribing judgement on his characters as simply observing them in action (although there is an amusingly tongue-in-cheek subplot satirizing the film's young republican character which unwinds in a hilariously contentious fashion). Everyone Says I Love You ends up exploring the inevitability of the contradictions and lapses in judgement of human nature, leaving each new weave of the plot largely bereft of directorial moral guiding and all the more human because of it. Though the title may suggest a comment on the devaluing of emotional excesses regarding love, Allen's film never trivializes or languishes on love, but merely presents it as a universal human concern, his fluffy approach belying a more credibly sweet interior (the film's ending riverside dance sequence stands out as one of the more quiet, poignant and beautiful climaxes in recent cinema). That said, the film at heart remains more of an experimental exploration than firmly quality film, as Allen's script lacks the zing and wit of many of his more assured works, lagging somewhat midway through, and the entire film has a highly cobbled together, incohesive and somewhat amateurish feel (whether or not this fits with Allen's intent at naturalism remains up for debate). In addition, Allen sometimes gets a little too silly for his own good (a song and dance number with ghosts in a funeral home is really pushing it), though he never quite gets carried away enough to lose track of his intent or film as a singular entity. Regardless of what they may lack in vocal credentials, the film's cast certainly excels in terms of performance. Drew Barrymore masters the sweetness, innocence yet unpredictability of a somewhat na&iuml;ve young woman in love, and Edward Norton is a scream as her thoroughly wholesome yet vaguely self-centred fianc&eacute; (their prospective engagement scene in a restaurant, with Norton essaying his best neurotic Allen impression in the midst of growing chaos, is likely the film's most hilarious moment). Allen himself finds an entirely appropriate role for himself without taking over the narrative, toning down his eccentricities for the role of a man attempting to reconstruct his entire life in the image of his prospective lover's ideals, and is fully convincing and lovably pathetic in the process. As said romantic interest, Julia Roberts is left with little material to work with, but channels a fitting sense of grounded yearning nonetheless. Alan Alda is hilarious as the central family's sweetly outspoken patriarch, threatening to steal the show on multiple occasions, Goldie Hawn is somewhat underused yet both witty and touching as his wife (and Allen's ex-wife). Tim Roth steals the show with a far too brief part as an unbalanced, recently released convict, and a young Natalie Portman excels at credibly conveying teenage yearning for love without lapsing into clich&eacute;. While an undeniably whimsical entry into the Allen canon, Everyone Says I Love You remains a thought-provoking and thoroughly charming (albeit somewhat clumsy) film easily worth experiencing for those beguiled by musicals as much as musical lovers. -7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did I miss this Woody Allen movie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gottlieb.cindy@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! An all star cast singing and dancing in between the dialog. It has the usual Woody Allen premise of love lost angst on Woody's part. The plot twists and turns with love as its theme. The little nuances that are classic Woody Allen in the background, like the teenagers drinking hard liquor that no one is noticing, the stereo-typing of ethnic peoples, playing stick hockey in the fancy foyer, to name a few that have you looking for the absurd as if a game within the movie watching. Everyone is looking for ideal love except maybe not Alan Alda who has already found his in Goldie Hawn. The actual singing by the actors was not so good but that's what made the movie so perfect. The musical numbers and dancing were so campy it was excellent and entertaining. At times like watching the June Taylor Dancers including the over head camera shots. BRILLIANT! The Groucho Marx routine and party to follow was the best! A Great movie and should be up there with the top 10 Best Movies of all Times.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable musical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now I did like the old school style direction when it came to this musical. And the musical numbers is good and even cute in some cases. But despite how it tries to go in that sweet and meaningful direction of it all, it just didn't work all together. This has multiple different subplots going but it just wasn't all that effective. Even if it does kinda tie together in the end for the most part. With Woody Allen's character story as the primary. Although I didn't really watch this for Woody Allen but for Edward Norton, who is almost impossible to dislike. This just wasn't all that absorbing despite it trying to be sweet and charming, I just didn't fall for it. The plot is about characters trying to find there path, which revolves around love, sex, fantasies, politics, enjoying life, Christian and atheist views. It even tries to be witty and edgy but wasn't feeling it. Like I said it does tie together in the end but not all that well. Fans of Woody Allen might like this film, it does have a lot of his trademarks in this. Woody Allen put a lot of ideas into this movie, but everything just seemed so rushed and poorly developed. It seem to lack heart and goes more towards opinionated life views, which isn't even all that deep. Edward Norton is always cool though. And the musical number and choreography is good but also forgettable. This movie is about a hour and a half long but felt longer. It's disappointing since this has a good cast. 3.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    god when is it over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rob0352002
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed Norton, Barrymore, Roberts, Hawn, Alda, Portman... what's not to love? Well the boring, plodding, banal and mind numbingly worked story line that is as intricate as a cereal box. How can anyone like this? Did they get awards because of the cast? This proves to me that pretentious nits make a good market for an inane movie a college student could have composed. It reminds me of those self-indulgent "I am melancholy pay attention to my deep thoughts" of the 70s genre, which is how old you have to be to find this mildly entertaining. Woody Allen should just give it up. Then again, people will pretend he has talent because they are suppose to. Kind of like people paid a zillion dollars a ticket to see washed up Streisand in concert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm through with love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There came a point when the trademark opening to Woody Allen movies - plain white text on black backgrounds accompanied by a jazz song - went from classy and charming to twee and self conscious. That point really seemed to hit home around his lacklustre 90s period, largely due to the indifferent quality of most of the product. If your jazz opening is ironic juxtaposition to a genuinely funny film, or a more museful one, then it works. If it presages a mediocre offering with Larry David then it can look a little self congratulatory and pretentious. That feeling extends throughout the whole of Everyone Says I Love You, a film that doesn't seem to know what it wants to be... a genuine musical homage or pastiche. If seeing hospital patients or the ghosts of the dead dancing to show tunes is your thing, then it's ideal. But this kind of humour would work more in the full-on hands of a Mel Brooks, not a nebbish pseudo intellectual. And I say that as a fan of Woody. One thing that surprises is how almost everyone can hold a reasonable note in the cast, even Woody himself, with Hawn and Norton reputedly told to sing worse to make it more realistic. And technically there's no faulting the skill behind this piece, Allen's first picture in over ten years to be shot outside New York. But there's a twee, self-amused feel throughout, something made even worse by the character Allen plays in the film. I'm a huge Woody Allen fan, but I would never claim he has a great number of strings to his acting bow. Here he plays Woody Allen - this time called "Joe Berlin" - as a man who psychologically manipulates Julia Roberts into bed with him. Using spied knowledge of her intimate psychological secrets, Allen says and does the right thing at all time to procure a physical relationship... sorry, but isn't that practically rape? This unsettling subtext to the movie unbalances it still further, a dispiriting turn of events in a film that never seems to know quite what it wants to be. It's nice to see Woody trying something new thirty years into his movie career, but Everyone Says I Love You really needs to be filed under "inessential Allen".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody says they love this movie -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaaber-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - but I'm here to complain. I find the film embarrassing. Its slipshod dramaturgy (not foreign to Allen) makes "Meet Me in St. Louis" look like Shakespeare. The voice-over babbles on and on so as to make you think that Woody Allen ought to have written a novel instead. The film as such seems like a sorry excuse for the musical numbers which are few and far between. And then, as often with Allen, I feel like having to listen to a guy who goes on and on about his affairs with beautiful women and what a great lover he is. This time he's taking Julia Roberts and Goldie Hawn hostages. I wish I could believe that it's all tongue-in-cheek, but I can't. I give it two stars for the music only.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Still A "Can't Miss" Woody Allen Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen produced,wrote and directed an All-Star cast musical comedy set in modern day New York,Venice and Paris in this film,Everyone Says I Love You.The ensemble cast includes Alan Alda,Drew Barrymore,Lukas Haas,Goldie Hawn,Gaby Hoffmann,Natasha Lyonne,Edward Norton,Natalie Portman,Julia Roberts,Tim Roth,David Ogden Stiers and Woody Allen himself. The story centered on a polite and comfortably well-off group of people and their romantic difficulties.DJ (Natasha Lyonne), who narrates the picture, is the daughter of divorced couple Steffi (Goldie Hawn) and Joe (Woody Allen). Since the break-up, Steffi has married Bob (Alan Alda); their children, DJ's half-sister and half-brother, are Skyler (Drew Barrymore) and Scott (Lukas Haas). Skyler is about to be married to a likable chap named Holden (Edward Norton). However, her mother Steffi, a wealthy liberal, cultivates people as "projects." Her latest project is ex-con Charles (Tim Roth), an extremely rude and crude customer. At family gatherings, everyone politely ignores his lapses in manners and good taste until Skyler postpones her wedding to have an affair with him. In a parallel storyline, we see that DJ is convinced that her unmarried dad would find a perfect mate in Von (Julia Roberts), and she contrives an elaborate (and successful) scheme to bring them together. Overall,this is one of the best musicals made in the 90's although it does not compared to those done in the past especially when it tries to emulate typical of '30s musicals.But nevertheless,it still passes as one of the best film features made since the performances of the actors are great.Also,the love story involved is told with sincerity and honesty.Aside from that,it also presented great songs such as songs such as "Just You, Just Me" and "My Baby Just Cares for Me,".In summary,this is a "can't miss" Woody Allen film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssgv
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a beautiful movie about family ,love and forgiveness. This musical proved to me once again that Woody Allen is one of the best directors alive. Before I watched this film I never thought about Julia Roberts as a good actress but she proved me wrong her performance had entertained me. Edward Norton and Drew Barrymore relationship was the most entertaining to me ,Edward Norton was funny ,my favorite character in this film is Tim Roth's character he was great. Truly entertaining musical. my rating 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love - something to make a song and dance about.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone Says I Love You is, not to beat about the bush, Woody Allen's musical. And a delightful confection it is too. Revolving around the life and loves of one family unit, the movie hasn't really got anything to say but presents itself with such style, warmth and wit that you can't help but enjoy it anyway. The cast, as is usual for a Woody Allen movie, is superb. Natasha Lyonne is the sassy teenage girl narrating the events while Goldie Hawn, Alan Alda and Woody Allen himself portray the parental figures. Drew Barrymore and Ed Norton are the young, courting couple who have their world disturbed by a crooked Tim Roth. Then we have Lukas Haas, Natalie Portman and Gaby Hoffmann playing the other teen-aged siblings. Oh, and I almost forgot to mention Julia Roberts as a woman plagued with problems who may end up being the one woman who stays with Woody Allen's character. Or she may not. There are plenty of enjoyable lines in the script, as per usual, but this is mainly about getting from one song to the next and the musical numbers are enjoyable enough. The big plus for this movie, though, is how Allen beautifully mixes the unreal with the real and this is demonstrated perfectly in a song and dance moment he has with Goldie Hawn near the end of the movie. In fact, when it gets to that scene you really get behind the movie and realise that it's been playing around all this time to get to that place where magic can seep into the mundanity of the real world. It's a beautiful and moving sequence that ranks up there with the very best work that Allen has ever put on film. For that one scene alone, I recommend that people check this film out. Don't worry though, there's plenty more to enjoy en route with superb turns from all of the actors involved, some nice moments that remind you of the gloriously bedazzling musicals of old and numerous little touches that should bring a smile to your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, this time, I said it (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not a fan of Woody. Among 325 movies i watched so far, only one comes from him and it was terribly dull. Beyond, i don't like the buzz heard each year about his new movie because he seems to be a industrial brand. However, Stephen King who faces the same critic has a good answer : if they can release so much, it's because they work the same. Nevertheless, i couldn't stand also that his movies star the most talked actress of the moment. But there, he has himself the perfect answer: he paid them. Finally, I picked up this movie because Natalie plays in it, and i must say this was an excellent moment. The movie is split between three romantic cities (New York, Paris and Venise) and the choice for a daily diary is always interesting. Woody is really funny here as an anguished but sweet father (i was one day compared to him for that). His romance with Julia is depicted with truth. Natalie and her big family are attaching. As the movie is a musical, I suppose i have to speak my opinion about it. For me, the songs and dance suck because they are not classic tunes (at last for me)and they just stop the story. However, the ballet at the Seine banks is poetic. In conclusion, if this wealthy family is faraway of most people life, they form a united one and they bring us an happy moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Professionally amateur
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pyrocitor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As an incredible affinity with nostalgic populism has been a recurring theme throughout his expansive career, the melding of a 1930s inspired musical and Woody Allen does not seem to be as unorthodox an idea as one might expect. However, in typical form, Allen proves far more interested in pursuing his own whimsical train of thought and interest than pursuing a topic along conventional expectations, opting for a 'musical' more reflexive about the role of the musical as a genre than concentrating on itself as a new entry into the genre. The result, Everyone Says I Love You, subsequently proves to be one of Allen's most silly, experimental, self-indulgent, and yet delightfully enjoyable films. While initial inspection would find criticism in the lacklustre singing and dancing efforts of his primary cast, it becomes clear over time than Allen's film attempts to harness the inspirational impact of the musical and the role it plays within the lives of the general public, particularly as a tool for inner expression. Through intentionally casting 'non-singers' (rumour has it than Allen neglected to inform any of the cast the film was a musical until after they were cast), the film achieves a naturalistic feel, as if providing real people with the sudden opportunity for cathartic song and dance in a way excluded from 'real life', thus exposing them and their inner workings as characters. And it is this methodology that brings the film to life, providing a unique spin on an otherwise familiar Allen narrative of a web of quirky yet credible individuals weaving in and out of each other's lives and relationships, suggesting the fluidity of romance and human nature. However, as always, Allen is less interested in ascribing judgement on his characters as simply observing them in action (although there is an amusingly tongue-in-cheek subplot satirizing the film's young republican character which unwinds in a hilariously contentious fashion). Everyone Says I Love You ends up exploring the inevitability of the contradictions and lapses in judgement of human nature, leaving each new weave of the plot largely bereft of directorial moral guiding and all the more human because of it. Though the title may suggest a comment on the devaluing of emotional excesses regarding love, Allen's film never trivializes or languishes on love, but merely presents it as a universal human concern, his fluffy approach belying a more credibly sweet interior (the film's ending riverside dance sequence stands out as one of the more quiet, poignant and beautiful climaxes in recent cinema). That said, the film at heart remains more of an experimental exploration than firmly quality film, as Allen's script lacks the zing and wit of many of his more assured works, lagging somewhat midway through, and the entire film has a highly cobbled together, incohesive and somewhat amateurish feel (whether or not this fits with Allen's intent at naturalism remains up for debate). In addition, Allen sometimes gets a little too silly for his own good (a song and dance number with ghosts in a funeral home is really pushing it), though he never quite gets carried away enough to lose track of his intent or film as a singular entity. Regardless of what they may lack in vocal credentials, the film's cast certainly excels in terms of performance. Drew Barrymore masters the sweetness, innocence yet unpredictability of a somewhat na&iuml;ve young woman in love, and Edward Norton is a scream as her thoroughly wholesome yet vaguely self-centred fianc&eacute; (their prospective engagement scene in a restaurant, with Norton essaying his best neurotic Allen impression in the midst of growing chaos, is likely the film's most hilarious moment). Allen himself finds an entirely appropriate role for himself without taking over the narrative, toning down his eccentricities for the role of a man attempting to reconstruct his entire life in the image of his prospective lover's ideals, and is fully convincing and lovably pathetic in the process. As said romantic interest, Julia Roberts is left with little material to work with, but channels a fitting sense of grounded yearning nonetheless. Alan Alda is hilarious as the central family's sweetly outspoken patriarch, threatening to steal the show on multiple occasions, Goldie Hawn is somewhat underused yet both witty and touching as his wife (and Allen's ex-wife). Tim Roth steals the show with a far too brief part as an unbalanced, recently released convict, and a young Natalie Portman excels at credibly conveying teenage yearning for love without lapsing into clich&eacute;. While an undeniably whimsical entry into the Allen canon, Everyone Says I Love You remains a thought-provoking and thoroughly charming (albeit somewhat clumsy) film easily worth experiencing for those beguiled by musicals as much as musical lovers. -7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did I miss this Woody Allen movie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gottlieb.cindy@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! An all star cast singing and dancing in between the dialog. It has the usual Woody Allen premise of love lost angst on Woody's part. The plot twists and turns with love as its theme. The little nuances that are classic Woody Allen in the background, like the teenagers drinking hard liquor that no one is noticing, the stereo-typing of ethnic peoples, playing stick hockey in the fancy foyer, to name a few that have you looking for the absurd as if a game within the movie watching. Everyone is looking for ideal love except maybe not Alan Alda who has already found his in Goldie Hawn. The actual singing by the actors was not so good but that's what made the movie so perfect. The musical numbers and dancing were so campy it was excellent and entertaining. At times like watching the June Taylor Dancers including the over head camera shots. BRILLIANT! The Groucho Marx routine and party to follow was the best! A Great movie and should be up there with the top 10 Best Movies of all Times.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable musical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now I did like the old school style direction when it came to this musical. And the musical numbers is good and even cute in some cases. But despite how it tries to go in that sweet and meaningful direction of it all, it just didn't work all together. This has multiple different subplots going but it just wasn't all that effective. Even if it does kinda tie together in the end for the most part. With Woody Allen's character story as the primary. Although I didn't really watch this for Woody Allen but for Edward Norton, who is almost impossible to dislike. This just wasn't all that absorbing despite it trying to be sweet and charming, I just didn't fall for it. The plot is about characters trying to find there path, which revolves around love, sex, fantasies, politics, enjoying life, Christian and atheist views. It even tries to be witty and edgy but wasn't feeling it. Like I said it does tie together in the end but not all that well. Fans of Woody Allen might like this film, it does have a lot of his trademarks in this. Woody Allen put a lot of ideas into this movie, but everything just seemed so rushed and poorly developed. It seem to lack heart and goes more towards opinionated life views, which isn't even all that deep. Edward Norton is always cool though. And the musical number and choreography is good but also forgettable. This movie is about a hour and a half long but felt longer. It's disappointing since this has a good cast. 3.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    god when is it over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rob0352002
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed Norton, Barrymore, Roberts, Hawn, Alda, Portman... what's not to love? Well the boring, plodding, banal and mind numbingly worked story line that is as intricate as a cereal box. How can anyone like this? Did they get awards because of the cast? This proves to me that pretentious nits make a good market for an inane movie a college student could have composed. It reminds me of those self-indulgent "I am melancholy pay attention to my deep thoughts" of the 70s genre, which is how old you have to be to find this mildly entertaining. Woody Allen should just give it up. Then again, people will pretend he has talent because they are suppose to. Kind of like people paid a zillion dollars a ticket to see washed up Streisand in concert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm through with love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There came a point when the trademark opening to Woody Allen movies - plain white text on black backgrounds accompanied by a jazz song - went from classy and charming to twee and self conscious. That point really seemed to hit home around his lacklustre 90s period, largely due to the indifferent quality of most of the product. If your jazz opening is ironic juxtaposition to a genuinely funny film, or a more museful one, then it works. If it presages a mediocre offering with Larry David then it can look a little self congratulatory and pretentious. That feeling extends throughout the whole of Everyone Says I Love You, a film that doesn't seem to know what it wants to be... a genuine musical homage or pastiche. If seeing hospital patients or the ghosts of the dead dancing to show tunes is your thing, then it's ideal. But this kind of humour would work more in the full-on hands of a Mel Brooks, not a nebbish pseudo intellectual. And I say that as a fan of Woody. One thing that surprises is how almost everyone can hold a reasonable note in the cast, even Woody himself, with Hawn and Norton reputedly told to sing worse to make it more realistic. And technically there's no faulting the skill behind this piece, Allen's first picture in over ten years to be shot outside New York. But there's a twee, self-amused feel throughout, something made even worse by the character Allen plays in the film. I'm a huge Woody Allen fan, but I would never claim he has a great number of strings to his acting bow. Here he plays Woody Allen - this time called "Joe Berlin" - as a man who psychologically manipulates Julia Roberts into bed with him. Using spied knowledge of her intimate psychological secrets, Allen says and does the right thing at all time to procure a physical relationship... sorry, but isn't that practically rape? This unsettling subtext to the movie unbalances it still further, a dispiriting turn of events in a film that never seems to know quite what it wants to be. It's nice to see Woody trying something new thirty years into his movie career, but Everyone Says I Love You really needs to be filed under "inessential Allen".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody says they love this movie -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaaber-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - but I'm here to complain. I find the film embarrassing. Its slipshod dramaturgy (not foreign to Allen) makes "Meet Me in St. Louis" look like Shakespeare. The voice-over babbles on and on so as to make you think that Woody Allen ought to have written a novel instead. The film as such seems like a sorry excuse for the musical numbers which are few and far between. And then, as often with Allen, I feel like having to listen to a guy who goes on and on about his affairs with beautiful women and what a great lover he is. This time he's taking Julia Roberts and Goldie Hawn hostages. I wish I could believe that it's all tongue-in-cheek, but I can't. I give it two stars for the music only.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Still A "Can't Miss" Woody Allen Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen produced,wrote and directed an All-Star cast musical comedy set in modern day New York,Venice and Paris in this film,Everyone Says I Love You.The ensemble cast includes Alan Alda,Drew Barrymore,Lukas Haas,Goldie Hawn,Gaby Hoffmann,Natasha Lyonne,Edward Norton,Natalie Portman,Julia Roberts,Tim Roth,David Ogden Stiers and Woody Allen himself. The story centered on a polite and comfortably well-off group of people and their romantic difficulties.DJ (Natasha Lyonne), who narrates the picture, is the daughter of divorced couple Steffi (Goldie Hawn) and Joe (Woody Allen). Since the break-up, Steffi has married Bob (Alan Alda); their children, DJ's half-sister and half-brother, are Skyler (Drew Barrymore) and Scott (Lukas Haas). Skyler is about to be married to a likable chap named Holden (Edward Norton). However, her mother Steffi, a wealthy liberal, cultivates people as "projects." Her latest project is ex-con Charles (Tim Roth), an extremely rude and crude customer. At family gatherings, everyone politely ignores his lapses in manners and good taste until Skyler postpones her wedding to have an affair with him. In a parallel storyline, we see that DJ is convinced that her unmarried dad would find a perfect mate in Von (Julia Roberts), and she contrives an elaborate (and successful) scheme to bring them together. Overall,this is one of the best musicals made in the 90's although it does not compared to those done in the past especially when it tries to emulate typical of '30s musicals.But nevertheless,it still passes as one of the best film features made since the performances of the actors are great.Also,the love story involved is told with sincerity and honesty.Aside from that,it also presented great songs such as songs such as "Just You, Just Me" and "My Baby Just Cares for Me,".In summary,this is a "can't miss" Woody Allen film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssgv
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a beautiful movie about family ,love and forgiveness. This musical proved to me once again that Woody Allen is one of the best directors alive. Before I watched this film I never thought about Julia Roberts as a good actress but she proved me wrong her performance had entertained me. Edward Norton and Drew Barrymore relationship was the most entertaining to me ,Edward Norton was funny ,my favorite character in this film is Tim Roth's character he was great. Truly entertaining musical. my rating 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love - something to make a song and dance about.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone Says I Love You is, not to beat about the bush, Woody Allen's musical. And a delightful confection it is too. Revolving around the life and loves of one family unit, the movie hasn't really got anything to say but presents itself with such style, warmth and wit that you can't help but enjoy it anyway. The cast, as is usual for a Woody Allen movie, is superb. Natasha Lyonne is the sassy teenage girl narrating the events while Goldie Hawn, Alan Alda and Woody Allen himself portray the parental figures. Drew Barrymore and Ed Norton are the young, courting couple who have their world disturbed by a crooked Tim Roth. Then we have Lukas Haas, Natalie Portman and Gaby Hoffmann playing the other teen-aged siblings. Oh, and I almost forgot to mention Julia Roberts as a woman plagued with problems who may end up being the one woman who stays with Woody Allen's character. Or she may not. There are plenty of enjoyable lines in the script, as per usual, but this is mainly about getting from one song to the next and the musical numbers are enjoyable enough. The big plus for this movie, though, is how Allen beautifully mixes the unreal with the real and this is demonstrated perfectly in a song and dance moment he has with Goldie Hawn near the end of the movie. In fact, when it gets to that scene you really get behind the movie and realise that it's been playing around all this time to get to that place where magic can seep into the mundanity of the real world. It's a beautiful and moving sequence that ranks up there with the very best work that Allen has ever put on film. For that one scene alone, I recommend that people check this film out. Don't worry though, there's plenty more to enjoy en route with superb turns from all of the actors involved, some nice moments that remind you of the gloriously bedazzling musicals of old and numerous little touches that should bring a smile to your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, this time, I said it (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not a fan of Woody. Among 325 movies i watched so far, only one comes from him and it was terribly dull. Beyond, i don't like the buzz heard each year about his new movie because he seems to be a industrial brand. However, Stephen King who faces the same critic has a good answer : if they can release so much, it's because they work the same. Nevertheless, i couldn't stand also that his movies star the most talked actress of the moment. But there, he has himself the perfect answer: he paid them. Finally, I picked up this movie because Natalie plays in it, and i must say this was an excellent moment. The movie is split between three romantic cities (New York, Paris and Venise) and the choice for a daily diary is always interesting. Woody is really funny here as an anguished but sweet father (i was one day compared to him for that). His romance with Julia is depicted with truth. Natalie and her big family are attaching. As the movie is a musical, I suppose i have to speak my opinion about it. For me, the songs and dance suck because they are not classic tunes (at last for me)and they just stop the story. However, the ballet at the Seine banks is poetic. In conclusion, if this wealthy family is faraway of most people life, they form a united one and they bring us an happy moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Professionally amateur
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pyrocitor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As an incredible affinity with nostalgic populism has been a recurring theme throughout his expansive career, the melding of a 1930s inspired musical and Woody Allen does not seem to be as unorthodox an idea as one might expect. However, in typical form, Allen proves far more interested in pursuing his own whimsical train of thought and interest than pursuing a topic along conventional expectations, opting for a 'musical' more reflexive about the role of the musical as a genre than concentrating on itself as a new entry into the genre. The result, Everyone Says I Love You, subsequently proves to be one of Allen's most silly, experimental, self-indulgent, and yet delightfully enjoyable films. While initial inspection would find criticism in the lacklustre singing and dancing efforts of his primary cast, it becomes clear over time than Allen's film attempts to harness the inspirational impact of the musical and the role it plays within the lives of the general public, particularly as a tool for inner expression. Through intentionally casting 'non-singers' (rumour has it than Allen neglected to inform any of the cast the film was a musical until after they were cast), the film achieves a naturalistic feel, as if providing real people with the sudden opportunity for cathartic song and dance in a way excluded from 'real life', thus exposing them and their inner workings as characters. And it is this methodology that brings the film to life, providing a unique spin on an otherwise familiar Allen narrative of a web of quirky yet credible individuals weaving in and out of each other's lives and relationships, suggesting the fluidity of romance and human nature. However, as always, Allen is less interested in ascribing judgement on his characters as simply observing them in action (although there is an amusingly tongue-in-cheek subplot satirizing the film's young republican character which unwinds in a hilariously contentious fashion). Everyone Says I Love You ends up exploring the inevitability of the contradictions and lapses in judgement of human nature, leaving each new weave of the plot largely bereft of directorial moral guiding and all the more human because of it. Though the title may suggest a comment on the devaluing of emotional excesses regarding love, Allen's film never trivializes or languishes on love, but merely presents it as a universal human concern, his fluffy approach belying a more credibly sweet interior (the film's ending riverside dance sequence stands out as one of the more quiet, poignant and beautiful climaxes in recent cinema). That said, the film at heart remains more of an experimental exploration than firmly quality film, as Allen's script lacks the zing and wit of many of his more assured works, lagging somewhat midway through, and the entire film has a highly cobbled together, incohesive and somewhat amateurish feel (whether or not this fits with Allen's intent at naturalism remains up for debate). In addition, Allen sometimes gets a little too silly for his own good (a song and dance number with ghosts in a funeral home is really pushing it), though he never quite gets carried away enough to lose track of his intent or film as a singular entity. Regardless of what they may lack in vocal credentials, the film's cast certainly excels in terms of performance. Drew Barrymore masters the sweetness, innocence yet unpredictability of a somewhat na&iuml;ve young woman in love, and Edward Norton is a scream as her thoroughly wholesome yet vaguely self-centred fianc&eacute; (their prospective engagement scene in a restaurant, with Norton essaying his best neurotic Allen impression in the midst of growing chaos, is likely the film's most hilarious moment). Allen himself finds an entirely appropriate role for himself without taking over the narrative, toning down his eccentricities for the role of a man attempting to reconstruct his entire life in the image of his prospective lover's ideals, and is fully convincing and lovably pathetic in the process. As said romantic interest, Julia Roberts is left with little material to work with, but channels a fitting sense of grounded yearning nonetheless. Alan Alda is hilarious as the central family's sweetly outspoken patriarch, threatening to steal the show on multiple occasions, Goldie Hawn is somewhat underused yet both witty and touching as his wife (and Allen's ex-wife). Tim Roth steals the show with a far too brief part as an unbalanced, recently released convict, and a young Natalie Portman excels at credibly conveying teenage yearning for love without lapsing into clich&eacute;. While an undeniably whimsical entry into the Allen canon, Everyone Says I Love You remains a thought-provoking and thoroughly charming (albeit somewhat clumsy) film easily worth experiencing for those beguiled by musicals as much as musical lovers. -7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did I miss this Woody Allen movie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gottlieb.cindy@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! An all star cast singing and dancing in between the dialog. It has the usual Woody Allen premise of love lost angst on Woody's part. The plot twists and turns with love as its theme. The little nuances that are classic Woody Allen in the background, like the teenagers drinking hard liquor that no one is noticing, the stereo-typing of ethnic peoples, playing stick hockey in the fancy foyer, to name a few that have you looking for the absurd as if a game within the movie watching. Everyone is looking for ideal love except maybe not Alan Alda who has already found his in Goldie Hawn. The actual singing by the actors was not so good but that's what made the movie so perfect. The musical numbers and dancing were so campy it was excellent and entertaining. At times like watching the June Taylor Dancers including the over head camera shots. BRILLIANT! The Groucho Marx routine and party to follow was the best! A Great movie and should be up there with the top 10 Best Movies of all Times.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable musical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now I did like the old school style direction when it came to this musical. And the musical numbers is good and even cute in some cases. But despite how it tries to go in that sweet and meaningful direction of it all, it just didn't work all together. This has multiple different subplots going but it just wasn't all that effective. Even if it does kinda tie together in the end for the most part. With Woody Allen's character story as the primary. Although I didn't really watch this for Woody Allen but for Edward Norton, who is almost impossible to dislike. This just wasn't all that absorbing despite it trying to be sweet and charming, I just didn't fall for it. The plot is about characters trying to find there path, which revolves around love, sex, fantasies, politics, enjoying life, Christian and atheist views. It even tries to be witty and edgy but wasn't feeling it. Like I said it does tie together in the end but not all that well. Fans of Woody Allen might like this film, it does have a lot of his trademarks in this. Woody Allen put a lot of ideas into this movie, but everything just seemed so rushed and poorly developed. It seem to lack heart and goes more towards opinionated life views, which isn't even all that deep. Edward Norton is always cool though. And the musical number and choreography is good but also forgettable. This movie is about a hour and a half long but felt longer. It's disappointing since this has a good cast. 3.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    god when is it over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rob0352002
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed Norton, Barrymore, Roberts, Hawn, Alda, Portman... what's not to love? Well the boring, plodding, banal and mind numbingly worked story line that is as intricate as a cereal box. How can anyone like this? Did they get awards because of the cast? This proves to me that pretentious nits make a good market for an inane movie a college student could have composed. It reminds me of those self-indulgent "I am melancholy pay attention to my deep thoughts" of the 70s genre, which is how old you have to be to find this mildly entertaining. Woody Allen should just give it up. Then again, people will pretend he has talent because they are suppose to. Kind of like people paid a zillion dollars a ticket to see washed up Streisand in concert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm through with love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There came a point when the trademark opening to Woody Allen movies - plain white text on black backgrounds accompanied by a jazz song - went from classy and charming to twee and self conscious. That point really seemed to hit home around his lacklustre 90s period, largely due to the indifferent quality of most of the product. If your jazz opening is ironic juxtaposition to a genuinely funny film, or a more museful one, then it works. If it presages a mediocre offering with Larry David then it can look a little self congratulatory and pretentious. That feeling extends throughout the whole of Everyone Says I Love You, a film that doesn't seem to know what it wants to be... a genuine musical homage or pastiche. If seeing hospital patients or the ghosts of the dead dancing to show tunes is your thing, then it's ideal. But this kind of humour would work more in the full-on hands of a Mel Brooks, not a nebbish pseudo intellectual. And I say that as a fan of Woody. One thing that surprises is how almost everyone can hold a reasonable note in the cast, even Woody himself, with Hawn and Norton reputedly told to sing worse to make it more realistic. And technically there's no faulting the skill behind this piece, Allen's first picture in over ten years to be shot outside New York. But there's a twee, self-amused feel throughout, something made even worse by the character Allen plays in the film. I'm a huge Woody Allen fan, but I would never claim he has a great number of strings to his acting bow. Here he plays Woody Allen - this time called "Joe Berlin" - as a man who psychologically manipulates Julia Roberts into bed with him. Using spied knowledge of her intimate psychological secrets, Allen says and does the right thing at all time to procure a physical relationship... sorry, but isn't that practically rape? This unsettling subtext to the movie unbalances it still further, a dispiriting turn of events in a film that never seems to know quite what it wants to be. It's nice to see Woody trying something new thirty years into his movie career, but Everyone Says I Love You really needs to be filed under "inessential Allen".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody says they love this movie -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaaber-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - but I'm here to complain. I find the film embarrassing. Its slipshod dramaturgy (not foreign to Allen) makes "Meet Me in St. Louis" look like Shakespeare. The voice-over babbles on and on so as to make you think that Woody Allen ought to have written a novel instead. The film as such seems like a sorry excuse for the musical numbers which are few and far between. And then, as often with Allen, I feel like having to listen to a guy who goes on and on about his affairs with beautiful women and what a great lover he is. This time he's taking Julia Roberts and Goldie Hawn hostages. I wish I could believe that it's all tongue-in-cheek, but I can't. I give it two stars for the music only.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Still A "Can't Miss" Woody Allen Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen produced,wrote and directed an All-Star cast musical comedy set in modern day New York,Venice and Paris in this film,Everyone Says I Love You.The ensemble cast includes Alan Alda,Drew Barrymore,Lukas Haas,Goldie Hawn,Gaby Hoffmann,Natasha Lyonne,Edward Norton,Natalie Portman,Julia Roberts,Tim Roth,David Ogden Stiers and Woody Allen himself. The story centered on a polite and comfortably well-off group of people and their romantic difficulties.DJ (Natasha Lyonne), who narrates the picture, is the daughter of divorced couple Steffi (Goldie Hawn) and Joe (Woody Allen). Since the break-up, Steffi has married Bob (Alan Alda); their children, DJ's half-sister and half-brother, are Skyler (Drew Barrymore) and Scott (Lukas Haas). Skyler is about to be married to a likable chap named Holden (Edward Norton). However, her mother Steffi, a wealthy liberal, cultivates people as "projects." Her latest project is ex-con Charles (Tim Roth), an extremely rude and crude customer. At family gatherings, everyone politely ignores his lapses in manners and good taste until Skyler postpones her wedding to have an affair with him. In a parallel storyline, we see that DJ is convinced that her unmarried dad would find a perfect mate in Von (Julia Roberts), and she contrives an elaborate (and successful) scheme to bring them together. Overall,this is one of the best musicals made in the 90's although it does not compared to those done in the past especially when it tries to emulate typical of '30s musicals.But nevertheless,it still passes as one of the best film features made since the performances of the actors are great.Also,the love story involved is told with sincerity and honesty.Aside from that,it also presented great songs such as songs such as "Just You, Just Me" and "My Baby Just Cares for Me,".In summary,this is a "can't miss" Woody Allen film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssgv
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a beautiful movie about family ,love and forgiveness. This musical proved to me once again that Woody Allen is one of the best directors alive. Before I watched this film I never thought about Julia Roberts as a good actress but she proved me wrong her performance had entertained me. Edward Norton and Drew Barrymore relationship was the most entertaining to me ,Edward Norton was funny ,my favorite character in this film is Tim Roth's character he was great. Truly entertaining musical. my rating 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love - something to make a song and dance about.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone Says I Love You is, not to beat about the bush, Woody Allen's musical. And a delightful confection it is too. Revolving around the life and loves of one family unit, the movie hasn't really got anything to say but presents itself with such style, warmth and wit that you can't help but enjoy it anyway. The cast, as is usual for a Woody Allen movie, is superb. Natasha Lyonne is the sassy teenage girl narrating the events while Goldie Hawn, Alan Alda and Woody Allen himself portray the parental figures. Drew Barrymore and Ed Norton are the young, courting couple who have their world disturbed by a crooked Tim Roth. Then we have Lukas Haas, Natalie Portman and Gaby Hoffmann playing the other teen-aged siblings. Oh, and I almost forgot to mention Julia Roberts as a woman plagued with problems who may end up being the one woman who stays with Woody Allen's character. Or she may not. There are plenty of enjoyable lines in the script, as per usual, but this is mainly about getting from one song to the next and the musical numbers are enjoyable enough. The big plus for this movie, though, is how Allen beautifully mixes the unreal with the real and this is demonstrated perfectly in a song and dance moment he has with Goldie Hawn near the end of the movie. In fact, when it gets to that scene you really get behind the movie and realise that it's been playing around all this time to get to that place where magic can seep into the mundanity of the real world. It's a beautiful and moving sequence that ranks up there with the very best work that Allen has ever put on film. For that one scene alone, I recommend that people check this film out. Don't worry though, there's plenty more to enjoy en route with superb turns from all of the actors involved, some nice moments that remind you of the gloriously bedazzling musicals of old and numerous little touches that should bring a smile to your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, this time, I said it (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not a fan of Woody. Among 325 movies i watched so far, only one comes from him and it was terribly dull. Beyond, i don't like the buzz heard each year about his new movie because he seems to be a industrial brand. However, Stephen King who faces the same critic has a good answer : if they can release so much, it's because they work the same. Nevertheless, i couldn't stand also that his movies star the most talked actress of the moment. But there, he has himself the perfect answer: he paid them. Finally, I picked up this movie because Natalie plays in it, and i must say this was an excellent moment. The movie is split between three romantic cities (New York, Paris and Venise) and the choice for a daily diary is always interesting. Woody is really funny here as an anguished but sweet father (i was one day compared to him for that). His romance with Julia is depicted with truth. Natalie and her big family are attaching. As the movie is a musical, I suppose i have to speak my opinion about it. For me, the songs and dance suck because they are not classic tunes (at last for me)and they just stop the story. However, the ballet at the Seine banks is poetic. In conclusion, if this wealthy family is faraway of most people life, they form a united one and they bring us an happy moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Professionally amateur
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pyrocitor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As an incredible affinity with nostalgic populism has been a recurring theme throughout his expansive career, the melding of a 1930s inspired musical and Woody Allen does not seem to be as unorthodox an idea as one might expect. However, in typical form, Allen proves far more interested in pursuing his own whimsical train of thought and interest than pursuing a topic along conventional expectations, opting for a 'musical' more reflexive about the role of the musical as a genre than concentrating on itself as a new entry into the genre. The result, Everyone Says I Love You, subsequently proves to be one of Allen's most silly, experimental, self-indulgent, and yet delightfully enjoyable films. While initial inspection would find criticism in the lacklustre singing and dancing efforts of his primary cast, it becomes clear over time than Allen's film attempts to harness the inspirational impact of the musical and the role it plays within the lives of the general public, particularly as a tool for inner expression. Through intentionally casting 'non-singers' (rumour has it than Allen neglected to inform any of the cast the film was a musical until after they were cast), the film achieves a naturalistic feel, as if providing real people with the sudden opportunity for cathartic song and dance in a way excluded from 'real life', thus exposing them and their inner workings as characters. And it is this methodology that brings the film to life, providing a unique spin on an otherwise familiar Allen narrative of a web of quirky yet credible individuals weaving in and out of each other's lives and relationships, suggesting the fluidity of romance and human nature. However, as always, Allen is less interested in ascribing judgement on his characters as simply observing them in action (although there is an amusingly tongue-in-cheek subplot satirizing the film's young republican character which unwinds in a hilariously contentious fashion). Everyone Says I Love You ends up exploring the inevitability of the contradictions and lapses in judgement of human nature, leaving each new weave of the plot largely bereft of directorial moral guiding and all the more human because of it. Though the title may suggest a comment on the devaluing of emotional excesses regarding love, Allen's film never trivializes or languishes on love, but merely presents it as a universal human concern, his fluffy approach belying a more credibly sweet interior (the film's ending riverside dance sequence stands out as one of the more quiet, poignant and beautiful climaxes in recent cinema). That said, the film at heart remains more of an experimental exploration than firmly quality film, as Allen's script lacks the zing and wit of many of his more assured works, lagging somewhat midway through, and the entire film has a highly cobbled together, incohesive and somewhat amateurish feel (whether or not this fits with Allen's intent at naturalism remains up for debate). In addition, Allen sometimes gets a little too silly for his own good (a song and dance number with ghosts in a funeral home is really pushing it), though he never quite gets carried away enough to lose track of his intent or film as a singular entity. Regardless of what they may lack in vocal credentials, the film's cast certainly excels in terms of performance. Drew Barrymore masters the sweetness, innocence yet unpredictability of a somewhat na&iuml;ve young woman in love, and Edward Norton is a scream as her thoroughly wholesome yet vaguely self-centred fianc&eacute; (their prospective engagement scene in a restaurant, with Norton essaying his best neurotic Allen impression in the midst of growing chaos, is likely the film's most hilarious moment). Allen himself finds an entirely appropriate role for himself without taking over the narrative, toning down his eccentricities for the role of a man attempting to reconstruct his entire life in the image of his prospective lover's ideals, and is fully convincing and lovably pathetic in the process. As said romantic interest, Julia Roberts is left with little material to work with, but channels a fitting sense of grounded yearning nonetheless. Alan Alda is hilarious as the central family's sweetly outspoken patriarch, threatening to steal the show on multiple occasions, Goldie Hawn is somewhat underused yet both witty and touching as his wife (and Allen's ex-wife). Tim Roth steals the show with a far too brief part as an unbalanced, recently released convict, and a young Natalie Portman excels at credibly conveying teenage yearning for love without lapsing into clich&eacute;. While an undeniably whimsical entry into the Allen canon, Everyone Says I Love You remains a thought-provoking and thoroughly charming (albeit somewhat clumsy) film easily worth experiencing for those beguiled by musicals as much as musical lovers. -7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did I miss this Woody Allen movie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gottlieb.cindy@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! An all star cast singing and dancing in between the dialog. It has the usual Woody Allen premise of love lost angst on Woody's part. The plot twists and turns with love as its theme. The little nuances that are classic Woody Allen in the background, like the teenagers drinking hard liquor that no one is noticing, the stereo-typing of ethnic peoples, playing stick hockey in the fancy foyer, to name a few that have you looking for the absurd as if a game within the movie watching. Everyone is looking for ideal love except maybe not Alan Alda who has already found his in Goldie Hawn. The actual singing by the actors was not so good but that's what made the movie so perfect. The musical numbers and dancing were so campy it was excellent and entertaining. At times like watching the June Taylor Dancers including the over head camera shots. BRILLIANT! The Groucho Marx routine and party to follow was the best! A Great movie and should be up there with the top 10 Best Movies of all Times.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable musical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now I did like the old school style direction when it came to this musical. And the musical numbers is good and even cute in some cases. But despite how it tries to go in that sweet and meaningful direction of it all, it just didn't work all together. This has multiple different subplots going but it just wasn't all that effective. Even if it does kinda tie together in the end for the most part. With Woody Allen's character story as the primary. Although I didn't really watch this for Woody Allen but for Edward Norton, who is almost impossible to dislike. This just wasn't all that absorbing despite it trying to be sweet and charming, I just didn't fall for it. The plot is about characters trying to find there path, which revolves around love, sex, fantasies, politics, enjoying life, Christian and atheist views. It even tries to be witty and edgy but wasn't feeling it. Like I said it does tie together in the end but not all that well. Fans of Woody Allen might like this film, it does have a lot of his trademarks in this. Woody Allen put a lot of ideas into this movie, but everything just seemed so rushed and poorly developed. It seem to lack heart and goes more towards opinionated life views, which isn't even all that deep. Edward Norton is always cool though. And the musical number and choreography is good but also forgettable. This movie is about a hour and a half long but felt longer. It's disappointing since this has a good cast. 3.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    god when is it over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rob0352002
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed Norton, Barrymore, Roberts, Hawn, Alda, Portman... what's not to love? Well the boring, plodding, banal and mind numbingly worked story line that is as intricate as a cereal box. How can anyone like this? Did they get awards because of the cast? This proves to me that pretentious nits make a good market for an inane movie a college student could have composed. It reminds me of those self-indulgent "I am melancholy pay attention to my deep thoughts" of the 70s genre, which is how old you have to be to find this mildly entertaining. Woody Allen should just give it up. Then again, people will pretend he has talent because they are suppose to. Kind of like people paid a zillion dollars a ticket to see washed up Streisand in concert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm through with love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There came a point when the trademark opening to Woody Allen movies - plain white text on black backgrounds accompanied by a jazz song - went from classy and charming to twee and self conscious. That point really seemed to hit home around his lacklustre 90s period, largely due to the indifferent quality of most of the product. If your jazz opening is ironic juxtaposition to a genuinely funny film, or a more museful one, then it works. If it presages a mediocre offering with Larry David then it can look a little self congratulatory and pretentious. That feeling extends throughout the whole of Everyone Says I Love You, a film that doesn't seem to know what it wants to be... a genuine musical homage or pastiche. If seeing hospital patients or the ghosts of the dead dancing to show tunes is your thing, then it's ideal. But this kind of humour would work more in the full-on hands of a Mel Brooks, not a nebbish pseudo intellectual. And I say that as a fan of Woody. One thing that surprises is how almost everyone can hold a reasonable note in the cast, even Woody himself, with Hawn and Norton reputedly told to sing worse to make it more realistic. And technically there's no faulting the skill behind this piece, Allen's first picture in over ten years to be shot outside New York. But there's a twee, self-amused feel throughout, something made even worse by the character Allen plays in the film. I'm a huge Woody Allen fan, but I would never claim he has a great number of strings to his acting bow. Here he plays Woody Allen - this time called "Joe Berlin" - as a man who psychologically manipulates Julia Roberts into bed with him. Using spied knowledge of her intimate psychological secrets, Allen says and does the right thing at all time to procure a physical relationship... sorry, but isn't that practically rape? This unsettling subtext to the movie unbalances it still further, a dispiriting turn of events in a film that never seems to know quite what it wants to be. It's nice to see Woody trying something new thirty years into his movie career, but Everyone Says I Love You really needs to be filed under "inessential Allen".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody says they love this movie -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaaber-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - but I'm here to complain. I find the film embarrassing. Its slipshod dramaturgy (not foreign to Allen) makes "Meet Me in St. Louis" look like Shakespeare. The voice-over babbles on and on so as to make you think that Woody Allen ought to have written a novel instead. The film as such seems like a sorry excuse for the musical numbers which are few and far between. And then, as often with Allen, I feel like having to listen to a guy who goes on and on about his affairs with beautiful women and what a great lover he is. This time he's taking Julia Roberts and Goldie Hawn hostages. I wish I could believe that it's all tongue-in-cheek, but I can't. I give it two stars for the music only.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Still A "Can't Miss" Woody Allen Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen produced,wrote and directed an All-Star cast musical comedy set in modern day New York,Venice and Paris in this film,Everyone Says I Love You.The ensemble cast includes Alan Alda,Drew Barrymore,Lukas Haas,Goldie Hawn,Gaby Hoffmann,Natasha Lyonne,Edward Norton,Natalie Portman,Julia Roberts,Tim Roth,David Ogden Stiers and Woody Allen himself. The story centered on a polite and comfortably well-off group of people and their romantic difficulties.DJ (Natasha Lyonne), who narrates the picture, is the daughter of divorced couple Steffi (Goldie Hawn) and Joe (Woody Allen). Since the break-up, Steffi has married Bob (Alan Alda); their children, DJ's half-sister and half-brother, are Skyler (Drew Barrymore) and Scott (Lukas Haas). Skyler is about to be married to a likable chap named Holden (Edward Norton). However, her mother Steffi, a wealthy liberal, cultivates people as "projects." Her latest project is ex-con Charles (Tim Roth), an extremely rude and crude customer. At family gatherings, everyone politely ignores his lapses in manners and good taste until Skyler postpones her wedding to have an affair with him. In a parallel storyline, we see that DJ is convinced that her unmarried dad would find a perfect mate in Von (Julia Roberts), and she contrives an elaborate (and successful) scheme to bring them together. Overall,this is one of the best musicals made in the 90's although it does not compared to those done in the past especially when it tries to emulate typical of '30s musicals.But nevertheless,it still passes as one of the best film features made since the performances of the actors are great.Also,the love story involved is told with sincerity and honesty.Aside from that,it also presented great songs such as songs such as "Just You, Just Me" and "My Baby Just Cares for Me,".In summary,this is a "can't miss" Woody Allen film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssgv
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a beautiful movie about family ,love and forgiveness. This musical proved to me once again that Woody Allen is one of the best directors alive. Before I watched this film I never thought about Julia Roberts as a good actress but she proved me wrong her performance had entertained me. Edward Norton and Drew Barrymore relationship was the most entertaining to me ,Edward Norton was funny ,my favorite character in this film is Tim Roth's character he was great. Truly entertaining musical. my rating 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love - something to make a song and dance about.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone Says I Love You is, not to beat about the bush, Woody Allen's musical. And a delightful confection it is too. Revolving around the life and loves of one family unit, the movie hasn't really got anything to say but presents itself with such style, warmth and wit that you can't help but enjoy it anyway. The cast, as is usual for a Woody Allen movie, is superb. Natasha Lyonne is the sassy teenage girl narrating the events while Goldie Hawn, Alan Alda and Woody Allen himself portray the parental figures. Drew Barrymore and Ed Norton are the young, courting couple who have their world disturbed by a crooked Tim Roth. Then we have Lukas Haas, Natalie Portman and Gaby Hoffmann playing the other teen-aged siblings. Oh, and I almost forgot to mention Julia Roberts as a woman plagued with problems who may end up being the one woman who stays with Woody Allen's character. Or she may not. There are plenty of enjoyable lines in the script, as per usual, but this is mainly about getting from one song to the next and the musical numbers are enjoyable enough. The big plus for this movie, though, is how Allen beautifully mixes the unreal with the real and this is demonstrated perfectly in a song and dance moment he has with Goldie Hawn near the end of the movie. In fact, when it gets to that scene you really get behind the movie and realise that it's been playing around all this time to get to that place where magic can seep into the mundanity of the real world. It's a beautiful and moving sequence that ranks up there with the very best work that Allen has ever put on film. For that one scene alone, I recommend that people check this film out. Don't worry though, there's plenty more to enjoy en route with superb turns from all of the actors involved, some nice moments that remind you of the gloriously bedazzling musicals of old and numerous little touches that should bring a smile to your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, this time, I said it (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not a fan of Woody. Among 325 movies i watched so far, only one comes from him and it was terribly dull. Beyond, i don't like the buzz heard each year about his new movie because he seems to be a industrial brand. However, Stephen King who faces the same critic has a good answer : if they can release so much, it's because they work the same. Nevertheless, i couldn't stand also that his movies star the most talked actress of the moment. But there, he has himself the perfect answer: he paid them. Finally, I picked up this movie because Natalie plays in it, and i must say this was an excellent moment. The movie is split between three romantic cities (New York, Paris and Venise) and the choice for a daily diary is always interesting. Woody is really funny here as an anguished but sweet father (i was one day compared to him for that). His romance with Julia is depicted with truth. Natalie and her big family are attaching. As the movie is a musical, I suppose i have to speak my opinion about it. For me, the songs and dance suck because they are not classic tunes (at last for me)and they just stop the story. However, the ballet at the Seine banks is poetic. In conclusion, if this wealthy family is faraway of most people life, they form a united one and they bring us an happy moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Professionally amateur
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pyrocitor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As an incredible affinity with nostalgic populism has been a recurring theme throughout his expansive career, the melding of a 1930s inspired musical and Woody Allen does not seem to be as unorthodox an idea as one might expect. However, in typical form, Allen proves far more interested in pursuing his own whimsical train of thought and interest than pursuing a topic along conventional expectations, opting for a 'musical' more reflexive about the role of the musical as a genre than concentrating on itself as a new entry into the genre. The result, Everyone Says I Love You, subsequently proves to be one of Allen's most silly, experimental, self-indulgent, and yet delightfully enjoyable films. While initial inspection would find criticism in the lacklustre singing and dancing efforts of his primary cast, it becomes clear over time than Allen's film attempts to harness the inspirational impact of the musical and the role it plays within the lives of the general public, particularly as a tool for inner expression. Through intentionally casting 'non-singers' (rumour has it than Allen neglected to inform any of the cast the film was a musical until after they were cast), the film achieves a naturalistic feel, as if providing real people with the sudden opportunity for cathartic song and dance in a way excluded from 'real life', thus exposing them and their inner workings as characters. And it is this methodology that brings the film to life, providing a unique spin on an otherwise familiar Allen narrative of a web of quirky yet credible individuals weaving in and out of each other's lives and relationships, suggesting the fluidity of romance and human nature. However, as always, Allen is less interested in ascribing judgement on his characters as simply observing them in action (although there is an amusingly tongue-in-cheek subplot satirizing the film's young republican character which unwinds in a hilariously contentious fashion). Everyone Says I Love You ends up exploring the inevitability of the contradictions and lapses in judgement of human nature, leaving each new weave of the plot largely bereft of directorial moral guiding and all the more human because of it. Though the title may suggest a comment on the devaluing of emotional excesses regarding love, Allen's film never trivializes or languishes on love, but merely presents it as a universal human concern, his fluffy approach belying a more credibly sweet interior (the film's ending riverside dance sequence stands out as one of the more quiet, poignant and beautiful climaxes in recent cinema). That said, the film at heart remains more of an experimental exploration than firmly quality film, as Allen's script lacks the zing and wit of many of his more assured works, lagging somewhat midway through, and the entire film has a highly cobbled together, incohesive and somewhat amateurish feel (whether or not this fits with Allen's intent at naturalism remains up for debate). In addition, Allen sometimes gets a little too silly for his own good (a song and dance number with ghosts in a funeral home is really pushing it), though he never quite gets carried away enough to lose track of his intent or film as a singular entity. Regardless of what they may lack in vocal credentials, the film's cast certainly excels in terms of performance. Drew Barrymore masters the sweetness, innocence yet unpredictability of a somewhat na&iuml;ve young woman in love, and Edward Norton is a scream as her thoroughly wholesome yet vaguely self-centred fianc&eacute; (their prospective engagement scene in a restaurant, with Norton essaying his best neurotic Allen impression in the midst of growing chaos, is likely the film's most hilarious moment). Allen himself finds an entirely appropriate role for himself without taking over the narrative, toning down his eccentricities for the role of a man attempting to reconstruct his entire life in the image of his prospective lover's ideals, and is fully convincing and lovably pathetic in the process. As said romantic interest, Julia Roberts is left with little material to work with, but channels a fitting sense of grounded yearning nonetheless. Alan Alda is hilarious as the central family's sweetly outspoken patriarch, threatening to steal the show on multiple occasions, Goldie Hawn is somewhat underused yet both witty and touching as his wife (and Allen's ex-wife). Tim Roth steals the show with a far too brief part as an unbalanced, recently released convict, and a young Natalie Portman excels at credibly conveying teenage yearning for love without lapsing into clich&eacute;. While an undeniably whimsical entry into the Allen canon, Everyone Says I Love You remains a thought-provoking and thoroughly charming (albeit somewhat clumsy) film easily worth experiencing for those beguiled by musicals as much as musical lovers. -7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How did I miss this Woody Allen movie?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gottlieb.cindy@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! An all star cast singing and dancing in between the dialog. It has the usual Woody Allen premise of love lost angst on Woody's part. The plot twists and turns with love as its theme. The little nuances that are classic Woody Allen in the background, like the teenagers drinking hard liquor that no one is noticing, the stereo-typing of ethnic peoples, playing stick hockey in the fancy foyer, to name a few that have you looking for the absurd as if a game within the movie watching. Everyone is looking for ideal love except maybe not Alan Alda who has already found his in Goldie Hawn. The actual singing by the actors was not so good but that's what made the movie so perfect. The musical numbers and dancing were so campy it was excellent and entertaining. At times like watching the June Taylor Dancers including the over head camera shots. BRILLIANT! The Groucho Marx routine and party to follow was the best! A Great movie and should be up there with the top 10 Best Movies of all Times.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forgettable musical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now I did like the old school style direction when it came to this musical. And the musical numbers is good and even cute in some cases. But despite how it tries to go in that sweet and meaningful direction of it all, it just didn't work all together. This has multiple different subplots going but it just wasn't all that effective. Even if it does kinda tie together in the end for the most part. With Woody Allen's character story as the primary. Although I didn't really watch this for Woody Allen but for Edward Norton, who is almost impossible to dislike. This just wasn't all that absorbing despite it trying to be sweet and charming, I just didn't fall for it. The plot is about characters trying to find there path, which revolves around love, sex, fantasies, politics, enjoying life, Christian and atheist views. It even tries to be witty and edgy but wasn't feeling it. Like I said it does tie together in the end but not all that well. Fans of Woody Allen might like this film, it does have a lot of his trademarks in this. Woody Allen put a lot of ideas into this movie, but everything just seemed so rushed and poorly developed. It seem to lack heart and goes more towards opinionated life views, which isn't even all that deep. Edward Norton is always cool though. And the musical number and choreography is good but also forgettable. This movie is about a hour and a half long but felt longer. It's disappointing since this has a good cast. 3.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    god when is it over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rob0352002
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ed Norton, Barrymore, Roberts, Hawn, Alda, Portman... what's not to love? Well the boring, plodding, banal and mind numbingly worked story line that is as intricate as a cereal box. How can anyone like this? Did they get awards because of the cast? This proves to me that pretentious nits make a good market for an inane movie a college student could have composed. It reminds me of those self-indulgent "I am melancholy pay attention to my deep thoughts" of the 70s genre, which is how old you have to be to find this mildly entertaining. Woody Allen should just give it up. Then again, people will pretend he has talent because they are suppose to. Kind of like people paid a zillion dollars a ticket to see washed up Streisand in concert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm through with love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There came a point when the trademark opening to Woody Allen movies - plain white text on black backgrounds accompanied by a jazz song - went from classy and charming to twee and self conscious. That point really seemed to hit home around his lacklustre 90s period, largely due to the indifferent quality of most of the product. If your jazz opening is ironic juxtaposition to a genuinely funny film, or a more museful one, then it works. If it presages a mediocre offering with Larry David then it can look a little self congratulatory and pretentious. That feeling extends throughout the whole of Everyone Says I Love You, a film that doesn't seem to know what it wants to be... a genuine musical homage or pastiche. If seeing hospital patients or the ghosts of the dead dancing to show tunes is your thing, then it's ideal. But this kind of humour would work more in the full-on hands of a Mel Brooks, not a nebbish pseudo intellectual. And I say that as a fan of Woody. One thing that surprises is how almost everyone can hold a reasonable note in the cast, even Woody himself, with Hawn and Norton reputedly told to sing worse to make it more realistic. And technically there's no faulting the skill behind this piece, Allen's first picture in over ten years to be shot outside New York. But there's a twee, self-amused feel throughout, something made even worse by the character Allen plays in the film. I'm a huge Woody Allen fan, but I would never claim he has a great number of strings to his acting bow. Here he plays Woody Allen - this time called "Joe Berlin" - as a man who psychologically manipulates Julia Roberts into bed with him. Using spied knowledge of her intimate psychological secrets, Allen says and does the right thing at all time to procure a physical relationship... sorry, but isn't that practically rape? This unsettling subtext to the movie unbalances it still further, a dispiriting turn of events in a film that never seems to know quite what it wants to be. It's nice to see Woody trying something new thirty years into his movie career, but Everyone Says I Love You really needs to be filed under "inessential Allen".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody says they love this movie -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kaaber-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - but I'm here to complain. I find the film embarrassing. Its slipshod dramaturgy (not foreign to Allen) makes "Meet Me in St. Louis" look like Shakespeare. The voice-over babbles on and on so as to make you think that Woody Allen ought to have written a novel instead. The film as such seems like a sorry excuse for the musical numbers which are few and far between. And then, as often with Allen, I feel like having to listen to a guy who goes on and on about his affairs with beautiful women and what a great lover he is. This time he's taking Julia Roberts and Goldie Hawn hostages. I wish I could believe that it's all tongue-in-cheek, but I can't. I give it two stars for the music only.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Still A "Can't Miss" Woody Allen Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen produced,wrote and directed an All-Star cast musical comedy set in modern day New York,Venice and Paris in this film,Everyone Says I Love You.The ensemble cast includes Alan Alda,Drew Barrymore,Lukas Haas,Goldie Hawn,Gaby Hoffmann,Natasha Lyonne,Edward Norton,Natalie Portman,Julia Roberts,Tim Roth,David Ogden Stiers and Woody Allen himself. The story centered on a polite and comfortably well-off group of people and their romantic difficulties.DJ (Natasha Lyonne), who narrates the picture, is the daughter of divorced couple Steffi (Goldie Hawn) and Joe (Woody Allen). Since the break-up, Steffi has married Bob (Alan Alda); their children, DJ's half-sister and half-brother, are Skyler (Drew Barrymore) and Scott (Lukas Haas). Skyler is about to be married to a likable chap named Holden (Edward Norton). However, her mother Steffi, a wealthy liberal, cultivates people as "projects." Her latest project is ex-con Charles (Tim Roth), an extremely rude and crude customer. At family gatherings, everyone politely ignores his lapses in manners and good taste until Skyler postpones her wedding to have an affair with him. In a parallel storyline, we see that DJ is convinced that her unmarried dad would find a perfect mate in Von (Julia Roberts), and she contrives an elaborate (and successful) scheme to bring them together. Overall,this is one of the best musicals made in the 90's although it does not compared to those done in the past especially when it tries to emulate typical of '30s musicals.But nevertheless,it still passes as one of the best film features made since the performances of the actors are great.Also,the love story involved is told with sincerity and honesty.Aside from that,it also presented great songs such as songs such as "Just You, Just Me" and "My Baby Just Cares for Me,".In summary,this is a "can't miss" Woody Allen film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssgv
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a beautiful movie about family ,love and forgiveness. This musical proved to me once again that Woody Allen is one of the best directors alive. Before I watched this film I never thought about Julia Roberts as a good actress but she proved me wrong her performance had entertained me. Edward Norton and Drew Barrymore relationship was the most entertaining to me ,Edward Norton was funny ,my favorite character in this film is Tim Roth's character he was great. Truly entertaining musical. my rating 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love - something to make a song and dance about.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone Says I Love You is, not to beat about the bush, Woody Allen's musical. And a delightful confection it is too. Revolving around the life and loves of one family unit, the movie hasn't really got anything to say but presents itself with such style, warmth and wit that you can't help but enjoy it anyway. The cast, as is usual for a Woody Allen movie, is superb. Natasha Lyonne is the sassy teenage girl narrating the events while Goldie Hawn, Alan Alda and Woody Allen himself portray the parental figures. Drew Barrymore and Ed Norton are the young, courting couple who have their world disturbed by a crooked Tim Roth. Then we have Lukas Haas, Natalie Portman and Gaby Hoffmann playing the other teen-aged siblings. Oh, and I almost forgot to mention Julia Roberts as a woman plagued with problems who may end up being the one woman who stays with Woody Allen's character. Or she may not. There are plenty of enjoyable lines in the script, as per usual, but this is mainly about getting from one song to the next and the musical numbers are enjoyable enough. The big plus for this movie, though, is how Allen beautifully mixes the unreal with the real and this is demonstrated perfectly in a song and dance moment he has with Goldie Hawn near the end of the movie. In fact, when it gets to that scene you really get behind the movie and realise that it's been playing around all this time to get to that place where magic can seep into the mundanity of the real world. It's a beautiful and moving sequence that ranks up there with the very best work that Allen has ever put on film. For that one scene alone, I recommend that people check this film out. Don't worry though, there's plenty more to enjoy en route with superb turns from all of the actors involved, some nice moments that remind you of the gloriously bedazzling musicals of old and numerous little touches that should bring a smile to your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, this time, I said it (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not a fan of Woody. Among 325 movies i watched so far, only one comes from him and it was terribly dull. Beyond, i don't like the buzz heard each year about his new movie because he seems to be a industrial brand. However, Stephen King who faces the same critic has a good answer : if they can release so much, it's because they work the same. Nevertheless, i couldn't stand also that his movies star the most talked actress of the moment. But there, he has himself the perfect answer: he paid them. Finally, I picked up this movie because Natalie plays in it, and i must say this was an excellent moment. The movie is split between three romantic cities (New York, Paris and Venise) and the choice for a daily diary is always interesting. Woody is really funny here as an anguished but sweet father (i was one day compared to him for that). His romance with Julia is depicted with truth. Natalie and her big family are attaching. As the movie is a musical, I suppose i have to speak my opinion about it. For me, the songs and dance suck because they are not classic tunes (at last for me)and they just stop the story. However, the ballet at the Seine banks is poetic. In conclusion, if this wealthy family is faraway of most people life, they form a united one and they bring us an happy moment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Professionally amateur
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pyrocitor
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As an incredible affinity with nostalgic populism has been a recurring theme throughout his expansive career, the melding of a 1930s inspired musical and Woody Allen does not seem to be as unorthodox an idea as one might expect. However, in typical form, Allen proves far more interested in pursuing his own whimsical train of thought and interest than pursuing a topic along conventional expectations, opting for a 'musical' more reflexive about the role of the musical as a genre than concentrating on itself as a new entry into the genre. The result, Everyone Says I Love You, subsequently proves to be one of Allen's most silly, experimental, self-indulgent, and yet delightfully enjoyable films. While initial inspection would find criticism in the lacklustre singing and dancing efforts of his primary cast, it becomes clear over time than Allen's film attempts to harness the inspirational impact of the musical and the role it plays within the lives of the general public, particularly as a tool for inner expression. Through intentionally casting 'non-singers' (rumour has it than Allen neglected to inform any of the cast the film was a musical until after they were cast), the film achieves a naturalistic feel, as if providing real people with the sudden opportunity for cathartic song and dance in a way excluded from 'real life', thus exposing them and their inner workings as characters. And it is this methodology that brings the film to life, providing a unique spin on an otherwise familiar Allen narrative of a web of quirky yet credible individuals weaving in and out of each other's lives and relationships, suggesting the fluidity of romance and human nature. However, as always, Allen is less interested in ascribing judgement on his characters as simply observing them in action (although there is an amusingly tongue-in-cheek subplot satirizing the film's young republican character which unwinds in a hilariously contentious fashion). Everyone Says I Love You ends up exploring the inevitability of the contradictions and lapses in judgement of human nature, leaving each new weave of the plot largely bereft of directorial moral guiding and all the more human because of it. Though the title may suggest a comment on the devaluing of emotional excesses regarding love, Allen's film never trivializes or languishes on love, but merely presents it as a universal human concern, his fluffy approach belying a more credibly sweet interior (the film's ending riverside dance sequence stands out as one of the more quiet, poignant and beautiful climaxes in recent cinema). That said, the film at heart remains more of an experimental exploration than firmly quality film, as Allen's script lacks the zing and wit of many of his more assured works, lagging somewhat midway through, and the entire film has a highly cobbled together, incohesive and somewhat amateurish feel (whether or not this fits with Allen's intent at naturalism remains up for debate). In addition, Allen sometimes gets a little too silly for his own good (a song and dance number with ghosts in a funeral home is really pushing it), though he never quite gets carried away enough to lose track of his intent or film as a singular entity. Regardless of what they may lack in vocal credentials, the film's cast certainly excels in terms of performance. Drew Barrymore masters the sweetness, innocence yet unpredictability of a somewhat na&iuml;ve young woman in love, and Edward Norton is a scream as her thoroughly wholesome yet vaguely self-centred fianc&eacute; (their prospective engagement scene in a restaurant, with Norton essaying his best neurotic Allen impression in the midst of growing chaos, is likely the film's most hilarious moment). Allen himself finds an entirely appropriate role for himself without taking over the narrative, toning down his eccentricities for the role of a man attempting to reconstruct his entire life in the image of his prospective lover's ideals, and is fully convincing and lovably pathetic in the process. As said romantic interest, Julia Roberts is left with little material to work with, but channels a fitting sense of grounded yearning nonetheless. Alan Alda is hilarious as the central family's sweetly outspoken patriarch, threatening to steal the show on multiple occasions, Goldie Hawn is somewhat underused yet both witty and touching as his wife (and Allen's ex-wife). Tim Roth steals the show with a far too brief part as an unbalanced, recently released convict, and a young Natalie Portman excels at credibly conveying teenage yearning for love without lapsing into clich&eacute;. While an undeniably whimsical entry into the Allen canon, Everyone Says I Love You remains a thought-provoking and thoroughly charming (albeit somewhat clumsy) film easily worth experiencing for those beguiled by musicals as much as musical lovers. -7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
