<filme>
 <id>
  32
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109508
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Crumb
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An intimate portrait of the controversial cartoonist and his traumatized family.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  This movie chronicles the life and times of R. Crumb. Robert Crumb is the cartoonist/artist who drew Keep On Truckin', Fritz the Cat, and played a major pioneering role in the genesis of underground comix. Through interviews with his mother, two brothers, wife, and ex-girlfriends, as well as selections from his vast quantity of graphic art, we are treated to a darkly comic ride through one man's subconscious mind. As stream-of-consciousness images incessantly flow forth from the tip of his pen, biting social satire is revealed, often along with a disturbing and haunting vision of Crumb's own betes noires and inadequacies. As his acid-trip induced images flicker across our own retinas, we gain a little insight into this complex and highly creative individual.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Documentary
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   satire
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   comic book
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   robert crumb
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   underground
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   art
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Terry Zwigoff
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Superior Pictures
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Robert Crumb
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Aline Kominsky
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Charles Crumb
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know for some time what this film listed in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die was about, so I was very interested when I found out it was a documentary about a famous comic book cartoonist who I had heard about. Robert Crumb is the cartoonist and artist who drew and created popular comics and images such as Fritz the Cat, Mr. Natural and Keep on Truckin', he was the major pioneer for the genesis and popularisation of underground comics. This documentary details his life from developing his talent for drawing and making his own comic books with his two brothers, and of course becoming famous, but we also get an insight into the darker and strange regions of his subconscious mind. Interviews come from Crumb himself, his mother, his two brothers Charles and Maxon who are perhaps more strange than Robert, his then wife Aline Kominsky who knows her husband is unusual and his ex- girlfriends, as well as other artists, art critics and historians, and some admirers. The work of Crumb started from childhood with his love for Disney and various cartoon characters, where he and his brothers would create their own adventure comic books, and growing up he developed his bizarre style which included satire and sexual and perverted imagery. It is interesting to hear his various stories about his creations, his relationships with his brothers, his parents and the women he was with, it is interesting to see how disturbed his brothers are (one committed suicide after the film), and it is interesting to see his works discussed, including the mentioning of killing off Fritz the Cat following the cartoon film which he did not approve. This has many elements to it, it is fascinating, it is artistic, it is strange and it is disturbing, Crumb is obviously a genius with his cartoon style and imagination, but his eccentric personality and family background is the most interesting thing to watch this for, a most worthwhile documentary film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In my top 5 films, ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zee
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always hated R. Crumb's comics, finding them misogynistic and racist and weird and unfunny. In my factory-town hippie youth, the boys who found them funny were boys I avoided. (I never met a girl or black person who did like them, though a few may exist.) So you'd think I might hate this movie, or not want to watch it, or that this review would be negative. But no. I love a good documentary and this is not merely good; it's a great one, directed by film genius Terry Zwigoff. Crumb the movie riveted me, showing me an intricate portrait of a complex man. This is not a short movie, but I was always engaged--great pacing and editing, surprising and revealing choices of scenes. To me what it says about "art" (or craft) is far less important than what it says about this one man. Crumb had a childhood that looks worse than the worst horror film I've ever seen. Bad father, bat**** crazy mother, and three genius boys that I suppose may carry the crazy gene too. As Zwigoff takes us into that bizarre home and the lives of the other brothers, we come to see that R. Crumb's art and life is a triumph of the human spirit, a flower blooming out of burbling sewage. To me, it's not an attractive flower, rather a noisome and homely thing, but dang it, a flower, and I ended up applauding him for doing so well with such beginnings. No matter how crazy your family is, you leave this film thinking, wow, thanks Mom and Dad for not being anywhere near this bad. Your own tiny neuroses will seem charming and mild in comparison to the brothers'. You leave the film with the sense that all things are possible--if Crumb did this with his life despite what you now know, what the heck is holding you back? And if a film can change people, even for a short time, this one has the capacity to make you more understanding of the worst people you meet. What if they had this much baggage? How can you possibly know what made them what they are? Everyone is doing the best s/he can, and while some days that seems like bad news, after watching the film, it feels like good news.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Successful Outlier From A Doomed Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Documentary of the art and life of Robert Crumb, a legendary and controversial cartoonist. It's one of those few pieces of non-fiction cinema that truly portrays a person's mind and describes with great dedication and care the essence of the subject at hand: Crumb is seen as a gentle man with bizarre and manic tendencies, being a sexual deviant, socially awkward, and a women hater (although the latter isn't as obvious) who inevitably distances himself from the rest of the world. When his brothers and his mother are interviewed, we read through the darker, more manic pages of the film: it is clear that obsession(or mental illness, if you want) and strong artistic creativity tragically cohabit within the family. "Crumb", besides reflecting that relationship between art and society that is partly present in modern American culture, is a sort of dedication to the people that by going against it unwillingly fall into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anykind of Artist can learn from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregg Di Lorenzo (gdilorenzo1@optimum.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Primarily: You are in the presence of a master creating and displaying his art, and throughout these portions of the film any kind of artist will find much to learn from this man. The comparison made that he is the "modern" D&uuml;rer is very apt. Secondarily: You are watching one the most humorous and (blackly) entertaining films ever produced anywhere. Yes, we are reassured once again that an (the) artists' personality(ies) cannot never be confused with or substituted for the work they have give us; the strongest humor comes from the aon-old maxim the truth is stranger than fiction... p.s. One last thing - had seen this piece over a decade ago, but a recent review of Crumb's 2009 outstanding "Genesis" work led back here and there to review. If you haven't read it yet do it tonight/day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb came out of the 1960s as the leading underground comic book artist. Sexually explicit material, usually with women drawn with huge buttocks were his signature. Album covers, including Janis Joplin's Big Brother and the Holding Company being the most well known, show a real and unique artist at work. Filmmaker Terry Zwigoff brings his camera into the Crumb family home; can you say dysfunctional? ? The word is not strong enough to describe this modern day Adam's Family. Robert's brother Charles looks like Lerch and despite his agoraphobia is also a creative genius. The Crumb's interactions are a train wreck in the making that you can't take your eyes off of. The brothers are both certifiably insane and yet hugely talented. Crumb is one of the best documentary's ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good and a bit creepy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb has become an icon in the world of underground comic artists, and this documentary takes a close look at his work and the often unhappy life that informed it with an intimacy that is both gratifying and disturbing. Crumb's art and career are celebrated here on film even while his dysfunctional adolescence, his personal insecurities and his sexual obsessions are dissected by family, friends, pop psychologists and other invited crackpots. We see how, by his own understanding, that young Robert Crumb developed his talent as a vehicle to reach out and connect with other people, especially girls, and then had to deal with the frustrations resulting from his failure to achieve success with this. We see how his cartooning style evolved, how certain repeated subjects and motifs found their way into his work. We get a close up view of Robert Crumb that is almost too close up. The film's intimacy with its subject creates an almost claustrophobic feel, especially since Crumb himself is almost painfully awkward and lacking in personal charm, his mother is an ogress, his wife and daughter seem wary and stiff on camera, and his older brother is borderline crazy. Especially interesting is Robert Crumb's brother Charles, who is also a cartoonist and quite talented but clearly mentally unbalanced. His work shows genuine technical polish and is extremely evocative. It is also morbid and obsessive to the point of wallowing in darkness and despair, since its creator is an over-40, out of work dingbat who lives and works in the attic of the Crumb family home. Charles was a key inspiration to the young Robert Crumb, yet he is also an object lesson. With a little less professional drive and career focus, Robert could easily have followed his brother's path in life and art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    darkly fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was never a fan of R. Crumb's work, finding it unpleasant and ugly, but I heard the documentary was good and it certainly is. This is a fascinating portrayal not just of the highly eccentric Crumb but also of his even more off-kilter brothers. They are a very messed up family, so messed up that their upbringing was probably even worse than it is described in the movie. The film works in a number of ways. It does a good job of exploring Crumb's artwork, where it came from and how he approaches it (even though it's mainly about the personal we do see some of his craftsmanship as well. It shows how his comics generate extreme reactions, most notably in the opposing reactions of a pretentious English guy who talks about Crumb as a great artist and a painfully politically correct woman who says he legitimizes horrible fantasies by expressing them. But more than anything, this is a movie that reveals the Crumb's disturbing personalities and dismal lives. Perhaps the most disturbing thing about it is how casually they discuss themselves, laughing boisterously as they talk about their odd sexuality and abusive father. It's a rather downbeat documentary but well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Real Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cinematic portrait of the controversial comic book writer/artist and his traumatized family. Crumb is the perfect subject matter for Terry Zwigoff, who is best known for "Ghost World", an adaptation of a graphic novel. Zwigoff clearly has an interest in independent comics and knows how to present them in a way that makes them interesting and accessible to people. Some of "Ghost World"'s biggest fans have never read a comic book, and I suspect one need not know who Crumb is to appreciate this documentary. His brother Charles lives in a "cloistered environment" of books, which is an interesting sight... he speaks of not yet having read Kant or Hegel, but you can see nearby a copy of a Buddhist book, suggesting that such things may not be beyond his range of interests. What Charles does now is unclear. Presumably nothing. And the other brother, Maxon, is even more bizarre. The constant cynicism is a welcome perspective. He seems happy, but Crumb constantly talks disparagingly of things. His attitude is interesting, and sometimes he suggests a Luddite viewpoint. He also, despite needing money, turned down Saturday Night Live and the Rolling Stones... running from fame. A gallery owner calls him the "Daumier of our time" and the Time art critic says he is the Brueghel for the second half of the 20th century. I suppose being compared to classic art is a compliment, though the fact they are such obscure names may not be complimentary at all... I do not know Daumier or Brueghel's work, so I cannot even say if I like it! If Crumb is not weird enough, just wait until they invite him behind the scenes at a pornographic "Leg Show" photo shoot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure gold, one of the greatest films of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gloede_The_Saint
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm in complete shock. I must admit that when it started off with David Lynch presents I knew I was in for something, but I had no idea what. I cannot believe that anyone would expose their life like this. Robert Crumb is what would be described as a pretty "sick" individual, his family more so. His brothers are talking about suicide attempts, molesting women, etc. Robert Crumb is basically letting you see ever part of his life. We even see him ride around on women's backs, which is apparently one of his favorite things in the whole world. If you are not familiar with him, he is a sort of satirical, sexually obsessed cartoonist, who among other things makes cartoons about his own crazy life. And he is a likable guy. Grim and openly perverted but he does have a personality. He is the amusing outcast who shows the world for what he thinks it is. Director Terry Zwigoff does this almost like a fictional film, of course there are interviews and most of it is conversations between Robert and people who knows him, but sometimes you think of him more as a Woody Allen kind of fictional characters. I is so far from the norm, and so much a character it's hard to believe he's real. The film itself has this weird form of just being. It's a dark comedy, and though it never stops being interesting and you can feel the somewhat morbid comedic atmosphere it's just hard to categorize as a comedy. It's more. It's something true, and something to think about; Though it's pretty impossible to figure out what it is you are supposed to think about. Individuality, society, norms, standards, art, perhaps everything in existence. At it's core you just know this is something special. It's not just the Crumb family quirks and distancing life style, the complete honesty about it and the emotions this brings, it's the look at the artistic work it creates, and maybe vice versa. This film needs to be experienced!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Documentary of Underground Cartoonist and Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Warning! Spoilers ahead! This movie succeeds largely because the documentarian does not inject his bias into the story, nor does he push any sort of agenda. He lets his subjects give their side of the story. He listens to both sides of the argument, whether they approve of what Robert Crumb has done as an artist, or whether he is nothing more than a bizarre pornographer. In all, the neutrality of the movie-maker is this film's best selling point, and I highly recommend this film as one that doesn't beat you over the head with its opinion or message; it lets the subjects do the talking. On the topic of semi-famous underground cartoonist Robert Crumb and his family, the film leaves one with an uneasy feeling at best. Charles, Robert's brother, and his mother reminded me of the recent HBO "Grey Gardens" movie, which itself was based on a documentary. If Robert Crumb can be perceived by some as a stark eccentric who cannot fit in to modern society, at least he has been able to create a stable home life with a loving family of his own. This movie is utterly tragic in its portrayal of Crumb's brothers, Charles and Maxon, especially so since Charles is gifted with exceptional cartooning skills (his artwork looked superior to Robert's best efforts), yet was cursed with severe psychiatric problems which prevented him from entering society as a functional individual. While Robert is a functional member of society, the overall impression the movie gave was that he was somewhat distant from other people, including his kin, and could not pick up easily on the feelings of others. The most poignant example of this was a brief (maybe one minute?) description of his father by Crumb's son from his first wife. Still, it was delightful to see Crumb nurture his children by helping them do artwork of their own. On the surface, Crumb may seem like a unique if peculiar individual: snobbish, detached from the outside world, relishing in dressing in anachronistic clothing and listening to old jazz records. Still, the impression was of a kind-hearted individual who found release through art. I did enjoy the movie's inclusion of those who objected to Crumb's art as blatantly pornographic, though my sense is that Crumb's work does not have the mainstream popularity which would make it troubling to society at large, nor the messages in his illustrations singularly sexual, to classify it as straightforwardly pornographic. A solid effort. I highly recommend this film to those who love documentaries.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know for some time what this film listed in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die was about, so I was very interested when I found out it was a documentary about a famous comic book cartoonist who I had heard about. Robert Crumb is the cartoonist and artist who drew and created popular comics and images such as Fritz the Cat, Mr. Natural and Keep on Truckin', he was the major pioneer for the genesis and popularisation of underground comics. This documentary details his life from developing his talent for drawing and making his own comic books with his two brothers, and of course becoming famous, but we also get an insight into the darker and strange regions of his subconscious mind. Interviews come from Crumb himself, his mother, his two brothers Charles and Maxon who are perhaps more strange than Robert, his then wife Aline Kominsky who knows her husband is unusual and his ex- girlfriends, as well as other artists, art critics and historians, and some admirers. The work of Crumb started from childhood with his love for Disney and various cartoon characters, where he and his brothers would create their own adventure comic books, and growing up he developed his bizarre style which included satire and sexual and perverted imagery. It is interesting to hear his various stories about his creations, his relationships with his brothers, his parents and the women he was with, it is interesting to see how disturbed his brothers are (one committed suicide after the film), and it is interesting to see his works discussed, including the mentioning of killing off Fritz the Cat following the cartoon film which he did not approve. This has many elements to it, it is fascinating, it is artistic, it is strange and it is disturbing, Crumb is obviously a genius with his cartoon style and imagination, but his eccentric personality and family background is the most interesting thing to watch this for, a most worthwhile documentary film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In my top 5 films, ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zee
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always hated R. Crumb's comics, finding them misogynistic and racist and weird and unfunny. In my factory-town hippie youth, the boys who found them funny were boys I avoided. (I never met a girl or black person who did like them, though a few may exist.) So you'd think I might hate this movie, or not want to watch it, or that this review would be negative. But no. I love a good documentary and this is not merely good; it's a great one, directed by film genius Terry Zwigoff. Crumb the movie riveted me, showing me an intricate portrait of a complex man. This is not a short movie, but I was always engaged--great pacing and editing, surprising and revealing choices of scenes. To me what it says about "art" (or craft) is far less important than what it says about this one man. Crumb had a childhood that looks worse than the worst horror film I've ever seen. Bad father, bat**** crazy mother, and three genius boys that I suppose may carry the crazy gene too. As Zwigoff takes us into that bizarre home and the lives of the other brothers, we come to see that R. Crumb's art and life is a triumph of the human spirit, a flower blooming out of burbling sewage. To me, it's not an attractive flower, rather a noisome and homely thing, but dang it, a flower, and I ended up applauding him for doing so well with such beginnings. No matter how crazy your family is, you leave this film thinking, wow, thanks Mom and Dad for not being anywhere near this bad. Your own tiny neuroses will seem charming and mild in comparison to the brothers'. You leave the film with the sense that all things are possible--if Crumb did this with his life despite what you now know, what the heck is holding you back? And if a film can change people, even for a short time, this one has the capacity to make you more understanding of the worst people you meet. What if they had this much baggage? How can you possibly know what made them what they are? Everyone is doing the best s/he can, and while some days that seems like bad news, after watching the film, it feels like good news.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Successful Outlier From A Doomed Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Documentary of the art and life of Robert Crumb, a legendary and controversial cartoonist. It's one of those few pieces of non-fiction cinema that truly portrays a person's mind and describes with great dedication and care the essence of the subject at hand: Crumb is seen as a gentle man with bizarre and manic tendencies, being a sexual deviant, socially awkward, and a women hater (although the latter isn't as obvious) who inevitably distances himself from the rest of the world. When his brothers and his mother are interviewed, we read through the darker, more manic pages of the film: it is clear that obsession(or mental illness, if you want) and strong artistic creativity tragically cohabit within the family. "Crumb", besides reflecting that relationship between art and society that is partly present in modern American culture, is a sort of dedication to the people that by going against it unwillingly fall into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anykind of Artist can learn from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregg Di Lorenzo (gdilorenzo1@optimum.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Primarily: You are in the presence of a master creating and displaying his art, and throughout these portions of the film any kind of artist will find much to learn from this man. The comparison made that he is the "modern" D&uuml;rer is very apt. Secondarily: You are watching one the most humorous and (blackly) entertaining films ever produced anywhere. Yes, we are reassured once again that an (the) artists' personality(ies) cannot never be confused with or substituted for the work they have give us; the strongest humor comes from the aon-old maxim the truth is stranger than fiction... p.s. One last thing - had seen this piece over a decade ago, but a recent review of Crumb's 2009 outstanding "Genesis" work led back here and there to review. If you haven't read it yet do it tonight/day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb came out of the 1960s as the leading underground comic book artist. Sexually explicit material, usually with women drawn with huge buttocks were his signature. Album covers, including Janis Joplin's Big Brother and the Holding Company being the most well known, show a real and unique artist at work. Filmmaker Terry Zwigoff brings his camera into the Crumb family home; can you say dysfunctional? ? The word is not strong enough to describe this modern day Adam's Family. Robert's brother Charles looks like Lerch and despite his agoraphobia is also a creative genius. The Crumb's interactions are a train wreck in the making that you can't take your eyes off of. The brothers are both certifiably insane and yet hugely talented. Crumb is one of the best documentary's ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good and a bit creepy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb has become an icon in the world of underground comic artists, and this documentary takes a close look at his work and the often unhappy life that informed it with an intimacy that is both gratifying and disturbing. Crumb's art and career are celebrated here on film even while his dysfunctional adolescence, his personal insecurities and his sexual obsessions are dissected by family, friends, pop psychologists and other invited crackpots. We see how, by his own understanding, that young Robert Crumb developed his talent as a vehicle to reach out and connect with other people, especially girls, and then had to deal with the frustrations resulting from his failure to achieve success with this. We see how his cartooning style evolved, how certain repeated subjects and motifs found their way into his work. We get a close up view of Robert Crumb that is almost too close up. The film's intimacy with its subject creates an almost claustrophobic feel, especially since Crumb himself is almost painfully awkward and lacking in personal charm, his mother is an ogress, his wife and daughter seem wary and stiff on camera, and his older brother is borderline crazy. Especially interesting is Robert Crumb's brother Charles, who is also a cartoonist and quite talented but clearly mentally unbalanced. His work shows genuine technical polish and is extremely evocative. It is also morbid and obsessive to the point of wallowing in darkness and despair, since its creator is an over-40, out of work dingbat who lives and works in the attic of the Crumb family home. Charles was a key inspiration to the young Robert Crumb, yet he is also an object lesson. With a little less professional drive and career focus, Robert could easily have followed his brother's path in life and art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    darkly fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was never a fan of R. Crumb's work, finding it unpleasant and ugly, but I heard the documentary was good and it certainly is. This is a fascinating portrayal not just of the highly eccentric Crumb but also of his even more off-kilter brothers. They are a very messed up family, so messed up that their upbringing was probably even worse than it is described in the movie. The film works in a number of ways. It does a good job of exploring Crumb's artwork, where it came from and how he approaches it (even though it's mainly about the personal we do see some of his craftsmanship as well. It shows how his comics generate extreme reactions, most notably in the opposing reactions of a pretentious English guy who talks about Crumb as a great artist and a painfully politically correct woman who says he legitimizes horrible fantasies by expressing them. But more than anything, this is a movie that reveals the Crumb's disturbing personalities and dismal lives. Perhaps the most disturbing thing about it is how casually they discuss themselves, laughing boisterously as they talk about their odd sexuality and abusive father. It's a rather downbeat documentary but well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Real Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cinematic portrait of the controversial comic book writer/artist and his traumatized family. Crumb is the perfect subject matter for Terry Zwigoff, who is best known for "Ghost World", an adaptation of a graphic novel. Zwigoff clearly has an interest in independent comics and knows how to present them in a way that makes them interesting and accessible to people. Some of "Ghost World"'s biggest fans have never read a comic book, and I suspect one need not know who Crumb is to appreciate this documentary. His brother Charles lives in a "cloistered environment" of books, which is an interesting sight... he speaks of not yet having read Kant or Hegel, but you can see nearby a copy of a Buddhist book, suggesting that such things may not be beyond his range of interests. What Charles does now is unclear. Presumably nothing. And the other brother, Maxon, is even more bizarre. The constant cynicism is a welcome perspective. He seems happy, but Crumb constantly talks disparagingly of things. His attitude is interesting, and sometimes he suggests a Luddite viewpoint. He also, despite needing money, turned down Saturday Night Live and the Rolling Stones... running from fame. A gallery owner calls him the "Daumier of our time" and the Time art critic says he is the Brueghel for the second half of the 20th century. I suppose being compared to classic art is a compliment, though the fact they are such obscure names may not be complimentary at all... I do not know Daumier or Brueghel's work, so I cannot even say if I like it! If Crumb is not weird enough, just wait until they invite him behind the scenes at a pornographic "Leg Show" photo shoot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure gold, one of the greatest films of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gloede_The_Saint
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm in complete shock. I must admit that when it started off with David Lynch presents I knew I was in for something, but I had no idea what. I cannot believe that anyone would expose their life like this. Robert Crumb is what would be described as a pretty "sick" individual, his family more so. His brothers are talking about suicide attempts, molesting women, etc. Robert Crumb is basically letting you see ever part of his life. We even see him ride around on women's backs, which is apparently one of his favorite things in the whole world. If you are not familiar with him, he is a sort of satirical, sexually obsessed cartoonist, who among other things makes cartoons about his own crazy life. And he is a likable guy. Grim and openly perverted but he does have a personality. He is the amusing outcast who shows the world for what he thinks it is. Director Terry Zwigoff does this almost like a fictional film, of course there are interviews and most of it is conversations between Robert and people who knows him, but sometimes you think of him more as a Woody Allen kind of fictional characters. I is so far from the norm, and so much a character it's hard to believe he's real. The film itself has this weird form of just being. It's a dark comedy, and though it never stops being interesting and you can feel the somewhat morbid comedic atmosphere it's just hard to categorize as a comedy. It's more. It's something true, and something to think about; Though it's pretty impossible to figure out what it is you are supposed to think about. Individuality, society, norms, standards, art, perhaps everything in existence. At it's core you just know this is something special. It's not just the Crumb family quirks and distancing life style, the complete honesty about it and the emotions this brings, it's the look at the artistic work it creates, and maybe vice versa. This film needs to be experienced!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Documentary of Underground Cartoonist and Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Warning! Spoilers ahead! This movie succeeds largely because the documentarian does not inject his bias into the story, nor does he push any sort of agenda. He lets his subjects give their side of the story. He listens to both sides of the argument, whether they approve of what Robert Crumb has done as an artist, or whether he is nothing more than a bizarre pornographer. In all, the neutrality of the movie-maker is this film's best selling point, and I highly recommend this film as one that doesn't beat you over the head with its opinion or message; it lets the subjects do the talking. On the topic of semi-famous underground cartoonist Robert Crumb and his family, the film leaves one with an uneasy feeling at best. Charles, Robert's brother, and his mother reminded me of the recent HBO "Grey Gardens" movie, which itself was based on a documentary. If Robert Crumb can be perceived by some as a stark eccentric who cannot fit in to modern society, at least he has been able to create a stable home life with a loving family of his own. This movie is utterly tragic in its portrayal of Crumb's brothers, Charles and Maxon, especially so since Charles is gifted with exceptional cartooning skills (his artwork looked superior to Robert's best efforts), yet was cursed with severe psychiatric problems which prevented him from entering society as a functional individual. While Robert is a functional member of society, the overall impression the movie gave was that he was somewhat distant from other people, including his kin, and could not pick up easily on the feelings of others. The most poignant example of this was a brief (maybe one minute?) description of his father by Crumb's son from his first wife. Still, it was delightful to see Crumb nurture his children by helping them do artwork of their own. On the surface, Crumb may seem like a unique if peculiar individual: snobbish, detached from the outside world, relishing in dressing in anachronistic clothing and listening to old jazz records. Still, the impression was of a kind-hearted individual who found release through art. I did enjoy the movie's inclusion of those who objected to Crumb's art as blatantly pornographic, though my sense is that Crumb's work does not have the mainstream popularity which would make it troubling to society at large, nor the messages in his illustrations singularly sexual, to classify it as straightforwardly pornographic. A solid effort. I highly recommend this film to those who love documentaries.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know for some time what this film listed in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die was about, so I was very interested when I found out it was a documentary about a famous comic book cartoonist who I had heard about. Robert Crumb is the cartoonist and artist who drew and created popular comics and images such as Fritz the Cat, Mr. Natural and Keep on Truckin', he was the major pioneer for the genesis and popularisation of underground comics. This documentary details his life from developing his talent for drawing and making his own comic books with his two brothers, and of course becoming famous, but we also get an insight into the darker and strange regions of his subconscious mind. Interviews come from Crumb himself, his mother, his two brothers Charles and Maxon who are perhaps more strange than Robert, his then wife Aline Kominsky who knows her husband is unusual and his ex- girlfriends, as well as other artists, art critics and historians, and some admirers. The work of Crumb started from childhood with his love for Disney and various cartoon characters, where he and his brothers would create their own adventure comic books, and growing up he developed his bizarre style which included satire and sexual and perverted imagery. It is interesting to hear his various stories about his creations, his relationships with his brothers, his parents and the women he was with, it is interesting to see how disturbed his brothers are (one committed suicide after the film), and it is interesting to see his works discussed, including the mentioning of killing off Fritz the Cat following the cartoon film which he did not approve. This has many elements to it, it is fascinating, it is artistic, it is strange and it is disturbing, Crumb is obviously a genius with his cartoon style and imagination, but his eccentric personality and family background is the most interesting thing to watch this for, a most worthwhile documentary film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In my top 5 films, ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zee
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always hated R. Crumb's comics, finding them misogynistic and racist and weird and unfunny. In my factory-town hippie youth, the boys who found them funny were boys I avoided. (I never met a girl or black person who did like them, though a few may exist.) So you'd think I might hate this movie, or not want to watch it, or that this review would be negative. But no. I love a good documentary and this is not merely good; it's a great one, directed by film genius Terry Zwigoff. Crumb the movie riveted me, showing me an intricate portrait of a complex man. This is not a short movie, but I was always engaged--great pacing and editing, surprising and revealing choices of scenes. To me what it says about "art" (or craft) is far less important than what it says about this one man. Crumb had a childhood that looks worse than the worst horror film I've ever seen. Bad father, bat**** crazy mother, and three genius boys that I suppose may carry the crazy gene too. As Zwigoff takes us into that bizarre home and the lives of the other brothers, we come to see that R. Crumb's art and life is a triumph of the human spirit, a flower blooming out of burbling sewage. To me, it's not an attractive flower, rather a noisome and homely thing, but dang it, a flower, and I ended up applauding him for doing so well with such beginnings. No matter how crazy your family is, you leave this film thinking, wow, thanks Mom and Dad for not being anywhere near this bad. Your own tiny neuroses will seem charming and mild in comparison to the brothers'. You leave the film with the sense that all things are possible--if Crumb did this with his life despite what you now know, what the heck is holding you back? And if a film can change people, even for a short time, this one has the capacity to make you more understanding of the worst people you meet. What if they had this much baggage? How can you possibly know what made them what they are? Everyone is doing the best s/he can, and while some days that seems like bad news, after watching the film, it feels like good news.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Successful Outlier From A Doomed Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Documentary of the art and life of Robert Crumb, a legendary and controversial cartoonist. It's one of those few pieces of non-fiction cinema that truly portrays a person's mind and describes with great dedication and care the essence of the subject at hand: Crumb is seen as a gentle man with bizarre and manic tendencies, being a sexual deviant, socially awkward, and a women hater (although the latter isn't as obvious) who inevitably distances himself from the rest of the world. When his brothers and his mother are interviewed, we read through the darker, more manic pages of the film: it is clear that obsession(or mental illness, if you want) and strong artistic creativity tragically cohabit within the family. "Crumb", besides reflecting that relationship between art and society that is partly present in modern American culture, is a sort of dedication to the people that by going against it unwillingly fall into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anykind of Artist can learn from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregg Di Lorenzo (gdilorenzo1@optimum.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Primarily: You are in the presence of a master creating and displaying his art, and throughout these portions of the film any kind of artist will find much to learn from this man. The comparison made that he is the "modern" D&uuml;rer is very apt. Secondarily: You are watching one the most humorous and (blackly) entertaining films ever produced anywhere. Yes, we are reassured once again that an (the) artists' personality(ies) cannot never be confused with or substituted for the work they have give us; the strongest humor comes from the aon-old maxim the truth is stranger than fiction... p.s. One last thing - had seen this piece over a decade ago, but a recent review of Crumb's 2009 outstanding "Genesis" work led back here and there to review. If you haven't read it yet do it tonight/day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb came out of the 1960s as the leading underground comic book artist. Sexually explicit material, usually with women drawn with huge buttocks were his signature. Album covers, including Janis Joplin's Big Brother and the Holding Company being the most well known, show a real and unique artist at work. Filmmaker Terry Zwigoff brings his camera into the Crumb family home; can you say dysfunctional? ? The word is not strong enough to describe this modern day Adam's Family. Robert's brother Charles looks like Lerch and despite his agoraphobia is also a creative genius. The Crumb's interactions are a train wreck in the making that you can't take your eyes off of. The brothers are both certifiably insane and yet hugely talented. Crumb is one of the best documentary's ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good and a bit creepy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb has become an icon in the world of underground comic artists, and this documentary takes a close look at his work and the often unhappy life that informed it with an intimacy that is both gratifying and disturbing. Crumb's art and career are celebrated here on film even while his dysfunctional adolescence, his personal insecurities and his sexual obsessions are dissected by family, friends, pop psychologists and other invited crackpots. We see how, by his own understanding, that young Robert Crumb developed his talent as a vehicle to reach out and connect with other people, especially girls, and then had to deal with the frustrations resulting from his failure to achieve success with this. We see how his cartooning style evolved, how certain repeated subjects and motifs found their way into his work. We get a close up view of Robert Crumb that is almost too close up. The film's intimacy with its subject creates an almost claustrophobic feel, especially since Crumb himself is almost painfully awkward and lacking in personal charm, his mother is an ogress, his wife and daughter seem wary and stiff on camera, and his older brother is borderline crazy. Especially interesting is Robert Crumb's brother Charles, who is also a cartoonist and quite talented but clearly mentally unbalanced. His work shows genuine technical polish and is extremely evocative. It is also morbid and obsessive to the point of wallowing in darkness and despair, since its creator is an over-40, out of work dingbat who lives and works in the attic of the Crumb family home. Charles was a key inspiration to the young Robert Crumb, yet he is also an object lesson. With a little less professional drive and career focus, Robert could easily have followed his brother's path in life and art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    darkly fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was never a fan of R. Crumb's work, finding it unpleasant and ugly, but I heard the documentary was good and it certainly is. This is a fascinating portrayal not just of the highly eccentric Crumb but also of his even more off-kilter brothers. They are a very messed up family, so messed up that their upbringing was probably even worse than it is described in the movie. The film works in a number of ways. It does a good job of exploring Crumb's artwork, where it came from and how he approaches it (even though it's mainly about the personal we do see some of his craftsmanship as well. It shows how his comics generate extreme reactions, most notably in the opposing reactions of a pretentious English guy who talks about Crumb as a great artist and a painfully politically correct woman who says he legitimizes horrible fantasies by expressing them. But more than anything, this is a movie that reveals the Crumb's disturbing personalities and dismal lives. Perhaps the most disturbing thing about it is how casually they discuss themselves, laughing boisterously as they talk about their odd sexuality and abusive father. It's a rather downbeat documentary but well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Real Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cinematic portrait of the controversial comic book writer/artist and his traumatized family. Crumb is the perfect subject matter for Terry Zwigoff, who is best known for "Ghost World", an adaptation of a graphic novel. Zwigoff clearly has an interest in independent comics and knows how to present them in a way that makes them interesting and accessible to people. Some of "Ghost World"'s biggest fans have never read a comic book, and I suspect one need not know who Crumb is to appreciate this documentary. His brother Charles lives in a "cloistered environment" of books, which is an interesting sight... he speaks of not yet having read Kant or Hegel, but you can see nearby a copy of a Buddhist book, suggesting that such things may not be beyond his range of interests. What Charles does now is unclear. Presumably nothing. And the other brother, Maxon, is even more bizarre. The constant cynicism is a welcome perspective. He seems happy, but Crumb constantly talks disparagingly of things. His attitude is interesting, and sometimes he suggests a Luddite viewpoint. He also, despite needing money, turned down Saturday Night Live and the Rolling Stones... running from fame. A gallery owner calls him the "Daumier of our time" and the Time art critic says he is the Brueghel for the second half of the 20th century. I suppose being compared to classic art is a compliment, though the fact they are such obscure names may not be complimentary at all... I do not know Daumier or Brueghel's work, so I cannot even say if I like it! If Crumb is not weird enough, just wait until they invite him behind the scenes at a pornographic "Leg Show" photo shoot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure gold, one of the greatest films of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gloede_The_Saint
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm in complete shock. I must admit that when it started off with David Lynch presents I knew I was in for something, but I had no idea what. I cannot believe that anyone would expose their life like this. Robert Crumb is what would be described as a pretty "sick" individual, his family more so. His brothers are talking about suicide attempts, molesting women, etc. Robert Crumb is basically letting you see ever part of his life. We even see him ride around on women's backs, which is apparently one of his favorite things in the whole world. If you are not familiar with him, he is a sort of satirical, sexually obsessed cartoonist, who among other things makes cartoons about his own crazy life. And he is a likable guy. Grim and openly perverted but he does have a personality. He is the amusing outcast who shows the world for what he thinks it is. Director Terry Zwigoff does this almost like a fictional film, of course there are interviews and most of it is conversations between Robert and people who knows him, but sometimes you think of him more as a Woody Allen kind of fictional characters. I is so far from the norm, and so much a character it's hard to believe he's real. The film itself has this weird form of just being. It's a dark comedy, and though it never stops being interesting and you can feel the somewhat morbid comedic atmosphere it's just hard to categorize as a comedy. It's more. It's something true, and something to think about; Though it's pretty impossible to figure out what it is you are supposed to think about. Individuality, society, norms, standards, art, perhaps everything in existence. At it's core you just know this is something special. It's not just the Crumb family quirks and distancing life style, the complete honesty about it and the emotions this brings, it's the look at the artistic work it creates, and maybe vice versa. This film needs to be experienced!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Documentary of Underground Cartoonist and Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Warning! Spoilers ahead! This movie succeeds largely because the documentarian does not inject his bias into the story, nor does he push any sort of agenda. He lets his subjects give their side of the story. He listens to both sides of the argument, whether they approve of what Robert Crumb has done as an artist, or whether he is nothing more than a bizarre pornographer. In all, the neutrality of the movie-maker is this film's best selling point, and I highly recommend this film as one that doesn't beat you over the head with its opinion or message; it lets the subjects do the talking. On the topic of semi-famous underground cartoonist Robert Crumb and his family, the film leaves one with an uneasy feeling at best. Charles, Robert's brother, and his mother reminded me of the recent HBO "Grey Gardens" movie, which itself was based on a documentary. If Robert Crumb can be perceived by some as a stark eccentric who cannot fit in to modern society, at least he has been able to create a stable home life with a loving family of his own. This movie is utterly tragic in its portrayal of Crumb's brothers, Charles and Maxon, especially so since Charles is gifted with exceptional cartooning skills (his artwork looked superior to Robert's best efforts), yet was cursed with severe psychiatric problems which prevented him from entering society as a functional individual. While Robert is a functional member of society, the overall impression the movie gave was that he was somewhat distant from other people, including his kin, and could not pick up easily on the feelings of others. The most poignant example of this was a brief (maybe one minute?) description of his father by Crumb's son from his first wife. Still, it was delightful to see Crumb nurture his children by helping them do artwork of their own. On the surface, Crumb may seem like a unique if peculiar individual: snobbish, detached from the outside world, relishing in dressing in anachronistic clothing and listening to old jazz records. Still, the impression was of a kind-hearted individual who found release through art. I did enjoy the movie's inclusion of those who objected to Crumb's art as blatantly pornographic, though my sense is that Crumb's work does not have the mainstream popularity which would make it troubling to society at large, nor the messages in his illustrations singularly sexual, to classify it as straightforwardly pornographic. A solid effort. I highly recommend this film to those who love documentaries.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know for some time what this film listed in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die was about, so I was very interested when I found out it was a documentary about a famous comic book cartoonist who I had heard about. Robert Crumb is the cartoonist and artist who drew and created popular comics and images such as Fritz the Cat, Mr. Natural and Keep on Truckin', he was the major pioneer for the genesis and popularisation of underground comics. This documentary details his life from developing his talent for drawing and making his own comic books with his two brothers, and of course becoming famous, but we also get an insight into the darker and strange regions of his subconscious mind. Interviews come from Crumb himself, his mother, his two brothers Charles and Maxon who are perhaps more strange than Robert, his then wife Aline Kominsky who knows her husband is unusual and his ex- girlfriends, as well as other artists, art critics and historians, and some admirers. The work of Crumb started from childhood with his love for Disney and various cartoon characters, where he and his brothers would create their own adventure comic books, and growing up he developed his bizarre style which included satire and sexual and perverted imagery. It is interesting to hear his various stories about his creations, his relationships with his brothers, his parents and the women he was with, it is interesting to see how disturbed his brothers are (one committed suicide after the film), and it is interesting to see his works discussed, including the mentioning of killing off Fritz the Cat following the cartoon film which he did not approve. This has many elements to it, it is fascinating, it is artistic, it is strange and it is disturbing, Crumb is obviously a genius with his cartoon style and imagination, but his eccentric personality and family background is the most interesting thing to watch this for, a most worthwhile documentary film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In my top 5 films, ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zee
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always hated R. Crumb's comics, finding them misogynistic and racist and weird and unfunny. In my factory-town hippie youth, the boys who found them funny were boys I avoided. (I never met a girl or black person who did like them, though a few may exist.) So you'd think I might hate this movie, or not want to watch it, or that this review would be negative. But no. I love a good documentary and this is not merely good; it's a great one, directed by film genius Terry Zwigoff. Crumb the movie riveted me, showing me an intricate portrait of a complex man. This is not a short movie, but I was always engaged--great pacing and editing, surprising and revealing choices of scenes. To me what it says about "art" (or craft) is far less important than what it says about this one man. Crumb had a childhood that looks worse than the worst horror film I've ever seen. Bad father, bat**** crazy mother, and three genius boys that I suppose may carry the crazy gene too. As Zwigoff takes us into that bizarre home and the lives of the other brothers, we come to see that R. Crumb's art and life is a triumph of the human spirit, a flower blooming out of burbling sewage. To me, it's not an attractive flower, rather a noisome and homely thing, but dang it, a flower, and I ended up applauding him for doing so well with such beginnings. No matter how crazy your family is, you leave this film thinking, wow, thanks Mom and Dad for not being anywhere near this bad. Your own tiny neuroses will seem charming and mild in comparison to the brothers'. You leave the film with the sense that all things are possible--if Crumb did this with his life despite what you now know, what the heck is holding you back? And if a film can change people, even for a short time, this one has the capacity to make you more understanding of the worst people you meet. What if they had this much baggage? How can you possibly know what made them what they are? Everyone is doing the best s/he can, and while some days that seems like bad news, after watching the film, it feels like good news.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Successful Outlier From A Doomed Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Documentary of the art and life of Robert Crumb, a legendary and controversial cartoonist. It's one of those few pieces of non-fiction cinema that truly portrays a person's mind and describes with great dedication and care the essence of the subject at hand: Crumb is seen as a gentle man with bizarre and manic tendencies, being a sexual deviant, socially awkward, and a women hater (although the latter isn't as obvious) who inevitably distances himself from the rest of the world. When his brothers and his mother are interviewed, we read through the darker, more manic pages of the film: it is clear that obsession(or mental illness, if you want) and strong artistic creativity tragically cohabit within the family. "Crumb", besides reflecting that relationship between art and society that is partly present in modern American culture, is a sort of dedication to the people that by going against it unwillingly fall into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anykind of Artist can learn from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregg Di Lorenzo (gdilorenzo1@optimum.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Primarily: You are in the presence of a master creating and displaying his art, and throughout these portions of the film any kind of artist will find much to learn from this man. The comparison made that he is the "modern" D&uuml;rer is very apt. Secondarily: You are watching one the most humorous and (blackly) entertaining films ever produced anywhere. Yes, we are reassured once again that an (the) artists' personality(ies) cannot never be confused with or substituted for the work they have give us; the strongest humor comes from the aon-old maxim the truth is stranger than fiction... p.s. One last thing - had seen this piece over a decade ago, but a recent review of Crumb's 2009 outstanding "Genesis" work led back here and there to review. If you haven't read it yet do it tonight/day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb came out of the 1960s as the leading underground comic book artist. Sexually explicit material, usually with women drawn with huge buttocks were his signature. Album covers, including Janis Joplin's Big Brother and the Holding Company being the most well known, show a real and unique artist at work. Filmmaker Terry Zwigoff brings his camera into the Crumb family home; can you say dysfunctional? ? The word is not strong enough to describe this modern day Adam's Family. Robert's brother Charles looks like Lerch and despite his agoraphobia is also a creative genius. The Crumb's interactions are a train wreck in the making that you can't take your eyes off of. The brothers are both certifiably insane and yet hugely talented. Crumb is one of the best documentary's ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good and a bit creepy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb has become an icon in the world of underground comic artists, and this documentary takes a close look at his work and the often unhappy life that informed it with an intimacy that is both gratifying and disturbing. Crumb's art and career are celebrated here on film even while his dysfunctional adolescence, his personal insecurities and his sexual obsessions are dissected by family, friends, pop psychologists and other invited crackpots. We see how, by his own understanding, that young Robert Crumb developed his talent as a vehicle to reach out and connect with other people, especially girls, and then had to deal with the frustrations resulting from his failure to achieve success with this. We see how his cartooning style evolved, how certain repeated subjects and motifs found their way into his work. We get a close up view of Robert Crumb that is almost too close up. The film's intimacy with its subject creates an almost claustrophobic feel, especially since Crumb himself is almost painfully awkward and lacking in personal charm, his mother is an ogress, his wife and daughter seem wary and stiff on camera, and his older brother is borderline crazy. Especially interesting is Robert Crumb's brother Charles, who is also a cartoonist and quite talented but clearly mentally unbalanced. His work shows genuine technical polish and is extremely evocative. It is also morbid and obsessive to the point of wallowing in darkness and despair, since its creator is an over-40, out of work dingbat who lives and works in the attic of the Crumb family home. Charles was a key inspiration to the young Robert Crumb, yet he is also an object lesson. With a little less professional drive and career focus, Robert could easily have followed his brother's path in life and art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    darkly fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was never a fan of R. Crumb's work, finding it unpleasant and ugly, but I heard the documentary was good and it certainly is. This is a fascinating portrayal not just of the highly eccentric Crumb but also of his even more off-kilter brothers. They are a very messed up family, so messed up that their upbringing was probably even worse than it is described in the movie. The film works in a number of ways. It does a good job of exploring Crumb's artwork, where it came from and how he approaches it (even though it's mainly about the personal we do see some of his craftsmanship as well. It shows how his comics generate extreme reactions, most notably in the opposing reactions of a pretentious English guy who talks about Crumb as a great artist and a painfully politically correct woman who says he legitimizes horrible fantasies by expressing them. But more than anything, this is a movie that reveals the Crumb's disturbing personalities and dismal lives. Perhaps the most disturbing thing about it is how casually they discuss themselves, laughing boisterously as they talk about their odd sexuality and abusive father. It's a rather downbeat documentary but well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Real Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cinematic portrait of the controversial comic book writer/artist and his traumatized family. Crumb is the perfect subject matter for Terry Zwigoff, who is best known for "Ghost World", an adaptation of a graphic novel. Zwigoff clearly has an interest in independent comics and knows how to present them in a way that makes them interesting and accessible to people. Some of "Ghost World"'s biggest fans have never read a comic book, and I suspect one need not know who Crumb is to appreciate this documentary. His brother Charles lives in a "cloistered environment" of books, which is an interesting sight... he speaks of not yet having read Kant or Hegel, but you can see nearby a copy of a Buddhist book, suggesting that such things may not be beyond his range of interests. What Charles does now is unclear. Presumably nothing. And the other brother, Maxon, is even more bizarre. The constant cynicism is a welcome perspective. He seems happy, but Crumb constantly talks disparagingly of things. His attitude is interesting, and sometimes he suggests a Luddite viewpoint. He also, despite needing money, turned down Saturday Night Live and the Rolling Stones... running from fame. A gallery owner calls him the "Daumier of our time" and the Time art critic says he is the Brueghel for the second half of the 20th century. I suppose being compared to classic art is a compliment, though the fact they are such obscure names may not be complimentary at all... I do not know Daumier or Brueghel's work, so I cannot even say if I like it! If Crumb is not weird enough, just wait until they invite him behind the scenes at a pornographic "Leg Show" photo shoot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure gold, one of the greatest films of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gloede_The_Saint
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm in complete shock. I must admit that when it started off with David Lynch presents I knew I was in for something, but I had no idea what. I cannot believe that anyone would expose their life like this. Robert Crumb is what would be described as a pretty "sick" individual, his family more so. His brothers are talking about suicide attempts, molesting women, etc. Robert Crumb is basically letting you see ever part of his life. We even see him ride around on women's backs, which is apparently one of his favorite things in the whole world. If you are not familiar with him, he is a sort of satirical, sexually obsessed cartoonist, who among other things makes cartoons about his own crazy life. And he is a likable guy. Grim and openly perverted but he does have a personality. He is the amusing outcast who shows the world for what he thinks it is. Director Terry Zwigoff does this almost like a fictional film, of course there are interviews and most of it is conversations between Robert and people who knows him, but sometimes you think of him more as a Woody Allen kind of fictional characters. I is so far from the norm, and so much a character it's hard to believe he's real. The film itself has this weird form of just being. It's a dark comedy, and though it never stops being interesting and you can feel the somewhat morbid comedic atmosphere it's just hard to categorize as a comedy. It's more. It's something true, and something to think about; Though it's pretty impossible to figure out what it is you are supposed to think about. Individuality, society, norms, standards, art, perhaps everything in existence. At it's core you just know this is something special. It's not just the Crumb family quirks and distancing life style, the complete honesty about it and the emotions this brings, it's the look at the artistic work it creates, and maybe vice versa. This film needs to be experienced!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Documentary of Underground Cartoonist and Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Warning! Spoilers ahead! This movie succeeds largely because the documentarian does not inject his bias into the story, nor does he push any sort of agenda. He lets his subjects give their side of the story. He listens to both sides of the argument, whether they approve of what Robert Crumb has done as an artist, or whether he is nothing more than a bizarre pornographer. In all, the neutrality of the movie-maker is this film's best selling point, and I highly recommend this film as one that doesn't beat you over the head with its opinion or message; it lets the subjects do the talking. On the topic of semi-famous underground cartoonist Robert Crumb and his family, the film leaves one with an uneasy feeling at best. Charles, Robert's brother, and his mother reminded me of the recent HBO "Grey Gardens" movie, which itself was based on a documentary. If Robert Crumb can be perceived by some as a stark eccentric who cannot fit in to modern society, at least he has been able to create a stable home life with a loving family of his own. This movie is utterly tragic in its portrayal of Crumb's brothers, Charles and Maxon, especially so since Charles is gifted with exceptional cartooning skills (his artwork looked superior to Robert's best efforts), yet was cursed with severe psychiatric problems which prevented him from entering society as a functional individual. While Robert is a functional member of society, the overall impression the movie gave was that he was somewhat distant from other people, including his kin, and could not pick up easily on the feelings of others. The most poignant example of this was a brief (maybe one minute?) description of his father by Crumb's son from his first wife. Still, it was delightful to see Crumb nurture his children by helping them do artwork of their own. On the surface, Crumb may seem like a unique if peculiar individual: snobbish, detached from the outside world, relishing in dressing in anachronistic clothing and listening to old jazz records. Still, the impression was of a kind-hearted individual who found release through art. I did enjoy the movie's inclusion of those who objected to Crumb's art as blatantly pornographic, though my sense is that Crumb's work does not have the mainstream popularity which would make it troubling to society at large, nor the messages in his illustrations singularly sexual, to classify it as straightforwardly pornographic. A solid effort. I highly recommend this film to those who love documentaries.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know for some time what this film listed in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die was about, so I was very interested when I found out it was a documentary about a famous comic book cartoonist who I had heard about. Robert Crumb is the cartoonist and artist who drew and created popular comics and images such as Fritz the Cat, Mr. Natural and Keep on Truckin', he was the major pioneer for the genesis and popularisation of underground comics. This documentary details his life from developing his talent for drawing and making his own comic books with his two brothers, and of course becoming famous, but we also get an insight into the darker and strange regions of his subconscious mind. Interviews come from Crumb himself, his mother, his two brothers Charles and Maxon who are perhaps more strange than Robert, his then wife Aline Kominsky who knows her husband is unusual and his ex- girlfriends, as well as other artists, art critics and historians, and some admirers. The work of Crumb started from childhood with his love for Disney and various cartoon characters, where he and his brothers would create their own adventure comic books, and growing up he developed his bizarre style which included satire and sexual and perverted imagery. It is interesting to hear his various stories about his creations, his relationships with his brothers, his parents and the women he was with, it is interesting to see how disturbed his brothers are (one committed suicide after the film), and it is interesting to see his works discussed, including the mentioning of killing off Fritz the Cat following the cartoon film which he did not approve. This has many elements to it, it is fascinating, it is artistic, it is strange and it is disturbing, Crumb is obviously a genius with his cartoon style and imagination, but his eccentric personality and family background is the most interesting thing to watch this for, a most worthwhile documentary film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In my top 5 films, ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zee
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always hated R. Crumb's comics, finding them misogynistic and racist and weird and unfunny. In my factory-town hippie youth, the boys who found them funny were boys I avoided. (I never met a girl or black person who did like them, though a few may exist.) So you'd think I might hate this movie, or not want to watch it, or that this review would be negative. But no. I love a good documentary and this is not merely good; it's a great one, directed by film genius Terry Zwigoff. Crumb the movie riveted me, showing me an intricate portrait of a complex man. This is not a short movie, but I was always engaged--great pacing and editing, surprising and revealing choices of scenes. To me what it says about "art" (or craft) is far less important than what it says about this one man. Crumb had a childhood that looks worse than the worst horror film I've ever seen. Bad father, bat**** crazy mother, and three genius boys that I suppose may carry the crazy gene too. As Zwigoff takes us into that bizarre home and the lives of the other brothers, we come to see that R. Crumb's art and life is a triumph of the human spirit, a flower blooming out of burbling sewage. To me, it's not an attractive flower, rather a noisome and homely thing, but dang it, a flower, and I ended up applauding him for doing so well with such beginnings. No matter how crazy your family is, you leave this film thinking, wow, thanks Mom and Dad for not being anywhere near this bad. Your own tiny neuroses will seem charming and mild in comparison to the brothers'. You leave the film with the sense that all things are possible--if Crumb did this with his life despite what you now know, what the heck is holding you back? And if a film can change people, even for a short time, this one has the capacity to make you more understanding of the worst people you meet. What if they had this much baggage? How can you possibly know what made them what they are? Everyone is doing the best s/he can, and while some days that seems like bad news, after watching the film, it feels like good news.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Successful Outlier From A Doomed Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Documentary of the art and life of Robert Crumb, a legendary and controversial cartoonist. It's one of those few pieces of non-fiction cinema that truly portrays a person's mind and describes with great dedication and care the essence of the subject at hand: Crumb is seen as a gentle man with bizarre and manic tendencies, being a sexual deviant, socially awkward, and a women hater (although the latter isn't as obvious) who inevitably distances himself from the rest of the world. When his brothers and his mother are interviewed, we read through the darker, more manic pages of the film: it is clear that obsession(or mental illness, if you want) and strong artistic creativity tragically cohabit within the family. "Crumb", besides reflecting that relationship between art and society that is partly present in modern American culture, is a sort of dedication to the people that by going against it unwillingly fall into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anykind of Artist can learn from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregg Di Lorenzo (gdilorenzo1@optimum.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Primarily: You are in the presence of a master creating and displaying his art, and throughout these portions of the film any kind of artist will find much to learn from this man. The comparison made that he is the "modern" D&uuml;rer is very apt. Secondarily: You are watching one the most humorous and (blackly) entertaining films ever produced anywhere. Yes, we are reassured once again that an (the) artists' personality(ies) cannot never be confused with or substituted for the work they have give us; the strongest humor comes from the aon-old maxim the truth is stranger than fiction... p.s. One last thing - had seen this piece over a decade ago, but a recent review of Crumb's 2009 outstanding "Genesis" work led back here and there to review. If you haven't read it yet do it tonight/day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb came out of the 1960s as the leading underground comic book artist. Sexually explicit material, usually with women drawn with huge buttocks were his signature. Album covers, including Janis Joplin's Big Brother and the Holding Company being the most well known, show a real and unique artist at work. Filmmaker Terry Zwigoff brings his camera into the Crumb family home; can you say dysfunctional? ? The word is not strong enough to describe this modern day Adam's Family. Robert's brother Charles looks like Lerch and despite his agoraphobia is also a creative genius. The Crumb's interactions are a train wreck in the making that you can't take your eyes off of. The brothers are both certifiably insane and yet hugely talented. Crumb is one of the best documentary's ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good and a bit creepy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb has become an icon in the world of underground comic artists, and this documentary takes a close look at his work and the often unhappy life that informed it with an intimacy that is both gratifying and disturbing. Crumb's art and career are celebrated here on film even while his dysfunctional adolescence, his personal insecurities and his sexual obsessions are dissected by family, friends, pop psychologists and other invited crackpots. We see how, by his own understanding, that young Robert Crumb developed his talent as a vehicle to reach out and connect with other people, especially girls, and then had to deal with the frustrations resulting from his failure to achieve success with this. We see how his cartooning style evolved, how certain repeated subjects and motifs found their way into his work. We get a close up view of Robert Crumb that is almost too close up. The film's intimacy with its subject creates an almost claustrophobic feel, especially since Crumb himself is almost painfully awkward and lacking in personal charm, his mother is an ogress, his wife and daughter seem wary and stiff on camera, and his older brother is borderline crazy. Especially interesting is Robert Crumb's brother Charles, who is also a cartoonist and quite talented but clearly mentally unbalanced. His work shows genuine technical polish and is extremely evocative. It is also morbid and obsessive to the point of wallowing in darkness and despair, since its creator is an over-40, out of work dingbat who lives and works in the attic of the Crumb family home. Charles was a key inspiration to the young Robert Crumb, yet he is also an object lesson. With a little less professional drive and career focus, Robert could easily have followed his brother's path in life and art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    darkly fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was never a fan of R. Crumb's work, finding it unpleasant and ugly, but I heard the documentary was good and it certainly is. This is a fascinating portrayal not just of the highly eccentric Crumb but also of his even more off-kilter brothers. They are a very messed up family, so messed up that their upbringing was probably even worse than it is described in the movie. The film works in a number of ways. It does a good job of exploring Crumb's artwork, where it came from and how he approaches it (even though it's mainly about the personal we do see some of his craftsmanship as well. It shows how his comics generate extreme reactions, most notably in the opposing reactions of a pretentious English guy who talks about Crumb as a great artist and a painfully politically correct woman who says he legitimizes horrible fantasies by expressing them. But more than anything, this is a movie that reveals the Crumb's disturbing personalities and dismal lives. Perhaps the most disturbing thing about it is how casually they discuss themselves, laughing boisterously as they talk about their odd sexuality and abusive father. It's a rather downbeat documentary but well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Real Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cinematic portrait of the controversial comic book writer/artist and his traumatized family. Crumb is the perfect subject matter for Terry Zwigoff, who is best known for "Ghost World", an adaptation of a graphic novel. Zwigoff clearly has an interest in independent comics and knows how to present them in a way that makes them interesting and accessible to people. Some of "Ghost World"'s biggest fans have never read a comic book, and I suspect one need not know who Crumb is to appreciate this documentary. His brother Charles lives in a "cloistered environment" of books, which is an interesting sight... he speaks of not yet having read Kant or Hegel, but you can see nearby a copy of a Buddhist book, suggesting that such things may not be beyond his range of interests. What Charles does now is unclear. Presumably nothing. And the other brother, Maxon, is even more bizarre. The constant cynicism is a welcome perspective. He seems happy, but Crumb constantly talks disparagingly of things. His attitude is interesting, and sometimes he suggests a Luddite viewpoint. He also, despite needing money, turned down Saturday Night Live and the Rolling Stones... running from fame. A gallery owner calls him the "Daumier of our time" and the Time art critic says he is the Brueghel for the second half of the 20th century. I suppose being compared to classic art is a compliment, though the fact they are such obscure names may not be complimentary at all... I do not know Daumier or Brueghel's work, so I cannot even say if I like it! If Crumb is not weird enough, just wait until they invite him behind the scenes at a pornographic "Leg Show" photo shoot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure gold, one of the greatest films of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gloede_The_Saint
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm in complete shock. I must admit that when it started off with David Lynch presents I knew I was in for something, but I had no idea what. I cannot believe that anyone would expose their life like this. Robert Crumb is what would be described as a pretty "sick" individual, his family more so. His brothers are talking about suicide attempts, molesting women, etc. Robert Crumb is basically letting you see ever part of his life. We even see him ride around on women's backs, which is apparently one of his favorite things in the whole world. If you are not familiar with him, he is a sort of satirical, sexually obsessed cartoonist, who among other things makes cartoons about his own crazy life. And he is a likable guy. Grim and openly perverted but he does have a personality. He is the amusing outcast who shows the world for what he thinks it is. Director Terry Zwigoff does this almost like a fictional film, of course there are interviews and most of it is conversations between Robert and people who knows him, but sometimes you think of him more as a Woody Allen kind of fictional characters. I is so far from the norm, and so much a character it's hard to believe he's real. The film itself has this weird form of just being. It's a dark comedy, and though it never stops being interesting and you can feel the somewhat morbid comedic atmosphere it's just hard to categorize as a comedy. It's more. It's something true, and something to think about; Though it's pretty impossible to figure out what it is you are supposed to think about. Individuality, society, norms, standards, art, perhaps everything in existence. At it's core you just know this is something special. It's not just the Crumb family quirks and distancing life style, the complete honesty about it and the emotions this brings, it's the look at the artistic work it creates, and maybe vice versa. This film needs to be experienced!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Documentary of Underground Cartoonist and Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Warning! Spoilers ahead! This movie succeeds largely because the documentarian does not inject his bias into the story, nor does he push any sort of agenda. He lets his subjects give their side of the story. He listens to both sides of the argument, whether they approve of what Robert Crumb has done as an artist, or whether he is nothing more than a bizarre pornographer. In all, the neutrality of the movie-maker is this film's best selling point, and I highly recommend this film as one that doesn't beat you over the head with its opinion or message; it lets the subjects do the talking. On the topic of semi-famous underground cartoonist Robert Crumb and his family, the film leaves one with an uneasy feeling at best. Charles, Robert's brother, and his mother reminded me of the recent HBO "Grey Gardens" movie, which itself was based on a documentary. If Robert Crumb can be perceived by some as a stark eccentric who cannot fit in to modern society, at least he has been able to create a stable home life with a loving family of his own. This movie is utterly tragic in its portrayal of Crumb's brothers, Charles and Maxon, especially so since Charles is gifted with exceptional cartooning skills (his artwork looked superior to Robert's best efforts), yet was cursed with severe psychiatric problems which prevented him from entering society as a functional individual. While Robert is a functional member of society, the overall impression the movie gave was that he was somewhat distant from other people, including his kin, and could not pick up easily on the feelings of others. The most poignant example of this was a brief (maybe one minute?) description of his father by Crumb's son from his first wife. Still, it was delightful to see Crumb nurture his children by helping them do artwork of their own. On the surface, Crumb may seem like a unique if peculiar individual: snobbish, detached from the outside world, relishing in dressing in anachronistic clothing and listening to old jazz records. Still, the impression was of a kind-hearted individual who found release through art. I did enjoy the movie's inclusion of those who objected to Crumb's art as blatantly pornographic, though my sense is that Crumb's work does not have the mainstream popularity which would make it troubling to society at large, nor the messages in his illustrations singularly sexual, to classify it as straightforwardly pornographic. A solid effort. I highly recommend this film to those who love documentaries.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know for some time what this film listed in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die was about, so I was very interested when I found out it was a documentary about a famous comic book cartoonist who I had heard about. Robert Crumb is the cartoonist and artist who drew and created popular comics and images such as Fritz the Cat, Mr. Natural and Keep on Truckin', he was the major pioneer for the genesis and popularisation of underground comics. This documentary details his life from developing his talent for drawing and making his own comic books with his two brothers, and of course becoming famous, but we also get an insight into the darker and strange regions of his subconscious mind. Interviews come from Crumb himself, his mother, his two brothers Charles and Maxon who are perhaps more strange than Robert, his then wife Aline Kominsky who knows her husband is unusual and his ex- girlfriends, as well as other artists, art critics and historians, and some admirers. The work of Crumb started from childhood with his love for Disney and various cartoon characters, where he and his brothers would create their own adventure comic books, and growing up he developed his bizarre style which included satire and sexual and perverted imagery. It is interesting to hear his various stories about his creations, his relationships with his brothers, his parents and the women he was with, it is interesting to see how disturbed his brothers are (one committed suicide after the film), and it is interesting to see his works discussed, including the mentioning of killing off Fritz the Cat following the cartoon film which he did not approve. This has many elements to it, it is fascinating, it is artistic, it is strange and it is disturbing, Crumb is obviously a genius with his cartoon style and imagination, but his eccentric personality and family background is the most interesting thing to watch this for, a most worthwhile documentary film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In my top 5 films, ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zee
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always hated R. Crumb's comics, finding them misogynistic and racist and weird and unfunny. In my factory-town hippie youth, the boys who found them funny were boys I avoided. (I never met a girl or black person who did like them, though a few may exist.) So you'd think I might hate this movie, or not want to watch it, or that this review would be negative. But no. I love a good documentary and this is not merely good; it's a great one, directed by film genius Terry Zwigoff. Crumb the movie riveted me, showing me an intricate portrait of a complex man. This is not a short movie, but I was always engaged--great pacing and editing, surprising and revealing choices of scenes. To me what it says about "art" (or craft) is far less important than what it says about this one man. Crumb had a childhood that looks worse than the worst horror film I've ever seen. Bad father, bat**** crazy mother, and three genius boys that I suppose may carry the crazy gene too. As Zwigoff takes us into that bizarre home and the lives of the other brothers, we come to see that R. Crumb's art and life is a triumph of the human spirit, a flower blooming out of burbling sewage. To me, it's not an attractive flower, rather a noisome and homely thing, but dang it, a flower, and I ended up applauding him for doing so well with such beginnings. No matter how crazy your family is, you leave this film thinking, wow, thanks Mom and Dad for not being anywhere near this bad. Your own tiny neuroses will seem charming and mild in comparison to the brothers'. You leave the film with the sense that all things are possible--if Crumb did this with his life despite what you now know, what the heck is holding you back? And if a film can change people, even for a short time, this one has the capacity to make you more understanding of the worst people you meet. What if they had this much baggage? How can you possibly know what made them what they are? Everyone is doing the best s/he can, and while some days that seems like bad news, after watching the film, it feels like good news.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Successful Outlier From A Doomed Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Documentary of the art and life of Robert Crumb, a legendary and controversial cartoonist. It's one of those few pieces of non-fiction cinema that truly portrays a person's mind and describes with great dedication and care the essence of the subject at hand: Crumb is seen as a gentle man with bizarre and manic tendencies, being a sexual deviant, socially awkward, and a women hater (although the latter isn't as obvious) who inevitably distances himself from the rest of the world. When his brothers and his mother are interviewed, we read through the darker, more manic pages of the film: it is clear that obsession(or mental illness, if you want) and strong artistic creativity tragically cohabit within the family. "Crumb", besides reflecting that relationship between art and society that is partly present in modern American culture, is a sort of dedication to the people that by going against it unwillingly fall into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anykind of Artist can learn from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregg Di Lorenzo (gdilorenzo1@optimum.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Primarily: You are in the presence of a master creating and displaying his art, and throughout these portions of the film any kind of artist will find much to learn from this man. The comparison made that he is the "modern" D&uuml;rer is very apt. Secondarily: You are watching one the most humorous and (blackly) entertaining films ever produced anywhere. Yes, we are reassured once again that an (the) artists' personality(ies) cannot never be confused with or substituted for the work they have give us; the strongest humor comes from the aon-old maxim the truth is stranger than fiction... p.s. One last thing - had seen this piece over a decade ago, but a recent review of Crumb's 2009 outstanding "Genesis" work led back here and there to review. If you haven't read it yet do it tonight/day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb came out of the 1960s as the leading underground comic book artist. Sexually explicit material, usually with women drawn with huge buttocks were his signature. Album covers, including Janis Joplin's Big Brother and the Holding Company being the most well known, show a real and unique artist at work. Filmmaker Terry Zwigoff brings his camera into the Crumb family home; can you say dysfunctional? ? The word is not strong enough to describe this modern day Adam's Family. Robert's brother Charles looks like Lerch and despite his agoraphobia is also a creative genius. The Crumb's interactions are a train wreck in the making that you can't take your eyes off of. The brothers are both certifiably insane and yet hugely talented. Crumb is one of the best documentary's ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good and a bit creepy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb has become an icon in the world of underground comic artists, and this documentary takes a close look at his work and the often unhappy life that informed it with an intimacy that is both gratifying and disturbing. Crumb's art and career are celebrated here on film even while his dysfunctional adolescence, his personal insecurities and his sexual obsessions are dissected by family, friends, pop psychologists and other invited crackpots. We see how, by his own understanding, that young Robert Crumb developed his talent as a vehicle to reach out and connect with other people, especially girls, and then had to deal with the frustrations resulting from his failure to achieve success with this. We see how his cartooning style evolved, how certain repeated subjects and motifs found their way into his work. We get a close up view of Robert Crumb that is almost too close up. The film's intimacy with its subject creates an almost claustrophobic feel, especially since Crumb himself is almost painfully awkward and lacking in personal charm, his mother is an ogress, his wife and daughter seem wary and stiff on camera, and his older brother is borderline crazy. Especially interesting is Robert Crumb's brother Charles, who is also a cartoonist and quite talented but clearly mentally unbalanced. His work shows genuine technical polish and is extremely evocative. It is also morbid and obsessive to the point of wallowing in darkness and despair, since its creator is an over-40, out of work dingbat who lives and works in the attic of the Crumb family home. Charles was a key inspiration to the young Robert Crumb, yet he is also an object lesson. With a little less professional drive and career focus, Robert could easily have followed his brother's path in life and art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    darkly fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was never a fan of R. Crumb's work, finding it unpleasant and ugly, but I heard the documentary was good and it certainly is. This is a fascinating portrayal not just of the highly eccentric Crumb but also of his even more off-kilter brothers. They are a very messed up family, so messed up that their upbringing was probably even worse than it is described in the movie. The film works in a number of ways. It does a good job of exploring Crumb's artwork, where it came from and how he approaches it (even though it's mainly about the personal we do see some of his craftsmanship as well. It shows how his comics generate extreme reactions, most notably in the opposing reactions of a pretentious English guy who talks about Crumb as a great artist and a painfully politically correct woman who says he legitimizes horrible fantasies by expressing them. But more than anything, this is a movie that reveals the Crumb's disturbing personalities and dismal lives. Perhaps the most disturbing thing about it is how casually they discuss themselves, laughing boisterously as they talk about their odd sexuality and abusive father. It's a rather downbeat documentary but well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Real Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cinematic portrait of the controversial comic book writer/artist and his traumatized family. Crumb is the perfect subject matter for Terry Zwigoff, who is best known for "Ghost World", an adaptation of a graphic novel. Zwigoff clearly has an interest in independent comics and knows how to present them in a way that makes them interesting and accessible to people. Some of "Ghost World"'s biggest fans have never read a comic book, and I suspect one need not know who Crumb is to appreciate this documentary. His brother Charles lives in a "cloistered environment" of books, which is an interesting sight... he speaks of not yet having read Kant or Hegel, but you can see nearby a copy of a Buddhist book, suggesting that such things may not be beyond his range of interests. What Charles does now is unclear. Presumably nothing. And the other brother, Maxon, is even more bizarre. The constant cynicism is a welcome perspective. He seems happy, but Crumb constantly talks disparagingly of things. His attitude is interesting, and sometimes he suggests a Luddite viewpoint. He also, despite needing money, turned down Saturday Night Live and the Rolling Stones... running from fame. A gallery owner calls him the "Daumier of our time" and the Time art critic says he is the Brueghel for the second half of the 20th century. I suppose being compared to classic art is a compliment, though the fact they are such obscure names may not be complimentary at all... I do not know Daumier or Brueghel's work, so I cannot even say if I like it! If Crumb is not weird enough, just wait until they invite him behind the scenes at a pornographic "Leg Show" photo shoot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure gold, one of the greatest films of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gloede_The_Saint
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm in complete shock. I must admit that when it started off with David Lynch presents I knew I was in for something, but I had no idea what. I cannot believe that anyone would expose their life like this. Robert Crumb is what would be described as a pretty "sick" individual, his family more so. His brothers are talking about suicide attempts, molesting women, etc. Robert Crumb is basically letting you see ever part of his life. We even see him ride around on women's backs, which is apparently one of his favorite things in the whole world. If you are not familiar with him, he is a sort of satirical, sexually obsessed cartoonist, who among other things makes cartoons about his own crazy life. And he is a likable guy. Grim and openly perverted but he does have a personality. He is the amusing outcast who shows the world for what he thinks it is. Director Terry Zwigoff does this almost like a fictional film, of course there are interviews and most of it is conversations between Robert and people who knows him, but sometimes you think of him more as a Woody Allen kind of fictional characters. I is so far from the norm, and so much a character it's hard to believe he's real. The film itself has this weird form of just being. It's a dark comedy, and though it never stops being interesting and you can feel the somewhat morbid comedic atmosphere it's just hard to categorize as a comedy. It's more. It's something true, and something to think about; Though it's pretty impossible to figure out what it is you are supposed to think about. Individuality, society, norms, standards, art, perhaps everything in existence. At it's core you just know this is something special. It's not just the Crumb family quirks and distancing life style, the complete honesty about it and the emotions this brings, it's the look at the artistic work it creates, and maybe vice versa. This film needs to be experienced!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Documentary of Underground Cartoonist and Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Warning! Spoilers ahead! This movie succeeds largely because the documentarian does not inject his bias into the story, nor does he push any sort of agenda. He lets his subjects give their side of the story. He listens to both sides of the argument, whether they approve of what Robert Crumb has done as an artist, or whether he is nothing more than a bizarre pornographer. In all, the neutrality of the movie-maker is this film's best selling point, and I highly recommend this film as one that doesn't beat you over the head with its opinion or message; it lets the subjects do the talking. On the topic of semi-famous underground cartoonist Robert Crumb and his family, the film leaves one with an uneasy feeling at best. Charles, Robert's brother, and his mother reminded me of the recent HBO "Grey Gardens" movie, which itself was based on a documentary. If Robert Crumb can be perceived by some as a stark eccentric who cannot fit in to modern society, at least he has been able to create a stable home life with a loving family of his own. This movie is utterly tragic in its portrayal of Crumb's brothers, Charles and Maxon, especially so since Charles is gifted with exceptional cartooning skills (his artwork looked superior to Robert's best efforts), yet was cursed with severe psychiatric problems which prevented him from entering society as a functional individual. While Robert is a functional member of society, the overall impression the movie gave was that he was somewhat distant from other people, including his kin, and could not pick up easily on the feelings of others. The most poignant example of this was a brief (maybe one minute?) description of his father by Crumb's son from his first wife. Still, it was delightful to see Crumb nurture his children by helping them do artwork of their own. On the surface, Crumb may seem like a unique if peculiar individual: snobbish, detached from the outside world, relishing in dressing in anachronistic clothing and listening to old jazz records. Still, the impression was of a kind-hearted individual who found release through art. I did enjoy the movie's inclusion of those who objected to Crumb's art as blatantly pornographic, though my sense is that Crumb's work does not have the mainstream popularity which would make it troubling to society at large, nor the messages in his illustrations singularly sexual, to classify it as straightforwardly pornographic. A solid effort. I highly recommend this film to those who love documentaries.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know for some time what this film listed in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die was about, so I was very interested when I found out it was a documentary about a famous comic book cartoonist who I had heard about. Robert Crumb is the cartoonist and artist who drew and created popular comics and images such as Fritz the Cat, Mr. Natural and Keep on Truckin', he was the major pioneer for the genesis and popularisation of underground comics. This documentary details his life from developing his talent for drawing and making his own comic books with his two brothers, and of course becoming famous, but we also get an insight into the darker and strange regions of his subconscious mind. Interviews come from Crumb himself, his mother, his two brothers Charles and Maxon who are perhaps more strange than Robert, his then wife Aline Kominsky who knows her husband is unusual and his ex- girlfriends, as well as other artists, art critics and historians, and some admirers. The work of Crumb started from childhood with his love for Disney and various cartoon characters, where he and his brothers would create their own adventure comic books, and growing up he developed his bizarre style which included satire and sexual and perverted imagery. It is interesting to hear his various stories about his creations, his relationships with his brothers, his parents and the women he was with, it is interesting to see how disturbed his brothers are (one committed suicide after the film), and it is interesting to see his works discussed, including the mentioning of killing off Fritz the Cat following the cartoon film which he did not approve. This has many elements to it, it is fascinating, it is artistic, it is strange and it is disturbing, Crumb is obviously a genius with his cartoon style and imagination, but his eccentric personality and family background is the most interesting thing to watch this for, a most worthwhile documentary film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In my top 5 films, ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zee
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always hated R. Crumb's comics, finding them misogynistic and racist and weird and unfunny. In my factory-town hippie youth, the boys who found them funny were boys I avoided. (I never met a girl or black person who did like them, though a few may exist.) So you'd think I might hate this movie, or not want to watch it, or that this review would be negative. But no. I love a good documentary and this is not merely good; it's a great one, directed by film genius Terry Zwigoff. Crumb the movie riveted me, showing me an intricate portrait of a complex man. This is not a short movie, but I was always engaged--great pacing and editing, surprising and revealing choices of scenes. To me what it says about "art" (or craft) is far less important than what it says about this one man. Crumb had a childhood that looks worse than the worst horror film I've ever seen. Bad father, bat**** crazy mother, and three genius boys that I suppose may carry the crazy gene too. As Zwigoff takes us into that bizarre home and the lives of the other brothers, we come to see that R. Crumb's art and life is a triumph of the human spirit, a flower blooming out of burbling sewage. To me, it's not an attractive flower, rather a noisome and homely thing, but dang it, a flower, and I ended up applauding him for doing so well with such beginnings. No matter how crazy your family is, you leave this film thinking, wow, thanks Mom and Dad for not being anywhere near this bad. Your own tiny neuroses will seem charming and mild in comparison to the brothers'. You leave the film with the sense that all things are possible--if Crumb did this with his life despite what you now know, what the heck is holding you back? And if a film can change people, even for a short time, this one has the capacity to make you more understanding of the worst people you meet. What if they had this much baggage? How can you possibly know what made them what they are? Everyone is doing the best s/he can, and while some days that seems like bad news, after watching the film, it feels like good news.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Successful Outlier From A Doomed Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Documentary of the art and life of Robert Crumb, a legendary and controversial cartoonist. It's one of those few pieces of non-fiction cinema that truly portrays a person's mind and describes with great dedication and care the essence of the subject at hand: Crumb is seen as a gentle man with bizarre and manic tendencies, being a sexual deviant, socially awkward, and a women hater (although the latter isn't as obvious) who inevitably distances himself from the rest of the world. When his brothers and his mother are interviewed, we read through the darker, more manic pages of the film: it is clear that obsession(or mental illness, if you want) and strong artistic creativity tragically cohabit within the family. "Crumb", besides reflecting that relationship between art and society that is partly present in modern American culture, is a sort of dedication to the people that by going against it unwillingly fall into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anykind of Artist can learn from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregg Di Lorenzo (gdilorenzo1@optimum.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Primarily: You are in the presence of a master creating and displaying his art, and throughout these portions of the film any kind of artist will find much to learn from this man. The comparison made that he is the "modern" D&uuml;rer is very apt. Secondarily: You are watching one the most humorous and (blackly) entertaining films ever produced anywhere. Yes, we are reassured once again that an (the) artists' personality(ies) cannot never be confused with or substituted for the work they have give us; the strongest humor comes from the aon-old maxim the truth is stranger than fiction... p.s. One last thing - had seen this piece over a decade ago, but a recent review of Crumb's 2009 outstanding "Genesis" work led back here and there to review. If you haven't read it yet do it tonight/day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb came out of the 1960s as the leading underground comic book artist. Sexually explicit material, usually with women drawn with huge buttocks were his signature. Album covers, including Janis Joplin's Big Brother and the Holding Company being the most well known, show a real and unique artist at work. Filmmaker Terry Zwigoff brings his camera into the Crumb family home; can you say dysfunctional? ? The word is not strong enough to describe this modern day Adam's Family. Robert's brother Charles looks like Lerch and despite his agoraphobia is also a creative genius. The Crumb's interactions are a train wreck in the making that you can't take your eyes off of. The brothers are both certifiably insane and yet hugely talented. Crumb is one of the best documentary's ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good and a bit creepy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb has become an icon in the world of underground comic artists, and this documentary takes a close look at his work and the often unhappy life that informed it with an intimacy that is both gratifying and disturbing. Crumb's art and career are celebrated here on film even while his dysfunctional adolescence, his personal insecurities and his sexual obsessions are dissected by family, friends, pop psychologists and other invited crackpots. We see how, by his own understanding, that young Robert Crumb developed his talent as a vehicle to reach out and connect with other people, especially girls, and then had to deal with the frustrations resulting from his failure to achieve success with this. We see how his cartooning style evolved, how certain repeated subjects and motifs found their way into his work. We get a close up view of Robert Crumb that is almost too close up. The film's intimacy with its subject creates an almost claustrophobic feel, especially since Crumb himself is almost painfully awkward and lacking in personal charm, his mother is an ogress, his wife and daughter seem wary and stiff on camera, and his older brother is borderline crazy. Especially interesting is Robert Crumb's brother Charles, who is also a cartoonist and quite talented but clearly mentally unbalanced. His work shows genuine technical polish and is extremely evocative. It is also morbid and obsessive to the point of wallowing in darkness and despair, since its creator is an over-40, out of work dingbat who lives and works in the attic of the Crumb family home. Charles was a key inspiration to the young Robert Crumb, yet he is also an object lesson. With a little less professional drive and career focus, Robert could easily have followed his brother's path in life and art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    darkly fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was never a fan of R. Crumb's work, finding it unpleasant and ugly, but I heard the documentary was good and it certainly is. This is a fascinating portrayal not just of the highly eccentric Crumb but also of his even more off-kilter brothers. They are a very messed up family, so messed up that their upbringing was probably even worse than it is described in the movie. The film works in a number of ways. It does a good job of exploring Crumb's artwork, where it came from and how he approaches it (even though it's mainly about the personal we do see some of his craftsmanship as well. It shows how his comics generate extreme reactions, most notably in the opposing reactions of a pretentious English guy who talks about Crumb as a great artist and a painfully politically correct woman who says he legitimizes horrible fantasies by expressing them. But more than anything, this is a movie that reveals the Crumb's disturbing personalities and dismal lives. Perhaps the most disturbing thing about it is how casually they discuss themselves, laughing boisterously as they talk about their odd sexuality and abusive father. It's a rather downbeat documentary but well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Real Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cinematic portrait of the controversial comic book writer/artist and his traumatized family. Crumb is the perfect subject matter for Terry Zwigoff, who is best known for "Ghost World", an adaptation of a graphic novel. Zwigoff clearly has an interest in independent comics and knows how to present them in a way that makes them interesting and accessible to people. Some of "Ghost World"'s biggest fans have never read a comic book, and I suspect one need not know who Crumb is to appreciate this documentary. His brother Charles lives in a "cloistered environment" of books, which is an interesting sight... he speaks of not yet having read Kant or Hegel, but you can see nearby a copy of a Buddhist book, suggesting that such things may not be beyond his range of interests. What Charles does now is unclear. Presumably nothing. And the other brother, Maxon, is even more bizarre. The constant cynicism is a welcome perspective. He seems happy, but Crumb constantly talks disparagingly of things. His attitude is interesting, and sometimes he suggests a Luddite viewpoint. He also, despite needing money, turned down Saturday Night Live and the Rolling Stones... running from fame. A gallery owner calls him the "Daumier of our time" and the Time art critic says he is the Brueghel for the second half of the 20th century. I suppose being compared to classic art is a compliment, though the fact they are such obscure names may not be complimentary at all... I do not know Daumier or Brueghel's work, so I cannot even say if I like it! If Crumb is not weird enough, just wait until they invite him behind the scenes at a pornographic "Leg Show" photo shoot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure gold, one of the greatest films of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gloede_The_Saint
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm in complete shock. I must admit that when it started off with David Lynch presents I knew I was in for something, but I had no idea what. I cannot believe that anyone would expose their life like this. Robert Crumb is what would be described as a pretty "sick" individual, his family more so. His brothers are talking about suicide attempts, molesting women, etc. Robert Crumb is basically letting you see ever part of his life. We even see him ride around on women's backs, which is apparently one of his favorite things in the whole world. If you are not familiar with him, he is a sort of satirical, sexually obsessed cartoonist, who among other things makes cartoons about his own crazy life. And he is a likable guy. Grim and openly perverted but he does have a personality. He is the amusing outcast who shows the world for what he thinks it is. Director Terry Zwigoff does this almost like a fictional film, of course there are interviews and most of it is conversations between Robert and people who knows him, but sometimes you think of him more as a Woody Allen kind of fictional characters. I is so far from the norm, and so much a character it's hard to believe he's real. The film itself has this weird form of just being. It's a dark comedy, and though it never stops being interesting and you can feel the somewhat morbid comedic atmosphere it's just hard to categorize as a comedy. It's more. It's something true, and something to think about; Though it's pretty impossible to figure out what it is you are supposed to think about. Individuality, society, norms, standards, art, perhaps everything in existence. At it's core you just know this is something special. It's not just the Crumb family quirks and distancing life style, the complete honesty about it and the emotions this brings, it's the look at the artistic work it creates, and maybe vice versa. This film needs to be experienced!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Documentary of Underground Cartoonist and Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Warning! Spoilers ahead! This movie succeeds largely because the documentarian does not inject his bias into the story, nor does he push any sort of agenda. He lets his subjects give their side of the story. He listens to both sides of the argument, whether they approve of what Robert Crumb has done as an artist, or whether he is nothing more than a bizarre pornographer. In all, the neutrality of the movie-maker is this film's best selling point, and I highly recommend this film as one that doesn't beat you over the head with its opinion or message; it lets the subjects do the talking. On the topic of semi-famous underground cartoonist Robert Crumb and his family, the film leaves one with an uneasy feeling at best. Charles, Robert's brother, and his mother reminded me of the recent HBO "Grey Gardens" movie, which itself was based on a documentary. If Robert Crumb can be perceived by some as a stark eccentric who cannot fit in to modern society, at least he has been able to create a stable home life with a loving family of his own. This movie is utterly tragic in its portrayal of Crumb's brothers, Charles and Maxon, especially so since Charles is gifted with exceptional cartooning skills (his artwork looked superior to Robert's best efforts), yet was cursed with severe psychiatric problems which prevented him from entering society as a functional individual. While Robert is a functional member of society, the overall impression the movie gave was that he was somewhat distant from other people, including his kin, and could not pick up easily on the feelings of others. The most poignant example of this was a brief (maybe one minute?) description of his father by Crumb's son from his first wife. Still, it was delightful to see Crumb nurture his children by helping them do artwork of their own. On the surface, Crumb may seem like a unique if peculiar individual: snobbish, detached from the outside world, relishing in dressing in anachronistic clothing and listening to old jazz records. Still, the impression was of a kind-hearted individual who found release through art. I did enjoy the movie's inclusion of those who objected to Crumb's art as blatantly pornographic, though my sense is that Crumb's work does not have the mainstream popularity which would make it troubling to society at large, nor the messages in his illustrations singularly sexual, to classify it as straightforwardly pornographic. A solid effort. I highly recommend this film to those who love documentaries.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know for some time what this film listed in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die was about, so I was very interested when I found out it was a documentary about a famous comic book cartoonist who I had heard about. Robert Crumb is the cartoonist and artist who drew and created popular comics and images such as Fritz the Cat, Mr. Natural and Keep on Truckin', he was the major pioneer for the genesis and popularisation of underground comics. This documentary details his life from developing his talent for drawing and making his own comic books with his two brothers, and of course becoming famous, but we also get an insight into the darker and strange regions of his subconscious mind. Interviews come from Crumb himself, his mother, his two brothers Charles and Maxon who are perhaps more strange than Robert, his then wife Aline Kominsky who knows her husband is unusual and his ex- girlfriends, as well as other artists, art critics and historians, and some admirers. The work of Crumb started from childhood with his love for Disney and various cartoon characters, where he and his brothers would create their own adventure comic books, and growing up he developed his bizarre style which included satire and sexual and perverted imagery. It is interesting to hear his various stories about his creations, his relationships with his brothers, his parents and the women he was with, it is interesting to see how disturbed his brothers are (one committed suicide after the film), and it is interesting to see his works discussed, including the mentioning of killing off Fritz the Cat following the cartoon film which he did not approve. This has many elements to it, it is fascinating, it is artistic, it is strange and it is disturbing, Crumb is obviously a genius with his cartoon style and imagination, but his eccentric personality and family background is the most interesting thing to watch this for, a most worthwhile documentary film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In my top 5 films, ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zee
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always hated R. Crumb's comics, finding them misogynistic and racist and weird and unfunny. In my factory-town hippie youth, the boys who found them funny were boys I avoided. (I never met a girl or black person who did like them, though a few may exist.) So you'd think I might hate this movie, or not want to watch it, or that this review would be negative. But no. I love a good documentary and this is not merely good; it's a great one, directed by film genius Terry Zwigoff. Crumb the movie riveted me, showing me an intricate portrait of a complex man. This is not a short movie, but I was always engaged--great pacing and editing, surprising and revealing choices of scenes. To me what it says about "art" (or craft) is far less important than what it says about this one man. Crumb had a childhood that looks worse than the worst horror film I've ever seen. Bad father, bat**** crazy mother, and three genius boys that I suppose may carry the crazy gene too. As Zwigoff takes us into that bizarre home and the lives of the other brothers, we come to see that R. Crumb's art and life is a triumph of the human spirit, a flower blooming out of burbling sewage. To me, it's not an attractive flower, rather a noisome and homely thing, but dang it, a flower, and I ended up applauding him for doing so well with such beginnings. No matter how crazy your family is, you leave this film thinking, wow, thanks Mom and Dad for not being anywhere near this bad. Your own tiny neuroses will seem charming and mild in comparison to the brothers'. You leave the film with the sense that all things are possible--if Crumb did this with his life despite what you now know, what the heck is holding you back? And if a film can change people, even for a short time, this one has the capacity to make you more understanding of the worst people you meet. What if they had this much baggage? How can you possibly know what made them what they are? Everyone is doing the best s/he can, and while some days that seems like bad news, after watching the film, it feels like good news.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Successful Outlier From A Doomed Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Documentary of the art and life of Robert Crumb, a legendary and controversial cartoonist. It's one of those few pieces of non-fiction cinema that truly portrays a person's mind and describes with great dedication and care the essence of the subject at hand: Crumb is seen as a gentle man with bizarre and manic tendencies, being a sexual deviant, socially awkward, and a women hater (although the latter isn't as obvious) who inevitably distances himself from the rest of the world. When his brothers and his mother are interviewed, we read through the darker, more manic pages of the film: it is clear that obsession(or mental illness, if you want) and strong artistic creativity tragically cohabit within the family. "Crumb", besides reflecting that relationship between art and society that is partly present in modern American culture, is a sort of dedication to the people that by going against it unwillingly fall into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anykind of Artist can learn from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregg Di Lorenzo (gdilorenzo1@optimum.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Primarily: You are in the presence of a master creating and displaying his art, and throughout these portions of the film any kind of artist will find much to learn from this man. The comparison made that he is the "modern" D&uuml;rer is very apt. Secondarily: You are watching one the most humorous and (blackly) entertaining films ever produced anywhere. Yes, we are reassured once again that an (the) artists' personality(ies) cannot never be confused with or substituted for the work they have give us; the strongest humor comes from the aon-old maxim the truth is stranger than fiction... p.s. One last thing - had seen this piece over a decade ago, but a recent review of Crumb's 2009 outstanding "Genesis" work led back here and there to review. If you haven't read it yet do it tonight/day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb came out of the 1960s as the leading underground comic book artist. Sexually explicit material, usually with women drawn with huge buttocks were his signature. Album covers, including Janis Joplin's Big Brother and the Holding Company being the most well known, show a real and unique artist at work. Filmmaker Terry Zwigoff brings his camera into the Crumb family home; can you say dysfunctional? ? The word is not strong enough to describe this modern day Adam's Family. Robert's brother Charles looks like Lerch and despite his agoraphobia is also a creative genius. The Crumb's interactions are a train wreck in the making that you can't take your eyes off of. The brothers are both certifiably insane and yet hugely talented. Crumb is one of the best documentary's ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good and a bit creepy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb has become an icon in the world of underground comic artists, and this documentary takes a close look at his work and the often unhappy life that informed it with an intimacy that is both gratifying and disturbing. Crumb's art and career are celebrated here on film even while his dysfunctional adolescence, his personal insecurities and his sexual obsessions are dissected by family, friends, pop psychologists and other invited crackpots. We see how, by his own understanding, that young Robert Crumb developed his talent as a vehicle to reach out and connect with other people, especially girls, and then had to deal with the frustrations resulting from his failure to achieve success with this. We see how his cartooning style evolved, how certain repeated subjects and motifs found their way into his work. We get a close up view of Robert Crumb that is almost too close up. The film's intimacy with its subject creates an almost claustrophobic feel, especially since Crumb himself is almost painfully awkward and lacking in personal charm, his mother is an ogress, his wife and daughter seem wary and stiff on camera, and his older brother is borderline crazy. Especially interesting is Robert Crumb's brother Charles, who is also a cartoonist and quite talented but clearly mentally unbalanced. His work shows genuine technical polish and is extremely evocative. It is also morbid and obsessive to the point of wallowing in darkness and despair, since its creator is an over-40, out of work dingbat who lives and works in the attic of the Crumb family home. Charles was a key inspiration to the young Robert Crumb, yet he is also an object lesson. With a little less professional drive and career focus, Robert could easily have followed his brother's path in life and art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    darkly fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was never a fan of R. Crumb's work, finding it unpleasant and ugly, but I heard the documentary was good and it certainly is. This is a fascinating portrayal not just of the highly eccentric Crumb but also of his even more off-kilter brothers. They are a very messed up family, so messed up that their upbringing was probably even worse than it is described in the movie. The film works in a number of ways. It does a good job of exploring Crumb's artwork, where it came from and how he approaches it (even though it's mainly about the personal we do see some of his craftsmanship as well. It shows how his comics generate extreme reactions, most notably in the opposing reactions of a pretentious English guy who talks about Crumb as a great artist and a painfully politically correct woman who says he legitimizes horrible fantasies by expressing them. But more than anything, this is a movie that reveals the Crumb's disturbing personalities and dismal lives. Perhaps the most disturbing thing about it is how casually they discuss themselves, laughing boisterously as they talk about their odd sexuality and abusive father. It's a rather downbeat documentary but well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Real Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cinematic portrait of the controversial comic book writer/artist and his traumatized family. Crumb is the perfect subject matter for Terry Zwigoff, who is best known for "Ghost World", an adaptation of a graphic novel. Zwigoff clearly has an interest in independent comics and knows how to present them in a way that makes them interesting and accessible to people. Some of "Ghost World"'s biggest fans have never read a comic book, and I suspect one need not know who Crumb is to appreciate this documentary. His brother Charles lives in a "cloistered environment" of books, which is an interesting sight... he speaks of not yet having read Kant or Hegel, but you can see nearby a copy of a Buddhist book, suggesting that such things may not be beyond his range of interests. What Charles does now is unclear. Presumably nothing. And the other brother, Maxon, is even more bizarre. The constant cynicism is a welcome perspective. He seems happy, but Crumb constantly talks disparagingly of things. His attitude is interesting, and sometimes he suggests a Luddite viewpoint. He also, despite needing money, turned down Saturday Night Live and the Rolling Stones... running from fame. A gallery owner calls him the "Daumier of our time" and the Time art critic says he is the Brueghel for the second half of the 20th century. I suppose being compared to classic art is a compliment, though the fact they are such obscure names may not be complimentary at all... I do not know Daumier or Brueghel's work, so I cannot even say if I like it! If Crumb is not weird enough, just wait until they invite him behind the scenes at a pornographic "Leg Show" photo shoot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure gold, one of the greatest films of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gloede_The_Saint
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm in complete shock. I must admit that when it started off with David Lynch presents I knew I was in for something, but I had no idea what. I cannot believe that anyone would expose their life like this. Robert Crumb is what would be described as a pretty "sick" individual, his family more so. His brothers are talking about suicide attempts, molesting women, etc. Robert Crumb is basically letting you see ever part of his life. We even see him ride around on women's backs, which is apparently one of his favorite things in the whole world. If you are not familiar with him, he is a sort of satirical, sexually obsessed cartoonist, who among other things makes cartoons about his own crazy life. And he is a likable guy. Grim and openly perverted but he does have a personality. He is the amusing outcast who shows the world for what he thinks it is. Director Terry Zwigoff does this almost like a fictional film, of course there are interviews and most of it is conversations between Robert and people who knows him, but sometimes you think of him more as a Woody Allen kind of fictional characters. I is so far from the norm, and so much a character it's hard to believe he's real. The film itself has this weird form of just being. It's a dark comedy, and though it never stops being interesting and you can feel the somewhat morbid comedic atmosphere it's just hard to categorize as a comedy. It's more. It's something true, and something to think about; Though it's pretty impossible to figure out what it is you are supposed to think about. Individuality, society, norms, standards, art, perhaps everything in existence. At it's core you just know this is something special. It's not just the Crumb family quirks and distancing life style, the complete honesty about it and the emotions this brings, it's the look at the artistic work it creates, and maybe vice versa. This film needs to be experienced!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Documentary of Underground Cartoonist and Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Warning! Spoilers ahead! This movie succeeds largely because the documentarian does not inject his bias into the story, nor does he push any sort of agenda. He lets his subjects give their side of the story. He listens to both sides of the argument, whether they approve of what Robert Crumb has done as an artist, or whether he is nothing more than a bizarre pornographer. In all, the neutrality of the movie-maker is this film's best selling point, and I highly recommend this film as one that doesn't beat you over the head with its opinion or message; it lets the subjects do the talking. On the topic of semi-famous underground cartoonist Robert Crumb and his family, the film leaves one with an uneasy feeling at best. Charles, Robert's brother, and his mother reminded me of the recent HBO "Grey Gardens" movie, which itself was based on a documentary. If Robert Crumb can be perceived by some as a stark eccentric who cannot fit in to modern society, at least he has been able to create a stable home life with a loving family of his own. This movie is utterly tragic in its portrayal of Crumb's brothers, Charles and Maxon, especially so since Charles is gifted with exceptional cartooning skills (his artwork looked superior to Robert's best efforts), yet was cursed with severe psychiatric problems which prevented him from entering society as a functional individual. While Robert is a functional member of society, the overall impression the movie gave was that he was somewhat distant from other people, including his kin, and could not pick up easily on the feelings of others. The most poignant example of this was a brief (maybe one minute?) description of his father by Crumb's son from his first wife. Still, it was delightful to see Crumb nurture his children by helping them do artwork of their own. On the surface, Crumb may seem like a unique if peculiar individual: snobbish, detached from the outside world, relishing in dressing in anachronistic clothing and listening to old jazz records. Still, the impression was of a kind-hearted individual who found release through art. I did enjoy the movie's inclusion of those who objected to Crumb's art as blatantly pornographic, though my sense is that Crumb's work does not have the mainstream popularity which would make it troubling to society at large, nor the messages in his illustrations singularly sexual, to classify it as straightforwardly pornographic. A solid effort. I highly recommend this film to those who love documentaries.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know for some time what this film listed in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die was about, so I was very interested when I found out it was a documentary about a famous comic book cartoonist who I had heard about. Robert Crumb is the cartoonist and artist who drew and created popular comics and images such as Fritz the Cat, Mr. Natural and Keep on Truckin', he was the major pioneer for the genesis and popularisation of underground comics. This documentary details his life from developing his talent for drawing and making his own comic books with his two brothers, and of course becoming famous, but we also get an insight into the darker and strange regions of his subconscious mind. Interviews come from Crumb himself, his mother, his two brothers Charles and Maxon who are perhaps more strange than Robert, his then wife Aline Kominsky who knows her husband is unusual and his ex- girlfriends, as well as other artists, art critics and historians, and some admirers. The work of Crumb started from childhood with his love for Disney and various cartoon characters, where he and his brothers would create their own adventure comic books, and growing up he developed his bizarre style which included satire and sexual and perverted imagery. It is interesting to hear his various stories about his creations, his relationships with his brothers, his parents and the women he was with, it is interesting to see how disturbed his brothers are (one committed suicide after the film), and it is interesting to see his works discussed, including the mentioning of killing off Fritz the Cat following the cartoon film which he did not approve. This has many elements to it, it is fascinating, it is artistic, it is strange and it is disturbing, Crumb is obviously a genius with his cartoon style and imagination, but his eccentric personality and family background is the most interesting thing to watch this for, a most worthwhile documentary film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In my top 5 films, ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zee
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always hated R. Crumb's comics, finding them misogynistic and racist and weird and unfunny. In my factory-town hippie youth, the boys who found them funny were boys I avoided. (I never met a girl or black person who did like them, though a few may exist.) So you'd think I might hate this movie, or not want to watch it, or that this review would be negative. But no. I love a good documentary and this is not merely good; it's a great one, directed by film genius Terry Zwigoff. Crumb the movie riveted me, showing me an intricate portrait of a complex man. This is not a short movie, but I was always engaged--great pacing and editing, surprising and revealing choices of scenes. To me what it says about "art" (or craft) is far less important than what it says about this one man. Crumb had a childhood that looks worse than the worst horror film I've ever seen. Bad father, bat**** crazy mother, and three genius boys that I suppose may carry the crazy gene too. As Zwigoff takes us into that bizarre home and the lives of the other brothers, we come to see that R. Crumb's art and life is a triumph of the human spirit, a flower blooming out of burbling sewage. To me, it's not an attractive flower, rather a noisome and homely thing, but dang it, a flower, and I ended up applauding him for doing so well with such beginnings. No matter how crazy your family is, you leave this film thinking, wow, thanks Mom and Dad for not being anywhere near this bad. Your own tiny neuroses will seem charming and mild in comparison to the brothers'. You leave the film with the sense that all things are possible--if Crumb did this with his life despite what you now know, what the heck is holding you back? And if a film can change people, even for a short time, this one has the capacity to make you more understanding of the worst people you meet. What if they had this much baggage? How can you possibly know what made them what they are? Everyone is doing the best s/he can, and while some days that seems like bad news, after watching the film, it feels like good news.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Successful Outlier From A Doomed Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Documentary of the art and life of Robert Crumb, a legendary and controversial cartoonist. It's one of those few pieces of non-fiction cinema that truly portrays a person's mind and describes with great dedication and care the essence of the subject at hand: Crumb is seen as a gentle man with bizarre and manic tendencies, being a sexual deviant, socially awkward, and a women hater (although the latter isn't as obvious) who inevitably distances himself from the rest of the world. When his brothers and his mother are interviewed, we read through the darker, more manic pages of the film: it is clear that obsession(or mental illness, if you want) and strong artistic creativity tragically cohabit within the family. "Crumb", besides reflecting that relationship between art and society that is partly present in modern American culture, is a sort of dedication to the people that by going against it unwillingly fall into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anykind of Artist can learn from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregg Di Lorenzo (gdilorenzo1@optimum.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Primarily: You are in the presence of a master creating and displaying his art, and throughout these portions of the film any kind of artist will find much to learn from this man. The comparison made that he is the "modern" D&uuml;rer is very apt. Secondarily: You are watching one the most humorous and (blackly) entertaining films ever produced anywhere. Yes, we are reassured once again that an (the) artists' personality(ies) cannot never be confused with or substituted for the work they have give us; the strongest humor comes from the aon-old maxim the truth is stranger than fiction... p.s. One last thing - had seen this piece over a decade ago, but a recent review of Crumb's 2009 outstanding "Genesis" work led back here and there to review. If you haven't read it yet do it tonight/day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb came out of the 1960s as the leading underground comic book artist. Sexually explicit material, usually with women drawn with huge buttocks were his signature. Album covers, including Janis Joplin's Big Brother and the Holding Company being the most well known, show a real and unique artist at work. Filmmaker Terry Zwigoff brings his camera into the Crumb family home; can you say dysfunctional? ? The word is not strong enough to describe this modern day Adam's Family. Robert's brother Charles looks like Lerch and despite his agoraphobia is also a creative genius. The Crumb's interactions are a train wreck in the making that you can't take your eyes off of. The brothers are both certifiably insane and yet hugely talented. Crumb is one of the best documentary's ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good and a bit creepy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb has become an icon in the world of underground comic artists, and this documentary takes a close look at his work and the often unhappy life that informed it with an intimacy that is both gratifying and disturbing. Crumb's art and career are celebrated here on film even while his dysfunctional adolescence, his personal insecurities and his sexual obsessions are dissected by family, friends, pop psychologists and other invited crackpots. We see how, by his own understanding, that young Robert Crumb developed his talent as a vehicle to reach out and connect with other people, especially girls, and then had to deal with the frustrations resulting from his failure to achieve success with this. We see how his cartooning style evolved, how certain repeated subjects and motifs found their way into his work. We get a close up view of Robert Crumb that is almost too close up. The film's intimacy with its subject creates an almost claustrophobic feel, especially since Crumb himself is almost painfully awkward and lacking in personal charm, his mother is an ogress, his wife and daughter seem wary and stiff on camera, and his older brother is borderline crazy. Especially interesting is Robert Crumb's brother Charles, who is also a cartoonist and quite talented but clearly mentally unbalanced. His work shows genuine technical polish and is extremely evocative. It is also morbid and obsessive to the point of wallowing in darkness and despair, since its creator is an over-40, out of work dingbat who lives and works in the attic of the Crumb family home. Charles was a key inspiration to the young Robert Crumb, yet he is also an object lesson. With a little less professional drive and career focus, Robert could easily have followed his brother's path in life and art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    darkly fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was never a fan of R. Crumb's work, finding it unpleasant and ugly, but I heard the documentary was good and it certainly is. This is a fascinating portrayal not just of the highly eccentric Crumb but also of his even more off-kilter brothers. They are a very messed up family, so messed up that their upbringing was probably even worse than it is described in the movie. The film works in a number of ways. It does a good job of exploring Crumb's artwork, where it came from and how he approaches it (even though it's mainly about the personal we do see some of his craftsmanship as well. It shows how his comics generate extreme reactions, most notably in the opposing reactions of a pretentious English guy who talks about Crumb as a great artist and a painfully politically correct woman who says he legitimizes horrible fantasies by expressing them. But more than anything, this is a movie that reveals the Crumb's disturbing personalities and dismal lives. Perhaps the most disturbing thing about it is how casually they discuss themselves, laughing boisterously as they talk about their odd sexuality and abusive father. It's a rather downbeat documentary but well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Real Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cinematic portrait of the controversial comic book writer/artist and his traumatized family. Crumb is the perfect subject matter for Terry Zwigoff, who is best known for "Ghost World", an adaptation of a graphic novel. Zwigoff clearly has an interest in independent comics and knows how to present them in a way that makes them interesting and accessible to people. Some of "Ghost World"'s biggest fans have never read a comic book, and I suspect one need not know who Crumb is to appreciate this documentary. His brother Charles lives in a "cloistered environment" of books, which is an interesting sight... he speaks of not yet having read Kant or Hegel, but you can see nearby a copy of a Buddhist book, suggesting that such things may not be beyond his range of interests. What Charles does now is unclear. Presumably nothing. And the other brother, Maxon, is even more bizarre. The constant cynicism is a welcome perspective. He seems happy, but Crumb constantly talks disparagingly of things. His attitude is interesting, and sometimes he suggests a Luddite viewpoint. He also, despite needing money, turned down Saturday Night Live and the Rolling Stones... running from fame. A gallery owner calls him the "Daumier of our time" and the Time art critic says he is the Brueghel for the second half of the 20th century. I suppose being compared to classic art is a compliment, though the fact they are such obscure names may not be complimentary at all... I do not know Daumier or Brueghel's work, so I cannot even say if I like it! If Crumb is not weird enough, just wait until they invite him behind the scenes at a pornographic "Leg Show" photo shoot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure gold, one of the greatest films of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gloede_The_Saint
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm in complete shock. I must admit that when it started off with David Lynch presents I knew I was in for something, but I had no idea what. I cannot believe that anyone would expose their life like this. Robert Crumb is what would be described as a pretty "sick" individual, his family more so. His brothers are talking about suicide attempts, molesting women, etc. Robert Crumb is basically letting you see ever part of his life. We even see him ride around on women's backs, which is apparently one of his favorite things in the whole world. If you are not familiar with him, he is a sort of satirical, sexually obsessed cartoonist, who among other things makes cartoons about his own crazy life. And he is a likable guy. Grim and openly perverted but he does have a personality. He is the amusing outcast who shows the world for what he thinks it is. Director Terry Zwigoff does this almost like a fictional film, of course there are interviews and most of it is conversations between Robert and people who knows him, but sometimes you think of him more as a Woody Allen kind of fictional characters. I is so far from the norm, and so much a character it's hard to believe he's real. The film itself has this weird form of just being. It's a dark comedy, and though it never stops being interesting and you can feel the somewhat morbid comedic atmosphere it's just hard to categorize as a comedy. It's more. It's something true, and something to think about; Though it's pretty impossible to figure out what it is you are supposed to think about. Individuality, society, norms, standards, art, perhaps everything in existence. At it's core you just know this is something special. It's not just the Crumb family quirks and distancing life style, the complete honesty about it and the emotions this brings, it's the look at the artistic work it creates, and maybe vice versa. This film needs to be experienced!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Documentary of Underground Cartoonist and Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Warning! Spoilers ahead! This movie succeeds largely because the documentarian does not inject his bias into the story, nor does he push any sort of agenda. He lets his subjects give their side of the story. He listens to both sides of the argument, whether they approve of what Robert Crumb has done as an artist, or whether he is nothing more than a bizarre pornographer. In all, the neutrality of the movie-maker is this film's best selling point, and I highly recommend this film as one that doesn't beat you over the head with its opinion or message; it lets the subjects do the talking. On the topic of semi-famous underground cartoonist Robert Crumb and his family, the film leaves one with an uneasy feeling at best. Charles, Robert's brother, and his mother reminded me of the recent HBO "Grey Gardens" movie, which itself was based on a documentary. If Robert Crumb can be perceived by some as a stark eccentric who cannot fit in to modern society, at least he has been able to create a stable home life with a loving family of his own. This movie is utterly tragic in its portrayal of Crumb's brothers, Charles and Maxon, especially so since Charles is gifted with exceptional cartooning skills (his artwork looked superior to Robert's best efforts), yet was cursed with severe psychiatric problems which prevented him from entering society as a functional individual. While Robert is a functional member of society, the overall impression the movie gave was that he was somewhat distant from other people, including his kin, and could not pick up easily on the feelings of others. The most poignant example of this was a brief (maybe one minute?) description of his father by Crumb's son from his first wife. Still, it was delightful to see Crumb nurture his children by helping them do artwork of their own. On the surface, Crumb may seem like a unique if peculiar individual: snobbish, detached from the outside world, relishing in dressing in anachronistic clothing and listening to old jazz records. Still, the impression was of a kind-hearted individual who found release through art. I did enjoy the movie's inclusion of those who objected to Crumb's art as blatantly pornographic, though my sense is that Crumb's work does not have the mainstream popularity which would make it troubling to society at large, nor the messages in his illustrations singularly sexual, to classify it as straightforwardly pornographic. A solid effort. I highly recommend this film to those who love documentaries.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know for some time what this film listed in the book 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die was about, so I was very interested when I found out it was a documentary about a famous comic book cartoonist who I had heard about. Robert Crumb is the cartoonist and artist who drew and created popular comics and images such as Fritz the Cat, Mr. Natural and Keep on Truckin', he was the major pioneer for the genesis and popularisation of underground comics. This documentary details his life from developing his talent for drawing and making his own comic books with his two brothers, and of course becoming famous, but we also get an insight into the darker and strange regions of his subconscious mind. Interviews come from Crumb himself, his mother, his two brothers Charles and Maxon who are perhaps more strange than Robert, his then wife Aline Kominsky who knows her husband is unusual and his ex- girlfriends, as well as other artists, art critics and historians, and some admirers. The work of Crumb started from childhood with his love for Disney and various cartoon characters, where he and his brothers would create their own adventure comic books, and growing up he developed his bizarre style which included satire and sexual and perverted imagery. It is interesting to hear his various stories about his creations, his relationships with his brothers, his parents and the women he was with, it is interesting to see how disturbed his brothers are (one committed suicide after the film), and it is interesting to see his works discussed, including the mentioning of killing off Fritz the Cat following the cartoon film which he did not approve. This has many elements to it, it is fascinating, it is artistic, it is strange and it is disturbing, Crumb is obviously a genius with his cartoon style and imagination, but his eccentric personality and family background is the most interesting thing to watch this for, a most worthwhile documentary film. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In my top 5 films, ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zee
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always hated R. Crumb's comics, finding them misogynistic and racist and weird and unfunny. In my factory-town hippie youth, the boys who found them funny were boys I avoided. (I never met a girl or black person who did like them, though a few may exist.) So you'd think I might hate this movie, or not want to watch it, or that this review would be negative. But no. I love a good documentary and this is not merely good; it's a great one, directed by film genius Terry Zwigoff. Crumb the movie riveted me, showing me an intricate portrait of a complex man. This is not a short movie, but I was always engaged--great pacing and editing, surprising and revealing choices of scenes. To me what it says about "art" (or craft) is far less important than what it says about this one man. Crumb had a childhood that looks worse than the worst horror film I've ever seen. Bad father, bat**** crazy mother, and three genius boys that I suppose may carry the crazy gene too. As Zwigoff takes us into that bizarre home and the lives of the other brothers, we come to see that R. Crumb's art and life is a triumph of the human spirit, a flower blooming out of burbling sewage. To me, it's not an attractive flower, rather a noisome and homely thing, but dang it, a flower, and I ended up applauding him for doing so well with such beginnings. No matter how crazy your family is, you leave this film thinking, wow, thanks Mom and Dad for not being anywhere near this bad. Your own tiny neuroses will seem charming and mild in comparison to the brothers'. You leave the film with the sense that all things are possible--if Crumb did this with his life despite what you now know, what the heck is holding you back? And if a film can change people, even for a short time, this one has the capacity to make you more understanding of the worst people you meet. What if they had this much baggage? How can you possibly know what made them what they are? Everyone is doing the best s/he can, and while some days that seems like bad news, after watching the film, it feels like good news.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Successful Outlier From A Doomed Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Documentary of the art and life of Robert Crumb, a legendary and controversial cartoonist. It's one of those few pieces of non-fiction cinema that truly portrays a person's mind and describes with great dedication and care the essence of the subject at hand: Crumb is seen as a gentle man with bizarre and manic tendencies, being a sexual deviant, socially awkward, and a women hater (although the latter isn't as obvious) who inevitably distances himself from the rest of the world. When his brothers and his mother are interviewed, we read through the darker, more manic pages of the film: it is clear that obsession(or mental illness, if you want) and strong artistic creativity tragically cohabit within the family. "Crumb", besides reflecting that relationship between art and society that is partly present in modern American culture, is a sort of dedication to the people that by going against it unwillingly fall into it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anykind of Artist can learn from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregg Di Lorenzo (gdilorenzo1@optimum.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Primarily: You are in the presence of a master creating and displaying his art, and throughout these portions of the film any kind of artist will find much to learn from this man. The comparison made that he is the "modern" D&uuml;rer is very apt. Secondarily: You are watching one the most humorous and (blackly) entertaining films ever produced anywhere. Yes, we are reassured once again that an (the) artists' personality(ies) cannot never be confused with or substituted for the work they have give us; the strongest humor comes from the aon-old maxim the truth is stranger than fiction... p.s. One last thing - had seen this piece over a decade ago, but a recent review of Crumb's 2009 outstanding "Genesis" work led back here and there to review. If you haven't read it yet do it tonight/day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb came out of the 1960s as the leading underground comic book artist. Sexually explicit material, usually with women drawn with huge buttocks were his signature. Album covers, including Janis Joplin's Big Brother and the Holding Company being the most well known, show a real and unique artist at work. Filmmaker Terry Zwigoff brings his camera into the Crumb family home; can you say dysfunctional? ? The word is not strong enough to describe this modern day Adam's Family. Robert's brother Charles looks like Lerch and despite his agoraphobia is also a creative genius. The Crumb's interactions are a train wreck in the making that you can't take your eyes off of. The brothers are both certifiably insane and yet hugely talented. Crumb is one of the best documentary's ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good and a bit creepy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Crumb has become an icon in the world of underground comic artists, and this documentary takes a close look at his work and the often unhappy life that informed it with an intimacy that is both gratifying and disturbing. Crumb's art and career are celebrated here on film even while his dysfunctional adolescence, his personal insecurities and his sexual obsessions are dissected by family, friends, pop psychologists and other invited crackpots. We see how, by his own understanding, that young Robert Crumb developed his talent as a vehicle to reach out and connect with other people, especially girls, and then had to deal with the frustrations resulting from his failure to achieve success with this. We see how his cartooning style evolved, how certain repeated subjects and motifs found their way into his work. We get a close up view of Robert Crumb that is almost too close up. The film's intimacy with its subject creates an almost claustrophobic feel, especially since Crumb himself is almost painfully awkward and lacking in personal charm, his mother is an ogress, his wife and daughter seem wary and stiff on camera, and his older brother is borderline crazy. Especially interesting is Robert Crumb's brother Charles, who is also a cartoonist and quite talented but clearly mentally unbalanced. His work shows genuine technical polish and is extremely evocative. It is also morbid and obsessive to the point of wallowing in darkness and despair, since its creator is an over-40, out of work dingbat who lives and works in the attic of the Crumb family home. Charles was a key inspiration to the young Robert Crumb, yet he is also an object lesson. With a little less professional drive and career focus, Robert could easily have followed his brother's path in life and art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    darkly fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was never a fan of R. Crumb's work, finding it unpleasant and ugly, but I heard the documentary was good and it certainly is. This is a fascinating portrayal not just of the highly eccentric Crumb but also of his even more off-kilter brothers. They are a very messed up family, so messed up that their upbringing was probably even worse than it is described in the movie. The film works in a number of ways. It does a good job of exploring Crumb's artwork, where it came from and how he approaches it (even though it's mainly about the personal we do see some of his craftsmanship as well. It shows how his comics generate extreme reactions, most notably in the opposing reactions of a pretentious English guy who talks about Crumb as a great artist and a painfully politically correct woman who says he legitimizes horrible fantasies by expressing them. But more than anything, this is a movie that reveals the Crumb's disturbing personalities and dismal lives. Perhaps the most disturbing thing about it is how casually they discuss themselves, laughing boisterously as they talk about their odd sexuality and abusive father. It's a rather downbeat documentary but well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Real Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A cinematic portrait of the controversial comic book writer/artist and his traumatized family. Crumb is the perfect subject matter for Terry Zwigoff, who is best known for "Ghost World", an adaptation of a graphic novel. Zwigoff clearly has an interest in independent comics and knows how to present them in a way that makes them interesting and accessible to people. Some of "Ghost World"'s biggest fans have never read a comic book, and I suspect one need not know who Crumb is to appreciate this documentary. His brother Charles lives in a "cloistered environment" of books, which is an interesting sight... he speaks of not yet having read Kant or Hegel, but you can see nearby a copy of a Buddhist book, suggesting that such things may not be beyond his range of interests. What Charles does now is unclear. Presumably nothing. And the other brother, Maxon, is even more bizarre. The constant cynicism is a welcome perspective. He seems happy, but Crumb constantly talks disparagingly of things. His attitude is interesting, and sometimes he suggests a Luddite viewpoint. He also, despite needing money, turned down Saturday Night Live and the Rolling Stones... running from fame. A gallery owner calls him the "Daumier of our time" and the Time art critic says he is the Brueghel for the second half of the 20th century. I suppose being compared to classic art is a compliment, though the fact they are such obscure names may not be complimentary at all... I do not know Daumier or Brueghel's work, so I cannot even say if I like it! If Crumb is not weird enough, just wait until they invite him behind the scenes at a pornographic "Leg Show" photo shoot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure gold, one of the greatest films of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gloede_The_Saint
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm in complete shock. I must admit that when it started off with David Lynch presents I knew I was in for something, but I had no idea what. I cannot believe that anyone would expose their life like this. Robert Crumb is what would be described as a pretty "sick" individual, his family more so. His brothers are talking about suicide attempts, molesting women, etc. Robert Crumb is basically letting you see ever part of his life. We even see him ride around on women's backs, which is apparently one of his favorite things in the whole world. If you are not familiar with him, he is a sort of satirical, sexually obsessed cartoonist, who among other things makes cartoons about his own crazy life. And he is a likable guy. Grim and openly perverted but he does have a personality. He is the amusing outcast who shows the world for what he thinks it is. Director Terry Zwigoff does this almost like a fictional film, of course there are interviews and most of it is conversations between Robert and people who knows him, but sometimes you think of him more as a Woody Allen kind of fictional characters. I is so far from the norm, and so much a character it's hard to believe he's real. The film itself has this weird form of just being. It's a dark comedy, and though it never stops being interesting and you can feel the somewhat morbid comedic atmosphere it's just hard to categorize as a comedy. It's more. It's something true, and something to think about; Though it's pretty impossible to figure out what it is you are supposed to think about. Individuality, society, norms, standards, art, perhaps everything in existence. At it's core you just know this is something special. It's not just the Crumb family quirks and distancing life style, the complete honesty about it and the emotions this brings, it's the look at the artistic work it creates, and maybe vice versa. This film needs to be experienced!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Documentary of Underground Cartoonist and Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Warning! Spoilers ahead! This movie succeeds largely because the documentarian does not inject his bias into the story, nor does he push any sort of agenda. He lets his subjects give their side of the story. He listens to both sides of the argument, whether they approve of what Robert Crumb has done as an artist, or whether he is nothing more than a bizarre pornographer. In all, the neutrality of the movie-maker is this film's best selling point, and I highly recommend this film as one that doesn't beat you over the head with its opinion or message; it lets the subjects do the talking. On the topic of semi-famous underground cartoonist Robert Crumb and his family, the film leaves one with an uneasy feeling at best. Charles, Robert's brother, and his mother reminded me of the recent HBO "Grey Gardens" movie, which itself was based on a documentary. If Robert Crumb can be perceived by some as a stark eccentric who cannot fit in to modern society, at least he has been able to create a stable home life with a loving family of his own. This movie is utterly tragic in its portrayal of Crumb's brothers, Charles and Maxon, especially so since Charles is gifted with exceptional cartooning skills (his artwork looked superior to Robert's best efforts), yet was cursed with severe psychiatric problems which prevented him from entering society as a functional individual. While Robert is a functional member of society, the overall impression the movie gave was that he was somewhat distant from other people, including his kin, and could not pick up easily on the feelings of others. The most poignant example of this was a brief (maybe one minute?) description of his father by Crumb's son from his first wife. Still, it was delightful to see Crumb nurture his children by helping them do artwork of their own. On the surface, Crumb may seem like a unique if peculiar individual: snobbish, detached from the outside world, relishing in dressing in anachronistic clothing and listening to old jazz records. Still, the impression was of a kind-hearted individual who found release through art. I did enjoy the movie's inclusion of those who objected to Crumb's art as blatantly pornographic, though my sense is that Crumb's work does not have the mainstream popularity which would make it troubling to society at large, nor the messages in his illustrations singularly sexual, to classify it as straightforwardly pornographic. A solid effort. I highly recommend this film to those who love documentaries.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
