<filme>
 <id>
  325
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115964
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Crash - Estranhos Prazeres
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  After getting into a serious car accident, a TV director discovers an underground sub-culture of scarred, omnisexual car-crash victims who use car accidents and the raw sexual energy they produce to try to rejuvenate his sex life with his wife.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Since a road accident left him with serious facial and bodily scarring, a former TV scientist has become obsessed by the marriage of motor-car technology with what he sees as the raw sexuality of car-crash victims. The scientist, along with a crash victim he has recently befriended, sets about performing a series of sexual acts in a variety of motor vehicles, either with other crash victims or with prostitutes whom they contort into the shape of trapped corpses. Ultimately, the scientist craves a suicidal union of blood, semen, and engine coolant, a union with which he becomes dangerously obsessed.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   car
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   car accident
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   car crash
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sex
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   semen
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   David Cronenberg
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   J.G. Ballard
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   David Cronenberg
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   James Spader
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Holly Hunter
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Elias Koteas
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trash! For perverts only (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the movie already sucked abusively my time by watching it, i won't give it much for my review. In short, this movie belongs to my black list of useless, pretentious, stupid movies that try to depict the worst depravities as an interest for art (as "Blow", "Irreversible"). What's worst is that, as usual, the addition of big names (here, Cronenberg, Holly Hunter) tries hypocritically to give respectability and the movie establishment gives dumbly prizes to such crap! There's only one truth to remember: there's nothing romantic or light about licentiousness: those people are cruel and dehumanized!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nihlistic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a novel by J.G. Ballad Crash was a highly controversial film when it was first released when it was released in 1996 for its depiction of sex and violence. Whilst it is controversial for a few scenes, its actual problem is that it a bad film. Director David Cronenberg has made so excellent films in many different genres, but Crash is a very shallow, nihilistic film about nothing. There are many problems with the film, it has the visual look and style of a TV film, characters with not much characterisation, people speaking in quiet tones and James Spader was a bland lead. Despite the film's attempts to have a said about the changing nature of sexuality in the world of technology, a look at subcultures, how people enjoy danger and thrills and sexual fetishes. But on the whole Crash is a film that has nothing to say about its subject matter and this is Cronenberg at his worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange, Stylish, Fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the great qualities of this film is the ability to constantly astonish with its relentless, shocking strangeness. "Crash" is most likely to leave viewers speechless, even those who are used to "weird" or unconventional. None of the scenes are gratuitous however, and "Crash" looks extremely stylish, as well as twisted enough to make one uneasy. Fortunately, this isn't 'cheap shocks' and the usual exploitation fare filmmakers throw in to stir some "controversy". Perverted addicts leading corrupt lives never been more fascinating. These people are craving some basic fulfillment, but are doomed to never achieve it in life. Metaphysical allegory? Probably. It's also a cold analysis of self-destructive compulsion. What's offensive is that these characters never even stop to consider the moral implications of their actions - hurting others who don't share their "hobby". Even if they did, it wouldn't make much of a difference, because they simply can't stop. Like Lynch, Cronenberg doesn't spoon-feed the "message" to the audience, so there are no answers, only uncomfortable but equally valid questions. I guess it takes guts to ask them. Dialogue is minimal and clever, and keeps the characters sealed. The narrative is filled with long pauses, eerie metallic riffs, empty glances directed inwards. Physical encounters are depersonalized and compulsive. There are always people around at the scene of sexual encounters or car crashes, and yet nobody bothers to notice or intervene. It's a surreal landscape of urban alienation that associates with voyeurism. Steel-cold (the unsettling score hits the right note as well), clinical in its depictions, "Crash" has a clean sharp edge that only a handful of directors could walk on with such elegance, insight and a sort of detachment that has a dream-like quality. All the actors are fearless and did a splendid job, especially James Spader, who is great as usual. He was born to play this role, with his other-worldly, strangely absent stare and androgynous beauty (It's surprising David Lynch never worked with him!). Spader's surreal performance is mind-blowing, as he gracefully carries along that creepy Cronenberg vibe. This is the same Spader who stole the show as the intriguing voyeur in "Sex, Lies and Videotape" and who would later do it again in the offbeat "Secretary". His other roles just didn't do justice to him. Likewise, Deborah Unger manages to turn into an abstraction, whispering her lines, floating in the same trance of addiction. The sexual scenes are elegantly choreographed. It's bizarre, disturbing and at times funny altogether, with a pretty sick sense of humor that's absolutely fantastic to a minority of people who can appreciate it. "Crash" explores sexual compulsion in a sterile environment, you can almost taste the metal. This is Cronenberg's best work and one of the most fascinating, audacious films ever made. Clearly not for everybody, but for those who enjoy the Absurd in all its complexity. Unforgettable cult classic to be watched in the uncut version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely for Anyone...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crash is a erotic drama by David Cronnenberg that explores a group of people that get sexually aroused by car crashes. It's probably the least accessible film Cronnenberg has made to date due to it's extreme amounts of fairly explicit sex, weird sexual fetishes and very muddled script. The cast does a wonderful job with the very limited material given. We have James Spader, Elias Koteas, Holly Hunter, Deborah Kara Unger and Rosanna Arquette to name a few. It's a nice thing that those actors showed some guts for doing this borderline softcore sex film. The NC-17 rating is very baffling to me. It's about as explicit in it's sexual content as 70's Japanese exploitation films like Sex and Fury or Female Prisoner Scorpion. It's hardly pornographic or even that extreme in terms of it's sexual fetishes so the NC-17 rating is pretty much an overkill. Crash doesn't have a real plot to speak of and most of the scenes start or end up with people having sex or grabbing each others crotches. It's all about the characters and the situations they go through but the muddled script doesn't really help that. Crash is mostly all surface and has very little depth to be had aside from the sex and the bizarre dialog. So either you will like this film and what it has to offer or you will despise it and just dismiss it as porn. I can't really recommend seeing Crash, unless you are very interested in the work of David Cronnenberg. So unless you are looking for some strange films about sexual fetishes and James Spader, your not going to enjoy this film as conventional entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Distant and detached - if HAL3000 made a movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Crash" remains Cronenberg's most controversial movies. Permeating with sex and obscenity, coupled with obsessions of both bodily and mechanical nature, it was born on shock factor. Film producer James Ballard (James Spader) and his promiscuous wife Catherine (the voluptuous Deborah Kara Unger) lead a life of mutually accepted sexual ventures, searching for ultimate satisfaction by indulging into various affairs. A car accident featuring Helen Remington (Holly Hunter) introduces another level of compulsive sexual mania - where sexual desires and metal mesh together to form a hybrid of death, car crashes and orgiastic pleasure. This introduces both James and Catherine to the Vaughan (Elias Koteas) and their common spiralling search for fulfilment, where boundaries are pushed further and further, while sperm leaks by the gallons... A story less about the addiction to sex or dangerous driving, but more about the growing infatuation with the mechanical, as it slowly overrides bodily desires to entail technoorganic fulfilment. As a car becomes a subject of desire, craving and our bodies seem to merge with its leather seats and metallic odour, Cronenberg shows a new phase of humanity. One devoid of emotion, cold and ever expanding, as desire becomes limitless to the death. Taking the issue of automotive obsession to the extreme "Crash" manages to pack an uneasy wallop, one however that is overlong and for half its running time directionless. Once the premise is clear characters indulge into sexual deviance to sexual deviance with each passing scene pushing themselves further, when the previously passed boundary no longer satisfies the growing need. Although the gist is evident the tirade of weird sex and masturbation becomes tiring and fails to add any further layers to the story. It is hard to blame Cronenberg, as the execution fits the story. Bleak, detached from emotion, jaded and monotonous fulfils the goal of presenting the lingering disconnect of characters, which are so lost in lack of feeling, whilst trying to discover fulfilment. Especially apparent when Ballard and Catherine have sex - physical pleasure is achieved, but emotional fulfilment is non-achievable. Therefore the search for emotion (one induced by the adrenaline rush of a crash) triggers a longing for more of this natural drug, but at the same time increasing the level required for satisfaction. This self-destructive behaviour is so natural, so human, but achieved through such dehumanised means... A tough piece of fiction, which is hard fought to be called pleasant, but definitely a shocking piece worthy of reflection and afterthought, not necessarily admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The quest for happiness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyma_Rizwaan_Khan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been noticing a lot of people watch Gus Van Sant or Cronenberg and they use the words 'pretentious' and 'hack'. I suppose the effect a piece of art has on you also says something about you as a person. The more disturbing art is the more you hear people discussing it - more and more people asking other people not to watch this because it is 'sick and twisted and disgusting'. But I for one, am pretty sure there is nothing pretentious about this movie. Hacks don't make movies like CRASH which barely receive any mainstream attention - they release movies like TWILIGHT and sit back and watch the money roll in. The movie is about a bunch of people trying to find the ultimate pleasure - and what is more pleasurable than a climax right? They have everything they need - good bodies, cars, jobs, good looking people around them and all the things people think are necessary and yet they find themselves feeling empty. All of a sudden, they end up becoming obsessed with car crashes and victims of car crashes. They feel like this is the way to get what they are lacking. But no matter how far, how sinister - how truly invigorating their experiences are, they cannot find happiness. That's what this movie is about - the quest for happiness - for that feeling of knowing joy of some kind. And whether or not it is possible to find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pontifikator
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people. Their sexual turn-on is car wrecks, and they cause them when they can't find them by chance. This movie, directed by David Cronenberg, is based on a novel by J. G. Ballard. This is a disturbing film. The sex scenes approach soft core porn, as the characters paw and grope each other, and there is rampant fetishism as well. However, I was unable to care about the characters. Casting James Spader as the lead guarantees a performance of flat affect. This sometimes works (as in "sex, lies, and videotape," when he plays a weird voyeur), but when he is the main character and I can't begin to like him or feel sympathy for him, it wrecks the movie for me. The problem with the film from my point of view is that I'm never given any reason to identify with these people and to care about their drive for this particular form of fetishism. I suspect the sex aspect of the film was too difficult for the director and/or the actors (including Holly Hunter, Elias Koteas, and Deborah Kara Unger) for them to develop their roles fully. Instead of some fascinating insight into a world I'd never heard of, I saw moments of soft core sex interspersed with dialog from affectless characters about whom I learned nothing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty dreary, but also undeniably fascinating.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer / producer / director David Cronenberg's grim adaptation of the J.G. Ballard novel tells the story of James Ballard (James Spader), who gets into a horrible car accident that actually has a stunning effect on his life, in particular his sex life. He and wife Catherine (Deborah Kara Unger) find themselves now inexorably drawn to the violence and destruction of car crashes and even the effect that such crashes have on the human body. They soon discover an underground group of people that celebrate this creepy fetish, led by the intense Vaughan (Elias Koteas), who with the help of stuntman friends recreates famous crashes involving celebrities (such as James Dean). Cronenberg is obviously a perfect choice to direct this sort of story, which obviously is not going to appeal to a lot of people but may very well intrigue some. It never gets too far into the heads of its characters, but doesn't really judge them, either, and illustrates how these individuals obsess over creating some sort of meaning in their lives and how human beings can attach a sexual element to just about anything. The weather in this Toronto-shot film is appropriately gloomy, matching the mood of the story telling, while the blood and gore is actually never overdone. Really, Cronenberg keeps the focus on the sexual nature of the story and characters and with the help of his very willing performers creates some very erotic scenes, of both the heterosexual and homosexual variety. There's some caressing of vehicle damage to go with the caressing of human bodies. The deeply committed cast, also including Holly Hunter and Rosanna Arquette, helps to draw you into this tale, while Howard Shore supplies a music score in his typical grandiose, full-of-foreboding style. Koteas is a standout as Vaughan. The film isn't perfect overall, as has already been mentioned, but it may keep some viewers watching due to the sexual frankness and explicitness on display. (This is available in both a 90 minute long R rated version and a 100 minute long NC-17 rated version.) Still, even with its flaws it leaves a fairly big impression; it's not likely it'll be easily forgotten. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The one thing Cronenberg has always unquestionably been talented at is weaving a highly disturbing atmosphere, and he does that beautifully on Crash. Unfortunately, though, the movie doesn't quite manage to draw the viewer into that atmosphere. It's meant as a metaphor for mankind's obsessions and perversions, but the horror is being piled on so thickly that I never once found myself immersed in any of the characters or caring about what happens to them, other than loathing them. James Spader is as fantastic as ever in exploring the depth of human perversion, and as always he manages a delicate balance of naive and sleazy, but he did better in subtler works like Secretary and Sex, Lies & Videotape.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Cronenberg must have been insane or under severe medication to write, produce and direct Crash, which is one of the worst movies that I have ever seen. It opens at an airplane hangar where James Spader character is grinding against his wife in a brief encounter, and within seconds is doing the nasty with an Asian woman in a camera room at a film set. Shortly afterwords, he is driving down the road and crashes head on into another car. A man goes through the windshield, but his wife, played by Holly Hunter is bloodied, and she is shown in the passenger seat without a bra, and her breast is noticed by Spader. He is bruised and recovering at a hospital and meets the survivor by chance, in the hallway. For some unknown reason, he visits the salvage yard to look at his wrecked car; and guess who just happens to be there at the same time; Holly Hunter, of course. He drives her to the airport and they have sex in the front seat of his car after discussing the bad traffic situation. He then goes back to his wife, and they get frisky. They apparently have an open marriage. We then meet a guy, Vaughan, who is obsessed with car accidents. He even reenacts the James Dean crash from 1955 with the same Porsche. Rosanna Arquette is Vaughan's prosthetic wearing friend, and we are given plenty of strange sexual quirks, such as scar worship. Vaughan rambles on with psycho babble and I was bored within the first thirty minutes of this garbage. Besides the bad script, the soundtrack, is annoying beyond description. A guitar playing with inordinate amounts of reverb is heard from beginning to end. Crash is a crashing bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trash! For perverts only (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the movie already sucked abusively my time by watching it, i won't give it much for my review. In short, this movie belongs to my black list of useless, pretentious, stupid movies that try to depict the worst depravities as an interest for art (as "Blow", "Irreversible"). What's worst is that, as usual, the addition of big names (here, Cronenberg, Holly Hunter) tries hypocritically to give respectability and the movie establishment gives dumbly prizes to such crap! There's only one truth to remember: there's nothing romantic or light about licentiousness: those people are cruel and dehumanized!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nihlistic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a novel by J.G. Ballad Crash was a highly controversial film when it was first released when it was released in 1996 for its depiction of sex and violence. Whilst it is controversial for a few scenes, its actual problem is that it a bad film. Director David Cronenberg has made so excellent films in many different genres, but Crash is a very shallow, nihilistic film about nothing. There are many problems with the film, it has the visual look and style of a TV film, characters with not much characterisation, people speaking in quiet tones and James Spader was a bland lead. Despite the film's attempts to have a said about the changing nature of sexuality in the world of technology, a look at subcultures, how people enjoy danger and thrills and sexual fetishes. But on the whole Crash is a film that has nothing to say about its subject matter and this is Cronenberg at his worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange, Stylish, Fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the great qualities of this film is the ability to constantly astonish with its relentless, shocking strangeness. "Crash" is most likely to leave viewers speechless, even those who are used to "weird" or unconventional. None of the scenes are gratuitous however, and "Crash" looks extremely stylish, as well as twisted enough to make one uneasy. Fortunately, this isn't 'cheap shocks' and the usual exploitation fare filmmakers throw in to stir some "controversy". Perverted addicts leading corrupt lives never been more fascinating. These people are craving some basic fulfillment, but are doomed to never achieve it in life. Metaphysical allegory? Probably. It's also a cold analysis of self-destructive compulsion. What's offensive is that these characters never even stop to consider the moral implications of their actions - hurting others who don't share their "hobby". Even if they did, it wouldn't make much of a difference, because they simply can't stop. Like Lynch, Cronenberg doesn't spoon-feed the "message" to the audience, so there are no answers, only uncomfortable but equally valid questions. I guess it takes guts to ask them. Dialogue is minimal and clever, and keeps the characters sealed. The narrative is filled with long pauses, eerie metallic riffs, empty glances directed inwards. Physical encounters are depersonalized and compulsive. There are always people around at the scene of sexual encounters or car crashes, and yet nobody bothers to notice or intervene. It's a surreal landscape of urban alienation that associates with voyeurism. Steel-cold (the unsettling score hits the right note as well), clinical in its depictions, "Crash" has a clean sharp edge that only a handful of directors could walk on with such elegance, insight and a sort of detachment that has a dream-like quality. All the actors are fearless and did a splendid job, especially James Spader, who is great as usual. He was born to play this role, with his other-worldly, strangely absent stare and androgynous beauty (It's surprising David Lynch never worked with him!). Spader's surreal performance is mind-blowing, as he gracefully carries along that creepy Cronenberg vibe. This is the same Spader who stole the show as the intriguing voyeur in "Sex, Lies and Videotape" and who would later do it again in the offbeat "Secretary". His other roles just didn't do justice to him. Likewise, Deborah Unger manages to turn into an abstraction, whispering her lines, floating in the same trance of addiction. The sexual scenes are elegantly choreographed. It's bizarre, disturbing and at times funny altogether, with a pretty sick sense of humor that's absolutely fantastic to a minority of people who can appreciate it. "Crash" explores sexual compulsion in a sterile environment, you can almost taste the metal. This is Cronenberg's best work and one of the most fascinating, audacious films ever made. Clearly not for everybody, but for those who enjoy the Absurd in all its complexity. Unforgettable cult classic to be watched in the uncut version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely for Anyone...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crash is a erotic drama by David Cronnenberg that explores a group of people that get sexually aroused by car crashes. It's probably the least accessible film Cronnenberg has made to date due to it's extreme amounts of fairly explicit sex, weird sexual fetishes and very muddled script. The cast does a wonderful job with the very limited material given. We have James Spader, Elias Koteas, Holly Hunter, Deborah Kara Unger and Rosanna Arquette to name a few. It's a nice thing that those actors showed some guts for doing this borderline softcore sex film. The NC-17 rating is very baffling to me. It's about as explicit in it's sexual content as 70's Japanese exploitation films like Sex and Fury or Female Prisoner Scorpion. It's hardly pornographic or even that extreme in terms of it's sexual fetishes so the NC-17 rating is pretty much an overkill. Crash doesn't have a real plot to speak of and most of the scenes start or end up with people having sex or grabbing each others crotches. It's all about the characters and the situations they go through but the muddled script doesn't really help that. Crash is mostly all surface and has very little depth to be had aside from the sex and the bizarre dialog. So either you will like this film and what it has to offer or you will despise it and just dismiss it as porn. I can't really recommend seeing Crash, unless you are very interested in the work of David Cronnenberg. So unless you are looking for some strange films about sexual fetishes and James Spader, your not going to enjoy this film as conventional entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Distant and detached - if HAL3000 made a movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Crash" remains Cronenberg's most controversial movies. Permeating with sex and obscenity, coupled with obsessions of both bodily and mechanical nature, it was born on shock factor. Film producer James Ballard (James Spader) and his promiscuous wife Catherine (the voluptuous Deborah Kara Unger) lead a life of mutually accepted sexual ventures, searching for ultimate satisfaction by indulging into various affairs. A car accident featuring Helen Remington (Holly Hunter) introduces another level of compulsive sexual mania - where sexual desires and metal mesh together to form a hybrid of death, car crashes and orgiastic pleasure. This introduces both James and Catherine to the Vaughan (Elias Koteas) and their common spiralling search for fulfilment, where boundaries are pushed further and further, while sperm leaks by the gallons... A story less about the addiction to sex or dangerous driving, but more about the growing infatuation with the mechanical, as it slowly overrides bodily desires to entail technoorganic fulfilment. As a car becomes a subject of desire, craving and our bodies seem to merge with its leather seats and metallic odour, Cronenberg shows a new phase of humanity. One devoid of emotion, cold and ever expanding, as desire becomes limitless to the death. Taking the issue of automotive obsession to the extreme "Crash" manages to pack an uneasy wallop, one however that is overlong and for half its running time directionless. Once the premise is clear characters indulge into sexual deviance to sexual deviance with each passing scene pushing themselves further, when the previously passed boundary no longer satisfies the growing need. Although the gist is evident the tirade of weird sex and masturbation becomes tiring and fails to add any further layers to the story. It is hard to blame Cronenberg, as the execution fits the story. Bleak, detached from emotion, jaded and monotonous fulfils the goal of presenting the lingering disconnect of characters, which are so lost in lack of feeling, whilst trying to discover fulfilment. Especially apparent when Ballard and Catherine have sex - physical pleasure is achieved, but emotional fulfilment is non-achievable. Therefore the search for emotion (one induced by the adrenaline rush of a crash) triggers a longing for more of this natural drug, but at the same time increasing the level required for satisfaction. This self-destructive behaviour is so natural, so human, but achieved through such dehumanised means... A tough piece of fiction, which is hard fought to be called pleasant, but definitely a shocking piece worthy of reflection and afterthought, not necessarily admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The quest for happiness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyma_Rizwaan_Khan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been noticing a lot of people watch Gus Van Sant or Cronenberg and they use the words 'pretentious' and 'hack'. I suppose the effect a piece of art has on you also says something about you as a person. The more disturbing art is the more you hear people discussing it - more and more people asking other people not to watch this because it is 'sick and twisted and disgusting'. But I for one, am pretty sure there is nothing pretentious about this movie. Hacks don't make movies like CRASH which barely receive any mainstream attention - they release movies like TWILIGHT and sit back and watch the money roll in. The movie is about a bunch of people trying to find the ultimate pleasure - and what is more pleasurable than a climax right? They have everything they need - good bodies, cars, jobs, good looking people around them and all the things people think are necessary and yet they find themselves feeling empty. All of a sudden, they end up becoming obsessed with car crashes and victims of car crashes. They feel like this is the way to get what they are lacking. But no matter how far, how sinister - how truly invigorating their experiences are, they cannot find happiness. That's what this movie is about - the quest for happiness - for that feeling of knowing joy of some kind. And whether or not it is possible to find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pontifikator
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people. Their sexual turn-on is car wrecks, and they cause them when they can't find them by chance. This movie, directed by David Cronenberg, is based on a novel by J. G. Ballard. This is a disturbing film. The sex scenes approach soft core porn, as the characters paw and grope each other, and there is rampant fetishism as well. However, I was unable to care about the characters. Casting James Spader as the lead guarantees a performance of flat affect. This sometimes works (as in "sex, lies, and videotape," when he plays a weird voyeur), but when he is the main character and I can't begin to like him or feel sympathy for him, it wrecks the movie for me. The problem with the film from my point of view is that I'm never given any reason to identify with these people and to care about their drive for this particular form of fetishism. I suspect the sex aspect of the film was too difficult for the director and/or the actors (including Holly Hunter, Elias Koteas, and Deborah Kara Unger) for them to develop their roles fully. Instead of some fascinating insight into a world I'd never heard of, I saw moments of soft core sex interspersed with dialog from affectless characters about whom I learned nothing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty dreary, but also undeniably fascinating.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer / producer / director David Cronenberg's grim adaptation of the J.G. Ballard novel tells the story of James Ballard (James Spader), who gets into a horrible car accident that actually has a stunning effect on his life, in particular his sex life. He and wife Catherine (Deborah Kara Unger) find themselves now inexorably drawn to the violence and destruction of car crashes and even the effect that such crashes have on the human body. They soon discover an underground group of people that celebrate this creepy fetish, led by the intense Vaughan (Elias Koteas), who with the help of stuntman friends recreates famous crashes involving celebrities (such as James Dean). Cronenberg is obviously a perfect choice to direct this sort of story, which obviously is not going to appeal to a lot of people but may very well intrigue some. It never gets too far into the heads of its characters, but doesn't really judge them, either, and illustrates how these individuals obsess over creating some sort of meaning in their lives and how human beings can attach a sexual element to just about anything. The weather in this Toronto-shot film is appropriately gloomy, matching the mood of the story telling, while the blood and gore is actually never overdone. Really, Cronenberg keeps the focus on the sexual nature of the story and characters and with the help of his very willing performers creates some very erotic scenes, of both the heterosexual and homosexual variety. There's some caressing of vehicle damage to go with the caressing of human bodies. The deeply committed cast, also including Holly Hunter and Rosanna Arquette, helps to draw you into this tale, while Howard Shore supplies a music score in his typical grandiose, full-of-foreboding style. Koteas is a standout as Vaughan. The film isn't perfect overall, as has already been mentioned, but it may keep some viewers watching due to the sexual frankness and explicitness on display. (This is available in both a 90 minute long R rated version and a 100 minute long NC-17 rated version.) Still, even with its flaws it leaves a fairly big impression; it's not likely it'll be easily forgotten. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The one thing Cronenberg has always unquestionably been talented at is weaving a highly disturbing atmosphere, and he does that beautifully on Crash. Unfortunately, though, the movie doesn't quite manage to draw the viewer into that atmosphere. It's meant as a metaphor for mankind's obsessions and perversions, but the horror is being piled on so thickly that I never once found myself immersed in any of the characters or caring about what happens to them, other than loathing them. James Spader is as fantastic as ever in exploring the depth of human perversion, and as always he manages a delicate balance of naive and sleazy, but he did better in subtler works like Secretary and Sex, Lies & Videotape.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Cronenberg must have been insane or under severe medication to write, produce and direct Crash, which is one of the worst movies that I have ever seen. It opens at an airplane hangar where James Spader character is grinding against his wife in a brief encounter, and within seconds is doing the nasty with an Asian woman in a camera room at a film set. Shortly afterwords, he is driving down the road and crashes head on into another car. A man goes through the windshield, but his wife, played by Holly Hunter is bloodied, and she is shown in the passenger seat without a bra, and her breast is noticed by Spader. He is bruised and recovering at a hospital and meets the survivor by chance, in the hallway. For some unknown reason, he visits the salvage yard to look at his wrecked car; and guess who just happens to be there at the same time; Holly Hunter, of course. He drives her to the airport and they have sex in the front seat of his car after discussing the bad traffic situation. He then goes back to his wife, and they get frisky. They apparently have an open marriage. We then meet a guy, Vaughan, who is obsessed with car accidents. He even reenacts the James Dean crash from 1955 with the same Porsche. Rosanna Arquette is Vaughan's prosthetic wearing friend, and we are given plenty of strange sexual quirks, such as scar worship. Vaughan rambles on with psycho babble and I was bored within the first thirty minutes of this garbage. Besides the bad script, the soundtrack, is annoying beyond description. A guitar playing with inordinate amounts of reverb is heard from beginning to end. Crash is a crashing bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trash! For perverts only (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the movie already sucked abusively my time by watching it, i won't give it much for my review. In short, this movie belongs to my black list of useless, pretentious, stupid movies that try to depict the worst depravities as an interest for art (as "Blow", "Irreversible"). What's worst is that, as usual, the addition of big names (here, Cronenberg, Holly Hunter) tries hypocritically to give respectability and the movie establishment gives dumbly prizes to such crap! There's only one truth to remember: there's nothing romantic or light about licentiousness: those people are cruel and dehumanized!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nihlistic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a novel by J.G. Ballad Crash was a highly controversial film when it was first released when it was released in 1996 for its depiction of sex and violence. Whilst it is controversial for a few scenes, its actual problem is that it a bad film. Director David Cronenberg has made so excellent films in many different genres, but Crash is a very shallow, nihilistic film about nothing. There are many problems with the film, it has the visual look and style of a TV film, characters with not much characterisation, people speaking in quiet tones and James Spader was a bland lead. Despite the film's attempts to have a said about the changing nature of sexuality in the world of technology, a look at subcultures, how people enjoy danger and thrills and sexual fetishes. But on the whole Crash is a film that has nothing to say about its subject matter and this is Cronenberg at his worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange, Stylish, Fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the great qualities of this film is the ability to constantly astonish with its relentless, shocking strangeness. "Crash" is most likely to leave viewers speechless, even those who are used to "weird" or unconventional. None of the scenes are gratuitous however, and "Crash" looks extremely stylish, as well as twisted enough to make one uneasy. Fortunately, this isn't 'cheap shocks' and the usual exploitation fare filmmakers throw in to stir some "controversy". Perverted addicts leading corrupt lives never been more fascinating. These people are craving some basic fulfillment, but are doomed to never achieve it in life. Metaphysical allegory? Probably. It's also a cold analysis of self-destructive compulsion. What's offensive is that these characters never even stop to consider the moral implications of their actions - hurting others who don't share their "hobby". Even if they did, it wouldn't make much of a difference, because they simply can't stop. Like Lynch, Cronenberg doesn't spoon-feed the "message" to the audience, so there are no answers, only uncomfortable but equally valid questions. I guess it takes guts to ask them. Dialogue is minimal and clever, and keeps the characters sealed. The narrative is filled with long pauses, eerie metallic riffs, empty glances directed inwards. Physical encounters are depersonalized and compulsive. There are always people around at the scene of sexual encounters or car crashes, and yet nobody bothers to notice or intervene. It's a surreal landscape of urban alienation that associates with voyeurism. Steel-cold (the unsettling score hits the right note as well), clinical in its depictions, "Crash" has a clean sharp edge that only a handful of directors could walk on with such elegance, insight and a sort of detachment that has a dream-like quality. All the actors are fearless and did a splendid job, especially James Spader, who is great as usual. He was born to play this role, with his other-worldly, strangely absent stare and androgynous beauty (It's surprising David Lynch never worked with him!). Spader's surreal performance is mind-blowing, as he gracefully carries along that creepy Cronenberg vibe. This is the same Spader who stole the show as the intriguing voyeur in "Sex, Lies and Videotape" and who would later do it again in the offbeat "Secretary". His other roles just didn't do justice to him. Likewise, Deborah Unger manages to turn into an abstraction, whispering her lines, floating in the same trance of addiction. The sexual scenes are elegantly choreographed. It's bizarre, disturbing and at times funny altogether, with a pretty sick sense of humor that's absolutely fantastic to a minority of people who can appreciate it. "Crash" explores sexual compulsion in a sterile environment, you can almost taste the metal. This is Cronenberg's best work and one of the most fascinating, audacious films ever made. Clearly not for everybody, but for those who enjoy the Absurd in all its complexity. Unforgettable cult classic to be watched in the uncut version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely for Anyone...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crash is a erotic drama by David Cronnenberg that explores a group of people that get sexually aroused by car crashes. It's probably the least accessible film Cronnenberg has made to date due to it's extreme amounts of fairly explicit sex, weird sexual fetishes and very muddled script. The cast does a wonderful job with the very limited material given. We have James Spader, Elias Koteas, Holly Hunter, Deborah Kara Unger and Rosanna Arquette to name a few. It's a nice thing that those actors showed some guts for doing this borderline softcore sex film. The NC-17 rating is very baffling to me. It's about as explicit in it's sexual content as 70's Japanese exploitation films like Sex and Fury or Female Prisoner Scorpion. It's hardly pornographic or even that extreme in terms of it's sexual fetishes so the NC-17 rating is pretty much an overkill. Crash doesn't have a real plot to speak of and most of the scenes start or end up with people having sex or grabbing each others crotches. It's all about the characters and the situations they go through but the muddled script doesn't really help that. Crash is mostly all surface and has very little depth to be had aside from the sex and the bizarre dialog. So either you will like this film and what it has to offer or you will despise it and just dismiss it as porn. I can't really recommend seeing Crash, unless you are very interested in the work of David Cronnenberg. So unless you are looking for some strange films about sexual fetishes and James Spader, your not going to enjoy this film as conventional entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Distant and detached - if HAL3000 made a movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Crash" remains Cronenberg's most controversial movies. Permeating with sex and obscenity, coupled with obsessions of both bodily and mechanical nature, it was born on shock factor. Film producer James Ballard (James Spader) and his promiscuous wife Catherine (the voluptuous Deborah Kara Unger) lead a life of mutually accepted sexual ventures, searching for ultimate satisfaction by indulging into various affairs. A car accident featuring Helen Remington (Holly Hunter) introduces another level of compulsive sexual mania - where sexual desires and metal mesh together to form a hybrid of death, car crashes and orgiastic pleasure. This introduces both James and Catherine to the Vaughan (Elias Koteas) and their common spiralling search for fulfilment, where boundaries are pushed further and further, while sperm leaks by the gallons... A story less about the addiction to sex or dangerous driving, but more about the growing infatuation with the mechanical, as it slowly overrides bodily desires to entail technoorganic fulfilment. As a car becomes a subject of desire, craving and our bodies seem to merge with its leather seats and metallic odour, Cronenberg shows a new phase of humanity. One devoid of emotion, cold and ever expanding, as desire becomes limitless to the death. Taking the issue of automotive obsession to the extreme "Crash" manages to pack an uneasy wallop, one however that is overlong and for half its running time directionless. Once the premise is clear characters indulge into sexual deviance to sexual deviance with each passing scene pushing themselves further, when the previously passed boundary no longer satisfies the growing need. Although the gist is evident the tirade of weird sex and masturbation becomes tiring and fails to add any further layers to the story. It is hard to blame Cronenberg, as the execution fits the story. Bleak, detached from emotion, jaded and monotonous fulfils the goal of presenting the lingering disconnect of characters, which are so lost in lack of feeling, whilst trying to discover fulfilment. Especially apparent when Ballard and Catherine have sex - physical pleasure is achieved, but emotional fulfilment is non-achievable. Therefore the search for emotion (one induced by the adrenaline rush of a crash) triggers a longing for more of this natural drug, but at the same time increasing the level required for satisfaction. This self-destructive behaviour is so natural, so human, but achieved through such dehumanised means... A tough piece of fiction, which is hard fought to be called pleasant, but definitely a shocking piece worthy of reflection and afterthought, not necessarily admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The quest for happiness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyma_Rizwaan_Khan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been noticing a lot of people watch Gus Van Sant or Cronenberg and they use the words 'pretentious' and 'hack'. I suppose the effect a piece of art has on you also says something about you as a person. The more disturbing art is the more you hear people discussing it - more and more people asking other people not to watch this because it is 'sick and twisted and disgusting'. But I for one, am pretty sure there is nothing pretentious about this movie. Hacks don't make movies like CRASH which barely receive any mainstream attention - they release movies like TWILIGHT and sit back and watch the money roll in. The movie is about a bunch of people trying to find the ultimate pleasure - and what is more pleasurable than a climax right? They have everything they need - good bodies, cars, jobs, good looking people around them and all the things people think are necessary and yet they find themselves feeling empty. All of a sudden, they end up becoming obsessed with car crashes and victims of car crashes. They feel like this is the way to get what they are lacking. But no matter how far, how sinister - how truly invigorating their experiences are, they cannot find happiness. That's what this movie is about - the quest for happiness - for that feeling of knowing joy of some kind. And whether or not it is possible to find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pontifikator
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people. Their sexual turn-on is car wrecks, and they cause them when they can't find them by chance. This movie, directed by David Cronenberg, is based on a novel by J. G. Ballard. This is a disturbing film. The sex scenes approach soft core porn, as the characters paw and grope each other, and there is rampant fetishism as well. However, I was unable to care about the characters. Casting James Spader as the lead guarantees a performance of flat affect. This sometimes works (as in "sex, lies, and videotape," when he plays a weird voyeur), but when he is the main character and I can't begin to like him or feel sympathy for him, it wrecks the movie for me. The problem with the film from my point of view is that I'm never given any reason to identify with these people and to care about their drive for this particular form of fetishism. I suspect the sex aspect of the film was too difficult for the director and/or the actors (including Holly Hunter, Elias Koteas, and Deborah Kara Unger) for them to develop their roles fully. Instead of some fascinating insight into a world I'd never heard of, I saw moments of soft core sex interspersed with dialog from affectless characters about whom I learned nothing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty dreary, but also undeniably fascinating.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer / producer / director David Cronenberg's grim adaptation of the J.G. Ballard novel tells the story of James Ballard (James Spader), who gets into a horrible car accident that actually has a stunning effect on his life, in particular his sex life. He and wife Catherine (Deborah Kara Unger) find themselves now inexorably drawn to the violence and destruction of car crashes and even the effect that such crashes have on the human body. They soon discover an underground group of people that celebrate this creepy fetish, led by the intense Vaughan (Elias Koteas), who with the help of stuntman friends recreates famous crashes involving celebrities (such as James Dean). Cronenberg is obviously a perfect choice to direct this sort of story, which obviously is not going to appeal to a lot of people but may very well intrigue some. It never gets too far into the heads of its characters, but doesn't really judge them, either, and illustrates how these individuals obsess over creating some sort of meaning in their lives and how human beings can attach a sexual element to just about anything. The weather in this Toronto-shot film is appropriately gloomy, matching the mood of the story telling, while the blood and gore is actually never overdone. Really, Cronenberg keeps the focus on the sexual nature of the story and characters and with the help of his very willing performers creates some very erotic scenes, of both the heterosexual and homosexual variety. There's some caressing of vehicle damage to go with the caressing of human bodies. The deeply committed cast, also including Holly Hunter and Rosanna Arquette, helps to draw you into this tale, while Howard Shore supplies a music score in his typical grandiose, full-of-foreboding style. Koteas is a standout as Vaughan. The film isn't perfect overall, as has already been mentioned, but it may keep some viewers watching due to the sexual frankness and explicitness on display. (This is available in both a 90 minute long R rated version and a 100 minute long NC-17 rated version.) Still, even with its flaws it leaves a fairly big impression; it's not likely it'll be easily forgotten. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The one thing Cronenberg has always unquestionably been talented at is weaving a highly disturbing atmosphere, and he does that beautifully on Crash. Unfortunately, though, the movie doesn't quite manage to draw the viewer into that atmosphere. It's meant as a metaphor for mankind's obsessions and perversions, but the horror is being piled on so thickly that I never once found myself immersed in any of the characters or caring about what happens to them, other than loathing them. James Spader is as fantastic as ever in exploring the depth of human perversion, and as always he manages a delicate balance of naive and sleazy, but he did better in subtler works like Secretary and Sex, Lies & Videotape.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Cronenberg must have been insane or under severe medication to write, produce and direct Crash, which is one of the worst movies that I have ever seen. It opens at an airplane hangar where James Spader character is grinding against his wife in a brief encounter, and within seconds is doing the nasty with an Asian woman in a camera room at a film set. Shortly afterwords, he is driving down the road and crashes head on into another car. A man goes through the windshield, but his wife, played by Holly Hunter is bloodied, and she is shown in the passenger seat without a bra, and her breast is noticed by Spader. He is bruised and recovering at a hospital and meets the survivor by chance, in the hallway. For some unknown reason, he visits the salvage yard to look at his wrecked car; and guess who just happens to be there at the same time; Holly Hunter, of course. He drives her to the airport and they have sex in the front seat of his car after discussing the bad traffic situation. He then goes back to his wife, and they get frisky. They apparently have an open marriage. We then meet a guy, Vaughan, who is obsessed with car accidents. He even reenacts the James Dean crash from 1955 with the same Porsche. Rosanna Arquette is Vaughan's prosthetic wearing friend, and we are given plenty of strange sexual quirks, such as scar worship. Vaughan rambles on with psycho babble and I was bored within the first thirty minutes of this garbage. Besides the bad script, the soundtrack, is annoying beyond description. A guitar playing with inordinate amounts of reverb is heard from beginning to end. Crash is a crashing bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trash! For perverts only (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the movie already sucked abusively my time by watching it, i won't give it much for my review. In short, this movie belongs to my black list of useless, pretentious, stupid movies that try to depict the worst depravities as an interest for art (as "Blow", "Irreversible"). What's worst is that, as usual, the addition of big names (here, Cronenberg, Holly Hunter) tries hypocritically to give respectability and the movie establishment gives dumbly prizes to such crap! There's only one truth to remember: there's nothing romantic or light about licentiousness: those people are cruel and dehumanized!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nihlistic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a novel by J.G. Ballad Crash was a highly controversial film when it was first released when it was released in 1996 for its depiction of sex and violence. Whilst it is controversial for a few scenes, its actual problem is that it a bad film. Director David Cronenberg has made so excellent films in many different genres, but Crash is a very shallow, nihilistic film about nothing. There are many problems with the film, it has the visual look and style of a TV film, characters with not much characterisation, people speaking in quiet tones and James Spader was a bland lead. Despite the film's attempts to have a said about the changing nature of sexuality in the world of technology, a look at subcultures, how people enjoy danger and thrills and sexual fetishes. But on the whole Crash is a film that has nothing to say about its subject matter and this is Cronenberg at his worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange, Stylish, Fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the great qualities of this film is the ability to constantly astonish with its relentless, shocking strangeness. "Crash" is most likely to leave viewers speechless, even those who are used to "weird" or unconventional. None of the scenes are gratuitous however, and "Crash" looks extremely stylish, as well as twisted enough to make one uneasy. Fortunately, this isn't 'cheap shocks' and the usual exploitation fare filmmakers throw in to stir some "controversy". Perverted addicts leading corrupt lives never been more fascinating. These people are craving some basic fulfillment, but are doomed to never achieve it in life. Metaphysical allegory? Probably. It's also a cold analysis of self-destructive compulsion. What's offensive is that these characters never even stop to consider the moral implications of their actions - hurting others who don't share their "hobby". Even if they did, it wouldn't make much of a difference, because they simply can't stop. Like Lynch, Cronenberg doesn't spoon-feed the "message" to the audience, so there are no answers, only uncomfortable but equally valid questions. I guess it takes guts to ask them. Dialogue is minimal and clever, and keeps the characters sealed. The narrative is filled with long pauses, eerie metallic riffs, empty glances directed inwards. Physical encounters are depersonalized and compulsive. There are always people around at the scene of sexual encounters or car crashes, and yet nobody bothers to notice or intervene. It's a surreal landscape of urban alienation that associates with voyeurism. Steel-cold (the unsettling score hits the right note as well), clinical in its depictions, "Crash" has a clean sharp edge that only a handful of directors could walk on with such elegance, insight and a sort of detachment that has a dream-like quality. All the actors are fearless and did a splendid job, especially James Spader, who is great as usual. He was born to play this role, with his other-worldly, strangely absent stare and androgynous beauty (It's surprising David Lynch never worked with him!). Spader's surreal performance is mind-blowing, as he gracefully carries along that creepy Cronenberg vibe. This is the same Spader who stole the show as the intriguing voyeur in "Sex, Lies and Videotape" and who would later do it again in the offbeat "Secretary". His other roles just didn't do justice to him. Likewise, Deborah Unger manages to turn into an abstraction, whispering her lines, floating in the same trance of addiction. The sexual scenes are elegantly choreographed. It's bizarre, disturbing and at times funny altogether, with a pretty sick sense of humor that's absolutely fantastic to a minority of people who can appreciate it. "Crash" explores sexual compulsion in a sterile environment, you can almost taste the metal. This is Cronenberg's best work and one of the most fascinating, audacious films ever made. Clearly not for everybody, but for those who enjoy the Absurd in all its complexity. Unforgettable cult classic to be watched in the uncut version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely for Anyone...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crash is a erotic drama by David Cronnenberg that explores a group of people that get sexually aroused by car crashes. It's probably the least accessible film Cronnenberg has made to date due to it's extreme amounts of fairly explicit sex, weird sexual fetishes and very muddled script. The cast does a wonderful job with the very limited material given. We have James Spader, Elias Koteas, Holly Hunter, Deborah Kara Unger and Rosanna Arquette to name a few. It's a nice thing that those actors showed some guts for doing this borderline softcore sex film. The NC-17 rating is very baffling to me. It's about as explicit in it's sexual content as 70's Japanese exploitation films like Sex and Fury or Female Prisoner Scorpion. It's hardly pornographic or even that extreme in terms of it's sexual fetishes so the NC-17 rating is pretty much an overkill. Crash doesn't have a real plot to speak of and most of the scenes start or end up with people having sex or grabbing each others crotches. It's all about the characters and the situations they go through but the muddled script doesn't really help that. Crash is mostly all surface and has very little depth to be had aside from the sex and the bizarre dialog. So either you will like this film and what it has to offer or you will despise it and just dismiss it as porn. I can't really recommend seeing Crash, unless you are very interested in the work of David Cronnenberg. So unless you are looking for some strange films about sexual fetishes and James Spader, your not going to enjoy this film as conventional entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Distant and detached - if HAL3000 made a movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Crash" remains Cronenberg's most controversial movies. Permeating with sex and obscenity, coupled with obsessions of both bodily and mechanical nature, it was born on shock factor. Film producer James Ballard (James Spader) and his promiscuous wife Catherine (the voluptuous Deborah Kara Unger) lead a life of mutually accepted sexual ventures, searching for ultimate satisfaction by indulging into various affairs. A car accident featuring Helen Remington (Holly Hunter) introduces another level of compulsive sexual mania - where sexual desires and metal mesh together to form a hybrid of death, car crashes and orgiastic pleasure. This introduces both James and Catherine to the Vaughan (Elias Koteas) and their common spiralling search for fulfilment, where boundaries are pushed further and further, while sperm leaks by the gallons... A story less about the addiction to sex or dangerous driving, but more about the growing infatuation with the mechanical, as it slowly overrides bodily desires to entail technoorganic fulfilment. As a car becomes a subject of desire, craving and our bodies seem to merge with its leather seats and metallic odour, Cronenberg shows a new phase of humanity. One devoid of emotion, cold and ever expanding, as desire becomes limitless to the death. Taking the issue of automotive obsession to the extreme "Crash" manages to pack an uneasy wallop, one however that is overlong and for half its running time directionless. Once the premise is clear characters indulge into sexual deviance to sexual deviance with each passing scene pushing themselves further, when the previously passed boundary no longer satisfies the growing need. Although the gist is evident the tirade of weird sex and masturbation becomes tiring and fails to add any further layers to the story. It is hard to blame Cronenberg, as the execution fits the story. Bleak, detached from emotion, jaded and monotonous fulfils the goal of presenting the lingering disconnect of characters, which are so lost in lack of feeling, whilst trying to discover fulfilment. Especially apparent when Ballard and Catherine have sex - physical pleasure is achieved, but emotional fulfilment is non-achievable. Therefore the search for emotion (one induced by the adrenaline rush of a crash) triggers a longing for more of this natural drug, but at the same time increasing the level required for satisfaction. This self-destructive behaviour is so natural, so human, but achieved through such dehumanised means... A tough piece of fiction, which is hard fought to be called pleasant, but definitely a shocking piece worthy of reflection and afterthought, not necessarily admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The quest for happiness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyma_Rizwaan_Khan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been noticing a lot of people watch Gus Van Sant or Cronenberg and they use the words 'pretentious' and 'hack'. I suppose the effect a piece of art has on you also says something about you as a person. The more disturbing art is the more you hear people discussing it - more and more people asking other people not to watch this because it is 'sick and twisted and disgusting'. But I for one, am pretty sure there is nothing pretentious about this movie. Hacks don't make movies like CRASH which barely receive any mainstream attention - they release movies like TWILIGHT and sit back and watch the money roll in. The movie is about a bunch of people trying to find the ultimate pleasure - and what is more pleasurable than a climax right? They have everything they need - good bodies, cars, jobs, good looking people around them and all the things people think are necessary and yet they find themselves feeling empty. All of a sudden, they end up becoming obsessed with car crashes and victims of car crashes. They feel like this is the way to get what they are lacking. But no matter how far, how sinister - how truly invigorating their experiences are, they cannot find happiness. That's what this movie is about - the quest for happiness - for that feeling of knowing joy of some kind. And whether or not it is possible to find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pontifikator
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people. Their sexual turn-on is car wrecks, and they cause them when they can't find them by chance. This movie, directed by David Cronenberg, is based on a novel by J. G. Ballard. This is a disturbing film. The sex scenes approach soft core porn, as the characters paw and grope each other, and there is rampant fetishism as well. However, I was unable to care about the characters. Casting James Spader as the lead guarantees a performance of flat affect. This sometimes works (as in "sex, lies, and videotape," when he plays a weird voyeur), but when he is the main character and I can't begin to like him or feel sympathy for him, it wrecks the movie for me. The problem with the film from my point of view is that I'm never given any reason to identify with these people and to care about their drive for this particular form of fetishism. I suspect the sex aspect of the film was too difficult for the director and/or the actors (including Holly Hunter, Elias Koteas, and Deborah Kara Unger) for them to develop their roles fully. Instead of some fascinating insight into a world I'd never heard of, I saw moments of soft core sex interspersed with dialog from affectless characters about whom I learned nothing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty dreary, but also undeniably fascinating.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer / producer / director David Cronenberg's grim adaptation of the J.G. Ballard novel tells the story of James Ballard (James Spader), who gets into a horrible car accident that actually has a stunning effect on his life, in particular his sex life. He and wife Catherine (Deborah Kara Unger) find themselves now inexorably drawn to the violence and destruction of car crashes and even the effect that such crashes have on the human body. They soon discover an underground group of people that celebrate this creepy fetish, led by the intense Vaughan (Elias Koteas), who with the help of stuntman friends recreates famous crashes involving celebrities (such as James Dean). Cronenberg is obviously a perfect choice to direct this sort of story, which obviously is not going to appeal to a lot of people but may very well intrigue some. It never gets too far into the heads of its characters, but doesn't really judge them, either, and illustrates how these individuals obsess over creating some sort of meaning in their lives and how human beings can attach a sexual element to just about anything. The weather in this Toronto-shot film is appropriately gloomy, matching the mood of the story telling, while the blood and gore is actually never overdone. Really, Cronenberg keeps the focus on the sexual nature of the story and characters and with the help of his very willing performers creates some very erotic scenes, of both the heterosexual and homosexual variety. There's some caressing of vehicle damage to go with the caressing of human bodies. The deeply committed cast, also including Holly Hunter and Rosanna Arquette, helps to draw you into this tale, while Howard Shore supplies a music score in his typical grandiose, full-of-foreboding style. Koteas is a standout as Vaughan. The film isn't perfect overall, as has already been mentioned, but it may keep some viewers watching due to the sexual frankness and explicitness on display. (This is available in both a 90 minute long R rated version and a 100 minute long NC-17 rated version.) Still, even with its flaws it leaves a fairly big impression; it's not likely it'll be easily forgotten. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The one thing Cronenberg has always unquestionably been talented at is weaving a highly disturbing atmosphere, and he does that beautifully on Crash. Unfortunately, though, the movie doesn't quite manage to draw the viewer into that atmosphere. It's meant as a metaphor for mankind's obsessions and perversions, but the horror is being piled on so thickly that I never once found myself immersed in any of the characters or caring about what happens to them, other than loathing them. James Spader is as fantastic as ever in exploring the depth of human perversion, and as always he manages a delicate balance of naive and sleazy, but he did better in subtler works like Secretary and Sex, Lies & Videotape.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Cronenberg must have been insane or under severe medication to write, produce and direct Crash, which is one of the worst movies that I have ever seen. It opens at an airplane hangar where James Spader character is grinding against his wife in a brief encounter, and within seconds is doing the nasty with an Asian woman in a camera room at a film set. Shortly afterwords, he is driving down the road and crashes head on into another car. A man goes through the windshield, but his wife, played by Holly Hunter is bloodied, and she is shown in the passenger seat without a bra, and her breast is noticed by Spader. He is bruised and recovering at a hospital and meets the survivor by chance, in the hallway. For some unknown reason, he visits the salvage yard to look at his wrecked car; and guess who just happens to be there at the same time; Holly Hunter, of course. He drives her to the airport and they have sex in the front seat of his car after discussing the bad traffic situation. He then goes back to his wife, and they get frisky. They apparently have an open marriage. We then meet a guy, Vaughan, who is obsessed with car accidents. He even reenacts the James Dean crash from 1955 with the same Porsche. Rosanna Arquette is Vaughan's prosthetic wearing friend, and we are given plenty of strange sexual quirks, such as scar worship. Vaughan rambles on with psycho babble and I was bored within the first thirty minutes of this garbage. Besides the bad script, the soundtrack, is annoying beyond description. A guitar playing with inordinate amounts of reverb is heard from beginning to end. Crash is a crashing bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trash! For perverts only (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the movie already sucked abusively my time by watching it, i won't give it much for my review. In short, this movie belongs to my black list of useless, pretentious, stupid movies that try to depict the worst depravities as an interest for art (as "Blow", "Irreversible"). What's worst is that, as usual, the addition of big names (here, Cronenberg, Holly Hunter) tries hypocritically to give respectability and the movie establishment gives dumbly prizes to such crap! There's only one truth to remember: there's nothing romantic or light about licentiousness: those people are cruel and dehumanized!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nihlistic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a novel by J.G. Ballad Crash was a highly controversial film when it was first released when it was released in 1996 for its depiction of sex and violence. Whilst it is controversial for a few scenes, its actual problem is that it a bad film. Director David Cronenberg has made so excellent films in many different genres, but Crash is a very shallow, nihilistic film about nothing. There are many problems with the film, it has the visual look and style of a TV film, characters with not much characterisation, people speaking in quiet tones and James Spader was a bland lead. Despite the film's attempts to have a said about the changing nature of sexuality in the world of technology, a look at subcultures, how people enjoy danger and thrills and sexual fetishes. But on the whole Crash is a film that has nothing to say about its subject matter and this is Cronenberg at his worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange, Stylish, Fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the great qualities of this film is the ability to constantly astonish with its relentless, shocking strangeness. "Crash" is most likely to leave viewers speechless, even those who are used to "weird" or unconventional. None of the scenes are gratuitous however, and "Crash" looks extremely stylish, as well as twisted enough to make one uneasy. Fortunately, this isn't 'cheap shocks' and the usual exploitation fare filmmakers throw in to stir some "controversy". Perverted addicts leading corrupt lives never been more fascinating. These people are craving some basic fulfillment, but are doomed to never achieve it in life. Metaphysical allegory? Probably. It's also a cold analysis of self-destructive compulsion. What's offensive is that these characters never even stop to consider the moral implications of their actions - hurting others who don't share their "hobby". Even if they did, it wouldn't make much of a difference, because they simply can't stop. Like Lynch, Cronenberg doesn't spoon-feed the "message" to the audience, so there are no answers, only uncomfortable but equally valid questions. I guess it takes guts to ask them. Dialogue is minimal and clever, and keeps the characters sealed. The narrative is filled with long pauses, eerie metallic riffs, empty glances directed inwards. Physical encounters are depersonalized and compulsive. There are always people around at the scene of sexual encounters or car crashes, and yet nobody bothers to notice or intervene. It's a surreal landscape of urban alienation that associates with voyeurism. Steel-cold (the unsettling score hits the right note as well), clinical in its depictions, "Crash" has a clean sharp edge that only a handful of directors could walk on with such elegance, insight and a sort of detachment that has a dream-like quality. All the actors are fearless and did a splendid job, especially James Spader, who is great as usual. He was born to play this role, with his other-worldly, strangely absent stare and androgynous beauty (It's surprising David Lynch never worked with him!). Spader's surreal performance is mind-blowing, as he gracefully carries along that creepy Cronenberg vibe. This is the same Spader who stole the show as the intriguing voyeur in "Sex, Lies and Videotape" and who would later do it again in the offbeat "Secretary". His other roles just didn't do justice to him. Likewise, Deborah Unger manages to turn into an abstraction, whispering her lines, floating in the same trance of addiction. The sexual scenes are elegantly choreographed. It's bizarre, disturbing and at times funny altogether, with a pretty sick sense of humor that's absolutely fantastic to a minority of people who can appreciate it. "Crash" explores sexual compulsion in a sterile environment, you can almost taste the metal. This is Cronenberg's best work and one of the most fascinating, audacious films ever made. Clearly not for everybody, but for those who enjoy the Absurd in all its complexity. Unforgettable cult classic to be watched in the uncut version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely for Anyone...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crash is a erotic drama by David Cronnenberg that explores a group of people that get sexually aroused by car crashes. It's probably the least accessible film Cronnenberg has made to date due to it's extreme amounts of fairly explicit sex, weird sexual fetishes and very muddled script. The cast does a wonderful job with the very limited material given. We have James Spader, Elias Koteas, Holly Hunter, Deborah Kara Unger and Rosanna Arquette to name a few. It's a nice thing that those actors showed some guts for doing this borderline softcore sex film. The NC-17 rating is very baffling to me. It's about as explicit in it's sexual content as 70's Japanese exploitation films like Sex and Fury or Female Prisoner Scorpion. It's hardly pornographic or even that extreme in terms of it's sexual fetishes so the NC-17 rating is pretty much an overkill. Crash doesn't have a real plot to speak of and most of the scenes start or end up with people having sex or grabbing each others crotches. It's all about the characters and the situations they go through but the muddled script doesn't really help that. Crash is mostly all surface and has very little depth to be had aside from the sex and the bizarre dialog. So either you will like this film and what it has to offer or you will despise it and just dismiss it as porn. I can't really recommend seeing Crash, unless you are very interested in the work of David Cronnenberg. So unless you are looking for some strange films about sexual fetishes and James Spader, your not going to enjoy this film as conventional entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Distant and detached - if HAL3000 made a movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Crash" remains Cronenberg's most controversial movies. Permeating with sex and obscenity, coupled with obsessions of both bodily and mechanical nature, it was born on shock factor. Film producer James Ballard (James Spader) and his promiscuous wife Catherine (the voluptuous Deborah Kara Unger) lead a life of mutually accepted sexual ventures, searching for ultimate satisfaction by indulging into various affairs. A car accident featuring Helen Remington (Holly Hunter) introduces another level of compulsive sexual mania - where sexual desires and metal mesh together to form a hybrid of death, car crashes and orgiastic pleasure. This introduces both James and Catherine to the Vaughan (Elias Koteas) and their common spiralling search for fulfilment, where boundaries are pushed further and further, while sperm leaks by the gallons... A story less about the addiction to sex or dangerous driving, but more about the growing infatuation with the mechanical, as it slowly overrides bodily desires to entail technoorganic fulfilment. As a car becomes a subject of desire, craving and our bodies seem to merge with its leather seats and metallic odour, Cronenberg shows a new phase of humanity. One devoid of emotion, cold and ever expanding, as desire becomes limitless to the death. Taking the issue of automotive obsession to the extreme "Crash" manages to pack an uneasy wallop, one however that is overlong and for half its running time directionless. Once the premise is clear characters indulge into sexual deviance to sexual deviance with each passing scene pushing themselves further, when the previously passed boundary no longer satisfies the growing need. Although the gist is evident the tirade of weird sex and masturbation becomes tiring and fails to add any further layers to the story. It is hard to blame Cronenberg, as the execution fits the story. Bleak, detached from emotion, jaded and monotonous fulfils the goal of presenting the lingering disconnect of characters, which are so lost in lack of feeling, whilst trying to discover fulfilment. Especially apparent when Ballard and Catherine have sex - physical pleasure is achieved, but emotional fulfilment is non-achievable. Therefore the search for emotion (one induced by the adrenaline rush of a crash) triggers a longing for more of this natural drug, but at the same time increasing the level required for satisfaction. This self-destructive behaviour is so natural, so human, but achieved through such dehumanised means... A tough piece of fiction, which is hard fought to be called pleasant, but definitely a shocking piece worthy of reflection and afterthought, not necessarily admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The quest for happiness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyma_Rizwaan_Khan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been noticing a lot of people watch Gus Van Sant or Cronenberg and they use the words 'pretentious' and 'hack'. I suppose the effect a piece of art has on you also says something about you as a person. The more disturbing art is the more you hear people discussing it - more and more people asking other people not to watch this because it is 'sick and twisted and disgusting'. But I for one, am pretty sure there is nothing pretentious about this movie. Hacks don't make movies like CRASH which barely receive any mainstream attention - they release movies like TWILIGHT and sit back and watch the money roll in. The movie is about a bunch of people trying to find the ultimate pleasure - and what is more pleasurable than a climax right? They have everything they need - good bodies, cars, jobs, good looking people around them and all the things people think are necessary and yet they find themselves feeling empty. All of a sudden, they end up becoming obsessed with car crashes and victims of car crashes. They feel like this is the way to get what they are lacking. But no matter how far, how sinister - how truly invigorating their experiences are, they cannot find happiness. That's what this movie is about - the quest for happiness - for that feeling of knowing joy of some kind. And whether or not it is possible to find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pontifikator
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people. Their sexual turn-on is car wrecks, and they cause them when they can't find them by chance. This movie, directed by David Cronenberg, is based on a novel by J. G. Ballard. This is a disturbing film. The sex scenes approach soft core porn, as the characters paw and grope each other, and there is rampant fetishism as well. However, I was unable to care about the characters. Casting James Spader as the lead guarantees a performance of flat affect. This sometimes works (as in "sex, lies, and videotape," when he plays a weird voyeur), but when he is the main character and I can't begin to like him or feel sympathy for him, it wrecks the movie for me. The problem with the film from my point of view is that I'm never given any reason to identify with these people and to care about their drive for this particular form of fetishism. I suspect the sex aspect of the film was too difficult for the director and/or the actors (including Holly Hunter, Elias Koteas, and Deborah Kara Unger) for them to develop their roles fully. Instead of some fascinating insight into a world I'd never heard of, I saw moments of soft core sex interspersed with dialog from affectless characters about whom I learned nothing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty dreary, but also undeniably fascinating.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer / producer / director David Cronenberg's grim adaptation of the J.G. Ballard novel tells the story of James Ballard (James Spader), who gets into a horrible car accident that actually has a stunning effect on his life, in particular his sex life. He and wife Catherine (Deborah Kara Unger) find themselves now inexorably drawn to the violence and destruction of car crashes and even the effect that such crashes have on the human body. They soon discover an underground group of people that celebrate this creepy fetish, led by the intense Vaughan (Elias Koteas), who with the help of stuntman friends recreates famous crashes involving celebrities (such as James Dean). Cronenberg is obviously a perfect choice to direct this sort of story, which obviously is not going to appeal to a lot of people but may very well intrigue some. It never gets too far into the heads of its characters, but doesn't really judge them, either, and illustrates how these individuals obsess over creating some sort of meaning in their lives and how human beings can attach a sexual element to just about anything. The weather in this Toronto-shot film is appropriately gloomy, matching the mood of the story telling, while the blood and gore is actually never overdone. Really, Cronenberg keeps the focus on the sexual nature of the story and characters and with the help of his very willing performers creates some very erotic scenes, of both the heterosexual and homosexual variety. There's some caressing of vehicle damage to go with the caressing of human bodies. The deeply committed cast, also including Holly Hunter and Rosanna Arquette, helps to draw you into this tale, while Howard Shore supplies a music score in his typical grandiose, full-of-foreboding style. Koteas is a standout as Vaughan. The film isn't perfect overall, as has already been mentioned, but it may keep some viewers watching due to the sexual frankness and explicitness on display. (This is available in both a 90 minute long R rated version and a 100 minute long NC-17 rated version.) Still, even with its flaws it leaves a fairly big impression; it's not likely it'll be easily forgotten. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The one thing Cronenberg has always unquestionably been talented at is weaving a highly disturbing atmosphere, and he does that beautifully on Crash. Unfortunately, though, the movie doesn't quite manage to draw the viewer into that atmosphere. It's meant as a metaphor for mankind's obsessions and perversions, but the horror is being piled on so thickly that I never once found myself immersed in any of the characters or caring about what happens to them, other than loathing them. James Spader is as fantastic as ever in exploring the depth of human perversion, and as always he manages a delicate balance of naive and sleazy, but he did better in subtler works like Secretary and Sex, Lies & Videotape.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Cronenberg must have been insane or under severe medication to write, produce and direct Crash, which is one of the worst movies that I have ever seen. It opens at an airplane hangar where James Spader character is grinding against his wife in a brief encounter, and within seconds is doing the nasty with an Asian woman in a camera room at a film set. Shortly afterwords, he is driving down the road and crashes head on into another car. A man goes through the windshield, but his wife, played by Holly Hunter is bloodied, and she is shown in the passenger seat without a bra, and her breast is noticed by Spader. He is bruised and recovering at a hospital and meets the survivor by chance, in the hallway. For some unknown reason, he visits the salvage yard to look at his wrecked car; and guess who just happens to be there at the same time; Holly Hunter, of course. He drives her to the airport and they have sex in the front seat of his car after discussing the bad traffic situation. He then goes back to his wife, and they get frisky. They apparently have an open marriage. We then meet a guy, Vaughan, who is obsessed with car accidents. He even reenacts the James Dean crash from 1955 with the same Porsche. Rosanna Arquette is Vaughan's prosthetic wearing friend, and we are given plenty of strange sexual quirks, such as scar worship. Vaughan rambles on with psycho babble and I was bored within the first thirty minutes of this garbage. Besides the bad script, the soundtrack, is annoying beyond description. A guitar playing with inordinate amounts of reverb is heard from beginning to end. Crash is a crashing bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trash! For perverts only (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the movie already sucked abusively my time by watching it, i won't give it much for my review. In short, this movie belongs to my black list of useless, pretentious, stupid movies that try to depict the worst depravities as an interest for art (as "Blow", "Irreversible"). What's worst is that, as usual, the addition of big names (here, Cronenberg, Holly Hunter) tries hypocritically to give respectability and the movie establishment gives dumbly prizes to such crap! There's only one truth to remember: there's nothing romantic or light about licentiousness: those people are cruel and dehumanized!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nihlistic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a novel by J.G. Ballad Crash was a highly controversial film when it was first released when it was released in 1996 for its depiction of sex and violence. Whilst it is controversial for a few scenes, its actual problem is that it a bad film. Director David Cronenberg has made so excellent films in many different genres, but Crash is a very shallow, nihilistic film about nothing. There are many problems with the film, it has the visual look and style of a TV film, characters with not much characterisation, people speaking in quiet tones and James Spader was a bland lead. Despite the film's attempts to have a said about the changing nature of sexuality in the world of technology, a look at subcultures, how people enjoy danger and thrills and sexual fetishes. But on the whole Crash is a film that has nothing to say about its subject matter and this is Cronenberg at his worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange, Stylish, Fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the great qualities of this film is the ability to constantly astonish with its relentless, shocking strangeness. "Crash" is most likely to leave viewers speechless, even those who are used to "weird" or unconventional. None of the scenes are gratuitous however, and "Crash" looks extremely stylish, as well as twisted enough to make one uneasy. Fortunately, this isn't 'cheap shocks' and the usual exploitation fare filmmakers throw in to stir some "controversy". Perverted addicts leading corrupt lives never been more fascinating. These people are craving some basic fulfillment, but are doomed to never achieve it in life. Metaphysical allegory? Probably. It's also a cold analysis of self-destructive compulsion. What's offensive is that these characters never even stop to consider the moral implications of their actions - hurting others who don't share their "hobby". Even if they did, it wouldn't make much of a difference, because they simply can't stop. Like Lynch, Cronenberg doesn't spoon-feed the "message" to the audience, so there are no answers, only uncomfortable but equally valid questions. I guess it takes guts to ask them. Dialogue is minimal and clever, and keeps the characters sealed. The narrative is filled with long pauses, eerie metallic riffs, empty glances directed inwards. Physical encounters are depersonalized and compulsive. There are always people around at the scene of sexual encounters or car crashes, and yet nobody bothers to notice or intervene. It's a surreal landscape of urban alienation that associates with voyeurism. Steel-cold (the unsettling score hits the right note as well), clinical in its depictions, "Crash" has a clean sharp edge that only a handful of directors could walk on with such elegance, insight and a sort of detachment that has a dream-like quality. All the actors are fearless and did a splendid job, especially James Spader, who is great as usual. He was born to play this role, with his other-worldly, strangely absent stare and androgynous beauty (It's surprising David Lynch never worked with him!). Spader's surreal performance is mind-blowing, as he gracefully carries along that creepy Cronenberg vibe. This is the same Spader who stole the show as the intriguing voyeur in "Sex, Lies and Videotape" and who would later do it again in the offbeat "Secretary". His other roles just didn't do justice to him. Likewise, Deborah Unger manages to turn into an abstraction, whispering her lines, floating in the same trance of addiction. The sexual scenes are elegantly choreographed. It's bizarre, disturbing and at times funny altogether, with a pretty sick sense of humor that's absolutely fantastic to a minority of people who can appreciate it. "Crash" explores sexual compulsion in a sterile environment, you can almost taste the metal. This is Cronenberg's best work and one of the most fascinating, audacious films ever made. Clearly not for everybody, but for those who enjoy the Absurd in all its complexity. Unforgettable cult classic to be watched in the uncut version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely for Anyone...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crash is a erotic drama by David Cronnenberg that explores a group of people that get sexually aroused by car crashes. It's probably the least accessible film Cronnenberg has made to date due to it's extreme amounts of fairly explicit sex, weird sexual fetishes and very muddled script. The cast does a wonderful job with the very limited material given. We have James Spader, Elias Koteas, Holly Hunter, Deborah Kara Unger and Rosanna Arquette to name a few. It's a nice thing that those actors showed some guts for doing this borderline softcore sex film. The NC-17 rating is very baffling to me. It's about as explicit in it's sexual content as 70's Japanese exploitation films like Sex and Fury or Female Prisoner Scorpion. It's hardly pornographic or even that extreme in terms of it's sexual fetishes so the NC-17 rating is pretty much an overkill. Crash doesn't have a real plot to speak of and most of the scenes start or end up with people having sex or grabbing each others crotches. It's all about the characters and the situations they go through but the muddled script doesn't really help that. Crash is mostly all surface and has very little depth to be had aside from the sex and the bizarre dialog. So either you will like this film and what it has to offer or you will despise it and just dismiss it as porn. I can't really recommend seeing Crash, unless you are very interested in the work of David Cronnenberg. So unless you are looking for some strange films about sexual fetishes and James Spader, your not going to enjoy this film as conventional entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Distant and detached - if HAL3000 made a movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Crash" remains Cronenberg's most controversial movies. Permeating with sex and obscenity, coupled with obsessions of both bodily and mechanical nature, it was born on shock factor. Film producer James Ballard (James Spader) and his promiscuous wife Catherine (the voluptuous Deborah Kara Unger) lead a life of mutually accepted sexual ventures, searching for ultimate satisfaction by indulging into various affairs. A car accident featuring Helen Remington (Holly Hunter) introduces another level of compulsive sexual mania - where sexual desires and metal mesh together to form a hybrid of death, car crashes and orgiastic pleasure. This introduces both James and Catherine to the Vaughan (Elias Koteas) and their common spiralling search for fulfilment, where boundaries are pushed further and further, while sperm leaks by the gallons... A story less about the addiction to sex or dangerous driving, but more about the growing infatuation with the mechanical, as it slowly overrides bodily desires to entail technoorganic fulfilment. As a car becomes a subject of desire, craving and our bodies seem to merge with its leather seats and metallic odour, Cronenberg shows a new phase of humanity. One devoid of emotion, cold and ever expanding, as desire becomes limitless to the death. Taking the issue of automotive obsession to the extreme "Crash" manages to pack an uneasy wallop, one however that is overlong and for half its running time directionless. Once the premise is clear characters indulge into sexual deviance to sexual deviance with each passing scene pushing themselves further, when the previously passed boundary no longer satisfies the growing need. Although the gist is evident the tirade of weird sex and masturbation becomes tiring and fails to add any further layers to the story. It is hard to blame Cronenberg, as the execution fits the story. Bleak, detached from emotion, jaded and monotonous fulfils the goal of presenting the lingering disconnect of characters, which are so lost in lack of feeling, whilst trying to discover fulfilment. Especially apparent when Ballard and Catherine have sex - physical pleasure is achieved, but emotional fulfilment is non-achievable. Therefore the search for emotion (one induced by the adrenaline rush of a crash) triggers a longing for more of this natural drug, but at the same time increasing the level required for satisfaction. This self-destructive behaviour is so natural, so human, but achieved through such dehumanised means... A tough piece of fiction, which is hard fought to be called pleasant, but definitely a shocking piece worthy of reflection and afterthought, not necessarily admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The quest for happiness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyma_Rizwaan_Khan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been noticing a lot of people watch Gus Van Sant or Cronenberg and they use the words 'pretentious' and 'hack'. I suppose the effect a piece of art has on you also says something about you as a person. The more disturbing art is the more you hear people discussing it - more and more people asking other people not to watch this because it is 'sick and twisted and disgusting'. But I for one, am pretty sure there is nothing pretentious about this movie. Hacks don't make movies like CRASH which barely receive any mainstream attention - they release movies like TWILIGHT and sit back and watch the money roll in. The movie is about a bunch of people trying to find the ultimate pleasure - and what is more pleasurable than a climax right? They have everything they need - good bodies, cars, jobs, good looking people around them and all the things people think are necessary and yet they find themselves feeling empty. All of a sudden, they end up becoming obsessed with car crashes and victims of car crashes. They feel like this is the way to get what they are lacking. But no matter how far, how sinister - how truly invigorating their experiences are, they cannot find happiness. That's what this movie is about - the quest for happiness - for that feeling of knowing joy of some kind. And whether or not it is possible to find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pontifikator
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people. Their sexual turn-on is car wrecks, and they cause them when they can't find them by chance. This movie, directed by David Cronenberg, is based on a novel by J. G. Ballard. This is a disturbing film. The sex scenes approach soft core porn, as the characters paw and grope each other, and there is rampant fetishism as well. However, I was unable to care about the characters. Casting James Spader as the lead guarantees a performance of flat affect. This sometimes works (as in "sex, lies, and videotape," when he plays a weird voyeur), but when he is the main character and I can't begin to like him or feel sympathy for him, it wrecks the movie for me. The problem with the film from my point of view is that I'm never given any reason to identify with these people and to care about their drive for this particular form of fetishism. I suspect the sex aspect of the film was too difficult for the director and/or the actors (including Holly Hunter, Elias Koteas, and Deborah Kara Unger) for them to develop their roles fully. Instead of some fascinating insight into a world I'd never heard of, I saw moments of soft core sex interspersed with dialog from affectless characters about whom I learned nothing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty dreary, but also undeniably fascinating.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer / producer / director David Cronenberg's grim adaptation of the J.G. Ballard novel tells the story of James Ballard (James Spader), who gets into a horrible car accident that actually has a stunning effect on his life, in particular his sex life. He and wife Catherine (Deborah Kara Unger) find themselves now inexorably drawn to the violence and destruction of car crashes and even the effect that such crashes have on the human body. They soon discover an underground group of people that celebrate this creepy fetish, led by the intense Vaughan (Elias Koteas), who with the help of stuntman friends recreates famous crashes involving celebrities (such as James Dean). Cronenberg is obviously a perfect choice to direct this sort of story, which obviously is not going to appeal to a lot of people but may very well intrigue some. It never gets too far into the heads of its characters, but doesn't really judge them, either, and illustrates how these individuals obsess over creating some sort of meaning in their lives and how human beings can attach a sexual element to just about anything. The weather in this Toronto-shot film is appropriately gloomy, matching the mood of the story telling, while the blood and gore is actually never overdone. Really, Cronenberg keeps the focus on the sexual nature of the story and characters and with the help of his very willing performers creates some very erotic scenes, of both the heterosexual and homosexual variety. There's some caressing of vehicle damage to go with the caressing of human bodies. The deeply committed cast, also including Holly Hunter and Rosanna Arquette, helps to draw you into this tale, while Howard Shore supplies a music score in his typical grandiose, full-of-foreboding style. Koteas is a standout as Vaughan. The film isn't perfect overall, as has already been mentioned, but it may keep some viewers watching due to the sexual frankness and explicitness on display. (This is available in both a 90 minute long R rated version and a 100 minute long NC-17 rated version.) Still, even with its flaws it leaves a fairly big impression; it's not likely it'll be easily forgotten. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The one thing Cronenberg has always unquestionably been talented at is weaving a highly disturbing atmosphere, and he does that beautifully on Crash. Unfortunately, though, the movie doesn't quite manage to draw the viewer into that atmosphere. It's meant as a metaphor for mankind's obsessions and perversions, but the horror is being piled on so thickly that I never once found myself immersed in any of the characters or caring about what happens to them, other than loathing them. James Spader is as fantastic as ever in exploring the depth of human perversion, and as always he manages a delicate balance of naive and sleazy, but he did better in subtler works like Secretary and Sex, Lies & Videotape.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Cronenberg must have been insane or under severe medication to write, produce and direct Crash, which is one of the worst movies that I have ever seen. It opens at an airplane hangar where James Spader character is grinding against his wife in a brief encounter, and within seconds is doing the nasty with an Asian woman in a camera room at a film set. Shortly afterwords, he is driving down the road and crashes head on into another car. A man goes through the windshield, but his wife, played by Holly Hunter is bloodied, and she is shown in the passenger seat without a bra, and her breast is noticed by Spader. He is bruised and recovering at a hospital and meets the survivor by chance, in the hallway. For some unknown reason, he visits the salvage yard to look at his wrecked car; and guess who just happens to be there at the same time; Holly Hunter, of course. He drives her to the airport and they have sex in the front seat of his car after discussing the bad traffic situation. He then goes back to his wife, and they get frisky. They apparently have an open marriage. We then meet a guy, Vaughan, who is obsessed with car accidents. He even reenacts the James Dean crash from 1955 with the same Porsche. Rosanna Arquette is Vaughan's prosthetic wearing friend, and we are given plenty of strange sexual quirks, such as scar worship. Vaughan rambles on with psycho babble and I was bored within the first thirty minutes of this garbage. Besides the bad script, the soundtrack, is annoying beyond description. A guitar playing with inordinate amounts of reverb is heard from beginning to end. Crash is a crashing bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trash! For perverts only (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the movie already sucked abusively my time by watching it, i won't give it much for my review. In short, this movie belongs to my black list of useless, pretentious, stupid movies that try to depict the worst depravities as an interest for art (as "Blow", "Irreversible"). What's worst is that, as usual, the addition of big names (here, Cronenberg, Holly Hunter) tries hypocritically to give respectability and the movie establishment gives dumbly prizes to such crap! There's only one truth to remember: there's nothing romantic or light about licentiousness: those people are cruel and dehumanized!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nihlistic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a novel by J.G. Ballad Crash was a highly controversial film when it was first released when it was released in 1996 for its depiction of sex and violence. Whilst it is controversial for a few scenes, its actual problem is that it a bad film. Director David Cronenberg has made so excellent films in many different genres, but Crash is a very shallow, nihilistic film about nothing. There are many problems with the film, it has the visual look and style of a TV film, characters with not much characterisation, people speaking in quiet tones and James Spader was a bland lead. Despite the film's attempts to have a said about the changing nature of sexuality in the world of technology, a look at subcultures, how people enjoy danger and thrills and sexual fetishes. But on the whole Crash is a film that has nothing to say about its subject matter and this is Cronenberg at his worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange, Stylish, Fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the great qualities of this film is the ability to constantly astonish with its relentless, shocking strangeness. "Crash" is most likely to leave viewers speechless, even those who are used to "weird" or unconventional. None of the scenes are gratuitous however, and "Crash" looks extremely stylish, as well as twisted enough to make one uneasy. Fortunately, this isn't 'cheap shocks' and the usual exploitation fare filmmakers throw in to stir some "controversy". Perverted addicts leading corrupt lives never been more fascinating. These people are craving some basic fulfillment, but are doomed to never achieve it in life. Metaphysical allegory? Probably. It's also a cold analysis of self-destructive compulsion. What's offensive is that these characters never even stop to consider the moral implications of their actions - hurting others who don't share their "hobby". Even if they did, it wouldn't make much of a difference, because they simply can't stop. Like Lynch, Cronenberg doesn't spoon-feed the "message" to the audience, so there are no answers, only uncomfortable but equally valid questions. I guess it takes guts to ask them. Dialogue is minimal and clever, and keeps the characters sealed. The narrative is filled with long pauses, eerie metallic riffs, empty glances directed inwards. Physical encounters are depersonalized and compulsive. There are always people around at the scene of sexual encounters or car crashes, and yet nobody bothers to notice or intervene. It's a surreal landscape of urban alienation that associates with voyeurism. Steel-cold (the unsettling score hits the right note as well), clinical in its depictions, "Crash" has a clean sharp edge that only a handful of directors could walk on with such elegance, insight and a sort of detachment that has a dream-like quality. All the actors are fearless and did a splendid job, especially James Spader, who is great as usual. He was born to play this role, with his other-worldly, strangely absent stare and androgynous beauty (It's surprising David Lynch never worked with him!). Spader's surreal performance is mind-blowing, as he gracefully carries along that creepy Cronenberg vibe. This is the same Spader who stole the show as the intriguing voyeur in "Sex, Lies and Videotape" and who would later do it again in the offbeat "Secretary". His other roles just didn't do justice to him. Likewise, Deborah Unger manages to turn into an abstraction, whispering her lines, floating in the same trance of addiction. The sexual scenes are elegantly choreographed. It's bizarre, disturbing and at times funny altogether, with a pretty sick sense of humor that's absolutely fantastic to a minority of people who can appreciate it. "Crash" explores sexual compulsion in a sterile environment, you can almost taste the metal. This is Cronenberg's best work and one of the most fascinating, audacious films ever made. Clearly not for everybody, but for those who enjoy the Absurd in all its complexity. Unforgettable cult classic to be watched in the uncut version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely for Anyone...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crash is a erotic drama by David Cronnenberg that explores a group of people that get sexually aroused by car crashes. It's probably the least accessible film Cronnenberg has made to date due to it's extreme amounts of fairly explicit sex, weird sexual fetishes and very muddled script. The cast does a wonderful job with the very limited material given. We have James Spader, Elias Koteas, Holly Hunter, Deborah Kara Unger and Rosanna Arquette to name a few. It's a nice thing that those actors showed some guts for doing this borderline softcore sex film. The NC-17 rating is very baffling to me. It's about as explicit in it's sexual content as 70's Japanese exploitation films like Sex and Fury or Female Prisoner Scorpion. It's hardly pornographic or even that extreme in terms of it's sexual fetishes so the NC-17 rating is pretty much an overkill. Crash doesn't have a real plot to speak of and most of the scenes start or end up with people having sex or grabbing each others crotches. It's all about the characters and the situations they go through but the muddled script doesn't really help that. Crash is mostly all surface and has very little depth to be had aside from the sex and the bizarre dialog. So either you will like this film and what it has to offer or you will despise it and just dismiss it as porn. I can't really recommend seeing Crash, unless you are very interested in the work of David Cronnenberg. So unless you are looking for some strange films about sexual fetishes and James Spader, your not going to enjoy this film as conventional entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Distant and detached - if HAL3000 made a movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Crash" remains Cronenberg's most controversial movies. Permeating with sex and obscenity, coupled with obsessions of both bodily and mechanical nature, it was born on shock factor. Film producer James Ballard (James Spader) and his promiscuous wife Catherine (the voluptuous Deborah Kara Unger) lead a life of mutually accepted sexual ventures, searching for ultimate satisfaction by indulging into various affairs. A car accident featuring Helen Remington (Holly Hunter) introduces another level of compulsive sexual mania - where sexual desires and metal mesh together to form a hybrid of death, car crashes and orgiastic pleasure. This introduces both James and Catherine to the Vaughan (Elias Koteas) and their common spiralling search for fulfilment, where boundaries are pushed further and further, while sperm leaks by the gallons... A story less about the addiction to sex or dangerous driving, but more about the growing infatuation with the mechanical, as it slowly overrides bodily desires to entail technoorganic fulfilment. As a car becomes a subject of desire, craving and our bodies seem to merge with its leather seats and metallic odour, Cronenberg shows a new phase of humanity. One devoid of emotion, cold and ever expanding, as desire becomes limitless to the death. Taking the issue of automotive obsession to the extreme "Crash" manages to pack an uneasy wallop, one however that is overlong and for half its running time directionless. Once the premise is clear characters indulge into sexual deviance to sexual deviance with each passing scene pushing themselves further, when the previously passed boundary no longer satisfies the growing need. Although the gist is evident the tirade of weird sex and masturbation becomes tiring and fails to add any further layers to the story. It is hard to blame Cronenberg, as the execution fits the story. Bleak, detached from emotion, jaded and monotonous fulfils the goal of presenting the lingering disconnect of characters, which are so lost in lack of feeling, whilst trying to discover fulfilment. Especially apparent when Ballard and Catherine have sex - physical pleasure is achieved, but emotional fulfilment is non-achievable. Therefore the search for emotion (one induced by the adrenaline rush of a crash) triggers a longing for more of this natural drug, but at the same time increasing the level required for satisfaction. This self-destructive behaviour is so natural, so human, but achieved through such dehumanised means... A tough piece of fiction, which is hard fought to be called pleasant, but definitely a shocking piece worthy of reflection and afterthought, not necessarily admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The quest for happiness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyma_Rizwaan_Khan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been noticing a lot of people watch Gus Van Sant or Cronenberg and they use the words 'pretentious' and 'hack'. I suppose the effect a piece of art has on you also says something about you as a person. The more disturbing art is the more you hear people discussing it - more and more people asking other people not to watch this because it is 'sick and twisted and disgusting'. But I for one, am pretty sure there is nothing pretentious about this movie. Hacks don't make movies like CRASH which barely receive any mainstream attention - they release movies like TWILIGHT and sit back and watch the money roll in. The movie is about a bunch of people trying to find the ultimate pleasure - and what is more pleasurable than a climax right? They have everything they need - good bodies, cars, jobs, good looking people around them and all the things people think are necessary and yet they find themselves feeling empty. All of a sudden, they end up becoming obsessed with car crashes and victims of car crashes. They feel like this is the way to get what they are lacking. But no matter how far, how sinister - how truly invigorating their experiences are, they cannot find happiness. That's what this movie is about - the quest for happiness - for that feeling of knowing joy of some kind. And whether or not it is possible to find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pontifikator
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people. Their sexual turn-on is car wrecks, and they cause them when they can't find them by chance. This movie, directed by David Cronenberg, is based on a novel by J. G. Ballard. This is a disturbing film. The sex scenes approach soft core porn, as the characters paw and grope each other, and there is rampant fetishism as well. However, I was unable to care about the characters. Casting James Spader as the lead guarantees a performance of flat affect. This sometimes works (as in "sex, lies, and videotape," when he plays a weird voyeur), but when he is the main character and I can't begin to like him or feel sympathy for him, it wrecks the movie for me. The problem with the film from my point of view is that I'm never given any reason to identify with these people and to care about their drive for this particular form of fetishism. I suspect the sex aspect of the film was too difficult for the director and/or the actors (including Holly Hunter, Elias Koteas, and Deborah Kara Unger) for them to develop their roles fully. Instead of some fascinating insight into a world I'd never heard of, I saw moments of soft core sex interspersed with dialog from affectless characters about whom I learned nothing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty dreary, but also undeniably fascinating.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer / producer / director David Cronenberg's grim adaptation of the J.G. Ballard novel tells the story of James Ballard (James Spader), who gets into a horrible car accident that actually has a stunning effect on his life, in particular his sex life. He and wife Catherine (Deborah Kara Unger) find themselves now inexorably drawn to the violence and destruction of car crashes and even the effect that such crashes have on the human body. They soon discover an underground group of people that celebrate this creepy fetish, led by the intense Vaughan (Elias Koteas), who with the help of stuntman friends recreates famous crashes involving celebrities (such as James Dean). Cronenberg is obviously a perfect choice to direct this sort of story, which obviously is not going to appeal to a lot of people but may very well intrigue some. It never gets too far into the heads of its characters, but doesn't really judge them, either, and illustrates how these individuals obsess over creating some sort of meaning in their lives and how human beings can attach a sexual element to just about anything. The weather in this Toronto-shot film is appropriately gloomy, matching the mood of the story telling, while the blood and gore is actually never overdone. Really, Cronenberg keeps the focus on the sexual nature of the story and characters and with the help of his very willing performers creates some very erotic scenes, of both the heterosexual and homosexual variety. There's some caressing of vehicle damage to go with the caressing of human bodies. The deeply committed cast, also including Holly Hunter and Rosanna Arquette, helps to draw you into this tale, while Howard Shore supplies a music score in his typical grandiose, full-of-foreboding style. Koteas is a standout as Vaughan. The film isn't perfect overall, as has already been mentioned, but it may keep some viewers watching due to the sexual frankness and explicitness on display. (This is available in both a 90 minute long R rated version and a 100 minute long NC-17 rated version.) Still, even with its flaws it leaves a fairly big impression; it's not likely it'll be easily forgotten. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The one thing Cronenberg has always unquestionably been talented at is weaving a highly disturbing atmosphere, and he does that beautifully on Crash. Unfortunately, though, the movie doesn't quite manage to draw the viewer into that atmosphere. It's meant as a metaphor for mankind's obsessions and perversions, but the horror is being piled on so thickly that I never once found myself immersed in any of the characters or caring about what happens to them, other than loathing them. James Spader is as fantastic as ever in exploring the depth of human perversion, and as always he manages a delicate balance of naive and sleazy, but he did better in subtler works like Secretary and Sex, Lies & Videotape.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Cronenberg must have been insane or under severe medication to write, produce and direct Crash, which is one of the worst movies that I have ever seen. It opens at an airplane hangar where James Spader character is grinding against his wife in a brief encounter, and within seconds is doing the nasty with an Asian woman in a camera room at a film set. Shortly afterwords, he is driving down the road and crashes head on into another car. A man goes through the windshield, but his wife, played by Holly Hunter is bloodied, and she is shown in the passenger seat without a bra, and her breast is noticed by Spader. He is bruised and recovering at a hospital and meets the survivor by chance, in the hallway. For some unknown reason, he visits the salvage yard to look at his wrecked car; and guess who just happens to be there at the same time; Holly Hunter, of course. He drives her to the airport and they have sex in the front seat of his car after discussing the bad traffic situation. He then goes back to his wife, and they get frisky. They apparently have an open marriage. We then meet a guy, Vaughan, who is obsessed with car accidents. He even reenacts the James Dean crash from 1955 with the same Porsche. Rosanna Arquette is Vaughan's prosthetic wearing friend, and we are given plenty of strange sexual quirks, such as scar worship. Vaughan rambles on with psycho babble and I was bored within the first thirty minutes of this garbage. Besides the bad script, the soundtrack, is annoying beyond description. A guitar playing with inordinate amounts of reverb is heard from beginning to end. Crash is a crashing bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trash! For perverts only (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the movie already sucked abusively my time by watching it, i won't give it much for my review. In short, this movie belongs to my black list of useless, pretentious, stupid movies that try to depict the worst depravities as an interest for art (as "Blow", "Irreversible"). What's worst is that, as usual, the addition of big names (here, Cronenberg, Holly Hunter) tries hypocritically to give respectability and the movie establishment gives dumbly prizes to such crap! There's only one truth to remember: there's nothing romantic or light about licentiousness: those people are cruel and dehumanized!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nihlistic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a novel by J.G. Ballad Crash was a highly controversial film when it was first released when it was released in 1996 for its depiction of sex and violence. Whilst it is controversial for a few scenes, its actual problem is that it a bad film. Director David Cronenberg has made so excellent films in many different genres, but Crash is a very shallow, nihilistic film about nothing. There are many problems with the film, it has the visual look and style of a TV film, characters with not much characterisation, people speaking in quiet tones and James Spader was a bland lead. Despite the film's attempts to have a said about the changing nature of sexuality in the world of technology, a look at subcultures, how people enjoy danger and thrills and sexual fetishes. But on the whole Crash is a film that has nothing to say about its subject matter and this is Cronenberg at his worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange, Stylish, Fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the great qualities of this film is the ability to constantly astonish with its relentless, shocking strangeness. "Crash" is most likely to leave viewers speechless, even those who are used to "weird" or unconventional. None of the scenes are gratuitous however, and "Crash" looks extremely stylish, as well as twisted enough to make one uneasy. Fortunately, this isn't 'cheap shocks' and the usual exploitation fare filmmakers throw in to stir some "controversy". Perverted addicts leading corrupt lives never been more fascinating. These people are craving some basic fulfillment, but are doomed to never achieve it in life. Metaphysical allegory? Probably. It's also a cold analysis of self-destructive compulsion. What's offensive is that these characters never even stop to consider the moral implications of their actions - hurting others who don't share their "hobby". Even if they did, it wouldn't make much of a difference, because they simply can't stop. Like Lynch, Cronenberg doesn't spoon-feed the "message" to the audience, so there are no answers, only uncomfortable but equally valid questions. I guess it takes guts to ask them. Dialogue is minimal and clever, and keeps the characters sealed. The narrative is filled with long pauses, eerie metallic riffs, empty glances directed inwards. Physical encounters are depersonalized and compulsive. There are always people around at the scene of sexual encounters or car crashes, and yet nobody bothers to notice or intervene. It's a surreal landscape of urban alienation that associates with voyeurism. Steel-cold (the unsettling score hits the right note as well), clinical in its depictions, "Crash" has a clean sharp edge that only a handful of directors could walk on with such elegance, insight and a sort of detachment that has a dream-like quality. All the actors are fearless and did a splendid job, especially James Spader, who is great as usual. He was born to play this role, with his other-worldly, strangely absent stare and androgynous beauty (It's surprising David Lynch never worked with him!). Spader's surreal performance is mind-blowing, as he gracefully carries along that creepy Cronenberg vibe. This is the same Spader who stole the show as the intriguing voyeur in "Sex, Lies and Videotape" and who would later do it again in the offbeat "Secretary". His other roles just didn't do justice to him. Likewise, Deborah Unger manages to turn into an abstraction, whispering her lines, floating in the same trance of addiction. The sexual scenes are elegantly choreographed. It's bizarre, disturbing and at times funny altogether, with a pretty sick sense of humor that's absolutely fantastic to a minority of people who can appreciate it. "Crash" explores sexual compulsion in a sterile environment, you can almost taste the metal. This is Cronenberg's best work and one of the most fascinating, audacious films ever made. Clearly not for everybody, but for those who enjoy the Absurd in all its complexity. Unforgettable cult classic to be watched in the uncut version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely for Anyone...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crash is a erotic drama by David Cronnenberg that explores a group of people that get sexually aroused by car crashes. It's probably the least accessible film Cronnenberg has made to date due to it's extreme amounts of fairly explicit sex, weird sexual fetishes and very muddled script. The cast does a wonderful job with the very limited material given. We have James Spader, Elias Koteas, Holly Hunter, Deborah Kara Unger and Rosanna Arquette to name a few. It's a nice thing that those actors showed some guts for doing this borderline softcore sex film. The NC-17 rating is very baffling to me. It's about as explicit in it's sexual content as 70's Japanese exploitation films like Sex and Fury or Female Prisoner Scorpion. It's hardly pornographic or even that extreme in terms of it's sexual fetishes so the NC-17 rating is pretty much an overkill. Crash doesn't have a real plot to speak of and most of the scenes start or end up with people having sex or grabbing each others crotches. It's all about the characters and the situations they go through but the muddled script doesn't really help that. Crash is mostly all surface and has very little depth to be had aside from the sex and the bizarre dialog. So either you will like this film and what it has to offer or you will despise it and just dismiss it as porn. I can't really recommend seeing Crash, unless you are very interested in the work of David Cronnenberg. So unless you are looking for some strange films about sexual fetishes and James Spader, your not going to enjoy this film as conventional entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Distant and detached - if HAL3000 made a movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Crash" remains Cronenberg's most controversial movies. Permeating with sex and obscenity, coupled with obsessions of both bodily and mechanical nature, it was born on shock factor. Film producer James Ballard (James Spader) and his promiscuous wife Catherine (the voluptuous Deborah Kara Unger) lead a life of mutually accepted sexual ventures, searching for ultimate satisfaction by indulging into various affairs. A car accident featuring Helen Remington (Holly Hunter) introduces another level of compulsive sexual mania - where sexual desires and metal mesh together to form a hybrid of death, car crashes and orgiastic pleasure. This introduces both James and Catherine to the Vaughan (Elias Koteas) and their common spiralling search for fulfilment, where boundaries are pushed further and further, while sperm leaks by the gallons... A story less about the addiction to sex or dangerous driving, but more about the growing infatuation with the mechanical, as it slowly overrides bodily desires to entail technoorganic fulfilment. As a car becomes a subject of desire, craving and our bodies seem to merge with its leather seats and metallic odour, Cronenberg shows a new phase of humanity. One devoid of emotion, cold and ever expanding, as desire becomes limitless to the death. Taking the issue of automotive obsession to the extreme "Crash" manages to pack an uneasy wallop, one however that is overlong and for half its running time directionless. Once the premise is clear characters indulge into sexual deviance to sexual deviance with each passing scene pushing themselves further, when the previously passed boundary no longer satisfies the growing need. Although the gist is evident the tirade of weird sex and masturbation becomes tiring and fails to add any further layers to the story. It is hard to blame Cronenberg, as the execution fits the story. Bleak, detached from emotion, jaded and monotonous fulfils the goal of presenting the lingering disconnect of characters, which are so lost in lack of feeling, whilst trying to discover fulfilment. Especially apparent when Ballard and Catherine have sex - physical pleasure is achieved, but emotional fulfilment is non-achievable. Therefore the search for emotion (one induced by the adrenaline rush of a crash) triggers a longing for more of this natural drug, but at the same time increasing the level required for satisfaction. This self-destructive behaviour is so natural, so human, but achieved through such dehumanised means... A tough piece of fiction, which is hard fought to be called pleasant, but definitely a shocking piece worthy of reflection and afterthought, not necessarily admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The quest for happiness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyma_Rizwaan_Khan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been noticing a lot of people watch Gus Van Sant or Cronenberg and they use the words 'pretentious' and 'hack'. I suppose the effect a piece of art has on you also says something about you as a person. The more disturbing art is the more you hear people discussing it - more and more people asking other people not to watch this because it is 'sick and twisted and disgusting'. But I for one, am pretty sure there is nothing pretentious about this movie. Hacks don't make movies like CRASH which barely receive any mainstream attention - they release movies like TWILIGHT and sit back and watch the money roll in. The movie is about a bunch of people trying to find the ultimate pleasure - and what is more pleasurable than a climax right? They have everything they need - good bodies, cars, jobs, good looking people around them and all the things people think are necessary and yet they find themselves feeling empty. All of a sudden, they end up becoming obsessed with car crashes and victims of car crashes. They feel like this is the way to get what they are lacking. But no matter how far, how sinister - how truly invigorating their experiences are, they cannot find happiness. That's what this movie is about - the quest for happiness - for that feeling of knowing joy of some kind. And whether or not it is possible to find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pontifikator
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people. Their sexual turn-on is car wrecks, and they cause them when they can't find them by chance. This movie, directed by David Cronenberg, is based on a novel by J. G. Ballard. This is a disturbing film. The sex scenes approach soft core porn, as the characters paw and grope each other, and there is rampant fetishism as well. However, I was unable to care about the characters. Casting James Spader as the lead guarantees a performance of flat affect. This sometimes works (as in "sex, lies, and videotape," when he plays a weird voyeur), but when he is the main character and I can't begin to like him or feel sympathy for him, it wrecks the movie for me. The problem with the film from my point of view is that I'm never given any reason to identify with these people and to care about their drive for this particular form of fetishism. I suspect the sex aspect of the film was too difficult for the director and/or the actors (including Holly Hunter, Elias Koteas, and Deborah Kara Unger) for them to develop their roles fully. Instead of some fascinating insight into a world I'd never heard of, I saw moments of soft core sex interspersed with dialog from affectless characters about whom I learned nothing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty dreary, but also undeniably fascinating.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer / producer / director David Cronenberg's grim adaptation of the J.G. Ballard novel tells the story of James Ballard (James Spader), who gets into a horrible car accident that actually has a stunning effect on his life, in particular his sex life. He and wife Catherine (Deborah Kara Unger) find themselves now inexorably drawn to the violence and destruction of car crashes and even the effect that such crashes have on the human body. They soon discover an underground group of people that celebrate this creepy fetish, led by the intense Vaughan (Elias Koteas), who with the help of stuntman friends recreates famous crashes involving celebrities (such as James Dean). Cronenberg is obviously a perfect choice to direct this sort of story, which obviously is not going to appeal to a lot of people but may very well intrigue some. It never gets too far into the heads of its characters, but doesn't really judge them, either, and illustrates how these individuals obsess over creating some sort of meaning in their lives and how human beings can attach a sexual element to just about anything. The weather in this Toronto-shot film is appropriately gloomy, matching the mood of the story telling, while the blood and gore is actually never overdone. Really, Cronenberg keeps the focus on the sexual nature of the story and characters and with the help of his very willing performers creates some very erotic scenes, of both the heterosexual and homosexual variety. There's some caressing of vehicle damage to go with the caressing of human bodies. The deeply committed cast, also including Holly Hunter and Rosanna Arquette, helps to draw you into this tale, while Howard Shore supplies a music score in his typical grandiose, full-of-foreboding style. Koteas is a standout as Vaughan. The film isn't perfect overall, as has already been mentioned, but it may keep some viewers watching due to the sexual frankness and explicitness on display. (This is available in both a 90 minute long R rated version and a 100 minute long NC-17 rated version.) Still, even with its flaws it leaves a fairly big impression; it's not likely it'll be easily forgotten. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The one thing Cronenberg has always unquestionably been talented at is weaving a highly disturbing atmosphere, and he does that beautifully on Crash. Unfortunately, though, the movie doesn't quite manage to draw the viewer into that atmosphere. It's meant as a metaphor for mankind's obsessions and perversions, but the horror is being piled on so thickly that I never once found myself immersed in any of the characters or caring about what happens to them, other than loathing them. James Spader is as fantastic as ever in exploring the depth of human perversion, and as always he manages a delicate balance of naive and sleazy, but he did better in subtler works like Secretary and Sex, Lies & Videotape.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Cronenberg must have been insane or under severe medication to write, produce and direct Crash, which is one of the worst movies that I have ever seen. It opens at an airplane hangar where James Spader character is grinding against his wife in a brief encounter, and within seconds is doing the nasty with an Asian woman in a camera room at a film set. Shortly afterwords, he is driving down the road and crashes head on into another car. A man goes through the windshield, but his wife, played by Holly Hunter is bloodied, and she is shown in the passenger seat without a bra, and her breast is noticed by Spader. He is bruised and recovering at a hospital and meets the survivor by chance, in the hallway. For some unknown reason, he visits the salvage yard to look at his wrecked car; and guess who just happens to be there at the same time; Holly Hunter, of course. He drives her to the airport and they have sex in the front seat of his car after discussing the bad traffic situation. He then goes back to his wife, and they get frisky. They apparently have an open marriage. We then meet a guy, Vaughan, who is obsessed with car accidents. He even reenacts the James Dean crash from 1955 with the same Porsche. Rosanna Arquette is Vaughan's prosthetic wearing friend, and we are given plenty of strange sexual quirks, such as scar worship. Vaughan rambles on with psycho babble and I was bored within the first thirty minutes of this garbage. Besides the bad script, the soundtrack, is annoying beyond description. A guitar playing with inordinate amounts of reverb is heard from beginning to end. Crash is a crashing bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trash! For perverts only (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the movie already sucked abusively my time by watching it, i won't give it much for my review. In short, this movie belongs to my black list of useless, pretentious, stupid movies that try to depict the worst depravities as an interest for art (as "Blow", "Irreversible"). What's worst is that, as usual, the addition of big names (here, Cronenberg, Holly Hunter) tries hypocritically to give respectability and the movie establishment gives dumbly prizes to such crap! There's only one truth to remember: there's nothing romantic or light about licentiousness: those people are cruel and dehumanized!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nihlistic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a novel by J.G. Ballad Crash was a highly controversial film when it was first released when it was released in 1996 for its depiction of sex and violence. Whilst it is controversial for a few scenes, its actual problem is that it a bad film. Director David Cronenberg has made so excellent films in many different genres, but Crash is a very shallow, nihilistic film about nothing. There are many problems with the film, it has the visual look and style of a TV film, characters with not much characterisation, people speaking in quiet tones and James Spader was a bland lead. Despite the film's attempts to have a said about the changing nature of sexuality in the world of technology, a look at subcultures, how people enjoy danger and thrills and sexual fetishes. But on the whole Crash is a film that has nothing to say about its subject matter and this is Cronenberg at his worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange, Stylish, Fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the great qualities of this film is the ability to constantly astonish with its relentless, shocking strangeness. "Crash" is most likely to leave viewers speechless, even those who are used to "weird" or unconventional. None of the scenes are gratuitous however, and "Crash" looks extremely stylish, as well as twisted enough to make one uneasy. Fortunately, this isn't 'cheap shocks' and the usual exploitation fare filmmakers throw in to stir some "controversy". Perverted addicts leading corrupt lives never been more fascinating. These people are craving some basic fulfillment, but are doomed to never achieve it in life. Metaphysical allegory? Probably. It's also a cold analysis of self-destructive compulsion. What's offensive is that these characters never even stop to consider the moral implications of their actions - hurting others who don't share their "hobby". Even if they did, it wouldn't make much of a difference, because they simply can't stop. Like Lynch, Cronenberg doesn't spoon-feed the "message" to the audience, so there are no answers, only uncomfortable but equally valid questions. I guess it takes guts to ask them. Dialogue is minimal and clever, and keeps the characters sealed. The narrative is filled with long pauses, eerie metallic riffs, empty glances directed inwards. Physical encounters are depersonalized and compulsive. There are always people around at the scene of sexual encounters or car crashes, and yet nobody bothers to notice or intervene. It's a surreal landscape of urban alienation that associates with voyeurism. Steel-cold (the unsettling score hits the right note as well), clinical in its depictions, "Crash" has a clean sharp edge that only a handful of directors could walk on with such elegance, insight and a sort of detachment that has a dream-like quality. All the actors are fearless and did a splendid job, especially James Spader, who is great as usual. He was born to play this role, with his other-worldly, strangely absent stare and androgynous beauty (It's surprising David Lynch never worked with him!). Spader's surreal performance is mind-blowing, as he gracefully carries along that creepy Cronenberg vibe. This is the same Spader who stole the show as the intriguing voyeur in "Sex, Lies and Videotape" and who would later do it again in the offbeat "Secretary". His other roles just didn't do justice to him. Likewise, Deborah Unger manages to turn into an abstraction, whispering her lines, floating in the same trance of addiction. The sexual scenes are elegantly choreographed. It's bizarre, disturbing and at times funny altogether, with a pretty sick sense of humor that's absolutely fantastic to a minority of people who can appreciate it. "Crash" explores sexual compulsion in a sterile environment, you can almost taste the metal. This is Cronenberg's best work and one of the most fascinating, audacious films ever made. Clearly not for everybody, but for those who enjoy the Absurd in all its complexity. Unforgettable cult classic to be watched in the uncut version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely for Anyone...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crash is a erotic drama by David Cronnenberg that explores a group of people that get sexually aroused by car crashes. It's probably the least accessible film Cronnenberg has made to date due to it's extreme amounts of fairly explicit sex, weird sexual fetishes and very muddled script. The cast does a wonderful job with the very limited material given. We have James Spader, Elias Koteas, Holly Hunter, Deborah Kara Unger and Rosanna Arquette to name a few. It's a nice thing that those actors showed some guts for doing this borderline softcore sex film. The NC-17 rating is very baffling to me. It's about as explicit in it's sexual content as 70's Japanese exploitation films like Sex and Fury or Female Prisoner Scorpion. It's hardly pornographic or even that extreme in terms of it's sexual fetishes so the NC-17 rating is pretty much an overkill. Crash doesn't have a real plot to speak of and most of the scenes start or end up with people having sex or grabbing each others crotches. It's all about the characters and the situations they go through but the muddled script doesn't really help that. Crash is mostly all surface and has very little depth to be had aside from the sex and the bizarre dialog. So either you will like this film and what it has to offer or you will despise it and just dismiss it as porn. I can't really recommend seeing Crash, unless you are very interested in the work of David Cronnenberg. So unless you are looking for some strange films about sexual fetishes and James Spader, your not going to enjoy this film as conventional entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Distant and detached - if HAL3000 made a movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Crash" remains Cronenberg's most controversial movies. Permeating with sex and obscenity, coupled with obsessions of both bodily and mechanical nature, it was born on shock factor. Film producer James Ballard (James Spader) and his promiscuous wife Catherine (the voluptuous Deborah Kara Unger) lead a life of mutually accepted sexual ventures, searching for ultimate satisfaction by indulging into various affairs. A car accident featuring Helen Remington (Holly Hunter) introduces another level of compulsive sexual mania - where sexual desires and metal mesh together to form a hybrid of death, car crashes and orgiastic pleasure. This introduces both James and Catherine to the Vaughan (Elias Koteas) and their common spiralling search for fulfilment, where boundaries are pushed further and further, while sperm leaks by the gallons... A story less about the addiction to sex or dangerous driving, but more about the growing infatuation with the mechanical, as it slowly overrides bodily desires to entail technoorganic fulfilment. As a car becomes a subject of desire, craving and our bodies seem to merge with its leather seats and metallic odour, Cronenberg shows a new phase of humanity. One devoid of emotion, cold and ever expanding, as desire becomes limitless to the death. Taking the issue of automotive obsession to the extreme "Crash" manages to pack an uneasy wallop, one however that is overlong and for half its running time directionless. Once the premise is clear characters indulge into sexual deviance to sexual deviance with each passing scene pushing themselves further, when the previously passed boundary no longer satisfies the growing need. Although the gist is evident the tirade of weird sex and masturbation becomes tiring and fails to add any further layers to the story. It is hard to blame Cronenberg, as the execution fits the story. Bleak, detached from emotion, jaded and monotonous fulfils the goal of presenting the lingering disconnect of characters, which are so lost in lack of feeling, whilst trying to discover fulfilment. Especially apparent when Ballard and Catherine have sex - physical pleasure is achieved, but emotional fulfilment is non-achievable. Therefore the search for emotion (one induced by the adrenaline rush of a crash) triggers a longing for more of this natural drug, but at the same time increasing the level required for satisfaction. This self-destructive behaviour is so natural, so human, but achieved through such dehumanised means... A tough piece of fiction, which is hard fought to be called pleasant, but definitely a shocking piece worthy of reflection and afterthought, not necessarily admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The quest for happiness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyma_Rizwaan_Khan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been noticing a lot of people watch Gus Van Sant or Cronenberg and they use the words 'pretentious' and 'hack'. I suppose the effect a piece of art has on you also says something about you as a person. The more disturbing art is the more you hear people discussing it - more and more people asking other people not to watch this because it is 'sick and twisted and disgusting'. But I for one, am pretty sure there is nothing pretentious about this movie. Hacks don't make movies like CRASH which barely receive any mainstream attention - they release movies like TWILIGHT and sit back and watch the money roll in. The movie is about a bunch of people trying to find the ultimate pleasure - and what is more pleasurable than a climax right? They have everything they need - good bodies, cars, jobs, good looking people around them and all the things people think are necessary and yet they find themselves feeling empty. All of a sudden, they end up becoming obsessed with car crashes and victims of car crashes. They feel like this is the way to get what they are lacking. But no matter how far, how sinister - how truly invigorating their experiences are, they cannot find happiness. That's what this movie is about - the quest for happiness - for that feeling of knowing joy of some kind. And whether or not it is possible to find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pontifikator
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people. Their sexual turn-on is car wrecks, and they cause them when they can't find them by chance. This movie, directed by David Cronenberg, is based on a novel by J. G. Ballard. This is a disturbing film. The sex scenes approach soft core porn, as the characters paw and grope each other, and there is rampant fetishism as well. However, I was unable to care about the characters. Casting James Spader as the lead guarantees a performance of flat affect. This sometimes works (as in "sex, lies, and videotape," when he plays a weird voyeur), but when he is the main character and I can't begin to like him or feel sympathy for him, it wrecks the movie for me. The problem with the film from my point of view is that I'm never given any reason to identify with these people and to care about their drive for this particular form of fetishism. I suspect the sex aspect of the film was too difficult for the director and/or the actors (including Holly Hunter, Elias Koteas, and Deborah Kara Unger) for them to develop their roles fully. Instead of some fascinating insight into a world I'd never heard of, I saw moments of soft core sex interspersed with dialog from affectless characters about whom I learned nothing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty dreary, but also undeniably fascinating.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer / producer / director David Cronenberg's grim adaptation of the J.G. Ballard novel tells the story of James Ballard (James Spader), who gets into a horrible car accident that actually has a stunning effect on his life, in particular his sex life. He and wife Catherine (Deborah Kara Unger) find themselves now inexorably drawn to the violence and destruction of car crashes and even the effect that such crashes have on the human body. They soon discover an underground group of people that celebrate this creepy fetish, led by the intense Vaughan (Elias Koteas), who with the help of stuntman friends recreates famous crashes involving celebrities (such as James Dean). Cronenberg is obviously a perfect choice to direct this sort of story, which obviously is not going to appeal to a lot of people but may very well intrigue some. It never gets too far into the heads of its characters, but doesn't really judge them, either, and illustrates how these individuals obsess over creating some sort of meaning in their lives and how human beings can attach a sexual element to just about anything. The weather in this Toronto-shot film is appropriately gloomy, matching the mood of the story telling, while the blood and gore is actually never overdone. Really, Cronenberg keeps the focus on the sexual nature of the story and characters and with the help of his very willing performers creates some very erotic scenes, of both the heterosexual and homosexual variety. There's some caressing of vehicle damage to go with the caressing of human bodies. The deeply committed cast, also including Holly Hunter and Rosanna Arquette, helps to draw you into this tale, while Howard Shore supplies a music score in his typical grandiose, full-of-foreboding style. Koteas is a standout as Vaughan. The film isn't perfect overall, as has already been mentioned, but it may keep some viewers watching due to the sexual frankness and explicitness on display. (This is available in both a 90 minute long R rated version and a 100 minute long NC-17 rated version.) Still, even with its flaws it leaves a fairly big impression; it's not likely it'll be easily forgotten. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The one thing Cronenberg has always unquestionably been talented at is weaving a highly disturbing atmosphere, and he does that beautifully on Crash. Unfortunately, though, the movie doesn't quite manage to draw the viewer into that atmosphere. It's meant as a metaphor for mankind's obsessions and perversions, but the horror is being piled on so thickly that I never once found myself immersed in any of the characters or caring about what happens to them, other than loathing them. James Spader is as fantastic as ever in exploring the depth of human perversion, and as always he manages a delicate balance of naive and sleazy, but he did better in subtler works like Secretary and Sex, Lies & Videotape.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Cronenberg must have been insane or under severe medication to write, produce and direct Crash, which is one of the worst movies that I have ever seen. It opens at an airplane hangar where James Spader character is grinding against his wife in a brief encounter, and within seconds is doing the nasty with an Asian woman in a camera room at a film set. Shortly afterwords, he is driving down the road and crashes head on into another car. A man goes through the windshield, but his wife, played by Holly Hunter is bloodied, and she is shown in the passenger seat without a bra, and her breast is noticed by Spader. He is bruised and recovering at a hospital and meets the survivor by chance, in the hallway. For some unknown reason, he visits the salvage yard to look at his wrecked car; and guess who just happens to be there at the same time; Holly Hunter, of course. He drives her to the airport and they have sex in the front seat of his car after discussing the bad traffic situation. He then goes back to his wife, and they get frisky. They apparently have an open marriage. We then meet a guy, Vaughan, who is obsessed with car accidents. He even reenacts the James Dean crash from 1955 with the same Porsche. Rosanna Arquette is Vaughan's prosthetic wearing friend, and we are given plenty of strange sexual quirks, such as scar worship. Vaughan rambles on with psycho babble and I was bored within the first thirty minutes of this garbage. Besides the bad script, the soundtrack, is annoying beyond description. A guitar playing with inordinate amounts of reverb is heard from beginning to end. Crash is a crashing bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trash! For perverts only (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the movie already sucked abusively my time by watching it, i won't give it much for my review. In short, this movie belongs to my black list of useless, pretentious, stupid movies that try to depict the worst depravities as an interest for art (as "Blow", "Irreversible"). What's worst is that, as usual, the addition of big names (here, Cronenberg, Holly Hunter) tries hypocritically to give respectability and the movie establishment gives dumbly prizes to such crap! There's only one truth to remember: there's nothing romantic or light about licentiousness: those people are cruel and dehumanized!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nihlistic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a novel by J.G. Ballad Crash was a highly controversial film when it was first released when it was released in 1996 for its depiction of sex and violence. Whilst it is controversial for a few scenes, its actual problem is that it a bad film. Director David Cronenberg has made so excellent films in many different genres, but Crash is a very shallow, nihilistic film about nothing. There are many problems with the film, it has the visual look and style of a TV film, characters with not much characterisation, people speaking in quiet tones and James Spader was a bland lead. Despite the film's attempts to have a said about the changing nature of sexuality in the world of technology, a look at subcultures, how people enjoy danger and thrills and sexual fetishes. But on the whole Crash is a film that has nothing to say about its subject matter and this is Cronenberg at his worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strange, Stylish, Fascinating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the great qualities of this film is the ability to constantly astonish with its relentless, shocking strangeness. "Crash" is most likely to leave viewers speechless, even those who are used to "weird" or unconventional. None of the scenes are gratuitous however, and "Crash" looks extremely stylish, as well as twisted enough to make one uneasy. Fortunately, this isn't 'cheap shocks' and the usual exploitation fare filmmakers throw in to stir some "controversy". Perverted addicts leading corrupt lives never been more fascinating. These people are craving some basic fulfillment, but are doomed to never achieve it in life. Metaphysical allegory? Probably. It's also a cold analysis of self-destructive compulsion. What's offensive is that these characters never even stop to consider the moral implications of their actions - hurting others who don't share their "hobby". Even if they did, it wouldn't make much of a difference, because they simply can't stop. Like Lynch, Cronenberg doesn't spoon-feed the "message" to the audience, so there are no answers, only uncomfortable but equally valid questions. I guess it takes guts to ask them. Dialogue is minimal and clever, and keeps the characters sealed. The narrative is filled with long pauses, eerie metallic riffs, empty glances directed inwards. Physical encounters are depersonalized and compulsive. There are always people around at the scene of sexual encounters or car crashes, and yet nobody bothers to notice or intervene. It's a surreal landscape of urban alienation that associates with voyeurism. Steel-cold (the unsettling score hits the right note as well), clinical in its depictions, "Crash" has a clean sharp edge that only a handful of directors could walk on with such elegance, insight and a sort of detachment that has a dream-like quality. All the actors are fearless and did a splendid job, especially James Spader, who is great as usual. He was born to play this role, with his other-worldly, strangely absent stare and androgynous beauty (It's surprising David Lynch never worked with him!). Spader's surreal performance is mind-blowing, as he gracefully carries along that creepy Cronenberg vibe. This is the same Spader who stole the show as the intriguing voyeur in "Sex, Lies and Videotape" and who would later do it again in the offbeat "Secretary". His other roles just didn't do justice to him. Likewise, Deborah Unger manages to turn into an abstraction, whispering her lines, floating in the same trance of addiction. The sexual scenes are elegantly choreographed. It's bizarre, disturbing and at times funny altogether, with a pretty sick sense of humor that's absolutely fantastic to a minority of people who can appreciate it. "Crash" explores sexual compulsion in a sterile environment, you can almost taste the metal. This is Cronenberg's best work and one of the most fascinating, audacious films ever made. Clearly not for everybody, but for those who enjoy the Absurd in all its complexity. Unforgettable cult classic to be watched in the uncut version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely for Anyone...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crash is a erotic drama by David Cronnenberg that explores a group of people that get sexually aroused by car crashes. It's probably the least accessible film Cronnenberg has made to date due to it's extreme amounts of fairly explicit sex, weird sexual fetishes and very muddled script. The cast does a wonderful job with the very limited material given. We have James Spader, Elias Koteas, Holly Hunter, Deborah Kara Unger and Rosanna Arquette to name a few. It's a nice thing that those actors showed some guts for doing this borderline softcore sex film. The NC-17 rating is very baffling to me. It's about as explicit in it's sexual content as 70's Japanese exploitation films like Sex and Fury or Female Prisoner Scorpion. It's hardly pornographic or even that extreme in terms of it's sexual fetishes so the NC-17 rating is pretty much an overkill. Crash doesn't have a real plot to speak of and most of the scenes start or end up with people having sex or grabbing each others crotches. It's all about the characters and the situations they go through but the muddled script doesn't really help that. Crash is mostly all surface and has very little depth to be had aside from the sex and the bizarre dialog. So either you will like this film and what it has to offer or you will despise it and just dismiss it as porn. I can't really recommend seeing Crash, unless you are very interested in the work of David Cronnenberg. So unless you are looking for some strange films about sexual fetishes and James Spader, your not going to enjoy this film as conventional entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Distant and detached - if HAL3000 made a movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Crash" remains Cronenberg's most controversial movies. Permeating with sex and obscenity, coupled with obsessions of both bodily and mechanical nature, it was born on shock factor. Film producer James Ballard (James Spader) and his promiscuous wife Catherine (the voluptuous Deborah Kara Unger) lead a life of mutually accepted sexual ventures, searching for ultimate satisfaction by indulging into various affairs. A car accident featuring Helen Remington (Holly Hunter) introduces another level of compulsive sexual mania - where sexual desires and metal mesh together to form a hybrid of death, car crashes and orgiastic pleasure. This introduces both James and Catherine to the Vaughan (Elias Koteas) and their common spiralling search for fulfilment, where boundaries are pushed further and further, while sperm leaks by the gallons... A story less about the addiction to sex or dangerous driving, but more about the growing infatuation with the mechanical, as it slowly overrides bodily desires to entail technoorganic fulfilment. As a car becomes a subject of desire, craving and our bodies seem to merge with its leather seats and metallic odour, Cronenberg shows a new phase of humanity. One devoid of emotion, cold and ever expanding, as desire becomes limitless to the death. Taking the issue of automotive obsession to the extreme "Crash" manages to pack an uneasy wallop, one however that is overlong and for half its running time directionless. Once the premise is clear characters indulge into sexual deviance to sexual deviance with each passing scene pushing themselves further, when the previously passed boundary no longer satisfies the growing need. Although the gist is evident the tirade of weird sex and masturbation becomes tiring and fails to add any further layers to the story. It is hard to blame Cronenberg, as the execution fits the story. Bleak, detached from emotion, jaded and monotonous fulfils the goal of presenting the lingering disconnect of characters, which are so lost in lack of feeling, whilst trying to discover fulfilment. Especially apparent when Ballard and Catherine have sex - physical pleasure is achieved, but emotional fulfilment is non-achievable. Therefore the search for emotion (one induced by the adrenaline rush of a crash) triggers a longing for more of this natural drug, but at the same time increasing the level required for satisfaction. This self-destructive behaviour is so natural, so human, but achieved through such dehumanised means... A tough piece of fiction, which is hard fought to be called pleasant, but definitely a shocking piece worthy of reflection and afterthought, not necessarily admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The quest for happiness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyma_Rizwaan_Khan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been noticing a lot of people watch Gus Van Sant or Cronenberg and they use the words 'pretentious' and 'hack'. I suppose the effect a piece of art has on you also says something about you as a person. The more disturbing art is the more you hear people discussing it - more and more people asking other people not to watch this because it is 'sick and twisted and disgusting'. But I for one, am pretty sure there is nothing pretentious about this movie. Hacks don't make movies like CRASH which barely receive any mainstream attention - they release movies like TWILIGHT and sit back and watch the money roll in. The movie is about a bunch of people trying to find the ultimate pleasure - and what is more pleasurable than a climax right? They have everything they need - good bodies, cars, jobs, good looking people around them and all the things people think are necessary and yet they find themselves feeling empty. All of a sudden, they end up becoming obsessed with car crashes and victims of car crashes. They feel like this is the way to get what they are lacking. But no matter how far, how sinister - how truly invigorating their experiences are, they cannot find happiness. That's what this movie is about - the quest for happiness - for that feeling of knowing joy of some kind. And whether or not it is possible to find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pontifikator
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about some very sick people. Their sexual turn-on is car wrecks, and they cause them when they can't find them by chance. This movie, directed by David Cronenberg, is based on a novel by J. G. Ballard. This is a disturbing film. The sex scenes approach soft core porn, as the characters paw and grope each other, and there is rampant fetishism as well. However, I was unable to care about the characters. Casting James Spader as the lead guarantees a performance of flat affect. This sometimes works (as in "sex, lies, and videotape," when he plays a weird voyeur), but when he is the main character and I can't begin to like him or feel sympathy for him, it wrecks the movie for me. The problem with the film from my point of view is that I'm never given any reason to identify with these people and to care about their drive for this particular form of fetishism. I suspect the sex aspect of the film was too difficult for the director and/or the actors (including Holly Hunter, Elias Koteas, and Deborah Kara Unger) for them to develop their roles fully. Instead of some fascinating insight into a world I'd never heard of, I saw moments of soft core sex interspersed with dialog from affectless characters about whom I learned nothing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty dreary, but also undeniably fascinating.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer / producer / director David Cronenberg's grim adaptation of the J.G. Ballard novel tells the story of James Ballard (James Spader), who gets into a horrible car accident that actually has a stunning effect on his life, in particular his sex life. He and wife Catherine (Deborah Kara Unger) find themselves now inexorably drawn to the violence and destruction of car crashes and even the effect that such crashes have on the human body. They soon discover an underground group of people that celebrate this creepy fetish, led by the intense Vaughan (Elias Koteas), who with the help of stuntman friends recreates famous crashes involving celebrities (such as James Dean). Cronenberg is obviously a perfect choice to direct this sort of story, which obviously is not going to appeal to a lot of people but may very well intrigue some. It never gets too far into the heads of its characters, but doesn't really judge them, either, and illustrates how these individuals obsess over creating some sort of meaning in their lives and how human beings can attach a sexual element to just about anything. The weather in this Toronto-shot film is appropriately gloomy, matching the mood of the story telling, while the blood and gore is actually never overdone. Really, Cronenberg keeps the focus on the sexual nature of the story and characters and with the help of his very willing performers creates some very erotic scenes, of both the heterosexual and homosexual variety. There's some caressing of vehicle damage to go with the caressing of human bodies. The deeply committed cast, also including Holly Hunter and Rosanna Arquette, helps to draw you into this tale, while Howard Shore supplies a music score in his typical grandiose, full-of-foreboding style. Koteas is a standout as Vaughan. The film isn't perfect overall, as has already been mentioned, but it may keep some viewers watching due to the sexual frankness and explicitness on display. (This is available in both a 90 minute long R rated version and a 100 minute long NC-17 rated version.) Still, even with its flaws it leaves a fairly big impression; it's not likely it'll be easily forgotten. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The one thing Cronenberg has always unquestionably been talented at is weaving a highly disturbing atmosphere, and he does that beautifully on Crash. Unfortunately, though, the movie doesn't quite manage to draw the viewer into that atmosphere. It's meant as a metaphor for mankind's obsessions and perversions, but the horror is being piled on so thickly that I never once found myself immersed in any of the characters or caring about what happens to them, other than loathing them. James Spader is as fantastic as ever in exploring the depth of human perversion, and as always he manages a delicate balance of naive and sleazy, but he did better in subtler works like Secretary and Sex, Lies & Videotape.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Cronenberg must have been insane or under severe medication to write, produce and direct Crash, which is one of the worst movies that I have ever seen. It opens at an airplane hangar where James Spader character is grinding against his wife in a brief encounter, and within seconds is doing the nasty with an Asian woman in a camera room at a film set. Shortly afterwords, he is driving down the road and crashes head on into another car. A man goes through the windshield, but his wife, played by Holly Hunter is bloodied, and she is shown in the passenger seat without a bra, and her breast is noticed by Spader. He is bruised and recovering at a hospital and meets the survivor by chance, in the hallway. For some unknown reason, he visits the salvage yard to look at his wrecked car; and guess who just happens to be there at the same time; Holly Hunter, of course. He drives her to the airport and they have sex in the front seat of his car after discussing the bad traffic situation. He then goes back to his wife, and they get frisky. They apparently have an open marriage. We then meet a guy, Vaughan, who is obsessed with car accidents. He even reenacts the James Dean crash from 1955 with the same Porsche. Rosanna Arquette is Vaughan's prosthetic wearing friend, and we are given plenty of strange sexual quirks, such as scar worship. Vaughan rambles on with psycho babble and I was bored within the first thirty minutes of this garbage. Besides the bad script, the soundtrack, is annoying beyond description. A guitar playing with inordinate amounts of reverb is heard from beginning to end. Crash is a crashing bore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
