<filme>
 <id>
  328
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118883
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Teoria da Conspira&ccedil;&atilde;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A man obsessed with conspiracy theories becomes a target after one of his theories turns out to be true. Unfortunately, in order to save himself, he has to figure out which theory it is.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Jerry Fletcher is a man in love with a woman he observes from afar. She works for the government. Fletcher is an outspoken critic of that government. He has conspiracy theories for everything, from aliens to political assassinations. But soon, one of his theories finds itself to be accurate. But which one? Some dangerous people want him dead and the only person he trusts is that woman he loves but does not know.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   conspiracy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   newsletter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   taxi
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   secret service
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fire
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Richard Donner
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Brian Helgeland
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Mel Gibson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Julia Roberts
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Patrick Stewart
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Which Theory Is True?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson is most sympathetic as conspiracy theorist Jerry Fletcher, who lives in a ultra-secure, booby trapped apartment where he publishes his newsletter critical of the government. Ironically, he loves government employee Alice Sutton(played by Julia Roberts) from afar. One day, their worlds collide when one of Jerry's theories seems to be true, as he becomes the target of assassination, and Alice helps him to go on the run from the unknown government forces. He thinks that Dr. Jonas(Patrick Stewart) will help him, but it turns out that was one conspiracy he didn't anticipate... Entertaining thriller is well directed by Richard Donner, with a good pace and reasonably believable story, though it does go on a bit too long, and becomes a bit too convoluted, but otherwise this film works well, and some of Jerry's theories may not be so nutty anymore...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    patsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a fan of Conspiracy Theories so I figured I would check this one out,, it's above average,, based on the acting between our stars, Mel Gibson, Julia Robert,, and Patrick Stewart,, I was hoping for an actual conspiracy,, instead we get the old,, CIA, mind control stuff, rogue killer programmed to assassinate someone,, which isn't that bad, but some of the theories in the movie like the Oliver Stone --George Bush one,, I was like wow OK.. Mel's character, Jerry Fletcher is majorly paranoid, insanely crazy as one of his theories actually turns out to be true, problem for him is as he has so many now he has to figure out which theory he is right about,, he get's help from a young lady he saved from a mugging 6 months ago,, so he is like her guardian angel so to speak,, very interesting movie,, once you get by all the covert military mind control stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiring for A Very Good Film-Conspiracy Theory ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I dislike Mel Gibson for the repeated bigoted remarks that he has made off the screen, I have to admit that he gave a riveting performance in this film. He portrays a cab driver who is constantly thinking up various conspiracies, and then becomes pursued when one of his conspiracy theories proves to be right. As an attorney,Julia Roberts, who lost her father in a mysterious shooting, becomes involved with Gibson. The film is a good one due to the plot twists and turns. You really don't know who is good and evil in it. Patrick Stewart portrays a man with many hats. You just don't know where he is at until the very end. Roberts comes slowly to believe in what Gibson is saying until it appears that he had killed her father. The ending may be disappointing to many, but was probably necessary due to the clandestine and safety measures for the Roberts part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mel Gibson wins over Julia Roberts to his conspiracy theory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Conspiracy Theory" is Hollywood at its best, combining capable stars, thrills, romance, with a well-written and well-plotted script under sure direction. I enjoyed it thoroughly. Mel Gibson does a terrific job as the taxi driver who has many conspiracy theories and then turns out not to be a kook but to have the best of reasons for getting pulled in to a real conspiracy. Julia Roberts shows her acting chops by effortlessly playing a government security employee who finds herself completely enmeshed with Gibson, not least because of his motivation to protect her and how that came about. Solid entertainment that does not require much effort to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Always in my best 10 !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mad Watcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was incredibly smart, well written, funny and romantic. One of Mel Gibson's best act. Julia Roberts was the best choice for Alice Sutton (I cant imagine somebody else). She was really beautiful in this movie. You cant take your eyes from the movie especially when the ending comes. Well written small details you need the catch. Movie was interestingly underrated, is it a conspiracy? Sometimes I think about that. I do not want to give any spoiler, but this is a must watch movie, you will never regret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    buiger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with Ebert on this one. The script does seem confused, as if it has been re-written. The beginning of the film has nothing to do with what happens after wards. The end result is a mix up where none of the ends meet, making the screenplay totally ridiculous and thoroughly unbelievable. Is Jerry really the insecure and paranoid "conspiracy freak" like in the beginning of the movie or a highly trained special agent/murderer of the CIA? He can't be both. This paradox is present throughout the film and I think it also confused Gibson because it seems he doesn't really know which way to take the character himself. All in all, nothing special, a less than average quality Hollywood production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterthomson
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson overacts his way through the whole pile of rubbish and Julia Roberts is clearly there for the pay cheque. The thinnest of stories with poor dialogue throughout. Gibsons pathetic constant mumbling is overbearing and annoying and Roberts part of the sycophantic token female is a crime against acting.Take away the background music and special effects and it is almost laughable. I cant remember seeing such an awful film. the attempts at romance are so far removed from reality it borders on fantasy.Of the many thousands of films I have seen throughout my life, this is by far the worst one ever.I cant believe Julia Roberts would be happy with her name on this one. For Mel Gibson, it highlights his obvious acting limitations and one dimensional ability in such a way that maybe a close friend should have had a quiet word with him.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiracy And Paranoia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Conspiracy Theory is an action thriller film that features two of the Hollywood A-list stars namely: Mel Gibson and Julia Roberts.The original screenplay,written by Brian Helgeland,centers on an eccentric taxi driver who believes many world events are triggered by government conspiracies, and the U.S. Justice Department attorney who becomes involved in his life.It was directed by Richard Donner. Conspiracy Theory centers on the themes of conspiracy and paranoia.Jerry Fletcher is a New York City cab driver who seems to have absorbed every bit of crackpot information passed along as "suppressed news" that's surfaced on talk radio or the Internet in the past 20 years. Jerry's heard 'em all and believes most of them, and even publishes his own journal of forbidden information, with a subscription list that now totals five people. In short, Jerry seems like just another New York City lunatic, and while he spends a fair amount of his spare time following Alice Sutton, a government attorney. Alice regards him as harmless; he once intervened while she was being mugged, and he's been acting like her benign if whacked-out protector ever since. However, one day Jerry is kidnapped and worked over by CIA operatives; he is convinced that one of the theories he uncovered must be for real -- but he has no idea which one. He tries to get Alice to help him, and before long both are drawn into a dangerous web that leads to a startling revelation of just how Jerry got this way. The movie is definitely not short on entertainment.Mel Gibson gives a fine and comic performance as Jerry.He is able to carry the film and make it interesting from beginning to end.Julia Roberts is also worthy of mention and provides outstanding and brilliant acting as she shares great chemistry with Gibson.Unfortunately,the romantic aspect between the two characters looks implausible considering that Gibson's character seems lunatic and paranoid. Also,some parts of the story are far from realistic especially the traits that Jerry has considering that he is always ahead of the government,police,FBI and even the CIA.But nevertheless,one might say that it is just a movie and the story provides suspense and tension inspite of the wit and humor inserted in between scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What if all those crazy conspiracy theories end up being true.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this movie is just brilliant. It is exactly the type of movie that I just love. There so much happening in the background and you are never sure what really is happening. The theme of this movie is "the truth will set you free", but what really is the truth. The movie leads you to believe one thing and then confronts you with something that destroys everything the you had built up, only to knock this down as well. What really is true? You will never know. You follow the main character through out the movie  and this character really knows a lot. On the outside he appears to be a nut with all of these conspiracy theories but then a layer is pealed off to reveal a little more about this character. What does this character really know? Who is he  well the movie may tell you, or it may not. You know who the bad guy is, or is he really the bad guy. The only certainty is Julia Roberts' character. She seems to be legit, or is she. Yes I am being ambiguous for this is the whole aspect of this movie. Ambiguity reigns and as you dig deeper in to look for the truth, the more questions that are raised. As such this movie is brilliant. It is in the similar vein to the Usual Suspects. It creates a story only to tear it down and leaving you wondering what happened. It is the ultimate conspiracy theory. The conspiracies that Mel Gibson's character brings out seem to be ultimately wild  yet they do seem to make sense. Mel Gibson's character is brilliant. He is like a child with huge amounts of knowledge. At first is appears to be a simple cab driver with a tonne of wild ideas; and then the layers of his character begin to be peeled off. What does he really know? The character doesn't know the answer to this question. One thing that is very definite is that he really brings out patterns. He can see a pattern in almost everything and the patterns he pulls out really makes one think  are these really conspiracies. One brilliant aspect of the movie are the little tricks and gadgets that are used. They do not dominate the movie; but they are there to show us how intelligent this character really is. The Firewall and the Beer Bomb are two examples. The beer bomb is where a bottle is balanced on the door knob and when the knob is turn the bottle breaks. The firewall is a much more brilliant thing for it will utterly destroy the apartment without damaging anything else. If it is brilliant and clever tricks that you are looking for then this is a movie to see. Patrick Stewart plays the bad guy  or is he a bad guy. Stewart is a brilliant actor; unfortunately his seven year stint in Star Trek has dulled his edge. When I see Stewart on the screen I immediately think of Captain Picard. This, to me, can really destroy a really good actor. Mel Gibson is seen as Mel Gibson; Julia Roberts is seen as Julia Roberts; but one cannot help seeing Patrick Stewart as Captain Jean-luc Picard. There was one gripe I had with the movie, but I cannot tell you because if I did it would spoil it. It is one the really would have made it absolutely brilliant; but in a fallen world nothing is brilliant. Remember the words of the movie  "the truth will set you free."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Paranoiac as Romantic Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Conspiracy Theory" Mel Gibson plays Jerry Fletcher, a New York taxi driver. (The film was directed by Richard Donner, who also directed Gibson in "Maverick" and the "Lethal Weapon" series). Jerry is an obsessive conspiracy theorist who habitually who lectures his passengers on his various theories. He believes, for example, that the fathers of Nobel Prize winners are being kidnapped by the authorities and forced to become sperm donors. He believes that NASA is trying to kill the President using a secret weapon on the Space Shuttle that can trigger earthquakes. And he believes that the Jews are responsible for all the wars in the world. Or was it Mel Gibson himself who said that? Strange how life can imitate art and actors start behaving like the characters they once portrayed. The film is not, however, simply a psychological study of an eccentric oddball. It is, in fact, an action-thriller; one of Jerry's theories actually proves to be true; it involves a conspiracy by the CIA and other American government agencies to brainwash people in order to sue them as assassins. I won't try and set out the plot, which is extremely complex and at times confusing, in any detail, but it involves the efforts of Jerry and Alice Sutton, a young lawyer with the US Justice Department, to expose this conspiracy. Alice is trying to find out the truth about the murder of her father, whom she believes may have been killed by the conspirators. This is a fairly standard thriller plot; the genre frequently involves conspiracies by people in high places to commit some dark deed or other. Julia Roberts, who plays Alice here, starred in two other films of this type in the nineties, "The Pelican Brief" and "I Love Trouble", although this second example treated the theme in a more light-hearted way and also included romantic comedy elements. There are, indeed, attempts to inject both romance and comedy into "Conspiracy Theory", although both fall rather flat. The main problem with the film, apart from the fact that the plot is difficult to follow, is that, despite Gibson's best efforts to make him likable, Jerry remains, at bottom, a nutcase, and nutcases do not generally make credible screen heroes, and certainly not credible romantic heroes. Alice, of course, ends up falling for Jerry, even though in real life, any sane woman would run a mile from him, probably while telling herself that not every lunatic is actually in an asylum. It is hard to regard as love's young dream the sort of man who is so paranoid that he padlocks the coffee and sugar canisters in his kitchen. There are two ways in which one could make a film about a character like Jerry Fletcher, either as a character-driven psychological drama or as a black comedy. In either case the character would probably have to be dealt with much less indulgently than he is here. A paranoid conspiracy theorist as romantic hero just doesn't work, even if there turns out to be a rational explanation for his paranoia. The film achieves little, other than the presumably unintended achievement of making extremist views seem slightly more acceptable. Both Gibson and Roberts have much more distinguished entries on their CVs than this one. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Which Theory Is True?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson is most sympathetic as conspiracy theorist Jerry Fletcher, who lives in a ultra-secure, booby trapped apartment where he publishes his newsletter critical of the government. Ironically, he loves government employee Alice Sutton(played by Julia Roberts) from afar. One day, their worlds collide when one of Jerry's theories seems to be true, as he becomes the target of assassination, and Alice helps him to go on the run from the unknown government forces. He thinks that Dr. Jonas(Patrick Stewart) will help him, but it turns out that was one conspiracy he didn't anticipate... Entertaining thriller is well directed by Richard Donner, with a good pace and reasonably believable story, though it does go on a bit too long, and becomes a bit too convoluted, but otherwise this film works well, and some of Jerry's theories may not be so nutty anymore...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    patsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a fan of Conspiracy Theories so I figured I would check this one out,, it's above average,, based on the acting between our stars, Mel Gibson, Julia Robert,, and Patrick Stewart,, I was hoping for an actual conspiracy,, instead we get the old,, CIA, mind control stuff, rogue killer programmed to assassinate someone,, which isn't that bad, but some of the theories in the movie like the Oliver Stone --George Bush one,, I was like wow OK.. Mel's character, Jerry Fletcher is majorly paranoid, insanely crazy as one of his theories actually turns out to be true, problem for him is as he has so many now he has to figure out which theory he is right about,, he get's help from a young lady he saved from a mugging 6 months ago,, so he is like her guardian angel so to speak,, very interesting movie,, once you get by all the covert military mind control stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiring for A Very Good Film-Conspiracy Theory ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I dislike Mel Gibson for the repeated bigoted remarks that he has made off the screen, I have to admit that he gave a riveting performance in this film. He portrays a cab driver who is constantly thinking up various conspiracies, and then becomes pursued when one of his conspiracy theories proves to be right. As an attorney,Julia Roberts, who lost her father in a mysterious shooting, becomes involved with Gibson. The film is a good one due to the plot twists and turns. You really don't know who is good and evil in it. Patrick Stewart portrays a man with many hats. You just don't know where he is at until the very end. Roberts comes slowly to believe in what Gibson is saying until it appears that he had killed her father. The ending may be disappointing to many, but was probably necessary due to the clandestine and safety measures for the Roberts part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mel Gibson wins over Julia Roberts to his conspiracy theory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Conspiracy Theory" is Hollywood at its best, combining capable stars, thrills, romance, with a well-written and well-plotted script under sure direction. I enjoyed it thoroughly. Mel Gibson does a terrific job as the taxi driver who has many conspiracy theories and then turns out not to be a kook but to have the best of reasons for getting pulled in to a real conspiracy. Julia Roberts shows her acting chops by effortlessly playing a government security employee who finds herself completely enmeshed with Gibson, not least because of his motivation to protect her and how that came about. Solid entertainment that does not require much effort to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Always in my best 10 !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mad Watcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was incredibly smart, well written, funny and romantic. One of Mel Gibson's best act. Julia Roberts was the best choice for Alice Sutton (I cant imagine somebody else). She was really beautiful in this movie. You cant take your eyes from the movie especially when the ending comes. Well written small details you need the catch. Movie was interestingly underrated, is it a conspiracy? Sometimes I think about that. I do not want to give any spoiler, but this is a must watch movie, you will never regret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    buiger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with Ebert on this one. The script does seem confused, as if it has been re-written. The beginning of the film has nothing to do with what happens after wards. The end result is a mix up where none of the ends meet, making the screenplay totally ridiculous and thoroughly unbelievable. Is Jerry really the insecure and paranoid "conspiracy freak" like in the beginning of the movie or a highly trained special agent/murderer of the CIA? He can't be both. This paradox is present throughout the film and I think it also confused Gibson because it seems he doesn't really know which way to take the character himself. All in all, nothing special, a less than average quality Hollywood production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterthomson
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson overacts his way through the whole pile of rubbish and Julia Roberts is clearly there for the pay cheque. The thinnest of stories with poor dialogue throughout. Gibsons pathetic constant mumbling is overbearing and annoying and Roberts part of the sycophantic token female is a crime against acting.Take away the background music and special effects and it is almost laughable. I cant remember seeing such an awful film. the attempts at romance are so far removed from reality it borders on fantasy.Of the many thousands of films I have seen throughout my life, this is by far the worst one ever.I cant believe Julia Roberts would be happy with her name on this one. For Mel Gibson, it highlights his obvious acting limitations and one dimensional ability in such a way that maybe a close friend should have had a quiet word with him.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiracy And Paranoia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Conspiracy Theory is an action thriller film that features two of the Hollywood A-list stars namely: Mel Gibson and Julia Roberts.The original screenplay,written by Brian Helgeland,centers on an eccentric taxi driver who believes many world events are triggered by government conspiracies, and the U.S. Justice Department attorney who becomes involved in his life.It was directed by Richard Donner. Conspiracy Theory centers on the themes of conspiracy and paranoia.Jerry Fletcher is a New York City cab driver who seems to have absorbed every bit of crackpot information passed along as "suppressed news" that's surfaced on talk radio or the Internet in the past 20 years. Jerry's heard 'em all and believes most of them, and even publishes his own journal of forbidden information, with a subscription list that now totals five people. In short, Jerry seems like just another New York City lunatic, and while he spends a fair amount of his spare time following Alice Sutton, a government attorney. Alice regards him as harmless; he once intervened while she was being mugged, and he's been acting like her benign if whacked-out protector ever since. However, one day Jerry is kidnapped and worked over by CIA operatives; he is convinced that one of the theories he uncovered must be for real -- but he has no idea which one. He tries to get Alice to help him, and before long both are drawn into a dangerous web that leads to a startling revelation of just how Jerry got this way. The movie is definitely not short on entertainment.Mel Gibson gives a fine and comic performance as Jerry.He is able to carry the film and make it interesting from beginning to end.Julia Roberts is also worthy of mention and provides outstanding and brilliant acting as she shares great chemistry with Gibson.Unfortunately,the romantic aspect between the two characters looks implausible considering that Gibson's character seems lunatic and paranoid. Also,some parts of the story are far from realistic especially the traits that Jerry has considering that he is always ahead of the government,police,FBI and even the CIA.But nevertheless,one might say that it is just a movie and the story provides suspense and tension inspite of the wit and humor inserted in between scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What if all those crazy conspiracy theories end up being true.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this movie is just brilliant. It is exactly the type of movie that I just love. There so much happening in the background and you are never sure what really is happening. The theme of this movie is "the truth will set you free", but what really is the truth. The movie leads you to believe one thing and then confronts you with something that destroys everything the you had built up, only to knock this down as well. What really is true? You will never know. You follow the main character through out the movie  and this character really knows a lot. On the outside he appears to be a nut with all of these conspiracy theories but then a layer is pealed off to reveal a little more about this character. What does this character really know? Who is he  well the movie may tell you, or it may not. You know who the bad guy is, or is he really the bad guy. The only certainty is Julia Roberts' character. She seems to be legit, or is she. Yes I am being ambiguous for this is the whole aspect of this movie. Ambiguity reigns and as you dig deeper in to look for the truth, the more questions that are raised. As such this movie is brilliant. It is in the similar vein to the Usual Suspects. It creates a story only to tear it down and leaving you wondering what happened. It is the ultimate conspiracy theory. The conspiracies that Mel Gibson's character brings out seem to be ultimately wild  yet they do seem to make sense. Mel Gibson's character is brilliant. He is like a child with huge amounts of knowledge. At first is appears to be a simple cab driver with a tonne of wild ideas; and then the layers of his character begin to be peeled off. What does he really know? The character doesn't know the answer to this question. One thing that is very definite is that he really brings out patterns. He can see a pattern in almost everything and the patterns he pulls out really makes one think  are these really conspiracies. One brilliant aspect of the movie are the little tricks and gadgets that are used. They do not dominate the movie; but they are there to show us how intelligent this character really is. The Firewall and the Beer Bomb are two examples. The beer bomb is where a bottle is balanced on the door knob and when the knob is turn the bottle breaks. The firewall is a much more brilliant thing for it will utterly destroy the apartment without damaging anything else. If it is brilliant and clever tricks that you are looking for then this is a movie to see. Patrick Stewart plays the bad guy  or is he a bad guy. Stewart is a brilliant actor; unfortunately his seven year stint in Star Trek has dulled his edge. When I see Stewart on the screen I immediately think of Captain Picard. This, to me, can really destroy a really good actor. Mel Gibson is seen as Mel Gibson; Julia Roberts is seen as Julia Roberts; but one cannot help seeing Patrick Stewart as Captain Jean-luc Picard. There was one gripe I had with the movie, but I cannot tell you because if I did it would spoil it. It is one the really would have made it absolutely brilliant; but in a fallen world nothing is brilliant. Remember the words of the movie  "the truth will set you free."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Paranoiac as Romantic Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Conspiracy Theory" Mel Gibson plays Jerry Fletcher, a New York taxi driver. (The film was directed by Richard Donner, who also directed Gibson in "Maverick" and the "Lethal Weapon" series). Jerry is an obsessive conspiracy theorist who habitually who lectures his passengers on his various theories. He believes, for example, that the fathers of Nobel Prize winners are being kidnapped by the authorities and forced to become sperm donors. He believes that NASA is trying to kill the President using a secret weapon on the Space Shuttle that can trigger earthquakes. And he believes that the Jews are responsible for all the wars in the world. Or was it Mel Gibson himself who said that? Strange how life can imitate art and actors start behaving like the characters they once portrayed. The film is not, however, simply a psychological study of an eccentric oddball. It is, in fact, an action-thriller; one of Jerry's theories actually proves to be true; it involves a conspiracy by the CIA and other American government agencies to brainwash people in order to sue them as assassins. I won't try and set out the plot, which is extremely complex and at times confusing, in any detail, but it involves the efforts of Jerry and Alice Sutton, a young lawyer with the US Justice Department, to expose this conspiracy. Alice is trying to find out the truth about the murder of her father, whom she believes may have been killed by the conspirators. This is a fairly standard thriller plot; the genre frequently involves conspiracies by people in high places to commit some dark deed or other. Julia Roberts, who plays Alice here, starred in two other films of this type in the nineties, "The Pelican Brief" and "I Love Trouble", although this second example treated the theme in a more light-hearted way and also included romantic comedy elements. There are, indeed, attempts to inject both romance and comedy into "Conspiracy Theory", although both fall rather flat. The main problem with the film, apart from the fact that the plot is difficult to follow, is that, despite Gibson's best efforts to make him likable, Jerry remains, at bottom, a nutcase, and nutcases do not generally make credible screen heroes, and certainly not credible romantic heroes. Alice, of course, ends up falling for Jerry, even though in real life, any sane woman would run a mile from him, probably while telling herself that not every lunatic is actually in an asylum. It is hard to regard as love's young dream the sort of man who is so paranoid that he padlocks the coffee and sugar canisters in his kitchen. There are two ways in which one could make a film about a character like Jerry Fletcher, either as a character-driven psychological drama or as a black comedy. In either case the character would probably have to be dealt with much less indulgently than he is here. A paranoid conspiracy theorist as romantic hero just doesn't work, even if there turns out to be a rational explanation for his paranoia. The film achieves little, other than the presumably unintended achievement of making extremist views seem slightly more acceptable. Both Gibson and Roberts have much more distinguished entries on their CVs than this one. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Which Theory Is True?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson is most sympathetic as conspiracy theorist Jerry Fletcher, who lives in a ultra-secure, booby trapped apartment where he publishes his newsletter critical of the government. Ironically, he loves government employee Alice Sutton(played by Julia Roberts) from afar. One day, their worlds collide when one of Jerry's theories seems to be true, as he becomes the target of assassination, and Alice helps him to go on the run from the unknown government forces. He thinks that Dr. Jonas(Patrick Stewart) will help him, but it turns out that was one conspiracy he didn't anticipate... Entertaining thriller is well directed by Richard Donner, with a good pace and reasonably believable story, though it does go on a bit too long, and becomes a bit too convoluted, but otherwise this film works well, and some of Jerry's theories may not be so nutty anymore...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    patsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a fan of Conspiracy Theories so I figured I would check this one out,, it's above average,, based on the acting between our stars, Mel Gibson, Julia Robert,, and Patrick Stewart,, I was hoping for an actual conspiracy,, instead we get the old,, CIA, mind control stuff, rogue killer programmed to assassinate someone,, which isn't that bad, but some of the theories in the movie like the Oliver Stone --George Bush one,, I was like wow OK.. Mel's character, Jerry Fletcher is majorly paranoid, insanely crazy as one of his theories actually turns out to be true, problem for him is as he has so many now he has to figure out which theory he is right about,, he get's help from a young lady he saved from a mugging 6 months ago,, so he is like her guardian angel so to speak,, very interesting movie,, once you get by all the covert military mind control stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiring for A Very Good Film-Conspiracy Theory ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I dislike Mel Gibson for the repeated bigoted remarks that he has made off the screen, I have to admit that he gave a riveting performance in this film. He portrays a cab driver who is constantly thinking up various conspiracies, and then becomes pursued when one of his conspiracy theories proves to be right. As an attorney,Julia Roberts, who lost her father in a mysterious shooting, becomes involved with Gibson. The film is a good one due to the plot twists and turns. You really don't know who is good and evil in it. Patrick Stewart portrays a man with many hats. You just don't know where he is at until the very end. Roberts comes slowly to believe in what Gibson is saying until it appears that he had killed her father. The ending may be disappointing to many, but was probably necessary due to the clandestine and safety measures for the Roberts part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mel Gibson wins over Julia Roberts to his conspiracy theory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Conspiracy Theory" is Hollywood at its best, combining capable stars, thrills, romance, with a well-written and well-plotted script under sure direction. I enjoyed it thoroughly. Mel Gibson does a terrific job as the taxi driver who has many conspiracy theories and then turns out not to be a kook but to have the best of reasons for getting pulled in to a real conspiracy. Julia Roberts shows her acting chops by effortlessly playing a government security employee who finds herself completely enmeshed with Gibson, not least because of his motivation to protect her and how that came about. Solid entertainment that does not require much effort to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Always in my best 10 !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mad Watcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was incredibly smart, well written, funny and romantic. One of Mel Gibson's best act. Julia Roberts was the best choice for Alice Sutton (I cant imagine somebody else). She was really beautiful in this movie. You cant take your eyes from the movie especially when the ending comes. Well written small details you need the catch. Movie was interestingly underrated, is it a conspiracy? Sometimes I think about that. I do not want to give any spoiler, but this is a must watch movie, you will never regret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    buiger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with Ebert on this one. The script does seem confused, as if it has been re-written. The beginning of the film has nothing to do with what happens after wards. The end result is a mix up where none of the ends meet, making the screenplay totally ridiculous and thoroughly unbelievable. Is Jerry really the insecure and paranoid "conspiracy freak" like in the beginning of the movie or a highly trained special agent/murderer of the CIA? He can't be both. This paradox is present throughout the film and I think it also confused Gibson because it seems he doesn't really know which way to take the character himself. All in all, nothing special, a less than average quality Hollywood production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterthomson
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson overacts his way through the whole pile of rubbish and Julia Roberts is clearly there for the pay cheque. The thinnest of stories with poor dialogue throughout. Gibsons pathetic constant mumbling is overbearing and annoying and Roberts part of the sycophantic token female is a crime against acting.Take away the background music and special effects and it is almost laughable. I cant remember seeing such an awful film. the attempts at romance are so far removed from reality it borders on fantasy.Of the many thousands of films I have seen throughout my life, this is by far the worst one ever.I cant believe Julia Roberts would be happy with her name on this one. For Mel Gibson, it highlights his obvious acting limitations and one dimensional ability in such a way that maybe a close friend should have had a quiet word with him.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiracy And Paranoia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Conspiracy Theory is an action thriller film that features two of the Hollywood A-list stars namely: Mel Gibson and Julia Roberts.The original screenplay,written by Brian Helgeland,centers on an eccentric taxi driver who believes many world events are triggered by government conspiracies, and the U.S. Justice Department attorney who becomes involved in his life.It was directed by Richard Donner. Conspiracy Theory centers on the themes of conspiracy and paranoia.Jerry Fletcher is a New York City cab driver who seems to have absorbed every bit of crackpot information passed along as "suppressed news" that's surfaced on talk radio or the Internet in the past 20 years. Jerry's heard 'em all and believes most of them, and even publishes his own journal of forbidden information, with a subscription list that now totals five people. In short, Jerry seems like just another New York City lunatic, and while he spends a fair amount of his spare time following Alice Sutton, a government attorney. Alice regards him as harmless; he once intervened while she was being mugged, and he's been acting like her benign if whacked-out protector ever since. However, one day Jerry is kidnapped and worked over by CIA operatives; he is convinced that one of the theories he uncovered must be for real -- but he has no idea which one. He tries to get Alice to help him, and before long both are drawn into a dangerous web that leads to a startling revelation of just how Jerry got this way. The movie is definitely not short on entertainment.Mel Gibson gives a fine and comic performance as Jerry.He is able to carry the film and make it interesting from beginning to end.Julia Roberts is also worthy of mention and provides outstanding and brilliant acting as she shares great chemistry with Gibson.Unfortunately,the romantic aspect between the two characters looks implausible considering that Gibson's character seems lunatic and paranoid. Also,some parts of the story are far from realistic especially the traits that Jerry has considering that he is always ahead of the government,police,FBI and even the CIA.But nevertheless,one might say that it is just a movie and the story provides suspense and tension inspite of the wit and humor inserted in between scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What if all those crazy conspiracy theories end up being true.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this movie is just brilliant. It is exactly the type of movie that I just love. There so much happening in the background and you are never sure what really is happening. The theme of this movie is "the truth will set you free", but what really is the truth. The movie leads you to believe one thing and then confronts you with something that destroys everything the you had built up, only to knock this down as well. What really is true? You will never know. You follow the main character through out the movie  and this character really knows a lot. On the outside he appears to be a nut with all of these conspiracy theories but then a layer is pealed off to reveal a little more about this character. What does this character really know? Who is he  well the movie may tell you, or it may not. You know who the bad guy is, or is he really the bad guy. The only certainty is Julia Roberts' character. She seems to be legit, or is she. Yes I am being ambiguous for this is the whole aspect of this movie. Ambiguity reigns and as you dig deeper in to look for the truth, the more questions that are raised. As such this movie is brilliant. It is in the similar vein to the Usual Suspects. It creates a story only to tear it down and leaving you wondering what happened. It is the ultimate conspiracy theory. The conspiracies that Mel Gibson's character brings out seem to be ultimately wild  yet they do seem to make sense. Mel Gibson's character is brilliant. He is like a child with huge amounts of knowledge. At first is appears to be a simple cab driver with a tonne of wild ideas; and then the layers of his character begin to be peeled off. What does he really know? The character doesn't know the answer to this question. One thing that is very definite is that he really brings out patterns. He can see a pattern in almost everything and the patterns he pulls out really makes one think  are these really conspiracies. One brilliant aspect of the movie are the little tricks and gadgets that are used. They do not dominate the movie; but they are there to show us how intelligent this character really is. The Firewall and the Beer Bomb are two examples. The beer bomb is where a bottle is balanced on the door knob and when the knob is turn the bottle breaks. The firewall is a much more brilliant thing for it will utterly destroy the apartment without damaging anything else. If it is brilliant and clever tricks that you are looking for then this is a movie to see. Patrick Stewart plays the bad guy  or is he a bad guy. Stewart is a brilliant actor; unfortunately his seven year stint in Star Trek has dulled his edge. When I see Stewart on the screen I immediately think of Captain Picard. This, to me, can really destroy a really good actor. Mel Gibson is seen as Mel Gibson; Julia Roberts is seen as Julia Roberts; but one cannot help seeing Patrick Stewart as Captain Jean-luc Picard. There was one gripe I had with the movie, but I cannot tell you because if I did it would spoil it. It is one the really would have made it absolutely brilliant; but in a fallen world nothing is brilliant. Remember the words of the movie  "the truth will set you free."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Paranoiac as Romantic Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Conspiracy Theory" Mel Gibson plays Jerry Fletcher, a New York taxi driver. (The film was directed by Richard Donner, who also directed Gibson in "Maverick" and the "Lethal Weapon" series). Jerry is an obsessive conspiracy theorist who habitually who lectures his passengers on his various theories. He believes, for example, that the fathers of Nobel Prize winners are being kidnapped by the authorities and forced to become sperm donors. He believes that NASA is trying to kill the President using a secret weapon on the Space Shuttle that can trigger earthquakes. And he believes that the Jews are responsible for all the wars in the world. Or was it Mel Gibson himself who said that? Strange how life can imitate art and actors start behaving like the characters they once portrayed. The film is not, however, simply a psychological study of an eccentric oddball. It is, in fact, an action-thriller; one of Jerry's theories actually proves to be true; it involves a conspiracy by the CIA and other American government agencies to brainwash people in order to sue them as assassins. I won't try and set out the plot, which is extremely complex and at times confusing, in any detail, but it involves the efforts of Jerry and Alice Sutton, a young lawyer with the US Justice Department, to expose this conspiracy. Alice is trying to find out the truth about the murder of her father, whom she believes may have been killed by the conspirators. This is a fairly standard thriller plot; the genre frequently involves conspiracies by people in high places to commit some dark deed or other. Julia Roberts, who plays Alice here, starred in two other films of this type in the nineties, "The Pelican Brief" and "I Love Trouble", although this second example treated the theme in a more light-hearted way and also included romantic comedy elements. There are, indeed, attempts to inject both romance and comedy into "Conspiracy Theory", although both fall rather flat. The main problem with the film, apart from the fact that the plot is difficult to follow, is that, despite Gibson's best efforts to make him likable, Jerry remains, at bottom, a nutcase, and nutcases do not generally make credible screen heroes, and certainly not credible romantic heroes. Alice, of course, ends up falling for Jerry, even though in real life, any sane woman would run a mile from him, probably while telling herself that not every lunatic is actually in an asylum. It is hard to regard as love's young dream the sort of man who is so paranoid that he padlocks the coffee and sugar canisters in his kitchen. There are two ways in which one could make a film about a character like Jerry Fletcher, either as a character-driven psychological drama or as a black comedy. In either case the character would probably have to be dealt with much less indulgently than he is here. A paranoid conspiracy theorist as romantic hero just doesn't work, even if there turns out to be a rational explanation for his paranoia. The film achieves little, other than the presumably unintended achievement of making extremist views seem slightly more acceptable. Both Gibson and Roberts have much more distinguished entries on their CVs than this one. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Which Theory Is True?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson is most sympathetic as conspiracy theorist Jerry Fletcher, who lives in a ultra-secure, booby trapped apartment where he publishes his newsletter critical of the government. Ironically, he loves government employee Alice Sutton(played by Julia Roberts) from afar. One day, their worlds collide when one of Jerry's theories seems to be true, as he becomes the target of assassination, and Alice helps him to go on the run from the unknown government forces. He thinks that Dr. Jonas(Patrick Stewart) will help him, but it turns out that was one conspiracy he didn't anticipate... Entertaining thriller is well directed by Richard Donner, with a good pace and reasonably believable story, though it does go on a bit too long, and becomes a bit too convoluted, but otherwise this film works well, and some of Jerry's theories may not be so nutty anymore...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    patsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a fan of Conspiracy Theories so I figured I would check this one out,, it's above average,, based on the acting between our stars, Mel Gibson, Julia Robert,, and Patrick Stewart,, I was hoping for an actual conspiracy,, instead we get the old,, CIA, mind control stuff, rogue killer programmed to assassinate someone,, which isn't that bad, but some of the theories in the movie like the Oliver Stone --George Bush one,, I was like wow OK.. Mel's character, Jerry Fletcher is majorly paranoid, insanely crazy as one of his theories actually turns out to be true, problem for him is as he has so many now he has to figure out which theory he is right about,, he get's help from a young lady he saved from a mugging 6 months ago,, so he is like her guardian angel so to speak,, very interesting movie,, once you get by all the covert military mind control stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiring for A Very Good Film-Conspiracy Theory ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I dislike Mel Gibson for the repeated bigoted remarks that he has made off the screen, I have to admit that he gave a riveting performance in this film. He portrays a cab driver who is constantly thinking up various conspiracies, and then becomes pursued when one of his conspiracy theories proves to be right. As an attorney,Julia Roberts, who lost her father in a mysterious shooting, becomes involved with Gibson. The film is a good one due to the plot twists and turns. You really don't know who is good and evil in it. Patrick Stewart portrays a man with many hats. You just don't know where he is at until the very end. Roberts comes slowly to believe in what Gibson is saying until it appears that he had killed her father. The ending may be disappointing to many, but was probably necessary due to the clandestine and safety measures for the Roberts part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mel Gibson wins over Julia Roberts to his conspiracy theory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Conspiracy Theory" is Hollywood at its best, combining capable stars, thrills, romance, with a well-written and well-plotted script under sure direction. I enjoyed it thoroughly. Mel Gibson does a terrific job as the taxi driver who has many conspiracy theories and then turns out not to be a kook but to have the best of reasons for getting pulled in to a real conspiracy. Julia Roberts shows her acting chops by effortlessly playing a government security employee who finds herself completely enmeshed with Gibson, not least because of his motivation to protect her and how that came about. Solid entertainment that does not require much effort to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Always in my best 10 !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mad Watcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was incredibly smart, well written, funny and romantic. One of Mel Gibson's best act. Julia Roberts was the best choice for Alice Sutton (I cant imagine somebody else). She was really beautiful in this movie. You cant take your eyes from the movie especially when the ending comes. Well written small details you need the catch. Movie was interestingly underrated, is it a conspiracy? Sometimes I think about that. I do not want to give any spoiler, but this is a must watch movie, you will never regret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    buiger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with Ebert on this one. The script does seem confused, as if it has been re-written. The beginning of the film has nothing to do with what happens after wards. The end result is a mix up where none of the ends meet, making the screenplay totally ridiculous and thoroughly unbelievable. Is Jerry really the insecure and paranoid "conspiracy freak" like in the beginning of the movie or a highly trained special agent/murderer of the CIA? He can't be both. This paradox is present throughout the film and I think it also confused Gibson because it seems he doesn't really know which way to take the character himself. All in all, nothing special, a less than average quality Hollywood production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterthomson
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson overacts his way through the whole pile of rubbish and Julia Roberts is clearly there for the pay cheque. The thinnest of stories with poor dialogue throughout. Gibsons pathetic constant mumbling is overbearing and annoying and Roberts part of the sycophantic token female is a crime against acting.Take away the background music and special effects and it is almost laughable. I cant remember seeing such an awful film. the attempts at romance are so far removed from reality it borders on fantasy.Of the many thousands of films I have seen throughout my life, this is by far the worst one ever.I cant believe Julia Roberts would be happy with her name on this one. For Mel Gibson, it highlights his obvious acting limitations and one dimensional ability in such a way that maybe a close friend should have had a quiet word with him.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiracy And Paranoia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Conspiracy Theory is an action thriller film that features two of the Hollywood A-list stars namely: Mel Gibson and Julia Roberts.The original screenplay,written by Brian Helgeland,centers on an eccentric taxi driver who believes many world events are triggered by government conspiracies, and the U.S. Justice Department attorney who becomes involved in his life.It was directed by Richard Donner. Conspiracy Theory centers on the themes of conspiracy and paranoia.Jerry Fletcher is a New York City cab driver who seems to have absorbed every bit of crackpot information passed along as "suppressed news" that's surfaced on talk radio or the Internet in the past 20 years. Jerry's heard 'em all and believes most of them, and even publishes his own journal of forbidden information, with a subscription list that now totals five people. In short, Jerry seems like just another New York City lunatic, and while he spends a fair amount of his spare time following Alice Sutton, a government attorney. Alice regards him as harmless; he once intervened while she was being mugged, and he's been acting like her benign if whacked-out protector ever since. However, one day Jerry is kidnapped and worked over by CIA operatives; he is convinced that one of the theories he uncovered must be for real -- but he has no idea which one. He tries to get Alice to help him, and before long both are drawn into a dangerous web that leads to a startling revelation of just how Jerry got this way. The movie is definitely not short on entertainment.Mel Gibson gives a fine and comic performance as Jerry.He is able to carry the film and make it interesting from beginning to end.Julia Roberts is also worthy of mention and provides outstanding and brilliant acting as she shares great chemistry with Gibson.Unfortunately,the romantic aspect between the two characters looks implausible considering that Gibson's character seems lunatic and paranoid. Also,some parts of the story are far from realistic especially the traits that Jerry has considering that he is always ahead of the government,police,FBI and even the CIA.But nevertheless,one might say that it is just a movie and the story provides suspense and tension inspite of the wit and humor inserted in between scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What if all those crazy conspiracy theories end up being true.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this movie is just brilliant. It is exactly the type of movie that I just love. There so much happening in the background and you are never sure what really is happening. The theme of this movie is "the truth will set you free", but what really is the truth. The movie leads you to believe one thing and then confronts you with something that destroys everything the you had built up, only to knock this down as well. What really is true? You will never know. You follow the main character through out the movie  and this character really knows a lot. On the outside he appears to be a nut with all of these conspiracy theories but then a layer is pealed off to reveal a little more about this character. What does this character really know? Who is he  well the movie may tell you, or it may not. You know who the bad guy is, or is he really the bad guy. The only certainty is Julia Roberts' character. She seems to be legit, or is she. Yes I am being ambiguous for this is the whole aspect of this movie. Ambiguity reigns and as you dig deeper in to look for the truth, the more questions that are raised. As such this movie is brilliant. It is in the similar vein to the Usual Suspects. It creates a story only to tear it down and leaving you wondering what happened. It is the ultimate conspiracy theory. The conspiracies that Mel Gibson's character brings out seem to be ultimately wild  yet they do seem to make sense. Mel Gibson's character is brilliant. He is like a child with huge amounts of knowledge. At first is appears to be a simple cab driver with a tonne of wild ideas; and then the layers of his character begin to be peeled off. What does he really know? The character doesn't know the answer to this question. One thing that is very definite is that he really brings out patterns. He can see a pattern in almost everything and the patterns he pulls out really makes one think  are these really conspiracies. One brilliant aspect of the movie are the little tricks and gadgets that are used. They do not dominate the movie; but they are there to show us how intelligent this character really is. The Firewall and the Beer Bomb are two examples. The beer bomb is where a bottle is balanced on the door knob and when the knob is turn the bottle breaks. The firewall is a much more brilliant thing for it will utterly destroy the apartment without damaging anything else. If it is brilliant and clever tricks that you are looking for then this is a movie to see. Patrick Stewart plays the bad guy  or is he a bad guy. Stewart is a brilliant actor; unfortunately his seven year stint in Star Trek has dulled his edge. When I see Stewart on the screen I immediately think of Captain Picard. This, to me, can really destroy a really good actor. Mel Gibson is seen as Mel Gibson; Julia Roberts is seen as Julia Roberts; but one cannot help seeing Patrick Stewart as Captain Jean-luc Picard. There was one gripe I had with the movie, but I cannot tell you because if I did it would spoil it. It is one the really would have made it absolutely brilliant; but in a fallen world nothing is brilliant. Remember the words of the movie  "the truth will set you free."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Paranoiac as Romantic Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Conspiracy Theory" Mel Gibson plays Jerry Fletcher, a New York taxi driver. (The film was directed by Richard Donner, who also directed Gibson in "Maverick" and the "Lethal Weapon" series). Jerry is an obsessive conspiracy theorist who habitually who lectures his passengers on his various theories. He believes, for example, that the fathers of Nobel Prize winners are being kidnapped by the authorities and forced to become sperm donors. He believes that NASA is trying to kill the President using a secret weapon on the Space Shuttle that can trigger earthquakes. And he believes that the Jews are responsible for all the wars in the world. Or was it Mel Gibson himself who said that? Strange how life can imitate art and actors start behaving like the characters they once portrayed. The film is not, however, simply a psychological study of an eccentric oddball. It is, in fact, an action-thriller; one of Jerry's theories actually proves to be true; it involves a conspiracy by the CIA and other American government agencies to brainwash people in order to sue them as assassins. I won't try and set out the plot, which is extremely complex and at times confusing, in any detail, but it involves the efforts of Jerry and Alice Sutton, a young lawyer with the US Justice Department, to expose this conspiracy. Alice is trying to find out the truth about the murder of her father, whom she believes may have been killed by the conspirators. This is a fairly standard thriller plot; the genre frequently involves conspiracies by people in high places to commit some dark deed or other. Julia Roberts, who plays Alice here, starred in two other films of this type in the nineties, "The Pelican Brief" and "I Love Trouble", although this second example treated the theme in a more light-hearted way and also included romantic comedy elements. There are, indeed, attempts to inject both romance and comedy into "Conspiracy Theory", although both fall rather flat. The main problem with the film, apart from the fact that the plot is difficult to follow, is that, despite Gibson's best efforts to make him likable, Jerry remains, at bottom, a nutcase, and nutcases do not generally make credible screen heroes, and certainly not credible romantic heroes. Alice, of course, ends up falling for Jerry, even though in real life, any sane woman would run a mile from him, probably while telling herself that not every lunatic is actually in an asylum. It is hard to regard as love's young dream the sort of man who is so paranoid that he padlocks the coffee and sugar canisters in his kitchen. There are two ways in which one could make a film about a character like Jerry Fletcher, either as a character-driven psychological drama or as a black comedy. In either case the character would probably have to be dealt with much less indulgently than he is here. A paranoid conspiracy theorist as romantic hero just doesn't work, even if there turns out to be a rational explanation for his paranoia. The film achieves little, other than the presumably unintended achievement of making extremist views seem slightly more acceptable. Both Gibson and Roberts have much more distinguished entries on their CVs than this one. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Which Theory Is True?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson is most sympathetic as conspiracy theorist Jerry Fletcher, who lives in a ultra-secure, booby trapped apartment where he publishes his newsletter critical of the government. Ironically, he loves government employee Alice Sutton(played by Julia Roberts) from afar. One day, their worlds collide when one of Jerry's theories seems to be true, as he becomes the target of assassination, and Alice helps him to go on the run from the unknown government forces. He thinks that Dr. Jonas(Patrick Stewart) will help him, but it turns out that was one conspiracy he didn't anticipate... Entertaining thriller is well directed by Richard Donner, with a good pace and reasonably believable story, though it does go on a bit too long, and becomes a bit too convoluted, but otherwise this film works well, and some of Jerry's theories may not be so nutty anymore...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    patsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a fan of Conspiracy Theories so I figured I would check this one out,, it's above average,, based on the acting between our stars, Mel Gibson, Julia Robert,, and Patrick Stewart,, I was hoping for an actual conspiracy,, instead we get the old,, CIA, mind control stuff, rogue killer programmed to assassinate someone,, which isn't that bad, but some of the theories in the movie like the Oliver Stone --George Bush one,, I was like wow OK.. Mel's character, Jerry Fletcher is majorly paranoid, insanely crazy as one of his theories actually turns out to be true, problem for him is as he has so many now he has to figure out which theory he is right about,, he get's help from a young lady he saved from a mugging 6 months ago,, so he is like her guardian angel so to speak,, very interesting movie,, once you get by all the covert military mind control stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiring for A Very Good Film-Conspiracy Theory ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I dislike Mel Gibson for the repeated bigoted remarks that he has made off the screen, I have to admit that he gave a riveting performance in this film. He portrays a cab driver who is constantly thinking up various conspiracies, and then becomes pursued when one of his conspiracy theories proves to be right. As an attorney,Julia Roberts, who lost her father in a mysterious shooting, becomes involved with Gibson. The film is a good one due to the plot twists and turns. You really don't know who is good and evil in it. Patrick Stewart portrays a man with many hats. You just don't know where he is at until the very end. Roberts comes slowly to believe in what Gibson is saying until it appears that he had killed her father. The ending may be disappointing to many, but was probably necessary due to the clandestine and safety measures for the Roberts part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mel Gibson wins over Julia Roberts to his conspiracy theory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Conspiracy Theory" is Hollywood at its best, combining capable stars, thrills, romance, with a well-written and well-plotted script under sure direction. I enjoyed it thoroughly. Mel Gibson does a terrific job as the taxi driver who has many conspiracy theories and then turns out not to be a kook but to have the best of reasons for getting pulled in to a real conspiracy. Julia Roberts shows her acting chops by effortlessly playing a government security employee who finds herself completely enmeshed with Gibson, not least because of his motivation to protect her and how that came about. Solid entertainment that does not require much effort to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Always in my best 10 !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mad Watcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was incredibly smart, well written, funny and romantic. One of Mel Gibson's best act. Julia Roberts was the best choice for Alice Sutton (I cant imagine somebody else). She was really beautiful in this movie. You cant take your eyes from the movie especially when the ending comes. Well written small details you need the catch. Movie was interestingly underrated, is it a conspiracy? Sometimes I think about that. I do not want to give any spoiler, but this is a must watch movie, you will never regret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    buiger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with Ebert on this one. The script does seem confused, as if it has been re-written. The beginning of the film has nothing to do with what happens after wards. The end result is a mix up where none of the ends meet, making the screenplay totally ridiculous and thoroughly unbelievable. Is Jerry really the insecure and paranoid "conspiracy freak" like in the beginning of the movie or a highly trained special agent/murderer of the CIA? He can't be both. This paradox is present throughout the film and I think it also confused Gibson because it seems he doesn't really know which way to take the character himself. All in all, nothing special, a less than average quality Hollywood production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterthomson
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson overacts his way through the whole pile of rubbish and Julia Roberts is clearly there for the pay cheque. The thinnest of stories with poor dialogue throughout. Gibsons pathetic constant mumbling is overbearing and annoying and Roberts part of the sycophantic token female is a crime against acting.Take away the background music and special effects and it is almost laughable. I cant remember seeing such an awful film. the attempts at romance are so far removed from reality it borders on fantasy.Of the many thousands of films I have seen throughout my life, this is by far the worst one ever.I cant believe Julia Roberts would be happy with her name on this one. For Mel Gibson, it highlights his obvious acting limitations and one dimensional ability in such a way that maybe a close friend should have had a quiet word with him.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiracy And Paranoia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Conspiracy Theory is an action thriller film that features two of the Hollywood A-list stars namely: Mel Gibson and Julia Roberts.The original screenplay,written by Brian Helgeland,centers on an eccentric taxi driver who believes many world events are triggered by government conspiracies, and the U.S. Justice Department attorney who becomes involved in his life.It was directed by Richard Donner. Conspiracy Theory centers on the themes of conspiracy and paranoia.Jerry Fletcher is a New York City cab driver who seems to have absorbed every bit of crackpot information passed along as "suppressed news" that's surfaced on talk radio or the Internet in the past 20 years. Jerry's heard 'em all and believes most of them, and even publishes his own journal of forbidden information, with a subscription list that now totals five people. In short, Jerry seems like just another New York City lunatic, and while he spends a fair amount of his spare time following Alice Sutton, a government attorney. Alice regards him as harmless; he once intervened while she was being mugged, and he's been acting like her benign if whacked-out protector ever since. However, one day Jerry is kidnapped and worked over by CIA operatives; he is convinced that one of the theories he uncovered must be for real -- but he has no idea which one. He tries to get Alice to help him, and before long both are drawn into a dangerous web that leads to a startling revelation of just how Jerry got this way. The movie is definitely not short on entertainment.Mel Gibson gives a fine and comic performance as Jerry.He is able to carry the film and make it interesting from beginning to end.Julia Roberts is also worthy of mention and provides outstanding and brilliant acting as she shares great chemistry with Gibson.Unfortunately,the romantic aspect between the two characters looks implausible considering that Gibson's character seems lunatic and paranoid. Also,some parts of the story are far from realistic especially the traits that Jerry has considering that he is always ahead of the government,police,FBI and even the CIA.But nevertheless,one might say that it is just a movie and the story provides suspense and tension inspite of the wit and humor inserted in between scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What if all those crazy conspiracy theories end up being true.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this movie is just brilliant. It is exactly the type of movie that I just love. There so much happening in the background and you are never sure what really is happening. The theme of this movie is "the truth will set you free", but what really is the truth. The movie leads you to believe one thing and then confronts you with something that destroys everything the you had built up, only to knock this down as well. What really is true? You will never know. You follow the main character through out the movie  and this character really knows a lot. On the outside he appears to be a nut with all of these conspiracy theories but then a layer is pealed off to reveal a little more about this character. What does this character really know? Who is he  well the movie may tell you, or it may not. You know who the bad guy is, or is he really the bad guy. The only certainty is Julia Roberts' character. She seems to be legit, or is she. Yes I am being ambiguous for this is the whole aspect of this movie. Ambiguity reigns and as you dig deeper in to look for the truth, the more questions that are raised. As such this movie is brilliant. It is in the similar vein to the Usual Suspects. It creates a story only to tear it down and leaving you wondering what happened. It is the ultimate conspiracy theory. The conspiracies that Mel Gibson's character brings out seem to be ultimately wild  yet they do seem to make sense. Mel Gibson's character is brilliant. He is like a child with huge amounts of knowledge. At first is appears to be a simple cab driver with a tonne of wild ideas; and then the layers of his character begin to be peeled off. What does he really know? The character doesn't know the answer to this question. One thing that is very definite is that he really brings out patterns. He can see a pattern in almost everything and the patterns he pulls out really makes one think  are these really conspiracies. One brilliant aspect of the movie are the little tricks and gadgets that are used. They do not dominate the movie; but they are there to show us how intelligent this character really is. The Firewall and the Beer Bomb are two examples. The beer bomb is where a bottle is balanced on the door knob and when the knob is turn the bottle breaks. The firewall is a much more brilliant thing for it will utterly destroy the apartment without damaging anything else. If it is brilliant and clever tricks that you are looking for then this is a movie to see. Patrick Stewart plays the bad guy  or is he a bad guy. Stewart is a brilliant actor; unfortunately his seven year stint in Star Trek has dulled his edge. When I see Stewart on the screen I immediately think of Captain Picard. This, to me, can really destroy a really good actor. Mel Gibson is seen as Mel Gibson; Julia Roberts is seen as Julia Roberts; but one cannot help seeing Patrick Stewart as Captain Jean-luc Picard. There was one gripe I had with the movie, but I cannot tell you because if I did it would spoil it. It is one the really would have made it absolutely brilliant; but in a fallen world nothing is brilliant. Remember the words of the movie  "the truth will set you free."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Paranoiac as Romantic Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Conspiracy Theory" Mel Gibson plays Jerry Fletcher, a New York taxi driver. (The film was directed by Richard Donner, who also directed Gibson in "Maverick" and the "Lethal Weapon" series). Jerry is an obsessive conspiracy theorist who habitually who lectures his passengers on his various theories. He believes, for example, that the fathers of Nobel Prize winners are being kidnapped by the authorities and forced to become sperm donors. He believes that NASA is trying to kill the President using a secret weapon on the Space Shuttle that can trigger earthquakes. And he believes that the Jews are responsible for all the wars in the world. Or was it Mel Gibson himself who said that? Strange how life can imitate art and actors start behaving like the characters they once portrayed. The film is not, however, simply a psychological study of an eccentric oddball. It is, in fact, an action-thriller; one of Jerry's theories actually proves to be true; it involves a conspiracy by the CIA and other American government agencies to brainwash people in order to sue them as assassins. I won't try and set out the plot, which is extremely complex and at times confusing, in any detail, but it involves the efforts of Jerry and Alice Sutton, a young lawyer with the US Justice Department, to expose this conspiracy. Alice is trying to find out the truth about the murder of her father, whom she believes may have been killed by the conspirators. This is a fairly standard thriller plot; the genre frequently involves conspiracies by people in high places to commit some dark deed or other. Julia Roberts, who plays Alice here, starred in two other films of this type in the nineties, "The Pelican Brief" and "I Love Trouble", although this second example treated the theme in a more light-hearted way and also included romantic comedy elements. There are, indeed, attempts to inject both romance and comedy into "Conspiracy Theory", although both fall rather flat. The main problem with the film, apart from the fact that the plot is difficult to follow, is that, despite Gibson's best efforts to make him likable, Jerry remains, at bottom, a nutcase, and nutcases do not generally make credible screen heroes, and certainly not credible romantic heroes. Alice, of course, ends up falling for Jerry, even though in real life, any sane woman would run a mile from him, probably while telling herself that not every lunatic is actually in an asylum. It is hard to regard as love's young dream the sort of man who is so paranoid that he padlocks the coffee and sugar canisters in his kitchen. There are two ways in which one could make a film about a character like Jerry Fletcher, either as a character-driven psychological drama or as a black comedy. In either case the character would probably have to be dealt with much less indulgently than he is here. A paranoid conspiracy theorist as romantic hero just doesn't work, even if there turns out to be a rational explanation for his paranoia. The film achieves little, other than the presumably unintended achievement of making extremist views seem slightly more acceptable. Both Gibson and Roberts have much more distinguished entries on their CVs than this one. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Which Theory Is True?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson is most sympathetic as conspiracy theorist Jerry Fletcher, who lives in a ultra-secure, booby trapped apartment where he publishes his newsletter critical of the government. Ironically, he loves government employee Alice Sutton(played by Julia Roberts) from afar. One day, their worlds collide when one of Jerry's theories seems to be true, as he becomes the target of assassination, and Alice helps him to go on the run from the unknown government forces. He thinks that Dr. Jonas(Patrick Stewart) will help him, but it turns out that was one conspiracy he didn't anticipate... Entertaining thriller is well directed by Richard Donner, with a good pace and reasonably believable story, though it does go on a bit too long, and becomes a bit too convoluted, but otherwise this film works well, and some of Jerry's theories may not be so nutty anymore...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    patsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a fan of Conspiracy Theories so I figured I would check this one out,, it's above average,, based on the acting between our stars, Mel Gibson, Julia Robert,, and Patrick Stewart,, I was hoping for an actual conspiracy,, instead we get the old,, CIA, mind control stuff, rogue killer programmed to assassinate someone,, which isn't that bad, but some of the theories in the movie like the Oliver Stone --George Bush one,, I was like wow OK.. Mel's character, Jerry Fletcher is majorly paranoid, insanely crazy as one of his theories actually turns out to be true, problem for him is as he has so many now he has to figure out which theory he is right about,, he get's help from a young lady he saved from a mugging 6 months ago,, so he is like her guardian angel so to speak,, very interesting movie,, once you get by all the covert military mind control stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiring for A Very Good Film-Conspiracy Theory ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I dislike Mel Gibson for the repeated bigoted remarks that he has made off the screen, I have to admit that he gave a riveting performance in this film. He portrays a cab driver who is constantly thinking up various conspiracies, and then becomes pursued when one of his conspiracy theories proves to be right. As an attorney,Julia Roberts, who lost her father in a mysterious shooting, becomes involved with Gibson. The film is a good one due to the plot twists and turns. You really don't know who is good and evil in it. Patrick Stewart portrays a man with many hats. You just don't know where he is at until the very end. Roberts comes slowly to believe in what Gibson is saying until it appears that he had killed her father. The ending may be disappointing to many, but was probably necessary due to the clandestine and safety measures for the Roberts part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mel Gibson wins over Julia Roberts to his conspiracy theory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Conspiracy Theory" is Hollywood at its best, combining capable stars, thrills, romance, with a well-written and well-plotted script under sure direction. I enjoyed it thoroughly. Mel Gibson does a terrific job as the taxi driver who has many conspiracy theories and then turns out not to be a kook but to have the best of reasons for getting pulled in to a real conspiracy. Julia Roberts shows her acting chops by effortlessly playing a government security employee who finds herself completely enmeshed with Gibson, not least because of his motivation to protect her and how that came about. Solid entertainment that does not require much effort to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Always in my best 10 !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mad Watcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was incredibly smart, well written, funny and romantic. One of Mel Gibson's best act. Julia Roberts was the best choice for Alice Sutton (I cant imagine somebody else). She was really beautiful in this movie. You cant take your eyes from the movie especially when the ending comes. Well written small details you need the catch. Movie was interestingly underrated, is it a conspiracy? Sometimes I think about that. I do not want to give any spoiler, but this is a must watch movie, you will never regret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    buiger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with Ebert on this one. The script does seem confused, as if it has been re-written. The beginning of the film has nothing to do with what happens after wards. The end result is a mix up where none of the ends meet, making the screenplay totally ridiculous and thoroughly unbelievable. Is Jerry really the insecure and paranoid "conspiracy freak" like in the beginning of the movie or a highly trained special agent/murderer of the CIA? He can't be both. This paradox is present throughout the film and I think it also confused Gibson because it seems he doesn't really know which way to take the character himself. All in all, nothing special, a less than average quality Hollywood production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterthomson
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson overacts his way through the whole pile of rubbish and Julia Roberts is clearly there for the pay cheque. The thinnest of stories with poor dialogue throughout. Gibsons pathetic constant mumbling is overbearing and annoying and Roberts part of the sycophantic token female is a crime against acting.Take away the background music and special effects and it is almost laughable. I cant remember seeing such an awful film. the attempts at romance are so far removed from reality it borders on fantasy.Of the many thousands of films I have seen throughout my life, this is by far the worst one ever.I cant believe Julia Roberts would be happy with her name on this one. For Mel Gibson, it highlights his obvious acting limitations and one dimensional ability in such a way that maybe a close friend should have had a quiet word with him.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiracy And Paranoia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Conspiracy Theory is an action thriller film that features two of the Hollywood A-list stars namely: Mel Gibson and Julia Roberts.The original screenplay,written by Brian Helgeland,centers on an eccentric taxi driver who believes many world events are triggered by government conspiracies, and the U.S. Justice Department attorney who becomes involved in his life.It was directed by Richard Donner. Conspiracy Theory centers on the themes of conspiracy and paranoia.Jerry Fletcher is a New York City cab driver who seems to have absorbed every bit of crackpot information passed along as "suppressed news" that's surfaced on talk radio or the Internet in the past 20 years. Jerry's heard 'em all and believes most of them, and even publishes his own journal of forbidden information, with a subscription list that now totals five people. In short, Jerry seems like just another New York City lunatic, and while he spends a fair amount of his spare time following Alice Sutton, a government attorney. Alice regards him as harmless; he once intervened while she was being mugged, and he's been acting like her benign if whacked-out protector ever since. However, one day Jerry is kidnapped and worked over by CIA operatives; he is convinced that one of the theories he uncovered must be for real -- but he has no idea which one. He tries to get Alice to help him, and before long both are drawn into a dangerous web that leads to a startling revelation of just how Jerry got this way. The movie is definitely not short on entertainment.Mel Gibson gives a fine and comic performance as Jerry.He is able to carry the film and make it interesting from beginning to end.Julia Roberts is also worthy of mention and provides outstanding and brilliant acting as she shares great chemistry with Gibson.Unfortunately,the romantic aspect between the two characters looks implausible considering that Gibson's character seems lunatic and paranoid. Also,some parts of the story are far from realistic especially the traits that Jerry has considering that he is always ahead of the government,police,FBI and even the CIA.But nevertheless,one might say that it is just a movie and the story provides suspense and tension inspite of the wit and humor inserted in between scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What if all those crazy conspiracy theories end up being true.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this movie is just brilliant. It is exactly the type of movie that I just love. There so much happening in the background and you are never sure what really is happening. The theme of this movie is "the truth will set you free", but what really is the truth. The movie leads you to believe one thing and then confronts you with something that destroys everything the you had built up, only to knock this down as well. What really is true? You will never know. You follow the main character through out the movie  and this character really knows a lot. On the outside he appears to be a nut with all of these conspiracy theories but then a layer is pealed off to reveal a little more about this character. What does this character really know? Who is he  well the movie may tell you, or it may not. You know who the bad guy is, or is he really the bad guy. The only certainty is Julia Roberts' character. She seems to be legit, or is she. Yes I am being ambiguous for this is the whole aspect of this movie. Ambiguity reigns and as you dig deeper in to look for the truth, the more questions that are raised. As such this movie is brilliant. It is in the similar vein to the Usual Suspects. It creates a story only to tear it down and leaving you wondering what happened. It is the ultimate conspiracy theory. The conspiracies that Mel Gibson's character brings out seem to be ultimately wild  yet they do seem to make sense. Mel Gibson's character is brilliant. He is like a child with huge amounts of knowledge. At first is appears to be a simple cab driver with a tonne of wild ideas; and then the layers of his character begin to be peeled off. What does he really know? The character doesn't know the answer to this question. One thing that is very definite is that he really brings out patterns. He can see a pattern in almost everything and the patterns he pulls out really makes one think  are these really conspiracies. One brilliant aspect of the movie are the little tricks and gadgets that are used. They do not dominate the movie; but they are there to show us how intelligent this character really is. The Firewall and the Beer Bomb are two examples. The beer bomb is where a bottle is balanced on the door knob and when the knob is turn the bottle breaks. The firewall is a much more brilliant thing for it will utterly destroy the apartment without damaging anything else. If it is brilliant and clever tricks that you are looking for then this is a movie to see. Patrick Stewart plays the bad guy  or is he a bad guy. Stewart is a brilliant actor; unfortunately his seven year stint in Star Trek has dulled his edge. When I see Stewart on the screen I immediately think of Captain Picard. This, to me, can really destroy a really good actor. Mel Gibson is seen as Mel Gibson; Julia Roberts is seen as Julia Roberts; but one cannot help seeing Patrick Stewart as Captain Jean-luc Picard. There was one gripe I had with the movie, but I cannot tell you because if I did it would spoil it. It is one the really would have made it absolutely brilliant; but in a fallen world nothing is brilliant. Remember the words of the movie  "the truth will set you free."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Paranoiac as Romantic Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Conspiracy Theory" Mel Gibson plays Jerry Fletcher, a New York taxi driver. (The film was directed by Richard Donner, who also directed Gibson in "Maverick" and the "Lethal Weapon" series). Jerry is an obsessive conspiracy theorist who habitually who lectures his passengers on his various theories. He believes, for example, that the fathers of Nobel Prize winners are being kidnapped by the authorities and forced to become sperm donors. He believes that NASA is trying to kill the President using a secret weapon on the Space Shuttle that can trigger earthquakes. And he believes that the Jews are responsible for all the wars in the world. Or was it Mel Gibson himself who said that? Strange how life can imitate art and actors start behaving like the characters they once portrayed. The film is not, however, simply a psychological study of an eccentric oddball. It is, in fact, an action-thriller; one of Jerry's theories actually proves to be true; it involves a conspiracy by the CIA and other American government agencies to brainwash people in order to sue them as assassins. I won't try and set out the plot, which is extremely complex and at times confusing, in any detail, but it involves the efforts of Jerry and Alice Sutton, a young lawyer with the US Justice Department, to expose this conspiracy. Alice is trying to find out the truth about the murder of her father, whom she believes may have been killed by the conspirators. This is a fairly standard thriller plot; the genre frequently involves conspiracies by people in high places to commit some dark deed or other. Julia Roberts, who plays Alice here, starred in two other films of this type in the nineties, "The Pelican Brief" and "I Love Trouble", although this second example treated the theme in a more light-hearted way and also included romantic comedy elements. There are, indeed, attempts to inject both romance and comedy into "Conspiracy Theory", although both fall rather flat. The main problem with the film, apart from the fact that the plot is difficult to follow, is that, despite Gibson's best efforts to make him likable, Jerry remains, at bottom, a nutcase, and nutcases do not generally make credible screen heroes, and certainly not credible romantic heroes. Alice, of course, ends up falling for Jerry, even though in real life, any sane woman would run a mile from him, probably while telling herself that not every lunatic is actually in an asylum. It is hard to regard as love's young dream the sort of man who is so paranoid that he padlocks the coffee and sugar canisters in his kitchen. There are two ways in which one could make a film about a character like Jerry Fletcher, either as a character-driven psychological drama or as a black comedy. In either case the character would probably have to be dealt with much less indulgently than he is here. A paranoid conspiracy theorist as romantic hero just doesn't work, even if there turns out to be a rational explanation for his paranoia. The film achieves little, other than the presumably unintended achievement of making extremist views seem slightly more acceptable. Both Gibson and Roberts have much more distinguished entries on their CVs than this one. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Which Theory Is True?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson is most sympathetic as conspiracy theorist Jerry Fletcher, who lives in a ultra-secure, booby trapped apartment where he publishes his newsletter critical of the government. Ironically, he loves government employee Alice Sutton(played by Julia Roberts) from afar. One day, their worlds collide when one of Jerry's theories seems to be true, as he becomes the target of assassination, and Alice helps him to go on the run from the unknown government forces. He thinks that Dr. Jonas(Patrick Stewart) will help him, but it turns out that was one conspiracy he didn't anticipate... Entertaining thriller is well directed by Richard Donner, with a good pace and reasonably believable story, though it does go on a bit too long, and becomes a bit too convoluted, but otherwise this film works well, and some of Jerry's theories may not be so nutty anymore...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    patsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a fan of Conspiracy Theories so I figured I would check this one out,, it's above average,, based on the acting between our stars, Mel Gibson, Julia Robert,, and Patrick Stewart,, I was hoping for an actual conspiracy,, instead we get the old,, CIA, mind control stuff, rogue killer programmed to assassinate someone,, which isn't that bad, but some of the theories in the movie like the Oliver Stone --George Bush one,, I was like wow OK.. Mel's character, Jerry Fletcher is majorly paranoid, insanely crazy as one of his theories actually turns out to be true, problem for him is as he has so many now he has to figure out which theory he is right about,, he get's help from a young lady he saved from a mugging 6 months ago,, so he is like her guardian angel so to speak,, very interesting movie,, once you get by all the covert military mind control stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiring for A Very Good Film-Conspiracy Theory ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I dislike Mel Gibson for the repeated bigoted remarks that he has made off the screen, I have to admit that he gave a riveting performance in this film. He portrays a cab driver who is constantly thinking up various conspiracies, and then becomes pursued when one of his conspiracy theories proves to be right. As an attorney,Julia Roberts, who lost her father in a mysterious shooting, becomes involved with Gibson. The film is a good one due to the plot twists and turns. You really don't know who is good and evil in it. Patrick Stewart portrays a man with many hats. You just don't know where he is at until the very end. Roberts comes slowly to believe in what Gibson is saying until it appears that he had killed her father. The ending may be disappointing to many, but was probably necessary due to the clandestine and safety measures for the Roberts part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mel Gibson wins over Julia Roberts to his conspiracy theory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Conspiracy Theory" is Hollywood at its best, combining capable stars, thrills, romance, with a well-written and well-plotted script under sure direction. I enjoyed it thoroughly. Mel Gibson does a terrific job as the taxi driver who has many conspiracy theories and then turns out not to be a kook but to have the best of reasons for getting pulled in to a real conspiracy. Julia Roberts shows her acting chops by effortlessly playing a government security employee who finds herself completely enmeshed with Gibson, not least because of his motivation to protect her and how that came about. Solid entertainment that does not require much effort to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Always in my best 10 !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mad Watcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was incredibly smart, well written, funny and romantic. One of Mel Gibson's best act. Julia Roberts was the best choice for Alice Sutton (I cant imagine somebody else). She was really beautiful in this movie. You cant take your eyes from the movie especially when the ending comes. Well written small details you need the catch. Movie was interestingly underrated, is it a conspiracy? Sometimes I think about that. I do not want to give any spoiler, but this is a must watch movie, you will never regret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    buiger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with Ebert on this one. The script does seem confused, as if it has been re-written. The beginning of the film has nothing to do with what happens after wards. The end result is a mix up where none of the ends meet, making the screenplay totally ridiculous and thoroughly unbelievable. Is Jerry really the insecure and paranoid "conspiracy freak" like in the beginning of the movie or a highly trained special agent/murderer of the CIA? He can't be both. This paradox is present throughout the film and I think it also confused Gibson because it seems he doesn't really know which way to take the character himself. All in all, nothing special, a less than average quality Hollywood production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterthomson
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson overacts his way through the whole pile of rubbish and Julia Roberts is clearly there for the pay cheque. The thinnest of stories with poor dialogue throughout. Gibsons pathetic constant mumbling is overbearing and annoying and Roberts part of the sycophantic token female is a crime against acting.Take away the background music and special effects and it is almost laughable. I cant remember seeing such an awful film. the attempts at romance are so far removed from reality it borders on fantasy.Of the many thousands of films I have seen throughout my life, this is by far the worst one ever.I cant believe Julia Roberts would be happy with her name on this one. For Mel Gibson, it highlights his obvious acting limitations and one dimensional ability in such a way that maybe a close friend should have had a quiet word with him.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiracy And Paranoia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Conspiracy Theory is an action thriller film that features two of the Hollywood A-list stars namely: Mel Gibson and Julia Roberts.The original screenplay,written by Brian Helgeland,centers on an eccentric taxi driver who believes many world events are triggered by government conspiracies, and the U.S. Justice Department attorney who becomes involved in his life.It was directed by Richard Donner. Conspiracy Theory centers on the themes of conspiracy and paranoia.Jerry Fletcher is a New York City cab driver who seems to have absorbed every bit of crackpot information passed along as "suppressed news" that's surfaced on talk radio or the Internet in the past 20 years. Jerry's heard 'em all and believes most of them, and even publishes his own journal of forbidden information, with a subscription list that now totals five people. In short, Jerry seems like just another New York City lunatic, and while he spends a fair amount of his spare time following Alice Sutton, a government attorney. Alice regards him as harmless; he once intervened while she was being mugged, and he's been acting like her benign if whacked-out protector ever since. However, one day Jerry is kidnapped and worked over by CIA operatives; he is convinced that one of the theories he uncovered must be for real -- but he has no idea which one. He tries to get Alice to help him, and before long both are drawn into a dangerous web that leads to a startling revelation of just how Jerry got this way. The movie is definitely not short on entertainment.Mel Gibson gives a fine and comic performance as Jerry.He is able to carry the film and make it interesting from beginning to end.Julia Roberts is also worthy of mention and provides outstanding and brilliant acting as she shares great chemistry with Gibson.Unfortunately,the romantic aspect between the two characters looks implausible considering that Gibson's character seems lunatic and paranoid. Also,some parts of the story are far from realistic especially the traits that Jerry has considering that he is always ahead of the government,police,FBI and even the CIA.But nevertheless,one might say that it is just a movie and the story provides suspense and tension inspite of the wit and humor inserted in between scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What if all those crazy conspiracy theories end up being true.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this movie is just brilliant. It is exactly the type of movie that I just love. There so much happening in the background and you are never sure what really is happening. The theme of this movie is "the truth will set you free", but what really is the truth. The movie leads you to believe one thing and then confronts you with something that destroys everything the you had built up, only to knock this down as well. What really is true? You will never know. You follow the main character through out the movie  and this character really knows a lot. On the outside he appears to be a nut with all of these conspiracy theories but then a layer is pealed off to reveal a little more about this character. What does this character really know? Who is he  well the movie may tell you, or it may not. You know who the bad guy is, or is he really the bad guy. The only certainty is Julia Roberts' character. She seems to be legit, or is she. Yes I am being ambiguous for this is the whole aspect of this movie. Ambiguity reigns and as you dig deeper in to look for the truth, the more questions that are raised. As such this movie is brilliant. It is in the similar vein to the Usual Suspects. It creates a story only to tear it down and leaving you wondering what happened. It is the ultimate conspiracy theory. The conspiracies that Mel Gibson's character brings out seem to be ultimately wild  yet they do seem to make sense. Mel Gibson's character is brilliant. He is like a child with huge amounts of knowledge. At first is appears to be a simple cab driver with a tonne of wild ideas; and then the layers of his character begin to be peeled off. What does he really know? The character doesn't know the answer to this question. One thing that is very definite is that he really brings out patterns. He can see a pattern in almost everything and the patterns he pulls out really makes one think  are these really conspiracies. One brilliant aspect of the movie are the little tricks and gadgets that are used. They do not dominate the movie; but they are there to show us how intelligent this character really is. The Firewall and the Beer Bomb are two examples. The beer bomb is where a bottle is balanced on the door knob and when the knob is turn the bottle breaks. The firewall is a much more brilliant thing for it will utterly destroy the apartment without damaging anything else. If it is brilliant and clever tricks that you are looking for then this is a movie to see. Patrick Stewart plays the bad guy  or is he a bad guy. Stewart is a brilliant actor; unfortunately his seven year stint in Star Trek has dulled his edge. When I see Stewart on the screen I immediately think of Captain Picard. This, to me, can really destroy a really good actor. Mel Gibson is seen as Mel Gibson; Julia Roberts is seen as Julia Roberts; but one cannot help seeing Patrick Stewart as Captain Jean-luc Picard. There was one gripe I had with the movie, but I cannot tell you because if I did it would spoil it. It is one the really would have made it absolutely brilliant; but in a fallen world nothing is brilliant. Remember the words of the movie  "the truth will set you free."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Paranoiac as Romantic Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Conspiracy Theory" Mel Gibson plays Jerry Fletcher, a New York taxi driver. (The film was directed by Richard Donner, who also directed Gibson in "Maverick" and the "Lethal Weapon" series). Jerry is an obsessive conspiracy theorist who habitually who lectures his passengers on his various theories. He believes, for example, that the fathers of Nobel Prize winners are being kidnapped by the authorities and forced to become sperm donors. He believes that NASA is trying to kill the President using a secret weapon on the Space Shuttle that can trigger earthquakes. And he believes that the Jews are responsible for all the wars in the world. Or was it Mel Gibson himself who said that? Strange how life can imitate art and actors start behaving like the characters they once portrayed. The film is not, however, simply a psychological study of an eccentric oddball. It is, in fact, an action-thriller; one of Jerry's theories actually proves to be true; it involves a conspiracy by the CIA and other American government agencies to brainwash people in order to sue them as assassins. I won't try and set out the plot, which is extremely complex and at times confusing, in any detail, but it involves the efforts of Jerry and Alice Sutton, a young lawyer with the US Justice Department, to expose this conspiracy. Alice is trying to find out the truth about the murder of her father, whom she believes may have been killed by the conspirators. This is a fairly standard thriller plot; the genre frequently involves conspiracies by people in high places to commit some dark deed or other. Julia Roberts, who plays Alice here, starred in two other films of this type in the nineties, "The Pelican Brief" and "I Love Trouble", although this second example treated the theme in a more light-hearted way and also included romantic comedy elements. There are, indeed, attempts to inject both romance and comedy into "Conspiracy Theory", although both fall rather flat. The main problem with the film, apart from the fact that the plot is difficult to follow, is that, despite Gibson's best efforts to make him likable, Jerry remains, at bottom, a nutcase, and nutcases do not generally make credible screen heroes, and certainly not credible romantic heroes. Alice, of course, ends up falling for Jerry, even though in real life, any sane woman would run a mile from him, probably while telling herself that not every lunatic is actually in an asylum. It is hard to regard as love's young dream the sort of man who is so paranoid that he padlocks the coffee and sugar canisters in his kitchen. There are two ways in which one could make a film about a character like Jerry Fletcher, either as a character-driven psychological drama or as a black comedy. In either case the character would probably have to be dealt with much less indulgently than he is here. A paranoid conspiracy theorist as romantic hero just doesn't work, even if there turns out to be a rational explanation for his paranoia. The film achieves little, other than the presumably unintended achievement of making extremist views seem slightly more acceptable. Both Gibson and Roberts have much more distinguished entries on their CVs than this one. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Which Theory Is True?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson is most sympathetic as conspiracy theorist Jerry Fletcher, who lives in a ultra-secure, booby trapped apartment where he publishes his newsletter critical of the government. Ironically, he loves government employee Alice Sutton(played by Julia Roberts) from afar. One day, their worlds collide when one of Jerry's theories seems to be true, as he becomes the target of assassination, and Alice helps him to go on the run from the unknown government forces. He thinks that Dr. Jonas(Patrick Stewart) will help him, but it turns out that was one conspiracy he didn't anticipate... Entertaining thriller is well directed by Richard Donner, with a good pace and reasonably believable story, though it does go on a bit too long, and becomes a bit too convoluted, but otherwise this film works well, and some of Jerry's theories may not be so nutty anymore...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    patsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a fan of Conspiracy Theories so I figured I would check this one out,, it's above average,, based on the acting between our stars, Mel Gibson, Julia Robert,, and Patrick Stewart,, I was hoping for an actual conspiracy,, instead we get the old,, CIA, mind control stuff, rogue killer programmed to assassinate someone,, which isn't that bad, but some of the theories in the movie like the Oliver Stone --George Bush one,, I was like wow OK.. Mel's character, Jerry Fletcher is majorly paranoid, insanely crazy as one of his theories actually turns out to be true, problem for him is as he has so many now he has to figure out which theory he is right about,, he get's help from a young lady he saved from a mugging 6 months ago,, so he is like her guardian angel so to speak,, very interesting movie,, once you get by all the covert military mind control stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiring for A Very Good Film-Conspiracy Theory ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I dislike Mel Gibson for the repeated bigoted remarks that he has made off the screen, I have to admit that he gave a riveting performance in this film. He portrays a cab driver who is constantly thinking up various conspiracies, and then becomes pursued when one of his conspiracy theories proves to be right. As an attorney,Julia Roberts, who lost her father in a mysterious shooting, becomes involved with Gibson. The film is a good one due to the plot twists and turns. You really don't know who is good and evil in it. Patrick Stewart portrays a man with many hats. You just don't know where he is at until the very end. Roberts comes slowly to believe in what Gibson is saying until it appears that he had killed her father. The ending may be disappointing to many, but was probably necessary due to the clandestine and safety measures for the Roberts part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mel Gibson wins over Julia Roberts to his conspiracy theory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Conspiracy Theory" is Hollywood at its best, combining capable stars, thrills, romance, with a well-written and well-plotted script under sure direction. I enjoyed it thoroughly. Mel Gibson does a terrific job as the taxi driver who has many conspiracy theories and then turns out not to be a kook but to have the best of reasons for getting pulled in to a real conspiracy. Julia Roberts shows her acting chops by effortlessly playing a government security employee who finds herself completely enmeshed with Gibson, not least because of his motivation to protect her and how that came about. Solid entertainment that does not require much effort to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Always in my best 10 !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mad Watcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was incredibly smart, well written, funny and romantic. One of Mel Gibson's best act. Julia Roberts was the best choice for Alice Sutton (I cant imagine somebody else). She was really beautiful in this movie. You cant take your eyes from the movie especially when the ending comes. Well written small details you need the catch. Movie was interestingly underrated, is it a conspiracy? Sometimes I think about that. I do not want to give any spoiler, but this is a must watch movie, you will never regret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    buiger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with Ebert on this one. The script does seem confused, as if it has been re-written. The beginning of the film has nothing to do with what happens after wards. The end result is a mix up where none of the ends meet, making the screenplay totally ridiculous and thoroughly unbelievable. Is Jerry really the insecure and paranoid "conspiracy freak" like in the beginning of the movie or a highly trained special agent/murderer of the CIA? He can't be both. This paradox is present throughout the film and I think it also confused Gibson because it seems he doesn't really know which way to take the character himself. All in all, nothing special, a less than average quality Hollywood production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterthomson
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson overacts his way through the whole pile of rubbish and Julia Roberts is clearly there for the pay cheque. The thinnest of stories with poor dialogue throughout. Gibsons pathetic constant mumbling is overbearing and annoying and Roberts part of the sycophantic token female is a crime against acting.Take away the background music and special effects and it is almost laughable. I cant remember seeing such an awful film. the attempts at romance are so far removed from reality it borders on fantasy.Of the many thousands of films I have seen throughout my life, this is by far the worst one ever.I cant believe Julia Roberts would be happy with her name on this one. For Mel Gibson, it highlights his obvious acting limitations and one dimensional ability in such a way that maybe a close friend should have had a quiet word with him.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiracy And Paranoia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Conspiracy Theory is an action thriller film that features two of the Hollywood A-list stars namely: Mel Gibson and Julia Roberts.The original screenplay,written by Brian Helgeland,centers on an eccentric taxi driver who believes many world events are triggered by government conspiracies, and the U.S. Justice Department attorney who becomes involved in his life.It was directed by Richard Donner. Conspiracy Theory centers on the themes of conspiracy and paranoia.Jerry Fletcher is a New York City cab driver who seems to have absorbed every bit of crackpot information passed along as "suppressed news" that's surfaced on talk radio or the Internet in the past 20 years. Jerry's heard 'em all and believes most of them, and even publishes his own journal of forbidden information, with a subscription list that now totals five people. In short, Jerry seems like just another New York City lunatic, and while he spends a fair amount of his spare time following Alice Sutton, a government attorney. Alice regards him as harmless; he once intervened while she was being mugged, and he's been acting like her benign if whacked-out protector ever since. However, one day Jerry is kidnapped and worked over by CIA operatives; he is convinced that one of the theories he uncovered must be for real -- but he has no idea which one. He tries to get Alice to help him, and before long both are drawn into a dangerous web that leads to a startling revelation of just how Jerry got this way. The movie is definitely not short on entertainment.Mel Gibson gives a fine and comic performance as Jerry.He is able to carry the film and make it interesting from beginning to end.Julia Roberts is also worthy of mention and provides outstanding and brilliant acting as she shares great chemistry with Gibson.Unfortunately,the romantic aspect between the two characters looks implausible considering that Gibson's character seems lunatic and paranoid. Also,some parts of the story are far from realistic especially the traits that Jerry has considering that he is always ahead of the government,police,FBI and even the CIA.But nevertheless,one might say that it is just a movie and the story provides suspense and tension inspite of the wit and humor inserted in between scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What if all those crazy conspiracy theories end up being true.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this movie is just brilliant. It is exactly the type of movie that I just love. There so much happening in the background and you are never sure what really is happening. The theme of this movie is "the truth will set you free", but what really is the truth. The movie leads you to believe one thing and then confronts you with something that destroys everything the you had built up, only to knock this down as well. What really is true? You will never know. You follow the main character through out the movie  and this character really knows a lot. On the outside he appears to be a nut with all of these conspiracy theories but then a layer is pealed off to reveal a little more about this character. What does this character really know? Who is he  well the movie may tell you, or it may not. You know who the bad guy is, or is he really the bad guy. The only certainty is Julia Roberts' character. She seems to be legit, or is she. Yes I am being ambiguous for this is the whole aspect of this movie. Ambiguity reigns and as you dig deeper in to look for the truth, the more questions that are raised. As such this movie is brilliant. It is in the similar vein to the Usual Suspects. It creates a story only to tear it down and leaving you wondering what happened. It is the ultimate conspiracy theory. The conspiracies that Mel Gibson's character brings out seem to be ultimately wild  yet they do seem to make sense. Mel Gibson's character is brilliant. He is like a child with huge amounts of knowledge. At first is appears to be a simple cab driver with a tonne of wild ideas; and then the layers of his character begin to be peeled off. What does he really know? The character doesn't know the answer to this question. One thing that is very definite is that he really brings out patterns. He can see a pattern in almost everything and the patterns he pulls out really makes one think  are these really conspiracies. One brilliant aspect of the movie are the little tricks and gadgets that are used. They do not dominate the movie; but they are there to show us how intelligent this character really is. The Firewall and the Beer Bomb are two examples. The beer bomb is where a bottle is balanced on the door knob and when the knob is turn the bottle breaks. The firewall is a much more brilliant thing for it will utterly destroy the apartment without damaging anything else. If it is brilliant and clever tricks that you are looking for then this is a movie to see. Patrick Stewart plays the bad guy  or is he a bad guy. Stewart is a brilliant actor; unfortunately his seven year stint in Star Trek has dulled his edge. When I see Stewart on the screen I immediately think of Captain Picard. This, to me, can really destroy a really good actor. Mel Gibson is seen as Mel Gibson; Julia Roberts is seen as Julia Roberts; but one cannot help seeing Patrick Stewart as Captain Jean-luc Picard. There was one gripe I had with the movie, but I cannot tell you because if I did it would spoil it. It is one the really would have made it absolutely brilliant; but in a fallen world nothing is brilliant. Remember the words of the movie  "the truth will set you free."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Paranoiac as Romantic Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Conspiracy Theory" Mel Gibson plays Jerry Fletcher, a New York taxi driver. (The film was directed by Richard Donner, who also directed Gibson in "Maverick" and the "Lethal Weapon" series). Jerry is an obsessive conspiracy theorist who habitually who lectures his passengers on his various theories. He believes, for example, that the fathers of Nobel Prize winners are being kidnapped by the authorities and forced to become sperm donors. He believes that NASA is trying to kill the President using a secret weapon on the Space Shuttle that can trigger earthquakes. And he believes that the Jews are responsible for all the wars in the world. Or was it Mel Gibson himself who said that? Strange how life can imitate art and actors start behaving like the characters they once portrayed. The film is not, however, simply a psychological study of an eccentric oddball. It is, in fact, an action-thriller; one of Jerry's theories actually proves to be true; it involves a conspiracy by the CIA and other American government agencies to brainwash people in order to sue them as assassins. I won't try and set out the plot, which is extremely complex and at times confusing, in any detail, but it involves the efforts of Jerry and Alice Sutton, a young lawyer with the US Justice Department, to expose this conspiracy. Alice is trying to find out the truth about the murder of her father, whom she believes may have been killed by the conspirators. This is a fairly standard thriller plot; the genre frequently involves conspiracies by people in high places to commit some dark deed or other. Julia Roberts, who plays Alice here, starred in two other films of this type in the nineties, "The Pelican Brief" and "I Love Trouble", although this second example treated the theme in a more light-hearted way and also included romantic comedy elements. There are, indeed, attempts to inject both romance and comedy into "Conspiracy Theory", although both fall rather flat. The main problem with the film, apart from the fact that the plot is difficult to follow, is that, despite Gibson's best efforts to make him likable, Jerry remains, at bottom, a nutcase, and nutcases do not generally make credible screen heroes, and certainly not credible romantic heroes. Alice, of course, ends up falling for Jerry, even though in real life, any sane woman would run a mile from him, probably while telling herself that not every lunatic is actually in an asylum. It is hard to regard as love's young dream the sort of man who is so paranoid that he padlocks the coffee and sugar canisters in his kitchen. There are two ways in which one could make a film about a character like Jerry Fletcher, either as a character-driven psychological drama or as a black comedy. In either case the character would probably have to be dealt with much less indulgently than he is here. A paranoid conspiracy theorist as romantic hero just doesn't work, even if there turns out to be a rational explanation for his paranoia. The film achieves little, other than the presumably unintended achievement of making extremist views seem slightly more acceptable. Both Gibson and Roberts have much more distinguished entries on their CVs than this one. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Which Theory Is True?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson is most sympathetic as conspiracy theorist Jerry Fletcher, who lives in a ultra-secure, booby trapped apartment where he publishes his newsletter critical of the government. Ironically, he loves government employee Alice Sutton(played by Julia Roberts) from afar. One day, their worlds collide when one of Jerry's theories seems to be true, as he becomes the target of assassination, and Alice helps him to go on the run from the unknown government forces. He thinks that Dr. Jonas(Patrick Stewart) will help him, but it turns out that was one conspiracy he didn't anticipate... Entertaining thriller is well directed by Richard Donner, with a good pace and reasonably believable story, though it does go on a bit too long, and becomes a bit too convoluted, but otherwise this film works well, and some of Jerry's theories may not be so nutty anymore...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    patsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a fan of Conspiracy Theories so I figured I would check this one out,, it's above average,, based on the acting between our stars, Mel Gibson, Julia Robert,, and Patrick Stewart,, I was hoping for an actual conspiracy,, instead we get the old,, CIA, mind control stuff, rogue killer programmed to assassinate someone,, which isn't that bad, but some of the theories in the movie like the Oliver Stone --George Bush one,, I was like wow OK.. Mel's character, Jerry Fletcher is majorly paranoid, insanely crazy as one of his theories actually turns out to be true, problem for him is as he has so many now he has to figure out which theory he is right about,, he get's help from a young lady he saved from a mugging 6 months ago,, so he is like her guardian angel so to speak,, very interesting movie,, once you get by all the covert military mind control stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiring for A Very Good Film-Conspiracy Theory ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I dislike Mel Gibson for the repeated bigoted remarks that he has made off the screen, I have to admit that he gave a riveting performance in this film. He portrays a cab driver who is constantly thinking up various conspiracies, and then becomes pursued when one of his conspiracy theories proves to be right. As an attorney,Julia Roberts, who lost her father in a mysterious shooting, becomes involved with Gibson. The film is a good one due to the plot twists and turns. You really don't know who is good and evil in it. Patrick Stewart portrays a man with many hats. You just don't know where he is at until the very end. Roberts comes slowly to believe in what Gibson is saying until it appears that he had killed her father. The ending may be disappointing to many, but was probably necessary due to the clandestine and safety measures for the Roberts part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mel Gibson wins over Julia Roberts to his conspiracy theory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Conspiracy Theory" is Hollywood at its best, combining capable stars, thrills, romance, with a well-written and well-plotted script under sure direction. I enjoyed it thoroughly. Mel Gibson does a terrific job as the taxi driver who has many conspiracy theories and then turns out not to be a kook but to have the best of reasons for getting pulled in to a real conspiracy. Julia Roberts shows her acting chops by effortlessly playing a government security employee who finds herself completely enmeshed with Gibson, not least because of his motivation to protect her and how that came about. Solid entertainment that does not require much effort to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Always in my best 10 !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mad Watcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was incredibly smart, well written, funny and romantic. One of Mel Gibson's best act. Julia Roberts was the best choice for Alice Sutton (I cant imagine somebody else). She was really beautiful in this movie. You cant take your eyes from the movie especially when the ending comes. Well written small details you need the catch. Movie was interestingly underrated, is it a conspiracy? Sometimes I think about that. I do not want to give any spoiler, but this is a must watch movie, you will never regret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    buiger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with Ebert on this one. The script does seem confused, as if it has been re-written. The beginning of the film has nothing to do with what happens after wards. The end result is a mix up where none of the ends meet, making the screenplay totally ridiculous and thoroughly unbelievable. Is Jerry really the insecure and paranoid "conspiracy freak" like in the beginning of the movie or a highly trained special agent/murderer of the CIA? He can't be both. This paradox is present throughout the film and I think it also confused Gibson because it seems he doesn't really know which way to take the character himself. All in all, nothing special, a less than average quality Hollywood production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterthomson
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson overacts his way through the whole pile of rubbish and Julia Roberts is clearly there for the pay cheque. The thinnest of stories with poor dialogue throughout. Gibsons pathetic constant mumbling is overbearing and annoying and Roberts part of the sycophantic token female is a crime against acting.Take away the background music and special effects and it is almost laughable. I cant remember seeing such an awful film. the attempts at romance are so far removed from reality it borders on fantasy.Of the many thousands of films I have seen throughout my life, this is by far the worst one ever.I cant believe Julia Roberts would be happy with her name on this one. For Mel Gibson, it highlights his obvious acting limitations and one dimensional ability in such a way that maybe a close friend should have had a quiet word with him.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiracy And Paranoia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Conspiracy Theory is an action thriller film that features two of the Hollywood A-list stars namely: Mel Gibson and Julia Roberts.The original screenplay,written by Brian Helgeland,centers on an eccentric taxi driver who believes many world events are triggered by government conspiracies, and the U.S. Justice Department attorney who becomes involved in his life.It was directed by Richard Donner. Conspiracy Theory centers on the themes of conspiracy and paranoia.Jerry Fletcher is a New York City cab driver who seems to have absorbed every bit of crackpot information passed along as "suppressed news" that's surfaced on talk radio or the Internet in the past 20 years. Jerry's heard 'em all and believes most of them, and even publishes his own journal of forbidden information, with a subscription list that now totals five people. In short, Jerry seems like just another New York City lunatic, and while he spends a fair amount of his spare time following Alice Sutton, a government attorney. Alice regards him as harmless; he once intervened while she was being mugged, and he's been acting like her benign if whacked-out protector ever since. However, one day Jerry is kidnapped and worked over by CIA operatives; he is convinced that one of the theories he uncovered must be for real -- but he has no idea which one. He tries to get Alice to help him, and before long both are drawn into a dangerous web that leads to a startling revelation of just how Jerry got this way. The movie is definitely not short on entertainment.Mel Gibson gives a fine and comic performance as Jerry.He is able to carry the film and make it interesting from beginning to end.Julia Roberts is also worthy of mention and provides outstanding and brilliant acting as she shares great chemistry with Gibson.Unfortunately,the romantic aspect between the two characters looks implausible considering that Gibson's character seems lunatic and paranoid. Also,some parts of the story are far from realistic especially the traits that Jerry has considering that he is always ahead of the government,police,FBI and even the CIA.But nevertheless,one might say that it is just a movie and the story provides suspense and tension inspite of the wit and humor inserted in between scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What if all those crazy conspiracy theories end up being true.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this movie is just brilliant. It is exactly the type of movie that I just love. There so much happening in the background and you are never sure what really is happening. The theme of this movie is "the truth will set you free", but what really is the truth. The movie leads you to believe one thing and then confronts you with something that destroys everything the you had built up, only to knock this down as well. What really is true? You will never know. You follow the main character through out the movie  and this character really knows a lot. On the outside he appears to be a nut with all of these conspiracy theories but then a layer is pealed off to reveal a little more about this character. What does this character really know? Who is he  well the movie may tell you, or it may not. You know who the bad guy is, or is he really the bad guy. The only certainty is Julia Roberts' character. She seems to be legit, or is she. Yes I am being ambiguous for this is the whole aspect of this movie. Ambiguity reigns and as you dig deeper in to look for the truth, the more questions that are raised. As such this movie is brilliant. It is in the similar vein to the Usual Suspects. It creates a story only to tear it down and leaving you wondering what happened. It is the ultimate conspiracy theory. The conspiracies that Mel Gibson's character brings out seem to be ultimately wild  yet they do seem to make sense. Mel Gibson's character is brilliant. He is like a child with huge amounts of knowledge. At first is appears to be a simple cab driver with a tonne of wild ideas; and then the layers of his character begin to be peeled off. What does he really know? The character doesn't know the answer to this question. One thing that is very definite is that he really brings out patterns. He can see a pattern in almost everything and the patterns he pulls out really makes one think  are these really conspiracies. One brilliant aspect of the movie are the little tricks and gadgets that are used. They do not dominate the movie; but they are there to show us how intelligent this character really is. The Firewall and the Beer Bomb are two examples. The beer bomb is where a bottle is balanced on the door knob and when the knob is turn the bottle breaks. The firewall is a much more brilliant thing for it will utterly destroy the apartment without damaging anything else. If it is brilliant and clever tricks that you are looking for then this is a movie to see. Patrick Stewart plays the bad guy  or is he a bad guy. Stewart is a brilliant actor; unfortunately his seven year stint in Star Trek has dulled his edge. When I see Stewart on the screen I immediately think of Captain Picard. This, to me, can really destroy a really good actor. Mel Gibson is seen as Mel Gibson; Julia Roberts is seen as Julia Roberts; but one cannot help seeing Patrick Stewart as Captain Jean-luc Picard. There was one gripe I had with the movie, but I cannot tell you because if I did it would spoil it. It is one the really would have made it absolutely brilliant; but in a fallen world nothing is brilliant. Remember the words of the movie  "the truth will set you free."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Paranoiac as Romantic Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Conspiracy Theory" Mel Gibson plays Jerry Fletcher, a New York taxi driver. (The film was directed by Richard Donner, who also directed Gibson in "Maverick" and the "Lethal Weapon" series). Jerry is an obsessive conspiracy theorist who habitually who lectures his passengers on his various theories. He believes, for example, that the fathers of Nobel Prize winners are being kidnapped by the authorities and forced to become sperm donors. He believes that NASA is trying to kill the President using a secret weapon on the Space Shuttle that can trigger earthquakes. And he believes that the Jews are responsible for all the wars in the world. Or was it Mel Gibson himself who said that? Strange how life can imitate art and actors start behaving like the characters they once portrayed. The film is not, however, simply a psychological study of an eccentric oddball. It is, in fact, an action-thriller; one of Jerry's theories actually proves to be true; it involves a conspiracy by the CIA and other American government agencies to brainwash people in order to sue them as assassins. I won't try and set out the plot, which is extremely complex and at times confusing, in any detail, but it involves the efforts of Jerry and Alice Sutton, a young lawyer with the US Justice Department, to expose this conspiracy. Alice is trying to find out the truth about the murder of her father, whom she believes may have been killed by the conspirators. This is a fairly standard thriller plot; the genre frequently involves conspiracies by people in high places to commit some dark deed or other. Julia Roberts, who plays Alice here, starred in two other films of this type in the nineties, "The Pelican Brief" and "I Love Trouble", although this second example treated the theme in a more light-hearted way and also included romantic comedy elements. There are, indeed, attempts to inject both romance and comedy into "Conspiracy Theory", although both fall rather flat. The main problem with the film, apart from the fact that the plot is difficult to follow, is that, despite Gibson's best efforts to make him likable, Jerry remains, at bottom, a nutcase, and nutcases do not generally make credible screen heroes, and certainly not credible romantic heroes. Alice, of course, ends up falling for Jerry, even though in real life, any sane woman would run a mile from him, probably while telling herself that not every lunatic is actually in an asylum. It is hard to regard as love's young dream the sort of man who is so paranoid that he padlocks the coffee and sugar canisters in his kitchen. There are two ways in which one could make a film about a character like Jerry Fletcher, either as a character-driven psychological drama or as a black comedy. In either case the character would probably have to be dealt with much less indulgently than he is here. A paranoid conspiracy theorist as romantic hero just doesn't work, even if there turns out to be a rational explanation for his paranoia. The film achieves little, other than the presumably unintended achievement of making extremist views seem slightly more acceptable. Both Gibson and Roberts have much more distinguished entries on their CVs than this one. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Which Theory Is True?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson is most sympathetic as conspiracy theorist Jerry Fletcher, who lives in a ultra-secure, booby trapped apartment where he publishes his newsletter critical of the government. Ironically, he loves government employee Alice Sutton(played by Julia Roberts) from afar. One day, their worlds collide when one of Jerry's theories seems to be true, as he becomes the target of assassination, and Alice helps him to go on the run from the unknown government forces. He thinks that Dr. Jonas(Patrick Stewart) will help him, but it turns out that was one conspiracy he didn't anticipate... Entertaining thriller is well directed by Richard Donner, with a good pace and reasonably believable story, though it does go on a bit too long, and becomes a bit too convoluted, but otherwise this film works well, and some of Jerry's theories may not be so nutty anymore...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    patsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always been a fan of Conspiracy Theories so I figured I would check this one out,, it's above average,, based on the acting between our stars, Mel Gibson, Julia Robert,, and Patrick Stewart,, I was hoping for an actual conspiracy,, instead we get the old,, CIA, mind control stuff, rogue killer programmed to assassinate someone,, which isn't that bad, but some of the theories in the movie like the Oliver Stone --George Bush one,, I was like wow OK.. Mel's character, Jerry Fletcher is majorly paranoid, insanely crazy as one of his theories actually turns out to be true, problem for him is as he has so many now he has to figure out which theory he is right about,, he get's help from a young lady he saved from a mugging 6 months ago,, so he is like her guardian angel so to speak,, very interesting movie,, once you get by all the covert military mind control stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiring for A Very Good Film-Conspiracy Theory ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As much as I dislike Mel Gibson for the repeated bigoted remarks that he has made off the screen, I have to admit that he gave a riveting performance in this film. He portrays a cab driver who is constantly thinking up various conspiracies, and then becomes pursued when one of his conspiracy theories proves to be right. As an attorney,Julia Roberts, who lost her father in a mysterious shooting, becomes involved with Gibson. The film is a good one due to the plot twists and turns. You really don't know who is good and evil in it. Patrick Stewart portrays a man with many hats. You just don't know where he is at until the very end. Roberts comes slowly to believe in what Gibson is saying until it appears that he had killed her father. The ending may be disappointing to many, but was probably necessary due to the clandestine and safety measures for the Roberts part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mel Gibson wins over Julia Roberts to his conspiracy theory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Conspiracy Theory" is Hollywood at its best, combining capable stars, thrills, romance, with a well-written and well-plotted script under sure direction. I enjoyed it thoroughly. Mel Gibson does a terrific job as the taxi driver who has many conspiracy theories and then turns out not to be a kook but to have the best of reasons for getting pulled in to a real conspiracy. Julia Roberts shows her acting chops by effortlessly playing a government security employee who finds herself completely enmeshed with Gibson, not least because of his motivation to protect her and how that came about. Solid entertainment that does not require much effort to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Always in my best 10 !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mad Watcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was incredibly smart, well written, funny and romantic. One of Mel Gibson's best act. Julia Roberts was the best choice for Alice Sutton (I cant imagine somebody else). She was really beautiful in this movie. You cant take your eyes from the movie especially when the ending comes. Well written small details you need the catch. Movie was interestingly underrated, is it a conspiracy? Sometimes I think about that. I do not want to give any spoiler, but this is a must watch movie, you will never regret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    buiger
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with Ebert on this one. The script does seem confused, as if it has been re-written. The beginning of the film has nothing to do with what happens after wards. The end result is a mix up where none of the ends meet, making the screenplay totally ridiculous and thoroughly unbelievable. Is Jerry really the insecure and paranoid "conspiracy freak" like in the beginning of the movie or a highly trained special agent/murderer of the CIA? He can't be both. This paradox is present throughout the film and I think it also confused Gibson because it seems he doesn't really know which way to take the character himself. All in all, nothing special, a less than average quality Hollywood production.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterthomson
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mel Gibson overacts his way through the whole pile of rubbish and Julia Roberts is clearly there for the pay cheque. The thinnest of stories with poor dialogue throughout. Gibsons pathetic constant mumbling is overbearing and annoying and Roberts part of the sycophantic token female is a crime against acting.Take away the background music and special effects and it is almost laughable. I cant remember seeing such an awful film. the attempts at romance are so far removed from reality it borders on fantasy.Of the many thousands of films I have seen throughout my life, this is by far the worst one ever.I cant believe Julia Roberts would be happy with her name on this one. For Mel Gibson, it highlights his obvious acting limitations and one dimensional ability in such a way that maybe a close friend should have had a quiet word with him.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Conspiracy And Paranoia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Conspiracy Theory is an action thriller film that features two of the Hollywood A-list stars namely: Mel Gibson and Julia Roberts.The original screenplay,written by Brian Helgeland,centers on an eccentric taxi driver who believes many world events are triggered by government conspiracies, and the U.S. Justice Department attorney who becomes involved in his life.It was directed by Richard Donner. Conspiracy Theory centers on the themes of conspiracy and paranoia.Jerry Fletcher is a New York City cab driver who seems to have absorbed every bit of crackpot information passed along as "suppressed news" that's surfaced on talk radio or the Internet in the past 20 years. Jerry's heard 'em all and believes most of them, and even publishes his own journal of forbidden information, with a subscription list that now totals five people. In short, Jerry seems like just another New York City lunatic, and while he spends a fair amount of his spare time following Alice Sutton, a government attorney. Alice regards him as harmless; he once intervened while she was being mugged, and he's been acting like her benign if whacked-out protector ever since. However, one day Jerry is kidnapped and worked over by CIA operatives; he is convinced that one of the theories he uncovered must be for real -- but he has no idea which one. He tries to get Alice to help him, and before long both are drawn into a dangerous web that leads to a startling revelation of just how Jerry got this way. The movie is definitely not short on entertainment.Mel Gibson gives a fine and comic performance as Jerry.He is able to carry the film and make it interesting from beginning to end.Julia Roberts is also worthy of mention and provides outstanding and brilliant acting as she shares great chemistry with Gibson.Unfortunately,the romantic aspect between the two characters looks implausible considering that Gibson's character seems lunatic and paranoid. Also,some parts of the story are far from realistic especially the traits that Jerry has considering that he is always ahead of the government,police,FBI and even the CIA.But nevertheless,one might say that it is just a movie and the story provides suspense and tension inspite of the wit and humor inserted in between scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What if all those crazy conspiracy theories end up being true.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this movie is just brilliant. It is exactly the type of movie that I just love. There so much happening in the background and you are never sure what really is happening. The theme of this movie is "the truth will set you free", but what really is the truth. The movie leads you to believe one thing and then confronts you with something that destroys everything the you had built up, only to knock this down as well. What really is true? You will never know. You follow the main character through out the movie  and this character really knows a lot. On the outside he appears to be a nut with all of these conspiracy theories but then a layer is pealed off to reveal a little more about this character. What does this character really know? Who is he  well the movie may tell you, or it may not. You know who the bad guy is, or is he really the bad guy. The only certainty is Julia Roberts' character. She seems to be legit, or is she. Yes I am being ambiguous for this is the whole aspect of this movie. Ambiguity reigns and as you dig deeper in to look for the truth, the more questions that are raised. As such this movie is brilliant. It is in the similar vein to the Usual Suspects. It creates a story only to tear it down and leaving you wondering what happened. It is the ultimate conspiracy theory. The conspiracies that Mel Gibson's character brings out seem to be ultimately wild  yet they do seem to make sense. Mel Gibson's character is brilliant. He is like a child with huge amounts of knowledge. At first is appears to be a simple cab driver with a tonne of wild ideas; and then the layers of his character begin to be peeled off. What does he really know? The character doesn't know the answer to this question. One thing that is very definite is that he really brings out patterns. He can see a pattern in almost everything and the patterns he pulls out really makes one think  are these really conspiracies. One brilliant aspect of the movie are the little tricks and gadgets that are used. They do not dominate the movie; but they are there to show us how intelligent this character really is. The Firewall and the Beer Bomb are two examples. The beer bomb is where a bottle is balanced on the door knob and when the knob is turn the bottle breaks. The firewall is a much more brilliant thing for it will utterly destroy the apartment without damaging anything else. If it is brilliant and clever tricks that you are looking for then this is a movie to see. Patrick Stewart plays the bad guy  or is he a bad guy. Stewart is a brilliant actor; unfortunately his seven year stint in Star Trek has dulled his edge. When I see Stewart on the screen I immediately think of Captain Picard. This, to me, can really destroy a really good actor. Mel Gibson is seen as Mel Gibson; Julia Roberts is seen as Julia Roberts; but one cannot help seeing Patrick Stewart as Captain Jean-luc Picard. There was one gripe I had with the movie, but I cannot tell you because if I did it would spoil it. It is one the really would have made it absolutely brilliant; but in a fallen world nothing is brilliant. Remember the words of the movie  "the truth will set you free."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Paranoiac as Romantic Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Conspiracy Theory" Mel Gibson plays Jerry Fletcher, a New York taxi driver. (The film was directed by Richard Donner, who also directed Gibson in "Maverick" and the "Lethal Weapon" series). Jerry is an obsessive conspiracy theorist who habitually who lectures his passengers on his various theories. He believes, for example, that the fathers of Nobel Prize winners are being kidnapped by the authorities and forced to become sperm donors. He believes that NASA is trying to kill the President using a secret weapon on the Space Shuttle that can trigger earthquakes. And he believes that the Jews are responsible for all the wars in the world. Or was it Mel Gibson himself who said that? Strange how life can imitate art and actors start behaving like the characters they once portrayed. The film is not, however, simply a psychological study of an eccentric oddball. It is, in fact, an action-thriller; one of Jerry's theories actually proves to be true; it involves a conspiracy by the CIA and other American government agencies to brainwash people in order to sue them as assassins. I won't try and set out the plot, which is extremely complex and at times confusing, in any detail, but it involves the efforts of Jerry and Alice Sutton, a young lawyer with the US Justice Department, to expose this conspiracy. Alice is trying to find out the truth about the murder of her father, whom she believes may have been killed by the conspirators. This is a fairly standard thriller plot; the genre frequently involves conspiracies by people in high places to commit some dark deed or other. Julia Roberts, who plays Alice here, starred in two other films of this type in the nineties, "The Pelican Brief" and "I Love Trouble", although this second example treated the theme in a more light-hearted way and also included romantic comedy elements. There are, indeed, attempts to inject both romance and comedy into "Conspiracy Theory", although both fall rather flat. The main problem with the film, apart from the fact that the plot is difficult to follow, is that, despite Gibson's best efforts to make him likable, Jerry remains, at bottom, a nutcase, and nutcases do not generally make credible screen heroes, and certainly not credible romantic heroes. Alice, of course, ends up falling for Jerry, even though in real life, any sane woman would run a mile from him, probably while telling herself that not every lunatic is actually in an asylum. It is hard to regard as love's young dream the sort of man who is so paranoid that he padlocks the coffee and sugar canisters in his kitchen. There are two ways in which one could make a film about a character like Jerry Fletcher, either as a character-driven psychological drama or as a black comedy. In either case the character would probably have to be dealt with much less indulgently than he is here. A paranoid conspiracy theorist as romantic hero just doesn't work, even if there turns out to be a rational explanation for his paranoia. The film achieves little, other than the presumably unintended achievement of making extremist views seem slightly more acceptable. Both Gibson and Roberts have much more distinguished entries on their CVs than this one. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
