<filme>
 <id>
  331
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119051
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  No Limite
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A billionaire and two other men are stranded, unequipped, by a plane crash in a dangerous wilderness. How many will survive to be rescued?
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A model has her rich, much older husband come with her to a photo shoot. But when their plane crashes in the middle of nowhere, a strong mind game erupts between the clever husband and the Jealous young photographer as they try to get back to civilization.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   photo shoot
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   photographer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   billionaire
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bear
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mind game
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Lee Tamahori
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   David Mamet
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Anthony Hopkins
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Alec Baldwin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Elle Macpherson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harrowing Survival Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anthony Hopkins plays billionaire Charles Morse, a bookish man who is married to a much younger woman(played by Elle McPherson) who is coveted by her photographer(Alec Baldwin) The two men, as well as an assistant(played by Harold Perrineau) are flown into a remote location in the Alaskan wilderness, when they are struck by a flock of birds, causing them to crash in the lake, killing the pilot, and placing the three survivors in a life and death struggle with not only the harsh elements, but a huge Kodiak bear that smells blood... Harrowing adventure drama from writer David Mamet is well directed by Lee Tamahori and acted by the leads, especially Anthony Hopkins, whose transformation from bookish introvert to determined survivalist is believable(they're not mutually exclusive anyway!) Relationship among the men is a bit muddled, especially after the climax, but solid thriller is also compelling and frightening. Not a film for people with a fear of bears...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Edge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scarecrow-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins) is a wealthy man ("with his own plane") who decides to join his supermodel wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson) and her photographic crew to a lodging in the snowy wilderness (of the breathtaking British Columbia mountains and surrounding areas). Charles, Mickey's photographer, Bob (Alec Baldwin), and Bob's assistant, Stephen (Harold Perrineau) go on (what was perceived to be) a small plane ride to a local native's cabin to see if he can transport some film for them but he's on a hunt for bear. Once in the air, birds fly into the plane's propeller, causing them to crash. The pilot killed, the remaining three have to hike it to a closer location of their cabin, but doing so won't be easy thanks to a maneating bear looking to feed its hunger for human flesh. A miscalculation involving "moving south" (Charles uses a paper clip and leaf on water to determine the direction of South following the wind, but a magnetic interference stirs them in a complete circle back to their starting point!), a deep cut on the leg while sharpening a spear (Stephen's "slip" costs him big-time), a bloody rag left on a tree branch (summoning the hungry bear), a nasty attack that shortens the numbers (Stephen never had a prayer), and surviving the elements with little supplies to speak of (matches and the clothes on them; the flares will be needed for later, but they are soon used, too) provide much high drama in this exciting survivalist adventure. Not only the bear's "toying with them" provides suspense, but the idea that Baldwin might be banging Charles' wife and potentially planning to kill him for both the missus and money also remains a point of emphasis throughout. Hopkins never fails to convince as this very intelligent "know-it-all" with almost all the answers when pressures and obstacles present themselves. Charles is always turned to by Stephen and Bob when a new problem rears its ugly head. But that damned bear (Bart the Bear is recognized as a star as the credits closedand should) just won't go away. Alec Baldwin has that knack for portraying likable assholes, and his Bob is no different here. He sometimes uses his sense of humor to blatantly knock Charles, but his respect for the man never wavers. Stephen's attack is brutal, and the bear's attempts towards Charles and Bob commands serious tension. The location of the film provides much atmosphere because of how detrimental it can be for the duo attempting to survive (the bear and the wilderness/peaks both offer their own challenges). Hopkins' subtly expressive face (particularly the mind's trying to solve problems like when Alec suffers a tough leg injury falling into a "dead fall" meant for bears, or his "makeshift" compass idea; later, that panic that soon fades to disappointment regarding Baldwin's condition is a masterclass of acting) speaks a great deal and it's his responsibility to communicate the situation his character faces. Baldwin needs us to like him so we are unsure of his intent towards Hopkins' life; the ending gives us a tragedy that seems regrettable because it didn't need to end that way. The simple use of a watch (and engravings on it) along with a list with specific handwriting are tools that reinforce the revelation regarding whether or not Charles was right or not regarding Bob and Mickey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men Lost...Find Their Way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kept alive by some witty Mamet-Speak and a stunning backdrop of sharp, beautiful Wilderness Cinematography along with believable Leads, this is quite an enjoyable "lost in the wilderness" Movie within a Modern mode of Class Warfare and Marital Infidelity. It is not an easy mix at times and as our duo duel with barbs, insights, and storytelling things can seem at odds with each other. Its like poker game or barroom banter set in the great outdoors. The ever encroachment of the Kodiak Bear could be read as a metaphor for the impending destruction of each Man's Id. Or maybe its just a way to add some lively Action to the Playwright's pontifications of Money, Lawyers, and Love. It is a quirky Film and the talent involved should be credited because they give this well worn Genre a new angle. In the end it is somewhat satisfying and there is enough here to keep both Audiences interested. Those with the flannel shirts and those with the stuffy shirts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Critic Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiemaexo
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins), a billionaire with photographic memory, and two other men, Robert "Bob" Green (Alec Baldwin), a photographer, and Stephen (Harold Perrineau), his assistant, arrive in a remote North America, along with Charles's much-younger wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson), a fashion model. The group is only there for a photo shoot and staying as guests at a lodge, they later are recruited to another area due to a sick model. After their plane crashes, the men attempt to hike to a more likely search area, only to find that a male Kodiak bear is stalking them. They elude it, but later the bear attacks their camp and kills Stephen. The angles of the movie were spectacular; it made you feel like you were out in the woods. Seeing the actors in this environment makes you want to put on a coat to watch the movie. A very strong performance by all the actors in a film that deals with using bare instincts on fighting wild animals, staying alive from the elements, and morality. I can understand why some of the more modern audience might find that to be a turn-off. The sets and locations alone are worth a rental. The photography is beautiful, the landscape comes alive, and sometimes it steals the picture away from the characters. Very strong performances by Anthony Hopkins, Bart the Bear, and Alec Baldwin, Not only were they great but they were troopers with the set. Anthony Hopkins got a severe case of pneumonia while filming out in the cold; I'm a huge fan so his performance was fantastic he can go from a city guy to survival and make it believable. His character was well portrayed and a flawless performance. Alec Baldwin also did a great job in this movie. (And I can't say that I was a big fan of Alec before this movie) I have only seen him in comedy, but I have a better opinion of him now. Elle McPherson has a small role which she played well and portrayed her character very well. A gripping storyline, fantastic scenery and a real sense of drama and survival, it delivers as an action/adventure film by giving some heart stopping sequences, and it never slows down. The Edge also delivers as a dramatic film, with an ending that is painfully sad, yet satisfying. They portray their characters with honesty, and with a realistic nature that only great actors can accomplish. As the plot twists and the pace picks up, you start to become so involved that you forget time is passing by. I strongly suggest this one to action lovers and to anyone who enjoys a good story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge When stranded in the woods, it's a good idea to throw used tampons into the shrubs to keep bears off your trail. Unfortunately, the marooned men in this thriller are fresh out of soiled feminine napkins. When Charles (Anthony Hopkins) crash lands in the wilderness along side Bob (Alec Baldwin), a man he suspects is having an affair with his wife (Elle MacPherson) and plotting his murder, he must resist the urge to beat him to the punch, because there are more pressing matters. Dwarfing the awkward company and harsh surroundings is a ravenous bear that's trailing them. Putting aside their personal matters, Charles and Bob combine their abilities to combat the Kodiak. Written by David Mamet, The Edge is a taunt tale of male bonding amongst bear attacks. The acting is proficient and the dialogue acute. However, aren't grizzlies more apt to attack burly men in tattered clothes? (Yellow Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The bear is smarter than two of the men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a fairly good action film with some excellent sequences in which a bear stalks and attacks 3 stranded men in the Alaskan wilds. I kept wondering "How did they get that shot?" There are some amazingly good effects. I did wonder whether or not the roar of a bear is like the sounds we were given here. It sounded a little much to me. The bear and Anthony Hopkins are the main stars of the show, and Alec Baldwin does a creditable job with a character that is written to be weak and not very smart. The adventure element is concocted. One can raise many questions about the sequence of events too. Making a big circle in the way they did was very implausible, since they scaled a mountain. In addition, this film follows the usual Hollywood rule that held in the old days and still holds, which is basically to kill off the black man. There must be dozens of similar adventure and war movies that follow this rule. In this case, the black man is an utter weak wimp who does nothing but complain. He is also very stupid. What a horribly written part! Baldwin's character is not far behind. Hopkins' character is at least sensible enough to have some idea of what to do in the wild, even if he ignores the fact that the sun rises in the east, but then it does get cloudy sometimes. With such weak characters, I kept thinking back to earlier adventure movies such as Five Came Back. Were men so wimpy in those old movies? Or is this yet another manifestation of the juvenile characters that seem more frequently to people today's movies? The script telegraphs the key plot points a little too well in the opening sequence. The music at times is too syrupy and grand when more danger and challenge should be in the air. The character arc of Hopkins is only subtly hinted at, because we don't know much about him at the start. I like his line at the end about all of us face serious challenges but we don't know when or what form they are going to take. But I dislike his final line shortly thereafter that the other men died saving his life. Why should he lie? He has confronted himself and nature in his essence. He has even realized that he has little to go back to. He has seen truths, but then he lies. The two men died because they made grievous mistakes in their choices. At best they died bravely or "like men". He might have said "They died like men". The strong point of the movie is not its philosophy. It's the conflict between men and a bear. The conflict between Baldwin and Hopkins over his wealth and his wife didn't really ring true as it was written, although Baldwin did, as I said, quite a good job with the part. Let me elaborate a bit on the above. First, too much is given away at the outset. Low-flying birds can bring down an airplane, and this happens subsequently. There is a bear trap, and, sure enough, it plays a part. Bears become man-killers, we are told, and sure enough, act 2 involves just such a critter. Hopkins is given a watch and a knife and, sure enough, they are important later. It's all too pat. It was evident far before Hopkins said that he would kill the bear that this would have to be done. The line went through my head before he spoke it. Meanwhile the Baldwin character was whining worse than the black man had done earlier, and that guy was so inept that he stabbed himself in the leg -- a deep gash mind you -- while trying to sharpen a piece of wood into a spear. Very smart going, mate. Well, this is really Mamet's fault. He could not write a plausible screenplay with the wilderness elements?? He had to concoct this? Now, was Hopkins so dense that he could not pick up, well before this cozy little trip, that his right hand man was deeply hostile toward him? And that he was going with his wife? This is a man who sees all and remembers all. He's a billionaire. He must have an organization that he created. His wife and Baldwin are far from discreet, but Hopkins is that blind? It's all done by writer Mamet so superficially and so lazily. When Baldwin gets around to trying to kill Hopkins, Hopkins does nothing to stop him from loading the rifle. Why? Meanwhile, Baldwin insists they go outside. Why? And once outside, he hesitates and then backs himself up. Why? He is incredibly weak, so weak that I wonder what Hopkins ever saw in him to have him around, and what his wife saw in him. And having saved the life of Hopkins earlier, you would think that maybe his psychology would change. He might even expect rewards, but no, his bitterness actually increases. Why? Mamet lost it in this one as compared with some of his earlier work. We are dealing here with noir-type betrayals, and they are not easy to handle. In films like Too Late for Tears, Out of the Past, Ace in the Hole, and many others, it takes careful development of the characterizations to "sell" them, i.e., make them believable. Mamet has not done this in The Edge. He has not used the interactions generated by the action scenes to do it either -- the direction of the movie didn't bring it out. So that this aspect of the movie, which is a major part of it, is a failure. The viewer is left grasping for understanding and meaning, rather than feeling these people are real and the events real and the meaning central to human experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat and Contrived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rich man and a fashion photographer fight for survival in the jungles after a plane crash. The story is implausible and the situations are contrived, but the biggest deficiency is the under-developed characters. Hopkins plays what looks like the most miserable billionaire in the world, a lonely and insecure fellow who thinks everybody is out to get his money. In the wilds, he turns out to be a super boy scout, but the character is so aloof that it's hard to feel anything for him. Baldwin is supposed to be larger-than-life, as evidenced by his hearty laughs in response to lame jokes, but his character is also flat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty mainstream stuff with unmet intentions of deep psychological conflict
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge (1997) This is a fun wilderness adventure movie with some terrific acting by both Alec Baldwin (as a spoiled bad boy) and Anthony Hopkins (as a very smart millionaire). They battle of wits, and the fighting of the elements, is fodder for screenwriter David Mamet, who has produced more interesting dialog than this, for sure. The third star is the Kodiak bear, who gets a huge credit line at the end, and who unites, at least sometimes, the two men in the cold isolation of Alaska. But let's face it, as much fun as this is, this is thin going. It even looks a bit like a slightly adult version of a Disney adventure film, with people bonding and conflicting as needed. In fact, if you start comparing this movie to others like it (there are a few), you might even consider the television series "Lost," which is at least more imaginative and full-blooded in its writing. Or just survival in the mountains you might check out "Touching the Void." I just saw the old Spencer Tracy movie "Mountain" this week, and it is a weird precursor to this one (minus the bear). That is, two people facing the elements have very different ideas of morality and of trust. Like that movie, this newer one doesn't explore the conflict of personae, or ethics, very far, giving only what are the obvious differences. That's not enough for a feature length affair. Which brings us back to Baldwin and Hopkins. They are, actually, enough to hold you in for the duration. You really do hope they survive, and if you wince at some of the dialog and at the appearance of bear traps at all the wrong moments, you can get into the drama of it pretty well. And into the scenery. Amazing stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clearly Mamet was never a Boy Scout
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty hard to take this film seriously, much of the time at least. The basic structure of the film is fine, and Hopkins and Baldwin both deliver fine performances. But the survival-related antics these men pull are straight out of a comic book, I think. (Trapping a chipmunk in a cage fashioned out of twigs??? Hilarious!!!) Although Bart the Bear also deserves his top billing, just about every scene he's in is utterly ludicrous. I guess that's not Bart's fault. Maybe his manager should've held out for a better script though. Watch it for the scenery, the machinations of the human characters and the dialog (at both of which Mamet excels), and for Hopkins' acting. And don't take any of the bear- or survival-related stuff seriously. This is not a movie to call to memory when you find yourself lost in the woods....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man vs Man vs Wild
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rasamanjari
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is both a psychological thriller and an authentic, wilderness survival movie. It pits man against the magnificent but harsh Alaskan wilderness, and, at the same time, it also pits man against man in a powerful, primitive struggle over a beautiful woman..a very beautiful woman--Elle Macpherson. Alex Baldwim is excellent as the confident, aggressive, young usurper, always looking for ways to bring down his competition, and Anthony Hopkins is exceptional as the wealthy, intelligent, aristocratic gentleman husband who gracefully endures his attacks while gradually realizing the painful truth. The thing i liked the most about this film is that they both have to depend on each other for survival in the Alaskan wild, while simultaneously dealing with their powerful emotions about each other and the relationship situation. The combination makes this film affect the sensibilities like no other i have seen. Well worth watching. The review alongside the movie poster did not begin to cover this film as it deserves to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harrowing Survival Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anthony Hopkins plays billionaire Charles Morse, a bookish man who is married to a much younger woman(played by Elle McPherson) who is coveted by her photographer(Alec Baldwin) The two men, as well as an assistant(played by Harold Perrineau) are flown into a remote location in the Alaskan wilderness, when they are struck by a flock of birds, causing them to crash in the lake, killing the pilot, and placing the three survivors in a life and death struggle with not only the harsh elements, but a huge Kodiak bear that smells blood... Harrowing adventure drama from writer David Mamet is well directed by Lee Tamahori and acted by the leads, especially Anthony Hopkins, whose transformation from bookish introvert to determined survivalist is believable(they're not mutually exclusive anyway!) Relationship among the men is a bit muddled, especially after the climax, but solid thriller is also compelling and frightening. Not a film for people with a fear of bears...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Edge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scarecrow-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins) is a wealthy man ("with his own plane") who decides to join his supermodel wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson) and her photographic crew to a lodging in the snowy wilderness (of the breathtaking British Columbia mountains and surrounding areas). Charles, Mickey's photographer, Bob (Alec Baldwin), and Bob's assistant, Stephen (Harold Perrineau) go on (what was perceived to be) a small plane ride to a local native's cabin to see if he can transport some film for them but he's on a hunt for bear. Once in the air, birds fly into the plane's propeller, causing them to crash. The pilot killed, the remaining three have to hike it to a closer location of their cabin, but doing so won't be easy thanks to a maneating bear looking to feed its hunger for human flesh. A miscalculation involving "moving south" (Charles uses a paper clip and leaf on water to determine the direction of South following the wind, but a magnetic interference stirs them in a complete circle back to their starting point!), a deep cut on the leg while sharpening a spear (Stephen's "slip" costs him big-time), a bloody rag left on a tree branch (summoning the hungry bear), a nasty attack that shortens the numbers (Stephen never had a prayer), and surviving the elements with little supplies to speak of (matches and the clothes on them; the flares will be needed for later, but they are soon used, too) provide much high drama in this exciting survivalist adventure. Not only the bear's "toying with them" provides suspense, but the idea that Baldwin might be banging Charles' wife and potentially planning to kill him for both the missus and money also remains a point of emphasis throughout. Hopkins never fails to convince as this very intelligent "know-it-all" with almost all the answers when pressures and obstacles present themselves. Charles is always turned to by Stephen and Bob when a new problem rears its ugly head. But that damned bear (Bart the Bear is recognized as a star as the credits closedand should) just won't go away. Alec Baldwin has that knack for portraying likable assholes, and his Bob is no different here. He sometimes uses his sense of humor to blatantly knock Charles, but his respect for the man never wavers. Stephen's attack is brutal, and the bear's attempts towards Charles and Bob commands serious tension. The location of the film provides much atmosphere because of how detrimental it can be for the duo attempting to survive (the bear and the wilderness/peaks both offer their own challenges). Hopkins' subtly expressive face (particularly the mind's trying to solve problems like when Alec suffers a tough leg injury falling into a "dead fall" meant for bears, or his "makeshift" compass idea; later, that panic that soon fades to disappointment regarding Baldwin's condition is a masterclass of acting) speaks a great deal and it's his responsibility to communicate the situation his character faces. Baldwin needs us to like him so we are unsure of his intent towards Hopkins' life; the ending gives us a tragedy that seems regrettable because it didn't need to end that way. The simple use of a watch (and engravings on it) along with a list with specific handwriting are tools that reinforce the revelation regarding whether or not Charles was right or not regarding Bob and Mickey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men Lost...Find Their Way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kept alive by some witty Mamet-Speak and a stunning backdrop of sharp, beautiful Wilderness Cinematography along with believable Leads, this is quite an enjoyable "lost in the wilderness" Movie within a Modern mode of Class Warfare and Marital Infidelity. It is not an easy mix at times and as our duo duel with barbs, insights, and storytelling things can seem at odds with each other. Its like poker game or barroom banter set in the great outdoors. The ever encroachment of the Kodiak Bear could be read as a metaphor for the impending destruction of each Man's Id. Or maybe its just a way to add some lively Action to the Playwright's pontifications of Money, Lawyers, and Love. It is a quirky Film and the talent involved should be credited because they give this well worn Genre a new angle. In the end it is somewhat satisfying and there is enough here to keep both Audiences interested. Those with the flannel shirts and those with the stuffy shirts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Critic Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiemaexo
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins), a billionaire with photographic memory, and two other men, Robert "Bob" Green (Alec Baldwin), a photographer, and Stephen (Harold Perrineau), his assistant, arrive in a remote North America, along with Charles's much-younger wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson), a fashion model. The group is only there for a photo shoot and staying as guests at a lodge, they later are recruited to another area due to a sick model. After their plane crashes, the men attempt to hike to a more likely search area, only to find that a male Kodiak bear is stalking them. They elude it, but later the bear attacks their camp and kills Stephen. The angles of the movie were spectacular; it made you feel like you were out in the woods. Seeing the actors in this environment makes you want to put on a coat to watch the movie. A very strong performance by all the actors in a film that deals with using bare instincts on fighting wild animals, staying alive from the elements, and morality. I can understand why some of the more modern audience might find that to be a turn-off. The sets and locations alone are worth a rental. The photography is beautiful, the landscape comes alive, and sometimes it steals the picture away from the characters. Very strong performances by Anthony Hopkins, Bart the Bear, and Alec Baldwin, Not only were they great but they were troopers with the set. Anthony Hopkins got a severe case of pneumonia while filming out in the cold; I'm a huge fan so his performance was fantastic he can go from a city guy to survival and make it believable. His character was well portrayed and a flawless performance. Alec Baldwin also did a great job in this movie. (And I can't say that I was a big fan of Alec before this movie) I have only seen him in comedy, but I have a better opinion of him now. Elle McPherson has a small role which she played well and portrayed her character very well. A gripping storyline, fantastic scenery and a real sense of drama and survival, it delivers as an action/adventure film by giving some heart stopping sequences, and it never slows down. The Edge also delivers as a dramatic film, with an ending that is painfully sad, yet satisfying. They portray their characters with honesty, and with a realistic nature that only great actors can accomplish. As the plot twists and the pace picks up, you start to become so involved that you forget time is passing by. I strongly suggest this one to action lovers and to anyone who enjoys a good story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge When stranded in the woods, it's a good idea to throw used tampons into the shrubs to keep bears off your trail. Unfortunately, the marooned men in this thriller are fresh out of soiled feminine napkins. When Charles (Anthony Hopkins) crash lands in the wilderness along side Bob (Alec Baldwin), a man he suspects is having an affair with his wife (Elle MacPherson) and plotting his murder, he must resist the urge to beat him to the punch, because there are more pressing matters. Dwarfing the awkward company and harsh surroundings is a ravenous bear that's trailing them. Putting aside their personal matters, Charles and Bob combine their abilities to combat the Kodiak. Written by David Mamet, The Edge is a taunt tale of male bonding amongst bear attacks. The acting is proficient and the dialogue acute. However, aren't grizzlies more apt to attack burly men in tattered clothes? (Yellow Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The bear is smarter than two of the men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a fairly good action film with some excellent sequences in which a bear stalks and attacks 3 stranded men in the Alaskan wilds. I kept wondering "How did they get that shot?" There are some amazingly good effects. I did wonder whether or not the roar of a bear is like the sounds we were given here. It sounded a little much to me. The bear and Anthony Hopkins are the main stars of the show, and Alec Baldwin does a creditable job with a character that is written to be weak and not very smart. The adventure element is concocted. One can raise many questions about the sequence of events too. Making a big circle in the way they did was very implausible, since they scaled a mountain. In addition, this film follows the usual Hollywood rule that held in the old days and still holds, which is basically to kill off the black man. There must be dozens of similar adventure and war movies that follow this rule. In this case, the black man is an utter weak wimp who does nothing but complain. He is also very stupid. What a horribly written part! Baldwin's character is not far behind. Hopkins' character is at least sensible enough to have some idea of what to do in the wild, even if he ignores the fact that the sun rises in the east, but then it does get cloudy sometimes. With such weak characters, I kept thinking back to earlier adventure movies such as Five Came Back. Were men so wimpy in those old movies? Or is this yet another manifestation of the juvenile characters that seem more frequently to people today's movies? The script telegraphs the key plot points a little too well in the opening sequence. The music at times is too syrupy and grand when more danger and challenge should be in the air. The character arc of Hopkins is only subtly hinted at, because we don't know much about him at the start. I like his line at the end about all of us face serious challenges but we don't know when or what form they are going to take. But I dislike his final line shortly thereafter that the other men died saving his life. Why should he lie? He has confronted himself and nature in his essence. He has even realized that he has little to go back to. He has seen truths, but then he lies. The two men died because they made grievous mistakes in their choices. At best they died bravely or "like men". He might have said "They died like men". The strong point of the movie is not its philosophy. It's the conflict between men and a bear. The conflict between Baldwin and Hopkins over his wealth and his wife didn't really ring true as it was written, although Baldwin did, as I said, quite a good job with the part. Let me elaborate a bit on the above. First, too much is given away at the outset. Low-flying birds can bring down an airplane, and this happens subsequently. There is a bear trap, and, sure enough, it plays a part. Bears become man-killers, we are told, and sure enough, act 2 involves just such a critter. Hopkins is given a watch and a knife and, sure enough, they are important later. It's all too pat. It was evident far before Hopkins said that he would kill the bear that this would have to be done. The line went through my head before he spoke it. Meanwhile the Baldwin character was whining worse than the black man had done earlier, and that guy was so inept that he stabbed himself in the leg -- a deep gash mind you -- while trying to sharpen a piece of wood into a spear. Very smart going, mate. Well, this is really Mamet's fault. He could not write a plausible screenplay with the wilderness elements?? He had to concoct this? Now, was Hopkins so dense that he could not pick up, well before this cozy little trip, that his right hand man was deeply hostile toward him? And that he was going with his wife? This is a man who sees all and remembers all. He's a billionaire. He must have an organization that he created. His wife and Baldwin are far from discreet, but Hopkins is that blind? It's all done by writer Mamet so superficially and so lazily. When Baldwin gets around to trying to kill Hopkins, Hopkins does nothing to stop him from loading the rifle. Why? Meanwhile, Baldwin insists they go outside. Why? And once outside, he hesitates and then backs himself up. Why? He is incredibly weak, so weak that I wonder what Hopkins ever saw in him to have him around, and what his wife saw in him. And having saved the life of Hopkins earlier, you would think that maybe his psychology would change. He might even expect rewards, but no, his bitterness actually increases. Why? Mamet lost it in this one as compared with some of his earlier work. We are dealing here with noir-type betrayals, and they are not easy to handle. In films like Too Late for Tears, Out of the Past, Ace in the Hole, and many others, it takes careful development of the characterizations to "sell" them, i.e., make them believable. Mamet has not done this in The Edge. He has not used the interactions generated by the action scenes to do it either -- the direction of the movie didn't bring it out. So that this aspect of the movie, which is a major part of it, is a failure. The viewer is left grasping for understanding and meaning, rather than feeling these people are real and the events real and the meaning central to human experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat and Contrived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rich man and a fashion photographer fight for survival in the jungles after a plane crash. The story is implausible and the situations are contrived, but the biggest deficiency is the under-developed characters. Hopkins plays what looks like the most miserable billionaire in the world, a lonely and insecure fellow who thinks everybody is out to get his money. In the wilds, he turns out to be a super boy scout, but the character is so aloof that it's hard to feel anything for him. Baldwin is supposed to be larger-than-life, as evidenced by his hearty laughs in response to lame jokes, but his character is also flat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty mainstream stuff with unmet intentions of deep psychological conflict
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge (1997) This is a fun wilderness adventure movie with some terrific acting by both Alec Baldwin (as a spoiled bad boy) and Anthony Hopkins (as a very smart millionaire). They battle of wits, and the fighting of the elements, is fodder for screenwriter David Mamet, who has produced more interesting dialog than this, for sure. The third star is the Kodiak bear, who gets a huge credit line at the end, and who unites, at least sometimes, the two men in the cold isolation of Alaska. But let's face it, as much fun as this is, this is thin going. It even looks a bit like a slightly adult version of a Disney adventure film, with people bonding and conflicting as needed. In fact, if you start comparing this movie to others like it (there are a few), you might even consider the television series "Lost," which is at least more imaginative and full-blooded in its writing. Or just survival in the mountains you might check out "Touching the Void." I just saw the old Spencer Tracy movie "Mountain" this week, and it is a weird precursor to this one (minus the bear). That is, two people facing the elements have very different ideas of morality and of trust. Like that movie, this newer one doesn't explore the conflict of personae, or ethics, very far, giving only what are the obvious differences. That's not enough for a feature length affair. Which brings us back to Baldwin and Hopkins. They are, actually, enough to hold you in for the duration. You really do hope they survive, and if you wince at some of the dialog and at the appearance of bear traps at all the wrong moments, you can get into the drama of it pretty well. And into the scenery. Amazing stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clearly Mamet was never a Boy Scout
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty hard to take this film seriously, much of the time at least. The basic structure of the film is fine, and Hopkins and Baldwin both deliver fine performances. But the survival-related antics these men pull are straight out of a comic book, I think. (Trapping a chipmunk in a cage fashioned out of twigs??? Hilarious!!!) Although Bart the Bear also deserves his top billing, just about every scene he's in is utterly ludicrous. I guess that's not Bart's fault. Maybe his manager should've held out for a better script though. Watch it for the scenery, the machinations of the human characters and the dialog (at both of which Mamet excels), and for Hopkins' acting. And don't take any of the bear- or survival-related stuff seriously. This is not a movie to call to memory when you find yourself lost in the woods....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man vs Man vs Wild
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rasamanjari
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is both a psychological thriller and an authentic, wilderness survival movie. It pits man against the magnificent but harsh Alaskan wilderness, and, at the same time, it also pits man against man in a powerful, primitive struggle over a beautiful woman..a very beautiful woman--Elle Macpherson. Alex Baldwim is excellent as the confident, aggressive, young usurper, always looking for ways to bring down his competition, and Anthony Hopkins is exceptional as the wealthy, intelligent, aristocratic gentleman husband who gracefully endures his attacks while gradually realizing the painful truth. The thing i liked the most about this film is that they both have to depend on each other for survival in the Alaskan wild, while simultaneously dealing with their powerful emotions about each other and the relationship situation. The combination makes this film affect the sensibilities like no other i have seen. Well worth watching. The review alongside the movie poster did not begin to cover this film as it deserves to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harrowing Survival Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anthony Hopkins plays billionaire Charles Morse, a bookish man who is married to a much younger woman(played by Elle McPherson) who is coveted by her photographer(Alec Baldwin) The two men, as well as an assistant(played by Harold Perrineau) are flown into a remote location in the Alaskan wilderness, when they are struck by a flock of birds, causing them to crash in the lake, killing the pilot, and placing the three survivors in a life and death struggle with not only the harsh elements, but a huge Kodiak bear that smells blood... Harrowing adventure drama from writer David Mamet is well directed by Lee Tamahori and acted by the leads, especially Anthony Hopkins, whose transformation from bookish introvert to determined survivalist is believable(they're not mutually exclusive anyway!) Relationship among the men is a bit muddled, especially after the climax, but solid thriller is also compelling and frightening. Not a film for people with a fear of bears...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Edge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scarecrow-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins) is a wealthy man ("with his own plane") who decides to join his supermodel wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson) and her photographic crew to a lodging in the snowy wilderness (of the breathtaking British Columbia mountains and surrounding areas). Charles, Mickey's photographer, Bob (Alec Baldwin), and Bob's assistant, Stephen (Harold Perrineau) go on (what was perceived to be) a small plane ride to a local native's cabin to see if he can transport some film for them but he's on a hunt for bear. Once in the air, birds fly into the plane's propeller, causing them to crash. The pilot killed, the remaining three have to hike it to a closer location of their cabin, but doing so won't be easy thanks to a maneating bear looking to feed its hunger for human flesh. A miscalculation involving "moving south" (Charles uses a paper clip and leaf on water to determine the direction of South following the wind, but a magnetic interference stirs them in a complete circle back to their starting point!), a deep cut on the leg while sharpening a spear (Stephen's "slip" costs him big-time), a bloody rag left on a tree branch (summoning the hungry bear), a nasty attack that shortens the numbers (Stephen never had a prayer), and surviving the elements with little supplies to speak of (matches and the clothes on them; the flares will be needed for later, but they are soon used, too) provide much high drama in this exciting survivalist adventure. Not only the bear's "toying with them" provides suspense, but the idea that Baldwin might be banging Charles' wife and potentially planning to kill him for both the missus and money also remains a point of emphasis throughout. Hopkins never fails to convince as this very intelligent "know-it-all" with almost all the answers when pressures and obstacles present themselves. Charles is always turned to by Stephen and Bob when a new problem rears its ugly head. But that damned bear (Bart the Bear is recognized as a star as the credits closedand should) just won't go away. Alec Baldwin has that knack for portraying likable assholes, and his Bob is no different here. He sometimes uses his sense of humor to blatantly knock Charles, but his respect for the man never wavers. Stephen's attack is brutal, and the bear's attempts towards Charles and Bob commands serious tension. The location of the film provides much atmosphere because of how detrimental it can be for the duo attempting to survive (the bear and the wilderness/peaks both offer their own challenges). Hopkins' subtly expressive face (particularly the mind's trying to solve problems like when Alec suffers a tough leg injury falling into a "dead fall" meant for bears, or his "makeshift" compass idea; later, that panic that soon fades to disappointment regarding Baldwin's condition is a masterclass of acting) speaks a great deal and it's his responsibility to communicate the situation his character faces. Baldwin needs us to like him so we are unsure of his intent towards Hopkins' life; the ending gives us a tragedy that seems regrettable because it didn't need to end that way. The simple use of a watch (and engravings on it) along with a list with specific handwriting are tools that reinforce the revelation regarding whether or not Charles was right or not regarding Bob and Mickey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men Lost...Find Their Way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kept alive by some witty Mamet-Speak and a stunning backdrop of sharp, beautiful Wilderness Cinematography along with believable Leads, this is quite an enjoyable "lost in the wilderness" Movie within a Modern mode of Class Warfare and Marital Infidelity. It is not an easy mix at times and as our duo duel with barbs, insights, and storytelling things can seem at odds with each other. Its like poker game or barroom banter set in the great outdoors. The ever encroachment of the Kodiak Bear could be read as a metaphor for the impending destruction of each Man's Id. Or maybe its just a way to add some lively Action to the Playwright's pontifications of Money, Lawyers, and Love. It is a quirky Film and the talent involved should be credited because they give this well worn Genre a new angle. In the end it is somewhat satisfying and there is enough here to keep both Audiences interested. Those with the flannel shirts and those with the stuffy shirts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Critic Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiemaexo
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins), a billionaire with photographic memory, and two other men, Robert "Bob" Green (Alec Baldwin), a photographer, and Stephen (Harold Perrineau), his assistant, arrive in a remote North America, along with Charles's much-younger wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson), a fashion model. The group is only there for a photo shoot and staying as guests at a lodge, they later are recruited to another area due to a sick model. After their plane crashes, the men attempt to hike to a more likely search area, only to find that a male Kodiak bear is stalking them. They elude it, but later the bear attacks their camp and kills Stephen. The angles of the movie were spectacular; it made you feel like you were out in the woods. Seeing the actors in this environment makes you want to put on a coat to watch the movie. A very strong performance by all the actors in a film that deals with using bare instincts on fighting wild animals, staying alive from the elements, and morality. I can understand why some of the more modern audience might find that to be a turn-off. The sets and locations alone are worth a rental. The photography is beautiful, the landscape comes alive, and sometimes it steals the picture away from the characters. Very strong performances by Anthony Hopkins, Bart the Bear, and Alec Baldwin, Not only were they great but they were troopers with the set. Anthony Hopkins got a severe case of pneumonia while filming out in the cold; I'm a huge fan so his performance was fantastic he can go from a city guy to survival and make it believable. His character was well portrayed and a flawless performance. Alec Baldwin also did a great job in this movie. (And I can't say that I was a big fan of Alec before this movie) I have only seen him in comedy, but I have a better opinion of him now. Elle McPherson has a small role which she played well and portrayed her character very well. A gripping storyline, fantastic scenery and a real sense of drama and survival, it delivers as an action/adventure film by giving some heart stopping sequences, and it never slows down. The Edge also delivers as a dramatic film, with an ending that is painfully sad, yet satisfying. They portray their characters with honesty, and with a realistic nature that only great actors can accomplish. As the plot twists and the pace picks up, you start to become so involved that you forget time is passing by. I strongly suggest this one to action lovers and to anyone who enjoys a good story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge When stranded in the woods, it's a good idea to throw used tampons into the shrubs to keep bears off your trail. Unfortunately, the marooned men in this thriller are fresh out of soiled feminine napkins. When Charles (Anthony Hopkins) crash lands in the wilderness along side Bob (Alec Baldwin), a man he suspects is having an affair with his wife (Elle MacPherson) and plotting his murder, he must resist the urge to beat him to the punch, because there are more pressing matters. Dwarfing the awkward company and harsh surroundings is a ravenous bear that's trailing them. Putting aside their personal matters, Charles and Bob combine their abilities to combat the Kodiak. Written by David Mamet, The Edge is a taunt tale of male bonding amongst bear attacks. The acting is proficient and the dialogue acute. However, aren't grizzlies more apt to attack burly men in tattered clothes? (Yellow Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The bear is smarter than two of the men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a fairly good action film with some excellent sequences in which a bear stalks and attacks 3 stranded men in the Alaskan wilds. I kept wondering "How did they get that shot?" There are some amazingly good effects. I did wonder whether or not the roar of a bear is like the sounds we were given here. It sounded a little much to me. The bear and Anthony Hopkins are the main stars of the show, and Alec Baldwin does a creditable job with a character that is written to be weak and not very smart. The adventure element is concocted. One can raise many questions about the sequence of events too. Making a big circle in the way they did was very implausible, since they scaled a mountain. In addition, this film follows the usual Hollywood rule that held in the old days and still holds, which is basically to kill off the black man. There must be dozens of similar adventure and war movies that follow this rule. In this case, the black man is an utter weak wimp who does nothing but complain. He is also very stupid. What a horribly written part! Baldwin's character is not far behind. Hopkins' character is at least sensible enough to have some idea of what to do in the wild, even if he ignores the fact that the sun rises in the east, but then it does get cloudy sometimes. With such weak characters, I kept thinking back to earlier adventure movies such as Five Came Back. Were men so wimpy in those old movies? Or is this yet another manifestation of the juvenile characters that seem more frequently to people today's movies? The script telegraphs the key plot points a little too well in the opening sequence. The music at times is too syrupy and grand when more danger and challenge should be in the air. The character arc of Hopkins is only subtly hinted at, because we don't know much about him at the start. I like his line at the end about all of us face serious challenges but we don't know when or what form they are going to take. But I dislike his final line shortly thereafter that the other men died saving his life. Why should he lie? He has confronted himself and nature in his essence. He has even realized that he has little to go back to. He has seen truths, but then he lies. The two men died because they made grievous mistakes in their choices. At best they died bravely or "like men". He might have said "They died like men". The strong point of the movie is not its philosophy. It's the conflict between men and a bear. The conflict between Baldwin and Hopkins over his wealth and his wife didn't really ring true as it was written, although Baldwin did, as I said, quite a good job with the part. Let me elaborate a bit on the above. First, too much is given away at the outset. Low-flying birds can bring down an airplane, and this happens subsequently. There is a bear trap, and, sure enough, it plays a part. Bears become man-killers, we are told, and sure enough, act 2 involves just such a critter. Hopkins is given a watch and a knife and, sure enough, they are important later. It's all too pat. It was evident far before Hopkins said that he would kill the bear that this would have to be done. The line went through my head before he spoke it. Meanwhile the Baldwin character was whining worse than the black man had done earlier, and that guy was so inept that he stabbed himself in the leg -- a deep gash mind you -- while trying to sharpen a piece of wood into a spear. Very smart going, mate. Well, this is really Mamet's fault. He could not write a plausible screenplay with the wilderness elements?? He had to concoct this? Now, was Hopkins so dense that he could not pick up, well before this cozy little trip, that his right hand man was deeply hostile toward him? And that he was going with his wife? This is a man who sees all and remembers all. He's a billionaire. He must have an organization that he created. His wife and Baldwin are far from discreet, but Hopkins is that blind? It's all done by writer Mamet so superficially and so lazily. When Baldwin gets around to trying to kill Hopkins, Hopkins does nothing to stop him from loading the rifle. Why? Meanwhile, Baldwin insists they go outside. Why? And once outside, he hesitates and then backs himself up. Why? He is incredibly weak, so weak that I wonder what Hopkins ever saw in him to have him around, and what his wife saw in him. And having saved the life of Hopkins earlier, you would think that maybe his psychology would change. He might even expect rewards, but no, his bitterness actually increases. Why? Mamet lost it in this one as compared with some of his earlier work. We are dealing here with noir-type betrayals, and they are not easy to handle. In films like Too Late for Tears, Out of the Past, Ace in the Hole, and many others, it takes careful development of the characterizations to "sell" them, i.e., make them believable. Mamet has not done this in The Edge. He has not used the interactions generated by the action scenes to do it either -- the direction of the movie didn't bring it out. So that this aspect of the movie, which is a major part of it, is a failure. The viewer is left grasping for understanding and meaning, rather than feeling these people are real and the events real and the meaning central to human experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat and Contrived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rich man and a fashion photographer fight for survival in the jungles after a plane crash. The story is implausible and the situations are contrived, but the biggest deficiency is the under-developed characters. Hopkins plays what looks like the most miserable billionaire in the world, a lonely and insecure fellow who thinks everybody is out to get his money. In the wilds, he turns out to be a super boy scout, but the character is so aloof that it's hard to feel anything for him. Baldwin is supposed to be larger-than-life, as evidenced by his hearty laughs in response to lame jokes, but his character is also flat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty mainstream stuff with unmet intentions of deep psychological conflict
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge (1997) This is a fun wilderness adventure movie with some terrific acting by both Alec Baldwin (as a spoiled bad boy) and Anthony Hopkins (as a very smart millionaire). They battle of wits, and the fighting of the elements, is fodder for screenwriter David Mamet, who has produced more interesting dialog than this, for sure. The third star is the Kodiak bear, who gets a huge credit line at the end, and who unites, at least sometimes, the two men in the cold isolation of Alaska. But let's face it, as much fun as this is, this is thin going. It even looks a bit like a slightly adult version of a Disney adventure film, with people bonding and conflicting as needed. In fact, if you start comparing this movie to others like it (there are a few), you might even consider the television series "Lost," which is at least more imaginative and full-blooded in its writing. Or just survival in the mountains you might check out "Touching the Void." I just saw the old Spencer Tracy movie "Mountain" this week, and it is a weird precursor to this one (minus the bear). That is, two people facing the elements have very different ideas of morality and of trust. Like that movie, this newer one doesn't explore the conflict of personae, or ethics, very far, giving only what are the obvious differences. That's not enough for a feature length affair. Which brings us back to Baldwin and Hopkins. They are, actually, enough to hold you in for the duration. You really do hope they survive, and if you wince at some of the dialog and at the appearance of bear traps at all the wrong moments, you can get into the drama of it pretty well. And into the scenery. Amazing stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clearly Mamet was never a Boy Scout
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty hard to take this film seriously, much of the time at least. The basic structure of the film is fine, and Hopkins and Baldwin both deliver fine performances. But the survival-related antics these men pull are straight out of a comic book, I think. (Trapping a chipmunk in a cage fashioned out of twigs??? Hilarious!!!) Although Bart the Bear also deserves his top billing, just about every scene he's in is utterly ludicrous. I guess that's not Bart's fault. Maybe his manager should've held out for a better script though. Watch it for the scenery, the machinations of the human characters and the dialog (at both of which Mamet excels), and for Hopkins' acting. And don't take any of the bear- or survival-related stuff seriously. This is not a movie to call to memory when you find yourself lost in the woods....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man vs Man vs Wild
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rasamanjari
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is both a psychological thriller and an authentic, wilderness survival movie. It pits man against the magnificent but harsh Alaskan wilderness, and, at the same time, it also pits man against man in a powerful, primitive struggle over a beautiful woman..a very beautiful woman--Elle Macpherson. Alex Baldwim is excellent as the confident, aggressive, young usurper, always looking for ways to bring down his competition, and Anthony Hopkins is exceptional as the wealthy, intelligent, aristocratic gentleman husband who gracefully endures his attacks while gradually realizing the painful truth. The thing i liked the most about this film is that they both have to depend on each other for survival in the Alaskan wild, while simultaneously dealing with their powerful emotions about each other and the relationship situation. The combination makes this film affect the sensibilities like no other i have seen. Well worth watching. The review alongside the movie poster did not begin to cover this film as it deserves to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harrowing Survival Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anthony Hopkins plays billionaire Charles Morse, a bookish man who is married to a much younger woman(played by Elle McPherson) who is coveted by her photographer(Alec Baldwin) The two men, as well as an assistant(played by Harold Perrineau) are flown into a remote location in the Alaskan wilderness, when they are struck by a flock of birds, causing them to crash in the lake, killing the pilot, and placing the three survivors in a life and death struggle with not only the harsh elements, but a huge Kodiak bear that smells blood... Harrowing adventure drama from writer David Mamet is well directed by Lee Tamahori and acted by the leads, especially Anthony Hopkins, whose transformation from bookish introvert to determined survivalist is believable(they're not mutually exclusive anyway!) Relationship among the men is a bit muddled, especially after the climax, but solid thriller is also compelling and frightening. Not a film for people with a fear of bears...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Edge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scarecrow-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins) is a wealthy man ("with his own plane") who decides to join his supermodel wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson) and her photographic crew to a lodging in the snowy wilderness (of the breathtaking British Columbia mountains and surrounding areas). Charles, Mickey's photographer, Bob (Alec Baldwin), and Bob's assistant, Stephen (Harold Perrineau) go on (what was perceived to be) a small plane ride to a local native's cabin to see if he can transport some film for them but he's on a hunt for bear. Once in the air, birds fly into the plane's propeller, causing them to crash. The pilot killed, the remaining three have to hike it to a closer location of their cabin, but doing so won't be easy thanks to a maneating bear looking to feed its hunger for human flesh. A miscalculation involving "moving south" (Charles uses a paper clip and leaf on water to determine the direction of South following the wind, but a magnetic interference stirs them in a complete circle back to their starting point!), a deep cut on the leg while sharpening a spear (Stephen's "slip" costs him big-time), a bloody rag left on a tree branch (summoning the hungry bear), a nasty attack that shortens the numbers (Stephen never had a prayer), and surviving the elements with little supplies to speak of (matches and the clothes on them; the flares will be needed for later, but they are soon used, too) provide much high drama in this exciting survivalist adventure. Not only the bear's "toying with them" provides suspense, but the idea that Baldwin might be banging Charles' wife and potentially planning to kill him for both the missus and money also remains a point of emphasis throughout. Hopkins never fails to convince as this very intelligent "know-it-all" with almost all the answers when pressures and obstacles present themselves. Charles is always turned to by Stephen and Bob when a new problem rears its ugly head. But that damned bear (Bart the Bear is recognized as a star as the credits closedand should) just won't go away. Alec Baldwin has that knack for portraying likable assholes, and his Bob is no different here. He sometimes uses his sense of humor to blatantly knock Charles, but his respect for the man never wavers. Stephen's attack is brutal, and the bear's attempts towards Charles and Bob commands serious tension. The location of the film provides much atmosphere because of how detrimental it can be for the duo attempting to survive (the bear and the wilderness/peaks both offer their own challenges). Hopkins' subtly expressive face (particularly the mind's trying to solve problems like when Alec suffers a tough leg injury falling into a "dead fall" meant for bears, or his "makeshift" compass idea; later, that panic that soon fades to disappointment regarding Baldwin's condition is a masterclass of acting) speaks a great deal and it's his responsibility to communicate the situation his character faces. Baldwin needs us to like him so we are unsure of his intent towards Hopkins' life; the ending gives us a tragedy that seems regrettable because it didn't need to end that way. The simple use of a watch (and engravings on it) along with a list with specific handwriting are tools that reinforce the revelation regarding whether or not Charles was right or not regarding Bob and Mickey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men Lost...Find Their Way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kept alive by some witty Mamet-Speak and a stunning backdrop of sharp, beautiful Wilderness Cinematography along with believable Leads, this is quite an enjoyable "lost in the wilderness" Movie within a Modern mode of Class Warfare and Marital Infidelity. It is not an easy mix at times and as our duo duel with barbs, insights, and storytelling things can seem at odds with each other. Its like poker game or barroom banter set in the great outdoors. The ever encroachment of the Kodiak Bear could be read as a metaphor for the impending destruction of each Man's Id. Or maybe its just a way to add some lively Action to the Playwright's pontifications of Money, Lawyers, and Love. It is a quirky Film and the talent involved should be credited because they give this well worn Genre a new angle. In the end it is somewhat satisfying and there is enough here to keep both Audiences interested. Those with the flannel shirts and those with the stuffy shirts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Critic Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiemaexo
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins), a billionaire with photographic memory, and two other men, Robert "Bob" Green (Alec Baldwin), a photographer, and Stephen (Harold Perrineau), his assistant, arrive in a remote North America, along with Charles's much-younger wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson), a fashion model. The group is only there for a photo shoot and staying as guests at a lodge, they later are recruited to another area due to a sick model. After their plane crashes, the men attempt to hike to a more likely search area, only to find that a male Kodiak bear is stalking them. They elude it, but later the bear attacks their camp and kills Stephen. The angles of the movie were spectacular; it made you feel like you were out in the woods. Seeing the actors in this environment makes you want to put on a coat to watch the movie. A very strong performance by all the actors in a film that deals with using bare instincts on fighting wild animals, staying alive from the elements, and morality. I can understand why some of the more modern audience might find that to be a turn-off. The sets and locations alone are worth a rental. The photography is beautiful, the landscape comes alive, and sometimes it steals the picture away from the characters. Very strong performances by Anthony Hopkins, Bart the Bear, and Alec Baldwin, Not only were they great but they were troopers with the set. Anthony Hopkins got a severe case of pneumonia while filming out in the cold; I'm a huge fan so his performance was fantastic he can go from a city guy to survival and make it believable. His character was well portrayed and a flawless performance. Alec Baldwin also did a great job in this movie. (And I can't say that I was a big fan of Alec before this movie) I have only seen him in comedy, but I have a better opinion of him now. Elle McPherson has a small role which she played well and portrayed her character very well. A gripping storyline, fantastic scenery and a real sense of drama and survival, it delivers as an action/adventure film by giving some heart stopping sequences, and it never slows down. The Edge also delivers as a dramatic film, with an ending that is painfully sad, yet satisfying. They portray their characters with honesty, and with a realistic nature that only great actors can accomplish. As the plot twists and the pace picks up, you start to become so involved that you forget time is passing by. I strongly suggest this one to action lovers and to anyone who enjoys a good story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge When stranded in the woods, it's a good idea to throw used tampons into the shrubs to keep bears off your trail. Unfortunately, the marooned men in this thriller are fresh out of soiled feminine napkins. When Charles (Anthony Hopkins) crash lands in the wilderness along side Bob (Alec Baldwin), a man he suspects is having an affair with his wife (Elle MacPherson) and plotting his murder, he must resist the urge to beat him to the punch, because there are more pressing matters. Dwarfing the awkward company and harsh surroundings is a ravenous bear that's trailing them. Putting aside their personal matters, Charles and Bob combine their abilities to combat the Kodiak. Written by David Mamet, The Edge is a taunt tale of male bonding amongst bear attacks. The acting is proficient and the dialogue acute. However, aren't grizzlies more apt to attack burly men in tattered clothes? (Yellow Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The bear is smarter than two of the men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a fairly good action film with some excellent sequences in which a bear stalks and attacks 3 stranded men in the Alaskan wilds. I kept wondering "How did they get that shot?" There are some amazingly good effects. I did wonder whether or not the roar of a bear is like the sounds we were given here. It sounded a little much to me. The bear and Anthony Hopkins are the main stars of the show, and Alec Baldwin does a creditable job with a character that is written to be weak and not very smart. The adventure element is concocted. One can raise many questions about the sequence of events too. Making a big circle in the way they did was very implausible, since they scaled a mountain. In addition, this film follows the usual Hollywood rule that held in the old days and still holds, which is basically to kill off the black man. There must be dozens of similar adventure and war movies that follow this rule. In this case, the black man is an utter weak wimp who does nothing but complain. He is also very stupid. What a horribly written part! Baldwin's character is not far behind. Hopkins' character is at least sensible enough to have some idea of what to do in the wild, even if he ignores the fact that the sun rises in the east, but then it does get cloudy sometimes. With such weak characters, I kept thinking back to earlier adventure movies such as Five Came Back. Were men so wimpy in those old movies? Or is this yet another manifestation of the juvenile characters that seem more frequently to people today's movies? The script telegraphs the key plot points a little too well in the opening sequence. The music at times is too syrupy and grand when more danger and challenge should be in the air. The character arc of Hopkins is only subtly hinted at, because we don't know much about him at the start. I like his line at the end about all of us face serious challenges but we don't know when or what form they are going to take. But I dislike his final line shortly thereafter that the other men died saving his life. Why should he lie? He has confronted himself and nature in his essence. He has even realized that he has little to go back to. He has seen truths, but then he lies. The two men died because they made grievous mistakes in their choices. At best they died bravely or "like men". He might have said "They died like men". The strong point of the movie is not its philosophy. It's the conflict between men and a bear. The conflict between Baldwin and Hopkins over his wealth and his wife didn't really ring true as it was written, although Baldwin did, as I said, quite a good job with the part. Let me elaborate a bit on the above. First, too much is given away at the outset. Low-flying birds can bring down an airplane, and this happens subsequently. There is a bear trap, and, sure enough, it plays a part. Bears become man-killers, we are told, and sure enough, act 2 involves just such a critter. Hopkins is given a watch and a knife and, sure enough, they are important later. It's all too pat. It was evident far before Hopkins said that he would kill the bear that this would have to be done. The line went through my head before he spoke it. Meanwhile the Baldwin character was whining worse than the black man had done earlier, and that guy was so inept that he stabbed himself in the leg -- a deep gash mind you -- while trying to sharpen a piece of wood into a spear. Very smart going, mate. Well, this is really Mamet's fault. He could not write a plausible screenplay with the wilderness elements?? He had to concoct this? Now, was Hopkins so dense that he could not pick up, well before this cozy little trip, that his right hand man was deeply hostile toward him? And that he was going with his wife? This is a man who sees all and remembers all. He's a billionaire. He must have an organization that he created. His wife and Baldwin are far from discreet, but Hopkins is that blind? It's all done by writer Mamet so superficially and so lazily. When Baldwin gets around to trying to kill Hopkins, Hopkins does nothing to stop him from loading the rifle. Why? Meanwhile, Baldwin insists they go outside. Why? And once outside, he hesitates and then backs himself up. Why? He is incredibly weak, so weak that I wonder what Hopkins ever saw in him to have him around, and what his wife saw in him. And having saved the life of Hopkins earlier, you would think that maybe his psychology would change. He might even expect rewards, but no, his bitterness actually increases. Why? Mamet lost it in this one as compared with some of his earlier work. We are dealing here with noir-type betrayals, and they are not easy to handle. In films like Too Late for Tears, Out of the Past, Ace in the Hole, and many others, it takes careful development of the characterizations to "sell" them, i.e., make them believable. Mamet has not done this in The Edge. He has not used the interactions generated by the action scenes to do it either -- the direction of the movie didn't bring it out. So that this aspect of the movie, which is a major part of it, is a failure. The viewer is left grasping for understanding and meaning, rather than feeling these people are real and the events real and the meaning central to human experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat and Contrived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rich man and a fashion photographer fight for survival in the jungles after a plane crash. The story is implausible and the situations are contrived, but the biggest deficiency is the under-developed characters. Hopkins plays what looks like the most miserable billionaire in the world, a lonely and insecure fellow who thinks everybody is out to get his money. In the wilds, he turns out to be a super boy scout, but the character is so aloof that it's hard to feel anything for him. Baldwin is supposed to be larger-than-life, as evidenced by his hearty laughs in response to lame jokes, but his character is also flat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty mainstream stuff with unmet intentions of deep psychological conflict
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge (1997) This is a fun wilderness adventure movie with some terrific acting by both Alec Baldwin (as a spoiled bad boy) and Anthony Hopkins (as a very smart millionaire). They battle of wits, and the fighting of the elements, is fodder for screenwriter David Mamet, who has produced more interesting dialog than this, for sure. The third star is the Kodiak bear, who gets a huge credit line at the end, and who unites, at least sometimes, the two men in the cold isolation of Alaska. But let's face it, as much fun as this is, this is thin going. It even looks a bit like a slightly adult version of a Disney adventure film, with people bonding and conflicting as needed. In fact, if you start comparing this movie to others like it (there are a few), you might even consider the television series "Lost," which is at least more imaginative and full-blooded in its writing. Or just survival in the mountains you might check out "Touching the Void." I just saw the old Spencer Tracy movie "Mountain" this week, and it is a weird precursor to this one (minus the bear). That is, two people facing the elements have very different ideas of morality and of trust. Like that movie, this newer one doesn't explore the conflict of personae, or ethics, very far, giving only what are the obvious differences. That's not enough for a feature length affair. Which brings us back to Baldwin and Hopkins. They are, actually, enough to hold you in for the duration. You really do hope they survive, and if you wince at some of the dialog and at the appearance of bear traps at all the wrong moments, you can get into the drama of it pretty well. And into the scenery. Amazing stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clearly Mamet was never a Boy Scout
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty hard to take this film seriously, much of the time at least. The basic structure of the film is fine, and Hopkins and Baldwin both deliver fine performances. But the survival-related antics these men pull are straight out of a comic book, I think. (Trapping a chipmunk in a cage fashioned out of twigs??? Hilarious!!!) Although Bart the Bear also deserves his top billing, just about every scene he's in is utterly ludicrous. I guess that's not Bart's fault. Maybe his manager should've held out for a better script though. Watch it for the scenery, the machinations of the human characters and the dialog (at both of which Mamet excels), and for Hopkins' acting. And don't take any of the bear- or survival-related stuff seriously. This is not a movie to call to memory when you find yourself lost in the woods....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man vs Man vs Wild
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rasamanjari
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is both a psychological thriller and an authentic, wilderness survival movie. It pits man against the magnificent but harsh Alaskan wilderness, and, at the same time, it also pits man against man in a powerful, primitive struggle over a beautiful woman..a very beautiful woman--Elle Macpherson. Alex Baldwim is excellent as the confident, aggressive, young usurper, always looking for ways to bring down his competition, and Anthony Hopkins is exceptional as the wealthy, intelligent, aristocratic gentleman husband who gracefully endures his attacks while gradually realizing the painful truth. The thing i liked the most about this film is that they both have to depend on each other for survival in the Alaskan wild, while simultaneously dealing with their powerful emotions about each other and the relationship situation. The combination makes this film affect the sensibilities like no other i have seen. Well worth watching. The review alongside the movie poster did not begin to cover this film as it deserves to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harrowing Survival Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anthony Hopkins plays billionaire Charles Morse, a bookish man who is married to a much younger woman(played by Elle McPherson) who is coveted by her photographer(Alec Baldwin) The two men, as well as an assistant(played by Harold Perrineau) are flown into a remote location in the Alaskan wilderness, when they are struck by a flock of birds, causing them to crash in the lake, killing the pilot, and placing the three survivors in a life and death struggle with not only the harsh elements, but a huge Kodiak bear that smells blood... Harrowing adventure drama from writer David Mamet is well directed by Lee Tamahori and acted by the leads, especially Anthony Hopkins, whose transformation from bookish introvert to determined survivalist is believable(they're not mutually exclusive anyway!) Relationship among the men is a bit muddled, especially after the climax, but solid thriller is also compelling and frightening. Not a film for people with a fear of bears...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Edge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scarecrow-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins) is a wealthy man ("with his own plane") who decides to join his supermodel wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson) and her photographic crew to a lodging in the snowy wilderness (of the breathtaking British Columbia mountains and surrounding areas). Charles, Mickey's photographer, Bob (Alec Baldwin), and Bob's assistant, Stephen (Harold Perrineau) go on (what was perceived to be) a small plane ride to a local native's cabin to see if he can transport some film for them but he's on a hunt for bear. Once in the air, birds fly into the plane's propeller, causing them to crash. The pilot killed, the remaining three have to hike it to a closer location of their cabin, but doing so won't be easy thanks to a maneating bear looking to feed its hunger for human flesh. A miscalculation involving "moving south" (Charles uses a paper clip and leaf on water to determine the direction of South following the wind, but a magnetic interference stirs them in a complete circle back to their starting point!), a deep cut on the leg while sharpening a spear (Stephen's "slip" costs him big-time), a bloody rag left on a tree branch (summoning the hungry bear), a nasty attack that shortens the numbers (Stephen never had a prayer), and surviving the elements with little supplies to speak of (matches and the clothes on them; the flares will be needed for later, but they are soon used, too) provide much high drama in this exciting survivalist adventure. Not only the bear's "toying with them" provides suspense, but the idea that Baldwin might be banging Charles' wife and potentially planning to kill him for both the missus and money also remains a point of emphasis throughout. Hopkins never fails to convince as this very intelligent "know-it-all" with almost all the answers when pressures and obstacles present themselves. Charles is always turned to by Stephen and Bob when a new problem rears its ugly head. But that damned bear (Bart the Bear is recognized as a star as the credits closedand should) just won't go away. Alec Baldwin has that knack for portraying likable assholes, and his Bob is no different here. He sometimes uses his sense of humor to blatantly knock Charles, but his respect for the man never wavers. Stephen's attack is brutal, and the bear's attempts towards Charles and Bob commands serious tension. The location of the film provides much atmosphere because of how detrimental it can be for the duo attempting to survive (the bear and the wilderness/peaks both offer their own challenges). Hopkins' subtly expressive face (particularly the mind's trying to solve problems like when Alec suffers a tough leg injury falling into a "dead fall" meant for bears, or his "makeshift" compass idea; later, that panic that soon fades to disappointment regarding Baldwin's condition is a masterclass of acting) speaks a great deal and it's his responsibility to communicate the situation his character faces. Baldwin needs us to like him so we are unsure of his intent towards Hopkins' life; the ending gives us a tragedy that seems regrettable because it didn't need to end that way. The simple use of a watch (and engravings on it) along with a list with specific handwriting are tools that reinforce the revelation regarding whether or not Charles was right or not regarding Bob and Mickey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men Lost...Find Their Way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kept alive by some witty Mamet-Speak and a stunning backdrop of sharp, beautiful Wilderness Cinematography along with believable Leads, this is quite an enjoyable "lost in the wilderness" Movie within a Modern mode of Class Warfare and Marital Infidelity. It is not an easy mix at times and as our duo duel with barbs, insights, and storytelling things can seem at odds with each other. Its like poker game or barroom banter set in the great outdoors. The ever encroachment of the Kodiak Bear could be read as a metaphor for the impending destruction of each Man's Id. Or maybe its just a way to add some lively Action to the Playwright's pontifications of Money, Lawyers, and Love. It is a quirky Film and the talent involved should be credited because they give this well worn Genre a new angle. In the end it is somewhat satisfying and there is enough here to keep both Audiences interested. Those with the flannel shirts and those with the stuffy shirts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Critic Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiemaexo
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins), a billionaire with photographic memory, and two other men, Robert "Bob" Green (Alec Baldwin), a photographer, and Stephen (Harold Perrineau), his assistant, arrive in a remote North America, along with Charles's much-younger wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson), a fashion model. The group is only there for a photo shoot and staying as guests at a lodge, they later are recruited to another area due to a sick model. After their plane crashes, the men attempt to hike to a more likely search area, only to find that a male Kodiak bear is stalking them. They elude it, but later the bear attacks their camp and kills Stephen. The angles of the movie were spectacular; it made you feel like you were out in the woods. Seeing the actors in this environment makes you want to put on a coat to watch the movie. A very strong performance by all the actors in a film that deals with using bare instincts on fighting wild animals, staying alive from the elements, and morality. I can understand why some of the more modern audience might find that to be a turn-off. The sets and locations alone are worth a rental. The photography is beautiful, the landscape comes alive, and sometimes it steals the picture away from the characters. Very strong performances by Anthony Hopkins, Bart the Bear, and Alec Baldwin, Not only were they great but they were troopers with the set. Anthony Hopkins got a severe case of pneumonia while filming out in the cold; I'm a huge fan so his performance was fantastic he can go from a city guy to survival and make it believable. His character was well portrayed and a flawless performance. Alec Baldwin also did a great job in this movie. (And I can't say that I was a big fan of Alec before this movie) I have only seen him in comedy, but I have a better opinion of him now. Elle McPherson has a small role which she played well and portrayed her character very well. A gripping storyline, fantastic scenery and a real sense of drama and survival, it delivers as an action/adventure film by giving some heart stopping sequences, and it never slows down. The Edge also delivers as a dramatic film, with an ending that is painfully sad, yet satisfying. They portray their characters with honesty, and with a realistic nature that only great actors can accomplish. As the plot twists and the pace picks up, you start to become so involved that you forget time is passing by. I strongly suggest this one to action lovers and to anyone who enjoys a good story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge When stranded in the woods, it's a good idea to throw used tampons into the shrubs to keep bears off your trail. Unfortunately, the marooned men in this thriller are fresh out of soiled feminine napkins. When Charles (Anthony Hopkins) crash lands in the wilderness along side Bob (Alec Baldwin), a man he suspects is having an affair with his wife (Elle MacPherson) and plotting his murder, he must resist the urge to beat him to the punch, because there are more pressing matters. Dwarfing the awkward company and harsh surroundings is a ravenous bear that's trailing them. Putting aside their personal matters, Charles and Bob combine their abilities to combat the Kodiak. Written by David Mamet, The Edge is a taunt tale of male bonding amongst bear attacks. The acting is proficient and the dialogue acute. However, aren't grizzlies more apt to attack burly men in tattered clothes? (Yellow Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The bear is smarter than two of the men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a fairly good action film with some excellent sequences in which a bear stalks and attacks 3 stranded men in the Alaskan wilds. I kept wondering "How did they get that shot?" There are some amazingly good effects. I did wonder whether or not the roar of a bear is like the sounds we were given here. It sounded a little much to me. The bear and Anthony Hopkins are the main stars of the show, and Alec Baldwin does a creditable job with a character that is written to be weak and not very smart. The adventure element is concocted. One can raise many questions about the sequence of events too. Making a big circle in the way they did was very implausible, since they scaled a mountain. In addition, this film follows the usual Hollywood rule that held in the old days and still holds, which is basically to kill off the black man. There must be dozens of similar adventure and war movies that follow this rule. In this case, the black man is an utter weak wimp who does nothing but complain. He is also very stupid. What a horribly written part! Baldwin's character is not far behind. Hopkins' character is at least sensible enough to have some idea of what to do in the wild, even if he ignores the fact that the sun rises in the east, but then it does get cloudy sometimes. With such weak characters, I kept thinking back to earlier adventure movies such as Five Came Back. Were men so wimpy in those old movies? Or is this yet another manifestation of the juvenile characters that seem more frequently to people today's movies? The script telegraphs the key plot points a little too well in the opening sequence. The music at times is too syrupy and grand when more danger and challenge should be in the air. The character arc of Hopkins is only subtly hinted at, because we don't know much about him at the start. I like his line at the end about all of us face serious challenges but we don't know when or what form they are going to take. But I dislike his final line shortly thereafter that the other men died saving his life. Why should he lie? He has confronted himself and nature in his essence. He has even realized that he has little to go back to. He has seen truths, but then he lies. The two men died because they made grievous mistakes in their choices. At best they died bravely or "like men". He might have said "They died like men". The strong point of the movie is not its philosophy. It's the conflict between men and a bear. The conflict between Baldwin and Hopkins over his wealth and his wife didn't really ring true as it was written, although Baldwin did, as I said, quite a good job with the part. Let me elaborate a bit on the above. First, too much is given away at the outset. Low-flying birds can bring down an airplane, and this happens subsequently. There is a bear trap, and, sure enough, it plays a part. Bears become man-killers, we are told, and sure enough, act 2 involves just such a critter. Hopkins is given a watch and a knife and, sure enough, they are important later. It's all too pat. It was evident far before Hopkins said that he would kill the bear that this would have to be done. The line went through my head before he spoke it. Meanwhile the Baldwin character was whining worse than the black man had done earlier, and that guy was so inept that he stabbed himself in the leg -- a deep gash mind you -- while trying to sharpen a piece of wood into a spear. Very smart going, mate. Well, this is really Mamet's fault. He could not write a plausible screenplay with the wilderness elements?? He had to concoct this? Now, was Hopkins so dense that he could not pick up, well before this cozy little trip, that his right hand man was deeply hostile toward him? And that he was going with his wife? This is a man who sees all and remembers all. He's a billionaire. He must have an organization that he created. His wife and Baldwin are far from discreet, but Hopkins is that blind? It's all done by writer Mamet so superficially and so lazily. When Baldwin gets around to trying to kill Hopkins, Hopkins does nothing to stop him from loading the rifle. Why? Meanwhile, Baldwin insists they go outside. Why? And once outside, he hesitates and then backs himself up. Why? He is incredibly weak, so weak that I wonder what Hopkins ever saw in him to have him around, and what his wife saw in him. And having saved the life of Hopkins earlier, you would think that maybe his psychology would change. He might even expect rewards, but no, his bitterness actually increases. Why? Mamet lost it in this one as compared with some of his earlier work. We are dealing here with noir-type betrayals, and they are not easy to handle. In films like Too Late for Tears, Out of the Past, Ace in the Hole, and many others, it takes careful development of the characterizations to "sell" them, i.e., make them believable. Mamet has not done this in The Edge. He has not used the interactions generated by the action scenes to do it either -- the direction of the movie didn't bring it out. So that this aspect of the movie, which is a major part of it, is a failure. The viewer is left grasping for understanding and meaning, rather than feeling these people are real and the events real and the meaning central to human experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat and Contrived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rich man and a fashion photographer fight for survival in the jungles after a plane crash. The story is implausible and the situations are contrived, but the biggest deficiency is the under-developed characters. Hopkins plays what looks like the most miserable billionaire in the world, a lonely and insecure fellow who thinks everybody is out to get his money. In the wilds, he turns out to be a super boy scout, but the character is so aloof that it's hard to feel anything for him. Baldwin is supposed to be larger-than-life, as evidenced by his hearty laughs in response to lame jokes, but his character is also flat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty mainstream stuff with unmet intentions of deep psychological conflict
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge (1997) This is a fun wilderness adventure movie with some terrific acting by both Alec Baldwin (as a spoiled bad boy) and Anthony Hopkins (as a very smart millionaire). They battle of wits, and the fighting of the elements, is fodder for screenwriter David Mamet, who has produced more interesting dialog than this, for sure. The third star is the Kodiak bear, who gets a huge credit line at the end, and who unites, at least sometimes, the two men in the cold isolation of Alaska. But let's face it, as much fun as this is, this is thin going. It even looks a bit like a slightly adult version of a Disney adventure film, with people bonding and conflicting as needed. In fact, if you start comparing this movie to others like it (there are a few), you might even consider the television series "Lost," which is at least more imaginative and full-blooded in its writing. Or just survival in the mountains you might check out "Touching the Void." I just saw the old Spencer Tracy movie "Mountain" this week, and it is a weird precursor to this one (minus the bear). That is, two people facing the elements have very different ideas of morality and of trust. Like that movie, this newer one doesn't explore the conflict of personae, or ethics, very far, giving only what are the obvious differences. That's not enough for a feature length affair. Which brings us back to Baldwin and Hopkins. They are, actually, enough to hold you in for the duration. You really do hope they survive, and if you wince at some of the dialog and at the appearance of bear traps at all the wrong moments, you can get into the drama of it pretty well. And into the scenery. Amazing stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clearly Mamet was never a Boy Scout
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty hard to take this film seriously, much of the time at least. The basic structure of the film is fine, and Hopkins and Baldwin both deliver fine performances. But the survival-related antics these men pull are straight out of a comic book, I think. (Trapping a chipmunk in a cage fashioned out of twigs??? Hilarious!!!) Although Bart the Bear also deserves his top billing, just about every scene he's in is utterly ludicrous. I guess that's not Bart's fault. Maybe his manager should've held out for a better script though. Watch it for the scenery, the machinations of the human characters and the dialog (at both of which Mamet excels), and for Hopkins' acting. And don't take any of the bear- or survival-related stuff seriously. This is not a movie to call to memory when you find yourself lost in the woods....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man vs Man vs Wild
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rasamanjari
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is both a psychological thriller and an authentic, wilderness survival movie. It pits man against the magnificent but harsh Alaskan wilderness, and, at the same time, it also pits man against man in a powerful, primitive struggle over a beautiful woman..a very beautiful woman--Elle Macpherson. Alex Baldwim is excellent as the confident, aggressive, young usurper, always looking for ways to bring down his competition, and Anthony Hopkins is exceptional as the wealthy, intelligent, aristocratic gentleman husband who gracefully endures his attacks while gradually realizing the painful truth. The thing i liked the most about this film is that they both have to depend on each other for survival in the Alaskan wild, while simultaneously dealing with their powerful emotions about each other and the relationship situation. The combination makes this film affect the sensibilities like no other i have seen. Well worth watching. The review alongside the movie poster did not begin to cover this film as it deserves to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harrowing Survival Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anthony Hopkins plays billionaire Charles Morse, a bookish man who is married to a much younger woman(played by Elle McPherson) who is coveted by her photographer(Alec Baldwin) The two men, as well as an assistant(played by Harold Perrineau) are flown into a remote location in the Alaskan wilderness, when they are struck by a flock of birds, causing them to crash in the lake, killing the pilot, and placing the three survivors in a life and death struggle with not only the harsh elements, but a huge Kodiak bear that smells blood... Harrowing adventure drama from writer David Mamet is well directed by Lee Tamahori and acted by the leads, especially Anthony Hopkins, whose transformation from bookish introvert to determined survivalist is believable(they're not mutually exclusive anyway!) Relationship among the men is a bit muddled, especially after the climax, but solid thriller is also compelling and frightening. Not a film for people with a fear of bears...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Edge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scarecrow-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins) is a wealthy man ("with his own plane") who decides to join his supermodel wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson) and her photographic crew to a lodging in the snowy wilderness (of the breathtaking British Columbia mountains and surrounding areas). Charles, Mickey's photographer, Bob (Alec Baldwin), and Bob's assistant, Stephen (Harold Perrineau) go on (what was perceived to be) a small plane ride to a local native's cabin to see if he can transport some film for them but he's on a hunt for bear. Once in the air, birds fly into the plane's propeller, causing them to crash. The pilot killed, the remaining three have to hike it to a closer location of their cabin, but doing so won't be easy thanks to a maneating bear looking to feed its hunger for human flesh. A miscalculation involving "moving south" (Charles uses a paper clip and leaf on water to determine the direction of South following the wind, but a magnetic interference stirs them in a complete circle back to their starting point!), a deep cut on the leg while sharpening a spear (Stephen's "slip" costs him big-time), a bloody rag left on a tree branch (summoning the hungry bear), a nasty attack that shortens the numbers (Stephen never had a prayer), and surviving the elements with little supplies to speak of (matches and the clothes on them; the flares will be needed for later, but they are soon used, too) provide much high drama in this exciting survivalist adventure. Not only the bear's "toying with them" provides suspense, but the idea that Baldwin might be banging Charles' wife and potentially planning to kill him for both the missus and money also remains a point of emphasis throughout. Hopkins never fails to convince as this very intelligent "know-it-all" with almost all the answers when pressures and obstacles present themselves. Charles is always turned to by Stephen and Bob when a new problem rears its ugly head. But that damned bear (Bart the Bear is recognized as a star as the credits closedand should) just won't go away. Alec Baldwin has that knack for portraying likable assholes, and his Bob is no different here. He sometimes uses his sense of humor to blatantly knock Charles, but his respect for the man never wavers. Stephen's attack is brutal, and the bear's attempts towards Charles and Bob commands serious tension. The location of the film provides much atmosphere because of how detrimental it can be for the duo attempting to survive (the bear and the wilderness/peaks both offer their own challenges). Hopkins' subtly expressive face (particularly the mind's trying to solve problems like when Alec suffers a tough leg injury falling into a "dead fall" meant for bears, or his "makeshift" compass idea; later, that panic that soon fades to disappointment regarding Baldwin's condition is a masterclass of acting) speaks a great deal and it's his responsibility to communicate the situation his character faces. Baldwin needs us to like him so we are unsure of his intent towards Hopkins' life; the ending gives us a tragedy that seems regrettable because it didn't need to end that way. The simple use of a watch (and engravings on it) along with a list with specific handwriting are tools that reinforce the revelation regarding whether or not Charles was right or not regarding Bob and Mickey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men Lost...Find Their Way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kept alive by some witty Mamet-Speak and a stunning backdrop of sharp, beautiful Wilderness Cinematography along with believable Leads, this is quite an enjoyable "lost in the wilderness" Movie within a Modern mode of Class Warfare and Marital Infidelity. It is not an easy mix at times and as our duo duel with barbs, insights, and storytelling things can seem at odds with each other. Its like poker game or barroom banter set in the great outdoors. The ever encroachment of the Kodiak Bear could be read as a metaphor for the impending destruction of each Man's Id. Or maybe its just a way to add some lively Action to the Playwright's pontifications of Money, Lawyers, and Love. It is a quirky Film and the talent involved should be credited because they give this well worn Genre a new angle. In the end it is somewhat satisfying and there is enough here to keep both Audiences interested. Those with the flannel shirts and those with the stuffy shirts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Critic Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiemaexo
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins), a billionaire with photographic memory, and two other men, Robert "Bob" Green (Alec Baldwin), a photographer, and Stephen (Harold Perrineau), his assistant, arrive in a remote North America, along with Charles's much-younger wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson), a fashion model. The group is only there for a photo shoot and staying as guests at a lodge, they later are recruited to another area due to a sick model. After their plane crashes, the men attempt to hike to a more likely search area, only to find that a male Kodiak bear is stalking them. They elude it, but later the bear attacks their camp and kills Stephen. The angles of the movie were spectacular; it made you feel like you were out in the woods. Seeing the actors in this environment makes you want to put on a coat to watch the movie. A very strong performance by all the actors in a film that deals with using bare instincts on fighting wild animals, staying alive from the elements, and morality. I can understand why some of the more modern audience might find that to be a turn-off. The sets and locations alone are worth a rental. The photography is beautiful, the landscape comes alive, and sometimes it steals the picture away from the characters. Very strong performances by Anthony Hopkins, Bart the Bear, and Alec Baldwin, Not only were they great but they were troopers with the set. Anthony Hopkins got a severe case of pneumonia while filming out in the cold; I'm a huge fan so his performance was fantastic he can go from a city guy to survival and make it believable. His character was well portrayed and a flawless performance. Alec Baldwin also did a great job in this movie. (And I can't say that I was a big fan of Alec before this movie) I have only seen him in comedy, but I have a better opinion of him now. Elle McPherson has a small role which she played well and portrayed her character very well. A gripping storyline, fantastic scenery and a real sense of drama and survival, it delivers as an action/adventure film by giving some heart stopping sequences, and it never slows down. The Edge also delivers as a dramatic film, with an ending that is painfully sad, yet satisfying. They portray their characters with honesty, and with a realistic nature that only great actors can accomplish. As the plot twists and the pace picks up, you start to become so involved that you forget time is passing by. I strongly suggest this one to action lovers and to anyone who enjoys a good story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge When stranded in the woods, it's a good idea to throw used tampons into the shrubs to keep bears off your trail. Unfortunately, the marooned men in this thriller are fresh out of soiled feminine napkins. When Charles (Anthony Hopkins) crash lands in the wilderness along side Bob (Alec Baldwin), a man he suspects is having an affair with his wife (Elle MacPherson) and plotting his murder, he must resist the urge to beat him to the punch, because there are more pressing matters. Dwarfing the awkward company and harsh surroundings is a ravenous bear that's trailing them. Putting aside their personal matters, Charles and Bob combine their abilities to combat the Kodiak. Written by David Mamet, The Edge is a taunt tale of male bonding amongst bear attacks. The acting is proficient and the dialogue acute. However, aren't grizzlies more apt to attack burly men in tattered clothes? (Yellow Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The bear is smarter than two of the men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a fairly good action film with some excellent sequences in which a bear stalks and attacks 3 stranded men in the Alaskan wilds. I kept wondering "How did they get that shot?" There are some amazingly good effects. I did wonder whether or not the roar of a bear is like the sounds we were given here. It sounded a little much to me. The bear and Anthony Hopkins are the main stars of the show, and Alec Baldwin does a creditable job with a character that is written to be weak and not very smart. The adventure element is concocted. One can raise many questions about the sequence of events too. Making a big circle in the way they did was very implausible, since they scaled a mountain. In addition, this film follows the usual Hollywood rule that held in the old days and still holds, which is basically to kill off the black man. There must be dozens of similar adventure and war movies that follow this rule. In this case, the black man is an utter weak wimp who does nothing but complain. He is also very stupid. What a horribly written part! Baldwin's character is not far behind. Hopkins' character is at least sensible enough to have some idea of what to do in the wild, even if he ignores the fact that the sun rises in the east, but then it does get cloudy sometimes. With such weak characters, I kept thinking back to earlier adventure movies such as Five Came Back. Were men so wimpy in those old movies? Or is this yet another manifestation of the juvenile characters that seem more frequently to people today's movies? The script telegraphs the key plot points a little too well in the opening sequence. The music at times is too syrupy and grand when more danger and challenge should be in the air. The character arc of Hopkins is only subtly hinted at, because we don't know much about him at the start. I like his line at the end about all of us face serious challenges but we don't know when or what form they are going to take. But I dislike his final line shortly thereafter that the other men died saving his life. Why should he lie? He has confronted himself and nature in his essence. He has even realized that he has little to go back to. He has seen truths, but then he lies. The two men died because they made grievous mistakes in their choices. At best they died bravely or "like men". He might have said "They died like men". The strong point of the movie is not its philosophy. It's the conflict between men and a bear. The conflict between Baldwin and Hopkins over his wealth and his wife didn't really ring true as it was written, although Baldwin did, as I said, quite a good job with the part. Let me elaborate a bit on the above. First, too much is given away at the outset. Low-flying birds can bring down an airplane, and this happens subsequently. There is a bear trap, and, sure enough, it plays a part. Bears become man-killers, we are told, and sure enough, act 2 involves just such a critter. Hopkins is given a watch and a knife and, sure enough, they are important later. It's all too pat. It was evident far before Hopkins said that he would kill the bear that this would have to be done. The line went through my head before he spoke it. Meanwhile the Baldwin character was whining worse than the black man had done earlier, and that guy was so inept that he stabbed himself in the leg -- a deep gash mind you -- while trying to sharpen a piece of wood into a spear. Very smart going, mate. Well, this is really Mamet's fault. He could not write a plausible screenplay with the wilderness elements?? He had to concoct this? Now, was Hopkins so dense that he could not pick up, well before this cozy little trip, that his right hand man was deeply hostile toward him? And that he was going with his wife? This is a man who sees all and remembers all. He's a billionaire. He must have an organization that he created. His wife and Baldwin are far from discreet, but Hopkins is that blind? It's all done by writer Mamet so superficially and so lazily. When Baldwin gets around to trying to kill Hopkins, Hopkins does nothing to stop him from loading the rifle. Why? Meanwhile, Baldwin insists they go outside. Why? And once outside, he hesitates and then backs himself up. Why? He is incredibly weak, so weak that I wonder what Hopkins ever saw in him to have him around, and what his wife saw in him. And having saved the life of Hopkins earlier, you would think that maybe his psychology would change. He might even expect rewards, but no, his bitterness actually increases. Why? Mamet lost it in this one as compared with some of his earlier work. We are dealing here with noir-type betrayals, and they are not easy to handle. In films like Too Late for Tears, Out of the Past, Ace in the Hole, and many others, it takes careful development of the characterizations to "sell" them, i.e., make them believable. Mamet has not done this in The Edge. He has not used the interactions generated by the action scenes to do it either -- the direction of the movie didn't bring it out. So that this aspect of the movie, which is a major part of it, is a failure. The viewer is left grasping for understanding and meaning, rather than feeling these people are real and the events real and the meaning central to human experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat and Contrived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rich man and a fashion photographer fight for survival in the jungles after a plane crash. The story is implausible and the situations are contrived, but the biggest deficiency is the under-developed characters. Hopkins plays what looks like the most miserable billionaire in the world, a lonely and insecure fellow who thinks everybody is out to get his money. In the wilds, he turns out to be a super boy scout, but the character is so aloof that it's hard to feel anything for him. Baldwin is supposed to be larger-than-life, as evidenced by his hearty laughs in response to lame jokes, but his character is also flat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty mainstream stuff with unmet intentions of deep psychological conflict
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge (1997) This is a fun wilderness adventure movie with some terrific acting by both Alec Baldwin (as a spoiled bad boy) and Anthony Hopkins (as a very smart millionaire). They battle of wits, and the fighting of the elements, is fodder for screenwriter David Mamet, who has produced more interesting dialog than this, for sure. The third star is the Kodiak bear, who gets a huge credit line at the end, and who unites, at least sometimes, the two men in the cold isolation of Alaska. But let's face it, as much fun as this is, this is thin going. It even looks a bit like a slightly adult version of a Disney adventure film, with people bonding and conflicting as needed. In fact, if you start comparing this movie to others like it (there are a few), you might even consider the television series "Lost," which is at least more imaginative and full-blooded in its writing. Or just survival in the mountains you might check out "Touching the Void." I just saw the old Spencer Tracy movie "Mountain" this week, and it is a weird precursor to this one (minus the bear). That is, two people facing the elements have very different ideas of morality and of trust. Like that movie, this newer one doesn't explore the conflict of personae, or ethics, very far, giving only what are the obvious differences. That's not enough for a feature length affair. Which brings us back to Baldwin and Hopkins. They are, actually, enough to hold you in for the duration. You really do hope they survive, and if you wince at some of the dialog and at the appearance of bear traps at all the wrong moments, you can get into the drama of it pretty well. And into the scenery. Amazing stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clearly Mamet was never a Boy Scout
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty hard to take this film seriously, much of the time at least. The basic structure of the film is fine, and Hopkins and Baldwin both deliver fine performances. But the survival-related antics these men pull are straight out of a comic book, I think. (Trapping a chipmunk in a cage fashioned out of twigs??? Hilarious!!!) Although Bart the Bear also deserves his top billing, just about every scene he's in is utterly ludicrous. I guess that's not Bart's fault. Maybe his manager should've held out for a better script though. Watch it for the scenery, the machinations of the human characters and the dialog (at both of which Mamet excels), and for Hopkins' acting. And don't take any of the bear- or survival-related stuff seriously. This is not a movie to call to memory when you find yourself lost in the woods....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man vs Man vs Wild
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rasamanjari
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is both a psychological thriller and an authentic, wilderness survival movie. It pits man against the magnificent but harsh Alaskan wilderness, and, at the same time, it also pits man against man in a powerful, primitive struggle over a beautiful woman..a very beautiful woman--Elle Macpherson. Alex Baldwim is excellent as the confident, aggressive, young usurper, always looking for ways to bring down his competition, and Anthony Hopkins is exceptional as the wealthy, intelligent, aristocratic gentleman husband who gracefully endures his attacks while gradually realizing the painful truth. The thing i liked the most about this film is that they both have to depend on each other for survival in the Alaskan wild, while simultaneously dealing with their powerful emotions about each other and the relationship situation. The combination makes this film affect the sensibilities like no other i have seen. Well worth watching. The review alongside the movie poster did not begin to cover this film as it deserves to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harrowing Survival Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anthony Hopkins plays billionaire Charles Morse, a bookish man who is married to a much younger woman(played by Elle McPherson) who is coveted by her photographer(Alec Baldwin) The two men, as well as an assistant(played by Harold Perrineau) are flown into a remote location in the Alaskan wilderness, when they are struck by a flock of birds, causing them to crash in the lake, killing the pilot, and placing the three survivors in a life and death struggle with not only the harsh elements, but a huge Kodiak bear that smells blood... Harrowing adventure drama from writer David Mamet is well directed by Lee Tamahori and acted by the leads, especially Anthony Hopkins, whose transformation from bookish introvert to determined survivalist is believable(they're not mutually exclusive anyway!) Relationship among the men is a bit muddled, especially after the climax, but solid thriller is also compelling and frightening. Not a film for people with a fear of bears...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Edge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scarecrow-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins) is a wealthy man ("with his own plane") who decides to join his supermodel wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson) and her photographic crew to a lodging in the snowy wilderness (of the breathtaking British Columbia mountains and surrounding areas). Charles, Mickey's photographer, Bob (Alec Baldwin), and Bob's assistant, Stephen (Harold Perrineau) go on (what was perceived to be) a small plane ride to a local native's cabin to see if he can transport some film for them but he's on a hunt for bear. Once in the air, birds fly into the plane's propeller, causing them to crash. The pilot killed, the remaining three have to hike it to a closer location of their cabin, but doing so won't be easy thanks to a maneating bear looking to feed its hunger for human flesh. A miscalculation involving "moving south" (Charles uses a paper clip and leaf on water to determine the direction of South following the wind, but a magnetic interference stirs them in a complete circle back to their starting point!), a deep cut on the leg while sharpening a spear (Stephen's "slip" costs him big-time), a bloody rag left on a tree branch (summoning the hungry bear), a nasty attack that shortens the numbers (Stephen never had a prayer), and surviving the elements with little supplies to speak of (matches and the clothes on them; the flares will be needed for later, but they are soon used, too) provide much high drama in this exciting survivalist adventure. Not only the bear's "toying with them" provides suspense, but the idea that Baldwin might be banging Charles' wife and potentially planning to kill him for both the missus and money also remains a point of emphasis throughout. Hopkins never fails to convince as this very intelligent "know-it-all" with almost all the answers when pressures and obstacles present themselves. Charles is always turned to by Stephen and Bob when a new problem rears its ugly head. But that damned bear (Bart the Bear is recognized as a star as the credits closedand should) just won't go away. Alec Baldwin has that knack for portraying likable assholes, and his Bob is no different here. He sometimes uses his sense of humor to blatantly knock Charles, but his respect for the man never wavers. Stephen's attack is brutal, and the bear's attempts towards Charles and Bob commands serious tension. The location of the film provides much atmosphere because of how detrimental it can be for the duo attempting to survive (the bear and the wilderness/peaks both offer their own challenges). Hopkins' subtly expressive face (particularly the mind's trying to solve problems like when Alec suffers a tough leg injury falling into a "dead fall" meant for bears, or his "makeshift" compass idea; later, that panic that soon fades to disappointment regarding Baldwin's condition is a masterclass of acting) speaks a great deal and it's his responsibility to communicate the situation his character faces. Baldwin needs us to like him so we are unsure of his intent towards Hopkins' life; the ending gives us a tragedy that seems regrettable because it didn't need to end that way. The simple use of a watch (and engravings on it) along with a list with specific handwriting are tools that reinforce the revelation regarding whether or not Charles was right or not regarding Bob and Mickey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men Lost...Find Their Way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kept alive by some witty Mamet-Speak and a stunning backdrop of sharp, beautiful Wilderness Cinematography along with believable Leads, this is quite an enjoyable "lost in the wilderness" Movie within a Modern mode of Class Warfare and Marital Infidelity. It is not an easy mix at times and as our duo duel with barbs, insights, and storytelling things can seem at odds with each other. Its like poker game or barroom banter set in the great outdoors. The ever encroachment of the Kodiak Bear could be read as a metaphor for the impending destruction of each Man's Id. Or maybe its just a way to add some lively Action to the Playwright's pontifications of Money, Lawyers, and Love. It is a quirky Film and the talent involved should be credited because they give this well worn Genre a new angle. In the end it is somewhat satisfying and there is enough here to keep both Audiences interested. Those with the flannel shirts and those with the stuffy shirts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Critic Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiemaexo
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins), a billionaire with photographic memory, and two other men, Robert "Bob" Green (Alec Baldwin), a photographer, and Stephen (Harold Perrineau), his assistant, arrive in a remote North America, along with Charles's much-younger wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson), a fashion model. The group is only there for a photo shoot and staying as guests at a lodge, they later are recruited to another area due to a sick model. After their plane crashes, the men attempt to hike to a more likely search area, only to find that a male Kodiak bear is stalking them. They elude it, but later the bear attacks their camp and kills Stephen. The angles of the movie were spectacular; it made you feel like you were out in the woods. Seeing the actors in this environment makes you want to put on a coat to watch the movie. A very strong performance by all the actors in a film that deals with using bare instincts on fighting wild animals, staying alive from the elements, and morality. I can understand why some of the more modern audience might find that to be a turn-off. The sets and locations alone are worth a rental. The photography is beautiful, the landscape comes alive, and sometimes it steals the picture away from the characters. Very strong performances by Anthony Hopkins, Bart the Bear, and Alec Baldwin, Not only were they great but they were troopers with the set. Anthony Hopkins got a severe case of pneumonia while filming out in the cold; I'm a huge fan so his performance was fantastic he can go from a city guy to survival and make it believable. His character was well portrayed and a flawless performance. Alec Baldwin also did a great job in this movie. (And I can't say that I was a big fan of Alec before this movie) I have only seen him in comedy, but I have a better opinion of him now. Elle McPherson has a small role which she played well and portrayed her character very well. A gripping storyline, fantastic scenery and a real sense of drama and survival, it delivers as an action/adventure film by giving some heart stopping sequences, and it never slows down. The Edge also delivers as a dramatic film, with an ending that is painfully sad, yet satisfying. They portray their characters with honesty, and with a realistic nature that only great actors can accomplish. As the plot twists and the pace picks up, you start to become so involved that you forget time is passing by. I strongly suggest this one to action lovers and to anyone who enjoys a good story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge When stranded in the woods, it's a good idea to throw used tampons into the shrubs to keep bears off your trail. Unfortunately, the marooned men in this thriller are fresh out of soiled feminine napkins. When Charles (Anthony Hopkins) crash lands in the wilderness along side Bob (Alec Baldwin), a man he suspects is having an affair with his wife (Elle MacPherson) and plotting his murder, he must resist the urge to beat him to the punch, because there are more pressing matters. Dwarfing the awkward company and harsh surroundings is a ravenous bear that's trailing them. Putting aside their personal matters, Charles and Bob combine their abilities to combat the Kodiak. Written by David Mamet, The Edge is a taunt tale of male bonding amongst bear attacks. The acting is proficient and the dialogue acute. However, aren't grizzlies more apt to attack burly men in tattered clothes? (Yellow Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The bear is smarter than two of the men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a fairly good action film with some excellent sequences in which a bear stalks and attacks 3 stranded men in the Alaskan wilds. I kept wondering "How did they get that shot?" There are some amazingly good effects. I did wonder whether or not the roar of a bear is like the sounds we were given here. It sounded a little much to me. The bear and Anthony Hopkins are the main stars of the show, and Alec Baldwin does a creditable job with a character that is written to be weak and not very smart. The adventure element is concocted. One can raise many questions about the sequence of events too. Making a big circle in the way they did was very implausible, since they scaled a mountain. In addition, this film follows the usual Hollywood rule that held in the old days and still holds, which is basically to kill off the black man. There must be dozens of similar adventure and war movies that follow this rule. In this case, the black man is an utter weak wimp who does nothing but complain. He is also very stupid. What a horribly written part! Baldwin's character is not far behind. Hopkins' character is at least sensible enough to have some idea of what to do in the wild, even if he ignores the fact that the sun rises in the east, but then it does get cloudy sometimes. With such weak characters, I kept thinking back to earlier adventure movies such as Five Came Back. Were men so wimpy in those old movies? Or is this yet another manifestation of the juvenile characters that seem more frequently to people today's movies? The script telegraphs the key plot points a little too well in the opening sequence. The music at times is too syrupy and grand when more danger and challenge should be in the air. The character arc of Hopkins is only subtly hinted at, because we don't know much about him at the start. I like his line at the end about all of us face serious challenges but we don't know when or what form they are going to take. But I dislike his final line shortly thereafter that the other men died saving his life. Why should he lie? He has confronted himself and nature in his essence. He has even realized that he has little to go back to. He has seen truths, but then he lies. The two men died because they made grievous mistakes in their choices. At best they died bravely or "like men". He might have said "They died like men". The strong point of the movie is not its philosophy. It's the conflict between men and a bear. The conflict between Baldwin and Hopkins over his wealth and his wife didn't really ring true as it was written, although Baldwin did, as I said, quite a good job with the part. Let me elaborate a bit on the above. First, too much is given away at the outset. Low-flying birds can bring down an airplane, and this happens subsequently. There is a bear trap, and, sure enough, it plays a part. Bears become man-killers, we are told, and sure enough, act 2 involves just such a critter. Hopkins is given a watch and a knife and, sure enough, they are important later. It's all too pat. It was evident far before Hopkins said that he would kill the bear that this would have to be done. The line went through my head before he spoke it. Meanwhile the Baldwin character was whining worse than the black man had done earlier, and that guy was so inept that he stabbed himself in the leg -- a deep gash mind you -- while trying to sharpen a piece of wood into a spear. Very smart going, mate. Well, this is really Mamet's fault. He could not write a plausible screenplay with the wilderness elements?? He had to concoct this? Now, was Hopkins so dense that he could not pick up, well before this cozy little trip, that his right hand man was deeply hostile toward him? And that he was going with his wife? This is a man who sees all and remembers all. He's a billionaire. He must have an organization that he created. His wife and Baldwin are far from discreet, but Hopkins is that blind? It's all done by writer Mamet so superficially and so lazily. When Baldwin gets around to trying to kill Hopkins, Hopkins does nothing to stop him from loading the rifle. Why? Meanwhile, Baldwin insists they go outside. Why? And once outside, he hesitates and then backs himself up. Why? He is incredibly weak, so weak that I wonder what Hopkins ever saw in him to have him around, and what his wife saw in him. And having saved the life of Hopkins earlier, you would think that maybe his psychology would change. He might even expect rewards, but no, his bitterness actually increases. Why? Mamet lost it in this one as compared with some of his earlier work. We are dealing here with noir-type betrayals, and they are not easy to handle. In films like Too Late for Tears, Out of the Past, Ace in the Hole, and many others, it takes careful development of the characterizations to "sell" them, i.e., make them believable. Mamet has not done this in The Edge. He has not used the interactions generated by the action scenes to do it either -- the direction of the movie didn't bring it out. So that this aspect of the movie, which is a major part of it, is a failure. The viewer is left grasping for understanding and meaning, rather than feeling these people are real and the events real and the meaning central to human experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat and Contrived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rich man and a fashion photographer fight for survival in the jungles after a plane crash. The story is implausible and the situations are contrived, but the biggest deficiency is the under-developed characters. Hopkins plays what looks like the most miserable billionaire in the world, a lonely and insecure fellow who thinks everybody is out to get his money. In the wilds, he turns out to be a super boy scout, but the character is so aloof that it's hard to feel anything for him. Baldwin is supposed to be larger-than-life, as evidenced by his hearty laughs in response to lame jokes, but his character is also flat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty mainstream stuff with unmet intentions of deep psychological conflict
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge (1997) This is a fun wilderness adventure movie with some terrific acting by both Alec Baldwin (as a spoiled bad boy) and Anthony Hopkins (as a very smart millionaire). They battle of wits, and the fighting of the elements, is fodder for screenwriter David Mamet, who has produced more interesting dialog than this, for sure. The third star is the Kodiak bear, who gets a huge credit line at the end, and who unites, at least sometimes, the two men in the cold isolation of Alaska. But let's face it, as much fun as this is, this is thin going. It even looks a bit like a slightly adult version of a Disney adventure film, with people bonding and conflicting as needed. In fact, if you start comparing this movie to others like it (there are a few), you might even consider the television series "Lost," which is at least more imaginative and full-blooded in its writing. Or just survival in the mountains you might check out "Touching the Void." I just saw the old Spencer Tracy movie "Mountain" this week, and it is a weird precursor to this one (minus the bear). That is, two people facing the elements have very different ideas of morality and of trust. Like that movie, this newer one doesn't explore the conflict of personae, or ethics, very far, giving only what are the obvious differences. That's not enough for a feature length affair. Which brings us back to Baldwin and Hopkins. They are, actually, enough to hold you in for the duration. You really do hope they survive, and if you wince at some of the dialog and at the appearance of bear traps at all the wrong moments, you can get into the drama of it pretty well. And into the scenery. Amazing stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clearly Mamet was never a Boy Scout
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty hard to take this film seriously, much of the time at least. The basic structure of the film is fine, and Hopkins and Baldwin both deliver fine performances. But the survival-related antics these men pull are straight out of a comic book, I think. (Trapping a chipmunk in a cage fashioned out of twigs??? Hilarious!!!) Although Bart the Bear also deserves his top billing, just about every scene he's in is utterly ludicrous. I guess that's not Bart's fault. Maybe his manager should've held out for a better script though. Watch it for the scenery, the machinations of the human characters and the dialog (at both of which Mamet excels), and for Hopkins' acting. And don't take any of the bear- or survival-related stuff seriously. This is not a movie to call to memory when you find yourself lost in the woods....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man vs Man vs Wild
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rasamanjari
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is both a psychological thriller and an authentic, wilderness survival movie. It pits man against the magnificent but harsh Alaskan wilderness, and, at the same time, it also pits man against man in a powerful, primitive struggle over a beautiful woman..a very beautiful woman--Elle Macpherson. Alex Baldwim is excellent as the confident, aggressive, young usurper, always looking for ways to bring down his competition, and Anthony Hopkins is exceptional as the wealthy, intelligent, aristocratic gentleman husband who gracefully endures his attacks while gradually realizing the painful truth. The thing i liked the most about this film is that they both have to depend on each other for survival in the Alaskan wild, while simultaneously dealing with their powerful emotions about each other and the relationship situation. The combination makes this film affect the sensibilities like no other i have seen. Well worth watching. The review alongside the movie poster did not begin to cover this film as it deserves to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harrowing Survival Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anthony Hopkins plays billionaire Charles Morse, a bookish man who is married to a much younger woman(played by Elle McPherson) who is coveted by her photographer(Alec Baldwin) The two men, as well as an assistant(played by Harold Perrineau) are flown into a remote location in the Alaskan wilderness, when they are struck by a flock of birds, causing them to crash in the lake, killing the pilot, and placing the three survivors in a life and death struggle with not only the harsh elements, but a huge Kodiak bear that smells blood... Harrowing adventure drama from writer David Mamet is well directed by Lee Tamahori and acted by the leads, especially Anthony Hopkins, whose transformation from bookish introvert to determined survivalist is believable(they're not mutually exclusive anyway!) Relationship among the men is a bit muddled, especially after the climax, but solid thriller is also compelling and frightening. Not a film for people with a fear of bears...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Edge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scarecrow-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins) is a wealthy man ("with his own plane") who decides to join his supermodel wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson) and her photographic crew to a lodging in the snowy wilderness (of the breathtaking British Columbia mountains and surrounding areas). Charles, Mickey's photographer, Bob (Alec Baldwin), and Bob's assistant, Stephen (Harold Perrineau) go on (what was perceived to be) a small plane ride to a local native's cabin to see if he can transport some film for them but he's on a hunt for bear. Once in the air, birds fly into the plane's propeller, causing them to crash. The pilot killed, the remaining three have to hike it to a closer location of their cabin, but doing so won't be easy thanks to a maneating bear looking to feed its hunger for human flesh. A miscalculation involving "moving south" (Charles uses a paper clip and leaf on water to determine the direction of South following the wind, but a magnetic interference stirs them in a complete circle back to their starting point!), a deep cut on the leg while sharpening a spear (Stephen's "slip" costs him big-time), a bloody rag left on a tree branch (summoning the hungry bear), a nasty attack that shortens the numbers (Stephen never had a prayer), and surviving the elements with little supplies to speak of (matches and the clothes on them; the flares will be needed for later, but they are soon used, too) provide much high drama in this exciting survivalist adventure. Not only the bear's "toying with them" provides suspense, but the idea that Baldwin might be banging Charles' wife and potentially planning to kill him for both the missus and money also remains a point of emphasis throughout. Hopkins never fails to convince as this very intelligent "know-it-all" with almost all the answers when pressures and obstacles present themselves. Charles is always turned to by Stephen and Bob when a new problem rears its ugly head. But that damned bear (Bart the Bear is recognized as a star as the credits closedand should) just won't go away. Alec Baldwin has that knack for portraying likable assholes, and his Bob is no different here. He sometimes uses his sense of humor to blatantly knock Charles, but his respect for the man never wavers. Stephen's attack is brutal, and the bear's attempts towards Charles and Bob commands serious tension. The location of the film provides much atmosphere because of how detrimental it can be for the duo attempting to survive (the bear and the wilderness/peaks both offer their own challenges). Hopkins' subtly expressive face (particularly the mind's trying to solve problems like when Alec suffers a tough leg injury falling into a "dead fall" meant for bears, or his "makeshift" compass idea; later, that panic that soon fades to disappointment regarding Baldwin's condition is a masterclass of acting) speaks a great deal and it's his responsibility to communicate the situation his character faces. Baldwin needs us to like him so we are unsure of his intent towards Hopkins' life; the ending gives us a tragedy that seems regrettable because it didn't need to end that way. The simple use of a watch (and engravings on it) along with a list with specific handwriting are tools that reinforce the revelation regarding whether or not Charles was right or not regarding Bob and Mickey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men Lost...Find Their Way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kept alive by some witty Mamet-Speak and a stunning backdrop of sharp, beautiful Wilderness Cinematography along with believable Leads, this is quite an enjoyable "lost in the wilderness" Movie within a Modern mode of Class Warfare and Marital Infidelity. It is not an easy mix at times and as our duo duel with barbs, insights, and storytelling things can seem at odds with each other. Its like poker game or barroom banter set in the great outdoors. The ever encroachment of the Kodiak Bear could be read as a metaphor for the impending destruction of each Man's Id. Or maybe its just a way to add some lively Action to the Playwright's pontifications of Money, Lawyers, and Love. It is a quirky Film and the talent involved should be credited because they give this well worn Genre a new angle. In the end it is somewhat satisfying and there is enough here to keep both Audiences interested. Those with the flannel shirts and those with the stuffy shirts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Critic Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiemaexo
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins), a billionaire with photographic memory, and two other men, Robert "Bob" Green (Alec Baldwin), a photographer, and Stephen (Harold Perrineau), his assistant, arrive in a remote North America, along with Charles's much-younger wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson), a fashion model. The group is only there for a photo shoot and staying as guests at a lodge, they later are recruited to another area due to a sick model. After their plane crashes, the men attempt to hike to a more likely search area, only to find that a male Kodiak bear is stalking them. They elude it, but later the bear attacks their camp and kills Stephen. The angles of the movie were spectacular; it made you feel like you were out in the woods. Seeing the actors in this environment makes you want to put on a coat to watch the movie. A very strong performance by all the actors in a film that deals with using bare instincts on fighting wild animals, staying alive from the elements, and morality. I can understand why some of the more modern audience might find that to be a turn-off. The sets and locations alone are worth a rental. The photography is beautiful, the landscape comes alive, and sometimes it steals the picture away from the characters. Very strong performances by Anthony Hopkins, Bart the Bear, and Alec Baldwin, Not only were they great but they were troopers with the set. Anthony Hopkins got a severe case of pneumonia while filming out in the cold; I'm a huge fan so his performance was fantastic he can go from a city guy to survival and make it believable. His character was well portrayed and a flawless performance. Alec Baldwin also did a great job in this movie. (And I can't say that I was a big fan of Alec before this movie) I have only seen him in comedy, but I have a better opinion of him now. Elle McPherson has a small role which she played well and portrayed her character very well. A gripping storyline, fantastic scenery and a real sense of drama and survival, it delivers as an action/adventure film by giving some heart stopping sequences, and it never slows down. The Edge also delivers as a dramatic film, with an ending that is painfully sad, yet satisfying. They portray their characters with honesty, and with a realistic nature that only great actors can accomplish. As the plot twists and the pace picks up, you start to become so involved that you forget time is passing by. I strongly suggest this one to action lovers and to anyone who enjoys a good story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge When stranded in the woods, it's a good idea to throw used tampons into the shrubs to keep bears off your trail. Unfortunately, the marooned men in this thriller are fresh out of soiled feminine napkins. When Charles (Anthony Hopkins) crash lands in the wilderness along side Bob (Alec Baldwin), a man he suspects is having an affair with his wife (Elle MacPherson) and plotting his murder, he must resist the urge to beat him to the punch, because there are more pressing matters. Dwarfing the awkward company and harsh surroundings is a ravenous bear that's trailing them. Putting aside their personal matters, Charles and Bob combine their abilities to combat the Kodiak. Written by David Mamet, The Edge is a taunt tale of male bonding amongst bear attacks. The acting is proficient and the dialogue acute. However, aren't grizzlies more apt to attack burly men in tattered clothes? (Yellow Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The bear is smarter than two of the men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a fairly good action film with some excellent sequences in which a bear stalks and attacks 3 stranded men in the Alaskan wilds. I kept wondering "How did they get that shot?" There are some amazingly good effects. I did wonder whether or not the roar of a bear is like the sounds we were given here. It sounded a little much to me. The bear and Anthony Hopkins are the main stars of the show, and Alec Baldwin does a creditable job with a character that is written to be weak and not very smart. The adventure element is concocted. One can raise many questions about the sequence of events too. Making a big circle in the way they did was very implausible, since they scaled a mountain. In addition, this film follows the usual Hollywood rule that held in the old days and still holds, which is basically to kill off the black man. There must be dozens of similar adventure and war movies that follow this rule. In this case, the black man is an utter weak wimp who does nothing but complain. He is also very stupid. What a horribly written part! Baldwin's character is not far behind. Hopkins' character is at least sensible enough to have some idea of what to do in the wild, even if he ignores the fact that the sun rises in the east, but then it does get cloudy sometimes. With such weak characters, I kept thinking back to earlier adventure movies such as Five Came Back. Were men so wimpy in those old movies? Or is this yet another manifestation of the juvenile characters that seem more frequently to people today's movies? The script telegraphs the key plot points a little too well in the opening sequence. The music at times is too syrupy and grand when more danger and challenge should be in the air. The character arc of Hopkins is only subtly hinted at, because we don't know much about him at the start. I like his line at the end about all of us face serious challenges but we don't know when or what form they are going to take. But I dislike his final line shortly thereafter that the other men died saving his life. Why should he lie? He has confronted himself and nature in his essence. He has even realized that he has little to go back to. He has seen truths, but then he lies. The two men died because they made grievous mistakes in their choices. At best they died bravely or "like men". He might have said "They died like men". The strong point of the movie is not its philosophy. It's the conflict between men and a bear. The conflict between Baldwin and Hopkins over his wealth and his wife didn't really ring true as it was written, although Baldwin did, as I said, quite a good job with the part. Let me elaborate a bit on the above. First, too much is given away at the outset. Low-flying birds can bring down an airplane, and this happens subsequently. There is a bear trap, and, sure enough, it plays a part. Bears become man-killers, we are told, and sure enough, act 2 involves just such a critter. Hopkins is given a watch and a knife and, sure enough, they are important later. It's all too pat. It was evident far before Hopkins said that he would kill the bear that this would have to be done. The line went through my head before he spoke it. Meanwhile the Baldwin character was whining worse than the black man had done earlier, and that guy was so inept that he stabbed himself in the leg -- a deep gash mind you -- while trying to sharpen a piece of wood into a spear. Very smart going, mate. Well, this is really Mamet's fault. He could not write a plausible screenplay with the wilderness elements?? He had to concoct this? Now, was Hopkins so dense that he could not pick up, well before this cozy little trip, that his right hand man was deeply hostile toward him? And that he was going with his wife? This is a man who sees all and remembers all. He's a billionaire. He must have an organization that he created. His wife and Baldwin are far from discreet, but Hopkins is that blind? It's all done by writer Mamet so superficially and so lazily. When Baldwin gets around to trying to kill Hopkins, Hopkins does nothing to stop him from loading the rifle. Why? Meanwhile, Baldwin insists they go outside. Why? And once outside, he hesitates and then backs himself up. Why? He is incredibly weak, so weak that I wonder what Hopkins ever saw in him to have him around, and what his wife saw in him. And having saved the life of Hopkins earlier, you would think that maybe his psychology would change. He might even expect rewards, but no, his bitterness actually increases. Why? Mamet lost it in this one as compared with some of his earlier work. We are dealing here with noir-type betrayals, and they are not easy to handle. In films like Too Late for Tears, Out of the Past, Ace in the Hole, and many others, it takes careful development of the characterizations to "sell" them, i.e., make them believable. Mamet has not done this in The Edge. He has not used the interactions generated by the action scenes to do it either -- the direction of the movie didn't bring it out. So that this aspect of the movie, which is a major part of it, is a failure. The viewer is left grasping for understanding and meaning, rather than feeling these people are real and the events real and the meaning central to human experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat and Contrived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rich man and a fashion photographer fight for survival in the jungles after a plane crash. The story is implausible and the situations are contrived, but the biggest deficiency is the under-developed characters. Hopkins plays what looks like the most miserable billionaire in the world, a lonely and insecure fellow who thinks everybody is out to get his money. In the wilds, he turns out to be a super boy scout, but the character is so aloof that it's hard to feel anything for him. Baldwin is supposed to be larger-than-life, as evidenced by his hearty laughs in response to lame jokes, but his character is also flat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty mainstream stuff with unmet intentions of deep psychological conflict
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge (1997) This is a fun wilderness adventure movie with some terrific acting by both Alec Baldwin (as a spoiled bad boy) and Anthony Hopkins (as a very smart millionaire). They battle of wits, and the fighting of the elements, is fodder for screenwriter David Mamet, who has produced more interesting dialog than this, for sure. The third star is the Kodiak bear, who gets a huge credit line at the end, and who unites, at least sometimes, the two men in the cold isolation of Alaska. But let's face it, as much fun as this is, this is thin going. It even looks a bit like a slightly adult version of a Disney adventure film, with people bonding and conflicting as needed. In fact, if you start comparing this movie to others like it (there are a few), you might even consider the television series "Lost," which is at least more imaginative and full-blooded in its writing. Or just survival in the mountains you might check out "Touching the Void." I just saw the old Spencer Tracy movie "Mountain" this week, and it is a weird precursor to this one (minus the bear). That is, two people facing the elements have very different ideas of morality and of trust. Like that movie, this newer one doesn't explore the conflict of personae, or ethics, very far, giving only what are the obvious differences. That's not enough for a feature length affair. Which brings us back to Baldwin and Hopkins. They are, actually, enough to hold you in for the duration. You really do hope they survive, and if you wince at some of the dialog and at the appearance of bear traps at all the wrong moments, you can get into the drama of it pretty well. And into the scenery. Amazing stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clearly Mamet was never a Boy Scout
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty hard to take this film seriously, much of the time at least. The basic structure of the film is fine, and Hopkins and Baldwin both deliver fine performances. But the survival-related antics these men pull are straight out of a comic book, I think. (Trapping a chipmunk in a cage fashioned out of twigs??? Hilarious!!!) Although Bart the Bear also deserves his top billing, just about every scene he's in is utterly ludicrous. I guess that's not Bart's fault. Maybe his manager should've held out for a better script though. Watch it for the scenery, the machinations of the human characters and the dialog (at both of which Mamet excels), and for Hopkins' acting. And don't take any of the bear- or survival-related stuff seriously. This is not a movie to call to memory when you find yourself lost in the woods....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man vs Man vs Wild
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rasamanjari
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is both a psychological thriller and an authentic, wilderness survival movie. It pits man against the magnificent but harsh Alaskan wilderness, and, at the same time, it also pits man against man in a powerful, primitive struggle over a beautiful woman..a very beautiful woman--Elle Macpherson. Alex Baldwim is excellent as the confident, aggressive, young usurper, always looking for ways to bring down his competition, and Anthony Hopkins is exceptional as the wealthy, intelligent, aristocratic gentleman husband who gracefully endures his attacks while gradually realizing the painful truth. The thing i liked the most about this film is that they both have to depend on each other for survival in the Alaskan wild, while simultaneously dealing with their powerful emotions about each other and the relationship situation. The combination makes this film affect the sensibilities like no other i have seen. Well worth watching. The review alongside the movie poster did not begin to cover this film as it deserves to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harrowing Survival Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anthony Hopkins plays billionaire Charles Morse, a bookish man who is married to a much younger woman(played by Elle McPherson) who is coveted by her photographer(Alec Baldwin) The two men, as well as an assistant(played by Harold Perrineau) are flown into a remote location in the Alaskan wilderness, when they are struck by a flock of birds, causing them to crash in the lake, killing the pilot, and placing the three survivors in a life and death struggle with not only the harsh elements, but a huge Kodiak bear that smells blood... Harrowing adventure drama from writer David Mamet is well directed by Lee Tamahori and acted by the leads, especially Anthony Hopkins, whose transformation from bookish introvert to determined survivalist is believable(they're not mutually exclusive anyway!) Relationship among the men is a bit muddled, especially after the climax, but solid thriller is also compelling and frightening. Not a film for people with a fear of bears...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Edge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scarecrow-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins) is a wealthy man ("with his own plane") who decides to join his supermodel wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson) and her photographic crew to a lodging in the snowy wilderness (of the breathtaking British Columbia mountains and surrounding areas). Charles, Mickey's photographer, Bob (Alec Baldwin), and Bob's assistant, Stephen (Harold Perrineau) go on (what was perceived to be) a small plane ride to a local native's cabin to see if he can transport some film for them but he's on a hunt for bear. Once in the air, birds fly into the plane's propeller, causing them to crash. The pilot killed, the remaining three have to hike it to a closer location of their cabin, but doing so won't be easy thanks to a maneating bear looking to feed its hunger for human flesh. A miscalculation involving "moving south" (Charles uses a paper clip and leaf on water to determine the direction of South following the wind, but a magnetic interference stirs them in a complete circle back to their starting point!), a deep cut on the leg while sharpening a spear (Stephen's "slip" costs him big-time), a bloody rag left on a tree branch (summoning the hungry bear), a nasty attack that shortens the numbers (Stephen never had a prayer), and surviving the elements with little supplies to speak of (matches and the clothes on them; the flares will be needed for later, but they are soon used, too) provide much high drama in this exciting survivalist adventure. Not only the bear's "toying with them" provides suspense, but the idea that Baldwin might be banging Charles' wife and potentially planning to kill him for both the missus and money also remains a point of emphasis throughout. Hopkins never fails to convince as this very intelligent "know-it-all" with almost all the answers when pressures and obstacles present themselves. Charles is always turned to by Stephen and Bob when a new problem rears its ugly head. But that damned bear (Bart the Bear is recognized as a star as the credits closedand should) just won't go away. Alec Baldwin has that knack for portraying likable assholes, and his Bob is no different here. He sometimes uses his sense of humor to blatantly knock Charles, but his respect for the man never wavers. Stephen's attack is brutal, and the bear's attempts towards Charles and Bob commands serious tension. The location of the film provides much atmosphere because of how detrimental it can be for the duo attempting to survive (the bear and the wilderness/peaks both offer their own challenges). Hopkins' subtly expressive face (particularly the mind's trying to solve problems like when Alec suffers a tough leg injury falling into a "dead fall" meant for bears, or his "makeshift" compass idea; later, that panic that soon fades to disappointment regarding Baldwin's condition is a masterclass of acting) speaks a great deal and it's his responsibility to communicate the situation his character faces. Baldwin needs us to like him so we are unsure of his intent towards Hopkins' life; the ending gives us a tragedy that seems regrettable because it didn't need to end that way. The simple use of a watch (and engravings on it) along with a list with specific handwriting are tools that reinforce the revelation regarding whether or not Charles was right or not regarding Bob and Mickey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men Lost...Find Their Way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kept alive by some witty Mamet-Speak and a stunning backdrop of sharp, beautiful Wilderness Cinematography along with believable Leads, this is quite an enjoyable "lost in the wilderness" Movie within a Modern mode of Class Warfare and Marital Infidelity. It is not an easy mix at times and as our duo duel with barbs, insights, and storytelling things can seem at odds with each other. Its like poker game or barroom banter set in the great outdoors. The ever encroachment of the Kodiak Bear could be read as a metaphor for the impending destruction of each Man's Id. Or maybe its just a way to add some lively Action to the Playwright's pontifications of Money, Lawyers, and Love. It is a quirky Film and the talent involved should be credited because they give this well worn Genre a new angle. In the end it is somewhat satisfying and there is enough here to keep both Audiences interested. Those with the flannel shirts and those with the stuffy shirts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Critic Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiemaexo
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins), a billionaire with photographic memory, and two other men, Robert "Bob" Green (Alec Baldwin), a photographer, and Stephen (Harold Perrineau), his assistant, arrive in a remote North America, along with Charles's much-younger wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson), a fashion model. The group is only there for a photo shoot and staying as guests at a lodge, they later are recruited to another area due to a sick model. After their plane crashes, the men attempt to hike to a more likely search area, only to find that a male Kodiak bear is stalking them. They elude it, but later the bear attacks their camp and kills Stephen. The angles of the movie were spectacular; it made you feel like you were out in the woods. Seeing the actors in this environment makes you want to put on a coat to watch the movie. A very strong performance by all the actors in a film that deals with using bare instincts on fighting wild animals, staying alive from the elements, and morality. I can understand why some of the more modern audience might find that to be a turn-off. The sets and locations alone are worth a rental. The photography is beautiful, the landscape comes alive, and sometimes it steals the picture away from the characters. Very strong performances by Anthony Hopkins, Bart the Bear, and Alec Baldwin, Not only were they great but they were troopers with the set. Anthony Hopkins got a severe case of pneumonia while filming out in the cold; I'm a huge fan so his performance was fantastic he can go from a city guy to survival and make it believable. His character was well portrayed and a flawless performance. Alec Baldwin also did a great job in this movie. (And I can't say that I was a big fan of Alec before this movie) I have only seen him in comedy, but I have a better opinion of him now. Elle McPherson has a small role which she played well and portrayed her character very well. A gripping storyline, fantastic scenery and a real sense of drama and survival, it delivers as an action/adventure film by giving some heart stopping sequences, and it never slows down. The Edge also delivers as a dramatic film, with an ending that is painfully sad, yet satisfying. They portray their characters with honesty, and with a realistic nature that only great actors can accomplish. As the plot twists and the pace picks up, you start to become so involved that you forget time is passing by. I strongly suggest this one to action lovers and to anyone who enjoys a good story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge When stranded in the woods, it's a good idea to throw used tampons into the shrubs to keep bears off your trail. Unfortunately, the marooned men in this thriller are fresh out of soiled feminine napkins. When Charles (Anthony Hopkins) crash lands in the wilderness along side Bob (Alec Baldwin), a man he suspects is having an affair with his wife (Elle MacPherson) and plotting his murder, he must resist the urge to beat him to the punch, because there are more pressing matters. Dwarfing the awkward company and harsh surroundings is a ravenous bear that's trailing them. Putting aside their personal matters, Charles and Bob combine their abilities to combat the Kodiak. Written by David Mamet, The Edge is a taunt tale of male bonding amongst bear attacks. The acting is proficient and the dialogue acute. However, aren't grizzlies more apt to attack burly men in tattered clothes? (Yellow Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The bear is smarter than two of the men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a fairly good action film with some excellent sequences in which a bear stalks and attacks 3 stranded men in the Alaskan wilds. I kept wondering "How did they get that shot?" There are some amazingly good effects. I did wonder whether or not the roar of a bear is like the sounds we were given here. It sounded a little much to me. The bear and Anthony Hopkins are the main stars of the show, and Alec Baldwin does a creditable job with a character that is written to be weak and not very smart. The adventure element is concocted. One can raise many questions about the sequence of events too. Making a big circle in the way they did was very implausible, since they scaled a mountain. In addition, this film follows the usual Hollywood rule that held in the old days and still holds, which is basically to kill off the black man. There must be dozens of similar adventure and war movies that follow this rule. In this case, the black man is an utter weak wimp who does nothing but complain. He is also very stupid. What a horribly written part! Baldwin's character is not far behind. Hopkins' character is at least sensible enough to have some idea of what to do in the wild, even if he ignores the fact that the sun rises in the east, but then it does get cloudy sometimes. With such weak characters, I kept thinking back to earlier adventure movies such as Five Came Back. Were men so wimpy in those old movies? Or is this yet another manifestation of the juvenile characters that seem more frequently to people today's movies? The script telegraphs the key plot points a little too well in the opening sequence. The music at times is too syrupy and grand when more danger and challenge should be in the air. The character arc of Hopkins is only subtly hinted at, because we don't know much about him at the start. I like his line at the end about all of us face serious challenges but we don't know when or what form they are going to take. But I dislike his final line shortly thereafter that the other men died saving his life. Why should he lie? He has confronted himself and nature in his essence. He has even realized that he has little to go back to. He has seen truths, but then he lies. The two men died because they made grievous mistakes in their choices. At best they died bravely or "like men". He might have said "They died like men". The strong point of the movie is not its philosophy. It's the conflict between men and a bear. The conflict between Baldwin and Hopkins over his wealth and his wife didn't really ring true as it was written, although Baldwin did, as I said, quite a good job with the part. Let me elaborate a bit on the above. First, too much is given away at the outset. Low-flying birds can bring down an airplane, and this happens subsequently. There is a bear trap, and, sure enough, it plays a part. Bears become man-killers, we are told, and sure enough, act 2 involves just such a critter. Hopkins is given a watch and a knife and, sure enough, they are important later. It's all too pat. It was evident far before Hopkins said that he would kill the bear that this would have to be done. The line went through my head before he spoke it. Meanwhile the Baldwin character was whining worse than the black man had done earlier, and that guy was so inept that he stabbed himself in the leg -- a deep gash mind you -- while trying to sharpen a piece of wood into a spear. Very smart going, mate. Well, this is really Mamet's fault. He could not write a plausible screenplay with the wilderness elements?? He had to concoct this? Now, was Hopkins so dense that he could not pick up, well before this cozy little trip, that his right hand man was deeply hostile toward him? And that he was going with his wife? This is a man who sees all and remembers all. He's a billionaire. He must have an organization that he created. His wife and Baldwin are far from discreet, but Hopkins is that blind? It's all done by writer Mamet so superficially and so lazily. When Baldwin gets around to trying to kill Hopkins, Hopkins does nothing to stop him from loading the rifle. Why? Meanwhile, Baldwin insists they go outside. Why? And once outside, he hesitates and then backs himself up. Why? He is incredibly weak, so weak that I wonder what Hopkins ever saw in him to have him around, and what his wife saw in him. And having saved the life of Hopkins earlier, you would think that maybe his psychology would change. He might even expect rewards, but no, his bitterness actually increases. Why? Mamet lost it in this one as compared with some of his earlier work. We are dealing here with noir-type betrayals, and they are not easy to handle. In films like Too Late for Tears, Out of the Past, Ace in the Hole, and many others, it takes careful development of the characterizations to "sell" them, i.e., make them believable. Mamet has not done this in The Edge. He has not used the interactions generated by the action scenes to do it either -- the direction of the movie didn't bring it out. So that this aspect of the movie, which is a major part of it, is a failure. The viewer is left grasping for understanding and meaning, rather than feeling these people are real and the events real and the meaning central to human experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat and Contrived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rich man and a fashion photographer fight for survival in the jungles after a plane crash. The story is implausible and the situations are contrived, but the biggest deficiency is the under-developed characters. Hopkins plays what looks like the most miserable billionaire in the world, a lonely and insecure fellow who thinks everybody is out to get his money. In the wilds, he turns out to be a super boy scout, but the character is so aloof that it's hard to feel anything for him. Baldwin is supposed to be larger-than-life, as evidenced by his hearty laughs in response to lame jokes, but his character is also flat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty mainstream stuff with unmet intentions of deep psychological conflict
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge (1997) This is a fun wilderness adventure movie with some terrific acting by both Alec Baldwin (as a spoiled bad boy) and Anthony Hopkins (as a very smart millionaire). They battle of wits, and the fighting of the elements, is fodder for screenwriter David Mamet, who has produced more interesting dialog than this, for sure. The third star is the Kodiak bear, who gets a huge credit line at the end, and who unites, at least sometimes, the two men in the cold isolation of Alaska. But let's face it, as much fun as this is, this is thin going. It even looks a bit like a slightly adult version of a Disney adventure film, with people bonding and conflicting as needed. In fact, if you start comparing this movie to others like it (there are a few), you might even consider the television series "Lost," which is at least more imaginative and full-blooded in its writing. Or just survival in the mountains you might check out "Touching the Void." I just saw the old Spencer Tracy movie "Mountain" this week, and it is a weird precursor to this one (minus the bear). That is, two people facing the elements have very different ideas of morality and of trust. Like that movie, this newer one doesn't explore the conflict of personae, or ethics, very far, giving only what are the obvious differences. That's not enough for a feature length affair. Which brings us back to Baldwin and Hopkins. They are, actually, enough to hold you in for the duration. You really do hope they survive, and if you wince at some of the dialog and at the appearance of bear traps at all the wrong moments, you can get into the drama of it pretty well. And into the scenery. Amazing stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clearly Mamet was never a Boy Scout
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty hard to take this film seriously, much of the time at least. The basic structure of the film is fine, and Hopkins and Baldwin both deliver fine performances. But the survival-related antics these men pull are straight out of a comic book, I think. (Trapping a chipmunk in a cage fashioned out of twigs??? Hilarious!!!) Although Bart the Bear also deserves his top billing, just about every scene he's in is utterly ludicrous. I guess that's not Bart's fault. Maybe his manager should've held out for a better script though. Watch it for the scenery, the machinations of the human characters and the dialog (at both of which Mamet excels), and for Hopkins' acting. And don't take any of the bear- or survival-related stuff seriously. This is not a movie to call to memory when you find yourself lost in the woods....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man vs Man vs Wild
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rasamanjari
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is both a psychological thriller and an authentic, wilderness survival movie. It pits man against the magnificent but harsh Alaskan wilderness, and, at the same time, it also pits man against man in a powerful, primitive struggle over a beautiful woman..a very beautiful woman--Elle Macpherson. Alex Baldwim is excellent as the confident, aggressive, young usurper, always looking for ways to bring down his competition, and Anthony Hopkins is exceptional as the wealthy, intelligent, aristocratic gentleman husband who gracefully endures his attacks while gradually realizing the painful truth. The thing i liked the most about this film is that they both have to depend on each other for survival in the Alaskan wild, while simultaneously dealing with their powerful emotions about each other and the relationship situation. The combination makes this film affect the sensibilities like no other i have seen. Well worth watching. The review alongside the movie poster did not begin to cover this film as it deserves to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harrowing Survival Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anthony Hopkins plays billionaire Charles Morse, a bookish man who is married to a much younger woman(played by Elle McPherson) who is coveted by her photographer(Alec Baldwin) The two men, as well as an assistant(played by Harold Perrineau) are flown into a remote location in the Alaskan wilderness, when they are struck by a flock of birds, causing them to crash in the lake, killing the pilot, and placing the three survivors in a life and death struggle with not only the harsh elements, but a huge Kodiak bear that smells blood... Harrowing adventure drama from writer David Mamet is well directed by Lee Tamahori and acted by the leads, especially Anthony Hopkins, whose transformation from bookish introvert to determined survivalist is believable(they're not mutually exclusive anyway!) Relationship among the men is a bit muddled, especially after the climax, but solid thriller is also compelling and frightening. Not a film for people with a fear of bears...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Edge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scarecrow-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins) is a wealthy man ("with his own plane") who decides to join his supermodel wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson) and her photographic crew to a lodging in the snowy wilderness (of the breathtaking British Columbia mountains and surrounding areas). Charles, Mickey's photographer, Bob (Alec Baldwin), and Bob's assistant, Stephen (Harold Perrineau) go on (what was perceived to be) a small plane ride to a local native's cabin to see if he can transport some film for them but he's on a hunt for bear. Once in the air, birds fly into the plane's propeller, causing them to crash. The pilot killed, the remaining three have to hike it to a closer location of their cabin, but doing so won't be easy thanks to a maneating bear looking to feed its hunger for human flesh. A miscalculation involving "moving south" (Charles uses a paper clip and leaf on water to determine the direction of South following the wind, but a magnetic interference stirs them in a complete circle back to their starting point!), a deep cut on the leg while sharpening a spear (Stephen's "slip" costs him big-time), a bloody rag left on a tree branch (summoning the hungry bear), a nasty attack that shortens the numbers (Stephen never had a prayer), and surviving the elements with little supplies to speak of (matches and the clothes on them; the flares will be needed for later, but they are soon used, too) provide much high drama in this exciting survivalist adventure. Not only the bear's "toying with them" provides suspense, but the idea that Baldwin might be banging Charles' wife and potentially planning to kill him for both the missus and money also remains a point of emphasis throughout. Hopkins never fails to convince as this very intelligent "know-it-all" with almost all the answers when pressures and obstacles present themselves. Charles is always turned to by Stephen and Bob when a new problem rears its ugly head. But that damned bear (Bart the Bear is recognized as a star as the credits closedand should) just won't go away. Alec Baldwin has that knack for portraying likable assholes, and his Bob is no different here. He sometimes uses his sense of humor to blatantly knock Charles, but his respect for the man never wavers. Stephen's attack is brutal, and the bear's attempts towards Charles and Bob commands serious tension. The location of the film provides much atmosphere because of how detrimental it can be for the duo attempting to survive (the bear and the wilderness/peaks both offer their own challenges). Hopkins' subtly expressive face (particularly the mind's trying to solve problems like when Alec suffers a tough leg injury falling into a "dead fall" meant for bears, or his "makeshift" compass idea; later, that panic that soon fades to disappointment regarding Baldwin's condition is a masterclass of acting) speaks a great deal and it's his responsibility to communicate the situation his character faces. Baldwin needs us to like him so we are unsure of his intent towards Hopkins' life; the ending gives us a tragedy that seems regrettable because it didn't need to end that way. The simple use of a watch (and engravings on it) along with a list with specific handwriting are tools that reinforce the revelation regarding whether or not Charles was right or not regarding Bob and Mickey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men Lost...Find Their Way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kept alive by some witty Mamet-Speak and a stunning backdrop of sharp, beautiful Wilderness Cinematography along with believable Leads, this is quite an enjoyable "lost in the wilderness" Movie within a Modern mode of Class Warfare and Marital Infidelity. It is not an easy mix at times and as our duo duel with barbs, insights, and storytelling things can seem at odds with each other. Its like poker game or barroom banter set in the great outdoors. The ever encroachment of the Kodiak Bear could be read as a metaphor for the impending destruction of each Man's Id. Or maybe its just a way to add some lively Action to the Playwright's pontifications of Money, Lawyers, and Love. It is a quirky Film and the talent involved should be credited because they give this well worn Genre a new angle. In the end it is somewhat satisfying and there is enough here to keep both Audiences interested. Those with the flannel shirts and those with the stuffy shirts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Critic Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiemaexo
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Charles Morse (Anthony Hopkins), a billionaire with photographic memory, and two other men, Robert "Bob" Green (Alec Baldwin), a photographer, and Stephen (Harold Perrineau), his assistant, arrive in a remote North America, along with Charles's much-younger wife, Mickey (Elle Macpherson), a fashion model. The group is only there for a photo shoot and staying as guests at a lodge, they later are recruited to another area due to a sick model. After their plane crashes, the men attempt to hike to a more likely search area, only to find that a male Kodiak bear is stalking them. They elude it, but later the bear attacks their camp and kills Stephen. The angles of the movie were spectacular; it made you feel like you were out in the woods. Seeing the actors in this environment makes you want to put on a coat to watch the movie. A very strong performance by all the actors in a film that deals with using bare instincts on fighting wild animals, staying alive from the elements, and morality. I can understand why some of the more modern audience might find that to be a turn-off. The sets and locations alone are worth a rental. The photography is beautiful, the landscape comes alive, and sometimes it steals the picture away from the characters. Very strong performances by Anthony Hopkins, Bart the Bear, and Alec Baldwin, Not only were they great but they were troopers with the set. Anthony Hopkins got a severe case of pneumonia while filming out in the cold; I'm a huge fan so his performance was fantastic he can go from a city guy to survival and make it believable. His character was well portrayed and a flawless performance. Alec Baldwin also did a great job in this movie. (And I can't say that I was a big fan of Alec before this movie) I have only seen him in comedy, but I have a better opinion of him now. Elle McPherson has a small role which she played well and portrayed her character very well. A gripping storyline, fantastic scenery and a real sense of drama and survival, it delivers as an action/adventure film by giving some heart stopping sequences, and it never slows down. The Edge also delivers as a dramatic film, with an ending that is painfully sad, yet satisfying. They portray their characters with honesty, and with a realistic nature that only great actors can accomplish. As the plot twists and the pace picks up, you start to become so involved that you forget time is passing by. I strongly suggest this one to action lovers and to anyone who enjoys a good story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge When stranded in the woods, it's a good idea to throw used tampons into the shrubs to keep bears off your trail. Unfortunately, the marooned men in this thriller are fresh out of soiled feminine napkins. When Charles (Anthony Hopkins) crash lands in the wilderness along side Bob (Alec Baldwin), a man he suspects is having an affair with his wife (Elle MacPherson) and plotting his murder, he must resist the urge to beat him to the punch, because there are more pressing matters. Dwarfing the awkward company and harsh surroundings is a ravenous bear that's trailing them. Putting aside their personal matters, Charles and Bob combine their abilities to combat the Kodiak. Written by David Mamet, The Edge is a taunt tale of male bonding amongst bear attacks. The acting is proficient and the dialogue acute. However, aren't grizzlies more apt to attack burly men in tattered clothes? (Yellow Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The bear is smarter than two of the men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a fairly good action film with some excellent sequences in which a bear stalks and attacks 3 stranded men in the Alaskan wilds. I kept wondering "How did they get that shot?" There are some amazingly good effects. I did wonder whether or not the roar of a bear is like the sounds we were given here. It sounded a little much to me. The bear and Anthony Hopkins are the main stars of the show, and Alec Baldwin does a creditable job with a character that is written to be weak and not very smart. The adventure element is concocted. One can raise many questions about the sequence of events too. Making a big circle in the way they did was very implausible, since they scaled a mountain. In addition, this film follows the usual Hollywood rule that held in the old days and still holds, which is basically to kill off the black man. There must be dozens of similar adventure and war movies that follow this rule. In this case, the black man is an utter weak wimp who does nothing but complain. He is also very stupid. What a horribly written part! Baldwin's character is not far behind. Hopkins' character is at least sensible enough to have some idea of what to do in the wild, even if he ignores the fact that the sun rises in the east, but then it does get cloudy sometimes. With such weak characters, I kept thinking back to earlier adventure movies such as Five Came Back. Were men so wimpy in those old movies? Or is this yet another manifestation of the juvenile characters that seem more frequently to people today's movies? The script telegraphs the key plot points a little too well in the opening sequence. The music at times is too syrupy and grand when more danger and challenge should be in the air. The character arc of Hopkins is only subtly hinted at, because we don't know much about him at the start. I like his line at the end about all of us face serious challenges but we don't know when or what form they are going to take. But I dislike his final line shortly thereafter that the other men died saving his life. Why should he lie? He has confronted himself and nature in his essence. He has even realized that he has little to go back to. He has seen truths, but then he lies. The two men died because they made grievous mistakes in their choices. At best they died bravely or "like men". He might have said "They died like men". The strong point of the movie is not its philosophy. It's the conflict between men and a bear. The conflict between Baldwin and Hopkins over his wealth and his wife didn't really ring true as it was written, although Baldwin did, as I said, quite a good job with the part. Let me elaborate a bit on the above. First, too much is given away at the outset. Low-flying birds can bring down an airplane, and this happens subsequently. There is a bear trap, and, sure enough, it plays a part. Bears become man-killers, we are told, and sure enough, act 2 involves just such a critter. Hopkins is given a watch and a knife and, sure enough, they are important later. It's all too pat. It was evident far before Hopkins said that he would kill the bear that this would have to be done. The line went through my head before he spoke it. Meanwhile the Baldwin character was whining worse than the black man had done earlier, and that guy was so inept that he stabbed himself in the leg -- a deep gash mind you -- while trying to sharpen a piece of wood into a spear. Very smart going, mate. Well, this is really Mamet's fault. He could not write a plausible screenplay with the wilderness elements?? He had to concoct this? Now, was Hopkins so dense that he could not pick up, well before this cozy little trip, that his right hand man was deeply hostile toward him? And that he was going with his wife? This is a man who sees all and remembers all. He's a billionaire. He must have an organization that he created. His wife and Baldwin are far from discreet, but Hopkins is that blind? It's all done by writer Mamet so superficially and so lazily. When Baldwin gets around to trying to kill Hopkins, Hopkins does nothing to stop him from loading the rifle. Why? Meanwhile, Baldwin insists they go outside. Why? And once outside, he hesitates and then backs himself up. Why? He is incredibly weak, so weak that I wonder what Hopkins ever saw in him to have him around, and what his wife saw in him. And having saved the life of Hopkins earlier, you would think that maybe his psychology would change. He might even expect rewards, but no, his bitterness actually increases. Why? Mamet lost it in this one as compared with some of his earlier work. We are dealing here with noir-type betrayals, and they are not easy to handle. In films like Too Late for Tears, Out of the Past, Ace in the Hole, and many others, it takes careful development of the characterizations to "sell" them, i.e., make them believable. Mamet has not done this in The Edge. He has not used the interactions generated by the action scenes to do it either -- the direction of the movie didn't bring it out. So that this aspect of the movie, which is a major part of it, is a failure. The viewer is left grasping for understanding and meaning, rather than feeling these people are real and the events real and the meaning central to human experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flat and Contrived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rich man and a fashion photographer fight for survival in the jungles after a plane crash. The story is implausible and the situations are contrived, but the biggest deficiency is the under-developed characters. Hopkins plays what looks like the most miserable billionaire in the world, a lonely and insecure fellow who thinks everybody is out to get his money. In the wilds, he turns out to be a super boy scout, but the character is so aloof that it's hard to feel anything for him. Baldwin is supposed to be larger-than-life, as evidenced by his hearty laughs in response to lame jokes, but his character is also flat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty mainstream stuff with unmet intentions of deep psychological conflict
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Edge (1997) This is a fun wilderness adventure movie with some terrific acting by both Alec Baldwin (as a spoiled bad boy) and Anthony Hopkins (as a very smart millionaire). They battle of wits, and the fighting of the elements, is fodder for screenwriter David Mamet, who has produced more interesting dialog than this, for sure. The third star is the Kodiak bear, who gets a huge credit line at the end, and who unites, at least sometimes, the two men in the cold isolation of Alaska. But let's face it, as much fun as this is, this is thin going. It even looks a bit like a slightly adult version of a Disney adventure film, with people bonding and conflicting as needed. In fact, if you start comparing this movie to others like it (there are a few), you might even consider the television series "Lost," which is at least more imaginative and full-blooded in its writing. Or just survival in the mountains you might check out "Touching the Void." I just saw the old Spencer Tracy movie "Mountain" this week, and it is a weird precursor to this one (minus the bear). That is, two people facing the elements have very different ideas of morality and of trust. Like that movie, this newer one doesn't explore the conflict of personae, or ethics, very far, giving only what are the obvious differences. That's not enough for a feature length affair. Which brings us back to Baldwin and Hopkins. They are, actually, enough to hold you in for the duration. You really do hope they survive, and if you wince at some of the dialog and at the appearance of bear traps at all the wrong moments, you can get into the drama of it pretty well. And into the scenery. Amazing stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clearly Mamet was never a Boy Scout
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty hard to take this film seriously, much of the time at least. The basic structure of the film is fine, and Hopkins and Baldwin both deliver fine performances. But the survival-related antics these men pull are straight out of a comic book, I think. (Trapping a chipmunk in a cage fashioned out of twigs??? Hilarious!!!) Although Bart the Bear also deserves his top billing, just about every scene he's in is utterly ludicrous. I guess that's not Bart's fault. Maybe his manager should've held out for a better script though. Watch it for the scenery, the machinations of the human characters and the dialog (at both of which Mamet excels), and for Hopkins' acting. And don't take any of the bear- or survival-related stuff seriously. This is not a movie to call to memory when you find yourself lost in the woods....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Man vs Man vs Wild
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rasamanjari
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is both a psychological thriller and an authentic, wilderness survival movie. It pits man against the magnificent but harsh Alaskan wilderness, and, at the same time, it also pits man against man in a powerful, primitive struggle over a beautiful woman..a very beautiful woman--Elle Macpherson. Alex Baldwim is excellent as the confident, aggressive, young usurper, always looking for ways to bring down his competition, and Anthony Hopkins is exceptional as the wealthy, intelligent, aristocratic gentleman husband who gracefully endures his attacks while gradually realizing the painful truth. The thing i liked the most about this film is that they both have to depend on each other for survival in the Alaskan wild, while simultaneously dealing with their powerful emotions about each other and the relationship situation. The combination makes this film affect the sensibilities like no other i have seen. Well worth watching. The review alongside the movie poster did not begin to cover this film as it deserves to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
