<filme>
 <id>
  336
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119906
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Brincando com a Morte
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Stripped of his medical license after performing an operation while high on amphetamines, famed LA surgeon Dr Eugene Sands abandons his former life only to find himself crossing paths with ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Stripped of his medical license after performing an operation while high on amphetamines, famed LA surgeon Dr Eugene Sands abandons his former life only to find himself crossing paths with Raymond Blossom, an infamous counterfeiter. Employed as a "gun-shot doctor" when Raymond's associates cannot risk visiting a hospital, Eugene is lured deep into the criminal world and becomes entangled with his boss's girlfriend.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   doctor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   surgeon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drug addiction
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gay slur
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Andy Wilson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Mark Haskell Smith
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   David Duchovny
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Timothy Hutton
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Angelina Jolie
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What A Let-Down!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing good comes out of "Playing God," a pointless Faustian medical thriller anesthetized with clich&eacute;s about a busted surgeon whose synthetic heroin habit lands him in with the dregs of the Los Angeles underworld. As "X-Files" actor David Duchovny's first starring role, this mediocre melodrama about redemption and retribution is less than scintillating. Actually, it is downright embarrassing. Ineptly directed and predictably scripted, "Playing God" penalizes both its rising star and moviegoers with implausible plot twists, cornball situations, and klutzy villains. Perhaps if the filmmakers had taken their straight, sober-minded drama and played it as broad comedy the film might have been more entertaining and less moronic. The Mark Haskell Smith screenplay is the stuff of which pulp fiction classics are created. Blazing shoot-outs, careening car chases, smart-aleck dialogue, eccentric criminals, and a blast-from-the-past soundtrack, featuring pop tunes such as the Bee Gee's "Jive Talking," flesh out what essentially constitutes a thin, one-dimensional character study. Under Andy Wilson's lackluster directing, these solid elements make for a soggy saga. A graduate of British TV shows such as "Cracker," Wilson never generates the adrenaline rush or visceral thrills that "Playing God" desperately needs to slam it into hyperkinetic overdrive. The filmmakers plunge their hapless hero into harm's way, but he never appears to be in real jeopardy. Wilson and Smith strive to make the murderous antics in their storyline appear surreal, but these results are hopelessly farcical. Especially annoying is Wilson's obvious video-editing style that employs geometric wipes as transitional bridges between episodes. As a doctor who has fallen from on high, Eugene Sands (David Duchovny) spends his time now getting high. What should qualify as cinematic irony in Smith's script winds up as comical incongruity. One night while he's scoring his junk in a dive of an L.A. bar, Sands witnesses a brutal shooting. When nobody calls 911, Sands intervenes and uses his ingenuity to save the wounded man. As it turns out, the poor slob worked for international smuggler Raymond Blossom (Timothy Hutton). Blossom is a wacky psycho who'd double-cross his own mother on the flip of a coin as well as a fashion designer's nightmare. Sands finds himself suddenly being smothered by Blossom's offer of works and drugs. The young, disadvantaged doctor doesn't know quite what to think. Blossom requires Sands' considerable medical talents to save a Russian hit-man who has information vital to Blossom's criminal interests. Initially, despite some misgivings, Sands agrees to perform the surgery and pocket a cool $10-thousand dollars. Before Sands can cruise into the sunset, a scheming, Dagwood Bumstead-esque FBI agent (Michael Massee) recruits Sands as his material witness to back up the person working undercover in Blossom's motley gang of Metallica rejects. Meanwhile, Blossom's sultry moll Claire (Angelina Jolie) complicates matters. Initially, she admires Sands, but she doesn't trust him. Things go incredibly wrong for everybody when a gang of vengeful Russian hit men invade Blossom's posh premises. They gun down one of Blossom's henchmen and put a bullet through Claire's chest. Before "Playing God" grinds predictably to its harebrained conclusion, the movie has Claire and Sands become lovers. Everything in Smith's script hangs on sudden reversals that are more stultifying than startling. Most ridiculous is Sands' unconvincing metamorphosis from a drugged out, self-depreciating loser to a resourceful, jaw-clenched action hero. Sands' fight with the sharp-shooting show-off Cyril (Andrew Tiernan) in a car is particularly unrealistic. Wilson's efforts to make "Playing God" different are doomed by his derivative approach. He bungles what should have been a minor film noir thriller. The story comes apart early on because the chain of events lacks dramatic cohesion. The final car chase starts out promisingly. Blossom and Claire dive into a truck, and as Sands follows them, two identical trucks breeze into the picture on either side of Blossom's ride. Sadly, Wilson does nothing original here, and the rest of the chase is a yawner. Nothing exciting occurs probably because their low budget couldn't afford any car crashes. The shoot-outs are staged with little panache. Most jarring of all is the surgery vignette enacted on a pool tale in an isolated hillbilly biker bar where Sands doctors the wounded Claire. Meantime, the FBI agents are so incompetent that a couple of brainless bad-guy buffoons can smash into their safe house and blast them into oblivion with little difficulty. The cast struggles with Smith's pseudo-cut dialogue that calls attention to the preposterous nature of the script. In the middle of the climactic car chase, Hutton's villain berates his struggling Claire for trying to disrupt the big auto chase. When movies indulge in self-mockery, you know that you're in trouble as an audience member. Presumably, by letting the characters poke fun at the plot twists, Wilson and Smith both hoped to distract spectators from the contrived quality of the story. Their well-intended attempts backfire miserably, and "Playing God" looks goofy. As the good guy hero who realizes the error of his ways, Duchovny maintains a poker face throughout the laughable proceedings. The filmmakers seem more intent on endorsing a didactic, anti-narcotics message than consistency of character. "Playing God" might have played better had Wilson and Smith kept their outlandish hero more strung out and challenged than straightened out and scrupulous. Duchovny's voice-over narration in the style of the old film noir detective thrillers seems more heavy-handed than handy. Jolie does little more than look pretty and pout her abundant lips. The movie takes a time-out to let the hero and the heroine bond with each other without shedding their clothes. As Sands' scumbag foe, Hutton drums up pathetic nastiness. Credit composer Richard Hartley with contributing a bouncy theme for the film. Die-hard "X-Files" fans beware: Scrub this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cross Gender Popcorn Picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underrated action movie that cannot escape that late twentieth century style of combining violent thrills and hard-boiled criminals with a patina of aloof detachment and self consciousness. Sometimes it works well (Tarantino/Rodriguez/Rami) but it is a tricky conceit and you have to be a talent to pull it off. Often the style fails miserably, but not here. While not in the same league as films directed by the above mentioned, this one has enough attraction to keep it from failing. It is an entertaining romp with a good story and is not brought down by some soggy script development and a couple of over the top, completely out there, characters (F.B.I. Agent and some assorted cartoon villains). Overall this one is overlooked as one of the better of this type of thing, a viewer-friendly cross gender popcorn picture, and is worth a view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    94 minutes you'll never get back...if you can stay awake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    excalibur212
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring movies i've seen in a long time, with a story that never really takes off, and a plot that goes nowhere, makes no sense, and can be summarized in one line. The only reason i even watched it was because i was having trouble sleeping, bored, and it was on a "2 for 1" Blu-Ray with "Color of Night" with Bruce Willis and Jane March (a GREAT B-movie, that is one of those it's so bad it's good...highly recommended and underrated!). I would never have paid to watch this movie or even taken time to download it for free...i can't imagine who would. I never understood why some actors have a career (David Duchovny, Kevin Cline, Kevin Spacey) who can't even act and deliver all their lines like they're stoned or asleep, in every single movie they're in. I guess they have good agents. Funny to see Angelina Jolie before she got all buffed and toned; her face actually reminds me of Christina Ricci in a strange way, without the toning and slimmed cheeks. I found nothing in this movie believable, including the strange casting choices (is Timothy's Hutton's character supposed to be bi/gay, because he certainly gives that vibe...i have never seen another movie with him in it either, and can't say i'd desire to). Basically no point to watch this movie unless you're having trouble sleeping, or out of curiosity because you bought the Color of Night Blu-Ray. Nuff said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Backyard of Baywatch (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know there aren't any ties between Baywatch and this movie. Except that they are shot in California, and more exactly in LA and its surroundings. Those locations struck me strongly while watching this movie. The audience moves as well in downtown than in the country, alternating beach and forest. The views you can find here complete the dreamy, cool ones of Baywatch, and even I didn't go there, I think this movie offers a good picture of the real LA. And really, I don't like very much this environment for a living and I prefer the San Francisco area. Now, the story is original but the gimmick (a doctor for healing thugs) is too much used. After the first one, the script becomes a collection of what-if: what-if the doctor visits junk heads, what if the doctor cures the wife's boss, etc.. Then, I am perplexed with the cast: Hutton has really no charisma for a nutty and violent boss. On the contrary, Jolie and above all, Duchvony are excellent. I really appreciate Duchovny, because he is a tall man but he is also quiet. He knows what he wants but he doesn't speak a lot. I like his humor, dry, detached that fits well with his personality. I'am sure that without this hot ticket, this movie would be actually left in limbs. NB: my trailer proposes a love scene between the two but it has been cut from the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lame but Angelina was cute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princessadorable
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall the movie was fairly lame....I was doing dishes while I watched it... I only watched it because Angelina Jolie was in it. The movie could have been better. The idea for the movie was excellent, which is why I'm sad this movie was such a bore. A doctor gets his license taken from him when he does a surgery under narcotics and then starts working for gangs as their doctor. That last sentence I just wrote was the movie, so if you read that sentence, congratulations...you saw the movie!! Angelina was 7/10 in this movie. She is cute, but not stunning. Her face is a full.. looks healthier than she does now, but in the movie it was a bit too full for my taste. Her lips are still very juicy and kissable in this movie. Overall 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave Robinson (dave@under-five-eight.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Duchovney creates a role that he was to replicate somewhat in Californication - the troubled talent. And it is a role he plays well. This thriller starts off at a good speed and carries you through to the end. Timothy Hutton plays a fine villain and Angelina Jolie pouts. The story of a disgraced doctor finding his way into a criminal world is well scripted. Drug addiction and a desire for the sultry Jolie mix a heady cocktail. Unfortunately towards the end the story gets a little weaker and the relationships between villains and the FBI is muddled and rushed as if it was created only to develop the final scene. But, that aside, a movie worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Duchovny way too cool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mathmaniac
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into the experience of watching this movie expecting very little. I wanted to see the movie ever since I saw the preview for it years ago. I wasn't even aware that Angelina Jolie was in this. I'm not a great fan of David Duchovny. Timothy Hutton I expected to play his usual 'charming criminal role' and not do much more. That said, I was truly pleasantly surprised. The film had a nice even pace, lots of blood-spattering gun play and very little sex. In fact, I don't recall Angelina Jolie planting those huge lips of hers on anybody. Hmmm. David Duchovny played his part to perfection. Next to Angelina Jolie, his slouching casual self, muted by his dope habit, could have easily been a drooling fool captivated by her 'loose woman' persona. Instead, befitting an ultra-cool guy with years of education and socialization behind him, he turned it way down and was the cool hipster dealing with really evil hipsters who, like himself, always had some drugs in a pocket or the glove compartment. And like a cool hipster, he naturally kept encountering more and more cool hipsters. Like the bikers on the road who turn out to be allies when he is on the run. He had great lines, as did Timothy Hutton. He showed a mastery of timing, as did Timothy Hutton. Angelina kind of passed from man to man, looking beautiful but NOT having great lines and not having much of a history. I am glad I ordered this film from Amazon and finally got to see it. It was satisfying if you like any of the aforementioned actors. I liked Angelina Jolie in this film and I usually don't. She just looked good - good enough to make men want her but not interesting enough for anyone to want to get to know her.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Timothy Hutton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yesterday I watched this movie on television and I'm not very happy about it.Script can pass as OK but other things can't.First,director Andy Wilson didn't do nothing special,so ordinary directing with few flaws.Second,casting is not good.David Duchovny doesn't have anything to be a leading actor in this movie.That scene when he raises his voice to say something is more funny then it is authoritative.He's very poor actor and his highest achievement are X-Files.Angelina Jolie also nothing,zero,bad.Why did she won Oscar?The way she acted is easy and that role could do any other actress.Only Timothy Hutton left some impression on me.He's mean and that suits him right.He can be good guy and bad too.He's the reason this movie can pass.Because of Hutton 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Credible Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebigeasy555
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Duchovny plays the lead role in this film.Now a lot of people upon finding that fact out wouldn't even bother watching it.Very unfair to say the least.David made his name on the x-files and is a decent actor. Dr Eugene Sands(Duchovny)is a drug addicted doctor struck off for malpractice.By sheer accident he becomes a private doctor for criminal millionaire Raymond Blossom.However the FBI take an interest in using Eugene to snare Blossom. Angelina Jolie is cast in the supporting role of clare-the gangsters moll.She puts in a solid performance. Timothy Hutton playing Blossom is superb and immersed himself deeply into his character. Duchovny himself isn't as bad as many people would think and in the end i would rate his performance his credible.His familiar monotonous tone and straight face is present but dosen't detract too much from the film
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    playing badly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to believe that in 1997 David Duchovny was at the top of his fame, with X-Files, one of the best sci-fi series ever, being at the top of the glory. Nine years later he is almost forgotten, and his tentatives to make it on the big screen failed miserably. I cannot even explain why, he is a fair actor, but probably his moment of fame cast him in a eternal role that takes big talent to break from. At the same time Angelina Jolie was much less known, and she was really lucky that a film like 'Playing God' did not led her career into a dead-end. Fortunately for her, 'The Bone Collector' and 'Girl, Interrupted' were waiting beyond the corner, and when Lara Croft came, her career was launched. There is not too much to be told about this film. It's the only big screen film of Andy Wilson, and there must be a reason. All is banal and most of what happens on the screen expected in this story of an ex-doctor who saves the life of a shooting victim in a bar only to find himself working for the mob. The off-screen voice is especially bad, with a moralistic text that kills any shade of cinematographic experience from the film. You probably will not meet the film but in DVD rental stores, or on TV. Try to look for something better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What A Let-Down!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing good comes out of "Playing God," a pointless Faustian medical thriller anesthetized with clich&eacute;s about a busted surgeon whose synthetic heroin habit lands him in with the dregs of the Los Angeles underworld. As "X-Files" actor David Duchovny's first starring role, this mediocre melodrama about redemption and retribution is less than scintillating. Actually, it is downright embarrassing. Ineptly directed and predictably scripted, "Playing God" penalizes both its rising star and moviegoers with implausible plot twists, cornball situations, and klutzy villains. Perhaps if the filmmakers had taken their straight, sober-minded drama and played it as broad comedy the film might have been more entertaining and less moronic. The Mark Haskell Smith screenplay is the stuff of which pulp fiction classics are created. Blazing shoot-outs, careening car chases, smart-aleck dialogue, eccentric criminals, and a blast-from-the-past soundtrack, featuring pop tunes such as the Bee Gee's "Jive Talking," flesh out what essentially constitutes a thin, one-dimensional character study. Under Andy Wilson's lackluster directing, these solid elements make for a soggy saga. A graduate of British TV shows such as "Cracker," Wilson never generates the adrenaline rush or visceral thrills that "Playing God" desperately needs to slam it into hyperkinetic overdrive. The filmmakers plunge their hapless hero into harm's way, but he never appears to be in real jeopardy. Wilson and Smith strive to make the murderous antics in their storyline appear surreal, but these results are hopelessly farcical. Especially annoying is Wilson's obvious video-editing style that employs geometric wipes as transitional bridges between episodes. As a doctor who has fallen from on high, Eugene Sands (David Duchovny) spends his time now getting high. What should qualify as cinematic irony in Smith's script winds up as comical incongruity. One night while he's scoring his junk in a dive of an L.A. bar, Sands witnesses a brutal shooting. When nobody calls 911, Sands intervenes and uses his ingenuity to save the wounded man. As it turns out, the poor slob worked for international smuggler Raymond Blossom (Timothy Hutton). Blossom is a wacky psycho who'd double-cross his own mother on the flip of a coin as well as a fashion designer's nightmare. Sands finds himself suddenly being smothered by Blossom's offer of works and drugs. The young, disadvantaged doctor doesn't know quite what to think. Blossom requires Sands' considerable medical talents to save a Russian hit-man who has information vital to Blossom's criminal interests. Initially, despite some misgivings, Sands agrees to perform the surgery and pocket a cool $10-thousand dollars. Before Sands can cruise into the sunset, a scheming, Dagwood Bumstead-esque FBI agent (Michael Massee) recruits Sands as his material witness to back up the person working undercover in Blossom's motley gang of Metallica rejects. Meanwhile, Blossom's sultry moll Claire (Angelina Jolie) complicates matters. Initially, she admires Sands, but she doesn't trust him. Things go incredibly wrong for everybody when a gang of vengeful Russian hit men invade Blossom's posh premises. They gun down one of Blossom's henchmen and put a bullet through Claire's chest. Before "Playing God" grinds predictably to its harebrained conclusion, the movie has Claire and Sands become lovers. Everything in Smith's script hangs on sudden reversals that are more stultifying than startling. Most ridiculous is Sands' unconvincing metamorphosis from a drugged out, self-depreciating loser to a resourceful, jaw-clenched action hero. Sands' fight with the sharp-shooting show-off Cyril (Andrew Tiernan) in a car is particularly unrealistic. Wilson's efforts to make "Playing God" different are doomed by his derivative approach. He bungles what should have been a minor film noir thriller. The story comes apart early on because the chain of events lacks dramatic cohesion. The final car chase starts out promisingly. Blossom and Claire dive into a truck, and as Sands follows them, two identical trucks breeze into the picture on either side of Blossom's ride. Sadly, Wilson does nothing original here, and the rest of the chase is a yawner. Nothing exciting occurs probably because their low budget couldn't afford any car crashes. The shoot-outs are staged with little panache. Most jarring of all is the surgery vignette enacted on a pool tale in an isolated hillbilly biker bar where Sands doctors the wounded Claire. Meantime, the FBI agents are so incompetent that a couple of brainless bad-guy buffoons can smash into their safe house and blast them into oblivion with little difficulty. The cast struggles with Smith's pseudo-cut dialogue that calls attention to the preposterous nature of the script. In the middle of the climactic car chase, Hutton's villain berates his struggling Claire for trying to disrupt the big auto chase. When movies indulge in self-mockery, you know that you're in trouble as an audience member. Presumably, by letting the characters poke fun at the plot twists, Wilson and Smith both hoped to distract spectators from the contrived quality of the story. Their well-intended attempts backfire miserably, and "Playing God" looks goofy. As the good guy hero who realizes the error of his ways, Duchovny maintains a poker face throughout the laughable proceedings. The filmmakers seem more intent on endorsing a didactic, anti-narcotics message than consistency of character. "Playing God" might have played better had Wilson and Smith kept their outlandish hero more strung out and challenged than straightened out and scrupulous. Duchovny's voice-over narration in the style of the old film noir detective thrillers seems more heavy-handed than handy. Jolie does little more than look pretty and pout her abundant lips. The movie takes a time-out to let the hero and the heroine bond with each other without shedding their clothes. As Sands' scumbag foe, Hutton drums up pathetic nastiness. Credit composer Richard Hartley with contributing a bouncy theme for the film. Die-hard "X-Files" fans beware: Scrub this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cross Gender Popcorn Picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underrated action movie that cannot escape that late twentieth century style of combining violent thrills and hard-boiled criminals with a patina of aloof detachment and self consciousness. Sometimes it works well (Tarantino/Rodriguez/Rami) but it is a tricky conceit and you have to be a talent to pull it off. Often the style fails miserably, but not here. While not in the same league as films directed by the above mentioned, this one has enough attraction to keep it from failing. It is an entertaining romp with a good story and is not brought down by some soggy script development and a couple of over the top, completely out there, characters (F.B.I. Agent and some assorted cartoon villains). Overall this one is overlooked as one of the better of this type of thing, a viewer-friendly cross gender popcorn picture, and is worth a view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    94 minutes you'll never get back...if you can stay awake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    excalibur212
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring movies i've seen in a long time, with a story that never really takes off, and a plot that goes nowhere, makes no sense, and can be summarized in one line. The only reason i even watched it was because i was having trouble sleeping, bored, and it was on a "2 for 1" Blu-Ray with "Color of Night" with Bruce Willis and Jane March (a GREAT B-movie, that is one of those it's so bad it's good...highly recommended and underrated!). I would never have paid to watch this movie or even taken time to download it for free...i can't imagine who would. I never understood why some actors have a career (David Duchovny, Kevin Cline, Kevin Spacey) who can't even act and deliver all their lines like they're stoned or asleep, in every single movie they're in. I guess they have good agents. Funny to see Angelina Jolie before she got all buffed and toned; her face actually reminds me of Christina Ricci in a strange way, without the toning and slimmed cheeks. I found nothing in this movie believable, including the strange casting choices (is Timothy's Hutton's character supposed to be bi/gay, because he certainly gives that vibe...i have never seen another movie with him in it either, and can't say i'd desire to). Basically no point to watch this movie unless you're having trouble sleeping, or out of curiosity because you bought the Color of Night Blu-Ray. Nuff said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Backyard of Baywatch (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know there aren't any ties between Baywatch and this movie. Except that they are shot in California, and more exactly in LA and its surroundings. Those locations struck me strongly while watching this movie. The audience moves as well in downtown than in the country, alternating beach and forest. The views you can find here complete the dreamy, cool ones of Baywatch, and even I didn't go there, I think this movie offers a good picture of the real LA. And really, I don't like very much this environment for a living and I prefer the San Francisco area. Now, the story is original but the gimmick (a doctor for healing thugs) is too much used. After the first one, the script becomes a collection of what-if: what-if the doctor visits junk heads, what if the doctor cures the wife's boss, etc.. Then, I am perplexed with the cast: Hutton has really no charisma for a nutty and violent boss. On the contrary, Jolie and above all, Duchvony are excellent. I really appreciate Duchovny, because he is a tall man but he is also quiet. He knows what he wants but he doesn't speak a lot. I like his humor, dry, detached that fits well with his personality. I'am sure that without this hot ticket, this movie would be actually left in limbs. NB: my trailer proposes a love scene between the two but it has been cut from the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lame but Angelina was cute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princessadorable
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall the movie was fairly lame....I was doing dishes while I watched it... I only watched it because Angelina Jolie was in it. The movie could have been better. The idea for the movie was excellent, which is why I'm sad this movie was such a bore. A doctor gets his license taken from him when he does a surgery under narcotics and then starts working for gangs as their doctor. That last sentence I just wrote was the movie, so if you read that sentence, congratulations...you saw the movie!! Angelina was 7/10 in this movie. She is cute, but not stunning. Her face is a full.. looks healthier than she does now, but in the movie it was a bit too full for my taste. Her lips are still very juicy and kissable in this movie. Overall 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave Robinson (dave@under-five-eight.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Duchovney creates a role that he was to replicate somewhat in Californication - the troubled talent. And it is a role he plays well. This thriller starts off at a good speed and carries you through to the end. Timothy Hutton plays a fine villain and Angelina Jolie pouts. The story of a disgraced doctor finding his way into a criminal world is well scripted. Drug addiction and a desire for the sultry Jolie mix a heady cocktail. Unfortunately towards the end the story gets a little weaker and the relationships between villains and the FBI is muddled and rushed as if it was created only to develop the final scene. But, that aside, a movie worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Duchovny way too cool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mathmaniac
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into the experience of watching this movie expecting very little. I wanted to see the movie ever since I saw the preview for it years ago. I wasn't even aware that Angelina Jolie was in this. I'm not a great fan of David Duchovny. Timothy Hutton I expected to play his usual 'charming criminal role' and not do much more. That said, I was truly pleasantly surprised. The film had a nice even pace, lots of blood-spattering gun play and very little sex. In fact, I don't recall Angelina Jolie planting those huge lips of hers on anybody. Hmmm. David Duchovny played his part to perfection. Next to Angelina Jolie, his slouching casual self, muted by his dope habit, could have easily been a drooling fool captivated by her 'loose woman' persona. Instead, befitting an ultra-cool guy with years of education and socialization behind him, he turned it way down and was the cool hipster dealing with really evil hipsters who, like himself, always had some drugs in a pocket or the glove compartment. And like a cool hipster, he naturally kept encountering more and more cool hipsters. Like the bikers on the road who turn out to be allies when he is on the run. He had great lines, as did Timothy Hutton. He showed a mastery of timing, as did Timothy Hutton. Angelina kind of passed from man to man, looking beautiful but NOT having great lines and not having much of a history. I am glad I ordered this film from Amazon and finally got to see it. It was satisfying if you like any of the aforementioned actors. I liked Angelina Jolie in this film and I usually don't. She just looked good - good enough to make men want her but not interesting enough for anyone to want to get to know her.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Timothy Hutton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yesterday I watched this movie on television and I'm not very happy about it.Script can pass as OK but other things can't.First,director Andy Wilson didn't do nothing special,so ordinary directing with few flaws.Second,casting is not good.David Duchovny doesn't have anything to be a leading actor in this movie.That scene when he raises his voice to say something is more funny then it is authoritative.He's very poor actor and his highest achievement are X-Files.Angelina Jolie also nothing,zero,bad.Why did she won Oscar?The way she acted is easy and that role could do any other actress.Only Timothy Hutton left some impression on me.He's mean and that suits him right.He can be good guy and bad too.He's the reason this movie can pass.Because of Hutton 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Credible Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebigeasy555
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Duchovny plays the lead role in this film.Now a lot of people upon finding that fact out wouldn't even bother watching it.Very unfair to say the least.David made his name on the x-files and is a decent actor. Dr Eugene Sands(Duchovny)is a drug addicted doctor struck off for malpractice.By sheer accident he becomes a private doctor for criminal millionaire Raymond Blossom.However the FBI take an interest in using Eugene to snare Blossom. Angelina Jolie is cast in the supporting role of clare-the gangsters moll.She puts in a solid performance. Timothy Hutton playing Blossom is superb and immersed himself deeply into his character. Duchovny himself isn't as bad as many people would think and in the end i would rate his performance his credible.His familiar monotonous tone and straight face is present but dosen't detract too much from the film
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    playing badly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to believe that in 1997 David Duchovny was at the top of his fame, with X-Files, one of the best sci-fi series ever, being at the top of the glory. Nine years later he is almost forgotten, and his tentatives to make it on the big screen failed miserably. I cannot even explain why, he is a fair actor, but probably his moment of fame cast him in a eternal role that takes big talent to break from. At the same time Angelina Jolie was much less known, and she was really lucky that a film like 'Playing God' did not led her career into a dead-end. Fortunately for her, 'The Bone Collector' and 'Girl, Interrupted' were waiting beyond the corner, and when Lara Croft came, her career was launched. There is not too much to be told about this film. It's the only big screen film of Andy Wilson, and there must be a reason. All is banal and most of what happens on the screen expected in this story of an ex-doctor who saves the life of a shooting victim in a bar only to find himself working for the mob. The off-screen voice is especially bad, with a moralistic text that kills any shade of cinematographic experience from the film. You probably will not meet the film but in DVD rental stores, or on TV. Try to look for something better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What A Let-Down!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing good comes out of "Playing God," a pointless Faustian medical thriller anesthetized with clich&eacute;s about a busted surgeon whose synthetic heroin habit lands him in with the dregs of the Los Angeles underworld. As "X-Files" actor David Duchovny's first starring role, this mediocre melodrama about redemption and retribution is less than scintillating. Actually, it is downright embarrassing. Ineptly directed and predictably scripted, "Playing God" penalizes both its rising star and moviegoers with implausible plot twists, cornball situations, and klutzy villains. Perhaps if the filmmakers had taken their straight, sober-minded drama and played it as broad comedy the film might have been more entertaining and less moronic. The Mark Haskell Smith screenplay is the stuff of which pulp fiction classics are created. Blazing shoot-outs, careening car chases, smart-aleck dialogue, eccentric criminals, and a blast-from-the-past soundtrack, featuring pop tunes such as the Bee Gee's "Jive Talking," flesh out what essentially constitutes a thin, one-dimensional character study. Under Andy Wilson's lackluster directing, these solid elements make for a soggy saga. A graduate of British TV shows such as "Cracker," Wilson never generates the adrenaline rush or visceral thrills that "Playing God" desperately needs to slam it into hyperkinetic overdrive. The filmmakers plunge their hapless hero into harm's way, but he never appears to be in real jeopardy. Wilson and Smith strive to make the murderous antics in their storyline appear surreal, but these results are hopelessly farcical. Especially annoying is Wilson's obvious video-editing style that employs geometric wipes as transitional bridges between episodes. As a doctor who has fallen from on high, Eugene Sands (David Duchovny) spends his time now getting high. What should qualify as cinematic irony in Smith's script winds up as comical incongruity. One night while he's scoring his junk in a dive of an L.A. bar, Sands witnesses a brutal shooting. When nobody calls 911, Sands intervenes and uses his ingenuity to save the wounded man. As it turns out, the poor slob worked for international smuggler Raymond Blossom (Timothy Hutton). Blossom is a wacky psycho who'd double-cross his own mother on the flip of a coin as well as a fashion designer's nightmare. Sands finds himself suddenly being smothered by Blossom's offer of works and drugs. The young, disadvantaged doctor doesn't know quite what to think. Blossom requires Sands' considerable medical talents to save a Russian hit-man who has information vital to Blossom's criminal interests. Initially, despite some misgivings, Sands agrees to perform the surgery and pocket a cool $10-thousand dollars. Before Sands can cruise into the sunset, a scheming, Dagwood Bumstead-esque FBI agent (Michael Massee) recruits Sands as his material witness to back up the person working undercover in Blossom's motley gang of Metallica rejects. Meanwhile, Blossom's sultry moll Claire (Angelina Jolie) complicates matters. Initially, she admires Sands, but she doesn't trust him. Things go incredibly wrong for everybody when a gang of vengeful Russian hit men invade Blossom's posh premises. They gun down one of Blossom's henchmen and put a bullet through Claire's chest. Before "Playing God" grinds predictably to its harebrained conclusion, the movie has Claire and Sands become lovers. Everything in Smith's script hangs on sudden reversals that are more stultifying than startling. Most ridiculous is Sands' unconvincing metamorphosis from a drugged out, self-depreciating loser to a resourceful, jaw-clenched action hero. Sands' fight with the sharp-shooting show-off Cyril (Andrew Tiernan) in a car is particularly unrealistic. Wilson's efforts to make "Playing God" different are doomed by his derivative approach. He bungles what should have been a minor film noir thriller. The story comes apart early on because the chain of events lacks dramatic cohesion. The final car chase starts out promisingly. Blossom and Claire dive into a truck, and as Sands follows them, two identical trucks breeze into the picture on either side of Blossom's ride. Sadly, Wilson does nothing original here, and the rest of the chase is a yawner. Nothing exciting occurs probably because their low budget couldn't afford any car crashes. The shoot-outs are staged with little panache. Most jarring of all is the surgery vignette enacted on a pool tale in an isolated hillbilly biker bar where Sands doctors the wounded Claire. Meantime, the FBI agents are so incompetent that a couple of brainless bad-guy buffoons can smash into their safe house and blast them into oblivion with little difficulty. The cast struggles with Smith's pseudo-cut dialogue that calls attention to the preposterous nature of the script. In the middle of the climactic car chase, Hutton's villain berates his struggling Claire for trying to disrupt the big auto chase. When movies indulge in self-mockery, you know that you're in trouble as an audience member. Presumably, by letting the characters poke fun at the plot twists, Wilson and Smith both hoped to distract spectators from the contrived quality of the story. Their well-intended attempts backfire miserably, and "Playing God" looks goofy. As the good guy hero who realizes the error of his ways, Duchovny maintains a poker face throughout the laughable proceedings. The filmmakers seem more intent on endorsing a didactic, anti-narcotics message than consistency of character. "Playing God" might have played better had Wilson and Smith kept their outlandish hero more strung out and challenged than straightened out and scrupulous. Duchovny's voice-over narration in the style of the old film noir detective thrillers seems more heavy-handed than handy. Jolie does little more than look pretty and pout her abundant lips. The movie takes a time-out to let the hero and the heroine bond with each other without shedding their clothes. As Sands' scumbag foe, Hutton drums up pathetic nastiness. Credit composer Richard Hartley with contributing a bouncy theme for the film. Die-hard "X-Files" fans beware: Scrub this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cross Gender Popcorn Picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underrated action movie that cannot escape that late twentieth century style of combining violent thrills and hard-boiled criminals with a patina of aloof detachment and self consciousness. Sometimes it works well (Tarantino/Rodriguez/Rami) but it is a tricky conceit and you have to be a talent to pull it off. Often the style fails miserably, but not here. While not in the same league as films directed by the above mentioned, this one has enough attraction to keep it from failing. It is an entertaining romp with a good story and is not brought down by some soggy script development and a couple of over the top, completely out there, characters (F.B.I. Agent and some assorted cartoon villains). Overall this one is overlooked as one of the better of this type of thing, a viewer-friendly cross gender popcorn picture, and is worth a view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    94 minutes you'll never get back...if you can stay awake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    excalibur212
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring movies i've seen in a long time, with a story that never really takes off, and a plot that goes nowhere, makes no sense, and can be summarized in one line. The only reason i even watched it was because i was having trouble sleeping, bored, and it was on a "2 for 1" Blu-Ray with "Color of Night" with Bruce Willis and Jane March (a GREAT B-movie, that is one of those it's so bad it's good...highly recommended and underrated!). I would never have paid to watch this movie or even taken time to download it for free...i can't imagine who would. I never understood why some actors have a career (David Duchovny, Kevin Cline, Kevin Spacey) who can't even act and deliver all their lines like they're stoned or asleep, in every single movie they're in. I guess they have good agents. Funny to see Angelina Jolie before she got all buffed and toned; her face actually reminds me of Christina Ricci in a strange way, without the toning and slimmed cheeks. I found nothing in this movie believable, including the strange casting choices (is Timothy's Hutton's character supposed to be bi/gay, because he certainly gives that vibe...i have never seen another movie with him in it either, and can't say i'd desire to). Basically no point to watch this movie unless you're having trouble sleeping, or out of curiosity because you bought the Color of Night Blu-Ray. Nuff said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Backyard of Baywatch (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know there aren't any ties between Baywatch and this movie. Except that they are shot in California, and more exactly in LA and its surroundings. Those locations struck me strongly while watching this movie. The audience moves as well in downtown than in the country, alternating beach and forest. The views you can find here complete the dreamy, cool ones of Baywatch, and even I didn't go there, I think this movie offers a good picture of the real LA. And really, I don't like very much this environment for a living and I prefer the San Francisco area. Now, the story is original but the gimmick (a doctor for healing thugs) is too much used. After the first one, the script becomes a collection of what-if: what-if the doctor visits junk heads, what if the doctor cures the wife's boss, etc.. Then, I am perplexed with the cast: Hutton has really no charisma for a nutty and violent boss. On the contrary, Jolie and above all, Duchvony are excellent. I really appreciate Duchovny, because he is a tall man but he is also quiet. He knows what he wants but he doesn't speak a lot. I like his humor, dry, detached that fits well with his personality. I'am sure that without this hot ticket, this movie would be actually left in limbs. NB: my trailer proposes a love scene between the two but it has been cut from the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lame but Angelina was cute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princessadorable
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall the movie was fairly lame....I was doing dishes while I watched it... I only watched it because Angelina Jolie was in it. The movie could have been better. The idea for the movie was excellent, which is why I'm sad this movie was such a bore. A doctor gets his license taken from him when he does a surgery under narcotics and then starts working for gangs as their doctor. That last sentence I just wrote was the movie, so if you read that sentence, congratulations...you saw the movie!! Angelina was 7/10 in this movie. She is cute, but not stunning. Her face is a full.. looks healthier than she does now, but in the movie it was a bit too full for my taste. Her lips are still very juicy and kissable in this movie. Overall 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave Robinson (dave@under-five-eight.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Duchovney creates a role that he was to replicate somewhat in Californication - the troubled talent. And it is a role he plays well. This thriller starts off at a good speed and carries you through to the end. Timothy Hutton plays a fine villain and Angelina Jolie pouts. The story of a disgraced doctor finding his way into a criminal world is well scripted. Drug addiction and a desire for the sultry Jolie mix a heady cocktail. Unfortunately towards the end the story gets a little weaker and the relationships between villains and the FBI is muddled and rushed as if it was created only to develop the final scene. But, that aside, a movie worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Duchovny way too cool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mathmaniac
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into the experience of watching this movie expecting very little. I wanted to see the movie ever since I saw the preview for it years ago. I wasn't even aware that Angelina Jolie was in this. I'm not a great fan of David Duchovny. Timothy Hutton I expected to play his usual 'charming criminal role' and not do much more. That said, I was truly pleasantly surprised. The film had a nice even pace, lots of blood-spattering gun play and very little sex. In fact, I don't recall Angelina Jolie planting those huge lips of hers on anybody. Hmmm. David Duchovny played his part to perfection. Next to Angelina Jolie, his slouching casual self, muted by his dope habit, could have easily been a drooling fool captivated by her 'loose woman' persona. Instead, befitting an ultra-cool guy with years of education and socialization behind him, he turned it way down and was the cool hipster dealing with really evil hipsters who, like himself, always had some drugs in a pocket or the glove compartment. And like a cool hipster, he naturally kept encountering more and more cool hipsters. Like the bikers on the road who turn out to be allies when he is on the run. He had great lines, as did Timothy Hutton. He showed a mastery of timing, as did Timothy Hutton. Angelina kind of passed from man to man, looking beautiful but NOT having great lines and not having much of a history. I am glad I ordered this film from Amazon and finally got to see it. It was satisfying if you like any of the aforementioned actors. I liked Angelina Jolie in this film and I usually don't. She just looked good - good enough to make men want her but not interesting enough for anyone to want to get to know her.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Timothy Hutton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yesterday I watched this movie on television and I'm not very happy about it.Script can pass as OK but other things can't.First,director Andy Wilson didn't do nothing special,so ordinary directing with few flaws.Second,casting is not good.David Duchovny doesn't have anything to be a leading actor in this movie.That scene when he raises his voice to say something is more funny then it is authoritative.He's very poor actor and his highest achievement are X-Files.Angelina Jolie also nothing,zero,bad.Why did she won Oscar?The way she acted is easy and that role could do any other actress.Only Timothy Hutton left some impression on me.He's mean and that suits him right.He can be good guy and bad too.He's the reason this movie can pass.Because of Hutton 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Credible Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebigeasy555
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Duchovny plays the lead role in this film.Now a lot of people upon finding that fact out wouldn't even bother watching it.Very unfair to say the least.David made his name on the x-files and is a decent actor. Dr Eugene Sands(Duchovny)is a drug addicted doctor struck off for malpractice.By sheer accident he becomes a private doctor for criminal millionaire Raymond Blossom.However the FBI take an interest in using Eugene to snare Blossom. Angelina Jolie is cast in the supporting role of clare-the gangsters moll.She puts in a solid performance. Timothy Hutton playing Blossom is superb and immersed himself deeply into his character. Duchovny himself isn't as bad as many people would think and in the end i would rate his performance his credible.His familiar monotonous tone and straight face is present but dosen't detract too much from the film
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    playing badly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to believe that in 1997 David Duchovny was at the top of his fame, with X-Files, one of the best sci-fi series ever, being at the top of the glory. Nine years later he is almost forgotten, and his tentatives to make it on the big screen failed miserably. I cannot even explain why, he is a fair actor, but probably his moment of fame cast him in a eternal role that takes big talent to break from. At the same time Angelina Jolie was much less known, and she was really lucky that a film like 'Playing God' did not led her career into a dead-end. Fortunately for her, 'The Bone Collector' and 'Girl, Interrupted' were waiting beyond the corner, and when Lara Croft came, her career was launched. There is not too much to be told about this film. It's the only big screen film of Andy Wilson, and there must be a reason. All is banal and most of what happens on the screen expected in this story of an ex-doctor who saves the life of a shooting victim in a bar only to find himself working for the mob. The off-screen voice is especially bad, with a moralistic text that kills any shade of cinematographic experience from the film. You probably will not meet the film but in DVD rental stores, or on TV. Try to look for something better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What A Let-Down!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing good comes out of "Playing God," a pointless Faustian medical thriller anesthetized with clich&eacute;s about a busted surgeon whose synthetic heroin habit lands him in with the dregs of the Los Angeles underworld. As "X-Files" actor David Duchovny's first starring role, this mediocre melodrama about redemption and retribution is less than scintillating. Actually, it is downright embarrassing. Ineptly directed and predictably scripted, "Playing God" penalizes both its rising star and moviegoers with implausible plot twists, cornball situations, and klutzy villains. Perhaps if the filmmakers had taken their straight, sober-minded drama and played it as broad comedy the film might have been more entertaining and less moronic. The Mark Haskell Smith screenplay is the stuff of which pulp fiction classics are created. Blazing shoot-outs, careening car chases, smart-aleck dialogue, eccentric criminals, and a blast-from-the-past soundtrack, featuring pop tunes such as the Bee Gee's "Jive Talking," flesh out what essentially constitutes a thin, one-dimensional character study. Under Andy Wilson's lackluster directing, these solid elements make for a soggy saga. A graduate of British TV shows such as "Cracker," Wilson never generates the adrenaline rush or visceral thrills that "Playing God" desperately needs to slam it into hyperkinetic overdrive. The filmmakers plunge their hapless hero into harm's way, but he never appears to be in real jeopardy. Wilson and Smith strive to make the murderous antics in their storyline appear surreal, but these results are hopelessly farcical. Especially annoying is Wilson's obvious video-editing style that employs geometric wipes as transitional bridges between episodes. As a doctor who has fallen from on high, Eugene Sands (David Duchovny) spends his time now getting high. What should qualify as cinematic irony in Smith's script winds up as comical incongruity. One night while he's scoring his junk in a dive of an L.A. bar, Sands witnesses a brutal shooting. When nobody calls 911, Sands intervenes and uses his ingenuity to save the wounded man. As it turns out, the poor slob worked for international smuggler Raymond Blossom (Timothy Hutton). Blossom is a wacky psycho who'd double-cross his own mother on the flip of a coin as well as a fashion designer's nightmare. Sands finds himself suddenly being smothered by Blossom's offer of works and drugs. The young, disadvantaged doctor doesn't know quite what to think. Blossom requires Sands' considerable medical talents to save a Russian hit-man who has information vital to Blossom's criminal interests. Initially, despite some misgivings, Sands agrees to perform the surgery and pocket a cool $10-thousand dollars. Before Sands can cruise into the sunset, a scheming, Dagwood Bumstead-esque FBI agent (Michael Massee) recruits Sands as his material witness to back up the person working undercover in Blossom's motley gang of Metallica rejects. Meanwhile, Blossom's sultry moll Claire (Angelina Jolie) complicates matters. Initially, she admires Sands, but she doesn't trust him. Things go incredibly wrong for everybody when a gang of vengeful Russian hit men invade Blossom's posh premises. They gun down one of Blossom's henchmen and put a bullet through Claire's chest. Before "Playing God" grinds predictably to its harebrained conclusion, the movie has Claire and Sands become lovers. Everything in Smith's script hangs on sudden reversals that are more stultifying than startling. Most ridiculous is Sands' unconvincing metamorphosis from a drugged out, self-depreciating loser to a resourceful, jaw-clenched action hero. Sands' fight with the sharp-shooting show-off Cyril (Andrew Tiernan) in a car is particularly unrealistic. Wilson's efforts to make "Playing God" different are doomed by his derivative approach. He bungles what should have been a minor film noir thriller. The story comes apart early on because the chain of events lacks dramatic cohesion. The final car chase starts out promisingly. Blossom and Claire dive into a truck, and as Sands follows them, two identical trucks breeze into the picture on either side of Blossom's ride. Sadly, Wilson does nothing original here, and the rest of the chase is a yawner. Nothing exciting occurs probably because their low budget couldn't afford any car crashes. The shoot-outs are staged with little panache. Most jarring of all is the surgery vignette enacted on a pool tale in an isolated hillbilly biker bar where Sands doctors the wounded Claire. Meantime, the FBI agents are so incompetent that a couple of brainless bad-guy buffoons can smash into their safe house and blast them into oblivion with little difficulty. The cast struggles with Smith's pseudo-cut dialogue that calls attention to the preposterous nature of the script. In the middle of the climactic car chase, Hutton's villain berates his struggling Claire for trying to disrupt the big auto chase. When movies indulge in self-mockery, you know that you're in trouble as an audience member. Presumably, by letting the characters poke fun at the plot twists, Wilson and Smith both hoped to distract spectators from the contrived quality of the story. Their well-intended attempts backfire miserably, and "Playing God" looks goofy. As the good guy hero who realizes the error of his ways, Duchovny maintains a poker face throughout the laughable proceedings. The filmmakers seem more intent on endorsing a didactic, anti-narcotics message than consistency of character. "Playing God" might have played better had Wilson and Smith kept their outlandish hero more strung out and challenged than straightened out and scrupulous. Duchovny's voice-over narration in the style of the old film noir detective thrillers seems more heavy-handed than handy. Jolie does little more than look pretty and pout her abundant lips. The movie takes a time-out to let the hero and the heroine bond with each other without shedding their clothes. As Sands' scumbag foe, Hutton drums up pathetic nastiness. Credit composer Richard Hartley with contributing a bouncy theme for the film. Die-hard "X-Files" fans beware: Scrub this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cross Gender Popcorn Picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underrated action movie that cannot escape that late twentieth century style of combining violent thrills and hard-boiled criminals with a patina of aloof detachment and self consciousness. Sometimes it works well (Tarantino/Rodriguez/Rami) but it is a tricky conceit and you have to be a talent to pull it off. Often the style fails miserably, but not here. While not in the same league as films directed by the above mentioned, this one has enough attraction to keep it from failing. It is an entertaining romp with a good story and is not brought down by some soggy script development and a couple of over the top, completely out there, characters (F.B.I. Agent and some assorted cartoon villains). Overall this one is overlooked as one of the better of this type of thing, a viewer-friendly cross gender popcorn picture, and is worth a view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    94 minutes you'll never get back...if you can stay awake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    excalibur212
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring movies i've seen in a long time, with a story that never really takes off, and a plot that goes nowhere, makes no sense, and can be summarized in one line. The only reason i even watched it was because i was having trouble sleeping, bored, and it was on a "2 for 1" Blu-Ray with "Color of Night" with Bruce Willis and Jane March (a GREAT B-movie, that is one of those it's so bad it's good...highly recommended and underrated!). I would never have paid to watch this movie or even taken time to download it for free...i can't imagine who would. I never understood why some actors have a career (David Duchovny, Kevin Cline, Kevin Spacey) who can't even act and deliver all their lines like they're stoned or asleep, in every single movie they're in. I guess they have good agents. Funny to see Angelina Jolie before she got all buffed and toned; her face actually reminds me of Christina Ricci in a strange way, without the toning and slimmed cheeks. I found nothing in this movie believable, including the strange casting choices (is Timothy's Hutton's character supposed to be bi/gay, because he certainly gives that vibe...i have never seen another movie with him in it either, and can't say i'd desire to). Basically no point to watch this movie unless you're having trouble sleeping, or out of curiosity because you bought the Color of Night Blu-Ray. Nuff said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Backyard of Baywatch (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know there aren't any ties between Baywatch and this movie. Except that they are shot in California, and more exactly in LA and its surroundings. Those locations struck me strongly while watching this movie. The audience moves as well in downtown than in the country, alternating beach and forest. The views you can find here complete the dreamy, cool ones of Baywatch, and even I didn't go there, I think this movie offers a good picture of the real LA. And really, I don't like very much this environment for a living and I prefer the San Francisco area. Now, the story is original but the gimmick (a doctor for healing thugs) is too much used. After the first one, the script becomes a collection of what-if: what-if the doctor visits junk heads, what if the doctor cures the wife's boss, etc.. Then, I am perplexed with the cast: Hutton has really no charisma for a nutty and violent boss. On the contrary, Jolie and above all, Duchvony are excellent. I really appreciate Duchovny, because he is a tall man but he is also quiet. He knows what he wants but he doesn't speak a lot. I like his humor, dry, detached that fits well with his personality. I'am sure that without this hot ticket, this movie would be actually left in limbs. NB: my trailer proposes a love scene between the two but it has been cut from the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lame but Angelina was cute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princessadorable
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall the movie was fairly lame....I was doing dishes while I watched it... I only watched it because Angelina Jolie was in it. The movie could have been better. The idea for the movie was excellent, which is why I'm sad this movie was such a bore. A doctor gets his license taken from him when he does a surgery under narcotics and then starts working for gangs as their doctor. That last sentence I just wrote was the movie, so if you read that sentence, congratulations...you saw the movie!! Angelina was 7/10 in this movie. She is cute, but not stunning. Her face is a full.. looks healthier than she does now, but in the movie it was a bit too full for my taste. Her lips are still very juicy and kissable in this movie. Overall 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave Robinson (dave@under-five-eight.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Duchovney creates a role that he was to replicate somewhat in Californication - the troubled talent. And it is a role he plays well. This thriller starts off at a good speed and carries you through to the end. Timothy Hutton plays a fine villain and Angelina Jolie pouts. The story of a disgraced doctor finding his way into a criminal world is well scripted. Drug addiction and a desire for the sultry Jolie mix a heady cocktail. Unfortunately towards the end the story gets a little weaker and the relationships between villains and the FBI is muddled and rushed as if it was created only to develop the final scene. But, that aside, a movie worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Duchovny way too cool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mathmaniac
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into the experience of watching this movie expecting very little. I wanted to see the movie ever since I saw the preview for it years ago. I wasn't even aware that Angelina Jolie was in this. I'm not a great fan of David Duchovny. Timothy Hutton I expected to play his usual 'charming criminal role' and not do much more. That said, I was truly pleasantly surprised. The film had a nice even pace, lots of blood-spattering gun play and very little sex. In fact, I don't recall Angelina Jolie planting those huge lips of hers on anybody. Hmmm. David Duchovny played his part to perfection. Next to Angelina Jolie, his slouching casual self, muted by his dope habit, could have easily been a drooling fool captivated by her 'loose woman' persona. Instead, befitting an ultra-cool guy with years of education and socialization behind him, he turned it way down and was the cool hipster dealing with really evil hipsters who, like himself, always had some drugs in a pocket or the glove compartment. And like a cool hipster, he naturally kept encountering more and more cool hipsters. Like the bikers on the road who turn out to be allies when he is on the run. He had great lines, as did Timothy Hutton. He showed a mastery of timing, as did Timothy Hutton. Angelina kind of passed from man to man, looking beautiful but NOT having great lines and not having much of a history. I am glad I ordered this film from Amazon and finally got to see it. It was satisfying if you like any of the aforementioned actors. I liked Angelina Jolie in this film and I usually don't. She just looked good - good enough to make men want her but not interesting enough for anyone to want to get to know her.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Timothy Hutton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yesterday I watched this movie on television and I'm not very happy about it.Script can pass as OK but other things can't.First,director Andy Wilson didn't do nothing special,so ordinary directing with few flaws.Second,casting is not good.David Duchovny doesn't have anything to be a leading actor in this movie.That scene when he raises his voice to say something is more funny then it is authoritative.He's very poor actor and his highest achievement are X-Files.Angelina Jolie also nothing,zero,bad.Why did she won Oscar?The way she acted is easy and that role could do any other actress.Only Timothy Hutton left some impression on me.He's mean and that suits him right.He can be good guy and bad too.He's the reason this movie can pass.Because of Hutton 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Credible Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebigeasy555
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Duchovny plays the lead role in this film.Now a lot of people upon finding that fact out wouldn't even bother watching it.Very unfair to say the least.David made his name on the x-files and is a decent actor. Dr Eugene Sands(Duchovny)is a drug addicted doctor struck off for malpractice.By sheer accident he becomes a private doctor for criminal millionaire Raymond Blossom.However the FBI take an interest in using Eugene to snare Blossom. Angelina Jolie is cast in the supporting role of clare-the gangsters moll.She puts in a solid performance. Timothy Hutton playing Blossom is superb and immersed himself deeply into his character. Duchovny himself isn't as bad as many people would think and in the end i would rate his performance his credible.His familiar monotonous tone and straight face is present but dosen't detract too much from the film
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    playing badly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to believe that in 1997 David Duchovny was at the top of his fame, with X-Files, one of the best sci-fi series ever, being at the top of the glory. Nine years later he is almost forgotten, and his tentatives to make it on the big screen failed miserably. I cannot even explain why, he is a fair actor, but probably his moment of fame cast him in a eternal role that takes big talent to break from. At the same time Angelina Jolie was much less known, and she was really lucky that a film like 'Playing God' did not led her career into a dead-end. Fortunately for her, 'The Bone Collector' and 'Girl, Interrupted' were waiting beyond the corner, and when Lara Croft came, her career was launched. There is not too much to be told about this film. It's the only big screen film of Andy Wilson, and there must be a reason. All is banal and most of what happens on the screen expected in this story of an ex-doctor who saves the life of a shooting victim in a bar only to find himself working for the mob. The off-screen voice is especially bad, with a moralistic text that kills any shade of cinematographic experience from the film. You probably will not meet the film but in DVD rental stores, or on TV. Try to look for something better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What A Let-Down!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing good comes out of "Playing God," a pointless Faustian medical thriller anesthetized with clich&eacute;s about a busted surgeon whose synthetic heroin habit lands him in with the dregs of the Los Angeles underworld. As "X-Files" actor David Duchovny's first starring role, this mediocre melodrama about redemption and retribution is less than scintillating. Actually, it is downright embarrassing. Ineptly directed and predictably scripted, "Playing God" penalizes both its rising star and moviegoers with implausible plot twists, cornball situations, and klutzy villains. Perhaps if the filmmakers had taken their straight, sober-minded drama and played it as broad comedy the film might have been more entertaining and less moronic. The Mark Haskell Smith screenplay is the stuff of which pulp fiction classics are created. Blazing shoot-outs, careening car chases, smart-aleck dialogue, eccentric criminals, and a blast-from-the-past soundtrack, featuring pop tunes such as the Bee Gee's "Jive Talking," flesh out what essentially constitutes a thin, one-dimensional character study. Under Andy Wilson's lackluster directing, these solid elements make for a soggy saga. A graduate of British TV shows such as "Cracker," Wilson never generates the adrenaline rush or visceral thrills that "Playing God" desperately needs to slam it into hyperkinetic overdrive. The filmmakers plunge their hapless hero into harm's way, but he never appears to be in real jeopardy. Wilson and Smith strive to make the murderous antics in their storyline appear surreal, but these results are hopelessly farcical. Especially annoying is Wilson's obvious video-editing style that employs geometric wipes as transitional bridges between episodes. As a doctor who has fallen from on high, Eugene Sands (David Duchovny) spends his time now getting high. What should qualify as cinematic irony in Smith's script winds up as comical incongruity. One night while he's scoring his junk in a dive of an L.A. bar, Sands witnesses a brutal shooting. When nobody calls 911, Sands intervenes and uses his ingenuity to save the wounded man. As it turns out, the poor slob worked for international smuggler Raymond Blossom (Timothy Hutton). Blossom is a wacky psycho who'd double-cross his own mother on the flip of a coin as well as a fashion designer's nightmare. Sands finds himself suddenly being smothered by Blossom's offer of works and drugs. The young, disadvantaged doctor doesn't know quite what to think. Blossom requires Sands' considerable medical talents to save a Russian hit-man who has information vital to Blossom's criminal interests. Initially, despite some misgivings, Sands agrees to perform the surgery and pocket a cool $10-thousand dollars. Before Sands can cruise into the sunset, a scheming, Dagwood Bumstead-esque FBI agent (Michael Massee) recruits Sands as his material witness to back up the person working undercover in Blossom's motley gang of Metallica rejects. Meanwhile, Blossom's sultry moll Claire (Angelina Jolie) complicates matters. Initially, she admires Sands, but she doesn't trust him. Things go incredibly wrong for everybody when a gang of vengeful Russian hit men invade Blossom's posh premises. They gun down one of Blossom's henchmen and put a bullet through Claire's chest. Before "Playing God" grinds predictably to its harebrained conclusion, the movie has Claire and Sands become lovers. Everything in Smith's script hangs on sudden reversals that are more stultifying than startling. Most ridiculous is Sands' unconvincing metamorphosis from a drugged out, self-depreciating loser to a resourceful, jaw-clenched action hero. Sands' fight with the sharp-shooting show-off Cyril (Andrew Tiernan) in a car is particularly unrealistic. Wilson's efforts to make "Playing God" different are doomed by his derivative approach. He bungles what should have been a minor film noir thriller. The story comes apart early on because the chain of events lacks dramatic cohesion. The final car chase starts out promisingly. Blossom and Claire dive into a truck, and as Sands follows them, two identical trucks breeze into the picture on either side of Blossom's ride. Sadly, Wilson does nothing original here, and the rest of the chase is a yawner. Nothing exciting occurs probably because their low budget couldn't afford any car crashes. The shoot-outs are staged with little panache. Most jarring of all is the surgery vignette enacted on a pool tale in an isolated hillbilly biker bar where Sands doctors the wounded Claire. Meantime, the FBI agents are so incompetent that a couple of brainless bad-guy buffoons can smash into their safe house and blast them into oblivion with little difficulty. The cast struggles with Smith's pseudo-cut dialogue that calls attention to the preposterous nature of the script. In the middle of the climactic car chase, Hutton's villain berates his struggling Claire for trying to disrupt the big auto chase. When movies indulge in self-mockery, you know that you're in trouble as an audience member. Presumably, by letting the characters poke fun at the plot twists, Wilson and Smith both hoped to distract spectators from the contrived quality of the story. Their well-intended attempts backfire miserably, and "Playing God" looks goofy. As the good guy hero who realizes the error of his ways, Duchovny maintains a poker face throughout the laughable proceedings. The filmmakers seem more intent on endorsing a didactic, anti-narcotics message than consistency of character. "Playing God" might have played better had Wilson and Smith kept their outlandish hero more strung out and challenged than straightened out and scrupulous. Duchovny's voice-over narration in the style of the old film noir detective thrillers seems more heavy-handed than handy. Jolie does little more than look pretty and pout her abundant lips. The movie takes a time-out to let the hero and the heroine bond with each other without shedding their clothes. As Sands' scumbag foe, Hutton drums up pathetic nastiness. Credit composer Richard Hartley with contributing a bouncy theme for the film. Die-hard "X-Files" fans beware: Scrub this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cross Gender Popcorn Picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underrated action movie that cannot escape that late twentieth century style of combining violent thrills and hard-boiled criminals with a patina of aloof detachment and self consciousness. Sometimes it works well (Tarantino/Rodriguez/Rami) but it is a tricky conceit and you have to be a talent to pull it off. Often the style fails miserably, but not here. While not in the same league as films directed by the above mentioned, this one has enough attraction to keep it from failing. It is an entertaining romp with a good story and is not brought down by some soggy script development and a couple of over the top, completely out there, characters (F.B.I. Agent and some assorted cartoon villains). Overall this one is overlooked as one of the better of this type of thing, a viewer-friendly cross gender popcorn picture, and is worth a view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    94 minutes you'll never get back...if you can stay awake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    excalibur212
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most boring movies i've seen in a long time, with a story that never really takes off, and a plot that goes nowhere, makes no sense, and can be summarized in one line. The only reason i even watched it was because i was having trouble sleeping, bored, and it was on a "2 for 1" Blu-Ray with "Color of Night" with Bruce Willis and Jane March (a GREAT B-movie, that is one of those it's so bad it's good...highly recommended and underrated!). I would never have paid to watch this movie or even taken time to download it for free...i can't imagine who would. I never understood why some actors have a career (David Duchovny, Kevin Cline, Kevin Spacey) who can't even act and deliver all their lines like they're stoned or asleep, in every single movie they're in. I guess they have good agents. Funny to see Angelina Jolie before she got all buffed and toned; her face actually reminds me of Christina Ricci in a strange way, without the toning and slimmed cheeks. I found nothing in this movie believable, including the strange casting choices (is Timothy's Hutton's character supposed to be bi/gay, because he certainly gives that vibe...i have never seen another movie with him in it either, and can't say i'd desire to). Basically no point to watch this movie unless you're having trouble sleeping, or out of curiosity because you bought the Color of Night Blu-Ray. Nuff said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Backyard of Baywatch (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know there aren't any ties between Baywatch and this movie. Except that they are shot in California, and more exactly in LA and its surroundings. Those locations struck me strongly while watching this movie. The audience moves as well in downtown than in the country, alternating beach and forest. The views you can find here complete the dreamy, cool ones of Baywatch, and even I didn't go there, I think this movie offers a good picture of the real LA. And really, I don't like very much this environment for a living and I prefer the San Francisco area. Now, the story is original but the gimmick (a doctor for healing thugs) is too much used. After the first one, the script becomes a collection of what-if: what-if the doctor visits junk heads, what if the doctor cures the wife's boss, etc.. Then, I am perplexed with the cast: Hutton has really no charisma for a nutty and violent boss. On the contrary, Jolie and above all, Duchvony are excellent. I really appreciate Duchovny, because he is a tall man but he is also quiet. He knows what he wants but he doesn't speak a lot. I like his humor, dry, detached that fits well with his personality. I'am sure that without this hot ticket, this movie would be actually left in limbs. NB: my trailer proposes a love scene between the two but it has been cut from the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lame but Angelina was cute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princessadorable
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall the movie was fairly lame....I was doing dishes while I watched it... I only watched it because Angelina Jolie was in it. The movie could have been better. The idea for the movie was excellent, which is why I'm sad this movie was such a bore. A doctor gets his license taken from him when he does a surgery under narcotics and then starts working for gangs as their doctor. That last sentence I just wrote was the movie, so if you read that sentence, congratulations...you saw the movie!! Angelina was 7/10 in this movie. She is cute, but not stunning. Her face is a full.. looks healthier than she does now, but in the movie it was a bit too full for my taste. Her lips are still very juicy and kissable in this movie. Overall 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave Robinson (dave@under-five-eight.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Duchovney creates a role that he was to replicate somewhat in Californication - the troubled talent. And it is a role he plays well. This thriller starts off at a good speed and carries you through to the end. Timothy Hutton plays a fine villain and Angelina Jolie pouts. The story of a disgraced doctor finding his way into a criminal world is well scripted. Drug addiction and a desire for the sultry Jolie mix a heady cocktail. Unfortunately towards the end the story gets a little weaker and the relationships between villains and the FBI is muddled and rushed as if it was created only to develop the final scene. But, that aside, a movie worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Duchovny way too cool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mathmaniac
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into the experience of watching this movie expecting very little. I wanted to see the movie ever since I saw the preview for it years ago. I wasn't even aware that Angelina Jolie was in this. I'm not a great fan of David Duchovny. Timothy Hutton I expected to play his usual 'charming criminal role' and not do much more. That said, I was truly pleasantly surprised. The film had a nice even pace, lots of blood-spattering gun play and very little sex. In fact, I don't recall Angelina Jolie planting those huge lips of hers on anybody. Hmmm. David Duchovny played his part to perfection. Next to Angelina Jolie, his slouching casual self, muted by his dope habit, could have easily been a drooling fool captivated by her 'loose woman' persona. Instead, befitting an ultra-cool guy with years of education and socialization behind him, he turned it way down and was the cool hipster dealing with really evil hipsters who, like himself, always had some drugs in a pocket or the glove compartment. And like a cool hipster, he naturally kept encountering more and more cool hipsters. Like the bikers on the road who turn out to be allies when he is on the run. He had great lines, as did Timothy Hutton. He showed a mastery of timing, as did Timothy Hutton. Angelina kind of passed from man to man, looking beautiful but NOT having great lines and not having much of a history. I am glad I ordered this film from Amazon and finally got to see it. It was satisfying if you like any of the aforementioned actors. I liked Angelina Jolie in this film and I usually don't. She just looked good - good enough to make men want her but not interesting enough for anyone to want to get to know her.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only Timothy Hutton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yesterday I watched this movie on television and I'm not very happy about it.Script can pass as OK but other things can't.First,director Andy Wilson didn't do nothing special,so ordinary directing with few flaws.Second,casting is not good.David Duchovny doesn't have anything to be a leading actor in this movie.That scene when he raises his voice to say something is more funny then it is authoritative.He's very poor actor and his highest achievement are X-Files.Angelina Jolie also nothing,zero,bad.Why did she won Oscar?The way she acted is easy and that role could do any other actress.Only Timothy Hutton left some impression on me.He's mean and that suits him right.He can be good guy and bad too.He's the reason this movie can pass.Because of Hutton 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Credible Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebigeasy555
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    David Duchovny plays the lead role in this film.Now a lot of people upon finding that fact out wouldn't even bother watching it.Very unfair to say the least.David made his name on the x-files and is a decent actor. Dr Eugene Sands(Duchovny)is a drug addicted doctor struck off for malpractice.By sheer accident he becomes a private doctor for criminal millionaire Raymond Blossom.However the FBI take an interest in using Eugene to snare Blossom. Angelina Jolie is cast in the supporting role of clare-the gangsters moll.She puts in a solid performance. Timothy Hutton playing Blossom is superb and immersed himself deeply into his character. Duchovny himself isn't as bad as many people would think and in the end i would rate his performance his credible.His familiar monotonous tone and straight face is present but dosen't detract too much from the film
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    playing badly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to believe that in 1997 David Duchovny was at the top of his fame, with X-Files, one of the best sci-fi series ever, being at the top of the glory. Nine years later he is almost forgotten, and his tentatives to make it on the big screen failed miserably. I cannot even explain why, he is a fair actor, but probably his moment of fame cast him in a eternal role that takes big talent to break from. At the same time Angelina Jolie was much less known, and she was really lucky that a film like 'Playing God' did not led her career into a dead-end. Fortunately for her, 'The Bone Collector' and 'Girl, Interrupted' were waiting beyond the corner, and when Lara Croft came, her career was launched. There is not too much to be told about this film. It's the only big screen film of Andy Wilson, and there must be a reason. All is banal and most of what happens on the screen expected in this story of an ex-doctor who saves the life of a shooting victim in a bar only to find himself working for the mob. The off-screen voice is especially bad, with a moralistic text that kills any shade of cinematographic experience from the film. You probably will not meet the film but in DVD rental stores, or on TV. Try to look for something better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
