<filme>
 <id>
  337
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119324
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  The House of Yes
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A mentally unbalanced young woman (who thinks she's Jackie Kennedy) flips into a murderous rage when her brother returns home to reveal he's engaged.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Jackie-O is anxiously awaiting the visit of her brother home for Thanksgiving, but isn't expecting him to bring a friend. She's even more shocked to learn that this friend is his fiance. It soon becomes clear that Jackie Kennedy's obsession is nothing compared to her obsession with her brother, as it also becomes clear she isn't the only member of the family with problems...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   thanksgiving
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   john f kennedy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hair brush
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   candle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder re enactment
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Mark Waters
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Wendy MacLeod
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Mark Waters
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Parker Posey
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Josh Hamilton
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tori Spelling
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for Parker Posey and Tori Spelling Fans!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    splambo100
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To the folks that think Ms Spelling did not turn in a good performance-I disagree. I was pleased with the drama she showed. She was still a young actress and has of course improved with age, but she was lithe and active and in this film I noticed she has the most perfectly formed hands and forearms of any actress on film. Not sure why I noticed this but if you watch again, look for this. She should use this feature to full effect. She also has a bit of a striking profile and eyes, similar to some other famous actors on stage. She could use her eyes to show more emotion. She showed her range to more effect when she was showing concern for the other characters. Parker Posey, of course, was in her full glory in this performance. She showed great skill with the acting process. If you listen to the film without watching the action, you see that she uses her voice to great effect. She truly stole this show. Ms Bujold of course exhibits great range of craft, so great to see her always. To top off the show, there is a cameo by a young Rachael Lee Cook. Fine performances by the men. Overall unique experience!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The House of Yes - A Family Tale of Disturbia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sat down to see this film, not really know what to expect from it, and was surprised by it. Very surprised. I had read a small synopsis online, and thought, why not give it a shot? What I got, was a twisted black comedy, with subjects of taboo, and a messy kind of attitude. The film stars Parker Posey, Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prince Jr. (what, you can be in dramas too?) and Genevi&egrave;ve Bujold. The film is directed by Mark Waters, his first feature film debut to say. A sense of strong film debut to say it the least. The film is about a mentally unbalanced woman, whom believes she is Jackie Kennedy. Already from the first time you see her, you feel that madness inside of her ... trying to escape. She seems to misses her brother, very much indeed. He is bringing a "friend" over to Thanksgiving, this friend is revealed to be his fianc&eacute;e. From there, a twisted tale of familial construction is on the way. Just to get it out of the system. The mentally unbalanced woman, "Jackie-O" is in deep love with her own brother Marty. In fact so deep in love, that she will do anything to get him for herself. They have done it before, and "Jackie-O" wants more. They tell their youngest brother, the secret ... and he then tells this to the fianc&eacute;e of Marty, whom he have began falling for. You can call like this, he is in love with her. They do it too, while the brother and sister downstairs are busy themselves. One can start to think, about how the mother is feeling about this whole affair? Yup. I feel like I am walking on a layer of thin ice right now, but hey it's a dark comedy. What did you expect? Apart from the Incest in the film, that is handled with such subtlety that it feels enigmatic. And when it happens, you feel like you are rooting more for them, than what the norm is. I went there! The film have that atmosphere of claustrophobia (since the action is taking place in one building the entire time), and hidden secrets are hinted in it's wake. The acting is very resembled that of theatricality - And I like very well that the sentences have this form of construction. It feels like you are seeing this a play, of which this film is based. I had not heard of that play before, and must say - it must be a better experience to witness the twisted (yes I have said that word too many times already) form of this tale live, with performances on the stage. Yet, it feels like I already have. Due to the fact of the theatricality of the film. The end of the film, is tear-jerking, and you feel dirty about it afterwords. I will not spoil that one. I don't know what to say anymore of the film, other than to recommend it highly. Most highly to supporters of black comedy. I had a great time seeing the film, but it is not for the easily offended, due to the fact of it's incestuous theme, and the atmospheric disturbance. So yeah, there you have it. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes people just don't know how to say no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small-scale personal drama with plenty of barbed one-liners, pitch-black comedy and disturbing subject matter starring Parker Posey in one of her best ever roles, if you're not already sold on this movie then shame on you. The story revolves around "Jackie-O" Pascal (played by Posey), a young woman who is slightly . . . . . . unwell in the head. She stays with her brother (Freddie Prinze Jr.) and mother (Genevieve Bujold) in the family home. Everything is about to get quite tense when the other brother (Josh Hamilton) comes to visit, bringing a fianc&eacute; (Tori Spelling) with him. "Jackie-O" struggles to maintain a civil facade as her jealousy bubbles up to the surface and her mental state worsens. Adapted from a play by Wendy MacLeod, The House Of Yes doesn't need any major dressing or stylistic flourishes to impress. It gets by on the strength of the source material, the fine dialogue voiced by some great actors. Even Freddie Prinze Jr. and Tori Spelling come across well, that's how good the material is. Posey is simply unforgettable in the main role, as appealing as she is clearly disturbed. It's the kind of role that people need to remember she's capable of, it's a tour de force. Josh Hamilton works well opposite her and gets a lot of the more amusing and disturbing dialogue exchanges. Freddie Prinze Jr. is effectively naive and apparently innocent while Tori Spelling is bemused and increasingly exasperated with the strange household she finds herself in. Genevieve Bujold isn't on screen for long but makes a great impression with every moment she has. Director Mark Waters, who also adapted the play, handles everything perfectly. It may not be the most cinematic film that you'll ever see but it's something that plays out like a cross between Neil LaBute and David Mamet. And that's a solid endorsement, in my view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trite, predictable and poorly acted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackshrack
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor! I am very tired of these kinds of movies. They seem to be a reaction against Hollywood. And in the end these "independent" movies are just as trite and empty. The first 5 minutes are intriguing and comedic. Afterwards, you get the sense that it becomes more and more of a play. Which I am not sure that there is any purpose in filming a play. I would imagine that the play would be a lot better. With the psychological dimension, a play can bring the viewer to imagine more than a film. But to film basically a play, you get the least of both world, in my opinion. Unless it is done in a very original way, like dogville. This movie just seemed trite and transparent to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not as tasteless as it might sound"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wes Lambert (mockingmovies@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writing recently about "Happy Tears" gave me pause to think about my trajectory as a Parker Posey fan which began in the mid 90's with "Party Girl". Unfortunately the indie cult status of "Party Girl" means it has a very very very long wait on Blockbuster.com. They might as well admit that it will never ship. However today "The House of Yes" arrived in the mail. This is a brilliant, wicked film that might suffer from the accusation of being pretentious with it's over indulged, privileged characters and lightning fast witty dialogue. The story is that Marty Pascel (Josh Hamilton) has made the unbelievable blunder of bringing his mousey girlfriend (Tori Spelling) home to meet his wealthy, dysfunctional family on the very night they will all be virtually trapped together by a hurricane. The driving force of the family and the movie as a whole is Parker Posey as Marty's sister, Jackie-O. She in step with the weather outside is pretty much an evil, brilliant, psychotic (with the pills to prove it) bitch in a little black dress. An unhealthy obsession with Jackie Onassis and Marty are icing on the cake. Worse yet for the poor girlfriend, once back in the fold, Marty does very little to discourage Jackie-O and ultimately joins in her twisted games. Nothing ends well here unless you see the world through Jackie-O's eyes that is. "House of Yes" also contains perhaps my favorite line of dialogue ever - "If people are going to start telling the truth around here, I'm going to bed". If your experience with Parker Posey is one of "You've Got Mail" and "Scream 3" or worse yet "Superman Returns", I suggest taking a trip back to the 90's to see how she earned the title queen of the indies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    theater of the absurd is so over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sophiej468
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this 1997 film of an earlier play is the proof. there's just too much real absurdity going on. Genevieve Bujold as the disconnected mother is the best thing in it, but these days, that isn't saying much, because so many people are disconnected. What there is of a plot about sibling incest and insanity is today totally predictable. A few (too few)funny lines. no one seems to know quite what to do with Parker Posey, except Christopher Guest, in his wonderful mockumentaries, in which she's very funny. Here, she just seems strained. Tori Spelling is quite appealing as the only normal character, a donut shop waitress who lands in a pretentious upscale family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a showcase for Parker Posey, interesting; on its own, fairly dire...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Wendy MacLeod's play about a 1963 Thanksgiving reunion between a young man and his peculiar family, including a twin sister who is obsessed with Jacqueline Kennedy. Oppressively set in a shadowy house during a raging storm, this head-scratching talk-fest quickly tires both the eye and the ear. The scenario is full of dreary eccentrics, although Parker Posey's 'Jackie-O' is a dark, original creation unto herself. The actress, known for going out on a limb with basically unplayable roles, manages to walk a fine line between comically scabrous and downright scary (which, in an otherwise boring movie, is a triumph). Other performances by Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prinze, Jr., and a sadly under-valued Genevieve Bujold are not quite as on-target, mainly due to the sophomoric writing. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The writing kills this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy_Terry_Moore
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from Wendy MacLeod's play with almost no apparent changes for better or worse, director Mark Waters penned this screenplay about the incest between a Jackie Onassis-obsessed girl and her obliging brother. From start to finish, the air is filled with intellectual dialogue like "What?" and "I don't know", including the padded repeating of several lines like "What do you do all day?" - five times in a row, that one. The acting is small-time all around except for the appealing performances of Genevieve Bujold and Tori Spelling as a spooky mother and waifish fianc&eacute;, respectively. Sometimes interesting dark comedy has occasional eerie moments if one can get past the JFK assassination 'parody'. Pretty good title, anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker Posey At Her Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jerry (Nglas)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very few movies based on plays can be successful, but House of Yes is not one of those that fail. It succeeds where others have failed because of the energy put into a film that is mostly dialog. Parker Posey shines as Jackie-O, the mentally troubled sister of Josh Hamilton and Freddy Prinze Jr. Tori Spelling, whose only other film I have enjoyed was Trick, did a great job of playing Jackie-O's doormat. The movie is at its strongest when Parker bares her sadness, always hidden beneath sarcasm. A classic movie of family dysfunction without playing out the same old tired roles. This family is anything but a typical dysfunctional family and though they all appear to be nuts, part of you wants to run out and find a family just like them, because looking past all of the sarcasm and insults, you sense and feel the love. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see strong acting. Parker Posey is on top of her game here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of my all time favorites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato002-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Incestial witty good fun. A new kind of interesting. The humor is fast and in your face. I just don't see movies like this ever. Most are too scared to make fun of touchy matters to this extent or they try so hard to be artistic that it becomes horribly boring. If u don't suck you'd enjoy it. Hey if Parker Posey was my sis and she looked like Rachael Leigh Cook when she was young, i would support incest even more so then the way half you retards support those idiot ants marching(aka troops). Every character plays the perfect role for the kind of actor or actress they are. Such as Parker playing another Insane bitch, and Freddie Prince playing a moron. Great movie if your open minded. Not the kinda movie to watch if u hide behind worthless moral values given by people who worship things that don't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for Parker Posey and Tori Spelling Fans!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    splambo100
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To the folks that think Ms Spelling did not turn in a good performance-I disagree. I was pleased with the drama she showed. She was still a young actress and has of course improved with age, but she was lithe and active and in this film I noticed she has the most perfectly formed hands and forearms of any actress on film. Not sure why I noticed this but if you watch again, look for this. She should use this feature to full effect. She also has a bit of a striking profile and eyes, similar to some other famous actors on stage. She could use her eyes to show more emotion. She showed her range to more effect when she was showing concern for the other characters. Parker Posey, of course, was in her full glory in this performance. She showed great skill with the acting process. If you listen to the film without watching the action, you see that she uses her voice to great effect. She truly stole this show. Ms Bujold of course exhibits great range of craft, so great to see her always. To top off the show, there is a cameo by a young Rachael Lee Cook. Fine performances by the men. Overall unique experience!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The House of Yes - A Family Tale of Disturbia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sat down to see this film, not really know what to expect from it, and was surprised by it. Very surprised. I had read a small synopsis online, and thought, why not give it a shot? What I got, was a twisted black comedy, with subjects of taboo, and a messy kind of attitude. The film stars Parker Posey, Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prince Jr. (what, you can be in dramas too?) and Genevi&egrave;ve Bujold. The film is directed by Mark Waters, his first feature film debut to say. A sense of strong film debut to say it the least. The film is about a mentally unbalanced woman, whom believes she is Jackie Kennedy. Already from the first time you see her, you feel that madness inside of her ... trying to escape. She seems to misses her brother, very much indeed. He is bringing a "friend" over to Thanksgiving, this friend is revealed to be his fianc&eacute;e. From there, a twisted tale of familial construction is on the way. Just to get it out of the system. The mentally unbalanced woman, "Jackie-O" is in deep love with her own brother Marty. In fact so deep in love, that she will do anything to get him for herself. They have done it before, and "Jackie-O" wants more. They tell their youngest brother, the secret ... and he then tells this to the fianc&eacute;e of Marty, whom he have began falling for. You can call like this, he is in love with her. They do it too, while the brother and sister downstairs are busy themselves. One can start to think, about how the mother is feeling about this whole affair? Yup. I feel like I am walking on a layer of thin ice right now, but hey it's a dark comedy. What did you expect? Apart from the Incest in the film, that is handled with such subtlety that it feels enigmatic. And when it happens, you feel like you are rooting more for them, than what the norm is. I went there! The film have that atmosphere of claustrophobia (since the action is taking place in one building the entire time), and hidden secrets are hinted in it's wake. The acting is very resembled that of theatricality - And I like very well that the sentences have this form of construction. It feels like you are seeing this a play, of which this film is based. I had not heard of that play before, and must say - it must be a better experience to witness the twisted (yes I have said that word too many times already) form of this tale live, with performances on the stage. Yet, it feels like I already have. Due to the fact of the theatricality of the film. The end of the film, is tear-jerking, and you feel dirty about it afterwords. I will not spoil that one. I don't know what to say anymore of the film, other than to recommend it highly. Most highly to supporters of black comedy. I had a great time seeing the film, but it is not for the easily offended, due to the fact of it's incestuous theme, and the atmospheric disturbance. So yeah, there you have it. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes people just don't know how to say no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small-scale personal drama with plenty of barbed one-liners, pitch-black comedy and disturbing subject matter starring Parker Posey in one of her best ever roles, if you're not already sold on this movie then shame on you. The story revolves around "Jackie-O" Pascal (played by Posey), a young woman who is slightly . . . . . . unwell in the head. She stays with her brother (Freddie Prinze Jr.) and mother (Genevieve Bujold) in the family home. Everything is about to get quite tense when the other brother (Josh Hamilton) comes to visit, bringing a fianc&eacute; (Tori Spelling) with him. "Jackie-O" struggles to maintain a civil facade as her jealousy bubbles up to the surface and her mental state worsens. Adapted from a play by Wendy MacLeod, The House Of Yes doesn't need any major dressing or stylistic flourishes to impress. It gets by on the strength of the source material, the fine dialogue voiced by some great actors. Even Freddie Prinze Jr. and Tori Spelling come across well, that's how good the material is. Posey is simply unforgettable in the main role, as appealing as she is clearly disturbed. It's the kind of role that people need to remember she's capable of, it's a tour de force. Josh Hamilton works well opposite her and gets a lot of the more amusing and disturbing dialogue exchanges. Freddie Prinze Jr. is effectively naive and apparently innocent while Tori Spelling is bemused and increasingly exasperated with the strange household she finds herself in. Genevieve Bujold isn't on screen for long but makes a great impression with every moment she has. Director Mark Waters, who also adapted the play, handles everything perfectly. It may not be the most cinematic film that you'll ever see but it's something that plays out like a cross between Neil LaBute and David Mamet. And that's a solid endorsement, in my view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trite, predictable and poorly acted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackshrack
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor! I am very tired of these kinds of movies. They seem to be a reaction against Hollywood. And in the end these "independent" movies are just as trite and empty. The first 5 minutes are intriguing and comedic. Afterwards, you get the sense that it becomes more and more of a play. Which I am not sure that there is any purpose in filming a play. I would imagine that the play would be a lot better. With the psychological dimension, a play can bring the viewer to imagine more than a film. But to film basically a play, you get the least of both world, in my opinion. Unless it is done in a very original way, like dogville. This movie just seemed trite and transparent to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not as tasteless as it might sound"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wes Lambert (mockingmovies@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writing recently about "Happy Tears" gave me pause to think about my trajectory as a Parker Posey fan which began in the mid 90's with "Party Girl". Unfortunately the indie cult status of "Party Girl" means it has a very very very long wait on Blockbuster.com. They might as well admit that it will never ship. However today "The House of Yes" arrived in the mail. This is a brilliant, wicked film that might suffer from the accusation of being pretentious with it's over indulged, privileged characters and lightning fast witty dialogue. The story is that Marty Pascel (Josh Hamilton) has made the unbelievable blunder of bringing his mousey girlfriend (Tori Spelling) home to meet his wealthy, dysfunctional family on the very night they will all be virtually trapped together by a hurricane. The driving force of the family and the movie as a whole is Parker Posey as Marty's sister, Jackie-O. She in step with the weather outside is pretty much an evil, brilliant, psychotic (with the pills to prove it) bitch in a little black dress. An unhealthy obsession with Jackie Onassis and Marty are icing on the cake. Worse yet for the poor girlfriend, once back in the fold, Marty does very little to discourage Jackie-O and ultimately joins in her twisted games. Nothing ends well here unless you see the world through Jackie-O's eyes that is. "House of Yes" also contains perhaps my favorite line of dialogue ever - "If people are going to start telling the truth around here, I'm going to bed". If your experience with Parker Posey is one of "You've Got Mail" and "Scream 3" or worse yet "Superman Returns", I suggest taking a trip back to the 90's to see how she earned the title queen of the indies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    theater of the absurd is so over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sophiej468
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this 1997 film of an earlier play is the proof. there's just too much real absurdity going on. Genevieve Bujold as the disconnected mother is the best thing in it, but these days, that isn't saying much, because so many people are disconnected. What there is of a plot about sibling incest and insanity is today totally predictable. A few (too few)funny lines. no one seems to know quite what to do with Parker Posey, except Christopher Guest, in his wonderful mockumentaries, in which she's very funny. Here, she just seems strained. Tori Spelling is quite appealing as the only normal character, a donut shop waitress who lands in a pretentious upscale family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a showcase for Parker Posey, interesting; on its own, fairly dire...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Wendy MacLeod's play about a 1963 Thanksgiving reunion between a young man and his peculiar family, including a twin sister who is obsessed with Jacqueline Kennedy. Oppressively set in a shadowy house during a raging storm, this head-scratching talk-fest quickly tires both the eye and the ear. The scenario is full of dreary eccentrics, although Parker Posey's 'Jackie-O' is a dark, original creation unto herself. The actress, known for going out on a limb with basically unplayable roles, manages to walk a fine line between comically scabrous and downright scary (which, in an otherwise boring movie, is a triumph). Other performances by Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prinze, Jr., and a sadly under-valued Genevieve Bujold are not quite as on-target, mainly due to the sophomoric writing. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The writing kills this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy_Terry_Moore
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from Wendy MacLeod's play with almost no apparent changes for better or worse, director Mark Waters penned this screenplay about the incest between a Jackie Onassis-obsessed girl and her obliging brother. From start to finish, the air is filled with intellectual dialogue like "What?" and "I don't know", including the padded repeating of several lines like "What do you do all day?" - five times in a row, that one. The acting is small-time all around except for the appealing performances of Genevieve Bujold and Tori Spelling as a spooky mother and waifish fianc&eacute;, respectively. Sometimes interesting dark comedy has occasional eerie moments if one can get past the JFK assassination 'parody'. Pretty good title, anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker Posey At Her Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jerry (Nglas)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very few movies based on plays can be successful, but House of Yes is not one of those that fail. It succeeds where others have failed because of the energy put into a film that is mostly dialog. Parker Posey shines as Jackie-O, the mentally troubled sister of Josh Hamilton and Freddy Prinze Jr. Tori Spelling, whose only other film I have enjoyed was Trick, did a great job of playing Jackie-O's doormat. The movie is at its strongest when Parker bares her sadness, always hidden beneath sarcasm. A classic movie of family dysfunction without playing out the same old tired roles. This family is anything but a typical dysfunctional family and though they all appear to be nuts, part of you wants to run out and find a family just like them, because looking past all of the sarcasm and insults, you sense and feel the love. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see strong acting. Parker Posey is on top of her game here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of my all time favorites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato002-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Incestial witty good fun. A new kind of interesting. The humor is fast and in your face. I just don't see movies like this ever. Most are too scared to make fun of touchy matters to this extent or they try so hard to be artistic that it becomes horribly boring. If u don't suck you'd enjoy it. Hey if Parker Posey was my sis and she looked like Rachael Leigh Cook when she was young, i would support incest even more so then the way half you retards support those idiot ants marching(aka troops). Every character plays the perfect role for the kind of actor or actress they are. Such as Parker playing another Insane bitch, and Freddie Prince playing a moron. Great movie if your open minded. Not the kinda movie to watch if u hide behind worthless moral values given by people who worship things that don't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for Parker Posey and Tori Spelling Fans!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    splambo100
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To the folks that think Ms Spelling did not turn in a good performance-I disagree. I was pleased with the drama she showed. She was still a young actress and has of course improved with age, but she was lithe and active and in this film I noticed she has the most perfectly formed hands and forearms of any actress on film. Not sure why I noticed this but if you watch again, look for this. She should use this feature to full effect. She also has a bit of a striking profile and eyes, similar to some other famous actors on stage. She could use her eyes to show more emotion. She showed her range to more effect when she was showing concern for the other characters. Parker Posey, of course, was in her full glory in this performance. She showed great skill with the acting process. If you listen to the film without watching the action, you see that she uses her voice to great effect. She truly stole this show. Ms Bujold of course exhibits great range of craft, so great to see her always. To top off the show, there is a cameo by a young Rachael Lee Cook. Fine performances by the men. Overall unique experience!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The House of Yes - A Family Tale of Disturbia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sat down to see this film, not really know what to expect from it, and was surprised by it. Very surprised. I had read a small synopsis online, and thought, why not give it a shot? What I got, was a twisted black comedy, with subjects of taboo, and a messy kind of attitude. The film stars Parker Posey, Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prince Jr. (what, you can be in dramas too?) and Genevi&egrave;ve Bujold. The film is directed by Mark Waters, his first feature film debut to say. A sense of strong film debut to say it the least. The film is about a mentally unbalanced woman, whom believes she is Jackie Kennedy. Already from the first time you see her, you feel that madness inside of her ... trying to escape. She seems to misses her brother, very much indeed. He is bringing a "friend" over to Thanksgiving, this friend is revealed to be his fianc&eacute;e. From there, a twisted tale of familial construction is on the way. Just to get it out of the system. The mentally unbalanced woman, "Jackie-O" is in deep love with her own brother Marty. In fact so deep in love, that she will do anything to get him for herself. They have done it before, and "Jackie-O" wants more. They tell their youngest brother, the secret ... and he then tells this to the fianc&eacute;e of Marty, whom he have began falling for. You can call like this, he is in love with her. They do it too, while the brother and sister downstairs are busy themselves. One can start to think, about how the mother is feeling about this whole affair? Yup. I feel like I am walking on a layer of thin ice right now, but hey it's a dark comedy. What did you expect? Apart from the Incest in the film, that is handled with such subtlety that it feels enigmatic. And when it happens, you feel like you are rooting more for them, than what the norm is. I went there! The film have that atmosphere of claustrophobia (since the action is taking place in one building the entire time), and hidden secrets are hinted in it's wake. The acting is very resembled that of theatricality - And I like very well that the sentences have this form of construction. It feels like you are seeing this a play, of which this film is based. I had not heard of that play before, and must say - it must be a better experience to witness the twisted (yes I have said that word too many times already) form of this tale live, with performances on the stage. Yet, it feels like I already have. Due to the fact of the theatricality of the film. The end of the film, is tear-jerking, and you feel dirty about it afterwords. I will not spoil that one. I don't know what to say anymore of the film, other than to recommend it highly. Most highly to supporters of black comedy. I had a great time seeing the film, but it is not for the easily offended, due to the fact of it's incestuous theme, and the atmospheric disturbance. So yeah, there you have it. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes people just don't know how to say no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small-scale personal drama with plenty of barbed one-liners, pitch-black comedy and disturbing subject matter starring Parker Posey in one of her best ever roles, if you're not already sold on this movie then shame on you. The story revolves around "Jackie-O" Pascal (played by Posey), a young woman who is slightly . . . . . . unwell in the head. She stays with her brother (Freddie Prinze Jr.) and mother (Genevieve Bujold) in the family home. Everything is about to get quite tense when the other brother (Josh Hamilton) comes to visit, bringing a fianc&eacute; (Tori Spelling) with him. "Jackie-O" struggles to maintain a civil facade as her jealousy bubbles up to the surface and her mental state worsens. Adapted from a play by Wendy MacLeod, The House Of Yes doesn't need any major dressing or stylistic flourishes to impress. It gets by on the strength of the source material, the fine dialogue voiced by some great actors. Even Freddie Prinze Jr. and Tori Spelling come across well, that's how good the material is. Posey is simply unforgettable in the main role, as appealing as she is clearly disturbed. It's the kind of role that people need to remember she's capable of, it's a tour de force. Josh Hamilton works well opposite her and gets a lot of the more amusing and disturbing dialogue exchanges. Freddie Prinze Jr. is effectively naive and apparently innocent while Tori Spelling is bemused and increasingly exasperated with the strange household she finds herself in. Genevieve Bujold isn't on screen for long but makes a great impression with every moment she has. Director Mark Waters, who also adapted the play, handles everything perfectly. It may not be the most cinematic film that you'll ever see but it's something that plays out like a cross between Neil LaBute and David Mamet. And that's a solid endorsement, in my view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trite, predictable and poorly acted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackshrack
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor! I am very tired of these kinds of movies. They seem to be a reaction against Hollywood. And in the end these "independent" movies are just as trite and empty. The first 5 minutes are intriguing and comedic. Afterwards, you get the sense that it becomes more and more of a play. Which I am not sure that there is any purpose in filming a play. I would imagine that the play would be a lot better. With the psychological dimension, a play can bring the viewer to imagine more than a film. But to film basically a play, you get the least of both world, in my opinion. Unless it is done in a very original way, like dogville. This movie just seemed trite and transparent to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not as tasteless as it might sound"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wes Lambert (mockingmovies@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writing recently about "Happy Tears" gave me pause to think about my trajectory as a Parker Posey fan which began in the mid 90's with "Party Girl". Unfortunately the indie cult status of "Party Girl" means it has a very very very long wait on Blockbuster.com. They might as well admit that it will never ship. However today "The House of Yes" arrived in the mail. This is a brilliant, wicked film that might suffer from the accusation of being pretentious with it's over indulged, privileged characters and lightning fast witty dialogue. The story is that Marty Pascel (Josh Hamilton) has made the unbelievable blunder of bringing his mousey girlfriend (Tori Spelling) home to meet his wealthy, dysfunctional family on the very night they will all be virtually trapped together by a hurricane. The driving force of the family and the movie as a whole is Parker Posey as Marty's sister, Jackie-O. She in step with the weather outside is pretty much an evil, brilliant, psychotic (with the pills to prove it) bitch in a little black dress. An unhealthy obsession with Jackie Onassis and Marty are icing on the cake. Worse yet for the poor girlfriend, once back in the fold, Marty does very little to discourage Jackie-O and ultimately joins in her twisted games. Nothing ends well here unless you see the world through Jackie-O's eyes that is. "House of Yes" also contains perhaps my favorite line of dialogue ever - "If people are going to start telling the truth around here, I'm going to bed". If your experience with Parker Posey is one of "You've Got Mail" and "Scream 3" or worse yet "Superman Returns", I suggest taking a trip back to the 90's to see how she earned the title queen of the indies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    theater of the absurd is so over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sophiej468
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this 1997 film of an earlier play is the proof. there's just too much real absurdity going on. Genevieve Bujold as the disconnected mother is the best thing in it, but these days, that isn't saying much, because so many people are disconnected. What there is of a plot about sibling incest and insanity is today totally predictable. A few (too few)funny lines. no one seems to know quite what to do with Parker Posey, except Christopher Guest, in his wonderful mockumentaries, in which she's very funny. Here, she just seems strained. Tori Spelling is quite appealing as the only normal character, a donut shop waitress who lands in a pretentious upscale family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a showcase for Parker Posey, interesting; on its own, fairly dire...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Wendy MacLeod's play about a 1963 Thanksgiving reunion between a young man and his peculiar family, including a twin sister who is obsessed with Jacqueline Kennedy. Oppressively set in a shadowy house during a raging storm, this head-scratching talk-fest quickly tires both the eye and the ear. The scenario is full of dreary eccentrics, although Parker Posey's 'Jackie-O' is a dark, original creation unto herself. The actress, known for going out on a limb with basically unplayable roles, manages to walk a fine line between comically scabrous and downright scary (which, in an otherwise boring movie, is a triumph). Other performances by Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prinze, Jr., and a sadly under-valued Genevieve Bujold are not quite as on-target, mainly due to the sophomoric writing. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The writing kills this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy_Terry_Moore
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from Wendy MacLeod's play with almost no apparent changes for better or worse, director Mark Waters penned this screenplay about the incest between a Jackie Onassis-obsessed girl and her obliging brother. From start to finish, the air is filled with intellectual dialogue like "What?" and "I don't know", including the padded repeating of several lines like "What do you do all day?" - five times in a row, that one. The acting is small-time all around except for the appealing performances of Genevieve Bujold and Tori Spelling as a spooky mother and waifish fianc&eacute;, respectively. Sometimes interesting dark comedy has occasional eerie moments if one can get past the JFK assassination 'parody'. Pretty good title, anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker Posey At Her Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jerry (Nglas)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very few movies based on plays can be successful, but House of Yes is not one of those that fail. It succeeds where others have failed because of the energy put into a film that is mostly dialog. Parker Posey shines as Jackie-O, the mentally troubled sister of Josh Hamilton and Freddy Prinze Jr. Tori Spelling, whose only other film I have enjoyed was Trick, did a great job of playing Jackie-O's doormat. The movie is at its strongest when Parker bares her sadness, always hidden beneath sarcasm. A classic movie of family dysfunction without playing out the same old tired roles. This family is anything but a typical dysfunctional family and though they all appear to be nuts, part of you wants to run out and find a family just like them, because looking past all of the sarcasm and insults, you sense and feel the love. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see strong acting. Parker Posey is on top of her game here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of my all time favorites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato002-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Incestial witty good fun. A new kind of interesting. The humor is fast and in your face. I just don't see movies like this ever. Most are too scared to make fun of touchy matters to this extent or they try so hard to be artistic that it becomes horribly boring. If u don't suck you'd enjoy it. Hey if Parker Posey was my sis and she looked like Rachael Leigh Cook when she was young, i would support incest even more so then the way half you retards support those idiot ants marching(aka troops). Every character plays the perfect role for the kind of actor or actress they are. Such as Parker playing another Insane bitch, and Freddie Prince playing a moron. Great movie if your open minded. Not the kinda movie to watch if u hide behind worthless moral values given by people who worship things that don't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for Parker Posey and Tori Spelling Fans!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    splambo100
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To the folks that think Ms Spelling did not turn in a good performance-I disagree. I was pleased with the drama she showed. She was still a young actress and has of course improved with age, but she was lithe and active and in this film I noticed she has the most perfectly formed hands and forearms of any actress on film. Not sure why I noticed this but if you watch again, look for this. She should use this feature to full effect. She also has a bit of a striking profile and eyes, similar to some other famous actors on stage. She could use her eyes to show more emotion. She showed her range to more effect when she was showing concern for the other characters. Parker Posey, of course, was in her full glory in this performance. She showed great skill with the acting process. If you listen to the film without watching the action, you see that she uses her voice to great effect. She truly stole this show. Ms Bujold of course exhibits great range of craft, so great to see her always. To top off the show, there is a cameo by a young Rachael Lee Cook. Fine performances by the men. Overall unique experience!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The House of Yes - A Family Tale of Disturbia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sat down to see this film, not really know what to expect from it, and was surprised by it. Very surprised. I had read a small synopsis online, and thought, why not give it a shot? What I got, was a twisted black comedy, with subjects of taboo, and a messy kind of attitude. The film stars Parker Posey, Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prince Jr. (what, you can be in dramas too?) and Genevi&egrave;ve Bujold. The film is directed by Mark Waters, his first feature film debut to say. A sense of strong film debut to say it the least. The film is about a mentally unbalanced woman, whom believes she is Jackie Kennedy. Already from the first time you see her, you feel that madness inside of her ... trying to escape. She seems to misses her brother, very much indeed. He is bringing a "friend" over to Thanksgiving, this friend is revealed to be his fianc&eacute;e. From there, a twisted tale of familial construction is on the way. Just to get it out of the system. The mentally unbalanced woman, "Jackie-O" is in deep love with her own brother Marty. In fact so deep in love, that she will do anything to get him for herself. They have done it before, and "Jackie-O" wants more. They tell their youngest brother, the secret ... and he then tells this to the fianc&eacute;e of Marty, whom he have began falling for. You can call like this, he is in love with her. They do it too, while the brother and sister downstairs are busy themselves. One can start to think, about how the mother is feeling about this whole affair? Yup. I feel like I am walking on a layer of thin ice right now, but hey it's a dark comedy. What did you expect? Apart from the Incest in the film, that is handled with such subtlety that it feels enigmatic. And when it happens, you feel like you are rooting more for them, than what the norm is. I went there! The film have that atmosphere of claustrophobia (since the action is taking place in one building the entire time), and hidden secrets are hinted in it's wake. The acting is very resembled that of theatricality - And I like very well that the sentences have this form of construction. It feels like you are seeing this a play, of which this film is based. I had not heard of that play before, and must say - it must be a better experience to witness the twisted (yes I have said that word too many times already) form of this tale live, with performances on the stage. Yet, it feels like I already have. Due to the fact of the theatricality of the film. The end of the film, is tear-jerking, and you feel dirty about it afterwords. I will not spoil that one. I don't know what to say anymore of the film, other than to recommend it highly. Most highly to supporters of black comedy. I had a great time seeing the film, but it is not for the easily offended, due to the fact of it's incestuous theme, and the atmospheric disturbance. So yeah, there you have it. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes people just don't know how to say no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small-scale personal drama with plenty of barbed one-liners, pitch-black comedy and disturbing subject matter starring Parker Posey in one of her best ever roles, if you're not already sold on this movie then shame on you. The story revolves around "Jackie-O" Pascal (played by Posey), a young woman who is slightly . . . . . . unwell in the head. She stays with her brother (Freddie Prinze Jr.) and mother (Genevieve Bujold) in the family home. Everything is about to get quite tense when the other brother (Josh Hamilton) comes to visit, bringing a fianc&eacute; (Tori Spelling) with him. "Jackie-O" struggles to maintain a civil facade as her jealousy bubbles up to the surface and her mental state worsens. Adapted from a play by Wendy MacLeod, The House Of Yes doesn't need any major dressing or stylistic flourishes to impress. It gets by on the strength of the source material, the fine dialogue voiced by some great actors. Even Freddie Prinze Jr. and Tori Spelling come across well, that's how good the material is. Posey is simply unforgettable in the main role, as appealing as she is clearly disturbed. It's the kind of role that people need to remember she's capable of, it's a tour de force. Josh Hamilton works well opposite her and gets a lot of the more amusing and disturbing dialogue exchanges. Freddie Prinze Jr. is effectively naive and apparently innocent while Tori Spelling is bemused and increasingly exasperated with the strange household she finds herself in. Genevieve Bujold isn't on screen for long but makes a great impression with every moment she has. Director Mark Waters, who also adapted the play, handles everything perfectly. It may not be the most cinematic film that you'll ever see but it's something that plays out like a cross between Neil LaBute and David Mamet. And that's a solid endorsement, in my view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trite, predictable and poorly acted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackshrack
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor! I am very tired of these kinds of movies. They seem to be a reaction against Hollywood. And in the end these "independent" movies are just as trite and empty. The first 5 minutes are intriguing and comedic. Afterwards, you get the sense that it becomes more and more of a play. Which I am not sure that there is any purpose in filming a play. I would imagine that the play would be a lot better. With the psychological dimension, a play can bring the viewer to imagine more than a film. But to film basically a play, you get the least of both world, in my opinion. Unless it is done in a very original way, like dogville. This movie just seemed trite and transparent to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not as tasteless as it might sound"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wes Lambert (mockingmovies@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writing recently about "Happy Tears" gave me pause to think about my trajectory as a Parker Posey fan which began in the mid 90's with "Party Girl". Unfortunately the indie cult status of "Party Girl" means it has a very very very long wait on Blockbuster.com. They might as well admit that it will never ship. However today "The House of Yes" arrived in the mail. This is a brilliant, wicked film that might suffer from the accusation of being pretentious with it's over indulged, privileged characters and lightning fast witty dialogue. The story is that Marty Pascel (Josh Hamilton) has made the unbelievable blunder of bringing his mousey girlfriend (Tori Spelling) home to meet his wealthy, dysfunctional family on the very night they will all be virtually trapped together by a hurricane. The driving force of the family and the movie as a whole is Parker Posey as Marty's sister, Jackie-O. She in step with the weather outside is pretty much an evil, brilliant, psychotic (with the pills to prove it) bitch in a little black dress. An unhealthy obsession with Jackie Onassis and Marty are icing on the cake. Worse yet for the poor girlfriend, once back in the fold, Marty does very little to discourage Jackie-O and ultimately joins in her twisted games. Nothing ends well here unless you see the world through Jackie-O's eyes that is. "House of Yes" also contains perhaps my favorite line of dialogue ever - "If people are going to start telling the truth around here, I'm going to bed". If your experience with Parker Posey is one of "You've Got Mail" and "Scream 3" or worse yet "Superman Returns", I suggest taking a trip back to the 90's to see how she earned the title queen of the indies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    theater of the absurd is so over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sophiej468
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this 1997 film of an earlier play is the proof. there's just too much real absurdity going on. Genevieve Bujold as the disconnected mother is the best thing in it, but these days, that isn't saying much, because so many people are disconnected. What there is of a plot about sibling incest and insanity is today totally predictable. A few (too few)funny lines. no one seems to know quite what to do with Parker Posey, except Christopher Guest, in his wonderful mockumentaries, in which she's very funny. Here, she just seems strained. Tori Spelling is quite appealing as the only normal character, a donut shop waitress who lands in a pretentious upscale family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a showcase for Parker Posey, interesting; on its own, fairly dire...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Wendy MacLeod's play about a 1963 Thanksgiving reunion between a young man and his peculiar family, including a twin sister who is obsessed with Jacqueline Kennedy. Oppressively set in a shadowy house during a raging storm, this head-scratching talk-fest quickly tires both the eye and the ear. The scenario is full of dreary eccentrics, although Parker Posey's 'Jackie-O' is a dark, original creation unto herself. The actress, known for going out on a limb with basically unplayable roles, manages to walk a fine line between comically scabrous and downright scary (which, in an otherwise boring movie, is a triumph). Other performances by Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prinze, Jr., and a sadly under-valued Genevieve Bujold are not quite as on-target, mainly due to the sophomoric writing. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The writing kills this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy_Terry_Moore
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from Wendy MacLeod's play with almost no apparent changes for better or worse, director Mark Waters penned this screenplay about the incest between a Jackie Onassis-obsessed girl and her obliging brother. From start to finish, the air is filled with intellectual dialogue like "What?" and "I don't know", including the padded repeating of several lines like "What do you do all day?" - five times in a row, that one. The acting is small-time all around except for the appealing performances of Genevieve Bujold and Tori Spelling as a spooky mother and waifish fianc&eacute;, respectively. Sometimes interesting dark comedy has occasional eerie moments if one can get past the JFK assassination 'parody'. Pretty good title, anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker Posey At Her Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jerry (Nglas)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very few movies based on plays can be successful, but House of Yes is not one of those that fail. It succeeds where others have failed because of the energy put into a film that is mostly dialog. Parker Posey shines as Jackie-O, the mentally troubled sister of Josh Hamilton and Freddy Prinze Jr. Tori Spelling, whose only other film I have enjoyed was Trick, did a great job of playing Jackie-O's doormat. The movie is at its strongest when Parker bares her sadness, always hidden beneath sarcasm. A classic movie of family dysfunction without playing out the same old tired roles. This family is anything but a typical dysfunctional family and though they all appear to be nuts, part of you wants to run out and find a family just like them, because looking past all of the sarcasm and insults, you sense and feel the love. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see strong acting. Parker Posey is on top of her game here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of my all time favorites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato002-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Incestial witty good fun. A new kind of interesting. The humor is fast and in your face. I just don't see movies like this ever. Most are too scared to make fun of touchy matters to this extent or they try so hard to be artistic that it becomes horribly boring. If u don't suck you'd enjoy it. Hey if Parker Posey was my sis and she looked like Rachael Leigh Cook when she was young, i would support incest even more so then the way half you retards support those idiot ants marching(aka troops). Every character plays the perfect role for the kind of actor or actress they are. Such as Parker playing another Insane bitch, and Freddie Prince playing a moron. Great movie if your open minded. Not the kinda movie to watch if u hide behind worthless moral values given by people who worship things that don't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for Parker Posey and Tori Spelling Fans!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    splambo100
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To the folks that think Ms Spelling did not turn in a good performance-I disagree. I was pleased with the drama she showed. She was still a young actress and has of course improved with age, but she was lithe and active and in this film I noticed she has the most perfectly formed hands and forearms of any actress on film. Not sure why I noticed this but if you watch again, look for this. She should use this feature to full effect. She also has a bit of a striking profile and eyes, similar to some other famous actors on stage. She could use her eyes to show more emotion. She showed her range to more effect when she was showing concern for the other characters. Parker Posey, of course, was in her full glory in this performance. She showed great skill with the acting process. If you listen to the film without watching the action, you see that she uses her voice to great effect. She truly stole this show. Ms Bujold of course exhibits great range of craft, so great to see her always. To top off the show, there is a cameo by a young Rachael Lee Cook. Fine performances by the men. Overall unique experience!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The House of Yes - A Family Tale of Disturbia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sat down to see this film, not really know what to expect from it, and was surprised by it. Very surprised. I had read a small synopsis online, and thought, why not give it a shot? What I got, was a twisted black comedy, with subjects of taboo, and a messy kind of attitude. The film stars Parker Posey, Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prince Jr. (what, you can be in dramas too?) and Genevi&egrave;ve Bujold. The film is directed by Mark Waters, his first feature film debut to say. A sense of strong film debut to say it the least. The film is about a mentally unbalanced woman, whom believes she is Jackie Kennedy. Already from the first time you see her, you feel that madness inside of her ... trying to escape. She seems to misses her brother, very much indeed. He is bringing a "friend" over to Thanksgiving, this friend is revealed to be his fianc&eacute;e. From there, a twisted tale of familial construction is on the way. Just to get it out of the system. The mentally unbalanced woman, "Jackie-O" is in deep love with her own brother Marty. In fact so deep in love, that she will do anything to get him for herself. They have done it before, and "Jackie-O" wants more. They tell their youngest brother, the secret ... and he then tells this to the fianc&eacute;e of Marty, whom he have began falling for. You can call like this, he is in love with her. They do it too, while the brother and sister downstairs are busy themselves. One can start to think, about how the mother is feeling about this whole affair? Yup. I feel like I am walking on a layer of thin ice right now, but hey it's a dark comedy. What did you expect? Apart from the Incest in the film, that is handled with such subtlety that it feels enigmatic. And when it happens, you feel like you are rooting more for them, than what the norm is. I went there! The film have that atmosphere of claustrophobia (since the action is taking place in one building the entire time), and hidden secrets are hinted in it's wake. The acting is very resembled that of theatricality - And I like very well that the sentences have this form of construction. It feels like you are seeing this a play, of which this film is based. I had not heard of that play before, and must say - it must be a better experience to witness the twisted (yes I have said that word too many times already) form of this tale live, with performances on the stage. Yet, it feels like I already have. Due to the fact of the theatricality of the film. The end of the film, is tear-jerking, and you feel dirty about it afterwords. I will not spoil that one. I don't know what to say anymore of the film, other than to recommend it highly. Most highly to supporters of black comedy. I had a great time seeing the film, but it is not for the easily offended, due to the fact of it's incestuous theme, and the atmospheric disturbance. So yeah, there you have it. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes people just don't know how to say no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small-scale personal drama with plenty of barbed one-liners, pitch-black comedy and disturbing subject matter starring Parker Posey in one of her best ever roles, if you're not already sold on this movie then shame on you. The story revolves around "Jackie-O" Pascal (played by Posey), a young woman who is slightly . . . . . . unwell in the head. She stays with her brother (Freddie Prinze Jr.) and mother (Genevieve Bujold) in the family home. Everything is about to get quite tense when the other brother (Josh Hamilton) comes to visit, bringing a fianc&eacute; (Tori Spelling) with him. "Jackie-O" struggles to maintain a civil facade as her jealousy bubbles up to the surface and her mental state worsens. Adapted from a play by Wendy MacLeod, The House Of Yes doesn't need any major dressing or stylistic flourishes to impress. It gets by on the strength of the source material, the fine dialogue voiced by some great actors. Even Freddie Prinze Jr. and Tori Spelling come across well, that's how good the material is. Posey is simply unforgettable in the main role, as appealing as she is clearly disturbed. It's the kind of role that people need to remember she's capable of, it's a tour de force. Josh Hamilton works well opposite her and gets a lot of the more amusing and disturbing dialogue exchanges. Freddie Prinze Jr. is effectively naive and apparently innocent while Tori Spelling is bemused and increasingly exasperated with the strange household she finds herself in. Genevieve Bujold isn't on screen for long but makes a great impression with every moment she has. Director Mark Waters, who also adapted the play, handles everything perfectly. It may not be the most cinematic film that you'll ever see but it's something that plays out like a cross between Neil LaBute and David Mamet. And that's a solid endorsement, in my view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trite, predictable and poorly acted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackshrack
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor! I am very tired of these kinds of movies. They seem to be a reaction against Hollywood. And in the end these "independent" movies are just as trite and empty. The first 5 minutes are intriguing and comedic. Afterwards, you get the sense that it becomes more and more of a play. Which I am not sure that there is any purpose in filming a play. I would imagine that the play would be a lot better. With the psychological dimension, a play can bring the viewer to imagine more than a film. But to film basically a play, you get the least of both world, in my opinion. Unless it is done in a very original way, like dogville. This movie just seemed trite and transparent to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not as tasteless as it might sound"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wes Lambert (mockingmovies@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writing recently about "Happy Tears" gave me pause to think about my trajectory as a Parker Posey fan which began in the mid 90's with "Party Girl". Unfortunately the indie cult status of "Party Girl" means it has a very very very long wait on Blockbuster.com. They might as well admit that it will never ship. However today "The House of Yes" arrived in the mail. This is a brilliant, wicked film that might suffer from the accusation of being pretentious with it's over indulged, privileged characters and lightning fast witty dialogue. The story is that Marty Pascel (Josh Hamilton) has made the unbelievable blunder of bringing his mousey girlfriend (Tori Spelling) home to meet his wealthy, dysfunctional family on the very night they will all be virtually trapped together by a hurricane. The driving force of the family and the movie as a whole is Parker Posey as Marty's sister, Jackie-O. She in step with the weather outside is pretty much an evil, brilliant, psychotic (with the pills to prove it) bitch in a little black dress. An unhealthy obsession with Jackie Onassis and Marty are icing on the cake. Worse yet for the poor girlfriend, once back in the fold, Marty does very little to discourage Jackie-O and ultimately joins in her twisted games. Nothing ends well here unless you see the world through Jackie-O's eyes that is. "House of Yes" also contains perhaps my favorite line of dialogue ever - "If people are going to start telling the truth around here, I'm going to bed". If your experience with Parker Posey is one of "You've Got Mail" and "Scream 3" or worse yet "Superman Returns", I suggest taking a trip back to the 90's to see how she earned the title queen of the indies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    theater of the absurd is so over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sophiej468
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this 1997 film of an earlier play is the proof. there's just too much real absurdity going on. Genevieve Bujold as the disconnected mother is the best thing in it, but these days, that isn't saying much, because so many people are disconnected. What there is of a plot about sibling incest and insanity is today totally predictable. A few (too few)funny lines. no one seems to know quite what to do with Parker Posey, except Christopher Guest, in his wonderful mockumentaries, in which she's very funny. Here, she just seems strained. Tori Spelling is quite appealing as the only normal character, a donut shop waitress who lands in a pretentious upscale family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a showcase for Parker Posey, interesting; on its own, fairly dire...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Wendy MacLeod's play about a 1963 Thanksgiving reunion between a young man and his peculiar family, including a twin sister who is obsessed with Jacqueline Kennedy. Oppressively set in a shadowy house during a raging storm, this head-scratching talk-fest quickly tires both the eye and the ear. The scenario is full of dreary eccentrics, although Parker Posey's 'Jackie-O' is a dark, original creation unto herself. The actress, known for going out on a limb with basically unplayable roles, manages to walk a fine line between comically scabrous and downright scary (which, in an otherwise boring movie, is a triumph). Other performances by Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prinze, Jr., and a sadly under-valued Genevieve Bujold are not quite as on-target, mainly due to the sophomoric writing. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The writing kills this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy_Terry_Moore
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from Wendy MacLeod's play with almost no apparent changes for better or worse, director Mark Waters penned this screenplay about the incest between a Jackie Onassis-obsessed girl and her obliging brother. From start to finish, the air is filled with intellectual dialogue like "What?" and "I don't know", including the padded repeating of several lines like "What do you do all day?" - five times in a row, that one. The acting is small-time all around except for the appealing performances of Genevieve Bujold and Tori Spelling as a spooky mother and waifish fianc&eacute;, respectively. Sometimes interesting dark comedy has occasional eerie moments if one can get past the JFK assassination 'parody'. Pretty good title, anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker Posey At Her Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jerry (Nglas)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very few movies based on plays can be successful, but House of Yes is not one of those that fail. It succeeds where others have failed because of the energy put into a film that is mostly dialog. Parker Posey shines as Jackie-O, the mentally troubled sister of Josh Hamilton and Freddy Prinze Jr. Tori Spelling, whose only other film I have enjoyed was Trick, did a great job of playing Jackie-O's doormat. The movie is at its strongest when Parker bares her sadness, always hidden beneath sarcasm. A classic movie of family dysfunction without playing out the same old tired roles. This family is anything but a typical dysfunctional family and though they all appear to be nuts, part of you wants to run out and find a family just like them, because looking past all of the sarcasm and insults, you sense and feel the love. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see strong acting. Parker Posey is on top of her game here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of my all time favorites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato002-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Incestial witty good fun. A new kind of interesting. The humor is fast and in your face. I just don't see movies like this ever. Most are too scared to make fun of touchy matters to this extent or they try so hard to be artistic that it becomes horribly boring. If u don't suck you'd enjoy it. Hey if Parker Posey was my sis and she looked like Rachael Leigh Cook when she was young, i would support incest even more so then the way half you retards support those idiot ants marching(aka troops). Every character plays the perfect role for the kind of actor or actress they are. Such as Parker playing another Insane bitch, and Freddie Prince playing a moron. Great movie if your open minded. Not the kinda movie to watch if u hide behind worthless moral values given by people who worship things that don't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for Parker Posey and Tori Spelling Fans!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    splambo100
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To the folks that think Ms Spelling did not turn in a good performance-I disagree. I was pleased with the drama she showed. She was still a young actress and has of course improved with age, but she was lithe and active and in this film I noticed she has the most perfectly formed hands and forearms of any actress on film. Not sure why I noticed this but if you watch again, look for this. She should use this feature to full effect. She also has a bit of a striking profile and eyes, similar to some other famous actors on stage. She could use her eyes to show more emotion. She showed her range to more effect when she was showing concern for the other characters. Parker Posey, of course, was in her full glory in this performance. She showed great skill with the acting process. If you listen to the film without watching the action, you see that she uses her voice to great effect. She truly stole this show. Ms Bujold of course exhibits great range of craft, so great to see her always. To top off the show, there is a cameo by a young Rachael Lee Cook. Fine performances by the men. Overall unique experience!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The House of Yes - A Family Tale of Disturbia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sat down to see this film, not really know what to expect from it, and was surprised by it. Very surprised. I had read a small synopsis online, and thought, why not give it a shot? What I got, was a twisted black comedy, with subjects of taboo, and a messy kind of attitude. The film stars Parker Posey, Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prince Jr. (what, you can be in dramas too?) and Genevi&egrave;ve Bujold. The film is directed by Mark Waters, his first feature film debut to say. A sense of strong film debut to say it the least. The film is about a mentally unbalanced woman, whom believes she is Jackie Kennedy. Already from the first time you see her, you feel that madness inside of her ... trying to escape. She seems to misses her brother, very much indeed. He is bringing a "friend" over to Thanksgiving, this friend is revealed to be his fianc&eacute;e. From there, a twisted tale of familial construction is on the way. Just to get it out of the system. The mentally unbalanced woman, "Jackie-O" is in deep love with her own brother Marty. In fact so deep in love, that she will do anything to get him for herself. They have done it before, and "Jackie-O" wants more. They tell their youngest brother, the secret ... and he then tells this to the fianc&eacute;e of Marty, whom he have began falling for. You can call like this, he is in love with her. They do it too, while the brother and sister downstairs are busy themselves. One can start to think, about how the mother is feeling about this whole affair? Yup. I feel like I am walking on a layer of thin ice right now, but hey it's a dark comedy. What did you expect? Apart from the Incest in the film, that is handled with such subtlety that it feels enigmatic. And when it happens, you feel like you are rooting more for them, than what the norm is. I went there! The film have that atmosphere of claustrophobia (since the action is taking place in one building the entire time), and hidden secrets are hinted in it's wake. The acting is very resembled that of theatricality - And I like very well that the sentences have this form of construction. It feels like you are seeing this a play, of which this film is based. I had not heard of that play before, and must say - it must be a better experience to witness the twisted (yes I have said that word too many times already) form of this tale live, with performances on the stage. Yet, it feels like I already have. Due to the fact of the theatricality of the film. The end of the film, is tear-jerking, and you feel dirty about it afterwords. I will not spoil that one. I don't know what to say anymore of the film, other than to recommend it highly. Most highly to supporters of black comedy. I had a great time seeing the film, but it is not for the easily offended, due to the fact of it's incestuous theme, and the atmospheric disturbance. So yeah, there you have it. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes people just don't know how to say no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small-scale personal drama with plenty of barbed one-liners, pitch-black comedy and disturbing subject matter starring Parker Posey in one of her best ever roles, if you're not already sold on this movie then shame on you. The story revolves around "Jackie-O" Pascal (played by Posey), a young woman who is slightly . . . . . . unwell in the head. She stays with her brother (Freddie Prinze Jr.) and mother (Genevieve Bujold) in the family home. Everything is about to get quite tense when the other brother (Josh Hamilton) comes to visit, bringing a fianc&eacute; (Tori Spelling) with him. "Jackie-O" struggles to maintain a civil facade as her jealousy bubbles up to the surface and her mental state worsens. Adapted from a play by Wendy MacLeod, The House Of Yes doesn't need any major dressing or stylistic flourishes to impress. It gets by on the strength of the source material, the fine dialogue voiced by some great actors. Even Freddie Prinze Jr. and Tori Spelling come across well, that's how good the material is. Posey is simply unforgettable in the main role, as appealing as she is clearly disturbed. It's the kind of role that people need to remember she's capable of, it's a tour de force. Josh Hamilton works well opposite her and gets a lot of the more amusing and disturbing dialogue exchanges. Freddie Prinze Jr. is effectively naive and apparently innocent while Tori Spelling is bemused and increasingly exasperated with the strange household she finds herself in. Genevieve Bujold isn't on screen for long but makes a great impression with every moment she has. Director Mark Waters, who also adapted the play, handles everything perfectly. It may not be the most cinematic film that you'll ever see but it's something that plays out like a cross between Neil LaBute and David Mamet. And that's a solid endorsement, in my view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trite, predictable and poorly acted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackshrack
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor! I am very tired of these kinds of movies. They seem to be a reaction against Hollywood. And in the end these "independent" movies are just as trite and empty. The first 5 minutes are intriguing and comedic. Afterwards, you get the sense that it becomes more and more of a play. Which I am not sure that there is any purpose in filming a play. I would imagine that the play would be a lot better. With the psychological dimension, a play can bring the viewer to imagine more than a film. But to film basically a play, you get the least of both world, in my opinion. Unless it is done in a very original way, like dogville. This movie just seemed trite and transparent to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not as tasteless as it might sound"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wes Lambert (mockingmovies@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writing recently about "Happy Tears" gave me pause to think about my trajectory as a Parker Posey fan which began in the mid 90's with "Party Girl". Unfortunately the indie cult status of "Party Girl" means it has a very very very long wait on Blockbuster.com. They might as well admit that it will never ship. However today "The House of Yes" arrived in the mail. This is a brilliant, wicked film that might suffer from the accusation of being pretentious with it's over indulged, privileged characters and lightning fast witty dialogue. The story is that Marty Pascel (Josh Hamilton) has made the unbelievable blunder of bringing his mousey girlfriend (Tori Spelling) home to meet his wealthy, dysfunctional family on the very night they will all be virtually trapped together by a hurricane. The driving force of the family and the movie as a whole is Parker Posey as Marty's sister, Jackie-O. She in step with the weather outside is pretty much an evil, brilliant, psychotic (with the pills to prove it) bitch in a little black dress. An unhealthy obsession with Jackie Onassis and Marty are icing on the cake. Worse yet for the poor girlfriend, once back in the fold, Marty does very little to discourage Jackie-O and ultimately joins in her twisted games. Nothing ends well here unless you see the world through Jackie-O's eyes that is. "House of Yes" also contains perhaps my favorite line of dialogue ever - "If people are going to start telling the truth around here, I'm going to bed". If your experience with Parker Posey is one of "You've Got Mail" and "Scream 3" or worse yet "Superman Returns", I suggest taking a trip back to the 90's to see how she earned the title queen of the indies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    theater of the absurd is so over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sophiej468
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this 1997 film of an earlier play is the proof. there's just too much real absurdity going on. Genevieve Bujold as the disconnected mother is the best thing in it, but these days, that isn't saying much, because so many people are disconnected. What there is of a plot about sibling incest and insanity is today totally predictable. A few (too few)funny lines. no one seems to know quite what to do with Parker Posey, except Christopher Guest, in his wonderful mockumentaries, in which she's very funny. Here, she just seems strained. Tori Spelling is quite appealing as the only normal character, a donut shop waitress who lands in a pretentious upscale family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a showcase for Parker Posey, interesting; on its own, fairly dire...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Wendy MacLeod's play about a 1963 Thanksgiving reunion between a young man and his peculiar family, including a twin sister who is obsessed with Jacqueline Kennedy. Oppressively set in a shadowy house during a raging storm, this head-scratching talk-fest quickly tires both the eye and the ear. The scenario is full of dreary eccentrics, although Parker Posey's 'Jackie-O' is a dark, original creation unto herself. The actress, known for going out on a limb with basically unplayable roles, manages to walk a fine line between comically scabrous and downright scary (which, in an otherwise boring movie, is a triumph). Other performances by Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prinze, Jr., and a sadly under-valued Genevieve Bujold are not quite as on-target, mainly due to the sophomoric writing. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The writing kills this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy_Terry_Moore
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from Wendy MacLeod's play with almost no apparent changes for better or worse, director Mark Waters penned this screenplay about the incest between a Jackie Onassis-obsessed girl and her obliging brother. From start to finish, the air is filled with intellectual dialogue like "What?" and "I don't know", including the padded repeating of several lines like "What do you do all day?" - five times in a row, that one. The acting is small-time all around except for the appealing performances of Genevieve Bujold and Tori Spelling as a spooky mother and waifish fianc&eacute;, respectively. Sometimes interesting dark comedy has occasional eerie moments if one can get past the JFK assassination 'parody'. Pretty good title, anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker Posey At Her Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jerry (Nglas)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very few movies based on plays can be successful, but House of Yes is not one of those that fail. It succeeds where others have failed because of the energy put into a film that is mostly dialog. Parker Posey shines as Jackie-O, the mentally troubled sister of Josh Hamilton and Freddy Prinze Jr. Tori Spelling, whose only other film I have enjoyed was Trick, did a great job of playing Jackie-O's doormat. The movie is at its strongest when Parker bares her sadness, always hidden beneath sarcasm. A classic movie of family dysfunction without playing out the same old tired roles. This family is anything but a typical dysfunctional family and though they all appear to be nuts, part of you wants to run out and find a family just like them, because looking past all of the sarcasm and insults, you sense and feel the love. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see strong acting. Parker Posey is on top of her game here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of my all time favorites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato002-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Incestial witty good fun. A new kind of interesting. The humor is fast and in your face. I just don't see movies like this ever. Most are too scared to make fun of touchy matters to this extent or they try so hard to be artistic that it becomes horribly boring. If u don't suck you'd enjoy it. Hey if Parker Posey was my sis and she looked like Rachael Leigh Cook when she was young, i would support incest even more so then the way half you retards support those idiot ants marching(aka troops). Every character plays the perfect role for the kind of actor or actress they are. Such as Parker playing another Insane bitch, and Freddie Prince playing a moron. Great movie if your open minded. Not the kinda movie to watch if u hide behind worthless moral values given by people who worship things that don't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for Parker Posey and Tori Spelling Fans!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    splambo100
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To the folks that think Ms Spelling did not turn in a good performance-I disagree. I was pleased with the drama she showed. She was still a young actress and has of course improved with age, but she was lithe and active and in this film I noticed she has the most perfectly formed hands and forearms of any actress on film. Not sure why I noticed this but if you watch again, look for this. She should use this feature to full effect. She also has a bit of a striking profile and eyes, similar to some other famous actors on stage. She could use her eyes to show more emotion. She showed her range to more effect when she was showing concern for the other characters. Parker Posey, of course, was in her full glory in this performance. She showed great skill with the acting process. If you listen to the film without watching the action, you see that she uses her voice to great effect. She truly stole this show. Ms Bujold of course exhibits great range of craft, so great to see her always. To top off the show, there is a cameo by a young Rachael Lee Cook. Fine performances by the men. Overall unique experience!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The House of Yes - A Family Tale of Disturbia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sat down to see this film, not really know what to expect from it, and was surprised by it. Very surprised. I had read a small synopsis online, and thought, why not give it a shot? What I got, was a twisted black comedy, with subjects of taboo, and a messy kind of attitude. The film stars Parker Posey, Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prince Jr. (what, you can be in dramas too?) and Genevi&egrave;ve Bujold. The film is directed by Mark Waters, his first feature film debut to say. A sense of strong film debut to say it the least. The film is about a mentally unbalanced woman, whom believes she is Jackie Kennedy. Already from the first time you see her, you feel that madness inside of her ... trying to escape. She seems to misses her brother, very much indeed. He is bringing a "friend" over to Thanksgiving, this friend is revealed to be his fianc&eacute;e. From there, a twisted tale of familial construction is on the way. Just to get it out of the system. The mentally unbalanced woman, "Jackie-O" is in deep love with her own brother Marty. In fact so deep in love, that she will do anything to get him for herself. They have done it before, and "Jackie-O" wants more. They tell their youngest brother, the secret ... and he then tells this to the fianc&eacute;e of Marty, whom he have began falling for. You can call like this, he is in love with her. They do it too, while the brother and sister downstairs are busy themselves. One can start to think, about how the mother is feeling about this whole affair? Yup. I feel like I am walking on a layer of thin ice right now, but hey it's a dark comedy. What did you expect? Apart from the Incest in the film, that is handled with such subtlety that it feels enigmatic. And when it happens, you feel like you are rooting more for them, than what the norm is. I went there! The film have that atmosphere of claustrophobia (since the action is taking place in one building the entire time), and hidden secrets are hinted in it's wake. The acting is very resembled that of theatricality - And I like very well that the sentences have this form of construction. It feels like you are seeing this a play, of which this film is based. I had not heard of that play before, and must say - it must be a better experience to witness the twisted (yes I have said that word too many times already) form of this tale live, with performances on the stage. Yet, it feels like I already have. Due to the fact of the theatricality of the film. The end of the film, is tear-jerking, and you feel dirty about it afterwords. I will not spoil that one. I don't know what to say anymore of the film, other than to recommend it highly. Most highly to supporters of black comedy. I had a great time seeing the film, but it is not for the easily offended, due to the fact of it's incestuous theme, and the atmospheric disturbance. So yeah, there you have it. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes people just don't know how to say no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small-scale personal drama with plenty of barbed one-liners, pitch-black comedy and disturbing subject matter starring Parker Posey in one of her best ever roles, if you're not already sold on this movie then shame on you. The story revolves around "Jackie-O" Pascal (played by Posey), a young woman who is slightly . . . . . . unwell in the head. She stays with her brother (Freddie Prinze Jr.) and mother (Genevieve Bujold) in the family home. Everything is about to get quite tense when the other brother (Josh Hamilton) comes to visit, bringing a fianc&eacute; (Tori Spelling) with him. "Jackie-O" struggles to maintain a civil facade as her jealousy bubbles up to the surface and her mental state worsens. Adapted from a play by Wendy MacLeod, The House Of Yes doesn't need any major dressing or stylistic flourishes to impress. It gets by on the strength of the source material, the fine dialogue voiced by some great actors. Even Freddie Prinze Jr. and Tori Spelling come across well, that's how good the material is. Posey is simply unforgettable in the main role, as appealing as she is clearly disturbed. It's the kind of role that people need to remember she's capable of, it's a tour de force. Josh Hamilton works well opposite her and gets a lot of the more amusing and disturbing dialogue exchanges. Freddie Prinze Jr. is effectively naive and apparently innocent while Tori Spelling is bemused and increasingly exasperated with the strange household she finds herself in. Genevieve Bujold isn't on screen for long but makes a great impression with every moment she has. Director Mark Waters, who also adapted the play, handles everything perfectly. It may not be the most cinematic film that you'll ever see but it's something that plays out like a cross between Neil LaBute and David Mamet. And that's a solid endorsement, in my view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trite, predictable and poorly acted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackshrack
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor! I am very tired of these kinds of movies. They seem to be a reaction against Hollywood. And in the end these "independent" movies are just as trite and empty. The first 5 minutes are intriguing and comedic. Afterwards, you get the sense that it becomes more and more of a play. Which I am not sure that there is any purpose in filming a play. I would imagine that the play would be a lot better. With the psychological dimension, a play can bring the viewer to imagine more than a film. But to film basically a play, you get the least of both world, in my opinion. Unless it is done in a very original way, like dogville. This movie just seemed trite and transparent to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not as tasteless as it might sound"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wes Lambert (mockingmovies@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writing recently about "Happy Tears" gave me pause to think about my trajectory as a Parker Posey fan which began in the mid 90's with "Party Girl". Unfortunately the indie cult status of "Party Girl" means it has a very very very long wait on Blockbuster.com. They might as well admit that it will never ship. However today "The House of Yes" arrived in the mail. This is a brilliant, wicked film that might suffer from the accusation of being pretentious with it's over indulged, privileged characters and lightning fast witty dialogue. The story is that Marty Pascel (Josh Hamilton) has made the unbelievable blunder of bringing his mousey girlfriend (Tori Spelling) home to meet his wealthy, dysfunctional family on the very night they will all be virtually trapped together by a hurricane. The driving force of the family and the movie as a whole is Parker Posey as Marty's sister, Jackie-O. She in step with the weather outside is pretty much an evil, brilliant, psychotic (with the pills to prove it) bitch in a little black dress. An unhealthy obsession with Jackie Onassis and Marty are icing on the cake. Worse yet for the poor girlfriend, once back in the fold, Marty does very little to discourage Jackie-O and ultimately joins in her twisted games. Nothing ends well here unless you see the world through Jackie-O's eyes that is. "House of Yes" also contains perhaps my favorite line of dialogue ever - "If people are going to start telling the truth around here, I'm going to bed". If your experience with Parker Posey is one of "You've Got Mail" and "Scream 3" or worse yet "Superman Returns", I suggest taking a trip back to the 90's to see how she earned the title queen of the indies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    theater of the absurd is so over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sophiej468
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this 1997 film of an earlier play is the proof. there's just too much real absurdity going on. Genevieve Bujold as the disconnected mother is the best thing in it, but these days, that isn't saying much, because so many people are disconnected. What there is of a plot about sibling incest and insanity is today totally predictable. A few (too few)funny lines. no one seems to know quite what to do with Parker Posey, except Christopher Guest, in his wonderful mockumentaries, in which she's very funny. Here, she just seems strained. Tori Spelling is quite appealing as the only normal character, a donut shop waitress who lands in a pretentious upscale family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a showcase for Parker Posey, interesting; on its own, fairly dire...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Wendy MacLeod's play about a 1963 Thanksgiving reunion between a young man and his peculiar family, including a twin sister who is obsessed with Jacqueline Kennedy. Oppressively set in a shadowy house during a raging storm, this head-scratching talk-fest quickly tires both the eye and the ear. The scenario is full of dreary eccentrics, although Parker Posey's 'Jackie-O' is a dark, original creation unto herself. The actress, known for going out on a limb with basically unplayable roles, manages to walk a fine line between comically scabrous and downright scary (which, in an otherwise boring movie, is a triumph). Other performances by Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prinze, Jr., and a sadly under-valued Genevieve Bujold are not quite as on-target, mainly due to the sophomoric writing. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The writing kills this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy_Terry_Moore
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from Wendy MacLeod's play with almost no apparent changes for better or worse, director Mark Waters penned this screenplay about the incest between a Jackie Onassis-obsessed girl and her obliging brother. From start to finish, the air is filled with intellectual dialogue like "What?" and "I don't know", including the padded repeating of several lines like "What do you do all day?" - five times in a row, that one. The acting is small-time all around except for the appealing performances of Genevieve Bujold and Tori Spelling as a spooky mother and waifish fianc&eacute;, respectively. Sometimes interesting dark comedy has occasional eerie moments if one can get past the JFK assassination 'parody'. Pretty good title, anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker Posey At Her Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jerry (Nglas)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very few movies based on plays can be successful, but House of Yes is not one of those that fail. It succeeds where others have failed because of the energy put into a film that is mostly dialog. Parker Posey shines as Jackie-O, the mentally troubled sister of Josh Hamilton and Freddy Prinze Jr. Tori Spelling, whose only other film I have enjoyed was Trick, did a great job of playing Jackie-O's doormat. The movie is at its strongest when Parker bares her sadness, always hidden beneath sarcasm. A classic movie of family dysfunction without playing out the same old tired roles. This family is anything but a typical dysfunctional family and though they all appear to be nuts, part of you wants to run out and find a family just like them, because looking past all of the sarcasm and insults, you sense and feel the love. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see strong acting. Parker Posey is on top of her game here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of my all time favorites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato002-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Incestial witty good fun. A new kind of interesting. The humor is fast and in your face. I just don't see movies like this ever. Most are too scared to make fun of touchy matters to this extent or they try so hard to be artistic that it becomes horribly boring. If u don't suck you'd enjoy it. Hey if Parker Posey was my sis and she looked like Rachael Leigh Cook when she was young, i would support incest even more so then the way half you retards support those idiot ants marching(aka troops). Every character plays the perfect role for the kind of actor or actress they are. Such as Parker playing another Insane bitch, and Freddie Prince playing a moron. Great movie if your open minded. Not the kinda movie to watch if u hide behind worthless moral values given by people who worship things that don't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for Parker Posey and Tori Spelling Fans!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    splambo100
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To the folks that think Ms Spelling did not turn in a good performance-I disagree. I was pleased with the drama she showed. She was still a young actress and has of course improved with age, but she was lithe and active and in this film I noticed she has the most perfectly formed hands and forearms of any actress on film. Not sure why I noticed this but if you watch again, look for this. She should use this feature to full effect. She also has a bit of a striking profile and eyes, similar to some other famous actors on stage. She could use her eyes to show more emotion. She showed her range to more effect when she was showing concern for the other characters. Parker Posey, of course, was in her full glory in this performance. She showed great skill with the acting process. If you listen to the film without watching the action, you see that she uses her voice to great effect. She truly stole this show. Ms Bujold of course exhibits great range of craft, so great to see her always. To top off the show, there is a cameo by a young Rachael Lee Cook. Fine performances by the men. Overall unique experience!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The House of Yes - A Family Tale of Disturbia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sat down to see this film, not really know what to expect from it, and was surprised by it. Very surprised. I had read a small synopsis online, and thought, why not give it a shot? What I got, was a twisted black comedy, with subjects of taboo, and a messy kind of attitude. The film stars Parker Posey, Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prince Jr. (what, you can be in dramas too?) and Genevi&egrave;ve Bujold. The film is directed by Mark Waters, his first feature film debut to say. A sense of strong film debut to say it the least. The film is about a mentally unbalanced woman, whom believes she is Jackie Kennedy. Already from the first time you see her, you feel that madness inside of her ... trying to escape. She seems to misses her brother, very much indeed. He is bringing a "friend" over to Thanksgiving, this friend is revealed to be his fianc&eacute;e. From there, a twisted tale of familial construction is on the way. Just to get it out of the system. The mentally unbalanced woman, "Jackie-O" is in deep love with her own brother Marty. In fact so deep in love, that she will do anything to get him for herself. They have done it before, and "Jackie-O" wants more. They tell their youngest brother, the secret ... and he then tells this to the fianc&eacute;e of Marty, whom he have began falling for. You can call like this, he is in love with her. They do it too, while the brother and sister downstairs are busy themselves. One can start to think, about how the mother is feeling about this whole affair? Yup. I feel like I am walking on a layer of thin ice right now, but hey it's a dark comedy. What did you expect? Apart from the Incest in the film, that is handled with such subtlety that it feels enigmatic. And when it happens, you feel like you are rooting more for them, than what the norm is. I went there! The film have that atmosphere of claustrophobia (since the action is taking place in one building the entire time), and hidden secrets are hinted in it's wake. The acting is very resembled that of theatricality - And I like very well that the sentences have this form of construction. It feels like you are seeing this a play, of which this film is based. I had not heard of that play before, and must say - it must be a better experience to witness the twisted (yes I have said that word too many times already) form of this tale live, with performances on the stage. Yet, it feels like I already have. Due to the fact of the theatricality of the film. The end of the film, is tear-jerking, and you feel dirty about it afterwords. I will not spoil that one. I don't know what to say anymore of the film, other than to recommend it highly. Most highly to supporters of black comedy. I had a great time seeing the film, but it is not for the easily offended, due to the fact of it's incestuous theme, and the atmospheric disturbance. So yeah, there you have it. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes people just don't know how to say no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small-scale personal drama with plenty of barbed one-liners, pitch-black comedy and disturbing subject matter starring Parker Posey in one of her best ever roles, if you're not already sold on this movie then shame on you. The story revolves around "Jackie-O" Pascal (played by Posey), a young woman who is slightly . . . . . . unwell in the head. She stays with her brother (Freddie Prinze Jr.) and mother (Genevieve Bujold) in the family home. Everything is about to get quite tense when the other brother (Josh Hamilton) comes to visit, bringing a fianc&eacute; (Tori Spelling) with him. "Jackie-O" struggles to maintain a civil facade as her jealousy bubbles up to the surface and her mental state worsens. Adapted from a play by Wendy MacLeod, The House Of Yes doesn't need any major dressing or stylistic flourishes to impress. It gets by on the strength of the source material, the fine dialogue voiced by some great actors. Even Freddie Prinze Jr. and Tori Spelling come across well, that's how good the material is. Posey is simply unforgettable in the main role, as appealing as she is clearly disturbed. It's the kind of role that people need to remember she's capable of, it's a tour de force. Josh Hamilton works well opposite her and gets a lot of the more amusing and disturbing dialogue exchanges. Freddie Prinze Jr. is effectively naive and apparently innocent while Tori Spelling is bemused and increasingly exasperated with the strange household she finds herself in. Genevieve Bujold isn't on screen for long but makes a great impression with every moment she has. Director Mark Waters, who also adapted the play, handles everything perfectly. It may not be the most cinematic film that you'll ever see but it's something that plays out like a cross between Neil LaBute and David Mamet. And that's a solid endorsement, in my view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trite, predictable and poorly acted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackshrack
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor! I am very tired of these kinds of movies. They seem to be a reaction against Hollywood. And in the end these "independent" movies are just as trite and empty. The first 5 minutes are intriguing and comedic. Afterwards, you get the sense that it becomes more and more of a play. Which I am not sure that there is any purpose in filming a play. I would imagine that the play would be a lot better. With the psychological dimension, a play can bring the viewer to imagine more than a film. But to film basically a play, you get the least of both world, in my opinion. Unless it is done in a very original way, like dogville. This movie just seemed trite and transparent to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not as tasteless as it might sound"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wes Lambert (mockingmovies@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writing recently about "Happy Tears" gave me pause to think about my trajectory as a Parker Posey fan which began in the mid 90's with "Party Girl". Unfortunately the indie cult status of "Party Girl" means it has a very very very long wait on Blockbuster.com. They might as well admit that it will never ship. However today "The House of Yes" arrived in the mail. This is a brilliant, wicked film that might suffer from the accusation of being pretentious with it's over indulged, privileged characters and lightning fast witty dialogue. The story is that Marty Pascel (Josh Hamilton) has made the unbelievable blunder of bringing his mousey girlfriend (Tori Spelling) home to meet his wealthy, dysfunctional family on the very night they will all be virtually trapped together by a hurricane. The driving force of the family and the movie as a whole is Parker Posey as Marty's sister, Jackie-O. She in step with the weather outside is pretty much an evil, brilliant, psychotic (with the pills to prove it) bitch in a little black dress. An unhealthy obsession with Jackie Onassis and Marty are icing on the cake. Worse yet for the poor girlfriend, once back in the fold, Marty does very little to discourage Jackie-O and ultimately joins in her twisted games. Nothing ends well here unless you see the world through Jackie-O's eyes that is. "House of Yes" also contains perhaps my favorite line of dialogue ever - "If people are going to start telling the truth around here, I'm going to bed". If your experience with Parker Posey is one of "You've Got Mail" and "Scream 3" or worse yet "Superman Returns", I suggest taking a trip back to the 90's to see how she earned the title queen of the indies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    theater of the absurd is so over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sophiej468
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this 1997 film of an earlier play is the proof. there's just too much real absurdity going on. Genevieve Bujold as the disconnected mother is the best thing in it, but these days, that isn't saying much, because so many people are disconnected. What there is of a plot about sibling incest and insanity is today totally predictable. A few (too few)funny lines. no one seems to know quite what to do with Parker Posey, except Christopher Guest, in his wonderful mockumentaries, in which she's very funny. Here, she just seems strained. Tori Spelling is quite appealing as the only normal character, a donut shop waitress who lands in a pretentious upscale family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a showcase for Parker Posey, interesting; on its own, fairly dire...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Wendy MacLeod's play about a 1963 Thanksgiving reunion between a young man and his peculiar family, including a twin sister who is obsessed with Jacqueline Kennedy. Oppressively set in a shadowy house during a raging storm, this head-scratching talk-fest quickly tires both the eye and the ear. The scenario is full of dreary eccentrics, although Parker Posey's 'Jackie-O' is a dark, original creation unto herself. The actress, known for going out on a limb with basically unplayable roles, manages to walk a fine line between comically scabrous and downright scary (which, in an otherwise boring movie, is a triumph). Other performances by Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prinze, Jr., and a sadly under-valued Genevieve Bujold are not quite as on-target, mainly due to the sophomoric writing. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The writing kills this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy_Terry_Moore
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from Wendy MacLeod's play with almost no apparent changes for better or worse, director Mark Waters penned this screenplay about the incest between a Jackie Onassis-obsessed girl and her obliging brother. From start to finish, the air is filled with intellectual dialogue like "What?" and "I don't know", including the padded repeating of several lines like "What do you do all day?" - five times in a row, that one. The acting is small-time all around except for the appealing performances of Genevieve Bujold and Tori Spelling as a spooky mother and waifish fianc&eacute;, respectively. Sometimes interesting dark comedy has occasional eerie moments if one can get past the JFK assassination 'parody'. Pretty good title, anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker Posey At Her Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jerry (Nglas)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very few movies based on plays can be successful, but House of Yes is not one of those that fail. It succeeds where others have failed because of the energy put into a film that is mostly dialog. Parker Posey shines as Jackie-O, the mentally troubled sister of Josh Hamilton and Freddy Prinze Jr. Tori Spelling, whose only other film I have enjoyed was Trick, did a great job of playing Jackie-O's doormat. The movie is at its strongest when Parker bares her sadness, always hidden beneath sarcasm. A classic movie of family dysfunction without playing out the same old tired roles. This family is anything but a typical dysfunctional family and though they all appear to be nuts, part of you wants to run out and find a family just like them, because looking past all of the sarcasm and insults, you sense and feel the love. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see strong acting. Parker Posey is on top of her game here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of my all time favorites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato002-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Incestial witty good fun. A new kind of interesting. The humor is fast and in your face. I just don't see movies like this ever. Most are too scared to make fun of touchy matters to this extent or they try so hard to be artistic that it becomes horribly boring. If u don't suck you'd enjoy it. Hey if Parker Posey was my sis and she looked like Rachael Leigh Cook when she was young, i would support incest even more so then the way half you retards support those idiot ants marching(aka troops). Every character plays the perfect role for the kind of actor or actress they are. Such as Parker playing another Insane bitch, and Freddie Prince playing a moron. Great movie if your open minded. Not the kinda movie to watch if u hide behind worthless moral values given by people who worship things that don't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Must see for Parker Posey and Tori Spelling Fans!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    splambo100
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To the folks that think Ms Spelling did not turn in a good performance-I disagree. I was pleased with the drama she showed. She was still a young actress and has of course improved with age, but she was lithe and active and in this film I noticed she has the most perfectly formed hands and forearms of any actress on film. Not sure why I noticed this but if you watch again, look for this. She should use this feature to full effect. She also has a bit of a striking profile and eyes, similar to some other famous actors on stage. She could use her eyes to show more emotion. She showed her range to more effect when she was showing concern for the other characters. Parker Posey, of course, was in her full glory in this performance. She showed great skill with the acting process. If you listen to the film without watching the action, you see that she uses her voice to great effect. She truly stole this show. Ms Bujold of course exhibits great range of craft, so great to see her always. To top off the show, there is a cameo by a young Rachael Lee Cook. Fine performances by the men. Overall unique experience!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The House of Yes - A Family Tale of Disturbia.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sat down to see this film, not really know what to expect from it, and was surprised by it. Very surprised. I had read a small synopsis online, and thought, why not give it a shot? What I got, was a twisted black comedy, with subjects of taboo, and a messy kind of attitude. The film stars Parker Posey, Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prince Jr. (what, you can be in dramas too?) and Genevi&egrave;ve Bujold. The film is directed by Mark Waters, his first feature film debut to say. A sense of strong film debut to say it the least. The film is about a mentally unbalanced woman, whom believes she is Jackie Kennedy. Already from the first time you see her, you feel that madness inside of her ... trying to escape. She seems to misses her brother, very much indeed. He is bringing a "friend" over to Thanksgiving, this friend is revealed to be his fianc&eacute;e. From there, a twisted tale of familial construction is on the way. Just to get it out of the system. The mentally unbalanced woman, "Jackie-O" is in deep love with her own brother Marty. In fact so deep in love, that she will do anything to get him for herself. They have done it before, and "Jackie-O" wants more. They tell their youngest brother, the secret ... and he then tells this to the fianc&eacute;e of Marty, whom he have began falling for. You can call like this, he is in love with her. They do it too, while the brother and sister downstairs are busy themselves. One can start to think, about how the mother is feeling about this whole affair? Yup. I feel like I am walking on a layer of thin ice right now, but hey it's a dark comedy. What did you expect? Apart from the Incest in the film, that is handled with such subtlety that it feels enigmatic. And when it happens, you feel like you are rooting more for them, than what the norm is. I went there! The film have that atmosphere of claustrophobia (since the action is taking place in one building the entire time), and hidden secrets are hinted in it's wake. The acting is very resembled that of theatricality - And I like very well that the sentences have this form of construction. It feels like you are seeing this a play, of which this film is based. I had not heard of that play before, and must say - it must be a better experience to witness the twisted (yes I have said that word too many times already) form of this tale live, with performances on the stage. Yet, it feels like I already have. Due to the fact of the theatricality of the film. The end of the film, is tear-jerking, and you feel dirty about it afterwords. I will not spoil that one. I don't know what to say anymore of the film, other than to recommend it highly. Most highly to supporters of black comedy. I had a great time seeing the film, but it is not for the easily offended, due to the fact of it's incestuous theme, and the atmospheric disturbance. So yeah, there you have it. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes people just don't know how to say no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small-scale personal drama with plenty of barbed one-liners, pitch-black comedy and disturbing subject matter starring Parker Posey in one of her best ever roles, if you're not already sold on this movie then shame on you. The story revolves around "Jackie-O" Pascal (played by Posey), a young woman who is slightly . . . . . . unwell in the head. She stays with her brother (Freddie Prinze Jr.) and mother (Genevieve Bujold) in the family home. Everything is about to get quite tense when the other brother (Josh Hamilton) comes to visit, bringing a fianc&eacute; (Tori Spelling) with him. "Jackie-O" struggles to maintain a civil facade as her jealousy bubbles up to the surface and her mental state worsens. Adapted from a play by Wendy MacLeod, The House Of Yes doesn't need any major dressing or stylistic flourishes to impress. It gets by on the strength of the source material, the fine dialogue voiced by some great actors. Even Freddie Prinze Jr. and Tori Spelling come across well, that's how good the material is. Posey is simply unforgettable in the main role, as appealing as she is clearly disturbed. It's the kind of role that people need to remember she's capable of, it's a tour de force. Josh Hamilton works well opposite her and gets a lot of the more amusing and disturbing dialogue exchanges. Freddie Prinze Jr. is effectively naive and apparently innocent while Tori Spelling is bemused and increasingly exasperated with the strange household she finds herself in. Genevieve Bujold isn't on screen for long but makes a great impression with every moment she has. Director Mark Waters, who also adapted the play, handles everything perfectly. It may not be the most cinematic film that you'll ever see but it's something that plays out like a cross between Neil LaBute and David Mamet. And that's a solid endorsement, in my view.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trite, predictable and poorly acted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackshrack
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very poor! I am very tired of these kinds of movies. They seem to be a reaction against Hollywood. And in the end these "independent" movies are just as trite and empty. The first 5 minutes are intriguing and comedic. Afterwards, you get the sense that it becomes more and more of a play. Which I am not sure that there is any purpose in filming a play. I would imagine that the play would be a lot better. With the psychological dimension, a play can bring the viewer to imagine more than a film. But to film basically a play, you get the least of both world, in my opinion. Unless it is done in a very original way, like dogville. This movie just seemed trite and transparent to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not as tasteless as it might sound"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wes Lambert (mockingmovies@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writing recently about "Happy Tears" gave me pause to think about my trajectory as a Parker Posey fan which began in the mid 90's with "Party Girl". Unfortunately the indie cult status of "Party Girl" means it has a very very very long wait on Blockbuster.com. They might as well admit that it will never ship. However today "The House of Yes" arrived in the mail. This is a brilliant, wicked film that might suffer from the accusation of being pretentious with it's over indulged, privileged characters and lightning fast witty dialogue. The story is that Marty Pascel (Josh Hamilton) has made the unbelievable blunder of bringing his mousey girlfriend (Tori Spelling) home to meet his wealthy, dysfunctional family on the very night they will all be virtually trapped together by a hurricane. The driving force of the family and the movie as a whole is Parker Posey as Marty's sister, Jackie-O. She in step with the weather outside is pretty much an evil, brilliant, psychotic (with the pills to prove it) bitch in a little black dress. An unhealthy obsession with Jackie Onassis and Marty are icing on the cake. Worse yet for the poor girlfriend, once back in the fold, Marty does very little to discourage Jackie-O and ultimately joins in her twisted games. Nothing ends well here unless you see the world through Jackie-O's eyes that is. "House of Yes" also contains perhaps my favorite line of dialogue ever - "If people are going to start telling the truth around here, I'm going to bed". If your experience with Parker Posey is one of "You've Got Mail" and "Scream 3" or worse yet "Superman Returns", I suggest taking a trip back to the 90's to see how she earned the title queen of the indies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    theater of the absurd is so over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sophiej468
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this 1997 film of an earlier play is the proof. there's just too much real absurdity going on. Genevieve Bujold as the disconnected mother is the best thing in it, but these days, that isn't saying much, because so many people are disconnected. What there is of a plot about sibling incest and insanity is today totally predictable. A few (too few)funny lines. no one seems to know quite what to do with Parker Posey, except Christopher Guest, in his wonderful mockumentaries, in which she's very funny. Here, she just seems strained. Tori Spelling is quite appealing as the only normal character, a donut shop waitress who lands in a pretentious upscale family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a showcase for Parker Posey, interesting; on its own, fairly dire...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From Wendy MacLeod's play about a 1963 Thanksgiving reunion between a young man and his peculiar family, including a twin sister who is obsessed with Jacqueline Kennedy. Oppressively set in a shadowy house during a raging storm, this head-scratching talk-fest quickly tires both the eye and the ear. The scenario is full of dreary eccentrics, although Parker Posey's 'Jackie-O' is a dark, original creation unto herself. The actress, known for going out on a limb with basically unplayable roles, manages to walk a fine line between comically scabrous and downright scary (which, in an otherwise boring movie, is a triumph). Other performances by Josh Hamilton, Tori Spelling, Freddie Prinze, Jr., and a sadly under-valued Genevieve Bujold are not quite as on-target, mainly due to the sophomoric writing. *1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The writing kills this.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy_Terry_Moore
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from Wendy MacLeod's play with almost no apparent changes for better or worse, director Mark Waters penned this screenplay about the incest between a Jackie Onassis-obsessed girl and her obliging brother. From start to finish, the air is filled with intellectual dialogue like "What?" and "I don't know", including the padded repeating of several lines like "What do you do all day?" - five times in a row, that one. The acting is small-time all around except for the appealing performances of Genevieve Bujold and Tori Spelling as a spooky mother and waifish fianc&eacute;, respectively. Sometimes interesting dark comedy has occasional eerie moments if one can get past the JFK assassination 'parody'. Pretty good title, anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Parker Posey At Her Best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jerry (Nglas)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Very few movies based on plays can be successful, but House of Yes is not one of those that fail. It succeeds where others have failed because of the energy put into a film that is mostly dialog. Parker Posey shines as Jackie-O, the mentally troubled sister of Josh Hamilton and Freddy Prinze Jr. Tori Spelling, whose only other film I have enjoyed was Trick, did a great job of playing Jackie-O's doormat. The movie is at its strongest when Parker bares her sadness, always hidden beneath sarcasm. A classic movie of family dysfunction without playing out the same old tired roles. This family is anything but a typical dysfunctional family and though they all appear to be nuts, part of you wants to run out and find a family just like them, because looking past all of the sarcasm and insults, you sense and feel the love. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see strong acting. Parker Posey is on top of her game here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of my all time favorites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato002-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Incestial witty good fun. A new kind of interesting. The humor is fast and in your face. I just don't see movies like this ever. Most are too scared to make fun of touchy matters to this extent or they try so hard to be artistic that it becomes horribly boring. If u don't suck you'd enjoy it. Hey if Parker Posey was my sis and she looked like Rachael Leigh Cook when she was young, i would support incest even more so then the way half you retards support those idiot ants marching(aka troops). Every character plays the perfect role for the kind of actor or actress they are. Such as Parker playing another Insane bitch, and Freddie Prince playing a moron. Great movie if your open minded. Not the kinda movie to watch if u hide behind worthless moral values given by people who worship things that don't exist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
