<filme>
 <id>
  34
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112887
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Gera&ccedil;&atilde;o Maldita
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Jordan White and Amy Blue, two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Jordan White and Amy Blue, two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos and quickiemarts.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   threesome
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drifter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   lost car
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female frontal nudity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   animated thought
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Gregg Araki
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Gregg Araki
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   James Duval
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rose McGowan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Johnathon Schaech
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quintessential Film of the 1990s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jordan White (James Duval) and Amy Blue (Rose McGowan), two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos and quickiemarts. While this is probably not a good movie, it holds a certain nostalgia value for me. Gregg Araki really struck a nerve with those coming of age in the 1990s who had an interest in the Gothic an industrial music scene. With the inclusion of references to Nine Inch Nails, Ministry and Skinny Puppy, it was perfect for that demographic. The 1990s had a nihilistic undertone that was not seen in the 1980s or 2000s, leading to such films as "Seven", "Dark City", and the popularity of Tim Burton and David Fincher. This fit in that trend easily and possibly propelled it. The follow-up, "Nowhere", similarly fit in, catching the tail end. (The trend essentially died with "The Matrix".)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cool movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Iris Hall
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -You could find a minimal spoiler- It is a cool movie full of memorable quotes and phrases. It has a strange topic and it makes no sense, but it also has that special ingredient to make it interesting. The three main characters are very special and they make connections through the lighter which is a curious detail. It is a teenage movie, a cult of messed up teens and dark comedy with edgy hotel rooms and rude language. It is the kind of movie that makes you wish you meet people like that and have almost the same adventures Another thing that makes it special is the details, it is full of them! We can call it a 'cult' movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaceheater2187-120-985197
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No mature person could call this film a beautiful, artful, deep movie without bursting into laughter. I'm not even sure where to start. The writing is excessively puerile. Insults such as "anus face" and "get your head out of your rectum" are among a plethora of childlike comebacks thrown around in this film. In what universe does this qualify as "clever, witty writing"? This thing claims to be a comedy. Comedy?! The only time I laughed was at the acting. James Duval delivered his lines in a manner that makes Keanu Reeves look like a ten-time Oscar winner. The plot is virtually nonexistent. They drive, they stop somewhere for greasy food (and the total price of everything they buy totals to $6.66), they accidentally kill someone, they check in at a sleazy motel, have erotic sex, and wake up the next morning and do it all over again. It gets old very quickly. The only reason I kept watching was to see if the plot eventually went anywhere. But no, the film continues in its circular manner until the totally out-of-place climax, and it just ends. I'm sure that's frustrated more people besides just me. Even the technical aspects are sub-standard. The lighting is so horrible at times that I had to turn the brightness to its max on my screen and still couldn't quite tell what was going on. I really would like to keep going, but I'm afraid this diatribe would never end. I'm giving this movie a 2/10. I can think of only two positives about this film, which is why I'm giving it a 2: the first is the soundtrack. Several 90s songs are played in the background during the pointless dialogue. Thank God those songs were there because they were the only things making those scenes tolerable. I also heard some late 80s tunes from time to time. However, if you're not a fan of this type of music, then this positive aspect won't appeal to you. The second positive I can think of was when there was about ten seconds of meaningful dialogue near the end of the film. James Duval's character asks Xavier what the meaning of existence is. Although the answer is rather banal and empty, at least there was an attempt to broach a deeper, more philosophical topic. That one line isn't probably worth a whole star, but I'm feeling particularly magnanimous today. But in no way do these two positives make up for the other 83 minutes of dreck. Avoid this film. The only people drawn to this movie have to be confused teenage emo goths who hate their parents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it. Totally deserves cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebitterend1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those great, special movies that came from the 90's wasteland. The script is insane, the cast are sexy, and it just feels like the perfect slice of late 90's desolation. If you're not into edgy, confronting subject matter, It's definitely not for you, but i like my films a little bit dangerous and out of control, and that's exactly what The Doom Generation is; out of control. Sure, there are plot points that don't quite fit, but they don't have to. The movie perfectly complements the emotional landscape of the characters. It's crazy, over sexed self absorbed angst with a side serving of nihilism. Accept it for what it is and enjoy it. Not enough films take the risks they used to, and i applaud The Doom Generation for being what it needs to be, the same way Natural Born Killers did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gregkae
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stunning piece elicits emotions that in my case were so intense that I submitted myself to the harrowing experience of the registration process just to be able to share with the world that I throw up more colourful ideas after a bad paella and a bottle of cheap lambrusco. I white-knuckled it on fast forward and it still dragged like a 45 minute tooth extraction; waxing your armpits hurts less. Whoever participated in churning out this steaming pile of manure should be sent to a pig farm for a lifetime of unpaid work. Pointless, clueless, plot less. No script, no dialogue, no direction. It makes you think though - who stole the money to finance it, who blackmailed the actors to take part in it, who browbeat a family member to shoot it, so yeah, it is thought provoking. My neighbour's cat suffering from chronic diarrhoea excretes stuff that has more substance to it. To top it off this drivel looks like it has been recorded on a point-and-shoot pocket camera bought at a country fair in eastern Europe. IMDb really has to introduce new ratings system, maybe minus points, so that pieces like the doom generation can get its undeniable praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phallic joy and the failure of heterosexuality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film in Araki's Teenage Apocalypse Trilogy builds upon the premises laid out in "Nowhere" and "Totally F***ed Up". And what better way to end a trilogy than with a threesome in the making? The three protagonists of this production are Jordan White, interpreted by James Duval who once again conveys all the confusion and insecurities of adolescence, Amy Blue, his sexy girlfriend and Xavier Red, a wild, aggressive and assertive guy they meet on the road. Together they will embark upon a journey that, without a clear destination, will bring forth certain aspects of their real 'selves'. At the beginning of the film, Jordan attempts to penetrate his girlfriend to no avail. But this is not a reference to impotence. It is rather a reaffirmation of what Lacan would denominate the nonexistence of sexual rapport. Amy tries to give directions to her insecure boyfriend about what to do with his penis. Obviously, sexual joy here is phallocentric. But let's not forget that the phallus is a signifier, and even the model of jouissance is bound to be seized in the idiocy of the practice that attests to it. A phallocentric perspective exemplifies the non-rapport in the Other. To declare that the jouissance is phallic is fundamentally to state it is solitary. That clearly explains why is it that Jordan and Amy are unable to consummate their passion, remaining as virgins. According to Lacan, the axiom "There is no such thing as sexual rapport" obeys to a basically solitary jouissance. When Jordan asks Amy "Don't you think sex is totally strange? Just the whole idea of it" he is essentially explaining how difficult it is to decode sex in the symbolic order, because sex can neither be translated into words nor discarded as simulacra (which happens very often in postmodern society). Amy then responds "I think maybe it's more powerful than we'd like it to be". And she is absolutely right about it. As soon as Xavier enters into scene, sexual dynamics are fiercely disrupted. Xavier is sexually overwhelming, he invades the personal space of the boy and the girl, disregarding gender divisions. When Jordan and Amy are taking a shower together, Xavier looks at them and masturbates. Masturbation is very relevant in "The Doom Generation", after all, what could best exemplify the solitary jouissance? Amy describes Xavier as a living support for the sexual organ, and Xavier has no problems in acting as a "walking penis", so to speak. He is rendered as the phallus, and because he is the phallus he becomes desirable for Amy and Jordan. According to Freud, the man possesses the phallus, for Lacan, however, the woman can also have it (let's remember that phallus is not a synonym for penis). In both cases, as embarrassment, as lack, a substitute to be looked for, yet essentially, sexuality will be there conditioned, determined. To have the phallus is to be afraid of losing it; to not have it is to seek for it. All this is demonstrated when Amy engages in sexual intercourse with Xavier, thus creating a specular moment, an instance which reflects a previous one, in which Jordan masturbates while he sees his girlfriend and his new friend copulating (dynamics that bear some similitude to Cristopher Munch's Harry + Max, so it's not surprising to see this filmmaker credited at the end). Nonetheless, one of the most fascinating aspects of the film is the feeling of impending doom that permeates reality over and over again. Amy will summarize it in one phrase: "there is no place for us in this world"; whereas Jordan will only inquire "ever felt like reality is more twisted than dreams?". "The Doom Generation" is as surreal as other Araki's films, and it picks up on a certain leit motif present in his cinematographic work: religious zealousness and all it entangles. From Amy's mother (a fervent scientologist) to billboards with messages such as The Rapture is Coming (a "doomsday" of sorts according to certain religious sects as explained in "Nowhere") or Prepare for the Apocalypse. Of course, there is also the constant emphasis on 666, the number of the beast; every time the characters buy food or have to pay for something, the price is exactly the same 6 dollars with 66 cents. 6.66. The film is thoroughly filled with what Genet would call paratextual references, here the "writing on the wall" is very visible, in every wall, in every store and gas station they visit. Reality seems to be seeping down under their very noses, although as Xavier reminds them: "I saw it on TV so it's gotta be true, right?". But there is little or nothing they can grab a hold on. And this capricious dynamic is reinforced by the fact that Amy is an interchangeable object a (object of desire), as a fast food employee confuses her with an old flame and chases her down, something that also happens with an enraged lesbian, and a gay man. All forms of sexuality (heterosexuality, male and female homosexuality) enable the completion of yet another trio. When Jordan, Amy and Xavier are finally ready for a threesome, something of the order of the real irrupts and dramatically changes everything. A violent group of men captures the protagonists, and threaten Jordan very seriously with removing his genitals. But what could castration mean? A rapport should be posited and established, from a subject of one sex to the phallus, and would not get inscribed by a rapport to the partner sexed differently. This is the value Lacan bestows on the universal allotted to the castration complex. Thus the Old Testament conjectures that Sodom will suit the man and Gomorrah the woman. If castration was metaphorical at the beginning (Jordan's inability to maintain an erection) here it takes a more literal approach, which is only fitting if we consider that sexual rapport for the protagonists will forever be impossible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant by Araki again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Totally brilliant psychedelic film by the director of Mysterious skin and Nowhere, Gregg Araki(one of my favourite directors). He managed to create another brilliant sexual film with that bit of weirdness that I love in films, with brilliant acting by the cast (especially James Duval), with brilliant shots that could only come from a brilliant director like himself. I don't understand why the overall rating is so low, maybe this film is just too far for most peoples stretch, a bit to arty and deranged, a bit to creative. To be seen to be believed A clear 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artsy and inept.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reaper
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worth a look if you absolutely positively must see Rose McGowan naked in various degrading situations, but not worth watching otherwise. This movie is not merely bad, but bad AND pretentious. The kind of movie that would have gotten the Mystery Science Theater 3000 treatment, if they could have cleaned the profanity from the soundtrack. The symbolism is laid on with a trowel; Araki must have learned that directors sometimes use color as a motif, so he saturates every frame with reds and blues and yellows. The number 666 appears numerous times - whoa! Symbol! Various sets have pithy signs on the wall - whoa! Symbol! The movie has its fans, but I simply cannot see why. Maybe Araki isn't the Ed Wood of our time, but then again, maybe he is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed to be a B movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mj_heiser-832-695491
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is more depth and thought to this movie than first meets the eye but the Doom Generation unfortunately falls to the ills of poor acting, poor screen writing, and major gaps and holes in the storyline. The first half of the movie, aside from setting up the storyline, is almost a waste of time. Still, the movie is an interesting study in the dark thought and actions of 3 teens on a road trip to hell finding elicit drugs, sex, and violence just at about every stop over. Amy and Jordan are two X Generation punk rockers best described as Stoned most of the time and looking for excitement. They picked up an older but even more-so on the edge low life named X or Xavier who was running from the 'Skin-heads'. As the movie goes along, the depth of depravity increases until Jordan who I find is the most redeemable character being the most harmless starts asking the question 'Is there any meaning in life'. Still I enjoyed some of the thought especially towards the end of the movie. There are some themes around redemption and salvation that I find interesting. There is a lot of sex in this movie of which while I found provocative in the beginning, a major turn off towards the end of the movie where especially for Amy and X, there was nothing sacred in sex. At the conclusion of the movie, Jordan it seemed was the redeemable character as he confesses his love for Amy. And, for those who are squeamish, avoid the ending at all costs. I found it a bit unnecessary and the ending scene in the car almost pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Soon: The History of The Doom Generation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, here's a fine example of hard-hitting, 90's Exploitation. Brought to you by Gregg Araki. The Doom Generation is a gritty, super-dismal, often hilarious tale of murder, betrayal, and sleaziness. We begin with a young couple, hanging out at a club, Amy Blue (meth-head), and Jordan White (pot-head). Amy is a vindictive little nightmare, who's just looking for an argument. And Jordan, well, Jordan doesn't do a whole lot of thinking, but is a good guy, who loves Amy, despite her personality issues. Amy and Jordan take it to the car, so they can lose their virginity, but are soon interrupted... Meet Xavier Red (killer), X for short. Xavier rudely enters Amy's car, rudely demanding she start driving so that he may live, rudely insulting her, subtly insulting Jordan, but he doesn't mind. Amy on the other hand, is about to blow her top, but at least she has someone to argue with now... no wait, he just went too far. Alright guy!! Out of the car. Later in the evening, the teenage, odd couple are rescued by their new pal, X from a trigger-happy, convenience store clerk. after X literally blows the mans head off. They all 3, right then and there, decide to take a road trip together, leaving behind everything. The night sure is going to hell, but at least Amy has someone to argue with again, that's what's important. It doesn't take Xavier long to make his intentions clear, with Amy, and despite the fact that she despises him, she's all for it. They don't try all that hard to hide this from Jordan, but it's cool, Jordan doesn't mind, "X seems like a nice guy". Amy doesn't mind Xavier's insults, Jordan doesn't mind that the man is sleeping with his girlfriend, and no one seems to be all that bothered by the fact that X kills someone every time they stop somewhere. The Doom Generation is harsh, and mean-spirited, and can be ugly, at times, just a swell movie, probably Araki's best. The religious, and apocalyptic metaphors won't go unnoticed, and neither will Rose McGowan, as a foul-mouthed teenager, with a chip on her shoulder, with James Duval's performance making her seem even worse. Some things occur, seemingly with the intention of confusing us, but that's OK, confusion only makes this seem more like exploitation from decades past. For something slightly similar, check out Nowhere... which reminds me, if you ever see both these movies, you might notice that it would be a much better fit if they switched the titles, just a thought. Although, The Doom Generation is deeper than it may seem, it's still a grim good time, with no redeeming qualities, Generation-X-ploitation. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quintessential Film of the 1990s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jordan White (James Duval) and Amy Blue (Rose McGowan), two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos and quickiemarts. While this is probably not a good movie, it holds a certain nostalgia value for me. Gregg Araki really struck a nerve with those coming of age in the 1990s who had an interest in the Gothic an industrial music scene. With the inclusion of references to Nine Inch Nails, Ministry and Skinny Puppy, it was perfect for that demographic. The 1990s had a nihilistic undertone that was not seen in the 1980s or 2000s, leading to such films as "Seven", "Dark City", and the popularity of Tim Burton and David Fincher. This fit in that trend easily and possibly propelled it. The follow-up, "Nowhere", similarly fit in, catching the tail end. (The trend essentially died with "The Matrix".)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cool movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Iris Hall
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -You could find a minimal spoiler- It is a cool movie full of memorable quotes and phrases. It has a strange topic and it makes no sense, but it also has that special ingredient to make it interesting. The three main characters are very special and they make connections through the lighter which is a curious detail. It is a teenage movie, a cult of messed up teens and dark comedy with edgy hotel rooms and rude language. It is the kind of movie that makes you wish you meet people like that and have almost the same adventures Another thing that makes it special is the details, it is full of them! We can call it a 'cult' movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaceheater2187-120-985197
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No mature person could call this film a beautiful, artful, deep movie without bursting into laughter. I'm not even sure where to start. The writing is excessively puerile. Insults such as "anus face" and "get your head out of your rectum" are among a plethora of childlike comebacks thrown around in this film. In what universe does this qualify as "clever, witty writing"? This thing claims to be a comedy. Comedy?! The only time I laughed was at the acting. James Duval delivered his lines in a manner that makes Keanu Reeves look like a ten-time Oscar winner. The plot is virtually nonexistent. They drive, they stop somewhere for greasy food (and the total price of everything they buy totals to $6.66), they accidentally kill someone, they check in at a sleazy motel, have erotic sex, and wake up the next morning and do it all over again. It gets old very quickly. The only reason I kept watching was to see if the plot eventually went anywhere. But no, the film continues in its circular manner until the totally out-of-place climax, and it just ends. I'm sure that's frustrated more people besides just me. Even the technical aspects are sub-standard. The lighting is so horrible at times that I had to turn the brightness to its max on my screen and still couldn't quite tell what was going on. I really would like to keep going, but I'm afraid this diatribe would never end. I'm giving this movie a 2/10. I can think of only two positives about this film, which is why I'm giving it a 2: the first is the soundtrack. Several 90s songs are played in the background during the pointless dialogue. Thank God those songs were there because they were the only things making those scenes tolerable. I also heard some late 80s tunes from time to time. However, if you're not a fan of this type of music, then this positive aspect won't appeal to you. The second positive I can think of was when there was about ten seconds of meaningful dialogue near the end of the film. James Duval's character asks Xavier what the meaning of existence is. Although the answer is rather banal and empty, at least there was an attempt to broach a deeper, more philosophical topic. That one line isn't probably worth a whole star, but I'm feeling particularly magnanimous today. But in no way do these two positives make up for the other 83 minutes of dreck. Avoid this film. The only people drawn to this movie have to be confused teenage emo goths who hate their parents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it. Totally deserves cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebitterend1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those great, special movies that came from the 90's wasteland. The script is insane, the cast are sexy, and it just feels like the perfect slice of late 90's desolation. If you're not into edgy, confronting subject matter, It's definitely not for you, but i like my films a little bit dangerous and out of control, and that's exactly what The Doom Generation is; out of control. Sure, there are plot points that don't quite fit, but they don't have to. The movie perfectly complements the emotional landscape of the characters. It's crazy, over sexed self absorbed angst with a side serving of nihilism. Accept it for what it is and enjoy it. Not enough films take the risks they used to, and i applaud The Doom Generation for being what it needs to be, the same way Natural Born Killers did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gregkae
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stunning piece elicits emotions that in my case were so intense that I submitted myself to the harrowing experience of the registration process just to be able to share with the world that I throw up more colourful ideas after a bad paella and a bottle of cheap lambrusco. I white-knuckled it on fast forward and it still dragged like a 45 minute tooth extraction; waxing your armpits hurts less. Whoever participated in churning out this steaming pile of manure should be sent to a pig farm for a lifetime of unpaid work. Pointless, clueless, plot less. No script, no dialogue, no direction. It makes you think though - who stole the money to finance it, who blackmailed the actors to take part in it, who browbeat a family member to shoot it, so yeah, it is thought provoking. My neighbour's cat suffering from chronic diarrhoea excretes stuff that has more substance to it. To top it off this drivel looks like it has been recorded on a point-and-shoot pocket camera bought at a country fair in eastern Europe. IMDb really has to introduce new ratings system, maybe minus points, so that pieces like the doom generation can get its undeniable praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phallic joy and the failure of heterosexuality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film in Araki's Teenage Apocalypse Trilogy builds upon the premises laid out in "Nowhere" and "Totally F***ed Up". And what better way to end a trilogy than with a threesome in the making? The three protagonists of this production are Jordan White, interpreted by James Duval who once again conveys all the confusion and insecurities of adolescence, Amy Blue, his sexy girlfriend and Xavier Red, a wild, aggressive and assertive guy they meet on the road. Together they will embark upon a journey that, without a clear destination, will bring forth certain aspects of their real 'selves'. At the beginning of the film, Jordan attempts to penetrate his girlfriend to no avail. But this is not a reference to impotence. It is rather a reaffirmation of what Lacan would denominate the nonexistence of sexual rapport. Amy tries to give directions to her insecure boyfriend about what to do with his penis. Obviously, sexual joy here is phallocentric. But let's not forget that the phallus is a signifier, and even the model of jouissance is bound to be seized in the idiocy of the practice that attests to it. A phallocentric perspective exemplifies the non-rapport in the Other. To declare that the jouissance is phallic is fundamentally to state it is solitary. That clearly explains why is it that Jordan and Amy are unable to consummate their passion, remaining as virgins. According to Lacan, the axiom "There is no such thing as sexual rapport" obeys to a basically solitary jouissance. When Jordan asks Amy "Don't you think sex is totally strange? Just the whole idea of it" he is essentially explaining how difficult it is to decode sex in the symbolic order, because sex can neither be translated into words nor discarded as simulacra (which happens very often in postmodern society). Amy then responds "I think maybe it's more powerful than we'd like it to be". And she is absolutely right about it. As soon as Xavier enters into scene, sexual dynamics are fiercely disrupted. Xavier is sexually overwhelming, he invades the personal space of the boy and the girl, disregarding gender divisions. When Jordan and Amy are taking a shower together, Xavier looks at them and masturbates. Masturbation is very relevant in "The Doom Generation", after all, what could best exemplify the solitary jouissance? Amy describes Xavier as a living support for the sexual organ, and Xavier has no problems in acting as a "walking penis", so to speak. He is rendered as the phallus, and because he is the phallus he becomes desirable for Amy and Jordan. According to Freud, the man possesses the phallus, for Lacan, however, the woman can also have it (let's remember that phallus is not a synonym for penis). In both cases, as embarrassment, as lack, a substitute to be looked for, yet essentially, sexuality will be there conditioned, determined. To have the phallus is to be afraid of losing it; to not have it is to seek for it. All this is demonstrated when Amy engages in sexual intercourse with Xavier, thus creating a specular moment, an instance which reflects a previous one, in which Jordan masturbates while he sees his girlfriend and his new friend copulating (dynamics that bear some similitude to Cristopher Munch's Harry + Max, so it's not surprising to see this filmmaker credited at the end). Nonetheless, one of the most fascinating aspects of the film is the feeling of impending doom that permeates reality over and over again. Amy will summarize it in one phrase: "there is no place for us in this world"; whereas Jordan will only inquire "ever felt like reality is more twisted than dreams?". "The Doom Generation" is as surreal as other Araki's films, and it picks up on a certain leit motif present in his cinematographic work: religious zealousness and all it entangles. From Amy's mother (a fervent scientologist) to billboards with messages such as The Rapture is Coming (a "doomsday" of sorts according to certain religious sects as explained in "Nowhere") or Prepare for the Apocalypse. Of course, there is also the constant emphasis on 666, the number of the beast; every time the characters buy food or have to pay for something, the price is exactly the same 6 dollars with 66 cents. 6.66. The film is thoroughly filled with what Genet would call paratextual references, here the "writing on the wall" is very visible, in every wall, in every store and gas station they visit. Reality seems to be seeping down under their very noses, although as Xavier reminds them: "I saw it on TV so it's gotta be true, right?". But there is little or nothing they can grab a hold on. And this capricious dynamic is reinforced by the fact that Amy is an interchangeable object a (object of desire), as a fast food employee confuses her with an old flame and chases her down, something that also happens with an enraged lesbian, and a gay man. All forms of sexuality (heterosexuality, male and female homosexuality) enable the completion of yet another trio. When Jordan, Amy and Xavier are finally ready for a threesome, something of the order of the real irrupts and dramatically changes everything. A violent group of men captures the protagonists, and threaten Jordan very seriously with removing his genitals. But what could castration mean? A rapport should be posited and established, from a subject of one sex to the phallus, and would not get inscribed by a rapport to the partner sexed differently. This is the value Lacan bestows on the universal allotted to the castration complex. Thus the Old Testament conjectures that Sodom will suit the man and Gomorrah the woman. If castration was metaphorical at the beginning (Jordan's inability to maintain an erection) here it takes a more literal approach, which is only fitting if we consider that sexual rapport for the protagonists will forever be impossible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant by Araki again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Totally brilliant psychedelic film by the director of Mysterious skin and Nowhere, Gregg Araki(one of my favourite directors). He managed to create another brilliant sexual film with that bit of weirdness that I love in films, with brilliant acting by the cast (especially James Duval), with brilliant shots that could only come from a brilliant director like himself. I don't understand why the overall rating is so low, maybe this film is just too far for most peoples stretch, a bit to arty and deranged, a bit to creative. To be seen to be believed A clear 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artsy and inept.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reaper
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worth a look if you absolutely positively must see Rose McGowan naked in various degrading situations, but not worth watching otherwise. This movie is not merely bad, but bad AND pretentious. The kind of movie that would have gotten the Mystery Science Theater 3000 treatment, if they could have cleaned the profanity from the soundtrack. The symbolism is laid on with a trowel; Araki must have learned that directors sometimes use color as a motif, so he saturates every frame with reds and blues and yellows. The number 666 appears numerous times - whoa! Symbol! Various sets have pithy signs on the wall - whoa! Symbol! The movie has its fans, but I simply cannot see why. Maybe Araki isn't the Ed Wood of our time, but then again, maybe he is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed to be a B movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mj_heiser-832-695491
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is more depth and thought to this movie than first meets the eye but the Doom Generation unfortunately falls to the ills of poor acting, poor screen writing, and major gaps and holes in the storyline. The first half of the movie, aside from setting up the storyline, is almost a waste of time. Still, the movie is an interesting study in the dark thought and actions of 3 teens on a road trip to hell finding elicit drugs, sex, and violence just at about every stop over. Amy and Jordan are two X Generation punk rockers best described as Stoned most of the time and looking for excitement. They picked up an older but even more-so on the edge low life named X or Xavier who was running from the 'Skin-heads'. As the movie goes along, the depth of depravity increases until Jordan who I find is the most redeemable character being the most harmless starts asking the question 'Is there any meaning in life'. Still I enjoyed some of the thought especially towards the end of the movie. There are some themes around redemption and salvation that I find interesting. There is a lot of sex in this movie of which while I found provocative in the beginning, a major turn off towards the end of the movie where especially for Amy and X, there was nothing sacred in sex. At the conclusion of the movie, Jordan it seemed was the redeemable character as he confesses his love for Amy. And, for those who are squeamish, avoid the ending at all costs. I found it a bit unnecessary and the ending scene in the car almost pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Soon: The History of The Doom Generation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, here's a fine example of hard-hitting, 90's Exploitation. Brought to you by Gregg Araki. The Doom Generation is a gritty, super-dismal, often hilarious tale of murder, betrayal, and sleaziness. We begin with a young couple, hanging out at a club, Amy Blue (meth-head), and Jordan White (pot-head). Amy is a vindictive little nightmare, who's just looking for an argument. And Jordan, well, Jordan doesn't do a whole lot of thinking, but is a good guy, who loves Amy, despite her personality issues. Amy and Jordan take it to the car, so they can lose their virginity, but are soon interrupted... Meet Xavier Red (killer), X for short. Xavier rudely enters Amy's car, rudely demanding she start driving so that he may live, rudely insulting her, subtly insulting Jordan, but he doesn't mind. Amy on the other hand, is about to blow her top, but at least she has someone to argue with now... no wait, he just went too far. Alright guy!! Out of the car. Later in the evening, the teenage, odd couple are rescued by their new pal, X from a trigger-happy, convenience store clerk. after X literally blows the mans head off. They all 3, right then and there, decide to take a road trip together, leaving behind everything. The night sure is going to hell, but at least Amy has someone to argue with again, that's what's important. It doesn't take Xavier long to make his intentions clear, with Amy, and despite the fact that she despises him, she's all for it. They don't try all that hard to hide this from Jordan, but it's cool, Jordan doesn't mind, "X seems like a nice guy". Amy doesn't mind Xavier's insults, Jordan doesn't mind that the man is sleeping with his girlfriend, and no one seems to be all that bothered by the fact that X kills someone every time they stop somewhere. The Doom Generation is harsh, and mean-spirited, and can be ugly, at times, just a swell movie, probably Araki's best. The religious, and apocalyptic metaphors won't go unnoticed, and neither will Rose McGowan, as a foul-mouthed teenager, with a chip on her shoulder, with James Duval's performance making her seem even worse. Some things occur, seemingly with the intention of confusing us, but that's OK, confusion only makes this seem more like exploitation from decades past. For something slightly similar, check out Nowhere... which reminds me, if you ever see both these movies, you might notice that it would be a much better fit if they switched the titles, just a thought. Although, The Doom Generation is deeper than it may seem, it's still a grim good time, with no redeeming qualities, Generation-X-ploitation. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quintessential Film of the 1990s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jordan White (James Duval) and Amy Blue (Rose McGowan), two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos and quickiemarts. While this is probably not a good movie, it holds a certain nostalgia value for me. Gregg Araki really struck a nerve with those coming of age in the 1990s who had an interest in the Gothic an industrial music scene. With the inclusion of references to Nine Inch Nails, Ministry and Skinny Puppy, it was perfect for that demographic. The 1990s had a nihilistic undertone that was not seen in the 1980s or 2000s, leading to such films as "Seven", "Dark City", and the popularity of Tim Burton and David Fincher. This fit in that trend easily and possibly propelled it. The follow-up, "Nowhere", similarly fit in, catching the tail end. (The trend essentially died with "The Matrix".)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cool movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Iris Hall
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -You could find a minimal spoiler- It is a cool movie full of memorable quotes and phrases. It has a strange topic and it makes no sense, but it also has that special ingredient to make it interesting. The three main characters are very special and they make connections through the lighter which is a curious detail. It is a teenage movie, a cult of messed up teens and dark comedy with edgy hotel rooms and rude language. It is the kind of movie that makes you wish you meet people like that and have almost the same adventures Another thing that makes it special is the details, it is full of them! We can call it a 'cult' movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaceheater2187-120-985197
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No mature person could call this film a beautiful, artful, deep movie without bursting into laughter. I'm not even sure where to start. The writing is excessively puerile. Insults such as "anus face" and "get your head out of your rectum" are among a plethora of childlike comebacks thrown around in this film. In what universe does this qualify as "clever, witty writing"? This thing claims to be a comedy. Comedy?! The only time I laughed was at the acting. James Duval delivered his lines in a manner that makes Keanu Reeves look like a ten-time Oscar winner. The plot is virtually nonexistent. They drive, they stop somewhere for greasy food (and the total price of everything they buy totals to $6.66), they accidentally kill someone, they check in at a sleazy motel, have erotic sex, and wake up the next morning and do it all over again. It gets old very quickly. The only reason I kept watching was to see if the plot eventually went anywhere. But no, the film continues in its circular manner until the totally out-of-place climax, and it just ends. I'm sure that's frustrated more people besides just me. Even the technical aspects are sub-standard. The lighting is so horrible at times that I had to turn the brightness to its max on my screen and still couldn't quite tell what was going on. I really would like to keep going, but I'm afraid this diatribe would never end. I'm giving this movie a 2/10. I can think of only two positives about this film, which is why I'm giving it a 2: the first is the soundtrack. Several 90s songs are played in the background during the pointless dialogue. Thank God those songs were there because they were the only things making those scenes tolerable. I also heard some late 80s tunes from time to time. However, if you're not a fan of this type of music, then this positive aspect won't appeal to you. The second positive I can think of was when there was about ten seconds of meaningful dialogue near the end of the film. James Duval's character asks Xavier what the meaning of existence is. Although the answer is rather banal and empty, at least there was an attempt to broach a deeper, more philosophical topic. That one line isn't probably worth a whole star, but I'm feeling particularly magnanimous today. But in no way do these two positives make up for the other 83 minutes of dreck. Avoid this film. The only people drawn to this movie have to be confused teenage emo goths who hate their parents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it. Totally deserves cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebitterend1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those great, special movies that came from the 90's wasteland. The script is insane, the cast are sexy, and it just feels like the perfect slice of late 90's desolation. If you're not into edgy, confronting subject matter, It's definitely not for you, but i like my films a little bit dangerous and out of control, and that's exactly what The Doom Generation is; out of control. Sure, there are plot points that don't quite fit, but they don't have to. The movie perfectly complements the emotional landscape of the characters. It's crazy, over sexed self absorbed angst with a side serving of nihilism. Accept it for what it is and enjoy it. Not enough films take the risks they used to, and i applaud The Doom Generation for being what it needs to be, the same way Natural Born Killers did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gregkae
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stunning piece elicits emotions that in my case were so intense that I submitted myself to the harrowing experience of the registration process just to be able to share with the world that I throw up more colourful ideas after a bad paella and a bottle of cheap lambrusco. I white-knuckled it on fast forward and it still dragged like a 45 minute tooth extraction; waxing your armpits hurts less. Whoever participated in churning out this steaming pile of manure should be sent to a pig farm for a lifetime of unpaid work. Pointless, clueless, plot less. No script, no dialogue, no direction. It makes you think though - who stole the money to finance it, who blackmailed the actors to take part in it, who browbeat a family member to shoot it, so yeah, it is thought provoking. My neighbour's cat suffering from chronic diarrhoea excretes stuff that has more substance to it. To top it off this drivel looks like it has been recorded on a point-and-shoot pocket camera bought at a country fair in eastern Europe. IMDb really has to introduce new ratings system, maybe minus points, so that pieces like the doom generation can get its undeniable praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phallic joy and the failure of heterosexuality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film in Araki's Teenage Apocalypse Trilogy builds upon the premises laid out in "Nowhere" and "Totally F***ed Up". And what better way to end a trilogy than with a threesome in the making? The three protagonists of this production are Jordan White, interpreted by James Duval who once again conveys all the confusion and insecurities of adolescence, Amy Blue, his sexy girlfriend and Xavier Red, a wild, aggressive and assertive guy they meet on the road. Together they will embark upon a journey that, without a clear destination, will bring forth certain aspects of their real 'selves'. At the beginning of the film, Jordan attempts to penetrate his girlfriend to no avail. But this is not a reference to impotence. It is rather a reaffirmation of what Lacan would denominate the nonexistence of sexual rapport. Amy tries to give directions to her insecure boyfriend about what to do with his penis. Obviously, sexual joy here is phallocentric. But let's not forget that the phallus is a signifier, and even the model of jouissance is bound to be seized in the idiocy of the practice that attests to it. A phallocentric perspective exemplifies the non-rapport in the Other. To declare that the jouissance is phallic is fundamentally to state it is solitary. That clearly explains why is it that Jordan and Amy are unable to consummate their passion, remaining as virgins. According to Lacan, the axiom "There is no such thing as sexual rapport" obeys to a basically solitary jouissance. When Jordan asks Amy "Don't you think sex is totally strange? Just the whole idea of it" he is essentially explaining how difficult it is to decode sex in the symbolic order, because sex can neither be translated into words nor discarded as simulacra (which happens very often in postmodern society). Amy then responds "I think maybe it's more powerful than we'd like it to be". And she is absolutely right about it. As soon as Xavier enters into scene, sexual dynamics are fiercely disrupted. Xavier is sexually overwhelming, he invades the personal space of the boy and the girl, disregarding gender divisions. When Jordan and Amy are taking a shower together, Xavier looks at them and masturbates. Masturbation is very relevant in "The Doom Generation", after all, what could best exemplify the solitary jouissance? Amy describes Xavier as a living support for the sexual organ, and Xavier has no problems in acting as a "walking penis", so to speak. He is rendered as the phallus, and because he is the phallus he becomes desirable for Amy and Jordan. According to Freud, the man possesses the phallus, for Lacan, however, the woman can also have it (let's remember that phallus is not a synonym for penis). In both cases, as embarrassment, as lack, a substitute to be looked for, yet essentially, sexuality will be there conditioned, determined. To have the phallus is to be afraid of losing it; to not have it is to seek for it. All this is demonstrated when Amy engages in sexual intercourse with Xavier, thus creating a specular moment, an instance which reflects a previous one, in which Jordan masturbates while he sees his girlfriend and his new friend copulating (dynamics that bear some similitude to Cristopher Munch's Harry + Max, so it's not surprising to see this filmmaker credited at the end). Nonetheless, one of the most fascinating aspects of the film is the feeling of impending doom that permeates reality over and over again. Amy will summarize it in one phrase: "there is no place for us in this world"; whereas Jordan will only inquire "ever felt like reality is more twisted than dreams?". "The Doom Generation" is as surreal as other Araki's films, and it picks up on a certain leit motif present in his cinematographic work: religious zealousness and all it entangles. From Amy's mother (a fervent scientologist) to billboards with messages such as The Rapture is Coming (a "doomsday" of sorts according to certain religious sects as explained in "Nowhere") or Prepare for the Apocalypse. Of course, there is also the constant emphasis on 666, the number of the beast; every time the characters buy food or have to pay for something, the price is exactly the same 6 dollars with 66 cents. 6.66. The film is thoroughly filled with what Genet would call paratextual references, here the "writing on the wall" is very visible, in every wall, in every store and gas station they visit. Reality seems to be seeping down under their very noses, although as Xavier reminds them: "I saw it on TV so it's gotta be true, right?". But there is little or nothing they can grab a hold on. And this capricious dynamic is reinforced by the fact that Amy is an interchangeable object a (object of desire), as a fast food employee confuses her with an old flame and chases her down, something that also happens with an enraged lesbian, and a gay man. All forms of sexuality (heterosexuality, male and female homosexuality) enable the completion of yet another trio. When Jordan, Amy and Xavier are finally ready for a threesome, something of the order of the real irrupts and dramatically changes everything. A violent group of men captures the protagonists, and threaten Jordan very seriously with removing his genitals. But what could castration mean? A rapport should be posited and established, from a subject of one sex to the phallus, and would not get inscribed by a rapport to the partner sexed differently. This is the value Lacan bestows on the universal allotted to the castration complex. Thus the Old Testament conjectures that Sodom will suit the man and Gomorrah the woman. If castration was metaphorical at the beginning (Jordan's inability to maintain an erection) here it takes a more literal approach, which is only fitting if we consider that sexual rapport for the protagonists will forever be impossible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant by Araki again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Totally brilliant psychedelic film by the director of Mysterious skin and Nowhere, Gregg Araki(one of my favourite directors). He managed to create another brilliant sexual film with that bit of weirdness that I love in films, with brilliant acting by the cast (especially James Duval), with brilliant shots that could only come from a brilliant director like himself. I don't understand why the overall rating is so low, maybe this film is just too far for most peoples stretch, a bit to arty and deranged, a bit to creative. To be seen to be believed A clear 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artsy and inept.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reaper
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worth a look if you absolutely positively must see Rose McGowan naked in various degrading situations, but not worth watching otherwise. This movie is not merely bad, but bad AND pretentious. The kind of movie that would have gotten the Mystery Science Theater 3000 treatment, if they could have cleaned the profanity from the soundtrack. The symbolism is laid on with a trowel; Araki must have learned that directors sometimes use color as a motif, so he saturates every frame with reds and blues and yellows. The number 666 appears numerous times - whoa! Symbol! Various sets have pithy signs on the wall - whoa! Symbol! The movie has its fans, but I simply cannot see why. Maybe Araki isn't the Ed Wood of our time, but then again, maybe he is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed to be a B movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mj_heiser-832-695491
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is more depth and thought to this movie than first meets the eye but the Doom Generation unfortunately falls to the ills of poor acting, poor screen writing, and major gaps and holes in the storyline. The first half of the movie, aside from setting up the storyline, is almost a waste of time. Still, the movie is an interesting study in the dark thought and actions of 3 teens on a road trip to hell finding elicit drugs, sex, and violence just at about every stop over. Amy and Jordan are two X Generation punk rockers best described as Stoned most of the time and looking for excitement. They picked up an older but even more-so on the edge low life named X or Xavier who was running from the 'Skin-heads'. As the movie goes along, the depth of depravity increases until Jordan who I find is the most redeemable character being the most harmless starts asking the question 'Is there any meaning in life'. Still I enjoyed some of the thought especially towards the end of the movie. There are some themes around redemption and salvation that I find interesting. There is a lot of sex in this movie of which while I found provocative in the beginning, a major turn off towards the end of the movie where especially for Amy and X, there was nothing sacred in sex. At the conclusion of the movie, Jordan it seemed was the redeemable character as he confesses his love for Amy. And, for those who are squeamish, avoid the ending at all costs. I found it a bit unnecessary and the ending scene in the car almost pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Soon: The History of The Doom Generation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, here's a fine example of hard-hitting, 90's Exploitation. Brought to you by Gregg Araki. The Doom Generation is a gritty, super-dismal, often hilarious tale of murder, betrayal, and sleaziness. We begin with a young couple, hanging out at a club, Amy Blue (meth-head), and Jordan White (pot-head). Amy is a vindictive little nightmare, who's just looking for an argument. And Jordan, well, Jordan doesn't do a whole lot of thinking, but is a good guy, who loves Amy, despite her personality issues. Amy and Jordan take it to the car, so they can lose their virginity, but are soon interrupted... Meet Xavier Red (killer), X for short. Xavier rudely enters Amy's car, rudely demanding she start driving so that he may live, rudely insulting her, subtly insulting Jordan, but he doesn't mind. Amy on the other hand, is about to blow her top, but at least she has someone to argue with now... no wait, he just went too far. Alright guy!! Out of the car. Later in the evening, the teenage, odd couple are rescued by their new pal, X from a trigger-happy, convenience store clerk. after X literally blows the mans head off. They all 3, right then and there, decide to take a road trip together, leaving behind everything. The night sure is going to hell, but at least Amy has someone to argue with again, that's what's important. It doesn't take Xavier long to make his intentions clear, with Amy, and despite the fact that she despises him, she's all for it. They don't try all that hard to hide this from Jordan, but it's cool, Jordan doesn't mind, "X seems like a nice guy". Amy doesn't mind Xavier's insults, Jordan doesn't mind that the man is sleeping with his girlfriend, and no one seems to be all that bothered by the fact that X kills someone every time they stop somewhere. The Doom Generation is harsh, and mean-spirited, and can be ugly, at times, just a swell movie, probably Araki's best. The religious, and apocalyptic metaphors won't go unnoticed, and neither will Rose McGowan, as a foul-mouthed teenager, with a chip on her shoulder, with James Duval's performance making her seem even worse. Some things occur, seemingly with the intention of confusing us, but that's OK, confusion only makes this seem more like exploitation from decades past. For something slightly similar, check out Nowhere... which reminds me, if you ever see both these movies, you might notice that it would be a much better fit if they switched the titles, just a thought. Although, The Doom Generation is deeper than it may seem, it's still a grim good time, with no redeeming qualities, Generation-X-ploitation. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quintessential Film of the 1990s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jordan White (James Duval) and Amy Blue (Rose McGowan), two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos and quickiemarts. While this is probably not a good movie, it holds a certain nostalgia value for me. Gregg Araki really struck a nerve with those coming of age in the 1990s who had an interest in the Gothic an industrial music scene. With the inclusion of references to Nine Inch Nails, Ministry and Skinny Puppy, it was perfect for that demographic. The 1990s had a nihilistic undertone that was not seen in the 1980s or 2000s, leading to such films as "Seven", "Dark City", and the popularity of Tim Burton and David Fincher. This fit in that trend easily and possibly propelled it. The follow-up, "Nowhere", similarly fit in, catching the tail end. (The trend essentially died with "The Matrix".)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cool movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Iris Hall
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -You could find a minimal spoiler- It is a cool movie full of memorable quotes and phrases. It has a strange topic and it makes no sense, but it also has that special ingredient to make it interesting. The three main characters are very special and they make connections through the lighter which is a curious detail. It is a teenage movie, a cult of messed up teens and dark comedy with edgy hotel rooms and rude language. It is the kind of movie that makes you wish you meet people like that and have almost the same adventures Another thing that makes it special is the details, it is full of them! We can call it a 'cult' movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaceheater2187-120-985197
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No mature person could call this film a beautiful, artful, deep movie without bursting into laughter. I'm not even sure where to start. The writing is excessively puerile. Insults such as "anus face" and "get your head out of your rectum" are among a plethora of childlike comebacks thrown around in this film. In what universe does this qualify as "clever, witty writing"? This thing claims to be a comedy. Comedy?! The only time I laughed was at the acting. James Duval delivered his lines in a manner that makes Keanu Reeves look like a ten-time Oscar winner. The plot is virtually nonexistent. They drive, they stop somewhere for greasy food (and the total price of everything they buy totals to $6.66), they accidentally kill someone, they check in at a sleazy motel, have erotic sex, and wake up the next morning and do it all over again. It gets old very quickly. The only reason I kept watching was to see if the plot eventually went anywhere. But no, the film continues in its circular manner until the totally out-of-place climax, and it just ends. I'm sure that's frustrated more people besides just me. Even the technical aspects are sub-standard. The lighting is so horrible at times that I had to turn the brightness to its max on my screen and still couldn't quite tell what was going on. I really would like to keep going, but I'm afraid this diatribe would never end. I'm giving this movie a 2/10. I can think of only two positives about this film, which is why I'm giving it a 2: the first is the soundtrack. Several 90s songs are played in the background during the pointless dialogue. Thank God those songs were there because they were the only things making those scenes tolerable. I also heard some late 80s tunes from time to time. However, if you're not a fan of this type of music, then this positive aspect won't appeal to you. The second positive I can think of was when there was about ten seconds of meaningful dialogue near the end of the film. James Duval's character asks Xavier what the meaning of existence is. Although the answer is rather banal and empty, at least there was an attempt to broach a deeper, more philosophical topic. That one line isn't probably worth a whole star, but I'm feeling particularly magnanimous today. But in no way do these two positives make up for the other 83 minutes of dreck. Avoid this film. The only people drawn to this movie have to be confused teenage emo goths who hate their parents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it. Totally deserves cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebitterend1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those great, special movies that came from the 90's wasteland. The script is insane, the cast are sexy, and it just feels like the perfect slice of late 90's desolation. If you're not into edgy, confronting subject matter, It's definitely not for you, but i like my films a little bit dangerous and out of control, and that's exactly what The Doom Generation is; out of control. Sure, there are plot points that don't quite fit, but they don't have to. The movie perfectly complements the emotional landscape of the characters. It's crazy, over sexed self absorbed angst with a side serving of nihilism. Accept it for what it is and enjoy it. Not enough films take the risks they used to, and i applaud The Doom Generation for being what it needs to be, the same way Natural Born Killers did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gregkae
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stunning piece elicits emotions that in my case were so intense that I submitted myself to the harrowing experience of the registration process just to be able to share with the world that I throw up more colourful ideas after a bad paella and a bottle of cheap lambrusco. I white-knuckled it on fast forward and it still dragged like a 45 minute tooth extraction; waxing your armpits hurts less. Whoever participated in churning out this steaming pile of manure should be sent to a pig farm for a lifetime of unpaid work. Pointless, clueless, plot less. No script, no dialogue, no direction. It makes you think though - who stole the money to finance it, who blackmailed the actors to take part in it, who browbeat a family member to shoot it, so yeah, it is thought provoking. My neighbour's cat suffering from chronic diarrhoea excretes stuff that has more substance to it. To top it off this drivel looks like it has been recorded on a point-and-shoot pocket camera bought at a country fair in eastern Europe. IMDb really has to introduce new ratings system, maybe minus points, so that pieces like the doom generation can get its undeniable praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phallic joy and the failure of heterosexuality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film in Araki's Teenage Apocalypse Trilogy builds upon the premises laid out in "Nowhere" and "Totally F***ed Up". And what better way to end a trilogy than with a threesome in the making? The three protagonists of this production are Jordan White, interpreted by James Duval who once again conveys all the confusion and insecurities of adolescence, Amy Blue, his sexy girlfriend and Xavier Red, a wild, aggressive and assertive guy they meet on the road. Together they will embark upon a journey that, without a clear destination, will bring forth certain aspects of their real 'selves'. At the beginning of the film, Jordan attempts to penetrate his girlfriend to no avail. But this is not a reference to impotence. It is rather a reaffirmation of what Lacan would denominate the nonexistence of sexual rapport. Amy tries to give directions to her insecure boyfriend about what to do with his penis. Obviously, sexual joy here is phallocentric. But let's not forget that the phallus is a signifier, and even the model of jouissance is bound to be seized in the idiocy of the practice that attests to it. A phallocentric perspective exemplifies the non-rapport in the Other. To declare that the jouissance is phallic is fundamentally to state it is solitary. That clearly explains why is it that Jordan and Amy are unable to consummate their passion, remaining as virgins. According to Lacan, the axiom "There is no such thing as sexual rapport" obeys to a basically solitary jouissance. When Jordan asks Amy "Don't you think sex is totally strange? Just the whole idea of it" he is essentially explaining how difficult it is to decode sex in the symbolic order, because sex can neither be translated into words nor discarded as simulacra (which happens very often in postmodern society). Amy then responds "I think maybe it's more powerful than we'd like it to be". And she is absolutely right about it. As soon as Xavier enters into scene, sexual dynamics are fiercely disrupted. Xavier is sexually overwhelming, he invades the personal space of the boy and the girl, disregarding gender divisions. When Jordan and Amy are taking a shower together, Xavier looks at them and masturbates. Masturbation is very relevant in "The Doom Generation", after all, what could best exemplify the solitary jouissance? Amy describes Xavier as a living support for the sexual organ, and Xavier has no problems in acting as a "walking penis", so to speak. He is rendered as the phallus, and because he is the phallus he becomes desirable for Amy and Jordan. According to Freud, the man possesses the phallus, for Lacan, however, the woman can also have it (let's remember that phallus is not a synonym for penis). In both cases, as embarrassment, as lack, a substitute to be looked for, yet essentially, sexuality will be there conditioned, determined. To have the phallus is to be afraid of losing it; to not have it is to seek for it. All this is demonstrated when Amy engages in sexual intercourse with Xavier, thus creating a specular moment, an instance which reflects a previous one, in which Jordan masturbates while he sees his girlfriend and his new friend copulating (dynamics that bear some similitude to Cristopher Munch's Harry + Max, so it's not surprising to see this filmmaker credited at the end). Nonetheless, one of the most fascinating aspects of the film is the feeling of impending doom that permeates reality over and over again. Amy will summarize it in one phrase: "there is no place for us in this world"; whereas Jordan will only inquire "ever felt like reality is more twisted than dreams?". "The Doom Generation" is as surreal as other Araki's films, and it picks up on a certain leit motif present in his cinematographic work: religious zealousness and all it entangles. From Amy's mother (a fervent scientologist) to billboards with messages such as The Rapture is Coming (a "doomsday" of sorts according to certain religious sects as explained in "Nowhere") or Prepare for the Apocalypse. Of course, there is also the constant emphasis on 666, the number of the beast; every time the characters buy food or have to pay for something, the price is exactly the same 6 dollars with 66 cents. 6.66. The film is thoroughly filled with what Genet would call paratextual references, here the "writing on the wall" is very visible, in every wall, in every store and gas station they visit. Reality seems to be seeping down under their very noses, although as Xavier reminds them: "I saw it on TV so it's gotta be true, right?". But there is little or nothing they can grab a hold on. And this capricious dynamic is reinforced by the fact that Amy is an interchangeable object a (object of desire), as a fast food employee confuses her with an old flame and chases her down, something that also happens with an enraged lesbian, and a gay man. All forms of sexuality (heterosexuality, male and female homosexuality) enable the completion of yet another trio. When Jordan, Amy and Xavier are finally ready for a threesome, something of the order of the real irrupts and dramatically changes everything. A violent group of men captures the protagonists, and threaten Jordan very seriously with removing his genitals. But what could castration mean? A rapport should be posited and established, from a subject of one sex to the phallus, and would not get inscribed by a rapport to the partner sexed differently. This is the value Lacan bestows on the universal allotted to the castration complex. Thus the Old Testament conjectures that Sodom will suit the man and Gomorrah the woman. If castration was metaphorical at the beginning (Jordan's inability to maintain an erection) here it takes a more literal approach, which is only fitting if we consider that sexual rapport for the protagonists will forever be impossible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant by Araki again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Totally brilliant psychedelic film by the director of Mysterious skin and Nowhere, Gregg Araki(one of my favourite directors). He managed to create another brilliant sexual film with that bit of weirdness that I love in films, with brilliant acting by the cast (especially James Duval), with brilliant shots that could only come from a brilliant director like himself. I don't understand why the overall rating is so low, maybe this film is just too far for most peoples stretch, a bit to arty and deranged, a bit to creative. To be seen to be believed A clear 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artsy and inept.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reaper
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worth a look if you absolutely positively must see Rose McGowan naked in various degrading situations, but not worth watching otherwise. This movie is not merely bad, but bad AND pretentious. The kind of movie that would have gotten the Mystery Science Theater 3000 treatment, if they could have cleaned the profanity from the soundtrack. The symbolism is laid on with a trowel; Araki must have learned that directors sometimes use color as a motif, so he saturates every frame with reds and blues and yellows. The number 666 appears numerous times - whoa! Symbol! Various sets have pithy signs on the wall - whoa! Symbol! The movie has its fans, but I simply cannot see why. Maybe Araki isn't the Ed Wood of our time, but then again, maybe he is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed to be a B movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mj_heiser-832-695491
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is more depth and thought to this movie than first meets the eye but the Doom Generation unfortunately falls to the ills of poor acting, poor screen writing, and major gaps and holes in the storyline. The first half of the movie, aside from setting up the storyline, is almost a waste of time. Still, the movie is an interesting study in the dark thought and actions of 3 teens on a road trip to hell finding elicit drugs, sex, and violence just at about every stop over. Amy and Jordan are two X Generation punk rockers best described as Stoned most of the time and looking for excitement. They picked up an older but even more-so on the edge low life named X or Xavier who was running from the 'Skin-heads'. As the movie goes along, the depth of depravity increases until Jordan who I find is the most redeemable character being the most harmless starts asking the question 'Is there any meaning in life'. Still I enjoyed some of the thought especially towards the end of the movie. There are some themes around redemption and salvation that I find interesting. There is a lot of sex in this movie of which while I found provocative in the beginning, a major turn off towards the end of the movie where especially for Amy and X, there was nothing sacred in sex. At the conclusion of the movie, Jordan it seemed was the redeemable character as he confesses his love for Amy. And, for those who are squeamish, avoid the ending at all costs. I found it a bit unnecessary and the ending scene in the car almost pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Soon: The History of The Doom Generation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, here's a fine example of hard-hitting, 90's Exploitation. Brought to you by Gregg Araki. The Doom Generation is a gritty, super-dismal, often hilarious tale of murder, betrayal, and sleaziness. We begin with a young couple, hanging out at a club, Amy Blue (meth-head), and Jordan White (pot-head). Amy is a vindictive little nightmare, who's just looking for an argument. And Jordan, well, Jordan doesn't do a whole lot of thinking, but is a good guy, who loves Amy, despite her personality issues. Amy and Jordan take it to the car, so they can lose their virginity, but are soon interrupted... Meet Xavier Red (killer), X for short. Xavier rudely enters Amy's car, rudely demanding she start driving so that he may live, rudely insulting her, subtly insulting Jordan, but he doesn't mind. Amy on the other hand, is about to blow her top, but at least she has someone to argue with now... no wait, he just went too far. Alright guy!! Out of the car. Later in the evening, the teenage, odd couple are rescued by their new pal, X from a trigger-happy, convenience store clerk. after X literally blows the mans head off. They all 3, right then and there, decide to take a road trip together, leaving behind everything. The night sure is going to hell, but at least Amy has someone to argue with again, that's what's important. It doesn't take Xavier long to make his intentions clear, with Amy, and despite the fact that she despises him, she's all for it. They don't try all that hard to hide this from Jordan, but it's cool, Jordan doesn't mind, "X seems like a nice guy". Amy doesn't mind Xavier's insults, Jordan doesn't mind that the man is sleeping with his girlfriend, and no one seems to be all that bothered by the fact that X kills someone every time they stop somewhere. The Doom Generation is harsh, and mean-spirited, and can be ugly, at times, just a swell movie, probably Araki's best. The religious, and apocalyptic metaphors won't go unnoticed, and neither will Rose McGowan, as a foul-mouthed teenager, with a chip on her shoulder, with James Duval's performance making her seem even worse. Some things occur, seemingly with the intention of confusing us, but that's OK, confusion only makes this seem more like exploitation from decades past. For something slightly similar, check out Nowhere... which reminds me, if you ever see both these movies, you might notice that it would be a much better fit if they switched the titles, just a thought. Although, The Doom Generation is deeper than it may seem, it's still a grim good time, with no redeeming qualities, Generation-X-ploitation. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quintessential Film of the 1990s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jordan White (James Duval) and Amy Blue (Rose McGowan), two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos and quickiemarts. While this is probably not a good movie, it holds a certain nostalgia value for me. Gregg Araki really struck a nerve with those coming of age in the 1990s who had an interest in the Gothic an industrial music scene. With the inclusion of references to Nine Inch Nails, Ministry and Skinny Puppy, it was perfect for that demographic. The 1990s had a nihilistic undertone that was not seen in the 1980s or 2000s, leading to such films as "Seven", "Dark City", and the popularity of Tim Burton and David Fincher. This fit in that trend easily and possibly propelled it. The follow-up, "Nowhere", similarly fit in, catching the tail end. (The trend essentially died with "The Matrix".)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cool movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Iris Hall
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -You could find a minimal spoiler- It is a cool movie full of memorable quotes and phrases. It has a strange topic and it makes no sense, but it also has that special ingredient to make it interesting. The three main characters are very special and they make connections through the lighter which is a curious detail. It is a teenage movie, a cult of messed up teens and dark comedy with edgy hotel rooms and rude language. It is the kind of movie that makes you wish you meet people like that and have almost the same adventures Another thing that makes it special is the details, it is full of them! We can call it a 'cult' movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaceheater2187-120-985197
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No mature person could call this film a beautiful, artful, deep movie without bursting into laughter. I'm not even sure where to start. The writing is excessively puerile. Insults such as "anus face" and "get your head out of your rectum" are among a plethora of childlike comebacks thrown around in this film. In what universe does this qualify as "clever, witty writing"? This thing claims to be a comedy. Comedy?! The only time I laughed was at the acting. James Duval delivered his lines in a manner that makes Keanu Reeves look like a ten-time Oscar winner. The plot is virtually nonexistent. They drive, they stop somewhere for greasy food (and the total price of everything they buy totals to $6.66), they accidentally kill someone, they check in at a sleazy motel, have erotic sex, and wake up the next morning and do it all over again. It gets old very quickly. The only reason I kept watching was to see if the plot eventually went anywhere. But no, the film continues in its circular manner until the totally out-of-place climax, and it just ends. I'm sure that's frustrated more people besides just me. Even the technical aspects are sub-standard. The lighting is so horrible at times that I had to turn the brightness to its max on my screen and still couldn't quite tell what was going on. I really would like to keep going, but I'm afraid this diatribe would never end. I'm giving this movie a 2/10. I can think of only two positives about this film, which is why I'm giving it a 2: the first is the soundtrack. Several 90s songs are played in the background during the pointless dialogue. Thank God those songs were there because they were the only things making those scenes tolerable. I also heard some late 80s tunes from time to time. However, if you're not a fan of this type of music, then this positive aspect won't appeal to you. The second positive I can think of was when there was about ten seconds of meaningful dialogue near the end of the film. James Duval's character asks Xavier what the meaning of existence is. Although the answer is rather banal and empty, at least there was an attempt to broach a deeper, more philosophical topic. That one line isn't probably worth a whole star, but I'm feeling particularly magnanimous today. But in no way do these two positives make up for the other 83 minutes of dreck. Avoid this film. The only people drawn to this movie have to be confused teenage emo goths who hate their parents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it. Totally deserves cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebitterend1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those great, special movies that came from the 90's wasteland. The script is insane, the cast are sexy, and it just feels like the perfect slice of late 90's desolation. If you're not into edgy, confronting subject matter, It's definitely not for you, but i like my films a little bit dangerous and out of control, and that's exactly what The Doom Generation is; out of control. Sure, there are plot points that don't quite fit, but they don't have to. The movie perfectly complements the emotional landscape of the characters. It's crazy, over sexed self absorbed angst with a side serving of nihilism. Accept it for what it is and enjoy it. Not enough films take the risks they used to, and i applaud The Doom Generation for being what it needs to be, the same way Natural Born Killers did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gregkae
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stunning piece elicits emotions that in my case were so intense that I submitted myself to the harrowing experience of the registration process just to be able to share with the world that I throw up more colourful ideas after a bad paella and a bottle of cheap lambrusco. I white-knuckled it on fast forward and it still dragged like a 45 minute tooth extraction; waxing your armpits hurts less. Whoever participated in churning out this steaming pile of manure should be sent to a pig farm for a lifetime of unpaid work. Pointless, clueless, plot less. No script, no dialogue, no direction. It makes you think though - who stole the money to finance it, who blackmailed the actors to take part in it, who browbeat a family member to shoot it, so yeah, it is thought provoking. My neighbour's cat suffering from chronic diarrhoea excretes stuff that has more substance to it. To top it off this drivel looks like it has been recorded on a point-and-shoot pocket camera bought at a country fair in eastern Europe. IMDb really has to introduce new ratings system, maybe minus points, so that pieces like the doom generation can get its undeniable praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phallic joy and the failure of heterosexuality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film in Araki's Teenage Apocalypse Trilogy builds upon the premises laid out in "Nowhere" and "Totally F***ed Up". And what better way to end a trilogy than with a threesome in the making? The three protagonists of this production are Jordan White, interpreted by James Duval who once again conveys all the confusion and insecurities of adolescence, Amy Blue, his sexy girlfriend and Xavier Red, a wild, aggressive and assertive guy they meet on the road. Together they will embark upon a journey that, without a clear destination, will bring forth certain aspects of their real 'selves'. At the beginning of the film, Jordan attempts to penetrate his girlfriend to no avail. But this is not a reference to impotence. It is rather a reaffirmation of what Lacan would denominate the nonexistence of sexual rapport. Amy tries to give directions to her insecure boyfriend about what to do with his penis. Obviously, sexual joy here is phallocentric. But let's not forget that the phallus is a signifier, and even the model of jouissance is bound to be seized in the idiocy of the practice that attests to it. A phallocentric perspective exemplifies the non-rapport in the Other. To declare that the jouissance is phallic is fundamentally to state it is solitary. That clearly explains why is it that Jordan and Amy are unable to consummate their passion, remaining as virgins. According to Lacan, the axiom "There is no such thing as sexual rapport" obeys to a basically solitary jouissance. When Jordan asks Amy "Don't you think sex is totally strange? Just the whole idea of it" he is essentially explaining how difficult it is to decode sex in the symbolic order, because sex can neither be translated into words nor discarded as simulacra (which happens very often in postmodern society). Amy then responds "I think maybe it's more powerful than we'd like it to be". And she is absolutely right about it. As soon as Xavier enters into scene, sexual dynamics are fiercely disrupted. Xavier is sexually overwhelming, he invades the personal space of the boy and the girl, disregarding gender divisions. When Jordan and Amy are taking a shower together, Xavier looks at them and masturbates. Masturbation is very relevant in "The Doom Generation", after all, what could best exemplify the solitary jouissance? Amy describes Xavier as a living support for the sexual organ, and Xavier has no problems in acting as a "walking penis", so to speak. He is rendered as the phallus, and because he is the phallus he becomes desirable for Amy and Jordan. According to Freud, the man possesses the phallus, for Lacan, however, the woman can also have it (let's remember that phallus is not a synonym for penis). In both cases, as embarrassment, as lack, a substitute to be looked for, yet essentially, sexuality will be there conditioned, determined. To have the phallus is to be afraid of losing it; to not have it is to seek for it. All this is demonstrated when Amy engages in sexual intercourse with Xavier, thus creating a specular moment, an instance which reflects a previous one, in which Jordan masturbates while he sees his girlfriend and his new friend copulating (dynamics that bear some similitude to Cristopher Munch's Harry + Max, so it's not surprising to see this filmmaker credited at the end). Nonetheless, one of the most fascinating aspects of the film is the feeling of impending doom that permeates reality over and over again. Amy will summarize it in one phrase: "there is no place for us in this world"; whereas Jordan will only inquire "ever felt like reality is more twisted than dreams?". "The Doom Generation" is as surreal as other Araki's films, and it picks up on a certain leit motif present in his cinematographic work: religious zealousness and all it entangles. From Amy's mother (a fervent scientologist) to billboards with messages such as The Rapture is Coming (a "doomsday" of sorts according to certain religious sects as explained in "Nowhere") or Prepare for the Apocalypse. Of course, there is also the constant emphasis on 666, the number of the beast; every time the characters buy food or have to pay for something, the price is exactly the same 6 dollars with 66 cents. 6.66. The film is thoroughly filled with what Genet would call paratextual references, here the "writing on the wall" is very visible, in every wall, in every store and gas station they visit. Reality seems to be seeping down under their very noses, although as Xavier reminds them: "I saw it on TV so it's gotta be true, right?". But there is little or nothing they can grab a hold on. And this capricious dynamic is reinforced by the fact that Amy is an interchangeable object a (object of desire), as a fast food employee confuses her with an old flame and chases her down, something that also happens with an enraged lesbian, and a gay man. All forms of sexuality (heterosexuality, male and female homosexuality) enable the completion of yet another trio. When Jordan, Amy and Xavier are finally ready for a threesome, something of the order of the real irrupts and dramatically changes everything. A violent group of men captures the protagonists, and threaten Jordan very seriously with removing his genitals. But what could castration mean? A rapport should be posited and established, from a subject of one sex to the phallus, and would not get inscribed by a rapport to the partner sexed differently. This is the value Lacan bestows on the universal allotted to the castration complex. Thus the Old Testament conjectures that Sodom will suit the man and Gomorrah the woman. If castration was metaphorical at the beginning (Jordan's inability to maintain an erection) here it takes a more literal approach, which is only fitting if we consider that sexual rapport for the protagonists will forever be impossible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant by Araki again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Totally brilliant psychedelic film by the director of Mysterious skin and Nowhere, Gregg Araki(one of my favourite directors). He managed to create another brilliant sexual film with that bit of weirdness that I love in films, with brilliant acting by the cast (especially James Duval), with brilliant shots that could only come from a brilliant director like himself. I don't understand why the overall rating is so low, maybe this film is just too far for most peoples stretch, a bit to arty and deranged, a bit to creative. To be seen to be believed A clear 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artsy and inept.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reaper
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worth a look if you absolutely positively must see Rose McGowan naked in various degrading situations, but not worth watching otherwise. This movie is not merely bad, but bad AND pretentious. The kind of movie that would have gotten the Mystery Science Theater 3000 treatment, if they could have cleaned the profanity from the soundtrack. The symbolism is laid on with a trowel; Araki must have learned that directors sometimes use color as a motif, so he saturates every frame with reds and blues and yellows. The number 666 appears numerous times - whoa! Symbol! Various sets have pithy signs on the wall - whoa! Symbol! The movie has its fans, but I simply cannot see why. Maybe Araki isn't the Ed Wood of our time, but then again, maybe he is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed to be a B movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mj_heiser-832-695491
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is more depth and thought to this movie than first meets the eye but the Doom Generation unfortunately falls to the ills of poor acting, poor screen writing, and major gaps and holes in the storyline. The first half of the movie, aside from setting up the storyline, is almost a waste of time. Still, the movie is an interesting study in the dark thought and actions of 3 teens on a road trip to hell finding elicit drugs, sex, and violence just at about every stop over. Amy and Jordan are two X Generation punk rockers best described as Stoned most of the time and looking for excitement. They picked up an older but even more-so on the edge low life named X or Xavier who was running from the 'Skin-heads'. As the movie goes along, the depth of depravity increases until Jordan who I find is the most redeemable character being the most harmless starts asking the question 'Is there any meaning in life'. Still I enjoyed some of the thought especially towards the end of the movie. There are some themes around redemption and salvation that I find interesting. There is a lot of sex in this movie of which while I found provocative in the beginning, a major turn off towards the end of the movie where especially for Amy and X, there was nothing sacred in sex. At the conclusion of the movie, Jordan it seemed was the redeemable character as he confesses his love for Amy. And, for those who are squeamish, avoid the ending at all costs. I found it a bit unnecessary and the ending scene in the car almost pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Soon: The History of The Doom Generation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, here's a fine example of hard-hitting, 90's Exploitation. Brought to you by Gregg Araki. The Doom Generation is a gritty, super-dismal, often hilarious tale of murder, betrayal, and sleaziness. We begin with a young couple, hanging out at a club, Amy Blue (meth-head), and Jordan White (pot-head). Amy is a vindictive little nightmare, who's just looking for an argument. And Jordan, well, Jordan doesn't do a whole lot of thinking, but is a good guy, who loves Amy, despite her personality issues. Amy and Jordan take it to the car, so they can lose their virginity, but are soon interrupted... Meet Xavier Red (killer), X for short. Xavier rudely enters Amy's car, rudely demanding she start driving so that he may live, rudely insulting her, subtly insulting Jordan, but he doesn't mind. Amy on the other hand, is about to blow her top, but at least she has someone to argue with now... no wait, he just went too far. Alright guy!! Out of the car. Later in the evening, the teenage, odd couple are rescued by their new pal, X from a trigger-happy, convenience store clerk. after X literally blows the mans head off. They all 3, right then and there, decide to take a road trip together, leaving behind everything. The night sure is going to hell, but at least Amy has someone to argue with again, that's what's important. It doesn't take Xavier long to make his intentions clear, with Amy, and despite the fact that she despises him, she's all for it. They don't try all that hard to hide this from Jordan, but it's cool, Jordan doesn't mind, "X seems like a nice guy". Amy doesn't mind Xavier's insults, Jordan doesn't mind that the man is sleeping with his girlfriend, and no one seems to be all that bothered by the fact that X kills someone every time they stop somewhere. The Doom Generation is harsh, and mean-spirited, and can be ugly, at times, just a swell movie, probably Araki's best. The religious, and apocalyptic metaphors won't go unnoticed, and neither will Rose McGowan, as a foul-mouthed teenager, with a chip on her shoulder, with James Duval's performance making her seem even worse. Some things occur, seemingly with the intention of confusing us, but that's OK, confusion only makes this seem more like exploitation from decades past. For something slightly similar, check out Nowhere... which reminds me, if you ever see both these movies, you might notice that it would be a much better fit if they switched the titles, just a thought. Although, The Doom Generation is deeper than it may seem, it's still a grim good time, with no redeeming qualities, Generation-X-ploitation. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quintessential Film of the 1990s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jordan White (James Duval) and Amy Blue (Rose McGowan), two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos and quickiemarts. While this is probably not a good movie, it holds a certain nostalgia value for me. Gregg Araki really struck a nerve with those coming of age in the 1990s who had an interest in the Gothic an industrial music scene. With the inclusion of references to Nine Inch Nails, Ministry and Skinny Puppy, it was perfect for that demographic. The 1990s had a nihilistic undertone that was not seen in the 1980s or 2000s, leading to such films as "Seven", "Dark City", and the popularity of Tim Burton and David Fincher. This fit in that trend easily and possibly propelled it. The follow-up, "Nowhere", similarly fit in, catching the tail end. (The trend essentially died with "The Matrix".)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cool movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Iris Hall
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -You could find a minimal spoiler- It is a cool movie full of memorable quotes and phrases. It has a strange topic and it makes no sense, but it also has that special ingredient to make it interesting. The three main characters are very special and they make connections through the lighter which is a curious detail. It is a teenage movie, a cult of messed up teens and dark comedy with edgy hotel rooms and rude language. It is the kind of movie that makes you wish you meet people like that and have almost the same adventures Another thing that makes it special is the details, it is full of them! We can call it a 'cult' movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaceheater2187-120-985197
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No mature person could call this film a beautiful, artful, deep movie without bursting into laughter. I'm not even sure where to start. The writing is excessively puerile. Insults such as "anus face" and "get your head out of your rectum" are among a plethora of childlike comebacks thrown around in this film. In what universe does this qualify as "clever, witty writing"? This thing claims to be a comedy. Comedy?! The only time I laughed was at the acting. James Duval delivered his lines in a manner that makes Keanu Reeves look like a ten-time Oscar winner. The plot is virtually nonexistent. They drive, they stop somewhere for greasy food (and the total price of everything they buy totals to $6.66), they accidentally kill someone, they check in at a sleazy motel, have erotic sex, and wake up the next morning and do it all over again. It gets old very quickly. The only reason I kept watching was to see if the plot eventually went anywhere. But no, the film continues in its circular manner until the totally out-of-place climax, and it just ends. I'm sure that's frustrated more people besides just me. Even the technical aspects are sub-standard. The lighting is so horrible at times that I had to turn the brightness to its max on my screen and still couldn't quite tell what was going on. I really would like to keep going, but I'm afraid this diatribe would never end. I'm giving this movie a 2/10. I can think of only two positives about this film, which is why I'm giving it a 2: the first is the soundtrack. Several 90s songs are played in the background during the pointless dialogue. Thank God those songs were there because they were the only things making those scenes tolerable. I also heard some late 80s tunes from time to time. However, if you're not a fan of this type of music, then this positive aspect won't appeal to you. The second positive I can think of was when there was about ten seconds of meaningful dialogue near the end of the film. James Duval's character asks Xavier what the meaning of existence is. Although the answer is rather banal and empty, at least there was an attempt to broach a deeper, more philosophical topic. That one line isn't probably worth a whole star, but I'm feeling particularly magnanimous today. But in no way do these two positives make up for the other 83 minutes of dreck. Avoid this film. The only people drawn to this movie have to be confused teenage emo goths who hate their parents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it. Totally deserves cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebitterend1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those great, special movies that came from the 90's wasteland. The script is insane, the cast are sexy, and it just feels like the perfect slice of late 90's desolation. If you're not into edgy, confronting subject matter, It's definitely not for you, but i like my films a little bit dangerous and out of control, and that's exactly what The Doom Generation is; out of control. Sure, there are plot points that don't quite fit, but they don't have to. The movie perfectly complements the emotional landscape of the characters. It's crazy, over sexed self absorbed angst with a side serving of nihilism. Accept it for what it is and enjoy it. Not enough films take the risks they used to, and i applaud The Doom Generation for being what it needs to be, the same way Natural Born Killers did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gregkae
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stunning piece elicits emotions that in my case were so intense that I submitted myself to the harrowing experience of the registration process just to be able to share with the world that I throw up more colourful ideas after a bad paella and a bottle of cheap lambrusco. I white-knuckled it on fast forward and it still dragged like a 45 minute tooth extraction; waxing your armpits hurts less. Whoever participated in churning out this steaming pile of manure should be sent to a pig farm for a lifetime of unpaid work. Pointless, clueless, plot less. No script, no dialogue, no direction. It makes you think though - who stole the money to finance it, who blackmailed the actors to take part in it, who browbeat a family member to shoot it, so yeah, it is thought provoking. My neighbour's cat suffering from chronic diarrhoea excretes stuff that has more substance to it. To top it off this drivel looks like it has been recorded on a point-and-shoot pocket camera bought at a country fair in eastern Europe. IMDb really has to introduce new ratings system, maybe minus points, so that pieces like the doom generation can get its undeniable praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phallic joy and the failure of heterosexuality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film in Araki's Teenage Apocalypse Trilogy builds upon the premises laid out in "Nowhere" and "Totally F***ed Up". And what better way to end a trilogy than with a threesome in the making? The three protagonists of this production are Jordan White, interpreted by James Duval who once again conveys all the confusion and insecurities of adolescence, Amy Blue, his sexy girlfriend and Xavier Red, a wild, aggressive and assertive guy they meet on the road. Together they will embark upon a journey that, without a clear destination, will bring forth certain aspects of their real 'selves'. At the beginning of the film, Jordan attempts to penetrate his girlfriend to no avail. But this is not a reference to impotence. It is rather a reaffirmation of what Lacan would denominate the nonexistence of sexual rapport. Amy tries to give directions to her insecure boyfriend about what to do with his penis. Obviously, sexual joy here is phallocentric. But let's not forget that the phallus is a signifier, and even the model of jouissance is bound to be seized in the idiocy of the practice that attests to it. A phallocentric perspective exemplifies the non-rapport in the Other. To declare that the jouissance is phallic is fundamentally to state it is solitary. That clearly explains why is it that Jordan and Amy are unable to consummate their passion, remaining as virgins. According to Lacan, the axiom "There is no such thing as sexual rapport" obeys to a basically solitary jouissance. When Jordan asks Amy "Don't you think sex is totally strange? Just the whole idea of it" he is essentially explaining how difficult it is to decode sex in the symbolic order, because sex can neither be translated into words nor discarded as simulacra (which happens very often in postmodern society). Amy then responds "I think maybe it's more powerful than we'd like it to be". And she is absolutely right about it. As soon as Xavier enters into scene, sexual dynamics are fiercely disrupted. Xavier is sexually overwhelming, he invades the personal space of the boy and the girl, disregarding gender divisions. When Jordan and Amy are taking a shower together, Xavier looks at them and masturbates. Masturbation is very relevant in "The Doom Generation", after all, what could best exemplify the solitary jouissance? Amy describes Xavier as a living support for the sexual organ, and Xavier has no problems in acting as a "walking penis", so to speak. He is rendered as the phallus, and because he is the phallus he becomes desirable for Amy and Jordan. According to Freud, the man possesses the phallus, for Lacan, however, the woman can also have it (let's remember that phallus is not a synonym for penis). In both cases, as embarrassment, as lack, a substitute to be looked for, yet essentially, sexuality will be there conditioned, determined. To have the phallus is to be afraid of losing it; to not have it is to seek for it. All this is demonstrated when Amy engages in sexual intercourse with Xavier, thus creating a specular moment, an instance which reflects a previous one, in which Jordan masturbates while he sees his girlfriend and his new friend copulating (dynamics that bear some similitude to Cristopher Munch's Harry + Max, so it's not surprising to see this filmmaker credited at the end). Nonetheless, one of the most fascinating aspects of the film is the feeling of impending doom that permeates reality over and over again. Amy will summarize it in one phrase: "there is no place for us in this world"; whereas Jordan will only inquire "ever felt like reality is more twisted than dreams?". "The Doom Generation" is as surreal as other Araki's films, and it picks up on a certain leit motif present in his cinematographic work: religious zealousness and all it entangles. From Amy's mother (a fervent scientologist) to billboards with messages such as The Rapture is Coming (a "doomsday" of sorts according to certain religious sects as explained in "Nowhere") or Prepare for the Apocalypse. Of course, there is also the constant emphasis on 666, the number of the beast; every time the characters buy food or have to pay for something, the price is exactly the same 6 dollars with 66 cents. 6.66. The film is thoroughly filled with what Genet would call paratextual references, here the "writing on the wall" is very visible, in every wall, in every store and gas station they visit. Reality seems to be seeping down under their very noses, although as Xavier reminds them: "I saw it on TV so it's gotta be true, right?". But there is little or nothing they can grab a hold on. And this capricious dynamic is reinforced by the fact that Amy is an interchangeable object a (object of desire), as a fast food employee confuses her with an old flame and chases her down, something that also happens with an enraged lesbian, and a gay man. All forms of sexuality (heterosexuality, male and female homosexuality) enable the completion of yet another trio. When Jordan, Amy and Xavier are finally ready for a threesome, something of the order of the real irrupts and dramatically changes everything. A violent group of men captures the protagonists, and threaten Jordan very seriously with removing his genitals. But what could castration mean? A rapport should be posited and established, from a subject of one sex to the phallus, and would not get inscribed by a rapport to the partner sexed differently. This is the value Lacan bestows on the universal allotted to the castration complex. Thus the Old Testament conjectures that Sodom will suit the man and Gomorrah the woman. If castration was metaphorical at the beginning (Jordan's inability to maintain an erection) here it takes a more literal approach, which is only fitting if we consider that sexual rapport for the protagonists will forever be impossible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant by Araki again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Totally brilliant psychedelic film by the director of Mysterious skin and Nowhere, Gregg Araki(one of my favourite directors). He managed to create another brilliant sexual film with that bit of weirdness that I love in films, with brilliant acting by the cast (especially James Duval), with brilliant shots that could only come from a brilliant director like himself. I don't understand why the overall rating is so low, maybe this film is just too far for most peoples stretch, a bit to arty and deranged, a bit to creative. To be seen to be believed A clear 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artsy and inept.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reaper
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worth a look if you absolutely positively must see Rose McGowan naked in various degrading situations, but not worth watching otherwise. This movie is not merely bad, but bad AND pretentious. The kind of movie that would have gotten the Mystery Science Theater 3000 treatment, if they could have cleaned the profanity from the soundtrack. The symbolism is laid on with a trowel; Araki must have learned that directors sometimes use color as a motif, so he saturates every frame with reds and blues and yellows. The number 666 appears numerous times - whoa! Symbol! Various sets have pithy signs on the wall - whoa! Symbol! The movie has its fans, but I simply cannot see why. Maybe Araki isn't the Ed Wood of our time, but then again, maybe he is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed to be a B movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mj_heiser-832-695491
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is more depth and thought to this movie than first meets the eye but the Doom Generation unfortunately falls to the ills of poor acting, poor screen writing, and major gaps and holes in the storyline. The first half of the movie, aside from setting up the storyline, is almost a waste of time. Still, the movie is an interesting study in the dark thought and actions of 3 teens on a road trip to hell finding elicit drugs, sex, and violence just at about every stop over. Amy and Jordan are two X Generation punk rockers best described as Stoned most of the time and looking for excitement. They picked up an older but even more-so on the edge low life named X or Xavier who was running from the 'Skin-heads'. As the movie goes along, the depth of depravity increases until Jordan who I find is the most redeemable character being the most harmless starts asking the question 'Is there any meaning in life'. Still I enjoyed some of the thought especially towards the end of the movie. There are some themes around redemption and salvation that I find interesting. There is a lot of sex in this movie of which while I found provocative in the beginning, a major turn off towards the end of the movie where especially for Amy and X, there was nothing sacred in sex. At the conclusion of the movie, Jordan it seemed was the redeemable character as he confesses his love for Amy. And, for those who are squeamish, avoid the ending at all costs. I found it a bit unnecessary and the ending scene in the car almost pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Soon: The History of The Doom Generation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, here's a fine example of hard-hitting, 90's Exploitation. Brought to you by Gregg Araki. The Doom Generation is a gritty, super-dismal, often hilarious tale of murder, betrayal, and sleaziness. We begin with a young couple, hanging out at a club, Amy Blue (meth-head), and Jordan White (pot-head). Amy is a vindictive little nightmare, who's just looking for an argument. And Jordan, well, Jordan doesn't do a whole lot of thinking, but is a good guy, who loves Amy, despite her personality issues. Amy and Jordan take it to the car, so they can lose their virginity, but are soon interrupted... Meet Xavier Red (killer), X for short. Xavier rudely enters Amy's car, rudely demanding she start driving so that he may live, rudely insulting her, subtly insulting Jordan, but he doesn't mind. Amy on the other hand, is about to blow her top, but at least she has someone to argue with now... no wait, he just went too far. Alright guy!! Out of the car. Later in the evening, the teenage, odd couple are rescued by their new pal, X from a trigger-happy, convenience store clerk. after X literally blows the mans head off. They all 3, right then and there, decide to take a road trip together, leaving behind everything. The night sure is going to hell, but at least Amy has someone to argue with again, that's what's important. It doesn't take Xavier long to make his intentions clear, with Amy, and despite the fact that she despises him, she's all for it. They don't try all that hard to hide this from Jordan, but it's cool, Jordan doesn't mind, "X seems like a nice guy". Amy doesn't mind Xavier's insults, Jordan doesn't mind that the man is sleeping with his girlfriend, and no one seems to be all that bothered by the fact that X kills someone every time they stop somewhere. The Doom Generation is harsh, and mean-spirited, and can be ugly, at times, just a swell movie, probably Araki's best. The religious, and apocalyptic metaphors won't go unnoticed, and neither will Rose McGowan, as a foul-mouthed teenager, with a chip on her shoulder, with James Duval's performance making her seem even worse. Some things occur, seemingly with the intention of confusing us, but that's OK, confusion only makes this seem more like exploitation from decades past. For something slightly similar, check out Nowhere... which reminds me, if you ever see both these movies, you might notice that it would be a much better fit if they switched the titles, just a thought. Although, The Doom Generation is deeper than it may seem, it's still a grim good time, with no redeeming qualities, Generation-X-ploitation. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quintessential Film of the 1990s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jordan White (James Duval) and Amy Blue (Rose McGowan), two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos and quickiemarts. While this is probably not a good movie, it holds a certain nostalgia value for me. Gregg Araki really struck a nerve with those coming of age in the 1990s who had an interest in the Gothic an industrial music scene. With the inclusion of references to Nine Inch Nails, Ministry and Skinny Puppy, it was perfect for that demographic. The 1990s had a nihilistic undertone that was not seen in the 1980s or 2000s, leading to such films as "Seven", "Dark City", and the popularity of Tim Burton and David Fincher. This fit in that trend easily and possibly propelled it. The follow-up, "Nowhere", similarly fit in, catching the tail end. (The trend essentially died with "The Matrix".)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cool movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Iris Hall
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -You could find a minimal spoiler- It is a cool movie full of memorable quotes and phrases. It has a strange topic and it makes no sense, but it also has that special ingredient to make it interesting. The three main characters are very special and they make connections through the lighter which is a curious detail. It is a teenage movie, a cult of messed up teens and dark comedy with edgy hotel rooms and rude language. It is the kind of movie that makes you wish you meet people like that and have almost the same adventures Another thing that makes it special is the details, it is full of them! We can call it a 'cult' movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaceheater2187-120-985197
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No mature person could call this film a beautiful, artful, deep movie without bursting into laughter. I'm not even sure where to start. The writing is excessively puerile. Insults such as "anus face" and "get your head out of your rectum" are among a plethora of childlike comebacks thrown around in this film. In what universe does this qualify as "clever, witty writing"? This thing claims to be a comedy. Comedy?! The only time I laughed was at the acting. James Duval delivered his lines in a manner that makes Keanu Reeves look like a ten-time Oscar winner. The plot is virtually nonexistent. They drive, they stop somewhere for greasy food (and the total price of everything they buy totals to $6.66), they accidentally kill someone, they check in at a sleazy motel, have erotic sex, and wake up the next morning and do it all over again. It gets old very quickly. The only reason I kept watching was to see if the plot eventually went anywhere. But no, the film continues in its circular manner until the totally out-of-place climax, and it just ends. I'm sure that's frustrated more people besides just me. Even the technical aspects are sub-standard. The lighting is so horrible at times that I had to turn the brightness to its max on my screen and still couldn't quite tell what was going on. I really would like to keep going, but I'm afraid this diatribe would never end. I'm giving this movie a 2/10. I can think of only two positives about this film, which is why I'm giving it a 2: the first is the soundtrack. Several 90s songs are played in the background during the pointless dialogue. Thank God those songs were there because they were the only things making those scenes tolerable. I also heard some late 80s tunes from time to time. However, if you're not a fan of this type of music, then this positive aspect won't appeal to you. The second positive I can think of was when there was about ten seconds of meaningful dialogue near the end of the film. James Duval's character asks Xavier what the meaning of existence is. Although the answer is rather banal and empty, at least there was an attempt to broach a deeper, more philosophical topic. That one line isn't probably worth a whole star, but I'm feeling particularly magnanimous today. But in no way do these two positives make up for the other 83 minutes of dreck. Avoid this film. The only people drawn to this movie have to be confused teenage emo goths who hate their parents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it. Totally deserves cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebitterend1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those great, special movies that came from the 90's wasteland. The script is insane, the cast are sexy, and it just feels like the perfect slice of late 90's desolation. If you're not into edgy, confronting subject matter, It's definitely not for you, but i like my films a little bit dangerous and out of control, and that's exactly what The Doom Generation is; out of control. Sure, there are plot points that don't quite fit, but they don't have to. The movie perfectly complements the emotional landscape of the characters. It's crazy, over sexed self absorbed angst with a side serving of nihilism. Accept it for what it is and enjoy it. Not enough films take the risks they used to, and i applaud The Doom Generation for being what it needs to be, the same way Natural Born Killers did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gregkae
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stunning piece elicits emotions that in my case were so intense that I submitted myself to the harrowing experience of the registration process just to be able to share with the world that I throw up more colourful ideas after a bad paella and a bottle of cheap lambrusco. I white-knuckled it on fast forward and it still dragged like a 45 minute tooth extraction; waxing your armpits hurts less. Whoever participated in churning out this steaming pile of manure should be sent to a pig farm for a lifetime of unpaid work. Pointless, clueless, plot less. No script, no dialogue, no direction. It makes you think though - who stole the money to finance it, who blackmailed the actors to take part in it, who browbeat a family member to shoot it, so yeah, it is thought provoking. My neighbour's cat suffering from chronic diarrhoea excretes stuff that has more substance to it. To top it off this drivel looks like it has been recorded on a point-and-shoot pocket camera bought at a country fair in eastern Europe. IMDb really has to introduce new ratings system, maybe minus points, so that pieces like the doom generation can get its undeniable praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phallic joy and the failure of heterosexuality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film in Araki's Teenage Apocalypse Trilogy builds upon the premises laid out in "Nowhere" and "Totally F***ed Up". And what better way to end a trilogy than with a threesome in the making? The three protagonists of this production are Jordan White, interpreted by James Duval who once again conveys all the confusion and insecurities of adolescence, Amy Blue, his sexy girlfriend and Xavier Red, a wild, aggressive and assertive guy they meet on the road. Together they will embark upon a journey that, without a clear destination, will bring forth certain aspects of their real 'selves'. At the beginning of the film, Jordan attempts to penetrate his girlfriend to no avail. But this is not a reference to impotence. It is rather a reaffirmation of what Lacan would denominate the nonexistence of sexual rapport. Amy tries to give directions to her insecure boyfriend about what to do with his penis. Obviously, sexual joy here is phallocentric. But let's not forget that the phallus is a signifier, and even the model of jouissance is bound to be seized in the idiocy of the practice that attests to it. A phallocentric perspective exemplifies the non-rapport in the Other. To declare that the jouissance is phallic is fundamentally to state it is solitary. That clearly explains why is it that Jordan and Amy are unable to consummate their passion, remaining as virgins. According to Lacan, the axiom "There is no such thing as sexual rapport" obeys to a basically solitary jouissance. When Jordan asks Amy "Don't you think sex is totally strange? Just the whole idea of it" he is essentially explaining how difficult it is to decode sex in the symbolic order, because sex can neither be translated into words nor discarded as simulacra (which happens very often in postmodern society). Amy then responds "I think maybe it's more powerful than we'd like it to be". And she is absolutely right about it. As soon as Xavier enters into scene, sexual dynamics are fiercely disrupted. Xavier is sexually overwhelming, he invades the personal space of the boy and the girl, disregarding gender divisions. When Jordan and Amy are taking a shower together, Xavier looks at them and masturbates. Masturbation is very relevant in "The Doom Generation", after all, what could best exemplify the solitary jouissance? Amy describes Xavier as a living support for the sexual organ, and Xavier has no problems in acting as a "walking penis", so to speak. He is rendered as the phallus, and because he is the phallus he becomes desirable for Amy and Jordan. According to Freud, the man possesses the phallus, for Lacan, however, the woman can also have it (let's remember that phallus is not a synonym for penis). In both cases, as embarrassment, as lack, a substitute to be looked for, yet essentially, sexuality will be there conditioned, determined. To have the phallus is to be afraid of losing it; to not have it is to seek for it. All this is demonstrated when Amy engages in sexual intercourse with Xavier, thus creating a specular moment, an instance which reflects a previous one, in which Jordan masturbates while he sees his girlfriend and his new friend copulating (dynamics that bear some similitude to Cristopher Munch's Harry + Max, so it's not surprising to see this filmmaker credited at the end). Nonetheless, one of the most fascinating aspects of the film is the feeling of impending doom that permeates reality over and over again. Amy will summarize it in one phrase: "there is no place for us in this world"; whereas Jordan will only inquire "ever felt like reality is more twisted than dreams?". "The Doom Generation" is as surreal as other Araki's films, and it picks up on a certain leit motif present in his cinematographic work: religious zealousness and all it entangles. From Amy's mother (a fervent scientologist) to billboards with messages such as The Rapture is Coming (a "doomsday" of sorts according to certain religious sects as explained in "Nowhere") or Prepare for the Apocalypse. Of course, there is also the constant emphasis on 666, the number of the beast; every time the characters buy food or have to pay for something, the price is exactly the same 6 dollars with 66 cents. 6.66. The film is thoroughly filled with what Genet would call paratextual references, here the "writing on the wall" is very visible, in every wall, in every store and gas station they visit. Reality seems to be seeping down under their very noses, although as Xavier reminds them: "I saw it on TV so it's gotta be true, right?". But there is little or nothing they can grab a hold on. And this capricious dynamic is reinforced by the fact that Amy is an interchangeable object a (object of desire), as a fast food employee confuses her with an old flame and chases her down, something that also happens with an enraged lesbian, and a gay man. All forms of sexuality (heterosexuality, male and female homosexuality) enable the completion of yet another trio. When Jordan, Amy and Xavier are finally ready for a threesome, something of the order of the real irrupts and dramatically changes everything. A violent group of men captures the protagonists, and threaten Jordan very seriously with removing his genitals. But what could castration mean? A rapport should be posited and established, from a subject of one sex to the phallus, and would not get inscribed by a rapport to the partner sexed differently. This is the value Lacan bestows on the universal allotted to the castration complex. Thus the Old Testament conjectures that Sodom will suit the man and Gomorrah the woman. If castration was metaphorical at the beginning (Jordan's inability to maintain an erection) here it takes a more literal approach, which is only fitting if we consider that sexual rapport for the protagonists will forever be impossible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant by Araki again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Totally brilliant psychedelic film by the director of Mysterious skin and Nowhere, Gregg Araki(one of my favourite directors). He managed to create another brilliant sexual film with that bit of weirdness that I love in films, with brilliant acting by the cast (especially James Duval), with brilliant shots that could only come from a brilliant director like himself. I don't understand why the overall rating is so low, maybe this film is just too far for most peoples stretch, a bit to arty and deranged, a bit to creative. To be seen to be believed A clear 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artsy and inept.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reaper
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worth a look if you absolutely positively must see Rose McGowan naked in various degrading situations, but not worth watching otherwise. This movie is not merely bad, but bad AND pretentious. The kind of movie that would have gotten the Mystery Science Theater 3000 treatment, if they could have cleaned the profanity from the soundtrack. The symbolism is laid on with a trowel; Araki must have learned that directors sometimes use color as a motif, so he saturates every frame with reds and blues and yellows. The number 666 appears numerous times - whoa! Symbol! Various sets have pithy signs on the wall - whoa! Symbol! The movie has its fans, but I simply cannot see why. Maybe Araki isn't the Ed Wood of our time, but then again, maybe he is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed to be a B movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mj_heiser-832-695491
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is more depth and thought to this movie than first meets the eye but the Doom Generation unfortunately falls to the ills of poor acting, poor screen writing, and major gaps and holes in the storyline. The first half of the movie, aside from setting up the storyline, is almost a waste of time. Still, the movie is an interesting study in the dark thought and actions of 3 teens on a road trip to hell finding elicit drugs, sex, and violence just at about every stop over. Amy and Jordan are two X Generation punk rockers best described as Stoned most of the time and looking for excitement. They picked up an older but even more-so on the edge low life named X or Xavier who was running from the 'Skin-heads'. As the movie goes along, the depth of depravity increases until Jordan who I find is the most redeemable character being the most harmless starts asking the question 'Is there any meaning in life'. Still I enjoyed some of the thought especially towards the end of the movie. There are some themes around redemption and salvation that I find interesting. There is a lot of sex in this movie of which while I found provocative in the beginning, a major turn off towards the end of the movie where especially for Amy and X, there was nothing sacred in sex. At the conclusion of the movie, Jordan it seemed was the redeemable character as he confesses his love for Amy. And, for those who are squeamish, avoid the ending at all costs. I found it a bit unnecessary and the ending scene in the car almost pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Soon: The History of The Doom Generation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, here's a fine example of hard-hitting, 90's Exploitation. Brought to you by Gregg Araki. The Doom Generation is a gritty, super-dismal, often hilarious tale of murder, betrayal, and sleaziness. We begin with a young couple, hanging out at a club, Amy Blue (meth-head), and Jordan White (pot-head). Amy is a vindictive little nightmare, who's just looking for an argument. And Jordan, well, Jordan doesn't do a whole lot of thinking, but is a good guy, who loves Amy, despite her personality issues. Amy and Jordan take it to the car, so they can lose their virginity, but are soon interrupted... Meet Xavier Red (killer), X for short. Xavier rudely enters Amy's car, rudely demanding she start driving so that he may live, rudely insulting her, subtly insulting Jordan, but he doesn't mind. Amy on the other hand, is about to blow her top, but at least she has someone to argue with now... no wait, he just went too far. Alright guy!! Out of the car. Later in the evening, the teenage, odd couple are rescued by their new pal, X from a trigger-happy, convenience store clerk. after X literally blows the mans head off. They all 3, right then and there, decide to take a road trip together, leaving behind everything. The night sure is going to hell, but at least Amy has someone to argue with again, that's what's important. It doesn't take Xavier long to make his intentions clear, with Amy, and despite the fact that she despises him, she's all for it. They don't try all that hard to hide this from Jordan, but it's cool, Jordan doesn't mind, "X seems like a nice guy". Amy doesn't mind Xavier's insults, Jordan doesn't mind that the man is sleeping with his girlfriend, and no one seems to be all that bothered by the fact that X kills someone every time they stop somewhere. The Doom Generation is harsh, and mean-spirited, and can be ugly, at times, just a swell movie, probably Araki's best. The religious, and apocalyptic metaphors won't go unnoticed, and neither will Rose McGowan, as a foul-mouthed teenager, with a chip on her shoulder, with James Duval's performance making her seem even worse. Some things occur, seemingly with the intention of confusing us, but that's OK, confusion only makes this seem more like exploitation from decades past. For something slightly similar, check out Nowhere... which reminds me, if you ever see both these movies, you might notice that it would be a much better fit if they switched the titles, just a thought. Although, The Doom Generation is deeper than it may seem, it's still a grim good time, with no redeeming qualities, Generation-X-ploitation. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quintessential Film of the 1990s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jordan White (James Duval) and Amy Blue (Rose McGowan), two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos and quickiemarts. While this is probably not a good movie, it holds a certain nostalgia value for me. Gregg Araki really struck a nerve with those coming of age in the 1990s who had an interest in the Gothic an industrial music scene. With the inclusion of references to Nine Inch Nails, Ministry and Skinny Puppy, it was perfect for that demographic. The 1990s had a nihilistic undertone that was not seen in the 1980s or 2000s, leading to such films as "Seven", "Dark City", and the popularity of Tim Burton and David Fincher. This fit in that trend easily and possibly propelled it. The follow-up, "Nowhere", similarly fit in, catching the tail end. (The trend essentially died with "The Matrix".)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cool movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Iris Hall
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -You could find a minimal spoiler- It is a cool movie full of memorable quotes and phrases. It has a strange topic and it makes no sense, but it also has that special ingredient to make it interesting. The three main characters are very special and they make connections through the lighter which is a curious detail. It is a teenage movie, a cult of messed up teens and dark comedy with edgy hotel rooms and rude language. It is the kind of movie that makes you wish you meet people like that and have almost the same adventures Another thing that makes it special is the details, it is full of them! We can call it a 'cult' movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaceheater2187-120-985197
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No mature person could call this film a beautiful, artful, deep movie without bursting into laughter. I'm not even sure where to start. The writing is excessively puerile. Insults such as "anus face" and "get your head out of your rectum" are among a plethora of childlike comebacks thrown around in this film. In what universe does this qualify as "clever, witty writing"? This thing claims to be a comedy. Comedy?! The only time I laughed was at the acting. James Duval delivered his lines in a manner that makes Keanu Reeves look like a ten-time Oscar winner. The plot is virtually nonexistent. They drive, they stop somewhere for greasy food (and the total price of everything they buy totals to $6.66), they accidentally kill someone, they check in at a sleazy motel, have erotic sex, and wake up the next morning and do it all over again. It gets old very quickly. The only reason I kept watching was to see if the plot eventually went anywhere. But no, the film continues in its circular manner until the totally out-of-place climax, and it just ends. I'm sure that's frustrated more people besides just me. Even the technical aspects are sub-standard. The lighting is so horrible at times that I had to turn the brightness to its max on my screen and still couldn't quite tell what was going on. I really would like to keep going, but I'm afraid this diatribe would never end. I'm giving this movie a 2/10. I can think of only two positives about this film, which is why I'm giving it a 2: the first is the soundtrack. Several 90s songs are played in the background during the pointless dialogue. Thank God those songs were there because they were the only things making those scenes tolerable. I also heard some late 80s tunes from time to time. However, if you're not a fan of this type of music, then this positive aspect won't appeal to you. The second positive I can think of was when there was about ten seconds of meaningful dialogue near the end of the film. James Duval's character asks Xavier what the meaning of existence is. Although the answer is rather banal and empty, at least there was an attempt to broach a deeper, more philosophical topic. That one line isn't probably worth a whole star, but I'm feeling particularly magnanimous today. But in no way do these two positives make up for the other 83 minutes of dreck. Avoid this film. The only people drawn to this movie have to be confused teenage emo goths who hate their parents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it. Totally deserves cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebitterend1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those great, special movies that came from the 90's wasteland. The script is insane, the cast are sexy, and it just feels like the perfect slice of late 90's desolation. If you're not into edgy, confronting subject matter, It's definitely not for you, but i like my films a little bit dangerous and out of control, and that's exactly what The Doom Generation is; out of control. Sure, there are plot points that don't quite fit, but they don't have to. The movie perfectly complements the emotional landscape of the characters. It's crazy, over sexed self absorbed angst with a side serving of nihilism. Accept it for what it is and enjoy it. Not enough films take the risks they used to, and i applaud The Doom Generation for being what it needs to be, the same way Natural Born Killers did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gregkae
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stunning piece elicits emotions that in my case were so intense that I submitted myself to the harrowing experience of the registration process just to be able to share with the world that I throw up more colourful ideas after a bad paella and a bottle of cheap lambrusco. I white-knuckled it on fast forward and it still dragged like a 45 minute tooth extraction; waxing your armpits hurts less. Whoever participated in churning out this steaming pile of manure should be sent to a pig farm for a lifetime of unpaid work. Pointless, clueless, plot less. No script, no dialogue, no direction. It makes you think though - who stole the money to finance it, who blackmailed the actors to take part in it, who browbeat a family member to shoot it, so yeah, it is thought provoking. My neighbour's cat suffering from chronic diarrhoea excretes stuff that has more substance to it. To top it off this drivel looks like it has been recorded on a point-and-shoot pocket camera bought at a country fair in eastern Europe. IMDb really has to introduce new ratings system, maybe minus points, so that pieces like the doom generation can get its undeniable praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phallic joy and the failure of heterosexuality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film in Araki's Teenage Apocalypse Trilogy builds upon the premises laid out in "Nowhere" and "Totally F***ed Up". And what better way to end a trilogy than with a threesome in the making? The three protagonists of this production are Jordan White, interpreted by James Duval who once again conveys all the confusion and insecurities of adolescence, Amy Blue, his sexy girlfriend and Xavier Red, a wild, aggressive and assertive guy they meet on the road. Together they will embark upon a journey that, without a clear destination, will bring forth certain aspects of their real 'selves'. At the beginning of the film, Jordan attempts to penetrate his girlfriend to no avail. But this is not a reference to impotence. It is rather a reaffirmation of what Lacan would denominate the nonexistence of sexual rapport. Amy tries to give directions to her insecure boyfriend about what to do with his penis. Obviously, sexual joy here is phallocentric. But let's not forget that the phallus is a signifier, and even the model of jouissance is bound to be seized in the idiocy of the practice that attests to it. A phallocentric perspective exemplifies the non-rapport in the Other. To declare that the jouissance is phallic is fundamentally to state it is solitary. That clearly explains why is it that Jordan and Amy are unable to consummate their passion, remaining as virgins. According to Lacan, the axiom "There is no such thing as sexual rapport" obeys to a basically solitary jouissance. When Jordan asks Amy "Don't you think sex is totally strange? Just the whole idea of it" he is essentially explaining how difficult it is to decode sex in the symbolic order, because sex can neither be translated into words nor discarded as simulacra (which happens very often in postmodern society). Amy then responds "I think maybe it's more powerful than we'd like it to be". And she is absolutely right about it. As soon as Xavier enters into scene, sexual dynamics are fiercely disrupted. Xavier is sexually overwhelming, he invades the personal space of the boy and the girl, disregarding gender divisions. When Jordan and Amy are taking a shower together, Xavier looks at them and masturbates. Masturbation is very relevant in "The Doom Generation", after all, what could best exemplify the solitary jouissance? Amy describes Xavier as a living support for the sexual organ, and Xavier has no problems in acting as a "walking penis", so to speak. He is rendered as the phallus, and because he is the phallus he becomes desirable for Amy and Jordan. According to Freud, the man possesses the phallus, for Lacan, however, the woman can also have it (let's remember that phallus is not a synonym for penis). In both cases, as embarrassment, as lack, a substitute to be looked for, yet essentially, sexuality will be there conditioned, determined. To have the phallus is to be afraid of losing it; to not have it is to seek for it. All this is demonstrated when Amy engages in sexual intercourse with Xavier, thus creating a specular moment, an instance which reflects a previous one, in which Jordan masturbates while he sees his girlfriend and his new friend copulating (dynamics that bear some similitude to Cristopher Munch's Harry + Max, so it's not surprising to see this filmmaker credited at the end). Nonetheless, one of the most fascinating aspects of the film is the feeling of impending doom that permeates reality over and over again. Amy will summarize it in one phrase: "there is no place for us in this world"; whereas Jordan will only inquire "ever felt like reality is more twisted than dreams?". "The Doom Generation" is as surreal as other Araki's films, and it picks up on a certain leit motif present in his cinematographic work: religious zealousness and all it entangles. From Amy's mother (a fervent scientologist) to billboards with messages such as The Rapture is Coming (a "doomsday" of sorts according to certain religious sects as explained in "Nowhere") or Prepare for the Apocalypse. Of course, there is also the constant emphasis on 666, the number of the beast; every time the characters buy food or have to pay for something, the price is exactly the same 6 dollars with 66 cents. 6.66. The film is thoroughly filled with what Genet would call paratextual references, here the "writing on the wall" is very visible, in every wall, in every store and gas station they visit. Reality seems to be seeping down under their very noses, although as Xavier reminds them: "I saw it on TV so it's gotta be true, right?". But there is little or nothing they can grab a hold on. And this capricious dynamic is reinforced by the fact that Amy is an interchangeable object a (object of desire), as a fast food employee confuses her with an old flame and chases her down, something that also happens with an enraged lesbian, and a gay man. All forms of sexuality (heterosexuality, male and female homosexuality) enable the completion of yet another trio. When Jordan, Amy and Xavier are finally ready for a threesome, something of the order of the real irrupts and dramatically changes everything. A violent group of men captures the protagonists, and threaten Jordan very seriously with removing his genitals. But what could castration mean? A rapport should be posited and established, from a subject of one sex to the phallus, and would not get inscribed by a rapport to the partner sexed differently. This is the value Lacan bestows on the universal allotted to the castration complex. Thus the Old Testament conjectures that Sodom will suit the man and Gomorrah the woman. If castration was metaphorical at the beginning (Jordan's inability to maintain an erection) here it takes a more literal approach, which is only fitting if we consider that sexual rapport for the protagonists will forever be impossible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant by Araki again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Totally brilliant psychedelic film by the director of Mysterious skin and Nowhere, Gregg Araki(one of my favourite directors). He managed to create another brilliant sexual film with that bit of weirdness that I love in films, with brilliant acting by the cast (especially James Duval), with brilliant shots that could only come from a brilliant director like himself. I don't understand why the overall rating is so low, maybe this film is just too far for most peoples stretch, a bit to arty and deranged, a bit to creative. To be seen to be believed A clear 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artsy and inept.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reaper
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worth a look if you absolutely positively must see Rose McGowan naked in various degrading situations, but not worth watching otherwise. This movie is not merely bad, but bad AND pretentious. The kind of movie that would have gotten the Mystery Science Theater 3000 treatment, if they could have cleaned the profanity from the soundtrack. The symbolism is laid on with a trowel; Araki must have learned that directors sometimes use color as a motif, so he saturates every frame with reds and blues and yellows. The number 666 appears numerous times - whoa! Symbol! Various sets have pithy signs on the wall - whoa! Symbol! The movie has its fans, but I simply cannot see why. Maybe Araki isn't the Ed Wood of our time, but then again, maybe he is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed to be a B movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mj_heiser-832-695491
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is more depth and thought to this movie than first meets the eye but the Doom Generation unfortunately falls to the ills of poor acting, poor screen writing, and major gaps and holes in the storyline. The first half of the movie, aside from setting up the storyline, is almost a waste of time. Still, the movie is an interesting study in the dark thought and actions of 3 teens on a road trip to hell finding elicit drugs, sex, and violence just at about every stop over. Amy and Jordan are two X Generation punk rockers best described as Stoned most of the time and looking for excitement. They picked up an older but even more-so on the edge low life named X or Xavier who was running from the 'Skin-heads'. As the movie goes along, the depth of depravity increases until Jordan who I find is the most redeemable character being the most harmless starts asking the question 'Is there any meaning in life'. Still I enjoyed some of the thought especially towards the end of the movie. There are some themes around redemption and salvation that I find interesting. There is a lot of sex in this movie of which while I found provocative in the beginning, a major turn off towards the end of the movie where especially for Amy and X, there was nothing sacred in sex. At the conclusion of the movie, Jordan it seemed was the redeemable character as he confesses his love for Amy. And, for those who are squeamish, avoid the ending at all costs. I found it a bit unnecessary and the ending scene in the car almost pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Soon: The History of The Doom Generation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, here's a fine example of hard-hitting, 90's Exploitation. Brought to you by Gregg Araki. The Doom Generation is a gritty, super-dismal, often hilarious tale of murder, betrayal, and sleaziness. We begin with a young couple, hanging out at a club, Amy Blue (meth-head), and Jordan White (pot-head). Amy is a vindictive little nightmare, who's just looking for an argument. And Jordan, well, Jordan doesn't do a whole lot of thinking, but is a good guy, who loves Amy, despite her personality issues. Amy and Jordan take it to the car, so they can lose their virginity, but are soon interrupted... Meet Xavier Red (killer), X for short. Xavier rudely enters Amy's car, rudely demanding she start driving so that he may live, rudely insulting her, subtly insulting Jordan, but he doesn't mind. Amy on the other hand, is about to blow her top, but at least she has someone to argue with now... no wait, he just went too far. Alright guy!! Out of the car. Later in the evening, the teenage, odd couple are rescued by their new pal, X from a trigger-happy, convenience store clerk. after X literally blows the mans head off. They all 3, right then and there, decide to take a road trip together, leaving behind everything. The night sure is going to hell, but at least Amy has someone to argue with again, that's what's important. It doesn't take Xavier long to make his intentions clear, with Amy, and despite the fact that she despises him, she's all for it. They don't try all that hard to hide this from Jordan, but it's cool, Jordan doesn't mind, "X seems like a nice guy". Amy doesn't mind Xavier's insults, Jordan doesn't mind that the man is sleeping with his girlfriend, and no one seems to be all that bothered by the fact that X kills someone every time they stop somewhere. The Doom Generation is harsh, and mean-spirited, and can be ugly, at times, just a swell movie, probably Araki's best. The religious, and apocalyptic metaphors won't go unnoticed, and neither will Rose McGowan, as a foul-mouthed teenager, with a chip on her shoulder, with James Duval's performance making her seem even worse. Some things occur, seemingly with the intention of confusing us, but that's OK, confusion only makes this seem more like exploitation from decades past. For something slightly similar, check out Nowhere... which reminds me, if you ever see both these movies, you might notice that it would be a much better fit if they switched the titles, just a thought. Although, The Doom Generation is deeper than it may seem, it's still a grim good time, with no redeeming qualities, Generation-X-ploitation. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quintessential Film of the 1990s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jordan White (James Duval) and Amy Blue (Rose McGowan), two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos and quickiemarts. While this is probably not a good movie, it holds a certain nostalgia value for me. Gregg Araki really struck a nerve with those coming of age in the 1990s who had an interest in the Gothic an industrial music scene. With the inclusion of references to Nine Inch Nails, Ministry and Skinny Puppy, it was perfect for that demographic. The 1990s had a nihilistic undertone that was not seen in the 1980s or 2000s, leading to such films as "Seven", "Dark City", and the popularity of Tim Burton and David Fincher. This fit in that trend easily and possibly propelled it. The follow-up, "Nowhere", similarly fit in, catching the tail end. (The trend essentially died with "The Matrix".)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cool movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Iris Hall
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -You could find a minimal spoiler- It is a cool movie full of memorable quotes and phrases. It has a strange topic and it makes no sense, but it also has that special ingredient to make it interesting. The three main characters are very special and they make connections through the lighter which is a curious detail. It is a teenage movie, a cult of messed up teens and dark comedy with edgy hotel rooms and rude language. It is the kind of movie that makes you wish you meet people like that and have almost the same adventures Another thing that makes it special is the details, it is full of them! We can call it a 'cult' movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaceheater2187-120-985197
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No mature person could call this film a beautiful, artful, deep movie without bursting into laughter. I'm not even sure where to start. The writing is excessively puerile. Insults such as "anus face" and "get your head out of your rectum" are among a plethora of childlike comebacks thrown around in this film. In what universe does this qualify as "clever, witty writing"? This thing claims to be a comedy. Comedy?! The only time I laughed was at the acting. James Duval delivered his lines in a manner that makes Keanu Reeves look like a ten-time Oscar winner. The plot is virtually nonexistent. They drive, they stop somewhere for greasy food (and the total price of everything they buy totals to $6.66), they accidentally kill someone, they check in at a sleazy motel, have erotic sex, and wake up the next morning and do it all over again. It gets old very quickly. The only reason I kept watching was to see if the plot eventually went anywhere. But no, the film continues in its circular manner until the totally out-of-place climax, and it just ends. I'm sure that's frustrated more people besides just me. Even the technical aspects are sub-standard. The lighting is so horrible at times that I had to turn the brightness to its max on my screen and still couldn't quite tell what was going on. I really would like to keep going, but I'm afraid this diatribe would never end. I'm giving this movie a 2/10. I can think of only two positives about this film, which is why I'm giving it a 2: the first is the soundtrack. Several 90s songs are played in the background during the pointless dialogue. Thank God those songs were there because they were the only things making those scenes tolerable. I also heard some late 80s tunes from time to time. However, if you're not a fan of this type of music, then this positive aspect won't appeal to you. The second positive I can think of was when there was about ten seconds of meaningful dialogue near the end of the film. James Duval's character asks Xavier what the meaning of existence is. Although the answer is rather banal and empty, at least there was an attempt to broach a deeper, more philosophical topic. That one line isn't probably worth a whole star, but I'm feeling particularly magnanimous today. But in no way do these two positives make up for the other 83 minutes of dreck. Avoid this film. The only people drawn to this movie have to be confused teenage emo goths who hate their parents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it. Totally deserves cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebitterend1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those great, special movies that came from the 90's wasteland. The script is insane, the cast are sexy, and it just feels like the perfect slice of late 90's desolation. If you're not into edgy, confronting subject matter, It's definitely not for you, but i like my films a little bit dangerous and out of control, and that's exactly what The Doom Generation is; out of control. Sure, there are plot points that don't quite fit, but they don't have to. The movie perfectly complements the emotional landscape of the characters. It's crazy, over sexed self absorbed angst with a side serving of nihilism. Accept it for what it is and enjoy it. Not enough films take the risks they used to, and i applaud The Doom Generation for being what it needs to be, the same way Natural Born Killers did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gregkae
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stunning piece elicits emotions that in my case were so intense that I submitted myself to the harrowing experience of the registration process just to be able to share with the world that I throw up more colourful ideas after a bad paella and a bottle of cheap lambrusco. I white-knuckled it on fast forward and it still dragged like a 45 minute tooth extraction; waxing your armpits hurts less. Whoever participated in churning out this steaming pile of manure should be sent to a pig farm for a lifetime of unpaid work. Pointless, clueless, plot less. No script, no dialogue, no direction. It makes you think though - who stole the money to finance it, who blackmailed the actors to take part in it, who browbeat a family member to shoot it, so yeah, it is thought provoking. My neighbour's cat suffering from chronic diarrhoea excretes stuff that has more substance to it. To top it off this drivel looks like it has been recorded on a point-and-shoot pocket camera bought at a country fair in eastern Europe. IMDb really has to introduce new ratings system, maybe minus points, so that pieces like the doom generation can get its undeniable praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phallic joy and the failure of heterosexuality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film in Araki's Teenage Apocalypse Trilogy builds upon the premises laid out in "Nowhere" and "Totally F***ed Up". And what better way to end a trilogy than with a threesome in the making? The three protagonists of this production are Jordan White, interpreted by James Duval who once again conveys all the confusion and insecurities of adolescence, Amy Blue, his sexy girlfriend and Xavier Red, a wild, aggressive and assertive guy they meet on the road. Together they will embark upon a journey that, without a clear destination, will bring forth certain aspects of their real 'selves'. At the beginning of the film, Jordan attempts to penetrate his girlfriend to no avail. But this is not a reference to impotence. It is rather a reaffirmation of what Lacan would denominate the nonexistence of sexual rapport. Amy tries to give directions to her insecure boyfriend about what to do with his penis. Obviously, sexual joy here is phallocentric. But let's not forget that the phallus is a signifier, and even the model of jouissance is bound to be seized in the idiocy of the practice that attests to it. A phallocentric perspective exemplifies the non-rapport in the Other. To declare that the jouissance is phallic is fundamentally to state it is solitary. That clearly explains why is it that Jordan and Amy are unable to consummate their passion, remaining as virgins. According to Lacan, the axiom "There is no such thing as sexual rapport" obeys to a basically solitary jouissance. When Jordan asks Amy "Don't you think sex is totally strange? Just the whole idea of it" he is essentially explaining how difficult it is to decode sex in the symbolic order, because sex can neither be translated into words nor discarded as simulacra (which happens very often in postmodern society). Amy then responds "I think maybe it's more powerful than we'd like it to be". And she is absolutely right about it. As soon as Xavier enters into scene, sexual dynamics are fiercely disrupted. Xavier is sexually overwhelming, he invades the personal space of the boy and the girl, disregarding gender divisions. When Jordan and Amy are taking a shower together, Xavier looks at them and masturbates. Masturbation is very relevant in "The Doom Generation", after all, what could best exemplify the solitary jouissance? Amy describes Xavier as a living support for the sexual organ, and Xavier has no problems in acting as a "walking penis", so to speak. He is rendered as the phallus, and because he is the phallus he becomes desirable for Amy and Jordan. According to Freud, the man possesses the phallus, for Lacan, however, the woman can also have it (let's remember that phallus is not a synonym for penis). In both cases, as embarrassment, as lack, a substitute to be looked for, yet essentially, sexuality will be there conditioned, determined. To have the phallus is to be afraid of losing it; to not have it is to seek for it. All this is demonstrated when Amy engages in sexual intercourse with Xavier, thus creating a specular moment, an instance which reflects a previous one, in which Jordan masturbates while he sees his girlfriend and his new friend copulating (dynamics that bear some similitude to Cristopher Munch's Harry + Max, so it's not surprising to see this filmmaker credited at the end). Nonetheless, one of the most fascinating aspects of the film is the feeling of impending doom that permeates reality over and over again. Amy will summarize it in one phrase: "there is no place for us in this world"; whereas Jordan will only inquire "ever felt like reality is more twisted than dreams?". "The Doom Generation" is as surreal as other Araki's films, and it picks up on a certain leit motif present in his cinematographic work: religious zealousness and all it entangles. From Amy's mother (a fervent scientologist) to billboards with messages such as The Rapture is Coming (a "doomsday" of sorts according to certain religious sects as explained in "Nowhere") or Prepare for the Apocalypse. Of course, there is also the constant emphasis on 666, the number of the beast; every time the characters buy food or have to pay for something, the price is exactly the same 6 dollars with 66 cents. 6.66. The film is thoroughly filled with what Genet would call paratextual references, here the "writing on the wall" is very visible, in every wall, in every store and gas station they visit. Reality seems to be seeping down under their very noses, although as Xavier reminds them: "I saw it on TV so it's gotta be true, right?". But there is little or nothing they can grab a hold on. And this capricious dynamic is reinforced by the fact that Amy is an interchangeable object a (object of desire), as a fast food employee confuses her with an old flame and chases her down, something that also happens with an enraged lesbian, and a gay man. All forms of sexuality (heterosexuality, male and female homosexuality) enable the completion of yet another trio. When Jordan, Amy and Xavier are finally ready for a threesome, something of the order of the real irrupts and dramatically changes everything. A violent group of men captures the protagonists, and threaten Jordan very seriously with removing his genitals. But what could castration mean? A rapport should be posited and established, from a subject of one sex to the phallus, and would not get inscribed by a rapport to the partner sexed differently. This is the value Lacan bestows on the universal allotted to the castration complex. Thus the Old Testament conjectures that Sodom will suit the man and Gomorrah the woman. If castration was metaphorical at the beginning (Jordan's inability to maintain an erection) here it takes a more literal approach, which is only fitting if we consider that sexual rapport for the protagonists will forever be impossible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant by Araki again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Totally brilliant psychedelic film by the director of Mysterious skin and Nowhere, Gregg Araki(one of my favourite directors). He managed to create another brilliant sexual film with that bit of weirdness that I love in films, with brilliant acting by the cast (especially James Duval), with brilliant shots that could only come from a brilliant director like himself. I don't understand why the overall rating is so low, maybe this film is just too far for most peoples stretch, a bit to arty and deranged, a bit to creative. To be seen to be believed A clear 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artsy and inept.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reaper
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worth a look if you absolutely positively must see Rose McGowan naked in various degrading situations, but not worth watching otherwise. This movie is not merely bad, but bad AND pretentious. The kind of movie that would have gotten the Mystery Science Theater 3000 treatment, if they could have cleaned the profanity from the soundtrack. The symbolism is laid on with a trowel; Araki must have learned that directors sometimes use color as a motif, so he saturates every frame with reds and blues and yellows. The number 666 appears numerous times - whoa! Symbol! Various sets have pithy signs on the wall - whoa! Symbol! The movie has its fans, but I simply cannot see why. Maybe Araki isn't the Ed Wood of our time, but then again, maybe he is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed to be a B movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mj_heiser-832-695491
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is more depth and thought to this movie than first meets the eye but the Doom Generation unfortunately falls to the ills of poor acting, poor screen writing, and major gaps and holes in the storyline. The first half of the movie, aside from setting up the storyline, is almost a waste of time. Still, the movie is an interesting study in the dark thought and actions of 3 teens on a road trip to hell finding elicit drugs, sex, and violence just at about every stop over. Amy and Jordan are two X Generation punk rockers best described as Stoned most of the time and looking for excitement. They picked up an older but even more-so on the edge low life named X or Xavier who was running from the 'Skin-heads'. As the movie goes along, the depth of depravity increases until Jordan who I find is the most redeemable character being the most harmless starts asking the question 'Is there any meaning in life'. Still I enjoyed some of the thought especially towards the end of the movie. There are some themes around redemption and salvation that I find interesting. There is a lot of sex in this movie of which while I found provocative in the beginning, a major turn off towards the end of the movie where especially for Amy and X, there was nothing sacred in sex. At the conclusion of the movie, Jordan it seemed was the redeemable character as he confesses his love for Amy. And, for those who are squeamish, avoid the ending at all costs. I found it a bit unnecessary and the ending scene in the car almost pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Soon: The History of The Doom Generation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, here's a fine example of hard-hitting, 90's Exploitation. Brought to you by Gregg Araki. The Doom Generation is a gritty, super-dismal, often hilarious tale of murder, betrayal, and sleaziness. We begin with a young couple, hanging out at a club, Amy Blue (meth-head), and Jordan White (pot-head). Amy is a vindictive little nightmare, who's just looking for an argument. And Jordan, well, Jordan doesn't do a whole lot of thinking, but is a good guy, who loves Amy, despite her personality issues. Amy and Jordan take it to the car, so they can lose their virginity, but are soon interrupted... Meet Xavier Red (killer), X for short. Xavier rudely enters Amy's car, rudely demanding she start driving so that he may live, rudely insulting her, subtly insulting Jordan, but he doesn't mind. Amy on the other hand, is about to blow her top, but at least she has someone to argue with now... no wait, he just went too far. Alright guy!! Out of the car. Later in the evening, the teenage, odd couple are rescued by their new pal, X from a trigger-happy, convenience store clerk. after X literally blows the mans head off. They all 3, right then and there, decide to take a road trip together, leaving behind everything. The night sure is going to hell, but at least Amy has someone to argue with again, that's what's important. It doesn't take Xavier long to make his intentions clear, with Amy, and despite the fact that she despises him, she's all for it. They don't try all that hard to hide this from Jordan, but it's cool, Jordan doesn't mind, "X seems like a nice guy". Amy doesn't mind Xavier's insults, Jordan doesn't mind that the man is sleeping with his girlfriend, and no one seems to be all that bothered by the fact that X kills someone every time they stop somewhere. The Doom Generation is harsh, and mean-spirited, and can be ugly, at times, just a swell movie, probably Araki's best. The religious, and apocalyptic metaphors won't go unnoticed, and neither will Rose McGowan, as a foul-mouthed teenager, with a chip on her shoulder, with James Duval's performance making her seem even worse. Some things occur, seemingly with the intention of confusing us, but that's OK, confusion only makes this seem more like exploitation from decades past. For something slightly similar, check out Nowhere... which reminds me, if you ever see both these movies, you might notice that it would be a much better fit if they switched the titles, just a thought. Although, The Doom Generation is deeper than it may seem, it's still a grim good time, with no redeeming qualities, Generation-X-ploitation. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quintessential Film of the 1990s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jordan White (James Duval) and Amy Blue (Rose McGowan), two troubled teens, pick up an adolescent drifter, Xavier Red. Together, the threesome embark on a sex and violence-filled journey through an America of psychos and quickiemarts. While this is probably not a good movie, it holds a certain nostalgia value for me. Gregg Araki really struck a nerve with those coming of age in the 1990s who had an interest in the Gothic an industrial music scene. With the inclusion of references to Nine Inch Nails, Ministry and Skinny Puppy, it was perfect for that demographic. The 1990s had a nihilistic undertone that was not seen in the 1980s or 2000s, leading to such films as "Seven", "Dark City", and the popularity of Tim Burton and David Fincher. This fit in that trend easily and possibly propelled it. The follow-up, "Nowhere", similarly fit in, catching the tail end. (The trend essentially died with "The Matrix".)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cool movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Iris Hall
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -You could find a minimal spoiler- It is a cool movie full of memorable quotes and phrases. It has a strange topic and it makes no sense, but it also has that special ingredient to make it interesting. The three main characters are very special and they make connections through the lighter which is a curious detail. It is a teenage movie, a cult of messed up teens and dark comedy with edgy hotel rooms and rude language. It is the kind of movie that makes you wish you meet people like that and have almost the same adventures Another thing that makes it special is the details, it is full of them! We can call it a 'cult' movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Waste of Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaceheater2187-120-985197
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No mature person could call this film a beautiful, artful, deep movie without bursting into laughter. I'm not even sure where to start. The writing is excessively puerile. Insults such as "anus face" and "get your head out of your rectum" are among a plethora of childlike comebacks thrown around in this film. In what universe does this qualify as "clever, witty writing"? This thing claims to be a comedy. Comedy?! The only time I laughed was at the acting. James Duval delivered his lines in a manner that makes Keanu Reeves look like a ten-time Oscar winner. The plot is virtually nonexistent. They drive, they stop somewhere for greasy food (and the total price of everything they buy totals to $6.66), they accidentally kill someone, they check in at a sleazy motel, have erotic sex, and wake up the next morning and do it all over again. It gets old very quickly. The only reason I kept watching was to see if the plot eventually went anywhere. But no, the film continues in its circular manner until the totally out-of-place climax, and it just ends. I'm sure that's frustrated more people besides just me. Even the technical aspects are sub-standard. The lighting is so horrible at times that I had to turn the brightness to its max on my screen and still couldn't quite tell what was going on. I really would like to keep going, but I'm afraid this diatribe would never end. I'm giving this movie a 2/10. I can think of only two positives about this film, which is why I'm giving it a 2: the first is the soundtrack. Several 90s songs are played in the background during the pointless dialogue. Thank God those songs were there because they were the only things making those scenes tolerable. I also heard some late 80s tunes from time to time. However, if you're not a fan of this type of music, then this positive aspect won't appeal to you. The second positive I can think of was when there was about ten seconds of meaningful dialogue near the end of the film. James Duval's character asks Xavier what the meaning of existence is. Although the answer is rather banal and empty, at least there was an attempt to broach a deeper, more philosophical topic. That one line isn't probably worth a whole star, but I'm feeling particularly magnanimous today. But in no way do these two positives make up for the other 83 minutes of dreck. Avoid this film. The only people drawn to this movie have to be confused teenage emo goths who hate their parents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it. Totally deserves cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thebitterend1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those great, special movies that came from the 90's wasteland. The script is insane, the cast are sexy, and it just feels like the perfect slice of late 90's desolation. If you're not into edgy, confronting subject matter, It's definitely not for you, but i like my films a little bit dangerous and out of control, and that's exactly what The Doom Generation is; out of control. Sure, there are plot points that don't quite fit, but they don't have to. The movie perfectly complements the emotional landscape of the characters. It's crazy, over sexed self absorbed angst with a side serving of nihilism. Accept it for what it is and enjoy it. Not enough films take the risks they used to, and i applaud The Doom Generation for being what it needs to be, the same way Natural Born Killers did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gregkae
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stunning piece elicits emotions that in my case were so intense that I submitted myself to the harrowing experience of the registration process just to be able to share with the world that I throw up more colourful ideas after a bad paella and a bottle of cheap lambrusco. I white-knuckled it on fast forward and it still dragged like a 45 minute tooth extraction; waxing your armpits hurts less. Whoever participated in churning out this steaming pile of manure should be sent to a pig farm for a lifetime of unpaid work. Pointless, clueless, plot less. No script, no dialogue, no direction. It makes you think though - who stole the money to finance it, who blackmailed the actors to take part in it, who browbeat a family member to shoot it, so yeah, it is thought provoking. My neighbour's cat suffering from chronic diarrhoea excretes stuff that has more substance to it. To top it off this drivel looks like it has been recorded on a point-and-shoot pocket camera bought at a country fair in eastern Europe. IMDb really has to introduce new ratings system, maybe minus points, so that pieces like the doom generation can get its undeniable praise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phallic joy and the failure of heterosexuality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arcadio Bolanos
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last film in Araki's Teenage Apocalypse Trilogy builds upon the premises laid out in "Nowhere" and "Totally F***ed Up". And what better way to end a trilogy than with a threesome in the making? The three protagonists of this production are Jordan White, interpreted by James Duval who once again conveys all the confusion and insecurities of adolescence, Amy Blue, his sexy girlfriend and Xavier Red, a wild, aggressive and assertive guy they meet on the road. Together they will embark upon a journey that, without a clear destination, will bring forth certain aspects of their real 'selves'. At the beginning of the film, Jordan attempts to penetrate his girlfriend to no avail. But this is not a reference to impotence. It is rather a reaffirmation of what Lacan would denominate the nonexistence of sexual rapport. Amy tries to give directions to her insecure boyfriend about what to do with his penis. Obviously, sexual joy here is phallocentric. But let's not forget that the phallus is a signifier, and even the model of jouissance is bound to be seized in the idiocy of the practice that attests to it. A phallocentric perspective exemplifies the non-rapport in the Other. To declare that the jouissance is phallic is fundamentally to state it is solitary. That clearly explains why is it that Jordan and Amy are unable to consummate their passion, remaining as virgins. According to Lacan, the axiom "There is no such thing as sexual rapport" obeys to a basically solitary jouissance. When Jordan asks Amy "Don't you think sex is totally strange? Just the whole idea of it" he is essentially explaining how difficult it is to decode sex in the symbolic order, because sex can neither be translated into words nor discarded as simulacra (which happens very often in postmodern society). Amy then responds "I think maybe it's more powerful than we'd like it to be". And she is absolutely right about it. As soon as Xavier enters into scene, sexual dynamics are fiercely disrupted. Xavier is sexually overwhelming, he invades the personal space of the boy and the girl, disregarding gender divisions. When Jordan and Amy are taking a shower together, Xavier looks at them and masturbates. Masturbation is very relevant in "The Doom Generation", after all, what could best exemplify the solitary jouissance? Amy describes Xavier as a living support for the sexual organ, and Xavier has no problems in acting as a "walking penis", so to speak. He is rendered as the phallus, and because he is the phallus he becomes desirable for Amy and Jordan. According to Freud, the man possesses the phallus, for Lacan, however, the woman can also have it (let's remember that phallus is not a synonym for penis). In both cases, as embarrassment, as lack, a substitute to be looked for, yet essentially, sexuality will be there conditioned, determined. To have the phallus is to be afraid of losing it; to not have it is to seek for it. All this is demonstrated when Amy engages in sexual intercourse with Xavier, thus creating a specular moment, an instance which reflects a previous one, in which Jordan masturbates while he sees his girlfriend and his new friend copulating (dynamics that bear some similitude to Cristopher Munch's Harry + Max, so it's not surprising to see this filmmaker credited at the end). Nonetheless, one of the most fascinating aspects of the film is the feeling of impending doom that permeates reality over and over again. Amy will summarize it in one phrase: "there is no place for us in this world"; whereas Jordan will only inquire "ever felt like reality is more twisted than dreams?". "The Doom Generation" is as surreal as other Araki's films, and it picks up on a certain leit motif present in his cinematographic work: religious zealousness and all it entangles. From Amy's mother (a fervent scientologist) to billboards with messages such as The Rapture is Coming (a "doomsday" of sorts according to certain religious sects as explained in "Nowhere") or Prepare for the Apocalypse. Of course, there is also the constant emphasis on 666, the number of the beast; every time the characters buy food or have to pay for something, the price is exactly the same 6 dollars with 66 cents. 6.66. The film is thoroughly filled with what Genet would call paratextual references, here the "writing on the wall" is very visible, in every wall, in every store and gas station they visit. Reality seems to be seeping down under their very noses, although as Xavier reminds them: "I saw it on TV so it's gotta be true, right?". But there is little or nothing they can grab a hold on. And this capricious dynamic is reinforced by the fact that Amy is an interchangeable object a (object of desire), as a fast food employee confuses her with an old flame and chases her down, something that also happens with an enraged lesbian, and a gay man. All forms of sexuality (heterosexuality, male and female homosexuality) enable the completion of yet another trio. When Jordan, Amy and Xavier are finally ready for a threesome, something of the order of the real irrupts and dramatically changes everything. A violent group of men captures the protagonists, and threaten Jordan very seriously with removing his genitals. But what could castration mean? A rapport should be posited and established, from a subject of one sex to the phallus, and would not get inscribed by a rapport to the partner sexed differently. This is the value Lacan bestows on the universal allotted to the castration complex. Thus the Old Testament conjectures that Sodom will suit the man and Gomorrah the woman. If castration was metaphorical at the beginning (Jordan's inability to maintain an erection) here it takes a more literal approach, which is only fitting if we consider that sexual rapport for the protagonists will forever be impossible.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant by Araki again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Totally brilliant psychedelic film by the director of Mysterious skin and Nowhere, Gregg Araki(one of my favourite directors). He managed to create another brilliant sexual film with that bit of weirdness that I love in films, with brilliant acting by the cast (especially James Duval), with brilliant shots that could only come from a brilliant director like himself. I don't understand why the overall rating is so low, maybe this film is just too far for most peoples stretch, a bit to arty and deranged, a bit to creative. To be seen to be believed A clear 8 out of ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Artsy and inept.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reaper
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worth a look if you absolutely positively must see Rose McGowan naked in various degrading situations, but not worth watching otherwise. This movie is not merely bad, but bad AND pretentious. The kind of movie that would have gotten the Mystery Science Theater 3000 treatment, if they could have cleaned the profanity from the soundtrack. The symbolism is laid on with a trowel; Araki must have learned that directors sometimes use color as a motif, so he saturates every frame with reds and blues and yellows. The number 666 appears numerous times - whoa! Symbol! Various sets have pithy signs on the wall - whoa! Symbol! The movie has its fans, but I simply cannot see why. Maybe Araki isn't the Ed Wood of our time, but then again, maybe he is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doomed to be a B movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mj_heiser-832-695491
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is more depth and thought to this movie than first meets the eye but the Doom Generation unfortunately falls to the ills of poor acting, poor screen writing, and major gaps and holes in the storyline. The first half of the movie, aside from setting up the storyline, is almost a waste of time. Still, the movie is an interesting study in the dark thought and actions of 3 teens on a road trip to hell finding elicit drugs, sex, and violence just at about every stop over. Amy and Jordan are two X Generation punk rockers best described as Stoned most of the time and looking for excitement. They picked up an older but even more-so on the edge low life named X or Xavier who was running from the 'Skin-heads'. As the movie goes along, the depth of depravity increases until Jordan who I find is the most redeemable character being the most harmless starts asking the question 'Is there any meaning in life'. Still I enjoyed some of the thought especially towards the end of the movie. There are some themes around redemption and salvation that I find interesting. There is a lot of sex in this movie of which while I found provocative in the beginning, a major turn off towards the end of the movie where especially for Amy and X, there was nothing sacred in sex. At the conclusion of the movie, Jordan it seemed was the redeemable character as he confesses his love for Amy. And, for those who are squeamish, avoid the ending at all costs. I found it a bit unnecessary and the ending scene in the car almost pointless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Soon: The History of The Doom Generation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now, here's a fine example of hard-hitting, 90's Exploitation. Brought to you by Gregg Araki. The Doom Generation is a gritty, super-dismal, often hilarious tale of murder, betrayal, and sleaziness. We begin with a young couple, hanging out at a club, Amy Blue (meth-head), and Jordan White (pot-head). Amy is a vindictive little nightmare, who's just looking for an argument. And Jordan, well, Jordan doesn't do a whole lot of thinking, but is a good guy, who loves Amy, despite her personality issues. Amy and Jordan take it to the car, so they can lose their virginity, but are soon interrupted... Meet Xavier Red (killer), X for short. Xavier rudely enters Amy's car, rudely demanding she start driving so that he may live, rudely insulting her, subtly insulting Jordan, but he doesn't mind. Amy on the other hand, is about to blow her top, but at least she has someone to argue with now... no wait, he just went too far. Alright guy!! Out of the car. Later in the evening, the teenage, odd couple are rescued by their new pal, X from a trigger-happy, convenience store clerk. after X literally blows the mans head off. They all 3, right then and there, decide to take a road trip together, leaving behind everything. The night sure is going to hell, but at least Amy has someone to argue with again, that's what's important. It doesn't take Xavier long to make his intentions clear, with Amy, and despite the fact that she despises him, she's all for it. They don't try all that hard to hide this from Jordan, but it's cool, Jordan doesn't mind, "X seems like a nice guy". Amy doesn't mind Xavier's insults, Jordan doesn't mind that the man is sleeping with his girlfriend, and no one seems to be all that bothered by the fact that X kills someone every time they stop somewhere. The Doom Generation is harsh, and mean-spirited, and can be ugly, at times, just a swell movie, probably Araki's best. The religious, and apocalyptic metaphors won't go unnoticed, and neither will Rose McGowan, as a foul-mouthed teenager, with a chip on her shoulder, with James Duval's performance making her seem even worse. Some things occur, seemingly with the intention of confusing us, but that's OK, confusion only makes this seem more like exploitation from decades past. For something slightly similar, check out Nowhere... which reminds me, if you ever see both these movies, you might notice that it would be a much better fit if they switched the titles, just a thought. Although, The Doom Generation is deeper than it may seem, it's still a grim good time, with no redeeming qualities, Generation-X-ploitation. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
