<filme>
 <id>
  345
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118954
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Desconstruindo Harry
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Suffering from writer's block and eagerly awaiting his writing award, Harry Block remembers events from his past and scenes from his best-selling books as characters, real and fictional, come back to haunt him.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Harry Block is a well-regarded novelist whose tendency to thinly-veil his own experiences in his work, as well as his un-apologetic attitude and his proclivity for pills and whores, has left him with three ex-wives that hate him. As he is about to be honored for his writing by the college that expelled him, he faces writer's block and the impending marriage of his latest flame to a writer friend. As scenes from his stories and novels pass and interact with him, Harry faces the people whose lives he has affected - wives, lovers, his son, his sister.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   writer's block
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   writing
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   novelist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   marriage
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   voice over narration
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Woody Allen
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Woody Allen
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Woody Allen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Judy Davis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Julia Louis-Dreyfus
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mixed Feelings...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick Cluxton
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been looking forward to seeing this film for quite a while, and when I finally had a chance I was pretty quick to take it up. As I started it, I regretted it immediately, I was bored and annoyed. Towards the end, it began to grow on me, but a lot just didn't do it for me. What I liked: I absolutely love the concept and the story. I have not seen any like it. What I like most is that while there is an actual plot and external events, it's more of a character study. They take an unlikable character and give him plenty of depth and sympathy to make up for his brash decisions and opinions. I love Woody Allen as a writer. I also liked the short stories; how they were narrated, the actual relevance they had to Harry's problems and friends, and how they were somewhat diverse. It wasn't just about the message. I both liked and disliked the scenes where they would cut to the same shot. It is very reminiscent of Jean- Loc Goddard's Breathless, which at times gave it a very relaxed, more realistic feel, considering that you could interpret that there were probably moments of silence between conversation, like something that happens in real conversation. However, when you cut in mid-sentence or make too many quick cuts, it's distracting and annoying to try and listen. What I hated: While I love that film is about Harry Block, I hated him. His guts, his obsession with sex, and the fact that he is so damn awkward. I hate Woody Allen as an actor. I appreciate when people stutter, pause, mix up words, or ramble in movies because that's what people do in real life. However, Woody Allen takes it and makes it absolutely obnoxious. His arms flail around, he never makes eye contact (or keeps his eyes on the road while driving). Overall, the word I would use to describe this movie is 'inconsistent,' with some scene being very funny and entertaining, while others made me want to scratch my DVD apart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing the indestructible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block (Woody Allen) is a neurotic, jittery, pill-popping author, condemned by those who known him well, and hailed by those who don't know him at all. Block has written lengthy, verbose novels that are thinly-disguised to hide the real relationships in his life, and for that reason, he has successfully alienated himself from all of his formers friends and family members. He often spends his days lonely, drinking, and hanging out with prostitutes, who he pays ample amounts of money to in order to get a quick-fix. The current silver-lining in Block's sad, dreary existence is that he will soon be recognized in a forthcoming ceremony by the university that kicked him out. He desperately wants company when he embarks on this trip, but because his novels have made it impossible for people to sympathize or like him on any level, he is left with quite a challenge. Even his ex-wife forbids him to spend the day with his young son so he can see his father may not be such a loser after all. Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is many things, but one of the most notable is it exists as an ode to the films of acclaimed Swedish director Ingmar Bergman. The film's plot alone mirrors that of Wild Strawberries, one of the man's most loved, which centered on a man and his pregnant daughter-in-law driving through the country so he could be granted with an award. The film made the tricky but probable analysis that a man can be loved by those who don't know him and simultaneously be hated by those who know him all too well. It was a tremendous achievement in foreign cinema and, in my opinion based on what I've seen thus far, Bergman's best film. Furthermore, this is one of Allen's darkest efforts to date. Not only is the film's protagonist almost remorseless in his treatment of others, but the way certain scenes are written and executed truly question how we're exactly supposed to respond. Take for example the scene when Block's panic attacks get the best of him and he needs to be consoled by a hooker he invited over the night before. While the relationship is nice - and without a doubt deeper than most prostitute/client relationships - it definitely shows just how depressing and almost broken Block's life is to the point where he needs to be reassured and comforted by a prostitute. The nihilism and cynicism of Allen's work shockingly doesn't become the detraction in the film, whereas the choppy narrative does and questionable ending does. The narrative, which continues to bounce between the current events in Block's life and the past events/relationships he held, is a bit too erratic and jumbled, quickly switching back and forth between the past and present with only a moderate amount of continuity. Not to mention the ending feels a bit put-on and unbelievable considering all that Block has put up with during the course of the film. Returning to the thought that the film is one giant homage to the works of Bergman, consider Allen's comically potent portrayal of the Devil here. Bergman made the Devil a living, breathing character in his film The Seventh Seal and made the film very existential and thought-provoking. Allen pays close attention-to-detail in terms of character relations and how one person after another is presented here. He animates the Devil character (played by Billy Crystal) terrifically here, using the right amount of black humor and comic-timing. Deconstructing Harry is a cynical delight of a film making exceptional use of Allen's writing/directing talents, but also the immensity and diversity of the cast at hand. Each star, whether it be Kirstie Alley, Julia Louise-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Billy Crystal, or Robin Williams, gets their own time to shine in the picture and all of them feel welcome and completely in-place in Allen's darkly funny world. It's once again apparent that Allen can make deeply personal, intriguing pictures, yet still be so foreign to his audience as a whole. Starring: Woody Allen, Caroline Aaron, Kirstie Alley, Bob Balaban, Richard Benjamin, Eric Bogosian, Billy Crystal, Judy Davis, Hazelle Goodman, Mariel Hemingway, Amy Irving, Julie Kavner, Eric Lloyd, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Demi Moore, Elisabeth Shue, Stanley Tucci, and Robin Williams. Directed by: Woody Allen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry, understanding Woody ... and ourselves ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Deconstructing Harry" stands, in my opinion, as one of Woody Allen's best, probably his last masterpiece although it doesn't have the 'masterpiece' vibe. It looks like a typical Woody Allen movie but watch it closely and you'll get more insights about the director, the artist, ultimately the man. If you're not interested in, enjoy the gags and forget about it  if you can. I am more and more confident that Woody Allen is never as inspired and of course- hilarious as when his movies work as media to expresses his personal fears, angst and frustrations. And being capable to distort life, facts and reality to produce insights based on his own living, and in the intellectual and emotional process, to enable us to question ourselves, is in my opinion the work of a true artist. The film might feel 'minor' compared to other Allen's films but for some reason, it touched me, not immediately, but the ending was one of Allen's most triumphal achievements. Don't let yourself guided by your first feelings, this is not Allen wrapped up in his own ego, the film works on higher levels, and use Allen's own demons to tunnel us into ours, to use our empathy as a lightning torch to find truth in our personal darkness. Woody Allen is the titular Harry, Block is his last name, a fitting one as the writer he plays seems to suffer from mental block, the nightmare of every writer. But this block is justified by the series of incidents that undermined his inspiration. "Deconstructing Harry" is set during the aftermath of Harry's best-seller's success, a novel where he unveiled his most intimate secrets involving his friends, ex-wives, sister, family and acquaintances. It is one thing to reveal one's intimate secrets but we tend to forget that our secrets involve our personal circle. As a writer, Harry doesn't embarrass with such dilemmas, inspiration commands the writing and the others' anger is only a collateral damage he can afford but still must deal with. He tries to hide the names, to use lamentable pseudonyms, but behind every character, there's Harry. The film, like "Radio Days" is a succession of little vignettes, all reflecting a part of Harry's life, this is what the whole deconstruction process is about, in a masterstroke of writing. Whether it's a writer whose wife rediscovered her Jewish faith after the birth of her son, an old man indulging himself to cannibalism, a man cheating on his wife in front of an old blind parent, it's all about Harry, his friends are not fooled, neither are we. Is there a message behind that? Yes, every single piece of work of an artist is autobiographical. I'm tired of the whole: "Woody Allen always plays the same character" argument, because rather than a criticism, this is the best homage he can receive. But I would specify it a little bit, he doesn't play the same character, but within his whole oeuvre, there is one and only one Woody Allen. To understand the personality, one has to follow his evolution step by step, film by film. In "Interiors", the artist put his own inspiration into perspective, in "Stardust Memories", his comical talent or in "Zelig", his capability to please to be part of the mood.. In "Deconstructing Harry", it seems like the constantly self-deprecating Woody Allen is finally over with his own demons, because he comes to one realization, this is the best thing he can do, this is the only talent he truly has, and he's only exploiting it for the best. One of his friends, played by Billy Crystal, stole his girlfriend, but he acknowledges he doesn't have his talent. And yes, Allen is the best screenwriter. At the film's apotheosis, when all the characters he created applauded him, you can see the overwhelming effect on his eyes, and for one second, we imagine Woody Allen being applauded by Annie Hall, Virgil, Hannah and her Sisters thanking him for having graced the silver screen and pleased a generation of movie goers, for more than 20 years. Almost 20 years later, Woody Allen is still prolific but you could feel a relief after "Deconstructing Harry", when he could finally get to more fictional stuff, and telling stories again. I didn't speak much of the film because it's typically Allenian with a great cast, a deliberately disjointed editing, sometimes confusing but I guess it's a benign artistic license in order to convey the chaotic aspect of Harry's life as a sort of story he tries to rewrite inside himself, with the same process of writing, erasing, rewriting, copy-pasting etc. But what rises above the whole chaos, is the self-reflexive approach of Allen to his own work, he did it with "Interiors" and "Stardust Memories", but the films were inspired by Bergman and Fellini's works. I guess it took the revival of his comical genius in the 80's and the early 90's so he could understand that the best one to talk about Woody and to deconstruct Woody, is still Woody. And from someone who wishes to become a writer and can't function in the cold and average normality of life, I realize that I'm more inclined to bloom during writing, and stop being so out-of-focus, I should be the one to give people the right glasses to see what I'm worth. This out-of-focus metaphor is a strike of comical genius, and it touched a very sensitive chord. I loved "Deconstructing Harry" in a very deep and personal level and as I get older, I feel a very strong connection to the artistic and even neurotic personality of Woody Allen. To deconstruct Harry is to understand Woody, and ... a certain part of ourselves, imprisoned in a life of futile conventions and begging for expression, no matter how hard, and painful or shameful they are. I guess we should all learn to deconstruct ourselves to be over with our inner demons.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The love between writer and character.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Dennen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is, in my opinion, one of Woody Allen's most underrated films. Often overlooked by a careers' worth of other more well known work, this late 90's Drama plays out a relationship seldom looked at; the relationship between a writer and their intellectual property. The characters in this film act as friends and loved ones, or rather memories of friends and loved ones. It's a look inside the mind of a neurotic writer, a writer whose life is both hitting a professional peak, while simultaneously hitting a personal low. Harry Block (Woody Allen), is dealing with past demons as well as present hurdles, all while preparing to receive a major award. To help deal with this accumulation of problems, characters from his fictional stories seep into his reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Allen's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is a rare film that takes it's title in the most literal ways, both in structure and in storytelling. The plot centers around Harry Block (played as only Allen himself could), a man suffering from writer's block as he prepares to accept an award from his old university, but this is only a loose strain to give the story a narrative though. What it's really focused on is Harry himself, his mind and his characters. In the traditional Allen sense, we get some external monologuing as he explores the mind of this neurotic, stuck and seemingly hopeless man, but he does it in a way that I've never seen him work before. The style of comedy is of course that Allen allure that no one could imitate, but there's also a vulgarity to it that I've never seen him go for before. There are words that I never thought I'd see in a Woody Allen film and the jokes are incredibly graphic, but it gives it this sense of brutal honesty that I haven't experienced from him up to this point. It's absolutely hilarious and quite true, it felt comically in the same sense of Louis C.K.'s work; vulgar and borderline offensive, but totally true to the point where it makes it's audience take a long look in the mirror. As we explore Harry, his few friends and his many exes, we are treated to short vignettes taken from his previous written work. Allen explores the mind of a writer so thoroughly it's mesmerizing, giving us looks into how true the "you write what you know" expression is, with characters that are directly based on his past lovers and himself. Each short story is hilarious in it's own right, but also sheds more light into the character himself, which is the ultimate draw of the film. I've never liked a performance from the writer/director more than I have here. He's got the neurosis and cynicism that he is a master at, but there's also an authenticity and darkness to him that I felt was more exposed than I've seen him before. His editing work is a masterstroke as well as he depicts Harry's real life as fractured, making quick cuts in scenes so that nothing seems to be fluid but it gives it this stream-of-consciousness touch that becomes fluid in itself, in detailing what he wants to accomplish. When we see his work displayed, there's no fragmentation, no awkward cuts, everything runs smoothly. The final scene of the film states the themes a little too strongly, as he practically spoonfeeds them to the audience, but it's a brilliant display of how a writer can become so broken and fractured in his own life that the only way he can achieve any clarity is through his work. A dark, touching, hilarious film with a strong message. Plus, it opens with Julia Louis-Dreyfus getting bent over and plowed in front of a blind woman, and you don't get much funnier than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It's me thinly disguised in fact, I don't even think I should disguise it any more  it's me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is probably Woody Allen's most interesting and controversial film from his troubled 90s period. Coming at the height of turmoil in his personal life, the same year that Deconstructing Harry was released, Allen married Soon Yi Previn and the world was given an insight into their relationship in the rewarding documentary Wild Man Blues (6). Deconstructing Harry sees him slam reality and fiction together, giving (except for one exception) an expletive-free and free-flowing series of fantasy vignettes with jump- cut, foul-mouthed bites of reality. For this reason more than any other it's a film that could upset Allen purists, as his attempt to capture real life sees multiple uses of the word "f***" and even the "c" word coming from Woody's lips on two occasions. Is the film misogynist? Possibly. Woody certainly appears to have anger towards women here, and while the ladies of the night so romantically depicted in the likable-but-bland Mighty Aphrodite (6) are here "whores" and "hookers", there's also more than an element of racial patronage. The adjoinder from an African American prostitute over whether she knows what a black hole is ("Yeah... that's how I make my living") is probably the most repellent line in an Allen film, bar none. Even today Woody is still capable of making watchable films, but they're rarely essential and tend towards the reactionary. Little of his later period has come close to matching the vibrancy and sheer anxiety-based energy of Deconstructing Harry. This is Woody venting his spleen for the masses, and seeming to toy with the "playing himself" questions. It may not be pleasant to watch, but it's never dull. Again, his Jewish fixations can be offensive, though the scenes with his sister and brother-in-law are amongst the funniest in this not quite laugh-a-minute vehicle. I loved the bit where he tells his sister's husband: "I think you're the opposite of paranoid. I think you go around with the insane delusion that people like you". Yeah, most of the jokes at this stage in his career are recycled, but they're given a new take by the level of unsettling acidity contained in this picture. Annie Hall this isn't. The 1990s won't be remembered as a golden age for Allen's work, a period where he was getting more laughs voicing a cartoon ant than in his own movies. Altogether he wrote and directed ten new films, as well as a grating TV movie of his 60s play/film Don't Drink The Water (4). Films like Alice (5), Manhattan Murder Mystery (6) or Shadows and Fog (5) are watchable yet forgettable, the first decade for Allen where the so-so outnumbered the good. Yet there's still some first rate work in his 90s period, with Husbands and Wives (7) treading familiar ground but in subtle new ways. Sweet and Lowdown (7), a biopic of a fictitious jazz musician, brims with invention... though his first musical, Everyone Says I Love You (q.v.) sadly does not. Perhaps most notable in the 90s is the casting of actors to play the "Woody Allen" role, as he was entering his 60s and perhaps straining even his own much-tested formula of "young girl falls for older intellectual". In this regard then Kenneth Brannagh surprisingly does a better job than John Cusack, playing a substitute in the rewarding Celebrity (7), as opposed to Cusack's turn in the jarring Bullets Over Broadway (5). Which brings us back to Deconstructing Harry, as Allen originally had no wish to star in the lead. Deconstructing Harry isn't a pleasant film to watch by any means. It's crass, foul-mouthed and even obnoxious on occasion. But the fragmented, sketchy nature of events and inventive sequences make it an easier viewing experience than an extended narrative. Not only that, but in watching something which appears to be such a personal statement, then it may not be Allen's most likable or accomplished film, but it remains one of the most intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Allen's homage to (and send-up of) WILD STRAWBERRIES has its pluses and minuses. It's interesting, and in a way refreshing, to see him being so blatantly crass. It's one of his darkest movies, and maybe his most cynical comedy. Some of it is riotously funny, like the confrontation with Kirstie Alley in the middle of a patient's therapy session, or his version of Hell (with Billy Crystal in one of his most enjoyable roles). But with all the little sub-stories going on, it comes off like a clearinghouse for unfinished ideas. Also, the fragmented, jerky editing (because he's being "deconstructed," get it?) is an annoying quirk that adds little. Still, there's a lots of laughs to be had and it's an interesting bit of self-deprecation combined with self-admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good Woody Allen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block is a successful writer who gets inspiration from people he knows.Everybody doesn't like that.And he has his flaws, like pills and whores.Now his old university is honoring him.Harry wants to take his son Hilly to the ceremony, but his ex-wife Joan says no.But Harry takes him there anyway, as he does take a prostitute named Cookie and a friend called Richard.What a day to remember that will be! Deconstructing Harry is a Woody Allen film from 1997.Woody Allen gives a really great performance in this movie.Luckily he cast himself.No complaints about the rest of the cast either.Kirstie Alley plays the part of Joan, Harry's ex-wife.Billy Crystal, who gets to do next year's Oscars again, plays Larry/The Devil.Lucy Davis is Lucy.Bob Balaban plays Richard.Elisabeth Shue plays Fay.Paul Giamatti is Prof. Abbott.Philip Bosco is Prof. Clark.Mariel Hemingway, who was also in Allen's Manhattan, plays Beth Kramer.Hazelle Goodman is Cookie.Amy Irving is Jane.Eric Lloyd plays Hilly.Now 90-year old Gene Saks plays Harry's Father.Tony Sirico is Policeman at Jail.Then there are some characters that are of Harry's creation.Richard Benjamin plays Ken.Julia Louis-Dreyfus is Leslie.Tobey Maguire plays Harvey Stern.Jennifer Garner is Woman in Elevator.Stanley Tucci is Paul Epstein.Demi Moore plays Helen.Robin Williams is Mel.Julie Kavner is Grace.This is a very fine Woody Allen movie of the 90's.It's often funny.You find yourself most amused, when they're driving with the hooker and doing some car singing.Also out of focus Robin Williams is hilarious.I get seasick just by looking at him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harry is a writer, Block.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another all-star cast, another central role played by writer-director Woody Allen and another look at a character full of flaws and neuroses, we're in very familiar territory this time around. Allen plays Harry Block, a writer who is struggling for the first time in his life with writer's block and who is also tense about an upcoming honour he is to receive from his old school. As he tries to iron out the many wrinkles in his life and deal with his worries he finds himself encountering many of his literary creations (both fictional and in the form of the real, living people he based them upon) and getting advice from them along the way. The notion of the artist confronted by his creations and the consequences of his work is a good one and the weaving of the fantasy strands through the reality of the piece allows for a lot of fun (especially when comparing a fictional character to the real person they were based on) but this film, overall, just somehow misses the mark. The script isn't quite sharp enough, none of the performers get enough time to make a good impression and nothing feels as if it's actually moving a narrative along from start to finish. With a cast including Bob Balaban, Judy Davis, Billy Crystal, Robin Williams, Richard Benjamin, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Eric Bogosian, Kirstie Alley, Julie Kavner, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Tony Sirico, Demi Moore and Elisabeth Shue it's a real shame that nobody gets a chance to shine. Billy Crystal gets to have the most fun but Robin Williams stars in the most enjoyable fantasy sequence as an actor who one day suddenly goes out of focus. As others have said, this is worth seeing as a companion piece to Stardust Memories (with that being about the director and this being about the writer) but I just found myself watching long sections of the film without actually, properly enjoying it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Digging to the core; leave no stone unturned.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Mighty Aphrodite is a nice Woody Allen, then Deconstructing Harry is certainly the pinnacle of his nasty side. Indeed, for non-Woody Allen fans, it would seem difficult to understand how two vastly different films could come from the same mind. Yet, the genius of Allen lays primarily in his writing, able to create and expound upon a brilliant idea of the story of a man who is unable to cope the negative and horrible lifestyle he abides with the successful and insightful writing and art he creates fictionally. This is a difficult film to review as it unfolds itself in a very bipolar manner: cinematically it works on the highest scale with terrific acting, direction, editing and one of Woody's best scripts. Yet, on the other hand, it is quite possibly his meanest and most cynical portrait of humanity. The character of Harry Block (whom no one was willing to play until Allen finally took it himself) is incredibly neurotic, egotistical, nihilistic and narcissistic and Allen takes him to the very end of his rope, almost encouraging us to not feel any sympathy towards him at all. Certainly no one else does; his entire family hates him for the way he vaguely portrays them in his books as cheap stereotypes of their personalities and beliefs. Still, there may be the slightest bit of humanity within this ball of neuroses if only because Woody Allen gives one of his very best performances here. Again, I must praise the large and star-studded cast for carrying much of the heavy material, especially in scenes that would feel out of place in other hands. In particular, Judy Davis, Elisabeth Shue and Bob Balaban are very good. I must also give praise to Billy Crystal who personifies the devil himself in Harry's mind and is evilly funny. I guess this should be recommended but only for serious Woody Allen fans. It convincingly gives an argument for why and how Allen is able to rationalize all the crazy events he has gone through in his life. Personally, I cannot say that I always agree with his worldview. But, he always does have something interesting to say and if he can continue to say it through films like this, then I feel I will be able to sit through them. However, be warned: this is a side of Woody Allen never seen prior and hardly seen since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mixed Feelings...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick Cluxton
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been looking forward to seeing this film for quite a while, and when I finally had a chance I was pretty quick to take it up. As I started it, I regretted it immediately, I was bored and annoyed. Towards the end, it began to grow on me, but a lot just didn't do it for me. What I liked: I absolutely love the concept and the story. I have not seen any like it. What I like most is that while there is an actual plot and external events, it's more of a character study. They take an unlikable character and give him plenty of depth and sympathy to make up for his brash decisions and opinions. I love Woody Allen as a writer. I also liked the short stories; how they were narrated, the actual relevance they had to Harry's problems and friends, and how they were somewhat diverse. It wasn't just about the message. I both liked and disliked the scenes where they would cut to the same shot. It is very reminiscent of Jean- Loc Goddard's Breathless, which at times gave it a very relaxed, more realistic feel, considering that you could interpret that there were probably moments of silence between conversation, like something that happens in real conversation. However, when you cut in mid-sentence or make too many quick cuts, it's distracting and annoying to try and listen. What I hated: While I love that film is about Harry Block, I hated him. His guts, his obsession with sex, and the fact that he is so damn awkward. I hate Woody Allen as an actor. I appreciate when people stutter, pause, mix up words, or ramble in movies because that's what people do in real life. However, Woody Allen takes it and makes it absolutely obnoxious. His arms flail around, he never makes eye contact (or keeps his eyes on the road while driving). Overall, the word I would use to describe this movie is 'inconsistent,' with some scene being very funny and entertaining, while others made me want to scratch my DVD apart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing the indestructible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block (Woody Allen) is a neurotic, jittery, pill-popping author, condemned by those who known him well, and hailed by those who don't know him at all. Block has written lengthy, verbose novels that are thinly-disguised to hide the real relationships in his life, and for that reason, he has successfully alienated himself from all of his formers friends and family members. He often spends his days lonely, drinking, and hanging out with prostitutes, who he pays ample amounts of money to in order to get a quick-fix. The current silver-lining in Block's sad, dreary existence is that he will soon be recognized in a forthcoming ceremony by the university that kicked him out. He desperately wants company when he embarks on this trip, but because his novels have made it impossible for people to sympathize or like him on any level, he is left with quite a challenge. Even his ex-wife forbids him to spend the day with his young son so he can see his father may not be such a loser after all. Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is many things, but one of the most notable is it exists as an ode to the films of acclaimed Swedish director Ingmar Bergman. The film's plot alone mirrors that of Wild Strawberries, one of the man's most loved, which centered on a man and his pregnant daughter-in-law driving through the country so he could be granted with an award. The film made the tricky but probable analysis that a man can be loved by those who don't know him and simultaneously be hated by those who know him all too well. It was a tremendous achievement in foreign cinema and, in my opinion based on what I've seen thus far, Bergman's best film. Furthermore, this is one of Allen's darkest efforts to date. Not only is the film's protagonist almost remorseless in his treatment of others, but the way certain scenes are written and executed truly question how we're exactly supposed to respond. Take for example the scene when Block's panic attacks get the best of him and he needs to be consoled by a hooker he invited over the night before. While the relationship is nice - and without a doubt deeper than most prostitute/client relationships - it definitely shows just how depressing and almost broken Block's life is to the point where he needs to be reassured and comforted by a prostitute. The nihilism and cynicism of Allen's work shockingly doesn't become the detraction in the film, whereas the choppy narrative does and questionable ending does. The narrative, which continues to bounce between the current events in Block's life and the past events/relationships he held, is a bit too erratic and jumbled, quickly switching back and forth between the past and present with only a moderate amount of continuity. Not to mention the ending feels a bit put-on and unbelievable considering all that Block has put up with during the course of the film. Returning to the thought that the film is one giant homage to the works of Bergman, consider Allen's comically potent portrayal of the Devil here. Bergman made the Devil a living, breathing character in his film The Seventh Seal and made the film very existential and thought-provoking. Allen pays close attention-to-detail in terms of character relations and how one person after another is presented here. He animates the Devil character (played by Billy Crystal) terrifically here, using the right amount of black humor and comic-timing. Deconstructing Harry is a cynical delight of a film making exceptional use of Allen's writing/directing talents, but also the immensity and diversity of the cast at hand. Each star, whether it be Kirstie Alley, Julia Louise-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Billy Crystal, or Robin Williams, gets their own time to shine in the picture and all of them feel welcome and completely in-place in Allen's darkly funny world. It's once again apparent that Allen can make deeply personal, intriguing pictures, yet still be so foreign to his audience as a whole. Starring: Woody Allen, Caroline Aaron, Kirstie Alley, Bob Balaban, Richard Benjamin, Eric Bogosian, Billy Crystal, Judy Davis, Hazelle Goodman, Mariel Hemingway, Amy Irving, Julie Kavner, Eric Lloyd, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Demi Moore, Elisabeth Shue, Stanley Tucci, and Robin Williams. Directed by: Woody Allen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry, understanding Woody ... and ourselves ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Deconstructing Harry" stands, in my opinion, as one of Woody Allen's best, probably his last masterpiece although it doesn't have the 'masterpiece' vibe. It looks like a typical Woody Allen movie but watch it closely and you'll get more insights about the director, the artist, ultimately the man. If you're not interested in, enjoy the gags and forget about it  if you can. I am more and more confident that Woody Allen is never as inspired and of course- hilarious as when his movies work as media to expresses his personal fears, angst and frustrations. And being capable to distort life, facts and reality to produce insights based on his own living, and in the intellectual and emotional process, to enable us to question ourselves, is in my opinion the work of a true artist. The film might feel 'minor' compared to other Allen's films but for some reason, it touched me, not immediately, but the ending was one of Allen's most triumphal achievements. Don't let yourself guided by your first feelings, this is not Allen wrapped up in his own ego, the film works on higher levels, and use Allen's own demons to tunnel us into ours, to use our empathy as a lightning torch to find truth in our personal darkness. Woody Allen is the titular Harry, Block is his last name, a fitting one as the writer he plays seems to suffer from mental block, the nightmare of every writer. But this block is justified by the series of incidents that undermined his inspiration. "Deconstructing Harry" is set during the aftermath of Harry's best-seller's success, a novel where he unveiled his most intimate secrets involving his friends, ex-wives, sister, family and acquaintances. It is one thing to reveal one's intimate secrets but we tend to forget that our secrets involve our personal circle. As a writer, Harry doesn't embarrass with such dilemmas, inspiration commands the writing and the others' anger is only a collateral damage he can afford but still must deal with. He tries to hide the names, to use lamentable pseudonyms, but behind every character, there's Harry. The film, like "Radio Days" is a succession of little vignettes, all reflecting a part of Harry's life, this is what the whole deconstruction process is about, in a masterstroke of writing. Whether it's a writer whose wife rediscovered her Jewish faith after the birth of her son, an old man indulging himself to cannibalism, a man cheating on his wife in front of an old blind parent, it's all about Harry, his friends are not fooled, neither are we. Is there a message behind that? Yes, every single piece of work of an artist is autobiographical. I'm tired of the whole: "Woody Allen always plays the same character" argument, because rather than a criticism, this is the best homage he can receive. But I would specify it a little bit, he doesn't play the same character, but within his whole oeuvre, there is one and only one Woody Allen. To understand the personality, one has to follow his evolution step by step, film by film. In "Interiors", the artist put his own inspiration into perspective, in "Stardust Memories", his comical talent or in "Zelig", his capability to please to be part of the mood.. In "Deconstructing Harry", it seems like the constantly self-deprecating Woody Allen is finally over with his own demons, because he comes to one realization, this is the best thing he can do, this is the only talent he truly has, and he's only exploiting it for the best. One of his friends, played by Billy Crystal, stole his girlfriend, but he acknowledges he doesn't have his talent. And yes, Allen is the best screenwriter. At the film's apotheosis, when all the characters he created applauded him, you can see the overwhelming effect on his eyes, and for one second, we imagine Woody Allen being applauded by Annie Hall, Virgil, Hannah and her Sisters thanking him for having graced the silver screen and pleased a generation of movie goers, for more than 20 years. Almost 20 years later, Woody Allen is still prolific but you could feel a relief after "Deconstructing Harry", when he could finally get to more fictional stuff, and telling stories again. I didn't speak much of the film because it's typically Allenian with a great cast, a deliberately disjointed editing, sometimes confusing but I guess it's a benign artistic license in order to convey the chaotic aspect of Harry's life as a sort of story he tries to rewrite inside himself, with the same process of writing, erasing, rewriting, copy-pasting etc. But what rises above the whole chaos, is the self-reflexive approach of Allen to his own work, he did it with "Interiors" and "Stardust Memories", but the films were inspired by Bergman and Fellini's works. I guess it took the revival of his comical genius in the 80's and the early 90's so he could understand that the best one to talk about Woody and to deconstruct Woody, is still Woody. And from someone who wishes to become a writer and can't function in the cold and average normality of life, I realize that I'm more inclined to bloom during writing, and stop being so out-of-focus, I should be the one to give people the right glasses to see what I'm worth. This out-of-focus metaphor is a strike of comical genius, and it touched a very sensitive chord. I loved "Deconstructing Harry" in a very deep and personal level and as I get older, I feel a very strong connection to the artistic and even neurotic personality of Woody Allen. To deconstruct Harry is to understand Woody, and ... a certain part of ourselves, imprisoned in a life of futile conventions and begging for expression, no matter how hard, and painful or shameful they are. I guess we should all learn to deconstruct ourselves to be over with our inner demons.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The love between writer and character.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Dennen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is, in my opinion, one of Woody Allen's most underrated films. Often overlooked by a careers' worth of other more well known work, this late 90's Drama plays out a relationship seldom looked at; the relationship between a writer and their intellectual property. The characters in this film act as friends and loved ones, or rather memories of friends and loved ones. It's a look inside the mind of a neurotic writer, a writer whose life is both hitting a professional peak, while simultaneously hitting a personal low. Harry Block (Woody Allen), is dealing with past demons as well as present hurdles, all while preparing to receive a major award. To help deal with this accumulation of problems, characters from his fictional stories seep into his reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Allen's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is a rare film that takes it's title in the most literal ways, both in structure and in storytelling. The plot centers around Harry Block (played as only Allen himself could), a man suffering from writer's block as he prepares to accept an award from his old university, but this is only a loose strain to give the story a narrative though. What it's really focused on is Harry himself, his mind and his characters. In the traditional Allen sense, we get some external monologuing as he explores the mind of this neurotic, stuck and seemingly hopeless man, but he does it in a way that I've never seen him work before. The style of comedy is of course that Allen allure that no one could imitate, but there's also a vulgarity to it that I've never seen him go for before. There are words that I never thought I'd see in a Woody Allen film and the jokes are incredibly graphic, but it gives it this sense of brutal honesty that I haven't experienced from him up to this point. It's absolutely hilarious and quite true, it felt comically in the same sense of Louis C.K.'s work; vulgar and borderline offensive, but totally true to the point where it makes it's audience take a long look in the mirror. As we explore Harry, his few friends and his many exes, we are treated to short vignettes taken from his previous written work. Allen explores the mind of a writer so thoroughly it's mesmerizing, giving us looks into how true the "you write what you know" expression is, with characters that are directly based on his past lovers and himself. Each short story is hilarious in it's own right, but also sheds more light into the character himself, which is the ultimate draw of the film. I've never liked a performance from the writer/director more than I have here. He's got the neurosis and cynicism that he is a master at, but there's also an authenticity and darkness to him that I felt was more exposed than I've seen him before. His editing work is a masterstroke as well as he depicts Harry's real life as fractured, making quick cuts in scenes so that nothing seems to be fluid but it gives it this stream-of-consciousness touch that becomes fluid in itself, in detailing what he wants to accomplish. When we see his work displayed, there's no fragmentation, no awkward cuts, everything runs smoothly. The final scene of the film states the themes a little too strongly, as he practically spoonfeeds them to the audience, but it's a brilliant display of how a writer can become so broken and fractured in his own life that the only way he can achieve any clarity is through his work. A dark, touching, hilarious film with a strong message. Plus, it opens with Julia Louis-Dreyfus getting bent over and plowed in front of a blind woman, and you don't get much funnier than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It's me thinly disguised in fact, I don't even think I should disguise it any more  it's me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is probably Woody Allen's most interesting and controversial film from his troubled 90s period. Coming at the height of turmoil in his personal life, the same year that Deconstructing Harry was released, Allen married Soon Yi Previn and the world was given an insight into their relationship in the rewarding documentary Wild Man Blues (6). Deconstructing Harry sees him slam reality and fiction together, giving (except for one exception) an expletive-free and free-flowing series of fantasy vignettes with jump- cut, foul-mouthed bites of reality. For this reason more than any other it's a film that could upset Allen purists, as his attempt to capture real life sees multiple uses of the word "f***" and even the "c" word coming from Woody's lips on two occasions. Is the film misogynist? Possibly. Woody certainly appears to have anger towards women here, and while the ladies of the night so romantically depicted in the likable-but-bland Mighty Aphrodite (6) are here "whores" and "hookers", there's also more than an element of racial patronage. The adjoinder from an African American prostitute over whether she knows what a black hole is ("Yeah... that's how I make my living") is probably the most repellent line in an Allen film, bar none. Even today Woody is still capable of making watchable films, but they're rarely essential and tend towards the reactionary. Little of his later period has come close to matching the vibrancy and sheer anxiety-based energy of Deconstructing Harry. This is Woody venting his spleen for the masses, and seeming to toy with the "playing himself" questions. It may not be pleasant to watch, but it's never dull. Again, his Jewish fixations can be offensive, though the scenes with his sister and brother-in-law are amongst the funniest in this not quite laugh-a-minute vehicle. I loved the bit where he tells his sister's husband: "I think you're the opposite of paranoid. I think you go around with the insane delusion that people like you". Yeah, most of the jokes at this stage in his career are recycled, but they're given a new take by the level of unsettling acidity contained in this picture. Annie Hall this isn't. The 1990s won't be remembered as a golden age for Allen's work, a period where he was getting more laughs voicing a cartoon ant than in his own movies. Altogether he wrote and directed ten new films, as well as a grating TV movie of his 60s play/film Don't Drink The Water (4). Films like Alice (5), Manhattan Murder Mystery (6) or Shadows and Fog (5) are watchable yet forgettable, the first decade for Allen where the so-so outnumbered the good. Yet there's still some first rate work in his 90s period, with Husbands and Wives (7) treading familiar ground but in subtle new ways. Sweet and Lowdown (7), a biopic of a fictitious jazz musician, brims with invention... though his first musical, Everyone Says I Love You (q.v.) sadly does not. Perhaps most notable in the 90s is the casting of actors to play the "Woody Allen" role, as he was entering his 60s and perhaps straining even his own much-tested formula of "young girl falls for older intellectual". In this regard then Kenneth Brannagh surprisingly does a better job than John Cusack, playing a substitute in the rewarding Celebrity (7), as opposed to Cusack's turn in the jarring Bullets Over Broadway (5). Which brings us back to Deconstructing Harry, as Allen originally had no wish to star in the lead. Deconstructing Harry isn't a pleasant film to watch by any means. It's crass, foul-mouthed and even obnoxious on occasion. But the fragmented, sketchy nature of events and inventive sequences make it an easier viewing experience than an extended narrative. Not only that, but in watching something which appears to be such a personal statement, then it may not be Allen's most likable or accomplished film, but it remains one of the most intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Allen's homage to (and send-up of) WILD STRAWBERRIES has its pluses and minuses. It's interesting, and in a way refreshing, to see him being so blatantly crass. It's one of his darkest movies, and maybe his most cynical comedy. Some of it is riotously funny, like the confrontation with Kirstie Alley in the middle of a patient's therapy session, or his version of Hell (with Billy Crystal in one of his most enjoyable roles). But with all the little sub-stories going on, it comes off like a clearinghouse for unfinished ideas. Also, the fragmented, jerky editing (because he's being "deconstructed," get it?) is an annoying quirk that adds little. Still, there's a lots of laughs to be had and it's an interesting bit of self-deprecation combined with self-admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good Woody Allen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block is a successful writer who gets inspiration from people he knows.Everybody doesn't like that.And he has his flaws, like pills and whores.Now his old university is honoring him.Harry wants to take his son Hilly to the ceremony, but his ex-wife Joan says no.But Harry takes him there anyway, as he does take a prostitute named Cookie and a friend called Richard.What a day to remember that will be! Deconstructing Harry is a Woody Allen film from 1997.Woody Allen gives a really great performance in this movie.Luckily he cast himself.No complaints about the rest of the cast either.Kirstie Alley plays the part of Joan, Harry's ex-wife.Billy Crystal, who gets to do next year's Oscars again, plays Larry/The Devil.Lucy Davis is Lucy.Bob Balaban plays Richard.Elisabeth Shue plays Fay.Paul Giamatti is Prof. Abbott.Philip Bosco is Prof. Clark.Mariel Hemingway, who was also in Allen's Manhattan, plays Beth Kramer.Hazelle Goodman is Cookie.Amy Irving is Jane.Eric Lloyd plays Hilly.Now 90-year old Gene Saks plays Harry's Father.Tony Sirico is Policeman at Jail.Then there are some characters that are of Harry's creation.Richard Benjamin plays Ken.Julia Louis-Dreyfus is Leslie.Tobey Maguire plays Harvey Stern.Jennifer Garner is Woman in Elevator.Stanley Tucci is Paul Epstein.Demi Moore plays Helen.Robin Williams is Mel.Julie Kavner is Grace.This is a very fine Woody Allen movie of the 90's.It's often funny.You find yourself most amused, when they're driving with the hooker and doing some car singing.Also out of focus Robin Williams is hilarious.I get seasick just by looking at him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harry is a writer, Block.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another all-star cast, another central role played by writer-director Woody Allen and another look at a character full of flaws and neuroses, we're in very familiar territory this time around. Allen plays Harry Block, a writer who is struggling for the first time in his life with writer's block and who is also tense about an upcoming honour he is to receive from his old school. As he tries to iron out the many wrinkles in his life and deal with his worries he finds himself encountering many of his literary creations (both fictional and in the form of the real, living people he based them upon) and getting advice from them along the way. The notion of the artist confronted by his creations and the consequences of his work is a good one and the weaving of the fantasy strands through the reality of the piece allows for a lot of fun (especially when comparing a fictional character to the real person they were based on) but this film, overall, just somehow misses the mark. The script isn't quite sharp enough, none of the performers get enough time to make a good impression and nothing feels as if it's actually moving a narrative along from start to finish. With a cast including Bob Balaban, Judy Davis, Billy Crystal, Robin Williams, Richard Benjamin, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Eric Bogosian, Kirstie Alley, Julie Kavner, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Tony Sirico, Demi Moore and Elisabeth Shue it's a real shame that nobody gets a chance to shine. Billy Crystal gets to have the most fun but Robin Williams stars in the most enjoyable fantasy sequence as an actor who one day suddenly goes out of focus. As others have said, this is worth seeing as a companion piece to Stardust Memories (with that being about the director and this being about the writer) but I just found myself watching long sections of the film without actually, properly enjoying it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Digging to the core; leave no stone unturned.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Mighty Aphrodite is a nice Woody Allen, then Deconstructing Harry is certainly the pinnacle of his nasty side. Indeed, for non-Woody Allen fans, it would seem difficult to understand how two vastly different films could come from the same mind. Yet, the genius of Allen lays primarily in his writing, able to create and expound upon a brilliant idea of the story of a man who is unable to cope the negative and horrible lifestyle he abides with the successful and insightful writing and art he creates fictionally. This is a difficult film to review as it unfolds itself in a very bipolar manner: cinematically it works on the highest scale with terrific acting, direction, editing and one of Woody's best scripts. Yet, on the other hand, it is quite possibly his meanest and most cynical portrait of humanity. The character of Harry Block (whom no one was willing to play until Allen finally took it himself) is incredibly neurotic, egotistical, nihilistic and narcissistic and Allen takes him to the very end of his rope, almost encouraging us to not feel any sympathy towards him at all. Certainly no one else does; his entire family hates him for the way he vaguely portrays them in his books as cheap stereotypes of their personalities and beliefs. Still, there may be the slightest bit of humanity within this ball of neuroses if only because Woody Allen gives one of his very best performances here. Again, I must praise the large and star-studded cast for carrying much of the heavy material, especially in scenes that would feel out of place in other hands. In particular, Judy Davis, Elisabeth Shue and Bob Balaban are very good. I must also give praise to Billy Crystal who personifies the devil himself in Harry's mind and is evilly funny. I guess this should be recommended but only for serious Woody Allen fans. It convincingly gives an argument for why and how Allen is able to rationalize all the crazy events he has gone through in his life. Personally, I cannot say that I always agree with his worldview. But, he always does have something interesting to say and if he can continue to say it through films like this, then I feel I will be able to sit through them. However, be warned: this is a side of Woody Allen never seen prior and hardly seen since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mixed Feelings...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick Cluxton
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been looking forward to seeing this film for quite a while, and when I finally had a chance I was pretty quick to take it up. As I started it, I regretted it immediately, I was bored and annoyed. Towards the end, it began to grow on me, but a lot just didn't do it for me. What I liked: I absolutely love the concept and the story. I have not seen any like it. What I like most is that while there is an actual plot and external events, it's more of a character study. They take an unlikable character and give him plenty of depth and sympathy to make up for his brash decisions and opinions. I love Woody Allen as a writer. I also liked the short stories; how they were narrated, the actual relevance they had to Harry's problems and friends, and how they were somewhat diverse. It wasn't just about the message. I both liked and disliked the scenes where they would cut to the same shot. It is very reminiscent of Jean- Loc Goddard's Breathless, which at times gave it a very relaxed, more realistic feel, considering that you could interpret that there were probably moments of silence between conversation, like something that happens in real conversation. However, when you cut in mid-sentence or make too many quick cuts, it's distracting and annoying to try and listen. What I hated: While I love that film is about Harry Block, I hated him. His guts, his obsession with sex, and the fact that he is so damn awkward. I hate Woody Allen as an actor. I appreciate when people stutter, pause, mix up words, or ramble in movies because that's what people do in real life. However, Woody Allen takes it and makes it absolutely obnoxious. His arms flail around, he never makes eye contact (or keeps his eyes on the road while driving). Overall, the word I would use to describe this movie is 'inconsistent,' with some scene being very funny and entertaining, while others made me want to scratch my DVD apart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing the indestructible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block (Woody Allen) is a neurotic, jittery, pill-popping author, condemned by those who known him well, and hailed by those who don't know him at all. Block has written lengthy, verbose novels that are thinly-disguised to hide the real relationships in his life, and for that reason, he has successfully alienated himself from all of his formers friends and family members. He often spends his days lonely, drinking, and hanging out with prostitutes, who he pays ample amounts of money to in order to get a quick-fix. The current silver-lining in Block's sad, dreary existence is that he will soon be recognized in a forthcoming ceremony by the university that kicked him out. He desperately wants company when he embarks on this trip, but because his novels have made it impossible for people to sympathize or like him on any level, he is left with quite a challenge. Even his ex-wife forbids him to spend the day with his young son so he can see his father may not be such a loser after all. Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is many things, but one of the most notable is it exists as an ode to the films of acclaimed Swedish director Ingmar Bergman. The film's plot alone mirrors that of Wild Strawberries, one of the man's most loved, which centered on a man and his pregnant daughter-in-law driving through the country so he could be granted with an award. The film made the tricky but probable analysis that a man can be loved by those who don't know him and simultaneously be hated by those who know him all too well. It was a tremendous achievement in foreign cinema and, in my opinion based on what I've seen thus far, Bergman's best film. Furthermore, this is one of Allen's darkest efforts to date. Not only is the film's protagonist almost remorseless in his treatment of others, but the way certain scenes are written and executed truly question how we're exactly supposed to respond. Take for example the scene when Block's panic attacks get the best of him and he needs to be consoled by a hooker he invited over the night before. While the relationship is nice - and without a doubt deeper than most prostitute/client relationships - it definitely shows just how depressing and almost broken Block's life is to the point where he needs to be reassured and comforted by a prostitute. The nihilism and cynicism of Allen's work shockingly doesn't become the detraction in the film, whereas the choppy narrative does and questionable ending does. The narrative, which continues to bounce between the current events in Block's life and the past events/relationships he held, is a bit too erratic and jumbled, quickly switching back and forth between the past and present with only a moderate amount of continuity. Not to mention the ending feels a bit put-on and unbelievable considering all that Block has put up with during the course of the film. Returning to the thought that the film is one giant homage to the works of Bergman, consider Allen's comically potent portrayal of the Devil here. Bergman made the Devil a living, breathing character in his film The Seventh Seal and made the film very existential and thought-provoking. Allen pays close attention-to-detail in terms of character relations and how one person after another is presented here. He animates the Devil character (played by Billy Crystal) terrifically here, using the right amount of black humor and comic-timing. Deconstructing Harry is a cynical delight of a film making exceptional use of Allen's writing/directing talents, but also the immensity and diversity of the cast at hand. Each star, whether it be Kirstie Alley, Julia Louise-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Billy Crystal, or Robin Williams, gets their own time to shine in the picture and all of them feel welcome and completely in-place in Allen's darkly funny world. It's once again apparent that Allen can make deeply personal, intriguing pictures, yet still be so foreign to his audience as a whole. Starring: Woody Allen, Caroline Aaron, Kirstie Alley, Bob Balaban, Richard Benjamin, Eric Bogosian, Billy Crystal, Judy Davis, Hazelle Goodman, Mariel Hemingway, Amy Irving, Julie Kavner, Eric Lloyd, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Demi Moore, Elisabeth Shue, Stanley Tucci, and Robin Williams. Directed by: Woody Allen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry, understanding Woody ... and ourselves ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Deconstructing Harry" stands, in my opinion, as one of Woody Allen's best, probably his last masterpiece although it doesn't have the 'masterpiece' vibe. It looks like a typical Woody Allen movie but watch it closely and you'll get more insights about the director, the artist, ultimately the man. If you're not interested in, enjoy the gags and forget about it  if you can. I am more and more confident that Woody Allen is never as inspired and of course- hilarious as when his movies work as media to expresses his personal fears, angst and frustrations. And being capable to distort life, facts and reality to produce insights based on his own living, and in the intellectual and emotional process, to enable us to question ourselves, is in my opinion the work of a true artist. The film might feel 'minor' compared to other Allen's films but for some reason, it touched me, not immediately, but the ending was one of Allen's most triumphal achievements. Don't let yourself guided by your first feelings, this is not Allen wrapped up in his own ego, the film works on higher levels, and use Allen's own demons to tunnel us into ours, to use our empathy as a lightning torch to find truth in our personal darkness. Woody Allen is the titular Harry, Block is his last name, a fitting one as the writer he plays seems to suffer from mental block, the nightmare of every writer. But this block is justified by the series of incidents that undermined his inspiration. "Deconstructing Harry" is set during the aftermath of Harry's best-seller's success, a novel where he unveiled his most intimate secrets involving his friends, ex-wives, sister, family and acquaintances. It is one thing to reveal one's intimate secrets but we tend to forget that our secrets involve our personal circle. As a writer, Harry doesn't embarrass with such dilemmas, inspiration commands the writing and the others' anger is only a collateral damage he can afford but still must deal with. He tries to hide the names, to use lamentable pseudonyms, but behind every character, there's Harry. The film, like "Radio Days" is a succession of little vignettes, all reflecting a part of Harry's life, this is what the whole deconstruction process is about, in a masterstroke of writing. Whether it's a writer whose wife rediscovered her Jewish faith after the birth of her son, an old man indulging himself to cannibalism, a man cheating on his wife in front of an old blind parent, it's all about Harry, his friends are not fooled, neither are we. Is there a message behind that? Yes, every single piece of work of an artist is autobiographical. I'm tired of the whole: "Woody Allen always plays the same character" argument, because rather than a criticism, this is the best homage he can receive. But I would specify it a little bit, he doesn't play the same character, but within his whole oeuvre, there is one and only one Woody Allen. To understand the personality, one has to follow his evolution step by step, film by film. In "Interiors", the artist put his own inspiration into perspective, in "Stardust Memories", his comical talent or in "Zelig", his capability to please to be part of the mood.. In "Deconstructing Harry", it seems like the constantly self-deprecating Woody Allen is finally over with his own demons, because he comes to one realization, this is the best thing he can do, this is the only talent he truly has, and he's only exploiting it for the best. One of his friends, played by Billy Crystal, stole his girlfriend, but he acknowledges he doesn't have his talent. And yes, Allen is the best screenwriter. At the film's apotheosis, when all the characters he created applauded him, you can see the overwhelming effect on his eyes, and for one second, we imagine Woody Allen being applauded by Annie Hall, Virgil, Hannah and her Sisters thanking him for having graced the silver screen and pleased a generation of movie goers, for more than 20 years. Almost 20 years later, Woody Allen is still prolific but you could feel a relief after "Deconstructing Harry", when he could finally get to more fictional stuff, and telling stories again. I didn't speak much of the film because it's typically Allenian with a great cast, a deliberately disjointed editing, sometimes confusing but I guess it's a benign artistic license in order to convey the chaotic aspect of Harry's life as a sort of story he tries to rewrite inside himself, with the same process of writing, erasing, rewriting, copy-pasting etc. But what rises above the whole chaos, is the self-reflexive approach of Allen to his own work, he did it with "Interiors" and "Stardust Memories", but the films were inspired by Bergman and Fellini's works. I guess it took the revival of his comical genius in the 80's and the early 90's so he could understand that the best one to talk about Woody and to deconstruct Woody, is still Woody. And from someone who wishes to become a writer and can't function in the cold and average normality of life, I realize that I'm more inclined to bloom during writing, and stop being so out-of-focus, I should be the one to give people the right glasses to see what I'm worth. This out-of-focus metaphor is a strike of comical genius, and it touched a very sensitive chord. I loved "Deconstructing Harry" in a very deep and personal level and as I get older, I feel a very strong connection to the artistic and even neurotic personality of Woody Allen. To deconstruct Harry is to understand Woody, and ... a certain part of ourselves, imprisoned in a life of futile conventions and begging for expression, no matter how hard, and painful or shameful they are. I guess we should all learn to deconstruct ourselves to be over with our inner demons.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The love between writer and character.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Dennen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is, in my opinion, one of Woody Allen's most underrated films. Often overlooked by a careers' worth of other more well known work, this late 90's Drama plays out a relationship seldom looked at; the relationship between a writer and their intellectual property. The characters in this film act as friends and loved ones, or rather memories of friends and loved ones. It's a look inside the mind of a neurotic writer, a writer whose life is both hitting a professional peak, while simultaneously hitting a personal low. Harry Block (Woody Allen), is dealing with past demons as well as present hurdles, all while preparing to receive a major award. To help deal with this accumulation of problems, characters from his fictional stories seep into his reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Allen's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is a rare film that takes it's title in the most literal ways, both in structure and in storytelling. The plot centers around Harry Block (played as only Allen himself could), a man suffering from writer's block as he prepares to accept an award from his old university, but this is only a loose strain to give the story a narrative though. What it's really focused on is Harry himself, his mind and his characters. In the traditional Allen sense, we get some external monologuing as he explores the mind of this neurotic, stuck and seemingly hopeless man, but he does it in a way that I've never seen him work before. The style of comedy is of course that Allen allure that no one could imitate, but there's also a vulgarity to it that I've never seen him go for before. There are words that I never thought I'd see in a Woody Allen film and the jokes are incredibly graphic, but it gives it this sense of brutal honesty that I haven't experienced from him up to this point. It's absolutely hilarious and quite true, it felt comically in the same sense of Louis C.K.'s work; vulgar and borderline offensive, but totally true to the point where it makes it's audience take a long look in the mirror. As we explore Harry, his few friends and his many exes, we are treated to short vignettes taken from his previous written work. Allen explores the mind of a writer so thoroughly it's mesmerizing, giving us looks into how true the "you write what you know" expression is, with characters that are directly based on his past lovers and himself. Each short story is hilarious in it's own right, but also sheds more light into the character himself, which is the ultimate draw of the film. I've never liked a performance from the writer/director more than I have here. He's got the neurosis and cynicism that he is a master at, but there's also an authenticity and darkness to him that I felt was more exposed than I've seen him before. His editing work is a masterstroke as well as he depicts Harry's real life as fractured, making quick cuts in scenes so that nothing seems to be fluid but it gives it this stream-of-consciousness touch that becomes fluid in itself, in detailing what he wants to accomplish. When we see his work displayed, there's no fragmentation, no awkward cuts, everything runs smoothly. The final scene of the film states the themes a little too strongly, as he practically spoonfeeds them to the audience, but it's a brilliant display of how a writer can become so broken and fractured in his own life that the only way he can achieve any clarity is through his work. A dark, touching, hilarious film with a strong message. Plus, it opens with Julia Louis-Dreyfus getting bent over and plowed in front of a blind woman, and you don't get much funnier than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It's me thinly disguised in fact, I don't even think I should disguise it any more  it's me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is probably Woody Allen's most interesting and controversial film from his troubled 90s period. Coming at the height of turmoil in his personal life, the same year that Deconstructing Harry was released, Allen married Soon Yi Previn and the world was given an insight into their relationship in the rewarding documentary Wild Man Blues (6). Deconstructing Harry sees him slam reality and fiction together, giving (except for one exception) an expletive-free and free-flowing series of fantasy vignettes with jump- cut, foul-mouthed bites of reality. For this reason more than any other it's a film that could upset Allen purists, as his attempt to capture real life sees multiple uses of the word "f***" and even the "c" word coming from Woody's lips on two occasions. Is the film misogynist? Possibly. Woody certainly appears to have anger towards women here, and while the ladies of the night so romantically depicted in the likable-but-bland Mighty Aphrodite (6) are here "whores" and "hookers", there's also more than an element of racial patronage. The adjoinder from an African American prostitute over whether she knows what a black hole is ("Yeah... that's how I make my living") is probably the most repellent line in an Allen film, bar none. Even today Woody is still capable of making watchable films, but they're rarely essential and tend towards the reactionary. Little of his later period has come close to matching the vibrancy and sheer anxiety-based energy of Deconstructing Harry. This is Woody venting his spleen for the masses, and seeming to toy with the "playing himself" questions. It may not be pleasant to watch, but it's never dull. Again, his Jewish fixations can be offensive, though the scenes with his sister and brother-in-law are amongst the funniest in this not quite laugh-a-minute vehicle. I loved the bit where he tells his sister's husband: "I think you're the opposite of paranoid. I think you go around with the insane delusion that people like you". Yeah, most of the jokes at this stage in his career are recycled, but they're given a new take by the level of unsettling acidity contained in this picture. Annie Hall this isn't. The 1990s won't be remembered as a golden age for Allen's work, a period where he was getting more laughs voicing a cartoon ant than in his own movies. Altogether he wrote and directed ten new films, as well as a grating TV movie of his 60s play/film Don't Drink The Water (4). Films like Alice (5), Manhattan Murder Mystery (6) or Shadows and Fog (5) are watchable yet forgettable, the first decade for Allen where the so-so outnumbered the good. Yet there's still some first rate work in his 90s period, with Husbands and Wives (7) treading familiar ground but in subtle new ways. Sweet and Lowdown (7), a biopic of a fictitious jazz musician, brims with invention... though his first musical, Everyone Says I Love You (q.v.) sadly does not. Perhaps most notable in the 90s is the casting of actors to play the "Woody Allen" role, as he was entering his 60s and perhaps straining even his own much-tested formula of "young girl falls for older intellectual". In this regard then Kenneth Brannagh surprisingly does a better job than John Cusack, playing a substitute in the rewarding Celebrity (7), as opposed to Cusack's turn in the jarring Bullets Over Broadway (5). Which brings us back to Deconstructing Harry, as Allen originally had no wish to star in the lead. Deconstructing Harry isn't a pleasant film to watch by any means. It's crass, foul-mouthed and even obnoxious on occasion. But the fragmented, sketchy nature of events and inventive sequences make it an easier viewing experience than an extended narrative. Not only that, but in watching something which appears to be such a personal statement, then it may not be Allen's most likable or accomplished film, but it remains one of the most intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Allen's homage to (and send-up of) WILD STRAWBERRIES has its pluses and minuses. It's interesting, and in a way refreshing, to see him being so blatantly crass. It's one of his darkest movies, and maybe his most cynical comedy. Some of it is riotously funny, like the confrontation with Kirstie Alley in the middle of a patient's therapy session, or his version of Hell (with Billy Crystal in one of his most enjoyable roles). But with all the little sub-stories going on, it comes off like a clearinghouse for unfinished ideas. Also, the fragmented, jerky editing (because he's being "deconstructed," get it?) is an annoying quirk that adds little. Still, there's a lots of laughs to be had and it's an interesting bit of self-deprecation combined with self-admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good Woody Allen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block is a successful writer who gets inspiration from people he knows.Everybody doesn't like that.And he has his flaws, like pills and whores.Now his old university is honoring him.Harry wants to take his son Hilly to the ceremony, but his ex-wife Joan says no.But Harry takes him there anyway, as he does take a prostitute named Cookie and a friend called Richard.What a day to remember that will be! Deconstructing Harry is a Woody Allen film from 1997.Woody Allen gives a really great performance in this movie.Luckily he cast himself.No complaints about the rest of the cast either.Kirstie Alley plays the part of Joan, Harry's ex-wife.Billy Crystal, who gets to do next year's Oscars again, plays Larry/The Devil.Lucy Davis is Lucy.Bob Balaban plays Richard.Elisabeth Shue plays Fay.Paul Giamatti is Prof. Abbott.Philip Bosco is Prof. Clark.Mariel Hemingway, who was also in Allen's Manhattan, plays Beth Kramer.Hazelle Goodman is Cookie.Amy Irving is Jane.Eric Lloyd plays Hilly.Now 90-year old Gene Saks plays Harry's Father.Tony Sirico is Policeman at Jail.Then there are some characters that are of Harry's creation.Richard Benjamin plays Ken.Julia Louis-Dreyfus is Leslie.Tobey Maguire plays Harvey Stern.Jennifer Garner is Woman in Elevator.Stanley Tucci is Paul Epstein.Demi Moore plays Helen.Robin Williams is Mel.Julie Kavner is Grace.This is a very fine Woody Allen movie of the 90's.It's often funny.You find yourself most amused, when they're driving with the hooker and doing some car singing.Also out of focus Robin Williams is hilarious.I get seasick just by looking at him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harry is a writer, Block.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another all-star cast, another central role played by writer-director Woody Allen and another look at a character full of flaws and neuroses, we're in very familiar territory this time around. Allen plays Harry Block, a writer who is struggling for the first time in his life with writer's block and who is also tense about an upcoming honour he is to receive from his old school. As he tries to iron out the many wrinkles in his life and deal with his worries he finds himself encountering many of his literary creations (both fictional and in the form of the real, living people he based them upon) and getting advice from them along the way. The notion of the artist confronted by his creations and the consequences of his work is a good one and the weaving of the fantasy strands through the reality of the piece allows for a lot of fun (especially when comparing a fictional character to the real person they were based on) but this film, overall, just somehow misses the mark. The script isn't quite sharp enough, none of the performers get enough time to make a good impression and nothing feels as if it's actually moving a narrative along from start to finish. With a cast including Bob Balaban, Judy Davis, Billy Crystal, Robin Williams, Richard Benjamin, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Eric Bogosian, Kirstie Alley, Julie Kavner, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Tony Sirico, Demi Moore and Elisabeth Shue it's a real shame that nobody gets a chance to shine. Billy Crystal gets to have the most fun but Robin Williams stars in the most enjoyable fantasy sequence as an actor who one day suddenly goes out of focus. As others have said, this is worth seeing as a companion piece to Stardust Memories (with that being about the director and this being about the writer) but I just found myself watching long sections of the film without actually, properly enjoying it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Digging to the core; leave no stone unturned.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Mighty Aphrodite is a nice Woody Allen, then Deconstructing Harry is certainly the pinnacle of his nasty side. Indeed, for non-Woody Allen fans, it would seem difficult to understand how two vastly different films could come from the same mind. Yet, the genius of Allen lays primarily in his writing, able to create and expound upon a brilliant idea of the story of a man who is unable to cope the negative and horrible lifestyle he abides with the successful and insightful writing and art he creates fictionally. This is a difficult film to review as it unfolds itself in a very bipolar manner: cinematically it works on the highest scale with terrific acting, direction, editing and one of Woody's best scripts. Yet, on the other hand, it is quite possibly his meanest and most cynical portrait of humanity. The character of Harry Block (whom no one was willing to play until Allen finally took it himself) is incredibly neurotic, egotistical, nihilistic and narcissistic and Allen takes him to the very end of his rope, almost encouraging us to not feel any sympathy towards him at all. Certainly no one else does; his entire family hates him for the way he vaguely portrays them in his books as cheap stereotypes of their personalities and beliefs. Still, there may be the slightest bit of humanity within this ball of neuroses if only because Woody Allen gives one of his very best performances here. Again, I must praise the large and star-studded cast for carrying much of the heavy material, especially in scenes that would feel out of place in other hands. In particular, Judy Davis, Elisabeth Shue and Bob Balaban are very good. I must also give praise to Billy Crystal who personifies the devil himself in Harry's mind and is evilly funny. I guess this should be recommended but only for serious Woody Allen fans. It convincingly gives an argument for why and how Allen is able to rationalize all the crazy events he has gone through in his life. Personally, I cannot say that I always agree with his worldview. But, he always does have something interesting to say and if he can continue to say it through films like this, then I feel I will be able to sit through them. However, be warned: this is a side of Woody Allen never seen prior and hardly seen since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mixed Feelings...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick Cluxton
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been looking forward to seeing this film for quite a while, and when I finally had a chance I was pretty quick to take it up. As I started it, I regretted it immediately, I was bored and annoyed. Towards the end, it began to grow on me, but a lot just didn't do it for me. What I liked: I absolutely love the concept and the story. I have not seen any like it. What I like most is that while there is an actual plot and external events, it's more of a character study. They take an unlikable character and give him plenty of depth and sympathy to make up for his brash decisions and opinions. I love Woody Allen as a writer. I also liked the short stories; how they were narrated, the actual relevance they had to Harry's problems and friends, and how they were somewhat diverse. It wasn't just about the message. I both liked and disliked the scenes where they would cut to the same shot. It is very reminiscent of Jean- Loc Goddard's Breathless, which at times gave it a very relaxed, more realistic feel, considering that you could interpret that there were probably moments of silence between conversation, like something that happens in real conversation. However, when you cut in mid-sentence or make too many quick cuts, it's distracting and annoying to try and listen. What I hated: While I love that film is about Harry Block, I hated him. His guts, his obsession with sex, and the fact that he is so damn awkward. I hate Woody Allen as an actor. I appreciate when people stutter, pause, mix up words, or ramble in movies because that's what people do in real life. However, Woody Allen takes it and makes it absolutely obnoxious. His arms flail around, he never makes eye contact (or keeps his eyes on the road while driving). Overall, the word I would use to describe this movie is 'inconsistent,' with some scene being very funny and entertaining, while others made me want to scratch my DVD apart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing the indestructible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block (Woody Allen) is a neurotic, jittery, pill-popping author, condemned by those who known him well, and hailed by those who don't know him at all. Block has written lengthy, verbose novels that are thinly-disguised to hide the real relationships in his life, and for that reason, he has successfully alienated himself from all of his formers friends and family members. He often spends his days lonely, drinking, and hanging out with prostitutes, who he pays ample amounts of money to in order to get a quick-fix. The current silver-lining in Block's sad, dreary existence is that he will soon be recognized in a forthcoming ceremony by the university that kicked him out. He desperately wants company when he embarks on this trip, but because his novels have made it impossible for people to sympathize or like him on any level, he is left with quite a challenge. Even his ex-wife forbids him to spend the day with his young son so he can see his father may not be such a loser after all. Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is many things, but one of the most notable is it exists as an ode to the films of acclaimed Swedish director Ingmar Bergman. The film's plot alone mirrors that of Wild Strawberries, one of the man's most loved, which centered on a man and his pregnant daughter-in-law driving through the country so he could be granted with an award. The film made the tricky but probable analysis that a man can be loved by those who don't know him and simultaneously be hated by those who know him all too well. It was a tremendous achievement in foreign cinema and, in my opinion based on what I've seen thus far, Bergman's best film. Furthermore, this is one of Allen's darkest efforts to date. Not only is the film's protagonist almost remorseless in his treatment of others, but the way certain scenes are written and executed truly question how we're exactly supposed to respond. Take for example the scene when Block's panic attacks get the best of him and he needs to be consoled by a hooker he invited over the night before. While the relationship is nice - and without a doubt deeper than most prostitute/client relationships - it definitely shows just how depressing and almost broken Block's life is to the point where he needs to be reassured and comforted by a prostitute. The nihilism and cynicism of Allen's work shockingly doesn't become the detraction in the film, whereas the choppy narrative does and questionable ending does. The narrative, which continues to bounce between the current events in Block's life and the past events/relationships he held, is a bit too erratic and jumbled, quickly switching back and forth between the past and present with only a moderate amount of continuity. Not to mention the ending feels a bit put-on and unbelievable considering all that Block has put up with during the course of the film. Returning to the thought that the film is one giant homage to the works of Bergman, consider Allen's comically potent portrayal of the Devil here. Bergman made the Devil a living, breathing character in his film The Seventh Seal and made the film very existential and thought-provoking. Allen pays close attention-to-detail in terms of character relations and how one person after another is presented here. He animates the Devil character (played by Billy Crystal) terrifically here, using the right amount of black humor and comic-timing. Deconstructing Harry is a cynical delight of a film making exceptional use of Allen's writing/directing talents, but also the immensity and diversity of the cast at hand. Each star, whether it be Kirstie Alley, Julia Louise-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Billy Crystal, or Robin Williams, gets their own time to shine in the picture and all of them feel welcome and completely in-place in Allen's darkly funny world. It's once again apparent that Allen can make deeply personal, intriguing pictures, yet still be so foreign to his audience as a whole. Starring: Woody Allen, Caroline Aaron, Kirstie Alley, Bob Balaban, Richard Benjamin, Eric Bogosian, Billy Crystal, Judy Davis, Hazelle Goodman, Mariel Hemingway, Amy Irving, Julie Kavner, Eric Lloyd, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Demi Moore, Elisabeth Shue, Stanley Tucci, and Robin Williams. Directed by: Woody Allen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry, understanding Woody ... and ourselves ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Deconstructing Harry" stands, in my opinion, as one of Woody Allen's best, probably his last masterpiece although it doesn't have the 'masterpiece' vibe. It looks like a typical Woody Allen movie but watch it closely and you'll get more insights about the director, the artist, ultimately the man. If you're not interested in, enjoy the gags and forget about it  if you can. I am more and more confident that Woody Allen is never as inspired and of course- hilarious as when his movies work as media to expresses his personal fears, angst and frustrations. And being capable to distort life, facts and reality to produce insights based on his own living, and in the intellectual and emotional process, to enable us to question ourselves, is in my opinion the work of a true artist. The film might feel 'minor' compared to other Allen's films but for some reason, it touched me, not immediately, but the ending was one of Allen's most triumphal achievements. Don't let yourself guided by your first feelings, this is not Allen wrapped up in his own ego, the film works on higher levels, and use Allen's own demons to tunnel us into ours, to use our empathy as a lightning torch to find truth in our personal darkness. Woody Allen is the titular Harry, Block is his last name, a fitting one as the writer he plays seems to suffer from mental block, the nightmare of every writer. But this block is justified by the series of incidents that undermined his inspiration. "Deconstructing Harry" is set during the aftermath of Harry's best-seller's success, a novel where he unveiled his most intimate secrets involving his friends, ex-wives, sister, family and acquaintances. It is one thing to reveal one's intimate secrets but we tend to forget that our secrets involve our personal circle. As a writer, Harry doesn't embarrass with such dilemmas, inspiration commands the writing and the others' anger is only a collateral damage he can afford but still must deal with. He tries to hide the names, to use lamentable pseudonyms, but behind every character, there's Harry. The film, like "Radio Days" is a succession of little vignettes, all reflecting a part of Harry's life, this is what the whole deconstruction process is about, in a masterstroke of writing. Whether it's a writer whose wife rediscovered her Jewish faith after the birth of her son, an old man indulging himself to cannibalism, a man cheating on his wife in front of an old blind parent, it's all about Harry, his friends are not fooled, neither are we. Is there a message behind that? Yes, every single piece of work of an artist is autobiographical. I'm tired of the whole: "Woody Allen always plays the same character" argument, because rather than a criticism, this is the best homage he can receive. But I would specify it a little bit, he doesn't play the same character, but within his whole oeuvre, there is one and only one Woody Allen. To understand the personality, one has to follow his evolution step by step, film by film. In "Interiors", the artist put his own inspiration into perspective, in "Stardust Memories", his comical talent or in "Zelig", his capability to please to be part of the mood.. In "Deconstructing Harry", it seems like the constantly self-deprecating Woody Allen is finally over with his own demons, because he comes to one realization, this is the best thing he can do, this is the only talent he truly has, and he's only exploiting it for the best. One of his friends, played by Billy Crystal, stole his girlfriend, but he acknowledges he doesn't have his talent. And yes, Allen is the best screenwriter. At the film's apotheosis, when all the characters he created applauded him, you can see the overwhelming effect on his eyes, and for one second, we imagine Woody Allen being applauded by Annie Hall, Virgil, Hannah and her Sisters thanking him for having graced the silver screen and pleased a generation of movie goers, for more than 20 years. Almost 20 years later, Woody Allen is still prolific but you could feel a relief after "Deconstructing Harry", when he could finally get to more fictional stuff, and telling stories again. I didn't speak much of the film because it's typically Allenian with a great cast, a deliberately disjointed editing, sometimes confusing but I guess it's a benign artistic license in order to convey the chaotic aspect of Harry's life as a sort of story he tries to rewrite inside himself, with the same process of writing, erasing, rewriting, copy-pasting etc. But what rises above the whole chaos, is the self-reflexive approach of Allen to his own work, he did it with "Interiors" and "Stardust Memories", but the films were inspired by Bergman and Fellini's works. I guess it took the revival of his comical genius in the 80's and the early 90's so he could understand that the best one to talk about Woody and to deconstruct Woody, is still Woody. And from someone who wishes to become a writer and can't function in the cold and average normality of life, I realize that I'm more inclined to bloom during writing, and stop being so out-of-focus, I should be the one to give people the right glasses to see what I'm worth. This out-of-focus metaphor is a strike of comical genius, and it touched a very sensitive chord. I loved "Deconstructing Harry" in a very deep and personal level and as I get older, I feel a very strong connection to the artistic and even neurotic personality of Woody Allen. To deconstruct Harry is to understand Woody, and ... a certain part of ourselves, imprisoned in a life of futile conventions and begging for expression, no matter how hard, and painful or shameful they are. I guess we should all learn to deconstruct ourselves to be over with our inner demons.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The love between writer and character.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Dennen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is, in my opinion, one of Woody Allen's most underrated films. Often overlooked by a careers' worth of other more well known work, this late 90's Drama plays out a relationship seldom looked at; the relationship between a writer and their intellectual property. The characters in this film act as friends and loved ones, or rather memories of friends and loved ones. It's a look inside the mind of a neurotic writer, a writer whose life is both hitting a professional peak, while simultaneously hitting a personal low. Harry Block (Woody Allen), is dealing with past demons as well as present hurdles, all while preparing to receive a major award. To help deal with this accumulation of problems, characters from his fictional stories seep into his reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Allen's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is a rare film that takes it's title in the most literal ways, both in structure and in storytelling. The plot centers around Harry Block (played as only Allen himself could), a man suffering from writer's block as he prepares to accept an award from his old university, but this is only a loose strain to give the story a narrative though. What it's really focused on is Harry himself, his mind and his characters. In the traditional Allen sense, we get some external monologuing as he explores the mind of this neurotic, stuck and seemingly hopeless man, but he does it in a way that I've never seen him work before. The style of comedy is of course that Allen allure that no one could imitate, but there's also a vulgarity to it that I've never seen him go for before. There are words that I never thought I'd see in a Woody Allen film and the jokes are incredibly graphic, but it gives it this sense of brutal honesty that I haven't experienced from him up to this point. It's absolutely hilarious and quite true, it felt comically in the same sense of Louis C.K.'s work; vulgar and borderline offensive, but totally true to the point where it makes it's audience take a long look in the mirror. As we explore Harry, his few friends and his many exes, we are treated to short vignettes taken from his previous written work. Allen explores the mind of a writer so thoroughly it's mesmerizing, giving us looks into how true the "you write what you know" expression is, with characters that are directly based on his past lovers and himself. Each short story is hilarious in it's own right, but also sheds more light into the character himself, which is the ultimate draw of the film. I've never liked a performance from the writer/director more than I have here. He's got the neurosis and cynicism that he is a master at, but there's also an authenticity and darkness to him that I felt was more exposed than I've seen him before. His editing work is a masterstroke as well as he depicts Harry's real life as fractured, making quick cuts in scenes so that nothing seems to be fluid but it gives it this stream-of-consciousness touch that becomes fluid in itself, in detailing what he wants to accomplish. When we see his work displayed, there's no fragmentation, no awkward cuts, everything runs smoothly. The final scene of the film states the themes a little too strongly, as he practically spoonfeeds them to the audience, but it's a brilliant display of how a writer can become so broken and fractured in his own life that the only way he can achieve any clarity is through his work. A dark, touching, hilarious film with a strong message. Plus, it opens with Julia Louis-Dreyfus getting bent over and plowed in front of a blind woman, and you don't get much funnier than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It's me thinly disguised in fact, I don't even think I should disguise it any more  it's me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is probably Woody Allen's most interesting and controversial film from his troubled 90s period. Coming at the height of turmoil in his personal life, the same year that Deconstructing Harry was released, Allen married Soon Yi Previn and the world was given an insight into their relationship in the rewarding documentary Wild Man Blues (6). Deconstructing Harry sees him slam reality and fiction together, giving (except for one exception) an expletive-free and free-flowing series of fantasy vignettes with jump- cut, foul-mouthed bites of reality. For this reason more than any other it's a film that could upset Allen purists, as his attempt to capture real life sees multiple uses of the word "f***" and even the "c" word coming from Woody's lips on two occasions. Is the film misogynist? Possibly. Woody certainly appears to have anger towards women here, and while the ladies of the night so romantically depicted in the likable-but-bland Mighty Aphrodite (6) are here "whores" and "hookers", there's also more than an element of racial patronage. The adjoinder from an African American prostitute over whether she knows what a black hole is ("Yeah... that's how I make my living") is probably the most repellent line in an Allen film, bar none. Even today Woody is still capable of making watchable films, but they're rarely essential and tend towards the reactionary. Little of his later period has come close to matching the vibrancy and sheer anxiety-based energy of Deconstructing Harry. This is Woody venting his spleen for the masses, and seeming to toy with the "playing himself" questions. It may not be pleasant to watch, but it's never dull. Again, his Jewish fixations can be offensive, though the scenes with his sister and brother-in-law are amongst the funniest in this not quite laugh-a-minute vehicle. I loved the bit where he tells his sister's husband: "I think you're the opposite of paranoid. I think you go around with the insane delusion that people like you". Yeah, most of the jokes at this stage in his career are recycled, but they're given a new take by the level of unsettling acidity contained in this picture. Annie Hall this isn't. The 1990s won't be remembered as a golden age for Allen's work, a period where he was getting more laughs voicing a cartoon ant than in his own movies. Altogether he wrote and directed ten new films, as well as a grating TV movie of his 60s play/film Don't Drink The Water (4). Films like Alice (5), Manhattan Murder Mystery (6) or Shadows and Fog (5) are watchable yet forgettable, the first decade for Allen where the so-so outnumbered the good. Yet there's still some first rate work in his 90s period, with Husbands and Wives (7) treading familiar ground but in subtle new ways. Sweet and Lowdown (7), a biopic of a fictitious jazz musician, brims with invention... though his first musical, Everyone Says I Love You (q.v.) sadly does not. Perhaps most notable in the 90s is the casting of actors to play the "Woody Allen" role, as he was entering his 60s and perhaps straining even his own much-tested formula of "young girl falls for older intellectual". In this regard then Kenneth Brannagh surprisingly does a better job than John Cusack, playing a substitute in the rewarding Celebrity (7), as opposed to Cusack's turn in the jarring Bullets Over Broadway (5). Which brings us back to Deconstructing Harry, as Allen originally had no wish to star in the lead. Deconstructing Harry isn't a pleasant film to watch by any means. It's crass, foul-mouthed and even obnoxious on occasion. But the fragmented, sketchy nature of events and inventive sequences make it an easier viewing experience than an extended narrative. Not only that, but in watching something which appears to be such a personal statement, then it may not be Allen's most likable or accomplished film, but it remains one of the most intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Allen's homage to (and send-up of) WILD STRAWBERRIES has its pluses and minuses. It's interesting, and in a way refreshing, to see him being so blatantly crass. It's one of his darkest movies, and maybe his most cynical comedy. Some of it is riotously funny, like the confrontation with Kirstie Alley in the middle of a patient's therapy session, or his version of Hell (with Billy Crystal in one of his most enjoyable roles). But with all the little sub-stories going on, it comes off like a clearinghouse for unfinished ideas. Also, the fragmented, jerky editing (because he's being "deconstructed," get it?) is an annoying quirk that adds little. Still, there's a lots of laughs to be had and it's an interesting bit of self-deprecation combined with self-admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good Woody Allen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block is a successful writer who gets inspiration from people he knows.Everybody doesn't like that.And he has his flaws, like pills and whores.Now his old university is honoring him.Harry wants to take his son Hilly to the ceremony, but his ex-wife Joan says no.But Harry takes him there anyway, as he does take a prostitute named Cookie and a friend called Richard.What a day to remember that will be! Deconstructing Harry is a Woody Allen film from 1997.Woody Allen gives a really great performance in this movie.Luckily he cast himself.No complaints about the rest of the cast either.Kirstie Alley plays the part of Joan, Harry's ex-wife.Billy Crystal, who gets to do next year's Oscars again, plays Larry/The Devil.Lucy Davis is Lucy.Bob Balaban plays Richard.Elisabeth Shue plays Fay.Paul Giamatti is Prof. Abbott.Philip Bosco is Prof. Clark.Mariel Hemingway, who was also in Allen's Manhattan, plays Beth Kramer.Hazelle Goodman is Cookie.Amy Irving is Jane.Eric Lloyd plays Hilly.Now 90-year old Gene Saks plays Harry's Father.Tony Sirico is Policeman at Jail.Then there are some characters that are of Harry's creation.Richard Benjamin plays Ken.Julia Louis-Dreyfus is Leslie.Tobey Maguire plays Harvey Stern.Jennifer Garner is Woman in Elevator.Stanley Tucci is Paul Epstein.Demi Moore plays Helen.Robin Williams is Mel.Julie Kavner is Grace.This is a very fine Woody Allen movie of the 90's.It's often funny.You find yourself most amused, when they're driving with the hooker and doing some car singing.Also out of focus Robin Williams is hilarious.I get seasick just by looking at him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harry is a writer, Block.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another all-star cast, another central role played by writer-director Woody Allen and another look at a character full of flaws and neuroses, we're in very familiar territory this time around. Allen plays Harry Block, a writer who is struggling for the first time in his life with writer's block and who is also tense about an upcoming honour he is to receive from his old school. As he tries to iron out the many wrinkles in his life and deal with his worries he finds himself encountering many of his literary creations (both fictional and in the form of the real, living people he based them upon) and getting advice from them along the way. The notion of the artist confronted by his creations and the consequences of his work is a good one and the weaving of the fantasy strands through the reality of the piece allows for a lot of fun (especially when comparing a fictional character to the real person they were based on) but this film, overall, just somehow misses the mark. The script isn't quite sharp enough, none of the performers get enough time to make a good impression and nothing feels as if it's actually moving a narrative along from start to finish. With a cast including Bob Balaban, Judy Davis, Billy Crystal, Robin Williams, Richard Benjamin, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Eric Bogosian, Kirstie Alley, Julie Kavner, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Tony Sirico, Demi Moore and Elisabeth Shue it's a real shame that nobody gets a chance to shine. Billy Crystal gets to have the most fun but Robin Williams stars in the most enjoyable fantasy sequence as an actor who one day suddenly goes out of focus. As others have said, this is worth seeing as a companion piece to Stardust Memories (with that being about the director and this being about the writer) but I just found myself watching long sections of the film without actually, properly enjoying it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Digging to the core; leave no stone unturned.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Mighty Aphrodite is a nice Woody Allen, then Deconstructing Harry is certainly the pinnacle of his nasty side. Indeed, for non-Woody Allen fans, it would seem difficult to understand how two vastly different films could come from the same mind. Yet, the genius of Allen lays primarily in his writing, able to create and expound upon a brilliant idea of the story of a man who is unable to cope the negative and horrible lifestyle he abides with the successful and insightful writing and art he creates fictionally. This is a difficult film to review as it unfolds itself in a very bipolar manner: cinematically it works on the highest scale with terrific acting, direction, editing and one of Woody's best scripts. Yet, on the other hand, it is quite possibly his meanest and most cynical portrait of humanity. The character of Harry Block (whom no one was willing to play until Allen finally took it himself) is incredibly neurotic, egotistical, nihilistic and narcissistic and Allen takes him to the very end of his rope, almost encouraging us to not feel any sympathy towards him at all. Certainly no one else does; his entire family hates him for the way he vaguely portrays them in his books as cheap stereotypes of their personalities and beliefs. Still, there may be the slightest bit of humanity within this ball of neuroses if only because Woody Allen gives one of his very best performances here. Again, I must praise the large and star-studded cast for carrying much of the heavy material, especially in scenes that would feel out of place in other hands. In particular, Judy Davis, Elisabeth Shue and Bob Balaban are very good. I must also give praise to Billy Crystal who personifies the devil himself in Harry's mind and is evilly funny. I guess this should be recommended but only for serious Woody Allen fans. It convincingly gives an argument for why and how Allen is able to rationalize all the crazy events he has gone through in his life. Personally, I cannot say that I always agree with his worldview. But, he always does have something interesting to say and if he can continue to say it through films like this, then I feel I will be able to sit through them. However, be warned: this is a side of Woody Allen never seen prior and hardly seen since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mixed Feelings...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick Cluxton
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been looking forward to seeing this film for quite a while, and when I finally had a chance I was pretty quick to take it up. As I started it, I regretted it immediately, I was bored and annoyed. Towards the end, it began to grow on me, but a lot just didn't do it for me. What I liked: I absolutely love the concept and the story. I have not seen any like it. What I like most is that while there is an actual plot and external events, it's more of a character study. They take an unlikable character and give him plenty of depth and sympathy to make up for his brash decisions and opinions. I love Woody Allen as a writer. I also liked the short stories; how they were narrated, the actual relevance they had to Harry's problems and friends, and how they were somewhat diverse. It wasn't just about the message. I both liked and disliked the scenes where they would cut to the same shot. It is very reminiscent of Jean- Loc Goddard's Breathless, which at times gave it a very relaxed, more realistic feel, considering that you could interpret that there were probably moments of silence between conversation, like something that happens in real conversation. However, when you cut in mid-sentence or make too many quick cuts, it's distracting and annoying to try and listen. What I hated: While I love that film is about Harry Block, I hated him. His guts, his obsession with sex, and the fact that he is so damn awkward. I hate Woody Allen as an actor. I appreciate when people stutter, pause, mix up words, or ramble in movies because that's what people do in real life. However, Woody Allen takes it and makes it absolutely obnoxious. His arms flail around, he never makes eye contact (or keeps his eyes on the road while driving). Overall, the word I would use to describe this movie is 'inconsistent,' with some scene being very funny and entertaining, while others made me want to scratch my DVD apart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing the indestructible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block (Woody Allen) is a neurotic, jittery, pill-popping author, condemned by those who known him well, and hailed by those who don't know him at all. Block has written lengthy, verbose novels that are thinly-disguised to hide the real relationships in his life, and for that reason, he has successfully alienated himself from all of his formers friends and family members. He often spends his days lonely, drinking, and hanging out with prostitutes, who he pays ample amounts of money to in order to get a quick-fix. The current silver-lining in Block's sad, dreary existence is that he will soon be recognized in a forthcoming ceremony by the university that kicked him out. He desperately wants company when he embarks on this trip, but because his novels have made it impossible for people to sympathize or like him on any level, he is left with quite a challenge. Even his ex-wife forbids him to spend the day with his young son so he can see his father may not be such a loser after all. Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is many things, but one of the most notable is it exists as an ode to the films of acclaimed Swedish director Ingmar Bergman. The film's plot alone mirrors that of Wild Strawberries, one of the man's most loved, which centered on a man and his pregnant daughter-in-law driving through the country so he could be granted with an award. The film made the tricky but probable analysis that a man can be loved by those who don't know him and simultaneously be hated by those who know him all too well. It was a tremendous achievement in foreign cinema and, in my opinion based on what I've seen thus far, Bergman's best film. Furthermore, this is one of Allen's darkest efforts to date. Not only is the film's protagonist almost remorseless in his treatment of others, but the way certain scenes are written and executed truly question how we're exactly supposed to respond. Take for example the scene when Block's panic attacks get the best of him and he needs to be consoled by a hooker he invited over the night before. While the relationship is nice - and without a doubt deeper than most prostitute/client relationships - it definitely shows just how depressing and almost broken Block's life is to the point where he needs to be reassured and comforted by a prostitute. The nihilism and cynicism of Allen's work shockingly doesn't become the detraction in the film, whereas the choppy narrative does and questionable ending does. The narrative, which continues to bounce between the current events in Block's life and the past events/relationships he held, is a bit too erratic and jumbled, quickly switching back and forth between the past and present with only a moderate amount of continuity. Not to mention the ending feels a bit put-on and unbelievable considering all that Block has put up with during the course of the film. Returning to the thought that the film is one giant homage to the works of Bergman, consider Allen's comically potent portrayal of the Devil here. Bergman made the Devil a living, breathing character in his film The Seventh Seal and made the film very existential and thought-provoking. Allen pays close attention-to-detail in terms of character relations and how one person after another is presented here. He animates the Devil character (played by Billy Crystal) terrifically here, using the right amount of black humor and comic-timing. Deconstructing Harry is a cynical delight of a film making exceptional use of Allen's writing/directing talents, but also the immensity and diversity of the cast at hand. Each star, whether it be Kirstie Alley, Julia Louise-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Billy Crystal, or Robin Williams, gets their own time to shine in the picture and all of them feel welcome and completely in-place in Allen's darkly funny world. It's once again apparent that Allen can make deeply personal, intriguing pictures, yet still be so foreign to his audience as a whole. Starring: Woody Allen, Caroline Aaron, Kirstie Alley, Bob Balaban, Richard Benjamin, Eric Bogosian, Billy Crystal, Judy Davis, Hazelle Goodman, Mariel Hemingway, Amy Irving, Julie Kavner, Eric Lloyd, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Demi Moore, Elisabeth Shue, Stanley Tucci, and Robin Williams. Directed by: Woody Allen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry, understanding Woody ... and ourselves ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Deconstructing Harry" stands, in my opinion, as one of Woody Allen's best, probably his last masterpiece although it doesn't have the 'masterpiece' vibe. It looks like a typical Woody Allen movie but watch it closely and you'll get more insights about the director, the artist, ultimately the man. If you're not interested in, enjoy the gags and forget about it  if you can. I am more and more confident that Woody Allen is never as inspired and of course- hilarious as when his movies work as media to expresses his personal fears, angst and frustrations. And being capable to distort life, facts and reality to produce insights based on his own living, and in the intellectual and emotional process, to enable us to question ourselves, is in my opinion the work of a true artist. The film might feel 'minor' compared to other Allen's films but for some reason, it touched me, not immediately, but the ending was one of Allen's most triumphal achievements. Don't let yourself guided by your first feelings, this is not Allen wrapped up in his own ego, the film works on higher levels, and use Allen's own demons to tunnel us into ours, to use our empathy as a lightning torch to find truth in our personal darkness. Woody Allen is the titular Harry, Block is his last name, a fitting one as the writer he plays seems to suffer from mental block, the nightmare of every writer. But this block is justified by the series of incidents that undermined his inspiration. "Deconstructing Harry" is set during the aftermath of Harry's best-seller's success, a novel where he unveiled his most intimate secrets involving his friends, ex-wives, sister, family and acquaintances. It is one thing to reveal one's intimate secrets but we tend to forget that our secrets involve our personal circle. As a writer, Harry doesn't embarrass with such dilemmas, inspiration commands the writing and the others' anger is only a collateral damage he can afford but still must deal with. He tries to hide the names, to use lamentable pseudonyms, but behind every character, there's Harry. The film, like "Radio Days" is a succession of little vignettes, all reflecting a part of Harry's life, this is what the whole deconstruction process is about, in a masterstroke of writing. Whether it's a writer whose wife rediscovered her Jewish faith after the birth of her son, an old man indulging himself to cannibalism, a man cheating on his wife in front of an old blind parent, it's all about Harry, his friends are not fooled, neither are we. Is there a message behind that? Yes, every single piece of work of an artist is autobiographical. I'm tired of the whole: "Woody Allen always plays the same character" argument, because rather than a criticism, this is the best homage he can receive. But I would specify it a little bit, he doesn't play the same character, but within his whole oeuvre, there is one and only one Woody Allen. To understand the personality, one has to follow his evolution step by step, film by film. In "Interiors", the artist put his own inspiration into perspective, in "Stardust Memories", his comical talent or in "Zelig", his capability to please to be part of the mood.. In "Deconstructing Harry", it seems like the constantly self-deprecating Woody Allen is finally over with his own demons, because he comes to one realization, this is the best thing he can do, this is the only talent he truly has, and he's only exploiting it for the best. One of his friends, played by Billy Crystal, stole his girlfriend, but he acknowledges he doesn't have his talent. And yes, Allen is the best screenwriter. At the film's apotheosis, when all the characters he created applauded him, you can see the overwhelming effect on his eyes, and for one second, we imagine Woody Allen being applauded by Annie Hall, Virgil, Hannah and her Sisters thanking him for having graced the silver screen and pleased a generation of movie goers, for more than 20 years. Almost 20 years later, Woody Allen is still prolific but you could feel a relief after "Deconstructing Harry", when he could finally get to more fictional stuff, and telling stories again. I didn't speak much of the film because it's typically Allenian with a great cast, a deliberately disjointed editing, sometimes confusing but I guess it's a benign artistic license in order to convey the chaotic aspect of Harry's life as a sort of story he tries to rewrite inside himself, with the same process of writing, erasing, rewriting, copy-pasting etc. But what rises above the whole chaos, is the self-reflexive approach of Allen to his own work, he did it with "Interiors" and "Stardust Memories", but the films were inspired by Bergman and Fellini's works. I guess it took the revival of his comical genius in the 80's and the early 90's so he could understand that the best one to talk about Woody and to deconstruct Woody, is still Woody. And from someone who wishes to become a writer and can't function in the cold and average normality of life, I realize that I'm more inclined to bloom during writing, and stop being so out-of-focus, I should be the one to give people the right glasses to see what I'm worth. This out-of-focus metaphor is a strike of comical genius, and it touched a very sensitive chord. I loved "Deconstructing Harry" in a very deep and personal level and as I get older, I feel a very strong connection to the artistic and even neurotic personality of Woody Allen. To deconstruct Harry is to understand Woody, and ... a certain part of ourselves, imprisoned in a life of futile conventions and begging for expression, no matter how hard, and painful or shameful they are. I guess we should all learn to deconstruct ourselves to be over with our inner demons.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The love between writer and character.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Dennen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is, in my opinion, one of Woody Allen's most underrated films. Often overlooked by a careers' worth of other more well known work, this late 90's Drama plays out a relationship seldom looked at; the relationship between a writer and their intellectual property. The characters in this film act as friends and loved ones, or rather memories of friends and loved ones. It's a look inside the mind of a neurotic writer, a writer whose life is both hitting a professional peak, while simultaneously hitting a personal low. Harry Block (Woody Allen), is dealing with past demons as well as present hurdles, all while preparing to receive a major award. To help deal with this accumulation of problems, characters from his fictional stories seep into his reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Allen's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is a rare film that takes it's title in the most literal ways, both in structure and in storytelling. The plot centers around Harry Block (played as only Allen himself could), a man suffering from writer's block as he prepares to accept an award from his old university, but this is only a loose strain to give the story a narrative though. What it's really focused on is Harry himself, his mind and his characters. In the traditional Allen sense, we get some external monologuing as he explores the mind of this neurotic, stuck and seemingly hopeless man, but he does it in a way that I've never seen him work before. The style of comedy is of course that Allen allure that no one could imitate, but there's also a vulgarity to it that I've never seen him go for before. There are words that I never thought I'd see in a Woody Allen film and the jokes are incredibly graphic, but it gives it this sense of brutal honesty that I haven't experienced from him up to this point. It's absolutely hilarious and quite true, it felt comically in the same sense of Louis C.K.'s work; vulgar and borderline offensive, but totally true to the point where it makes it's audience take a long look in the mirror. As we explore Harry, his few friends and his many exes, we are treated to short vignettes taken from his previous written work. Allen explores the mind of a writer so thoroughly it's mesmerizing, giving us looks into how true the "you write what you know" expression is, with characters that are directly based on his past lovers and himself. Each short story is hilarious in it's own right, but also sheds more light into the character himself, which is the ultimate draw of the film. I've never liked a performance from the writer/director more than I have here. He's got the neurosis and cynicism that he is a master at, but there's also an authenticity and darkness to him that I felt was more exposed than I've seen him before. His editing work is a masterstroke as well as he depicts Harry's real life as fractured, making quick cuts in scenes so that nothing seems to be fluid but it gives it this stream-of-consciousness touch that becomes fluid in itself, in detailing what he wants to accomplish. When we see his work displayed, there's no fragmentation, no awkward cuts, everything runs smoothly. The final scene of the film states the themes a little too strongly, as he practically spoonfeeds them to the audience, but it's a brilliant display of how a writer can become so broken and fractured in his own life that the only way he can achieve any clarity is through his work. A dark, touching, hilarious film with a strong message. Plus, it opens with Julia Louis-Dreyfus getting bent over and plowed in front of a blind woman, and you don't get much funnier than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It's me thinly disguised in fact, I don't even think I should disguise it any more  it's me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is probably Woody Allen's most interesting and controversial film from his troubled 90s period. Coming at the height of turmoil in his personal life, the same year that Deconstructing Harry was released, Allen married Soon Yi Previn and the world was given an insight into their relationship in the rewarding documentary Wild Man Blues (6). Deconstructing Harry sees him slam reality and fiction together, giving (except for one exception) an expletive-free and free-flowing series of fantasy vignettes with jump- cut, foul-mouthed bites of reality. For this reason more than any other it's a film that could upset Allen purists, as his attempt to capture real life sees multiple uses of the word "f***" and even the "c" word coming from Woody's lips on two occasions. Is the film misogynist? Possibly. Woody certainly appears to have anger towards women here, and while the ladies of the night so romantically depicted in the likable-but-bland Mighty Aphrodite (6) are here "whores" and "hookers", there's also more than an element of racial patronage. The adjoinder from an African American prostitute over whether she knows what a black hole is ("Yeah... that's how I make my living") is probably the most repellent line in an Allen film, bar none. Even today Woody is still capable of making watchable films, but they're rarely essential and tend towards the reactionary. Little of his later period has come close to matching the vibrancy and sheer anxiety-based energy of Deconstructing Harry. This is Woody venting his spleen for the masses, and seeming to toy with the "playing himself" questions. It may not be pleasant to watch, but it's never dull. Again, his Jewish fixations can be offensive, though the scenes with his sister and brother-in-law are amongst the funniest in this not quite laugh-a-minute vehicle. I loved the bit where he tells his sister's husband: "I think you're the opposite of paranoid. I think you go around with the insane delusion that people like you". Yeah, most of the jokes at this stage in his career are recycled, but they're given a new take by the level of unsettling acidity contained in this picture. Annie Hall this isn't. The 1990s won't be remembered as a golden age for Allen's work, a period where he was getting more laughs voicing a cartoon ant than in his own movies. Altogether he wrote and directed ten new films, as well as a grating TV movie of his 60s play/film Don't Drink The Water (4). Films like Alice (5), Manhattan Murder Mystery (6) or Shadows and Fog (5) are watchable yet forgettable, the first decade for Allen where the so-so outnumbered the good. Yet there's still some first rate work in his 90s period, with Husbands and Wives (7) treading familiar ground but in subtle new ways. Sweet and Lowdown (7), a biopic of a fictitious jazz musician, brims with invention... though his first musical, Everyone Says I Love You (q.v.) sadly does not. Perhaps most notable in the 90s is the casting of actors to play the "Woody Allen" role, as he was entering his 60s and perhaps straining even his own much-tested formula of "young girl falls for older intellectual". In this regard then Kenneth Brannagh surprisingly does a better job than John Cusack, playing a substitute in the rewarding Celebrity (7), as opposed to Cusack's turn in the jarring Bullets Over Broadway (5). Which brings us back to Deconstructing Harry, as Allen originally had no wish to star in the lead. Deconstructing Harry isn't a pleasant film to watch by any means. It's crass, foul-mouthed and even obnoxious on occasion. But the fragmented, sketchy nature of events and inventive sequences make it an easier viewing experience than an extended narrative. Not only that, but in watching something which appears to be such a personal statement, then it may not be Allen's most likable or accomplished film, but it remains one of the most intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Allen's homage to (and send-up of) WILD STRAWBERRIES has its pluses and minuses. It's interesting, and in a way refreshing, to see him being so blatantly crass. It's one of his darkest movies, and maybe his most cynical comedy. Some of it is riotously funny, like the confrontation with Kirstie Alley in the middle of a patient's therapy session, or his version of Hell (with Billy Crystal in one of his most enjoyable roles). But with all the little sub-stories going on, it comes off like a clearinghouse for unfinished ideas. Also, the fragmented, jerky editing (because he's being "deconstructed," get it?) is an annoying quirk that adds little. Still, there's a lots of laughs to be had and it's an interesting bit of self-deprecation combined with self-admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good Woody Allen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block is a successful writer who gets inspiration from people he knows.Everybody doesn't like that.And he has his flaws, like pills and whores.Now his old university is honoring him.Harry wants to take his son Hilly to the ceremony, but his ex-wife Joan says no.But Harry takes him there anyway, as he does take a prostitute named Cookie and a friend called Richard.What a day to remember that will be! Deconstructing Harry is a Woody Allen film from 1997.Woody Allen gives a really great performance in this movie.Luckily he cast himself.No complaints about the rest of the cast either.Kirstie Alley plays the part of Joan, Harry's ex-wife.Billy Crystal, who gets to do next year's Oscars again, plays Larry/The Devil.Lucy Davis is Lucy.Bob Balaban plays Richard.Elisabeth Shue plays Fay.Paul Giamatti is Prof. Abbott.Philip Bosco is Prof. Clark.Mariel Hemingway, who was also in Allen's Manhattan, plays Beth Kramer.Hazelle Goodman is Cookie.Amy Irving is Jane.Eric Lloyd plays Hilly.Now 90-year old Gene Saks plays Harry's Father.Tony Sirico is Policeman at Jail.Then there are some characters that are of Harry's creation.Richard Benjamin plays Ken.Julia Louis-Dreyfus is Leslie.Tobey Maguire plays Harvey Stern.Jennifer Garner is Woman in Elevator.Stanley Tucci is Paul Epstein.Demi Moore plays Helen.Robin Williams is Mel.Julie Kavner is Grace.This is a very fine Woody Allen movie of the 90's.It's often funny.You find yourself most amused, when they're driving with the hooker and doing some car singing.Also out of focus Robin Williams is hilarious.I get seasick just by looking at him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harry is a writer, Block.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another all-star cast, another central role played by writer-director Woody Allen and another look at a character full of flaws and neuroses, we're in very familiar territory this time around. Allen plays Harry Block, a writer who is struggling for the first time in his life with writer's block and who is also tense about an upcoming honour he is to receive from his old school. As he tries to iron out the many wrinkles in his life and deal with his worries he finds himself encountering many of his literary creations (both fictional and in the form of the real, living people he based them upon) and getting advice from them along the way. The notion of the artist confronted by his creations and the consequences of his work is a good one and the weaving of the fantasy strands through the reality of the piece allows for a lot of fun (especially when comparing a fictional character to the real person they were based on) but this film, overall, just somehow misses the mark. The script isn't quite sharp enough, none of the performers get enough time to make a good impression and nothing feels as if it's actually moving a narrative along from start to finish. With a cast including Bob Balaban, Judy Davis, Billy Crystal, Robin Williams, Richard Benjamin, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Eric Bogosian, Kirstie Alley, Julie Kavner, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Tony Sirico, Demi Moore and Elisabeth Shue it's a real shame that nobody gets a chance to shine. Billy Crystal gets to have the most fun but Robin Williams stars in the most enjoyable fantasy sequence as an actor who one day suddenly goes out of focus. As others have said, this is worth seeing as a companion piece to Stardust Memories (with that being about the director and this being about the writer) but I just found myself watching long sections of the film without actually, properly enjoying it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Digging to the core; leave no stone unturned.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Mighty Aphrodite is a nice Woody Allen, then Deconstructing Harry is certainly the pinnacle of his nasty side. Indeed, for non-Woody Allen fans, it would seem difficult to understand how two vastly different films could come from the same mind. Yet, the genius of Allen lays primarily in his writing, able to create and expound upon a brilliant idea of the story of a man who is unable to cope the negative and horrible lifestyle he abides with the successful and insightful writing and art he creates fictionally. This is a difficult film to review as it unfolds itself in a very bipolar manner: cinematically it works on the highest scale with terrific acting, direction, editing and one of Woody's best scripts. Yet, on the other hand, it is quite possibly his meanest and most cynical portrait of humanity. The character of Harry Block (whom no one was willing to play until Allen finally took it himself) is incredibly neurotic, egotistical, nihilistic and narcissistic and Allen takes him to the very end of his rope, almost encouraging us to not feel any sympathy towards him at all. Certainly no one else does; his entire family hates him for the way he vaguely portrays them in his books as cheap stereotypes of their personalities and beliefs. Still, there may be the slightest bit of humanity within this ball of neuroses if only because Woody Allen gives one of his very best performances here. Again, I must praise the large and star-studded cast for carrying much of the heavy material, especially in scenes that would feel out of place in other hands. In particular, Judy Davis, Elisabeth Shue and Bob Balaban are very good. I must also give praise to Billy Crystal who personifies the devil himself in Harry's mind and is evilly funny. I guess this should be recommended but only for serious Woody Allen fans. It convincingly gives an argument for why and how Allen is able to rationalize all the crazy events he has gone through in his life. Personally, I cannot say that I always agree with his worldview. But, he always does have something interesting to say and if he can continue to say it through films like this, then I feel I will be able to sit through them. However, be warned: this is a side of Woody Allen never seen prior and hardly seen since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mixed Feelings...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick Cluxton
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been looking forward to seeing this film for quite a while, and when I finally had a chance I was pretty quick to take it up. As I started it, I regretted it immediately, I was bored and annoyed. Towards the end, it began to grow on me, but a lot just didn't do it for me. What I liked: I absolutely love the concept and the story. I have not seen any like it. What I like most is that while there is an actual plot and external events, it's more of a character study. They take an unlikable character and give him plenty of depth and sympathy to make up for his brash decisions and opinions. I love Woody Allen as a writer. I also liked the short stories; how they were narrated, the actual relevance they had to Harry's problems and friends, and how they were somewhat diverse. It wasn't just about the message. I both liked and disliked the scenes where they would cut to the same shot. It is very reminiscent of Jean- Loc Goddard's Breathless, which at times gave it a very relaxed, more realistic feel, considering that you could interpret that there were probably moments of silence between conversation, like something that happens in real conversation. However, when you cut in mid-sentence or make too many quick cuts, it's distracting and annoying to try and listen. What I hated: While I love that film is about Harry Block, I hated him. His guts, his obsession with sex, and the fact that he is so damn awkward. I hate Woody Allen as an actor. I appreciate when people stutter, pause, mix up words, or ramble in movies because that's what people do in real life. However, Woody Allen takes it and makes it absolutely obnoxious. His arms flail around, he never makes eye contact (or keeps his eyes on the road while driving). Overall, the word I would use to describe this movie is 'inconsistent,' with some scene being very funny and entertaining, while others made me want to scratch my DVD apart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing the indestructible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block (Woody Allen) is a neurotic, jittery, pill-popping author, condemned by those who known him well, and hailed by those who don't know him at all. Block has written lengthy, verbose novels that are thinly-disguised to hide the real relationships in his life, and for that reason, he has successfully alienated himself from all of his formers friends and family members. He often spends his days lonely, drinking, and hanging out with prostitutes, who he pays ample amounts of money to in order to get a quick-fix. The current silver-lining in Block's sad, dreary existence is that he will soon be recognized in a forthcoming ceremony by the university that kicked him out. He desperately wants company when he embarks on this trip, but because his novels have made it impossible for people to sympathize or like him on any level, he is left with quite a challenge. Even his ex-wife forbids him to spend the day with his young son so he can see his father may not be such a loser after all. Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is many things, but one of the most notable is it exists as an ode to the films of acclaimed Swedish director Ingmar Bergman. The film's plot alone mirrors that of Wild Strawberries, one of the man's most loved, which centered on a man and his pregnant daughter-in-law driving through the country so he could be granted with an award. The film made the tricky but probable analysis that a man can be loved by those who don't know him and simultaneously be hated by those who know him all too well. It was a tremendous achievement in foreign cinema and, in my opinion based on what I've seen thus far, Bergman's best film. Furthermore, this is one of Allen's darkest efforts to date. Not only is the film's protagonist almost remorseless in his treatment of others, but the way certain scenes are written and executed truly question how we're exactly supposed to respond. Take for example the scene when Block's panic attacks get the best of him and he needs to be consoled by a hooker he invited over the night before. While the relationship is nice - and without a doubt deeper than most prostitute/client relationships - it definitely shows just how depressing and almost broken Block's life is to the point where he needs to be reassured and comforted by a prostitute. The nihilism and cynicism of Allen's work shockingly doesn't become the detraction in the film, whereas the choppy narrative does and questionable ending does. The narrative, which continues to bounce between the current events in Block's life and the past events/relationships he held, is a bit too erratic and jumbled, quickly switching back and forth between the past and present with only a moderate amount of continuity. Not to mention the ending feels a bit put-on and unbelievable considering all that Block has put up with during the course of the film. Returning to the thought that the film is one giant homage to the works of Bergman, consider Allen's comically potent portrayal of the Devil here. Bergman made the Devil a living, breathing character in his film The Seventh Seal and made the film very existential and thought-provoking. Allen pays close attention-to-detail in terms of character relations and how one person after another is presented here. He animates the Devil character (played by Billy Crystal) terrifically here, using the right amount of black humor and comic-timing. Deconstructing Harry is a cynical delight of a film making exceptional use of Allen's writing/directing talents, but also the immensity and diversity of the cast at hand. Each star, whether it be Kirstie Alley, Julia Louise-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Billy Crystal, or Robin Williams, gets their own time to shine in the picture and all of them feel welcome and completely in-place in Allen's darkly funny world. It's once again apparent that Allen can make deeply personal, intriguing pictures, yet still be so foreign to his audience as a whole. Starring: Woody Allen, Caroline Aaron, Kirstie Alley, Bob Balaban, Richard Benjamin, Eric Bogosian, Billy Crystal, Judy Davis, Hazelle Goodman, Mariel Hemingway, Amy Irving, Julie Kavner, Eric Lloyd, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Demi Moore, Elisabeth Shue, Stanley Tucci, and Robin Williams. Directed by: Woody Allen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry, understanding Woody ... and ourselves ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Deconstructing Harry" stands, in my opinion, as one of Woody Allen's best, probably his last masterpiece although it doesn't have the 'masterpiece' vibe. It looks like a typical Woody Allen movie but watch it closely and you'll get more insights about the director, the artist, ultimately the man. If you're not interested in, enjoy the gags and forget about it  if you can. I am more and more confident that Woody Allen is never as inspired and of course- hilarious as when his movies work as media to expresses his personal fears, angst and frustrations. And being capable to distort life, facts and reality to produce insights based on his own living, and in the intellectual and emotional process, to enable us to question ourselves, is in my opinion the work of a true artist. The film might feel 'minor' compared to other Allen's films but for some reason, it touched me, not immediately, but the ending was one of Allen's most triumphal achievements. Don't let yourself guided by your first feelings, this is not Allen wrapped up in his own ego, the film works on higher levels, and use Allen's own demons to tunnel us into ours, to use our empathy as a lightning torch to find truth in our personal darkness. Woody Allen is the titular Harry, Block is his last name, a fitting one as the writer he plays seems to suffer from mental block, the nightmare of every writer. But this block is justified by the series of incidents that undermined his inspiration. "Deconstructing Harry" is set during the aftermath of Harry's best-seller's success, a novel where he unveiled his most intimate secrets involving his friends, ex-wives, sister, family and acquaintances. It is one thing to reveal one's intimate secrets but we tend to forget that our secrets involve our personal circle. As a writer, Harry doesn't embarrass with such dilemmas, inspiration commands the writing and the others' anger is only a collateral damage he can afford but still must deal with. He tries to hide the names, to use lamentable pseudonyms, but behind every character, there's Harry. The film, like "Radio Days" is a succession of little vignettes, all reflecting a part of Harry's life, this is what the whole deconstruction process is about, in a masterstroke of writing. Whether it's a writer whose wife rediscovered her Jewish faith after the birth of her son, an old man indulging himself to cannibalism, a man cheating on his wife in front of an old blind parent, it's all about Harry, his friends are not fooled, neither are we. Is there a message behind that? Yes, every single piece of work of an artist is autobiographical. I'm tired of the whole: "Woody Allen always plays the same character" argument, because rather than a criticism, this is the best homage he can receive. But I would specify it a little bit, he doesn't play the same character, but within his whole oeuvre, there is one and only one Woody Allen. To understand the personality, one has to follow his evolution step by step, film by film. In "Interiors", the artist put his own inspiration into perspective, in "Stardust Memories", his comical talent or in "Zelig", his capability to please to be part of the mood.. In "Deconstructing Harry", it seems like the constantly self-deprecating Woody Allen is finally over with his own demons, because he comes to one realization, this is the best thing he can do, this is the only talent he truly has, and he's only exploiting it for the best. One of his friends, played by Billy Crystal, stole his girlfriend, but he acknowledges he doesn't have his talent. And yes, Allen is the best screenwriter. At the film's apotheosis, when all the characters he created applauded him, you can see the overwhelming effect on his eyes, and for one second, we imagine Woody Allen being applauded by Annie Hall, Virgil, Hannah and her Sisters thanking him for having graced the silver screen and pleased a generation of movie goers, for more than 20 years. Almost 20 years later, Woody Allen is still prolific but you could feel a relief after "Deconstructing Harry", when he could finally get to more fictional stuff, and telling stories again. I didn't speak much of the film because it's typically Allenian with a great cast, a deliberately disjointed editing, sometimes confusing but I guess it's a benign artistic license in order to convey the chaotic aspect of Harry's life as a sort of story he tries to rewrite inside himself, with the same process of writing, erasing, rewriting, copy-pasting etc. But what rises above the whole chaos, is the self-reflexive approach of Allen to his own work, he did it with "Interiors" and "Stardust Memories", but the films were inspired by Bergman and Fellini's works. I guess it took the revival of his comical genius in the 80's and the early 90's so he could understand that the best one to talk about Woody and to deconstruct Woody, is still Woody. And from someone who wishes to become a writer and can't function in the cold and average normality of life, I realize that I'm more inclined to bloom during writing, and stop being so out-of-focus, I should be the one to give people the right glasses to see what I'm worth. This out-of-focus metaphor is a strike of comical genius, and it touched a very sensitive chord. I loved "Deconstructing Harry" in a very deep and personal level and as I get older, I feel a very strong connection to the artistic and even neurotic personality of Woody Allen. To deconstruct Harry is to understand Woody, and ... a certain part of ourselves, imprisoned in a life of futile conventions and begging for expression, no matter how hard, and painful or shameful they are. I guess we should all learn to deconstruct ourselves to be over with our inner demons.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The love between writer and character.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Dennen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is, in my opinion, one of Woody Allen's most underrated films. Often overlooked by a careers' worth of other more well known work, this late 90's Drama plays out a relationship seldom looked at; the relationship between a writer and their intellectual property. The characters in this film act as friends and loved ones, or rather memories of friends and loved ones. It's a look inside the mind of a neurotic writer, a writer whose life is both hitting a professional peak, while simultaneously hitting a personal low. Harry Block (Woody Allen), is dealing with past demons as well as present hurdles, all while preparing to receive a major award. To help deal with this accumulation of problems, characters from his fictional stories seep into his reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Allen's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is a rare film that takes it's title in the most literal ways, both in structure and in storytelling. The plot centers around Harry Block (played as only Allen himself could), a man suffering from writer's block as he prepares to accept an award from his old university, but this is only a loose strain to give the story a narrative though. What it's really focused on is Harry himself, his mind and his characters. In the traditional Allen sense, we get some external monologuing as he explores the mind of this neurotic, stuck and seemingly hopeless man, but he does it in a way that I've never seen him work before. The style of comedy is of course that Allen allure that no one could imitate, but there's also a vulgarity to it that I've never seen him go for before. There are words that I never thought I'd see in a Woody Allen film and the jokes are incredibly graphic, but it gives it this sense of brutal honesty that I haven't experienced from him up to this point. It's absolutely hilarious and quite true, it felt comically in the same sense of Louis C.K.'s work; vulgar and borderline offensive, but totally true to the point where it makes it's audience take a long look in the mirror. As we explore Harry, his few friends and his many exes, we are treated to short vignettes taken from his previous written work. Allen explores the mind of a writer so thoroughly it's mesmerizing, giving us looks into how true the "you write what you know" expression is, with characters that are directly based on his past lovers and himself. Each short story is hilarious in it's own right, but also sheds more light into the character himself, which is the ultimate draw of the film. I've never liked a performance from the writer/director more than I have here. He's got the neurosis and cynicism that he is a master at, but there's also an authenticity and darkness to him that I felt was more exposed than I've seen him before. His editing work is a masterstroke as well as he depicts Harry's real life as fractured, making quick cuts in scenes so that nothing seems to be fluid but it gives it this stream-of-consciousness touch that becomes fluid in itself, in detailing what he wants to accomplish. When we see his work displayed, there's no fragmentation, no awkward cuts, everything runs smoothly. The final scene of the film states the themes a little too strongly, as he practically spoonfeeds them to the audience, but it's a brilliant display of how a writer can become so broken and fractured in his own life that the only way he can achieve any clarity is through his work. A dark, touching, hilarious film with a strong message. Plus, it opens with Julia Louis-Dreyfus getting bent over and plowed in front of a blind woman, and you don't get much funnier than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It's me thinly disguised in fact, I don't even think I should disguise it any more  it's me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is probably Woody Allen's most interesting and controversial film from his troubled 90s period. Coming at the height of turmoil in his personal life, the same year that Deconstructing Harry was released, Allen married Soon Yi Previn and the world was given an insight into their relationship in the rewarding documentary Wild Man Blues (6). Deconstructing Harry sees him slam reality and fiction together, giving (except for one exception) an expletive-free and free-flowing series of fantasy vignettes with jump- cut, foul-mouthed bites of reality. For this reason more than any other it's a film that could upset Allen purists, as his attempt to capture real life sees multiple uses of the word "f***" and even the "c" word coming from Woody's lips on two occasions. Is the film misogynist? Possibly. Woody certainly appears to have anger towards women here, and while the ladies of the night so romantically depicted in the likable-but-bland Mighty Aphrodite (6) are here "whores" and "hookers", there's also more than an element of racial patronage. The adjoinder from an African American prostitute over whether she knows what a black hole is ("Yeah... that's how I make my living") is probably the most repellent line in an Allen film, bar none. Even today Woody is still capable of making watchable films, but they're rarely essential and tend towards the reactionary. Little of his later period has come close to matching the vibrancy and sheer anxiety-based energy of Deconstructing Harry. This is Woody venting his spleen for the masses, and seeming to toy with the "playing himself" questions. It may not be pleasant to watch, but it's never dull. Again, his Jewish fixations can be offensive, though the scenes with his sister and brother-in-law are amongst the funniest in this not quite laugh-a-minute vehicle. I loved the bit where he tells his sister's husband: "I think you're the opposite of paranoid. I think you go around with the insane delusion that people like you". Yeah, most of the jokes at this stage in his career are recycled, but they're given a new take by the level of unsettling acidity contained in this picture. Annie Hall this isn't. The 1990s won't be remembered as a golden age for Allen's work, a period where he was getting more laughs voicing a cartoon ant than in his own movies. Altogether he wrote and directed ten new films, as well as a grating TV movie of his 60s play/film Don't Drink The Water (4). Films like Alice (5), Manhattan Murder Mystery (6) or Shadows and Fog (5) are watchable yet forgettable, the first decade for Allen where the so-so outnumbered the good. Yet there's still some first rate work in his 90s period, with Husbands and Wives (7) treading familiar ground but in subtle new ways. Sweet and Lowdown (7), a biopic of a fictitious jazz musician, brims with invention... though his first musical, Everyone Says I Love You (q.v.) sadly does not. Perhaps most notable in the 90s is the casting of actors to play the "Woody Allen" role, as he was entering his 60s and perhaps straining even his own much-tested formula of "young girl falls for older intellectual". In this regard then Kenneth Brannagh surprisingly does a better job than John Cusack, playing a substitute in the rewarding Celebrity (7), as opposed to Cusack's turn in the jarring Bullets Over Broadway (5). Which brings us back to Deconstructing Harry, as Allen originally had no wish to star in the lead. Deconstructing Harry isn't a pleasant film to watch by any means. It's crass, foul-mouthed and even obnoxious on occasion. But the fragmented, sketchy nature of events and inventive sequences make it an easier viewing experience than an extended narrative. Not only that, but in watching something which appears to be such a personal statement, then it may not be Allen's most likable or accomplished film, but it remains one of the most intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Allen's homage to (and send-up of) WILD STRAWBERRIES has its pluses and minuses. It's interesting, and in a way refreshing, to see him being so blatantly crass. It's one of his darkest movies, and maybe his most cynical comedy. Some of it is riotously funny, like the confrontation with Kirstie Alley in the middle of a patient's therapy session, or his version of Hell (with Billy Crystal in one of his most enjoyable roles). But with all the little sub-stories going on, it comes off like a clearinghouse for unfinished ideas. Also, the fragmented, jerky editing (because he's being "deconstructed," get it?) is an annoying quirk that adds little. Still, there's a lots of laughs to be had and it's an interesting bit of self-deprecation combined with self-admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good Woody Allen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block is a successful writer who gets inspiration from people he knows.Everybody doesn't like that.And he has his flaws, like pills and whores.Now his old university is honoring him.Harry wants to take his son Hilly to the ceremony, but his ex-wife Joan says no.But Harry takes him there anyway, as he does take a prostitute named Cookie and a friend called Richard.What a day to remember that will be! Deconstructing Harry is a Woody Allen film from 1997.Woody Allen gives a really great performance in this movie.Luckily he cast himself.No complaints about the rest of the cast either.Kirstie Alley plays the part of Joan, Harry's ex-wife.Billy Crystal, who gets to do next year's Oscars again, plays Larry/The Devil.Lucy Davis is Lucy.Bob Balaban plays Richard.Elisabeth Shue plays Fay.Paul Giamatti is Prof. Abbott.Philip Bosco is Prof. Clark.Mariel Hemingway, who was also in Allen's Manhattan, plays Beth Kramer.Hazelle Goodman is Cookie.Amy Irving is Jane.Eric Lloyd plays Hilly.Now 90-year old Gene Saks plays Harry's Father.Tony Sirico is Policeman at Jail.Then there are some characters that are of Harry's creation.Richard Benjamin plays Ken.Julia Louis-Dreyfus is Leslie.Tobey Maguire plays Harvey Stern.Jennifer Garner is Woman in Elevator.Stanley Tucci is Paul Epstein.Demi Moore plays Helen.Robin Williams is Mel.Julie Kavner is Grace.This is a very fine Woody Allen movie of the 90's.It's often funny.You find yourself most amused, when they're driving with the hooker and doing some car singing.Also out of focus Robin Williams is hilarious.I get seasick just by looking at him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harry is a writer, Block.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another all-star cast, another central role played by writer-director Woody Allen and another look at a character full of flaws and neuroses, we're in very familiar territory this time around. Allen plays Harry Block, a writer who is struggling for the first time in his life with writer's block and who is also tense about an upcoming honour he is to receive from his old school. As he tries to iron out the many wrinkles in his life and deal with his worries he finds himself encountering many of his literary creations (both fictional and in the form of the real, living people he based them upon) and getting advice from them along the way. The notion of the artist confronted by his creations and the consequences of his work is a good one and the weaving of the fantasy strands through the reality of the piece allows for a lot of fun (especially when comparing a fictional character to the real person they were based on) but this film, overall, just somehow misses the mark. The script isn't quite sharp enough, none of the performers get enough time to make a good impression and nothing feels as if it's actually moving a narrative along from start to finish. With a cast including Bob Balaban, Judy Davis, Billy Crystal, Robin Williams, Richard Benjamin, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Eric Bogosian, Kirstie Alley, Julie Kavner, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Tony Sirico, Demi Moore and Elisabeth Shue it's a real shame that nobody gets a chance to shine. Billy Crystal gets to have the most fun but Robin Williams stars in the most enjoyable fantasy sequence as an actor who one day suddenly goes out of focus. As others have said, this is worth seeing as a companion piece to Stardust Memories (with that being about the director and this being about the writer) but I just found myself watching long sections of the film without actually, properly enjoying it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Digging to the core; leave no stone unturned.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Mighty Aphrodite is a nice Woody Allen, then Deconstructing Harry is certainly the pinnacle of his nasty side. Indeed, for non-Woody Allen fans, it would seem difficult to understand how two vastly different films could come from the same mind. Yet, the genius of Allen lays primarily in his writing, able to create and expound upon a brilliant idea of the story of a man who is unable to cope the negative and horrible lifestyle he abides with the successful and insightful writing and art he creates fictionally. This is a difficult film to review as it unfolds itself in a very bipolar manner: cinematically it works on the highest scale with terrific acting, direction, editing and one of Woody's best scripts. Yet, on the other hand, it is quite possibly his meanest and most cynical portrait of humanity. The character of Harry Block (whom no one was willing to play until Allen finally took it himself) is incredibly neurotic, egotistical, nihilistic and narcissistic and Allen takes him to the very end of his rope, almost encouraging us to not feel any sympathy towards him at all. Certainly no one else does; his entire family hates him for the way he vaguely portrays them in his books as cheap stereotypes of their personalities and beliefs. Still, there may be the slightest bit of humanity within this ball of neuroses if only because Woody Allen gives one of his very best performances here. Again, I must praise the large and star-studded cast for carrying much of the heavy material, especially in scenes that would feel out of place in other hands. In particular, Judy Davis, Elisabeth Shue and Bob Balaban are very good. I must also give praise to Billy Crystal who personifies the devil himself in Harry's mind and is evilly funny. I guess this should be recommended but only for serious Woody Allen fans. It convincingly gives an argument for why and how Allen is able to rationalize all the crazy events he has gone through in his life. Personally, I cannot say that I always agree with his worldview. But, he always does have something interesting to say and if he can continue to say it through films like this, then I feel I will be able to sit through them. However, be warned: this is a side of Woody Allen never seen prior and hardly seen since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mixed Feelings...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick Cluxton
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been looking forward to seeing this film for quite a while, and when I finally had a chance I was pretty quick to take it up. As I started it, I regretted it immediately, I was bored and annoyed. Towards the end, it began to grow on me, but a lot just didn't do it for me. What I liked: I absolutely love the concept and the story. I have not seen any like it. What I like most is that while there is an actual plot and external events, it's more of a character study. They take an unlikable character and give him plenty of depth and sympathy to make up for his brash decisions and opinions. I love Woody Allen as a writer. I also liked the short stories; how they were narrated, the actual relevance they had to Harry's problems and friends, and how they were somewhat diverse. It wasn't just about the message. I both liked and disliked the scenes where they would cut to the same shot. It is very reminiscent of Jean- Loc Goddard's Breathless, which at times gave it a very relaxed, more realistic feel, considering that you could interpret that there were probably moments of silence between conversation, like something that happens in real conversation. However, when you cut in mid-sentence or make too many quick cuts, it's distracting and annoying to try and listen. What I hated: While I love that film is about Harry Block, I hated him. His guts, his obsession with sex, and the fact that he is so damn awkward. I hate Woody Allen as an actor. I appreciate when people stutter, pause, mix up words, or ramble in movies because that's what people do in real life. However, Woody Allen takes it and makes it absolutely obnoxious. His arms flail around, he never makes eye contact (or keeps his eyes on the road while driving). Overall, the word I would use to describe this movie is 'inconsistent,' with some scene being very funny and entertaining, while others made me want to scratch my DVD apart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing the indestructible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block (Woody Allen) is a neurotic, jittery, pill-popping author, condemned by those who known him well, and hailed by those who don't know him at all. Block has written lengthy, verbose novels that are thinly-disguised to hide the real relationships in his life, and for that reason, he has successfully alienated himself from all of his formers friends and family members. He often spends his days lonely, drinking, and hanging out with prostitutes, who he pays ample amounts of money to in order to get a quick-fix. The current silver-lining in Block's sad, dreary existence is that he will soon be recognized in a forthcoming ceremony by the university that kicked him out. He desperately wants company when he embarks on this trip, but because his novels have made it impossible for people to sympathize or like him on any level, he is left with quite a challenge. Even his ex-wife forbids him to spend the day with his young son so he can see his father may not be such a loser after all. Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is many things, but one of the most notable is it exists as an ode to the films of acclaimed Swedish director Ingmar Bergman. The film's plot alone mirrors that of Wild Strawberries, one of the man's most loved, which centered on a man and his pregnant daughter-in-law driving through the country so he could be granted with an award. The film made the tricky but probable analysis that a man can be loved by those who don't know him and simultaneously be hated by those who know him all too well. It was a tremendous achievement in foreign cinema and, in my opinion based on what I've seen thus far, Bergman's best film. Furthermore, this is one of Allen's darkest efforts to date. Not only is the film's protagonist almost remorseless in his treatment of others, but the way certain scenes are written and executed truly question how we're exactly supposed to respond. Take for example the scene when Block's panic attacks get the best of him and he needs to be consoled by a hooker he invited over the night before. While the relationship is nice - and without a doubt deeper than most prostitute/client relationships - it definitely shows just how depressing and almost broken Block's life is to the point where he needs to be reassured and comforted by a prostitute. The nihilism and cynicism of Allen's work shockingly doesn't become the detraction in the film, whereas the choppy narrative does and questionable ending does. The narrative, which continues to bounce between the current events in Block's life and the past events/relationships he held, is a bit too erratic and jumbled, quickly switching back and forth between the past and present with only a moderate amount of continuity. Not to mention the ending feels a bit put-on and unbelievable considering all that Block has put up with during the course of the film. Returning to the thought that the film is one giant homage to the works of Bergman, consider Allen's comically potent portrayal of the Devil here. Bergman made the Devil a living, breathing character in his film The Seventh Seal and made the film very existential and thought-provoking. Allen pays close attention-to-detail in terms of character relations and how one person after another is presented here. He animates the Devil character (played by Billy Crystal) terrifically here, using the right amount of black humor and comic-timing. Deconstructing Harry is a cynical delight of a film making exceptional use of Allen's writing/directing talents, but also the immensity and diversity of the cast at hand. Each star, whether it be Kirstie Alley, Julia Louise-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Billy Crystal, or Robin Williams, gets their own time to shine in the picture and all of them feel welcome and completely in-place in Allen's darkly funny world. It's once again apparent that Allen can make deeply personal, intriguing pictures, yet still be so foreign to his audience as a whole. Starring: Woody Allen, Caroline Aaron, Kirstie Alley, Bob Balaban, Richard Benjamin, Eric Bogosian, Billy Crystal, Judy Davis, Hazelle Goodman, Mariel Hemingway, Amy Irving, Julie Kavner, Eric Lloyd, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Demi Moore, Elisabeth Shue, Stanley Tucci, and Robin Williams. Directed by: Woody Allen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry, understanding Woody ... and ourselves ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Deconstructing Harry" stands, in my opinion, as one of Woody Allen's best, probably his last masterpiece although it doesn't have the 'masterpiece' vibe. It looks like a typical Woody Allen movie but watch it closely and you'll get more insights about the director, the artist, ultimately the man. If you're not interested in, enjoy the gags and forget about it  if you can. I am more and more confident that Woody Allen is never as inspired and of course- hilarious as when his movies work as media to expresses his personal fears, angst and frustrations. And being capable to distort life, facts and reality to produce insights based on his own living, and in the intellectual and emotional process, to enable us to question ourselves, is in my opinion the work of a true artist. The film might feel 'minor' compared to other Allen's films but for some reason, it touched me, not immediately, but the ending was one of Allen's most triumphal achievements. Don't let yourself guided by your first feelings, this is not Allen wrapped up in his own ego, the film works on higher levels, and use Allen's own demons to tunnel us into ours, to use our empathy as a lightning torch to find truth in our personal darkness. Woody Allen is the titular Harry, Block is his last name, a fitting one as the writer he plays seems to suffer from mental block, the nightmare of every writer. But this block is justified by the series of incidents that undermined his inspiration. "Deconstructing Harry" is set during the aftermath of Harry's best-seller's success, a novel where he unveiled his most intimate secrets involving his friends, ex-wives, sister, family and acquaintances. It is one thing to reveal one's intimate secrets but we tend to forget that our secrets involve our personal circle. As a writer, Harry doesn't embarrass with such dilemmas, inspiration commands the writing and the others' anger is only a collateral damage he can afford but still must deal with. He tries to hide the names, to use lamentable pseudonyms, but behind every character, there's Harry. The film, like "Radio Days" is a succession of little vignettes, all reflecting a part of Harry's life, this is what the whole deconstruction process is about, in a masterstroke of writing. Whether it's a writer whose wife rediscovered her Jewish faith after the birth of her son, an old man indulging himself to cannibalism, a man cheating on his wife in front of an old blind parent, it's all about Harry, his friends are not fooled, neither are we. Is there a message behind that? Yes, every single piece of work of an artist is autobiographical. I'm tired of the whole: "Woody Allen always plays the same character" argument, because rather than a criticism, this is the best homage he can receive. But I would specify it a little bit, he doesn't play the same character, but within his whole oeuvre, there is one and only one Woody Allen. To understand the personality, one has to follow his evolution step by step, film by film. In "Interiors", the artist put his own inspiration into perspective, in "Stardust Memories", his comical talent or in "Zelig", his capability to please to be part of the mood.. In "Deconstructing Harry", it seems like the constantly self-deprecating Woody Allen is finally over with his own demons, because he comes to one realization, this is the best thing he can do, this is the only talent he truly has, and he's only exploiting it for the best. One of his friends, played by Billy Crystal, stole his girlfriend, but he acknowledges he doesn't have his talent. And yes, Allen is the best screenwriter. At the film's apotheosis, when all the characters he created applauded him, you can see the overwhelming effect on his eyes, and for one second, we imagine Woody Allen being applauded by Annie Hall, Virgil, Hannah and her Sisters thanking him for having graced the silver screen and pleased a generation of movie goers, for more than 20 years. Almost 20 years later, Woody Allen is still prolific but you could feel a relief after "Deconstructing Harry", when he could finally get to more fictional stuff, and telling stories again. I didn't speak much of the film because it's typically Allenian with a great cast, a deliberately disjointed editing, sometimes confusing but I guess it's a benign artistic license in order to convey the chaotic aspect of Harry's life as a sort of story he tries to rewrite inside himself, with the same process of writing, erasing, rewriting, copy-pasting etc. But what rises above the whole chaos, is the self-reflexive approach of Allen to his own work, he did it with "Interiors" and "Stardust Memories", but the films were inspired by Bergman and Fellini's works. I guess it took the revival of his comical genius in the 80's and the early 90's so he could understand that the best one to talk about Woody and to deconstruct Woody, is still Woody. And from someone who wishes to become a writer and can't function in the cold and average normality of life, I realize that I'm more inclined to bloom during writing, and stop being so out-of-focus, I should be the one to give people the right glasses to see what I'm worth. This out-of-focus metaphor is a strike of comical genius, and it touched a very sensitive chord. I loved "Deconstructing Harry" in a very deep and personal level and as I get older, I feel a very strong connection to the artistic and even neurotic personality of Woody Allen. To deconstruct Harry is to understand Woody, and ... a certain part of ourselves, imprisoned in a life of futile conventions and begging for expression, no matter how hard, and painful or shameful they are. I guess we should all learn to deconstruct ourselves to be over with our inner demons.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The love between writer and character.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Dennen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is, in my opinion, one of Woody Allen's most underrated films. Often overlooked by a careers' worth of other more well known work, this late 90's Drama plays out a relationship seldom looked at; the relationship between a writer and their intellectual property. The characters in this film act as friends and loved ones, or rather memories of friends and loved ones. It's a look inside the mind of a neurotic writer, a writer whose life is both hitting a professional peak, while simultaneously hitting a personal low. Harry Block (Woody Allen), is dealing with past demons as well as present hurdles, all while preparing to receive a major award. To help deal with this accumulation of problems, characters from his fictional stories seep into his reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Allen's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is a rare film that takes it's title in the most literal ways, both in structure and in storytelling. The plot centers around Harry Block (played as only Allen himself could), a man suffering from writer's block as he prepares to accept an award from his old university, but this is only a loose strain to give the story a narrative though. What it's really focused on is Harry himself, his mind and his characters. In the traditional Allen sense, we get some external monologuing as he explores the mind of this neurotic, stuck and seemingly hopeless man, but he does it in a way that I've never seen him work before. The style of comedy is of course that Allen allure that no one could imitate, but there's also a vulgarity to it that I've never seen him go for before. There are words that I never thought I'd see in a Woody Allen film and the jokes are incredibly graphic, but it gives it this sense of brutal honesty that I haven't experienced from him up to this point. It's absolutely hilarious and quite true, it felt comically in the same sense of Louis C.K.'s work; vulgar and borderline offensive, but totally true to the point where it makes it's audience take a long look in the mirror. As we explore Harry, his few friends and his many exes, we are treated to short vignettes taken from his previous written work. Allen explores the mind of a writer so thoroughly it's mesmerizing, giving us looks into how true the "you write what you know" expression is, with characters that are directly based on his past lovers and himself. Each short story is hilarious in it's own right, but also sheds more light into the character himself, which is the ultimate draw of the film. I've never liked a performance from the writer/director more than I have here. He's got the neurosis and cynicism that he is a master at, but there's also an authenticity and darkness to him that I felt was more exposed than I've seen him before. His editing work is a masterstroke as well as he depicts Harry's real life as fractured, making quick cuts in scenes so that nothing seems to be fluid but it gives it this stream-of-consciousness touch that becomes fluid in itself, in detailing what he wants to accomplish. When we see his work displayed, there's no fragmentation, no awkward cuts, everything runs smoothly. The final scene of the film states the themes a little too strongly, as he practically spoonfeeds them to the audience, but it's a brilliant display of how a writer can become so broken and fractured in his own life that the only way he can achieve any clarity is through his work. A dark, touching, hilarious film with a strong message. Plus, it opens with Julia Louis-Dreyfus getting bent over and plowed in front of a blind woman, and you don't get much funnier than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It's me thinly disguised in fact, I don't even think I should disguise it any more  it's me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is probably Woody Allen's most interesting and controversial film from his troubled 90s period. Coming at the height of turmoil in his personal life, the same year that Deconstructing Harry was released, Allen married Soon Yi Previn and the world was given an insight into their relationship in the rewarding documentary Wild Man Blues (6). Deconstructing Harry sees him slam reality and fiction together, giving (except for one exception) an expletive-free and free-flowing series of fantasy vignettes with jump- cut, foul-mouthed bites of reality. For this reason more than any other it's a film that could upset Allen purists, as his attempt to capture real life sees multiple uses of the word "f***" and even the "c" word coming from Woody's lips on two occasions. Is the film misogynist? Possibly. Woody certainly appears to have anger towards women here, and while the ladies of the night so romantically depicted in the likable-but-bland Mighty Aphrodite (6) are here "whores" and "hookers", there's also more than an element of racial patronage. The adjoinder from an African American prostitute over whether she knows what a black hole is ("Yeah... that's how I make my living") is probably the most repellent line in an Allen film, bar none. Even today Woody is still capable of making watchable films, but they're rarely essential and tend towards the reactionary. Little of his later period has come close to matching the vibrancy and sheer anxiety-based energy of Deconstructing Harry. This is Woody venting his spleen for the masses, and seeming to toy with the "playing himself" questions. It may not be pleasant to watch, but it's never dull. Again, his Jewish fixations can be offensive, though the scenes with his sister and brother-in-law are amongst the funniest in this not quite laugh-a-minute vehicle. I loved the bit where he tells his sister's husband: "I think you're the opposite of paranoid. I think you go around with the insane delusion that people like you". Yeah, most of the jokes at this stage in his career are recycled, but they're given a new take by the level of unsettling acidity contained in this picture. Annie Hall this isn't. The 1990s won't be remembered as a golden age for Allen's work, a period where he was getting more laughs voicing a cartoon ant than in his own movies. Altogether he wrote and directed ten new films, as well as a grating TV movie of his 60s play/film Don't Drink The Water (4). Films like Alice (5), Manhattan Murder Mystery (6) or Shadows and Fog (5) are watchable yet forgettable, the first decade for Allen where the so-so outnumbered the good. Yet there's still some first rate work in his 90s period, with Husbands and Wives (7) treading familiar ground but in subtle new ways. Sweet and Lowdown (7), a biopic of a fictitious jazz musician, brims with invention... though his first musical, Everyone Says I Love You (q.v.) sadly does not. Perhaps most notable in the 90s is the casting of actors to play the "Woody Allen" role, as he was entering his 60s and perhaps straining even his own much-tested formula of "young girl falls for older intellectual". In this regard then Kenneth Brannagh surprisingly does a better job than John Cusack, playing a substitute in the rewarding Celebrity (7), as opposed to Cusack's turn in the jarring Bullets Over Broadway (5). Which brings us back to Deconstructing Harry, as Allen originally had no wish to star in the lead. Deconstructing Harry isn't a pleasant film to watch by any means. It's crass, foul-mouthed and even obnoxious on occasion. But the fragmented, sketchy nature of events and inventive sequences make it an easier viewing experience than an extended narrative. Not only that, but in watching something which appears to be such a personal statement, then it may not be Allen's most likable or accomplished film, but it remains one of the most intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Allen's homage to (and send-up of) WILD STRAWBERRIES has its pluses and minuses. It's interesting, and in a way refreshing, to see him being so blatantly crass. It's one of his darkest movies, and maybe his most cynical comedy. Some of it is riotously funny, like the confrontation with Kirstie Alley in the middle of a patient's therapy session, or his version of Hell (with Billy Crystal in one of his most enjoyable roles). But with all the little sub-stories going on, it comes off like a clearinghouse for unfinished ideas. Also, the fragmented, jerky editing (because he's being "deconstructed," get it?) is an annoying quirk that adds little. Still, there's a lots of laughs to be had and it's an interesting bit of self-deprecation combined with self-admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good Woody Allen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block is a successful writer who gets inspiration from people he knows.Everybody doesn't like that.And he has his flaws, like pills and whores.Now his old university is honoring him.Harry wants to take his son Hilly to the ceremony, but his ex-wife Joan says no.But Harry takes him there anyway, as he does take a prostitute named Cookie and a friend called Richard.What a day to remember that will be! Deconstructing Harry is a Woody Allen film from 1997.Woody Allen gives a really great performance in this movie.Luckily he cast himself.No complaints about the rest of the cast either.Kirstie Alley plays the part of Joan, Harry's ex-wife.Billy Crystal, who gets to do next year's Oscars again, plays Larry/The Devil.Lucy Davis is Lucy.Bob Balaban plays Richard.Elisabeth Shue plays Fay.Paul Giamatti is Prof. Abbott.Philip Bosco is Prof. Clark.Mariel Hemingway, who was also in Allen's Manhattan, plays Beth Kramer.Hazelle Goodman is Cookie.Amy Irving is Jane.Eric Lloyd plays Hilly.Now 90-year old Gene Saks plays Harry's Father.Tony Sirico is Policeman at Jail.Then there are some characters that are of Harry's creation.Richard Benjamin plays Ken.Julia Louis-Dreyfus is Leslie.Tobey Maguire plays Harvey Stern.Jennifer Garner is Woman in Elevator.Stanley Tucci is Paul Epstein.Demi Moore plays Helen.Robin Williams is Mel.Julie Kavner is Grace.This is a very fine Woody Allen movie of the 90's.It's often funny.You find yourself most amused, when they're driving with the hooker and doing some car singing.Also out of focus Robin Williams is hilarious.I get seasick just by looking at him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harry is a writer, Block.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another all-star cast, another central role played by writer-director Woody Allen and another look at a character full of flaws and neuroses, we're in very familiar territory this time around. Allen plays Harry Block, a writer who is struggling for the first time in his life with writer's block and who is also tense about an upcoming honour he is to receive from his old school. As he tries to iron out the many wrinkles in his life and deal with his worries he finds himself encountering many of his literary creations (both fictional and in the form of the real, living people he based them upon) and getting advice from them along the way. The notion of the artist confronted by his creations and the consequences of his work is a good one and the weaving of the fantasy strands through the reality of the piece allows for a lot of fun (especially when comparing a fictional character to the real person they were based on) but this film, overall, just somehow misses the mark. The script isn't quite sharp enough, none of the performers get enough time to make a good impression and nothing feels as if it's actually moving a narrative along from start to finish. With a cast including Bob Balaban, Judy Davis, Billy Crystal, Robin Williams, Richard Benjamin, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Eric Bogosian, Kirstie Alley, Julie Kavner, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Tony Sirico, Demi Moore and Elisabeth Shue it's a real shame that nobody gets a chance to shine. Billy Crystal gets to have the most fun but Robin Williams stars in the most enjoyable fantasy sequence as an actor who one day suddenly goes out of focus. As others have said, this is worth seeing as a companion piece to Stardust Memories (with that being about the director and this being about the writer) but I just found myself watching long sections of the film without actually, properly enjoying it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Digging to the core; leave no stone unturned.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Mighty Aphrodite is a nice Woody Allen, then Deconstructing Harry is certainly the pinnacle of his nasty side. Indeed, for non-Woody Allen fans, it would seem difficult to understand how two vastly different films could come from the same mind. Yet, the genius of Allen lays primarily in his writing, able to create and expound upon a brilliant idea of the story of a man who is unable to cope the negative and horrible lifestyle he abides with the successful and insightful writing and art he creates fictionally. This is a difficult film to review as it unfolds itself in a very bipolar manner: cinematically it works on the highest scale with terrific acting, direction, editing and one of Woody's best scripts. Yet, on the other hand, it is quite possibly his meanest and most cynical portrait of humanity. The character of Harry Block (whom no one was willing to play until Allen finally took it himself) is incredibly neurotic, egotistical, nihilistic and narcissistic and Allen takes him to the very end of his rope, almost encouraging us to not feel any sympathy towards him at all. Certainly no one else does; his entire family hates him for the way he vaguely portrays them in his books as cheap stereotypes of their personalities and beliefs. Still, there may be the slightest bit of humanity within this ball of neuroses if only because Woody Allen gives one of his very best performances here. Again, I must praise the large and star-studded cast for carrying much of the heavy material, especially in scenes that would feel out of place in other hands. In particular, Judy Davis, Elisabeth Shue and Bob Balaban are very good. I must also give praise to Billy Crystal who personifies the devil himself in Harry's mind and is evilly funny. I guess this should be recommended but only for serious Woody Allen fans. It convincingly gives an argument for why and how Allen is able to rationalize all the crazy events he has gone through in his life. Personally, I cannot say that I always agree with his worldview. But, he always does have something interesting to say and if he can continue to say it through films like this, then I feel I will be able to sit through them. However, be warned: this is a side of Woody Allen never seen prior and hardly seen since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mixed Feelings...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick Cluxton
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been looking forward to seeing this film for quite a while, and when I finally had a chance I was pretty quick to take it up. As I started it, I regretted it immediately, I was bored and annoyed. Towards the end, it began to grow on me, but a lot just didn't do it for me. What I liked: I absolutely love the concept and the story. I have not seen any like it. What I like most is that while there is an actual plot and external events, it's more of a character study. They take an unlikable character and give him plenty of depth and sympathy to make up for his brash decisions and opinions. I love Woody Allen as a writer. I also liked the short stories; how they were narrated, the actual relevance they had to Harry's problems and friends, and how they were somewhat diverse. It wasn't just about the message. I both liked and disliked the scenes where they would cut to the same shot. It is very reminiscent of Jean- Loc Goddard's Breathless, which at times gave it a very relaxed, more realistic feel, considering that you could interpret that there were probably moments of silence between conversation, like something that happens in real conversation. However, when you cut in mid-sentence or make too many quick cuts, it's distracting and annoying to try and listen. What I hated: While I love that film is about Harry Block, I hated him. His guts, his obsession with sex, and the fact that he is so damn awkward. I hate Woody Allen as an actor. I appreciate when people stutter, pause, mix up words, or ramble in movies because that's what people do in real life. However, Woody Allen takes it and makes it absolutely obnoxious. His arms flail around, he never makes eye contact (or keeps his eyes on the road while driving). Overall, the word I would use to describe this movie is 'inconsistent,' with some scene being very funny and entertaining, while others made me want to scratch my DVD apart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing the indestructible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block (Woody Allen) is a neurotic, jittery, pill-popping author, condemned by those who known him well, and hailed by those who don't know him at all. Block has written lengthy, verbose novels that are thinly-disguised to hide the real relationships in his life, and for that reason, he has successfully alienated himself from all of his formers friends and family members. He often spends his days lonely, drinking, and hanging out with prostitutes, who he pays ample amounts of money to in order to get a quick-fix. The current silver-lining in Block's sad, dreary existence is that he will soon be recognized in a forthcoming ceremony by the university that kicked him out. He desperately wants company when he embarks on this trip, but because his novels have made it impossible for people to sympathize or like him on any level, he is left with quite a challenge. Even his ex-wife forbids him to spend the day with his young son so he can see his father may not be such a loser after all. Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is many things, but one of the most notable is it exists as an ode to the films of acclaimed Swedish director Ingmar Bergman. The film's plot alone mirrors that of Wild Strawberries, one of the man's most loved, which centered on a man and his pregnant daughter-in-law driving through the country so he could be granted with an award. The film made the tricky but probable analysis that a man can be loved by those who don't know him and simultaneously be hated by those who know him all too well. It was a tremendous achievement in foreign cinema and, in my opinion based on what I've seen thus far, Bergman's best film. Furthermore, this is one of Allen's darkest efforts to date. Not only is the film's protagonist almost remorseless in his treatment of others, but the way certain scenes are written and executed truly question how we're exactly supposed to respond. Take for example the scene when Block's panic attacks get the best of him and he needs to be consoled by a hooker he invited over the night before. While the relationship is nice - and without a doubt deeper than most prostitute/client relationships - it definitely shows just how depressing and almost broken Block's life is to the point where he needs to be reassured and comforted by a prostitute. The nihilism and cynicism of Allen's work shockingly doesn't become the detraction in the film, whereas the choppy narrative does and questionable ending does. The narrative, which continues to bounce between the current events in Block's life and the past events/relationships he held, is a bit too erratic and jumbled, quickly switching back and forth between the past and present with only a moderate amount of continuity. Not to mention the ending feels a bit put-on and unbelievable considering all that Block has put up with during the course of the film. Returning to the thought that the film is one giant homage to the works of Bergman, consider Allen's comically potent portrayal of the Devil here. Bergman made the Devil a living, breathing character in his film The Seventh Seal and made the film very existential and thought-provoking. Allen pays close attention-to-detail in terms of character relations and how one person after another is presented here. He animates the Devil character (played by Billy Crystal) terrifically here, using the right amount of black humor and comic-timing. Deconstructing Harry is a cynical delight of a film making exceptional use of Allen's writing/directing talents, but also the immensity and diversity of the cast at hand. Each star, whether it be Kirstie Alley, Julia Louise-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Billy Crystal, or Robin Williams, gets their own time to shine in the picture and all of them feel welcome and completely in-place in Allen's darkly funny world. It's once again apparent that Allen can make deeply personal, intriguing pictures, yet still be so foreign to his audience as a whole. Starring: Woody Allen, Caroline Aaron, Kirstie Alley, Bob Balaban, Richard Benjamin, Eric Bogosian, Billy Crystal, Judy Davis, Hazelle Goodman, Mariel Hemingway, Amy Irving, Julie Kavner, Eric Lloyd, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Demi Moore, Elisabeth Shue, Stanley Tucci, and Robin Williams. Directed by: Woody Allen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry, understanding Woody ... and ourselves ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Deconstructing Harry" stands, in my opinion, as one of Woody Allen's best, probably his last masterpiece although it doesn't have the 'masterpiece' vibe. It looks like a typical Woody Allen movie but watch it closely and you'll get more insights about the director, the artist, ultimately the man. If you're not interested in, enjoy the gags and forget about it  if you can. I am more and more confident that Woody Allen is never as inspired and of course- hilarious as when his movies work as media to expresses his personal fears, angst and frustrations. And being capable to distort life, facts and reality to produce insights based on his own living, and in the intellectual and emotional process, to enable us to question ourselves, is in my opinion the work of a true artist. The film might feel 'minor' compared to other Allen's films but for some reason, it touched me, not immediately, but the ending was one of Allen's most triumphal achievements. Don't let yourself guided by your first feelings, this is not Allen wrapped up in his own ego, the film works on higher levels, and use Allen's own demons to tunnel us into ours, to use our empathy as a lightning torch to find truth in our personal darkness. Woody Allen is the titular Harry, Block is his last name, a fitting one as the writer he plays seems to suffer from mental block, the nightmare of every writer. But this block is justified by the series of incidents that undermined his inspiration. "Deconstructing Harry" is set during the aftermath of Harry's best-seller's success, a novel where he unveiled his most intimate secrets involving his friends, ex-wives, sister, family and acquaintances. It is one thing to reveal one's intimate secrets but we tend to forget that our secrets involve our personal circle. As a writer, Harry doesn't embarrass with such dilemmas, inspiration commands the writing and the others' anger is only a collateral damage he can afford but still must deal with. He tries to hide the names, to use lamentable pseudonyms, but behind every character, there's Harry. The film, like "Radio Days" is a succession of little vignettes, all reflecting a part of Harry's life, this is what the whole deconstruction process is about, in a masterstroke of writing. Whether it's a writer whose wife rediscovered her Jewish faith after the birth of her son, an old man indulging himself to cannibalism, a man cheating on his wife in front of an old blind parent, it's all about Harry, his friends are not fooled, neither are we. Is there a message behind that? Yes, every single piece of work of an artist is autobiographical. I'm tired of the whole: "Woody Allen always plays the same character" argument, because rather than a criticism, this is the best homage he can receive. But I would specify it a little bit, he doesn't play the same character, but within his whole oeuvre, there is one and only one Woody Allen. To understand the personality, one has to follow his evolution step by step, film by film. In "Interiors", the artist put his own inspiration into perspective, in "Stardust Memories", his comical talent or in "Zelig", his capability to please to be part of the mood.. In "Deconstructing Harry", it seems like the constantly self-deprecating Woody Allen is finally over with his own demons, because he comes to one realization, this is the best thing he can do, this is the only talent he truly has, and he's only exploiting it for the best. One of his friends, played by Billy Crystal, stole his girlfriend, but he acknowledges he doesn't have his talent. And yes, Allen is the best screenwriter. At the film's apotheosis, when all the characters he created applauded him, you can see the overwhelming effect on his eyes, and for one second, we imagine Woody Allen being applauded by Annie Hall, Virgil, Hannah and her Sisters thanking him for having graced the silver screen and pleased a generation of movie goers, for more than 20 years. Almost 20 years later, Woody Allen is still prolific but you could feel a relief after "Deconstructing Harry", when he could finally get to more fictional stuff, and telling stories again. I didn't speak much of the film because it's typically Allenian with a great cast, a deliberately disjointed editing, sometimes confusing but I guess it's a benign artistic license in order to convey the chaotic aspect of Harry's life as a sort of story he tries to rewrite inside himself, with the same process of writing, erasing, rewriting, copy-pasting etc. But what rises above the whole chaos, is the self-reflexive approach of Allen to his own work, he did it with "Interiors" and "Stardust Memories", but the films were inspired by Bergman and Fellini's works. I guess it took the revival of his comical genius in the 80's and the early 90's so he could understand that the best one to talk about Woody and to deconstruct Woody, is still Woody. And from someone who wishes to become a writer and can't function in the cold and average normality of life, I realize that I'm more inclined to bloom during writing, and stop being so out-of-focus, I should be the one to give people the right glasses to see what I'm worth. This out-of-focus metaphor is a strike of comical genius, and it touched a very sensitive chord. I loved "Deconstructing Harry" in a very deep and personal level and as I get older, I feel a very strong connection to the artistic and even neurotic personality of Woody Allen. To deconstruct Harry is to understand Woody, and ... a certain part of ourselves, imprisoned in a life of futile conventions and begging for expression, no matter how hard, and painful or shameful they are. I guess we should all learn to deconstruct ourselves to be over with our inner demons.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The love between writer and character.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Dennen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is, in my opinion, one of Woody Allen's most underrated films. Often overlooked by a careers' worth of other more well known work, this late 90's Drama plays out a relationship seldom looked at; the relationship between a writer and their intellectual property. The characters in this film act as friends and loved ones, or rather memories of friends and loved ones. It's a look inside the mind of a neurotic writer, a writer whose life is both hitting a professional peak, while simultaneously hitting a personal low. Harry Block (Woody Allen), is dealing with past demons as well as present hurdles, all while preparing to receive a major award. To help deal with this accumulation of problems, characters from his fictional stories seep into his reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Allen's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is a rare film that takes it's title in the most literal ways, both in structure and in storytelling. The plot centers around Harry Block (played as only Allen himself could), a man suffering from writer's block as he prepares to accept an award from his old university, but this is only a loose strain to give the story a narrative though. What it's really focused on is Harry himself, his mind and his characters. In the traditional Allen sense, we get some external monologuing as he explores the mind of this neurotic, stuck and seemingly hopeless man, but he does it in a way that I've never seen him work before. The style of comedy is of course that Allen allure that no one could imitate, but there's also a vulgarity to it that I've never seen him go for before. There are words that I never thought I'd see in a Woody Allen film and the jokes are incredibly graphic, but it gives it this sense of brutal honesty that I haven't experienced from him up to this point. It's absolutely hilarious and quite true, it felt comically in the same sense of Louis C.K.'s work; vulgar and borderline offensive, but totally true to the point where it makes it's audience take a long look in the mirror. As we explore Harry, his few friends and his many exes, we are treated to short vignettes taken from his previous written work. Allen explores the mind of a writer so thoroughly it's mesmerizing, giving us looks into how true the "you write what you know" expression is, with characters that are directly based on his past lovers and himself. Each short story is hilarious in it's own right, but also sheds more light into the character himself, which is the ultimate draw of the film. I've never liked a performance from the writer/director more than I have here. He's got the neurosis and cynicism that he is a master at, but there's also an authenticity and darkness to him that I felt was more exposed than I've seen him before. His editing work is a masterstroke as well as he depicts Harry's real life as fractured, making quick cuts in scenes so that nothing seems to be fluid but it gives it this stream-of-consciousness touch that becomes fluid in itself, in detailing what he wants to accomplish. When we see his work displayed, there's no fragmentation, no awkward cuts, everything runs smoothly. The final scene of the film states the themes a little too strongly, as he practically spoonfeeds them to the audience, but it's a brilliant display of how a writer can become so broken and fractured in his own life that the only way he can achieve any clarity is through his work. A dark, touching, hilarious film with a strong message. Plus, it opens with Julia Louis-Dreyfus getting bent over and plowed in front of a blind woman, and you don't get much funnier than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It's me thinly disguised in fact, I don't even think I should disguise it any more  it's me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is probably Woody Allen's most interesting and controversial film from his troubled 90s period. Coming at the height of turmoil in his personal life, the same year that Deconstructing Harry was released, Allen married Soon Yi Previn and the world was given an insight into their relationship in the rewarding documentary Wild Man Blues (6). Deconstructing Harry sees him slam reality and fiction together, giving (except for one exception) an expletive-free and free-flowing series of fantasy vignettes with jump- cut, foul-mouthed bites of reality. For this reason more than any other it's a film that could upset Allen purists, as his attempt to capture real life sees multiple uses of the word "f***" and even the "c" word coming from Woody's lips on two occasions. Is the film misogynist? Possibly. Woody certainly appears to have anger towards women here, and while the ladies of the night so romantically depicted in the likable-but-bland Mighty Aphrodite (6) are here "whores" and "hookers", there's also more than an element of racial patronage. The adjoinder from an African American prostitute over whether she knows what a black hole is ("Yeah... that's how I make my living") is probably the most repellent line in an Allen film, bar none. Even today Woody is still capable of making watchable films, but they're rarely essential and tend towards the reactionary. Little of his later period has come close to matching the vibrancy and sheer anxiety-based energy of Deconstructing Harry. This is Woody venting his spleen for the masses, and seeming to toy with the "playing himself" questions. It may not be pleasant to watch, but it's never dull. Again, his Jewish fixations can be offensive, though the scenes with his sister and brother-in-law are amongst the funniest in this not quite laugh-a-minute vehicle. I loved the bit where he tells his sister's husband: "I think you're the opposite of paranoid. I think you go around with the insane delusion that people like you". Yeah, most of the jokes at this stage in his career are recycled, but they're given a new take by the level of unsettling acidity contained in this picture. Annie Hall this isn't. The 1990s won't be remembered as a golden age for Allen's work, a period where he was getting more laughs voicing a cartoon ant than in his own movies. Altogether he wrote and directed ten new films, as well as a grating TV movie of his 60s play/film Don't Drink The Water (4). Films like Alice (5), Manhattan Murder Mystery (6) or Shadows and Fog (5) are watchable yet forgettable, the first decade for Allen where the so-so outnumbered the good. Yet there's still some first rate work in his 90s period, with Husbands and Wives (7) treading familiar ground but in subtle new ways. Sweet and Lowdown (7), a biopic of a fictitious jazz musician, brims with invention... though his first musical, Everyone Says I Love You (q.v.) sadly does not. Perhaps most notable in the 90s is the casting of actors to play the "Woody Allen" role, as he was entering his 60s and perhaps straining even his own much-tested formula of "young girl falls for older intellectual". In this regard then Kenneth Brannagh surprisingly does a better job than John Cusack, playing a substitute in the rewarding Celebrity (7), as opposed to Cusack's turn in the jarring Bullets Over Broadway (5). Which brings us back to Deconstructing Harry, as Allen originally had no wish to star in the lead. Deconstructing Harry isn't a pleasant film to watch by any means. It's crass, foul-mouthed and even obnoxious on occasion. But the fragmented, sketchy nature of events and inventive sequences make it an easier viewing experience than an extended narrative. Not only that, but in watching something which appears to be such a personal statement, then it may not be Allen's most likable or accomplished film, but it remains one of the most intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Allen's homage to (and send-up of) WILD STRAWBERRIES has its pluses and minuses. It's interesting, and in a way refreshing, to see him being so blatantly crass. It's one of his darkest movies, and maybe his most cynical comedy. Some of it is riotously funny, like the confrontation with Kirstie Alley in the middle of a patient's therapy session, or his version of Hell (with Billy Crystal in one of his most enjoyable roles). But with all the little sub-stories going on, it comes off like a clearinghouse for unfinished ideas. Also, the fragmented, jerky editing (because he's being "deconstructed," get it?) is an annoying quirk that adds little. Still, there's a lots of laughs to be had and it's an interesting bit of self-deprecation combined with self-admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good Woody Allen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block is a successful writer who gets inspiration from people he knows.Everybody doesn't like that.And he has his flaws, like pills and whores.Now his old university is honoring him.Harry wants to take his son Hilly to the ceremony, but his ex-wife Joan says no.But Harry takes him there anyway, as he does take a prostitute named Cookie and a friend called Richard.What a day to remember that will be! Deconstructing Harry is a Woody Allen film from 1997.Woody Allen gives a really great performance in this movie.Luckily he cast himself.No complaints about the rest of the cast either.Kirstie Alley plays the part of Joan, Harry's ex-wife.Billy Crystal, who gets to do next year's Oscars again, plays Larry/The Devil.Lucy Davis is Lucy.Bob Balaban plays Richard.Elisabeth Shue plays Fay.Paul Giamatti is Prof. Abbott.Philip Bosco is Prof. Clark.Mariel Hemingway, who was also in Allen's Manhattan, plays Beth Kramer.Hazelle Goodman is Cookie.Amy Irving is Jane.Eric Lloyd plays Hilly.Now 90-year old Gene Saks plays Harry's Father.Tony Sirico is Policeman at Jail.Then there are some characters that are of Harry's creation.Richard Benjamin plays Ken.Julia Louis-Dreyfus is Leslie.Tobey Maguire plays Harvey Stern.Jennifer Garner is Woman in Elevator.Stanley Tucci is Paul Epstein.Demi Moore plays Helen.Robin Williams is Mel.Julie Kavner is Grace.This is a very fine Woody Allen movie of the 90's.It's often funny.You find yourself most amused, when they're driving with the hooker and doing some car singing.Also out of focus Robin Williams is hilarious.I get seasick just by looking at him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harry is a writer, Block.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another all-star cast, another central role played by writer-director Woody Allen and another look at a character full of flaws and neuroses, we're in very familiar territory this time around. Allen plays Harry Block, a writer who is struggling for the first time in his life with writer's block and who is also tense about an upcoming honour he is to receive from his old school. As he tries to iron out the many wrinkles in his life and deal with his worries he finds himself encountering many of his literary creations (both fictional and in the form of the real, living people he based them upon) and getting advice from them along the way. The notion of the artist confronted by his creations and the consequences of his work is a good one and the weaving of the fantasy strands through the reality of the piece allows for a lot of fun (especially when comparing a fictional character to the real person they were based on) but this film, overall, just somehow misses the mark. The script isn't quite sharp enough, none of the performers get enough time to make a good impression and nothing feels as if it's actually moving a narrative along from start to finish. With a cast including Bob Balaban, Judy Davis, Billy Crystal, Robin Williams, Richard Benjamin, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Eric Bogosian, Kirstie Alley, Julie Kavner, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Tony Sirico, Demi Moore and Elisabeth Shue it's a real shame that nobody gets a chance to shine. Billy Crystal gets to have the most fun but Robin Williams stars in the most enjoyable fantasy sequence as an actor who one day suddenly goes out of focus. As others have said, this is worth seeing as a companion piece to Stardust Memories (with that being about the director and this being about the writer) but I just found myself watching long sections of the film without actually, properly enjoying it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Digging to the core; leave no stone unturned.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Mighty Aphrodite is a nice Woody Allen, then Deconstructing Harry is certainly the pinnacle of his nasty side. Indeed, for non-Woody Allen fans, it would seem difficult to understand how two vastly different films could come from the same mind. Yet, the genius of Allen lays primarily in his writing, able to create and expound upon a brilliant idea of the story of a man who is unable to cope the negative and horrible lifestyle he abides with the successful and insightful writing and art he creates fictionally. This is a difficult film to review as it unfolds itself in a very bipolar manner: cinematically it works on the highest scale with terrific acting, direction, editing and one of Woody's best scripts. Yet, on the other hand, it is quite possibly his meanest and most cynical portrait of humanity. The character of Harry Block (whom no one was willing to play until Allen finally took it himself) is incredibly neurotic, egotistical, nihilistic and narcissistic and Allen takes him to the very end of his rope, almost encouraging us to not feel any sympathy towards him at all. Certainly no one else does; his entire family hates him for the way he vaguely portrays them in his books as cheap stereotypes of their personalities and beliefs. Still, there may be the slightest bit of humanity within this ball of neuroses if only because Woody Allen gives one of his very best performances here. Again, I must praise the large and star-studded cast for carrying much of the heavy material, especially in scenes that would feel out of place in other hands. In particular, Judy Davis, Elisabeth Shue and Bob Balaban are very good. I must also give praise to Billy Crystal who personifies the devil himself in Harry's mind and is evilly funny. I guess this should be recommended but only for serious Woody Allen fans. It convincingly gives an argument for why and how Allen is able to rationalize all the crazy events he has gone through in his life. Personally, I cannot say that I always agree with his worldview. But, he always does have something interesting to say and if he can continue to say it through films like this, then I feel I will be able to sit through them. However, be warned: this is a side of Woody Allen never seen prior and hardly seen since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mixed Feelings...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick Cluxton
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been looking forward to seeing this film for quite a while, and when I finally had a chance I was pretty quick to take it up. As I started it, I regretted it immediately, I was bored and annoyed. Towards the end, it began to grow on me, but a lot just didn't do it for me. What I liked: I absolutely love the concept and the story. I have not seen any like it. What I like most is that while there is an actual plot and external events, it's more of a character study. They take an unlikable character and give him plenty of depth and sympathy to make up for his brash decisions and opinions. I love Woody Allen as a writer. I also liked the short stories; how they were narrated, the actual relevance they had to Harry's problems and friends, and how they were somewhat diverse. It wasn't just about the message. I both liked and disliked the scenes where they would cut to the same shot. It is very reminiscent of Jean- Loc Goddard's Breathless, which at times gave it a very relaxed, more realistic feel, considering that you could interpret that there were probably moments of silence between conversation, like something that happens in real conversation. However, when you cut in mid-sentence or make too many quick cuts, it's distracting and annoying to try and listen. What I hated: While I love that film is about Harry Block, I hated him. His guts, his obsession with sex, and the fact that he is so damn awkward. I hate Woody Allen as an actor. I appreciate when people stutter, pause, mix up words, or ramble in movies because that's what people do in real life. However, Woody Allen takes it and makes it absolutely obnoxious. His arms flail around, he never makes eye contact (or keeps his eyes on the road while driving). Overall, the word I would use to describe this movie is 'inconsistent,' with some scene being very funny and entertaining, while others made me want to scratch my DVD apart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing the indestructible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block (Woody Allen) is a neurotic, jittery, pill-popping author, condemned by those who known him well, and hailed by those who don't know him at all. Block has written lengthy, verbose novels that are thinly-disguised to hide the real relationships in his life, and for that reason, he has successfully alienated himself from all of his formers friends and family members. He often spends his days lonely, drinking, and hanging out with prostitutes, who he pays ample amounts of money to in order to get a quick-fix. The current silver-lining in Block's sad, dreary existence is that he will soon be recognized in a forthcoming ceremony by the university that kicked him out. He desperately wants company when he embarks on this trip, but because his novels have made it impossible for people to sympathize or like him on any level, he is left with quite a challenge. Even his ex-wife forbids him to spend the day with his young son so he can see his father may not be such a loser after all. Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is many things, but one of the most notable is it exists as an ode to the films of acclaimed Swedish director Ingmar Bergman. The film's plot alone mirrors that of Wild Strawberries, one of the man's most loved, which centered on a man and his pregnant daughter-in-law driving through the country so he could be granted with an award. The film made the tricky but probable analysis that a man can be loved by those who don't know him and simultaneously be hated by those who know him all too well. It was a tremendous achievement in foreign cinema and, in my opinion based on what I've seen thus far, Bergman's best film. Furthermore, this is one of Allen's darkest efforts to date. Not only is the film's protagonist almost remorseless in his treatment of others, but the way certain scenes are written and executed truly question how we're exactly supposed to respond. Take for example the scene when Block's panic attacks get the best of him and he needs to be consoled by a hooker he invited over the night before. While the relationship is nice - and without a doubt deeper than most prostitute/client relationships - it definitely shows just how depressing and almost broken Block's life is to the point where he needs to be reassured and comforted by a prostitute. The nihilism and cynicism of Allen's work shockingly doesn't become the detraction in the film, whereas the choppy narrative does and questionable ending does. The narrative, which continues to bounce between the current events in Block's life and the past events/relationships he held, is a bit too erratic and jumbled, quickly switching back and forth between the past and present with only a moderate amount of continuity. Not to mention the ending feels a bit put-on and unbelievable considering all that Block has put up with during the course of the film. Returning to the thought that the film is one giant homage to the works of Bergman, consider Allen's comically potent portrayal of the Devil here. Bergman made the Devil a living, breathing character in his film The Seventh Seal and made the film very existential and thought-provoking. Allen pays close attention-to-detail in terms of character relations and how one person after another is presented here. He animates the Devil character (played by Billy Crystal) terrifically here, using the right amount of black humor and comic-timing. Deconstructing Harry is a cynical delight of a film making exceptional use of Allen's writing/directing talents, but also the immensity and diversity of the cast at hand. Each star, whether it be Kirstie Alley, Julia Louise-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Billy Crystal, or Robin Williams, gets their own time to shine in the picture and all of them feel welcome and completely in-place in Allen's darkly funny world. It's once again apparent that Allen can make deeply personal, intriguing pictures, yet still be so foreign to his audience as a whole. Starring: Woody Allen, Caroline Aaron, Kirstie Alley, Bob Balaban, Richard Benjamin, Eric Bogosian, Billy Crystal, Judy Davis, Hazelle Goodman, Mariel Hemingway, Amy Irving, Julie Kavner, Eric Lloyd, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Demi Moore, Elisabeth Shue, Stanley Tucci, and Robin Williams. Directed by: Woody Allen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry, understanding Woody ... and ourselves ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Deconstructing Harry" stands, in my opinion, as one of Woody Allen's best, probably his last masterpiece although it doesn't have the 'masterpiece' vibe. It looks like a typical Woody Allen movie but watch it closely and you'll get more insights about the director, the artist, ultimately the man. If you're not interested in, enjoy the gags and forget about it  if you can. I am more and more confident that Woody Allen is never as inspired and of course- hilarious as when his movies work as media to expresses his personal fears, angst and frustrations. And being capable to distort life, facts and reality to produce insights based on his own living, and in the intellectual and emotional process, to enable us to question ourselves, is in my opinion the work of a true artist. The film might feel 'minor' compared to other Allen's films but for some reason, it touched me, not immediately, but the ending was one of Allen's most triumphal achievements. Don't let yourself guided by your first feelings, this is not Allen wrapped up in his own ego, the film works on higher levels, and use Allen's own demons to tunnel us into ours, to use our empathy as a lightning torch to find truth in our personal darkness. Woody Allen is the titular Harry, Block is his last name, a fitting one as the writer he plays seems to suffer from mental block, the nightmare of every writer. But this block is justified by the series of incidents that undermined his inspiration. "Deconstructing Harry" is set during the aftermath of Harry's best-seller's success, a novel where he unveiled his most intimate secrets involving his friends, ex-wives, sister, family and acquaintances. It is one thing to reveal one's intimate secrets but we tend to forget that our secrets involve our personal circle. As a writer, Harry doesn't embarrass with such dilemmas, inspiration commands the writing and the others' anger is only a collateral damage he can afford but still must deal with. He tries to hide the names, to use lamentable pseudonyms, but behind every character, there's Harry. The film, like "Radio Days" is a succession of little vignettes, all reflecting a part of Harry's life, this is what the whole deconstruction process is about, in a masterstroke of writing. Whether it's a writer whose wife rediscovered her Jewish faith after the birth of her son, an old man indulging himself to cannibalism, a man cheating on his wife in front of an old blind parent, it's all about Harry, his friends are not fooled, neither are we. Is there a message behind that? Yes, every single piece of work of an artist is autobiographical. I'm tired of the whole: "Woody Allen always plays the same character" argument, because rather than a criticism, this is the best homage he can receive. But I would specify it a little bit, he doesn't play the same character, but within his whole oeuvre, there is one and only one Woody Allen. To understand the personality, one has to follow his evolution step by step, film by film. In "Interiors", the artist put his own inspiration into perspective, in "Stardust Memories", his comical talent or in "Zelig", his capability to please to be part of the mood.. In "Deconstructing Harry", it seems like the constantly self-deprecating Woody Allen is finally over with his own demons, because he comes to one realization, this is the best thing he can do, this is the only talent he truly has, and he's only exploiting it for the best. One of his friends, played by Billy Crystal, stole his girlfriend, but he acknowledges he doesn't have his talent. And yes, Allen is the best screenwriter. At the film's apotheosis, when all the characters he created applauded him, you can see the overwhelming effect on his eyes, and for one second, we imagine Woody Allen being applauded by Annie Hall, Virgil, Hannah and her Sisters thanking him for having graced the silver screen and pleased a generation of movie goers, for more than 20 years. Almost 20 years later, Woody Allen is still prolific but you could feel a relief after "Deconstructing Harry", when he could finally get to more fictional stuff, and telling stories again. I didn't speak much of the film because it's typically Allenian with a great cast, a deliberately disjointed editing, sometimes confusing but I guess it's a benign artistic license in order to convey the chaotic aspect of Harry's life as a sort of story he tries to rewrite inside himself, with the same process of writing, erasing, rewriting, copy-pasting etc. But what rises above the whole chaos, is the self-reflexive approach of Allen to his own work, he did it with "Interiors" and "Stardust Memories", but the films were inspired by Bergman and Fellini's works. I guess it took the revival of his comical genius in the 80's and the early 90's so he could understand that the best one to talk about Woody and to deconstruct Woody, is still Woody. And from someone who wishes to become a writer and can't function in the cold and average normality of life, I realize that I'm more inclined to bloom during writing, and stop being so out-of-focus, I should be the one to give people the right glasses to see what I'm worth. This out-of-focus metaphor is a strike of comical genius, and it touched a very sensitive chord. I loved "Deconstructing Harry" in a very deep and personal level and as I get older, I feel a very strong connection to the artistic and even neurotic personality of Woody Allen. To deconstruct Harry is to understand Woody, and ... a certain part of ourselves, imprisoned in a life of futile conventions and begging for expression, no matter how hard, and painful or shameful they are. I guess we should all learn to deconstruct ourselves to be over with our inner demons.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The love between writer and character.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Dennen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is, in my opinion, one of Woody Allen's most underrated films. Often overlooked by a careers' worth of other more well known work, this late 90's Drama plays out a relationship seldom looked at; the relationship between a writer and their intellectual property. The characters in this film act as friends and loved ones, or rather memories of friends and loved ones. It's a look inside the mind of a neurotic writer, a writer whose life is both hitting a professional peak, while simultaneously hitting a personal low. Harry Block (Woody Allen), is dealing with past demons as well as present hurdles, all while preparing to receive a major award. To help deal with this accumulation of problems, characters from his fictional stories seep into his reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Allen's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is a rare film that takes it's title in the most literal ways, both in structure and in storytelling. The plot centers around Harry Block (played as only Allen himself could), a man suffering from writer's block as he prepares to accept an award from his old university, but this is only a loose strain to give the story a narrative though. What it's really focused on is Harry himself, his mind and his characters. In the traditional Allen sense, we get some external monologuing as he explores the mind of this neurotic, stuck and seemingly hopeless man, but he does it in a way that I've never seen him work before. The style of comedy is of course that Allen allure that no one could imitate, but there's also a vulgarity to it that I've never seen him go for before. There are words that I never thought I'd see in a Woody Allen film and the jokes are incredibly graphic, but it gives it this sense of brutal honesty that I haven't experienced from him up to this point. It's absolutely hilarious and quite true, it felt comically in the same sense of Louis C.K.'s work; vulgar and borderline offensive, but totally true to the point where it makes it's audience take a long look in the mirror. As we explore Harry, his few friends and his many exes, we are treated to short vignettes taken from his previous written work. Allen explores the mind of a writer so thoroughly it's mesmerizing, giving us looks into how true the "you write what you know" expression is, with characters that are directly based on his past lovers and himself. Each short story is hilarious in it's own right, but also sheds more light into the character himself, which is the ultimate draw of the film. I've never liked a performance from the writer/director more than I have here. He's got the neurosis and cynicism that he is a master at, but there's also an authenticity and darkness to him that I felt was more exposed than I've seen him before. His editing work is a masterstroke as well as he depicts Harry's real life as fractured, making quick cuts in scenes so that nothing seems to be fluid but it gives it this stream-of-consciousness touch that becomes fluid in itself, in detailing what he wants to accomplish. When we see his work displayed, there's no fragmentation, no awkward cuts, everything runs smoothly. The final scene of the film states the themes a little too strongly, as he practically spoonfeeds them to the audience, but it's a brilliant display of how a writer can become so broken and fractured in his own life that the only way he can achieve any clarity is through his work. A dark, touching, hilarious film with a strong message. Plus, it opens with Julia Louis-Dreyfus getting bent over and plowed in front of a blind woman, and you don't get much funnier than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It's me thinly disguised in fact, I don't even think I should disguise it any more  it's me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is probably Woody Allen's most interesting and controversial film from his troubled 90s period. Coming at the height of turmoil in his personal life, the same year that Deconstructing Harry was released, Allen married Soon Yi Previn and the world was given an insight into their relationship in the rewarding documentary Wild Man Blues (6). Deconstructing Harry sees him slam reality and fiction together, giving (except for one exception) an expletive-free and free-flowing series of fantasy vignettes with jump- cut, foul-mouthed bites of reality. For this reason more than any other it's a film that could upset Allen purists, as his attempt to capture real life sees multiple uses of the word "f***" and even the "c" word coming from Woody's lips on two occasions. Is the film misogynist? Possibly. Woody certainly appears to have anger towards women here, and while the ladies of the night so romantically depicted in the likable-but-bland Mighty Aphrodite (6) are here "whores" and "hookers", there's also more than an element of racial patronage. The adjoinder from an African American prostitute over whether she knows what a black hole is ("Yeah... that's how I make my living") is probably the most repellent line in an Allen film, bar none. Even today Woody is still capable of making watchable films, but they're rarely essential and tend towards the reactionary. Little of his later period has come close to matching the vibrancy and sheer anxiety-based energy of Deconstructing Harry. This is Woody venting his spleen for the masses, and seeming to toy with the "playing himself" questions. It may not be pleasant to watch, but it's never dull. Again, his Jewish fixations can be offensive, though the scenes with his sister and brother-in-law are amongst the funniest in this not quite laugh-a-minute vehicle. I loved the bit where he tells his sister's husband: "I think you're the opposite of paranoid. I think you go around with the insane delusion that people like you". Yeah, most of the jokes at this stage in his career are recycled, but they're given a new take by the level of unsettling acidity contained in this picture. Annie Hall this isn't. The 1990s won't be remembered as a golden age for Allen's work, a period where he was getting more laughs voicing a cartoon ant than in his own movies. Altogether he wrote and directed ten new films, as well as a grating TV movie of his 60s play/film Don't Drink The Water (4). Films like Alice (5), Manhattan Murder Mystery (6) or Shadows and Fog (5) are watchable yet forgettable, the first decade for Allen where the so-so outnumbered the good. Yet there's still some first rate work in his 90s period, with Husbands and Wives (7) treading familiar ground but in subtle new ways. Sweet and Lowdown (7), a biopic of a fictitious jazz musician, brims with invention... though his first musical, Everyone Says I Love You (q.v.) sadly does not. Perhaps most notable in the 90s is the casting of actors to play the "Woody Allen" role, as he was entering his 60s and perhaps straining even his own much-tested formula of "young girl falls for older intellectual". In this regard then Kenneth Brannagh surprisingly does a better job than John Cusack, playing a substitute in the rewarding Celebrity (7), as opposed to Cusack's turn in the jarring Bullets Over Broadway (5). Which brings us back to Deconstructing Harry, as Allen originally had no wish to star in the lead. Deconstructing Harry isn't a pleasant film to watch by any means. It's crass, foul-mouthed and even obnoxious on occasion. But the fragmented, sketchy nature of events and inventive sequences make it an easier viewing experience than an extended narrative. Not only that, but in watching something which appears to be such a personal statement, then it may not be Allen's most likable or accomplished film, but it remains one of the most intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Allen's homage to (and send-up of) WILD STRAWBERRIES has its pluses and minuses. It's interesting, and in a way refreshing, to see him being so blatantly crass. It's one of his darkest movies, and maybe his most cynical comedy. Some of it is riotously funny, like the confrontation with Kirstie Alley in the middle of a patient's therapy session, or his version of Hell (with Billy Crystal in one of his most enjoyable roles). But with all the little sub-stories going on, it comes off like a clearinghouse for unfinished ideas. Also, the fragmented, jerky editing (because he's being "deconstructed," get it?) is an annoying quirk that adds little. Still, there's a lots of laughs to be had and it's an interesting bit of self-deprecation combined with self-admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good Woody Allen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block is a successful writer who gets inspiration from people he knows.Everybody doesn't like that.And he has his flaws, like pills and whores.Now his old university is honoring him.Harry wants to take his son Hilly to the ceremony, but his ex-wife Joan says no.But Harry takes him there anyway, as he does take a prostitute named Cookie and a friend called Richard.What a day to remember that will be! Deconstructing Harry is a Woody Allen film from 1997.Woody Allen gives a really great performance in this movie.Luckily he cast himself.No complaints about the rest of the cast either.Kirstie Alley plays the part of Joan, Harry's ex-wife.Billy Crystal, who gets to do next year's Oscars again, plays Larry/The Devil.Lucy Davis is Lucy.Bob Balaban plays Richard.Elisabeth Shue plays Fay.Paul Giamatti is Prof. Abbott.Philip Bosco is Prof. Clark.Mariel Hemingway, who was also in Allen's Manhattan, plays Beth Kramer.Hazelle Goodman is Cookie.Amy Irving is Jane.Eric Lloyd plays Hilly.Now 90-year old Gene Saks plays Harry's Father.Tony Sirico is Policeman at Jail.Then there are some characters that are of Harry's creation.Richard Benjamin plays Ken.Julia Louis-Dreyfus is Leslie.Tobey Maguire plays Harvey Stern.Jennifer Garner is Woman in Elevator.Stanley Tucci is Paul Epstein.Demi Moore plays Helen.Robin Williams is Mel.Julie Kavner is Grace.This is a very fine Woody Allen movie of the 90's.It's often funny.You find yourself most amused, when they're driving with the hooker and doing some car singing.Also out of focus Robin Williams is hilarious.I get seasick just by looking at him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harry is a writer, Block.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another all-star cast, another central role played by writer-director Woody Allen and another look at a character full of flaws and neuroses, we're in very familiar territory this time around. Allen plays Harry Block, a writer who is struggling for the first time in his life with writer's block and who is also tense about an upcoming honour he is to receive from his old school. As he tries to iron out the many wrinkles in his life and deal with his worries he finds himself encountering many of his literary creations (both fictional and in the form of the real, living people he based them upon) and getting advice from them along the way. The notion of the artist confronted by his creations and the consequences of his work is a good one and the weaving of the fantasy strands through the reality of the piece allows for a lot of fun (especially when comparing a fictional character to the real person they were based on) but this film, overall, just somehow misses the mark. The script isn't quite sharp enough, none of the performers get enough time to make a good impression and nothing feels as if it's actually moving a narrative along from start to finish. With a cast including Bob Balaban, Judy Davis, Billy Crystal, Robin Williams, Richard Benjamin, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Eric Bogosian, Kirstie Alley, Julie Kavner, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Tony Sirico, Demi Moore and Elisabeth Shue it's a real shame that nobody gets a chance to shine. Billy Crystal gets to have the most fun but Robin Williams stars in the most enjoyable fantasy sequence as an actor who one day suddenly goes out of focus. As others have said, this is worth seeing as a companion piece to Stardust Memories (with that being about the director and this being about the writer) but I just found myself watching long sections of the film without actually, properly enjoying it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Digging to the core; leave no stone unturned.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Mighty Aphrodite is a nice Woody Allen, then Deconstructing Harry is certainly the pinnacle of his nasty side. Indeed, for non-Woody Allen fans, it would seem difficult to understand how two vastly different films could come from the same mind. Yet, the genius of Allen lays primarily in his writing, able to create and expound upon a brilliant idea of the story of a man who is unable to cope the negative and horrible lifestyle he abides with the successful and insightful writing and art he creates fictionally. This is a difficult film to review as it unfolds itself in a very bipolar manner: cinematically it works on the highest scale with terrific acting, direction, editing and one of Woody's best scripts. Yet, on the other hand, it is quite possibly his meanest and most cynical portrait of humanity. The character of Harry Block (whom no one was willing to play until Allen finally took it himself) is incredibly neurotic, egotistical, nihilistic and narcissistic and Allen takes him to the very end of his rope, almost encouraging us to not feel any sympathy towards him at all. Certainly no one else does; his entire family hates him for the way he vaguely portrays them in his books as cheap stereotypes of their personalities and beliefs. Still, there may be the slightest bit of humanity within this ball of neuroses if only because Woody Allen gives one of his very best performances here. Again, I must praise the large and star-studded cast for carrying much of the heavy material, especially in scenes that would feel out of place in other hands. In particular, Judy Davis, Elisabeth Shue and Bob Balaban are very good. I must also give praise to Billy Crystal who personifies the devil himself in Harry's mind and is evilly funny. I guess this should be recommended but only for serious Woody Allen fans. It convincingly gives an argument for why and how Allen is able to rationalize all the crazy events he has gone through in his life. Personally, I cannot say that I always agree with his worldview. But, he always does have something interesting to say and if he can continue to say it through films like this, then I feel I will be able to sit through them. However, be warned: this is a side of Woody Allen never seen prior and hardly seen since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mixed Feelings...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick Cluxton
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been looking forward to seeing this film for quite a while, and when I finally had a chance I was pretty quick to take it up. As I started it, I regretted it immediately, I was bored and annoyed. Towards the end, it began to grow on me, but a lot just didn't do it for me. What I liked: I absolutely love the concept and the story. I have not seen any like it. What I like most is that while there is an actual plot and external events, it's more of a character study. They take an unlikable character and give him plenty of depth and sympathy to make up for his brash decisions and opinions. I love Woody Allen as a writer. I also liked the short stories; how they were narrated, the actual relevance they had to Harry's problems and friends, and how they were somewhat diverse. It wasn't just about the message. I both liked and disliked the scenes where they would cut to the same shot. It is very reminiscent of Jean- Loc Goddard's Breathless, which at times gave it a very relaxed, more realistic feel, considering that you could interpret that there were probably moments of silence between conversation, like something that happens in real conversation. However, when you cut in mid-sentence or make too many quick cuts, it's distracting and annoying to try and listen. What I hated: While I love that film is about Harry Block, I hated him. His guts, his obsession with sex, and the fact that he is so damn awkward. I hate Woody Allen as an actor. I appreciate when people stutter, pause, mix up words, or ramble in movies because that's what people do in real life. However, Woody Allen takes it and makes it absolutely obnoxious. His arms flail around, he never makes eye contact (or keeps his eyes on the road while driving). Overall, the word I would use to describe this movie is 'inconsistent,' with some scene being very funny and entertaining, while others made me want to scratch my DVD apart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing the indestructible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block (Woody Allen) is a neurotic, jittery, pill-popping author, condemned by those who known him well, and hailed by those who don't know him at all. Block has written lengthy, verbose novels that are thinly-disguised to hide the real relationships in his life, and for that reason, he has successfully alienated himself from all of his formers friends and family members. He often spends his days lonely, drinking, and hanging out with prostitutes, who he pays ample amounts of money to in order to get a quick-fix. The current silver-lining in Block's sad, dreary existence is that he will soon be recognized in a forthcoming ceremony by the university that kicked him out. He desperately wants company when he embarks on this trip, but because his novels have made it impossible for people to sympathize or like him on any level, he is left with quite a challenge. Even his ex-wife forbids him to spend the day with his young son so he can see his father may not be such a loser after all. Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is many things, but one of the most notable is it exists as an ode to the films of acclaimed Swedish director Ingmar Bergman. The film's plot alone mirrors that of Wild Strawberries, one of the man's most loved, which centered on a man and his pregnant daughter-in-law driving through the country so he could be granted with an award. The film made the tricky but probable analysis that a man can be loved by those who don't know him and simultaneously be hated by those who know him all too well. It was a tremendous achievement in foreign cinema and, in my opinion based on what I've seen thus far, Bergman's best film. Furthermore, this is one of Allen's darkest efforts to date. Not only is the film's protagonist almost remorseless in his treatment of others, but the way certain scenes are written and executed truly question how we're exactly supposed to respond. Take for example the scene when Block's panic attacks get the best of him and he needs to be consoled by a hooker he invited over the night before. While the relationship is nice - and without a doubt deeper than most prostitute/client relationships - it definitely shows just how depressing and almost broken Block's life is to the point where he needs to be reassured and comforted by a prostitute. The nihilism and cynicism of Allen's work shockingly doesn't become the detraction in the film, whereas the choppy narrative does and questionable ending does. The narrative, which continues to bounce between the current events in Block's life and the past events/relationships he held, is a bit too erratic and jumbled, quickly switching back and forth between the past and present with only a moderate amount of continuity. Not to mention the ending feels a bit put-on and unbelievable considering all that Block has put up with during the course of the film. Returning to the thought that the film is one giant homage to the works of Bergman, consider Allen's comically potent portrayal of the Devil here. Bergman made the Devil a living, breathing character in his film The Seventh Seal and made the film very existential and thought-provoking. Allen pays close attention-to-detail in terms of character relations and how one person after another is presented here. He animates the Devil character (played by Billy Crystal) terrifically here, using the right amount of black humor and comic-timing. Deconstructing Harry is a cynical delight of a film making exceptional use of Allen's writing/directing talents, but also the immensity and diversity of the cast at hand. Each star, whether it be Kirstie Alley, Julia Louise-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Billy Crystal, or Robin Williams, gets their own time to shine in the picture and all of them feel welcome and completely in-place in Allen's darkly funny world. It's once again apparent that Allen can make deeply personal, intriguing pictures, yet still be so foreign to his audience as a whole. Starring: Woody Allen, Caroline Aaron, Kirstie Alley, Bob Balaban, Richard Benjamin, Eric Bogosian, Billy Crystal, Judy Davis, Hazelle Goodman, Mariel Hemingway, Amy Irving, Julie Kavner, Eric Lloyd, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Tobey Maguire, Demi Moore, Elisabeth Shue, Stanley Tucci, and Robin Williams. Directed by: Woody Allen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry, understanding Woody ... and ourselves ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Deconstructing Harry" stands, in my opinion, as one of Woody Allen's best, probably his last masterpiece although it doesn't have the 'masterpiece' vibe. It looks like a typical Woody Allen movie but watch it closely and you'll get more insights about the director, the artist, ultimately the man. If you're not interested in, enjoy the gags and forget about it  if you can. I am more and more confident that Woody Allen is never as inspired and of course- hilarious as when his movies work as media to expresses his personal fears, angst and frustrations. And being capable to distort life, facts and reality to produce insights based on his own living, and in the intellectual and emotional process, to enable us to question ourselves, is in my opinion the work of a true artist. The film might feel 'minor' compared to other Allen's films but for some reason, it touched me, not immediately, but the ending was one of Allen's most triumphal achievements. Don't let yourself guided by your first feelings, this is not Allen wrapped up in his own ego, the film works on higher levels, and use Allen's own demons to tunnel us into ours, to use our empathy as a lightning torch to find truth in our personal darkness. Woody Allen is the titular Harry, Block is his last name, a fitting one as the writer he plays seems to suffer from mental block, the nightmare of every writer. But this block is justified by the series of incidents that undermined his inspiration. "Deconstructing Harry" is set during the aftermath of Harry's best-seller's success, a novel where he unveiled his most intimate secrets involving his friends, ex-wives, sister, family and acquaintances. It is one thing to reveal one's intimate secrets but we tend to forget that our secrets involve our personal circle. As a writer, Harry doesn't embarrass with such dilemmas, inspiration commands the writing and the others' anger is only a collateral damage he can afford but still must deal with. He tries to hide the names, to use lamentable pseudonyms, but behind every character, there's Harry. The film, like "Radio Days" is a succession of little vignettes, all reflecting a part of Harry's life, this is what the whole deconstruction process is about, in a masterstroke of writing. Whether it's a writer whose wife rediscovered her Jewish faith after the birth of her son, an old man indulging himself to cannibalism, a man cheating on his wife in front of an old blind parent, it's all about Harry, his friends are not fooled, neither are we. Is there a message behind that? Yes, every single piece of work of an artist is autobiographical. I'm tired of the whole: "Woody Allen always plays the same character" argument, because rather than a criticism, this is the best homage he can receive. But I would specify it a little bit, he doesn't play the same character, but within his whole oeuvre, there is one and only one Woody Allen. To understand the personality, one has to follow his evolution step by step, film by film. In "Interiors", the artist put his own inspiration into perspective, in "Stardust Memories", his comical talent or in "Zelig", his capability to please to be part of the mood.. In "Deconstructing Harry", it seems like the constantly self-deprecating Woody Allen is finally over with his own demons, because he comes to one realization, this is the best thing he can do, this is the only talent he truly has, and he's only exploiting it for the best. One of his friends, played by Billy Crystal, stole his girlfriend, but he acknowledges he doesn't have his talent. And yes, Allen is the best screenwriter. At the film's apotheosis, when all the characters he created applauded him, you can see the overwhelming effect on his eyes, and for one second, we imagine Woody Allen being applauded by Annie Hall, Virgil, Hannah and her Sisters thanking him for having graced the silver screen and pleased a generation of movie goers, for more than 20 years. Almost 20 years later, Woody Allen is still prolific but you could feel a relief after "Deconstructing Harry", when he could finally get to more fictional stuff, and telling stories again. I didn't speak much of the film because it's typically Allenian with a great cast, a deliberately disjointed editing, sometimes confusing but I guess it's a benign artistic license in order to convey the chaotic aspect of Harry's life as a sort of story he tries to rewrite inside himself, with the same process of writing, erasing, rewriting, copy-pasting etc. But what rises above the whole chaos, is the self-reflexive approach of Allen to his own work, he did it with "Interiors" and "Stardust Memories", but the films were inspired by Bergman and Fellini's works. I guess it took the revival of his comical genius in the 80's and the early 90's so he could understand that the best one to talk about Woody and to deconstruct Woody, is still Woody. And from someone who wishes to become a writer and can't function in the cold and average normality of life, I realize that I'm more inclined to bloom during writing, and stop being so out-of-focus, I should be the one to give people the right glasses to see what I'm worth. This out-of-focus metaphor is a strike of comical genius, and it touched a very sensitive chord. I loved "Deconstructing Harry" in a very deep and personal level and as I get older, I feel a very strong connection to the artistic and even neurotic personality of Woody Allen. To deconstruct Harry is to understand Woody, and ... a certain part of ourselves, imprisoned in a life of futile conventions and begging for expression, no matter how hard, and painful or shameful they are. I guess we should all learn to deconstruct ourselves to be over with our inner demons.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The love between writer and character.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Dennen
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is, in my opinion, one of Woody Allen's most underrated films. Often overlooked by a careers' worth of other more well known work, this late 90's Drama plays out a relationship seldom looked at; the relationship between a writer and their intellectual property. The characters in this film act as friends and loved ones, or rather memories of friends and loved ones. It's a look inside the mind of a neurotic writer, a writer whose life is both hitting a professional peak, while simultaneously hitting a personal low. Harry Block (Woody Allen), is dealing with past demons as well as present hurdles, all while preparing to receive a major award. To help deal with this accumulation of problems, characters from his fictional stories seep into his reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Allen's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woody Allen's Deconstructing Harry is a rare film that takes it's title in the most literal ways, both in structure and in storytelling. The plot centers around Harry Block (played as only Allen himself could), a man suffering from writer's block as he prepares to accept an award from his old university, but this is only a loose strain to give the story a narrative though. What it's really focused on is Harry himself, his mind and his characters. In the traditional Allen sense, we get some external monologuing as he explores the mind of this neurotic, stuck and seemingly hopeless man, but he does it in a way that I've never seen him work before. The style of comedy is of course that Allen allure that no one could imitate, but there's also a vulgarity to it that I've never seen him go for before. There are words that I never thought I'd see in a Woody Allen film and the jokes are incredibly graphic, but it gives it this sense of brutal honesty that I haven't experienced from him up to this point. It's absolutely hilarious and quite true, it felt comically in the same sense of Louis C.K.'s work; vulgar and borderline offensive, but totally true to the point where it makes it's audience take a long look in the mirror. As we explore Harry, his few friends and his many exes, we are treated to short vignettes taken from his previous written work. Allen explores the mind of a writer so thoroughly it's mesmerizing, giving us looks into how true the "you write what you know" expression is, with characters that are directly based on his past lovers and himself. Each short story is hilarious in it's own right, but also sheds more light into the character himself, which is the ultimate draw of the film. I've never liked a performance from the writer/director more than I have here. He's got the neurosis and cynicism that he is a master at, but there's also an authenticity and darkness to him that I felt was more exposed than I've seen him before. His editing work is a masterstroke as well as he depicts Harry's real life as fractured, making quick cuts in scenes so that nothing seems to be fluid but it gives it this stream-of-consciousness touch that becomes fluid in itself, in detailing what he wants to accomplish. When we see his work displayed, there's no fragmentation, no awkward cuts, everything runs smoothly. The final scene of the film states the themes a little too strongly, as he practically spoonfeeds them to the audience, but it's a brilliant display of how a writer can become so broken and fractured in his own life that the only way he can achieve any clarity is through his work. A dark, touching, hilarious film with a strong message. Plus, it opens with Julia Louis-Dreyfus getting bent over and plowed in front of a blind woman, and you don't get much funnier than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It's me thinly disguised in fact, I don't even think I should disguise it any more  it's me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Movie_Cat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Deconstructing Harry is probably Woody Allen's most interesting and controversial film from his troubled 90s period. Coming at the height of turmoil in his personal life, the same year that Deconstructing Harry was released, Allen married Soon Yi Previn and the world was given an insight into their relationship in the rewarding documentary Wild Man Blues (6). Deconstructing Harry sees him slam reality and fiction together, giving (except for one exception) an expletive-free and free-flowing series of fantasy vignettes with jump- cut, foul-mouthed bites of reality. For this reason more than any other it's a film that could upset Allen purists, as his attempt to capture real life sees multiple uses of the word "f***" and even the "c" word coming from Woody's lips on two occasions. Is the film misogynist? Possibly. Woody certainly appears to have anger towards women here, and while the ladies of the night so romantically depicted in the likable-but-bland Mighty Aphrodite (6) are here "whores" and "hookers", there's also more than an element of racial patronage. The adjoinder from an African American prostitute over whether she knows what a black hole is ("Yeah... that's how I make my living") is probably the most repellent line in an Allen film, bar none. Even today Woody is still capable of making watchable films, but they're rarely essential and tend towards the reactionary. Little of his later period has come close to matching the vibrancy and sheer anxiety-based energy of Deconstructing Harry. This is Woody venting his spleen for the masses, and seeming to toy with the "playing himself" questions. It may not be pleasant to watch, but it's never dull. Again, his Jewish fixations can be offensive, though the scenes with his sister and brother-in-law are amongst the funniest in this not quite laugh-a-minute vehicle. I loved the bit where he tells his sister's husband: "I think you're the opposite of paranoid. I think you go around with the insane delusion that people like you". Yeah, most of the jokes at this stage in his career are recycled, but they're given a new take by the level of unsettling acidity contained in this picture. Annie Hall this isn't. The 1990s won't be remembered as a golden age for Allen's work, a period where he was getting more laughs voicing a cartoon ant than in his own movies. Altogether he wrote and directed ten new films, as well as a grating TV movie of his 60s play/film Don't Drink The Water (4). Films like Alice (5), Manhattan Murder Mystery (6) or Shadows and Fog (5) are watchable yet forgettable, the first decade for Allen where the so-so outnumbered the good. Yet there's still some first rate work in his 90s period, with Husbands and Wives (7) treading familiar ground but in subtle new ways. Sweet and Lowdown (7), a biopic of a fictitious jazz musician, brims with invention... though his first musical, Everyone Says I Love You (q.v.) sadly does not. Perhaps most notable in the 90s is the casting of actors to play the "Woody Allen" role, as he was entering his 60s and perhaps straining even his own much-tested formula of "young girl falls for older intellectual". In this regard then Kenneth Brannagh surprisingly does a better job than John Cusack, playing a substitute in the rewarding Celebrity (7), as opposed to Cusack's turn in the jarring Bullets Over Broadway (5). Which brings us back to Deconstructing Harry, as Allen originally had no wish to star in the lead. Deconstructing Harry isn't a pleasant film to watch by any means. It's crass, foul-mouthed and even obnoxious on occasion. But the fragmented, sketchy nature of events and inventive sequences make it an easier viewing experience than an extended narrative. Not only that, but in watching something which appears to be such a personal statement, then it may not be Allen's most likable or accomplished film, but it remains one of the most intriguing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deconstructing Harry (1997)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin Teller
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Allen's homage to (and send-up of) WILD STRAWBERRIES has its pluses and minuses. It's interesting, and in a way refreshing, to see him being so blatantly crass. It's one of his darkest movies, and maybe his most cynical comedy. Some of it is riotously funny, like the confrontation with Kirstie Alley in the middle of a patient's therapy session, or his version of Hell (with Billy Crystal in one of his most enjoyable roles). But with all the little sub-stories going on, it comes off like a clearinghouse for unfinished ideas. Also, the fragmented, jerky editing (because he's being "deconstructed," get it?) is an annoying quirk that adds little. Still, there's a lots of laughs to be had and it's an interesting bit of self-deprecation combined with self-admiration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good Woody Allen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Block is a successful writer who gets inspiration from people he knows.Everybody doesn't like that.And he has his flaws, like pills and whores.Now his old university is honoring him.Harry wants to take his son Hilly to the ceremony, but his ex-wife Joan says no.But Harry takes him there anyway, as he does take a prostitute named Cookie and a friend called Richard.What a day to remember that will be! Deconstructing Harry is a Woody Allen film from 1997.Woody Allen gives a really great performance in this movie.Luckily he cast himself.No complaints about the rest of the cast either.Kirstie Alley plays the part of Joan, Harry's ex-wife.Billy Crystal, who gets to do next year's Oscars again, plays Larry/The Devil.Lucy Davis is Lucy.Bob Balaban plays Richard.Elisabeth Shue plays Fay.Paul Giamatti is Prof. Abbott.Philip Bosco is Prof. Clark.Mariel Hemingway, who was also in Allen's Manhattan, plays Beth Kramer.Hazelle Goodman is Cookie.Amy Irving is Jane.Eric Lloyd plays Hilly.Now 90-year old Gene Saks plays Harry's Father.Tony Sirico is Policeman at Jail.Then there are some characters that are of Harry's creation.Richard Benjamin plays Ken.Julia Louis-Dreyfus is Leslie.Tobey Maguire plays Harvey Stern.Jennifer Garner is Woman in Elevator.Stanley Tucci is Paul Epstein.Demi Moore plays Helen.Robin Williams is Mel.Julie Kavner is Grace.This is a very fine Woody Allen movie of the 90's.It's often funny.You find yourself most amused, when they're driving with the hooker and doing some car singing.Also out of focus Robin Williams is hilarious.I get seasick just by looking at him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harry is a writer, Block.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyler-and-jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another all-star cast, another central role played by writer-director Woody Allen and another look at a character full of flaws and neuroses, we're in very familiar territory this time around. Allen plays Harry Block, a writer who is struggling for the first time in his life with writer's block and who is also tense about an upcoming honour he is to receive from his old school. As he tries to iron out the many wrinkles in his life and deal with his worries he finds himself encountering many of his literary creations (both fictional and in the form of the real, living people he based them upon) and getting advice from them along the way. The notion of the artist confronted by his creations and the consequences of his work is a good one and the weaving of the fantasy strands through the reality of the piece allows for a lot of fun (especially when comparing a fictional character to the real person they were based on) but this film, overall, just somehow misses the mark. The script isn't quite sharp enough, none of the performers get enough time to make a good impression and nothing feels as if it's actually moving a narrative along from start to finish. With a cast including Bob Balaban, Judy Davis, Billy Crystal, Robin Williams, Richard Benjamin, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Eric Bogosian, Kirstie Alley, Julie Kavner, Tobey Maguire, Stanley Tucci, Tony Sirico, Demi Moore and Elisabeth Shue it's a real shame that nobody gets a chance to shine. Billy Crystal gets to have the most fun but Robin Williams stars in the most enjoyable fantasy sequence as an actor who one day suddenly goes out of focus. As others have said, this is worth seeing as a companion piece to Stardust Memories (with that being about the director and this being about the writer) but I just found myself watching long sections of the film without actually, properly enjoying it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Digging to the core; leave no stone unturned.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Mighty Aphrodite is a nice Woody Allen, then Deconstructing Harry is certainly the pinnacle of his nasty side. Indeed, for non-Woody Allen fans, it would seem difficult to understand how two vastly different films could come from the same mind. Yet, the genius of Allen lays primarily in his writing, able to create and expound upon a brilliant idea of the story of a man who is unable to cope the negative and horrible lifestyle he abides with the successful and insightful writing and art he creates fictionally. This is a difficult film to review as it unfolds itself in a very bipolar manner: cinematically it works on the highest scale with terrific acting, direction, editing and one of Woody's best scripts. Yet, on the other hand, it is quite possibly his meanest and most cynical portrait of humanity. The character of Harry Block (whom no one was willing to play until Allen finally took it himself) is incredibly neurotic, egotistical, nihilistic and narcissistic and Allen takes him to the very end of his rope, almost encouraging us to not feel any sympathy towards him at all. Certainly no one else does; his entire family hates him for the way he vaguely portrays them in his books as cheap stereotypes of their personalities and beliefs. Still, there may be the slightest bit of humanity within this ball of neuroses if only because Woody Allen gives one of his very best performances here. Again, I must praise the large and star-studded cast for carrying much of the heavy material, especially in scenes that would feel out of place in other hands. In particular, Judy Davis, Elisabeth Shue and Bob Balaban are very good. I must also give praise to Billy Crystal who personifies the devil himself in Harry's mind and is evilly funny. I guess this should be recommended but only for serious Woody Allen fans. It convincingly gives an argument for why and how Allen is able to rationalize all the crazy events he has gone through in his life. Personally, I cannot say that I always agree with his worldview. But, he always does have something interesting to say and if he can continue to say it through films like this, then I feel I will be able to sit through them. However, be warned: this is a side of Woody Allen never seen prior and hardly seen since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
