<filme>
 <id>
  346
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119396
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Jackie Brown
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A flight attendant becomes a key figure in a plot between the police and an arms dealer.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Jackie Brown is the name of a flight attendant who gets caught smuggling her boss' gun money on the airline she works for. Luckily for her, the Fed Ray Nicolet and the LA Cop Mark Dargus decide to team up in order to arrest the arms dealer she works for, whose name they don't even know. Here's when she has to choose one way: tell Nicolet and Dargus about Ordell Robbie (the arms dealer) and get her freedom -except that if Ordell suspects you're talking about him, you're dead- or keep her mouth shut and do some time. That's when she meets Max Cherry -her bail bondsman-, a late fifties, recently separated, burnt-out man, who falls in love with her. Then Jackie comes up with a plan to play the Feds off against Ordell and the guys he works with -Louis Gara and Melanie Ralston, among others- and walk off with their money. But she needs Max's help. No one is going to stand in the way of his million dollar payoff...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   arms dealer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   atf
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bail
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   flight attendant
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Quentin Tarantino
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Quentin Tarantino
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Elmore Leonard
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Pam Grier
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Samuel L. Jackson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert Forster
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Tarantino Crime Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pam Grier, Samuel L. Jackson, Robert Forster, Robert De Niro, Michael Keaton, Michael Bowen, Chris Tucker, Tommy 'Tiny' Lister and Bridget Fonda star in Quentin Tarantino's 1997 crime thriller based on a novel, "Rum Punch." This begins with flight attendant, Jackie Brown (Grier) who gets arrested for possession of drugs and a large amount of cash. She learns that her gun-dealing friend, Ordell Robbie (Jackson) set her up and decides to get back at him. Forster plays bail bondsman, Max Cherry who is hired by Ordell to bail her out of jail for 10 grand. Soon, Jackie meets Max who not only falls for her, but helps her steal Ordell's cash. Keaton plays FBI agent, Ray Nicollete, Bowen plays his partner, Mark Dargus, De Niro plays Ordell's pal, Lois Gara, Fonda plays Ordell's mistress, Melanie Ralston, Tucker (Friday) plays Ordell's friend, Beaumont Livingston and Lister (Friday) plays Max's assistant, Winston. This is a good film with a great cast that also has a nice tribute to 70's films & music. I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Excitement or Violence You Would Look For In a Tarantino Film,But Still Really Good,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Brown is a terrific movie with a very well developed storyline like all Quentin Tarantino's movies and a very talented cast.I certainly didn't enjoy it as much as Tarantino's previous work,Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction,it wasn't as violent,action packed or as exciting as them and I was a bit disappointed by it,but it still is a really good movie.This focuses a lot more on characters and dialogue,which didn't bother me because I really liked these characters and the dialogue was very well written.The cast are all fantastic,Pam Grier and Robert Forster both did a fantastic job,but the best performances had to be Samuel L Jackson and Robert De Niro,their both some of my favourite actors,they always get really interested in their characters,and this is no exception.Fans of Quentin Tarantino will be disappointed by Jackie Brown,but its still a very good,character driven movie. Jackie Brown (Pam Grier) gets involved with an arms dealer and the police force after a few mistakes she made in the past that brought her into jail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quentin, you owe us an apology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    videorama-759-859391
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When first hearing of this title, you would of expected another Pulp Fiction. Sadly here you;re very mistaken. You've been very short changed I'm afraid. Working from Elmore Leonard's novel, Quentin must of been self conscious in his telling of this nothing impressive tale. There's hardly any Tarantino humor or VIOLENCE. We have a few stretched out scenes, wasted ones, of little significance, ones that take place in Jackson's Venice beach apartment. We can tell he's held back here, as if to honor or not disrespect crime author, Leonard's book. Pam Grier playing the title, one of the many great performances, is a 44 year old black woman trying to make ends meat, by earning her undeserved share of money made off selling guns, that her boss, Ordell Robbie sells. Jackson is fun to watch in this, playing bad good, in reverse to the much gentler and reserved teacher he played in 187. When Grier is arrested by the feds, she has her own way of snaking out of it, outwitting authorities, while hatching a plan to rip off Ordeal. You gotta admire the courage and strength of the character, but the storytelling just seems to be prolonged. There's not many surprises in the thriller department either. We know what each character wants, whether he/she is good or bad. They're an open book. Deniro was fun to watch as as ex parolee friend of Jackson, who lags around in Jackson's apartment with skinny bikini bodied pot smoking Mel (Fonda). Her murder in the car park was a shock. On the whole Jackie Brown was a bitter disappointment when seeing it in the cinema. This disappointing feature almost had me wondering if I was in the right cinema. I enjoyed it more second time around on video, but this Tarantino flick is a two an hour flick that could of easily been told in 90 minutes. It's just a prolonged story with a lot of flat, not much happening scenes. If Tarantino did it his way, minus Leonard's' influence, we would of had a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the less Tarantinesque of Tarantino's movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow I missed 'Jackie Brown' - a Tarantino movie made in 1997 which takes in his directing career a chronological place between 'Pulp Fiction' and the two 'Kill Bill' movies. It is to some extent the less Tarantinesque of the Tarantino movies - 150 minutes of solid film making, a violent gangster movie very much in tone with the 90s, but lacking the excesses and the sarcasm of his greatest films. I am sure though that many other folks will consider it the best or one of the best films in his career, exactly for the same reasons I did not like it completely. Great acting by Samuel L. Jackson, Robert De Niro, Bridget Fonda and Palm Grier. Excellent soul music soundtrack - Tarantino's mobsters have a special taste for music, did you notice?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Authentic and well acted but it drags on for far too long
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kluseba
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino is a man between genius and madness who has created some of the best movies ever but also a few true Fails in my opinion. "Jackie Brown" is just between both extremes for me and is maybe his most unspectacular film to date. On the positive side, this movie is Tarantino's most organic one until now. The characters are more credible than usual, the dialogues aren't all too over the top and the story line is quite easy to follow. The movie includes no special effects, shock moments or unexpected twists and feels surprisingly down to earth for a Quentin Tarantino movie. From that point of view, it's a quite unique movie from him. The acting is authentic and very well done. Pam Grier plays an attractive and intelligent lady in her forties who starts the movie as a victim just to become the one who plays with each other character around her. Samuel L. Jackson does a convincing role as superficial but not dumb gangster. Robert Forster plays a bondsman and smart gentleman with a lot of charisma as well. He's the actor I somehow like the most in this movie. In addition to the movie's authentic mood and the great acting, the soundtrack is as always quite convincing as well and introduces us to many great Afroamerican musicians. I must though admit that I preferred by far the soundtracks of other Tarantino movies such as "Kill Bill" or "Django Unchained" for example. On the other side, the movie definitely has its lengths as many Tarantino movies. There are some more or less important endless dialogues that should have been shortened in my opinion. This movie would have just been fine with a running time between ninety and one-hundred-five minutes in my opinion. Apart of that, the story is not only down to earth but also quite unspectacular and there isn't that much going on in two hours and a half. The movie feels a little bit too simple at some points. Apart of the acting, the movie lacks of a true highlight. The killing scenes are really unspectacular and you don't see very much. It's the same thing for one single and quite boring sex scene. The movie is supposed to have a few humorous moments but they really aren't all that memorable. The showdown in the mall also lacks tension. It shows us the same scene from three different views which gets quite redundant. The only truly gripping moments in this movie are the first E encounter between Pam Grier and Samuel L. Jackson in her apartment and the scene when Robert Forster and Samuel L. Jackson go to the Office of the bondsman. In the end, this film could have been a standout movie in Tranatino's career because it's quite different from what he usually does. The film though fails from that point of view and drags on far too long and turns out to be quite unspectacular or even boring at some points. It all feels more like a theatre play where convincing dialogues by solid actors matter but not much more. I have seen far worse but also far better movies and I would only recommend this flick to die hard fans of Quentin Tarantino's works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this 1 star because I had to give it something. I really REALLY hated what I saw of this movie. I didn't actually last till the end. I was going to try and then I decided I had more important things to do with my time, like wash some clothes and feed the dogs. I adore Tarantino films. This one was a complete dud. Self-indulgent nonsense about characters I couldn't care less about talking about stuff that really doesn't matter. All the dialogue was slow & dragged on and on pointlessly. There was no action to speak of and the plot was thin and uninteresting. Really, don't waste your time. And please, if you're a Tarantino fan, don't poison your appreciation for his work by watching this stinker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Brown getting' down!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike dewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may be old news now, but Quentin T. showed out in this fast and sassy maxi-scam caper flick. He couldn't have hired a better acting ensemble to pull this off, to wit, Pam Grier, Robert Forster, Sammy J., Bobby D., Brigid F., Chris Tucker, Michael K., etc. For starters, I think this is the best performance of Pam G's career: she exhibits a multi-dimensional persona here I have never seen her pull off before. For example, notice how she effortlessly segues from the street-savvy demeanor whilst in the company of Sammy J., etc., to the middle-class, nice girl, good-diction modus operandi when she's in the company of the the likes of Robert F. She shows how tight her game really is and isn't afraid to do whatever it takes to pull off her intended caper. Robert F., mild of manner and well composed, is cast as the antithesis of the Sammy J. character who is a down-and-dirty, bombastic rascal. Notice how Robert F's character, a white bail-bondsman, effortlessly mixes in well with people of color without being obsequious or trying to be hip: He is merely himself and lets that fact set the tone for whatever may ensue. Sammy J. is his usual awesome self, with great support from Bobby D. and Brigid F. That unholy trio makes sparks fly as the drama unfolds. Notice how Bobby D's character slowly shifts gears from a mellow understated ex-con to a violent shooter when he becomes unduly provoked: a nice touch from Mr. DeNiro. Quentin T's usually crisp directorial skills are in evidence here, as his cutting in and moving back and forth in time work very well. His rewinds in time allow the viewer to see the same scenes from another vantage point so that one can see the logical progression of events from several angles. All that and an awesome, cleverly positioned soundtrack that kicks much booty! How about "Across 110th Street" at the ending? Did she "get across" or what?! This is my favorite Quentin T. film: ya gotta check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some thoughts...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artistgp
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll refrain from summarizing the entire film because you've either already seen it or you're interested in watching the story. Instead I'll just share some thoughts I had with you. It definitely felt like a step down from most of his films. There wasn't anything revolutionary about the film. The beginning seemed to lag for a good while. It eventually picked up steam during the heist portion of the movie, but that in itself didn't really seem to have anything new to add to that genre. The were some really nice long shots in the film (I'm a huge fan of artistically staged lengthy takes), the car pulling into the empty lot on the other side of the fence is a good example. I will say tho, that there were some long shots that seemed to be stretched out for no apparent reason other than just to do it. The acting was solid. The characters were a mix. Jackie was stuck in a dead end job for somewhere around twenty years and yet she proved to be quite the master mind by the end of the movie. Kind of makes you wonder why she wasn't able to advance in her career. Jackson's character was well played and was indeed intriguing, but after a while I kind of wished he would leave me alone. It's not a bad movie, but not one I would recommend to someone else. These are just my thoughts on this particular project. If you're interested in the film I'd urge you to see it and make your own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black Sheep of the Tarantino Family, Jackie's More Substance-Minded Than Style-Blinded
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Easily Quentin Tarantino's most mature work, which admittedly isn't saying much for a director who brought us the Five Point Palm Exploding Heart Technique and a literal blast of adrenaline to the heart. That's not to say his films have ever lacked in substance - rather, I think the true depth of their character is merely overshadowed by those visceral moments of graphic excess and their stylish methods of delivery. Jackie Brown, instead, manages to step out from that bloody shadow and shine on its own volition. Its lingering close-ups and long doses of heady silence give the impression that the plot is moving slowly, when in fact it's going roughly a mile a minute. Tarantino just wants us to savor the performances of his all-star cast and the tangle of plot threads that surrounds them before forcing our heads out the window and punching the gas in the last twenty minutes. Along the way, he subtly, efficiently grazes a gamut of emotions that leaves us deeply invested in the (often untimely) fate of each character. Rich, complex and rewarding, it's not as flashy as Pulp Fiction or Reservoir Dogs, but it's every bit as excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly enjoyable crime caper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tarantino is often derided by his dismissives as an over zealous, pop-culturally obsessed schizoid with a penchant for fetishizing violence and, oddly enough, feet. But in this 1997 adaptation of the Elmore Leonard novel, and hot off the heels off the watershed event that was Pulp Fiction three years prior, he chose to follow up his electric filmography by incorporating a slightly more complex and elegant plot in the form of a heist caper. What sets it apart from other entries in the genre (and subsequent adaptations of Leonard works by the likes of other gen X indie directors like Soderbergh), is Tarantino's unique combination of cinema homage and pastiche that gives the proceedings a fresh and vibrant aura. Tarantino skillfully employs elements of blaxploitation through choice soundtrack, camera work, and elegant casting. Pam Grier in the eponymous title role as a middle aged Afro-American woman attempting to emerge out on top of a crime sting is not only a headstrong and intelligently spunky protagonist, but through the course of the film she offers an acute sensitivity to her situation that adds a gravity to the story. coupled with a subtle turn by Robert Forster, in a similair comeback role to John Travolta in Pulp, as an aging, jaded bail bondsman who is injected with a burst of vitalic romantic interest in Jackie Brown, and the subsequent bonding that grows between them offers Tarantino his most empathetically human and thematic material thus far. But the most entertaining turn in from the cast is Samuel L Jackson as the fast-talking, foul mouthed thug who isn't quite as clever of a criminal as he thinks he is. The often witty and hilarious dialogue exchanges between he, Bridget Fonda, and an unassuming Robert DeNiro as a bumbling, apathetic accomplice is amusing and carries the film deftly onward, even when it threatens to be dragged down by the slightly dry plot. But there is a noticeable lack of cloying pop cultural references in the script that Tarantino is known for. Instead, it is all just great character acting, and he manages to make the mundane a roller coaster of verbal levity. The look of the picture is great, with skillfully composed shots and fine tuned audio, with a killer soundtrack to top it off. Jackie Brown is a tightly made film that delivers in its black humor and a feel good tale of one sassy feminist throwback getting the better of her clueless colleagues, and learning a little bit of mid life wisdom along the way. Highly recommended for fans of well constructed and stylish crime capers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Tarantino Crime Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pam Grier, Samuel L. Jackson, Robert Forster, Robert De Niro, Michael Keaton, Michael Bowen, Chris Tucker, Tommy 'Tiny' Lister and Bridget Fonda star in Quentin Tarantino's 1997 crime thriller based on a novel, "Rum Punch." This begins with flight attendant, Jackie Brown (Grier) who gets arrested for possession of drugs and a large amount of cash. She learns that her gun-dealing friend, Ordell Robbie (Jackson) set her up and decides to get back at him. Forster plays bail bondsman, Max Cherry who is hired by Ordell to bail her out of jail for 10 grand. Soon, Jackie meets Max who not only falls for her, but helps her steal Ordell's cash. Keaton plays FBI agent, Ray Nicollete, Bowen plays his partner, Mark Dargus, De Niro plays Ordell's pal, Lois Gara, Fonda plays Ordell's mistress, Melanie Ralston, Tucker (Friday) plays Ordell's friend, Beaumont Livingston and Lister (Friday) plays Max's assistant, Winston. This is a good film with a great cast that also has a nice tribute to 70's films & music. I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Excitement or Violence You Would Look For In a Tarantino Film,But Still Really Good,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Brown is a terrific movie with a very well developed storyline like all Quentin Tarantino's movies and a very talented cast.I certainly didn't enjoy it as much as Tarantino's previous work,Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction,it wasn't as violent,action packed or as exciting as them and I was a bit disappointed by it,but it still is a really good movie.This focuses a lot more on characters and dialogue,which didn't bother me because I really liked these characters and the dialogue was very well written.The cast are all fantastic,Pam Grier and Robert Forster both did a fantastic job,but the best performances had to be Samuel L Jackson and Robert De Niro,their both some of my favourite actors,they always get really interested in their characters,and this is no exception.Fans of Quentin Tarantino will be disappointed by Jackie Brown,but its still a very good,character driven movie. Jackie Brown (Pam Grier) gets involved with an arms dealer and the police force after a few mistakes she made in the past that brought her into jail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quentin, you owe us an apology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    videorama-759-859391
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When first hearing of this title, you would of expected another Pulp Fiction. Sadly here you;re very mistaken. You've been very short changed I'm afraid. Working from Elmore Leonard's novel, Quentin must of been self conscious in his telling of this nothing impressive tale. There's hardly any Tarantino humor or VIOLENCE. We have a few stretched out scenes, wasted ones, of little significance, ones that take place in Jackson's Venice beach apartment. We can tell he's held back here, as if to honor or not disrespect crime author, Leonard's book. Pam Grier playing the title, one of the many great performances, is a 44 year old black woman trying to make ends meat, by earning her undeserved share of money made off selling guns, that her boss, Ordell Robbie sells. Jackson is fun to watch in this, playing bad good, in reverse to the much gentler and reserved teacher he played in 187. When Grier is arrested by the feds, she has her own way of snaking out of it, outwitting authorities, while hatching a plan to rip off Ordeal. You gotta admire the courage and strength of the character, but the storytelling just seems to be prolonged. There's not many surprises in the thriller department either. We know what each character wants, whether he/she is good or bad. They're an open book. Deniro was fun to watch as as ex parolee friend of Jackson, who lags around in Jackson's apartment with skinny bikini bodied pot smoking Mel (Fonda). Her murder in the car park was a shock. On the whole Jackie Brown was a bitter disappointment when seeing it in the cinema. This disappointing feature almost had me wondering if I was in the right cinema. I enjoyed it more second time around on video, but this Tarantino flick is a two an hour flick that could of easily been told in 90 minutes. It's just a prolonged story with a lot of flat, not much happening scenes. If Tarantino did it his way, minus Leonard's' influence, we would of had a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the less Tarantinesque of Tarantino's movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow I missed 'Jackie Brown' - a Tarantino movie made in 1997 which takes in his directing career a chronological place between 'Pulp Fiction' and the two 'Kill Bill' movies. It is to some extent the less Tarantinesque of the Tarantino movies - 150 minutes of solid film making, a violent gangster movie very much in tone with the 90s, but lacking the excesses and the sarcasm of his greatest films. I am sure though that many other folks will consider it the best or one of the best films in his career, exactly for the same reasons I did not like it completely. Great acting by Samuel L. Jackson, Robert De Niro, Bridget Fonda and Palm Grier. Excellent soul music soundtrack - Tarantino's mobsters have a special taste for music, did you notice?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Authentic and well acted but it drags on for far too long
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kluseba
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino is a man between genius and madness who has created some of the best movies ever but also a few true Fails in my opinion. "Jackie Brown" is just between both extremes for me and is maybe his most unspectacular film to date. On the positive side, this movie is Tarantino's most organic one until now. The characters are more credible than usual, the dialogues aren't all too over the top and the story line is quite easy to follow. The movie includes no special effects, shock moments or unexpected twists and feels surprisingly down to earth for a Quentin Tarantino movie. From that point of view, it's a quite unique movie from him. The acting is authentic and very well done. Pam Grier plays an attractive and intelligent lady in her forties who starts the movie as a victim just to become the one who plays with each other character around her. Samuel L. Jackson does a convincing role as superficial but not dumb gangster. Robert Forster plays a bondsman and smart gentleman with a lot of charisma as well. He's the actor I somehow like the most in this movie. In addition to the movie's authentic mood and the great acting, the soundtrack is as always quite convincing as well and introduces us to many great Afroamerican musicians. I must though admit that I preferred by far the soundtracks of other Tarantino movies such as "Kill Bill" or "Django Unchained" for example. On the other side, the movie definitely has its lengths as many Tarantino movies. There are some more or less important endless dialogues that should have been shortened in my opinion. This movie would have just been fine with a running time between ninety and one-hundred-five minutes in my opinion. Apart of that, the story is not only down to earth but also quite unspectacular and there isn't that much going on in two hours and a half. The movie feels a little bit too simple at some points. Apart of the acting, the movie lacks of a true highlight. The killing scenes are really unspectacular and you don't see very much. It's the same thing for one single and quite boring sex scene. The movie is supposed to have a few humorous moments but they really aren't all that memorable. The showdown in the mall also lacks tension. It shows us the same scene from three different views which gets quite redundant. The only truly gripping moments in this movie are the first E encounter between Pam Grier and Samuel L. Jackson in her apartment and the scene when Robert Forster and Samuel L. Jackson go to the Office of the bondsman. In the end, this film could have been a standout movie in Tranatino's career because it's quite different from what he usually does. The film though fails from that point of view and drags on far too long and turns out to be quite unspectacular or even boring at some points. It all feels more like a theatre play where convincing dialogues by solid actors matter but not much more. I have seen far worse but also far better movies and I would only recommend this flick to die hard fans of Quentin Tarantino's works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this 1 star because I had to give it something. I really REALLY hated what I saw of this movie. I didn't actually last till the end. I was going to try and then I decided I had more important things to do with my time, like wash some clothes and feed the dogs. I adore Tarantino films. This one was a complete dud. Self-indulgent nonsense about characters I couldn't care less about talking about stuff that really doesn't matter. All the dialogue was slow & dragged on and on pointlessly. There was no action to speak of and the plot was thin and uninteresting. Really, don't waste your time. And please, if you're a Tarantino fan, don't poison your appreciation for his work by watching this stinker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Brown getting' down!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike dewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may be old news now, but Quentin T. showed out in this fast and sassy maxi-scam caper flick. He couldn't have hired a better acting ensemble to pull this off, to wit, Pam Grier, Robert Forster, Sammy J., Bobby D., Brigid F., Chris Tucker, Michael K., etc. For starters, I think this is the best performance of Pam G's career: she exhibits a multi-dimensional persona here I have never seen her pull off before. For example, notice how she effortlessly segues from the street-savvy demeanor whilst in the company of Sammy J., etc., to the middle-class, nice girl, good-diction modus operandi when she's in the company of the the likes of Robert F. She shows how tight her game really is and isn't afraid to do whatever it takes to pull off her intended caper. Robert F., mild of manner and well composed, is cast as the antithesis of the Sammy J. character who is a down-and-dirty, bombastic rascal. Notice how Robert F's character, a white bail-bondsman, effortlessly mixes in well with people of color without being obsequious or trying to be hip: He is merely himself and lets that fact set the tone for whatever may ensue. Sammy J. is his usual awesome self, with great support from Bobby D. and Brigid F. That unholy trio makes sparks fly as the drama unfolds. Notice how Bobby D's character slowly shifts gears from a mellow understated ex-con to a violent shooter when he becomes unduly provoked: a nice touch from Mr. DeNiro. Quentin T's usually crisp directorial skills are in evidence here, as his cutting in and moving back and forth in time work very well. His rewinds in time allow the viewer to see the same scenes from another vantage point so that one can see the logical progression of events from several angles. All that and an awesome, cleverly positioned soundtrack that kicks much booty! How about "Across 110th Street" at the ending? Did she "get across" or what?! This is my favorite Quentin T. film: ya gotta check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some thoughts...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artistgp
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll refrain from summarizing the entire film because you've either already seen it or you're interested in watching the story. Instead I'll just share some thoughts I had with you. It definitely felt like a step down from most of his films. There wasn't anything revolutionary about the film. The beginning seemed to lag for a good while. It eventually picked up steam during the heist portion of the movie, but that in itself didn't really seem to have anything new to add to that genre. The were some really nice long shots in the film (I'm a huge fan of artistically staged lengthy takes), the car pulling into the empty lot on the other side of the fence is a good example. I will say tho, that there were some long shots that seemed to be stretched out for no apparent reason other than just to do it. The acting was solid. The characters were a mix. Jackie was stuck in a dead end job for somewhere around twenty years and yet she proved to be quite the master mind by the end of the movie. Kind of makes you wonder why she wasn't able to advance in her career. Jackson's character was well played and was indeed intriguing, but after a while I kind of wished he would leave me alone. It's not a bad movie, but not one I would recommend to someone else. These are just my thoughts on this particular project. If you're interested in the film I'd urge you to see it and make your own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black Sheep of the Tarantino Family, Jackie's More Substance-Minded Than Style-Blinded
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Easily Quentin Tarantino's most mature work, which admittedly isn't saying much for a director who brought us the Five Point Palm Exploding Heart Technique and a literal blast of adrenaline to the heart. That's not to say his films have ever lacked in substance - rather, I think the true depth of their character is merely overshadowed by those visceral moments of graphic excess and their stylish methods of delivery. Jackie Brown, instead, manages to step out from that bloody shadow and shine on its own volition. Its lingering close-ups and long doses of heady silence give the impression that the plot is moving slowly, when in fact it's going roughly a mile a minute. Tarantino just wants us to savor the performances of his all-star cast and the tangle of plot threads that surrounds them before forcing our heads out the window and punching the gas in the last twenty minutes. Along the way, he subtly, efficiently grazes a gamut of emotions that leaves us deeply invested in the (often untimely) fate of each character. Rich, complex and rewarding, it's not as flashy as Pulp Fiction or Reservoir Dogs, but it's every bit as excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly enjoyable crime caper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tarantino is often derided by his dismissives as an over zealous, pop-culturally obsessed schizoid with a penchant for fetishizing violence and, oddly enough, feet. But in this 1997 adaptation of the Elmore Leonard novel, and hot off the heels off the watershed event that was Pulp Fiction three years prior, he chose to follow up his electric filmography by incorporating a slightly more complex and elegant plot in the form of a heist caper. What sets it apart from other entries in the genre (and subsequent adaptations of Leonard works by the likes of other gen X indie directors like Soderbergh), is Tarantino's unique combination of cinema homage and pastiche that gives the proceedings a fresh and vibrant aura. Tarantino skillfully employs elements of blaxploitation through choice soundtrack, camera work, and elegant casting. Pam Grier in the eponymous title role as a middle aged Afro-American woman attempting to emerge out on top of a crime sting is not only a headstrong and intelligently spunky protagonist, but through the course of the film she offers an acute sensitivity to her situation that adds a gravity to the story. coupled with a subtle turn by Robert Forster, in a similair comeback role to John Travolta in Pulp, as an aging, jaded bail bondsman who is injected with a burst of vitalic romantic interest in Jackie Brown, and the subsequent bonding that grows between them offers Tarantino his most empathetically human and thematic material thus far. But the most entertaining turn in from the cast is Samuel L Jackson as the fast-talking, foul mouthed thug who isn't quite as clever of a criminal as he thinks he is. The often witty and hilarious dialogue exchanges between he, Bridget Fonda, and an unassuming Robert DeNiro as a bumbling, apathetic accomplice is amusing and carries the film deftly onward, even when it threatens to be dragged down by the slightly dry plot. But there is a noticeable lack of cloying pop cultural references in the script that Tarantino is known for. Instead, it is all just great character acting, and he manages to make the mundane a roller coaster of verbal levity. The look of the picture is great, with skillfully composed shots and fine tuned audio, with a killer soundtrack to top it off. Jackie Brown is a tightly made film that delivers in its black humor and a feel good tale of one sassy feminist throwback getting the better of her clueless colleagues, and learning a little bit of mid life wisdom along the way. Highly recommended for fans of well constructed and stylish crime capers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Tarantino Crime Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pam Grier, Samuel L. Jackson, Robert Forster, Robert De Niro, Michael Keaton, Michael Bowen, Chris Tucker, Tommy 'Tiny' Lister and Bridget Fonda star in Quentin Tarantino's 1997 crime thriller based on a novel, "Rum Punch." This begins with flight attendant, Jackie Brown (Grier) who gets arrested for possession of drugs and a large amount of cash. She learns that her gun-dealing friend, Ordell Robbie (Jackson) set her up and decides to get back at him. Forster plays bail bondsman, Max Cherry who is hired by Ordell to bail her out of jail for 10 grand. Soon, Jackie meets Max who not only falls for her, but helps her steal Ordell's cash. Keaton plays FBI agent, Ray Nicollete, Bowen plays his partner, Mark Dargus, De Niro plays Ordell's pal, Lois Gara, Fonda plays Ordell's mistress, Melanie Ralston, Tucker (Friday) plays Ordell's friend, Beaumont Livingston and Lister (Friday) plays Max's assistant, Winston. This is a good film with a great cast that also has a nice tribute to 70's films & music. I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Excitement or Violence You Would Look For In a Tarantino Film,But Still Really Good,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Brown is a terrific movie with a very well developed storyline like all Quentin Tarantino's movies and a very talented cast.I certainly didn't enjoy it as much as Tarantino's previous work,Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction,it wasn't as violent,action packed or as exciting as them and I was a bit disappointed by it,but it still is a really good movie.This focuses a lot more on characters and dialogue,which didn't bother me because I really liked these characters and the dialogue was very well written.The cast are all fantastic,Pam Grier and Robert Forster both did a fantastic job,but the best performances had to be Samuel L Jackson and Robert De Niro,their both some of my favourite actors,they always get really interested in their characters,and this is no exception.Fans of Quentin Tarantino will be disappointed by Jackie Brown,but its still a very good,character driven movie. Jackie Brown (Pam Grier) gets involved with an arms dealer and the police force after a few mistakes she made in the past that brought her into jail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quentin, you owe us an apology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    videorama-759-859391
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When first hearing of this title, you would of expected another Pulp Fiction. Sadly here you;re very mistaken. You've been very short changed I'm afraid. Working from Elmore Leonard's novel, Quentin must of been self conscious in his telling of this nothing impressive tale. There's hardly any Tarantino humor or VIOLENCE. We have a few stretched out scenes, wasted ones, of little significance, ones that take place in Jackson's Venice beach apartment. We can tell he's held back here, as if to honor or not disrespect crime author, Leonard's book. Pam Grier playing the title, one of the many great performances, is a 44 year old black woman trying to make ends meat, by earning her undeserved share of money made off selling guns, that her boss, Ordell Robbie sells. Jackson is fun to watch in this, playing bad good, in reverse to the much gentler and reserved teacher he played in 187. When Grier is arrested by the feds, she has her own way of snaking out of it, outwitting authorities, while hatching a plan to rip off Ordeal. You gotta admire the courage and strength of the character, but the storytelling just seems to be prolonged. There's not many surprises in the thriller department either. We know what each character wants, whether he/she is good or bad. They're an open book. Deniro was fun to watch as as ex parolee friend of Jackson, who lags around in Jackson's apartment with skinny bikini bodied pot smoking Mel (Fonda). Her murder in the car park was a shock. On the whole Jackie Brown was a bitter disappointment when seeing it in the cinema. This disappointing feature almost had me wondering if I was in the right cinema. I enjoyed it more second time around on video, but this Tarantino flick is a two an hour flick that could of easily been told in 90 minutes. It's just a prolonged story with a lot of flat, not much happening scenes. If Tarantino did it his way, minus Leonard's' influence, we would of had a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the less Tarantinesque of Tarantino's movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow I missed 'Jackie Brown' - a Tarantino movie made in 1997 which takes in his directing career a chronological place between 'Pulp Fiction' and the two 'Kill Bill' movies. It is to some extent the less Tarantinesque of the Tarantino movies - 150 minutes of solid film making, a violent gangster movie very much in tone with the 90s, but lacking the excesses and the sarcasm of his greatest films. I am sure though that many other folks will consider it the best or one of the best films in his career, exactly for the same reasons I did not like it completely. Great acting by Samuel L. Jackson, Robert De Niro, Bridget Fonda and Palm Grier. Excellent soul music soundtrack - Tarantino's mobsters have a special taste for music, did you notice?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Authentic and well acted but it drags on for far too long
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kluseba
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino is a man between genius and madness who has created some of the best movies ever but also a few true Fails in my opinion. "Jackie Brown" is just between both extremes for me and is maybe his most unspectacular film to date. On the positive side, this movie is Tarantino's most organic one until now. The characters are more credible than usual, the dialogues aren't all too over the top and the story line is quite easy to follow. The movie includes no special effects, shock moments or unexpected twists and feels surprisingly down to earth for a Quentin Tarantino movie. From that point of view, it's a quite unique movie from him. The acting is authentic and very well done. Pam Grier plays an attractive and intelligent lady in her forties who starts the movie as a victim just to become the one who plays with each other character around her. Samuel L. Jackson does a convincing role as superficial but not dumb gangster. Robert Forster plays a bondsman and smart gentleman with a lot of charisma as well. He's the actor I somehow like the most in this movie. In addition to the movie's authentic mood and the great acting, the soundtrack is as always quite convincing as well and introduces us to many great Afroamerican musicians. I must though admit that I preferred by far the soundtracks of other Tarantino movies such as "Kill Bill" or "Django Unchained" for example. On the other side, the movie definitely has its lengths as many Tarantino movies. There are some more or less important endless dialogues that should have been shortened in my opinion. This movie would have just been fine with a running time between ninety and one-hundred-five minutes in my opinion. Apart of that, the story is not only down to earth but also quite unspectacular and there isn't that much going on in two hours and a half. The movie feels a little bit too simple at some points. Apart of the acting, the movie lacks of a true highlight. The killing scenes are really unspectacular and you don't see very much. It's the same thing for one single and quite boring sex scene. The movie is supposed to have a few humorous moments but they really aren't all that memorable. The showdown in the mall also lacks tension. It shows us the same scene from three different views which gets quite redundant. The only truly gripping moments in this movie are the first E encounter between Pam Grier and Samuel L. Jackson in her apartment and the scene when Robert Forster and Samuel L. Jackson go to the Office of the bondsman. In the end, this film could have been a standout movie in Tranatino's career because it's quite different from what he usually does. The film though fails from that point of view and drags on far too long and turns out to be quite unspectacular or even boring at some points. It all feels more like a theatre play where convincing dialogues by solid actors matter but not much more. I have seen far worse but also far better movies and I would only recommend this flick to die hard fans of Quentin Tarantino's works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this 1 star because I had to give it something. I really REALLY hated what I saw of this movie. I didn't actually last till the end. I was going to try and then I decided I had more important things to do with my time, like wash some clothes and feed the dogs. I adore Tarantino films. This one was a complete dud. Self-indulgent nonsense about characters I couldn't care less about talking about stuff that really doesn't matter. All the dialogue was slow & dragged on and on pointlessly. There was no action to speak of and the plot was thin and uninteresting. Really, don't waste your time. And please, if you're a Tarantino fan, don't poison your appreciation for his work by watching this stinker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Brown getting' down!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike dewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may be old news now, but Quentin T. showed out in this fast and sassy maxi-scam caper flick. He couldn't have hired a better acting ensemble to pull this off, to wit, Pam Grier, Robert Forster, Sammy J., Bobby D., Brigid F., Chris Tucker, Michael K., etc. For starters, I think this is the best performance of Pam G's career: she exhibits a multi-dimensional persona here I have never seen her pull off before. For example, notice how she effortlessly segues from the street-savvy demeanor whilst in the company of Sammy J., etc., to the middle-class, nice girl, good-diction modus operandi when she's in the company of the the likes of Robert F. She shows how tight her game really is and isn't afraid to do whatever it takes to pull off her intended caper. Robert F., mild of manner and well composed, is cast as the antithesis of the Sammy J. character who is a down-and-dirty, bombastic rascal. Notice how Robert F's character, a white bail-bondsman, effortlessly mixes in well with people of color without being obsequious or trying to be hip: He is merely himself and lets that fact set the tone for whatever may ensue. Sammy J. is his usual awesome self, with great support from Bobby D. and Brigid F. That unholy trio makes sparks fly as the drama unfolds. Notice how Bobby D's character slowly shifts gears from a mellow understated ex-con to a violent shooter when he becomes unduly provoked: a nice touch from Mr. DeNiro. Quentin T's usually crisp directorial skills are in evidence here, as his cutting in and moving back and forth in time work very well. His rewinds in time allow the viewer to see the same scenes from another vantage point so that one can see the logical progression of events from several angles. All that and an awesome, cleverly positioned soundtrack that kicks much booty! How about "Across 110th Street" at the ending? Did she "get across" or what?! This is my favorite Quentin T. film: ya gotta check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some thoughts...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artistgp
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll refrain from summarizing the entire film because you've either already seen it or you're interested in watching the story. Instead I'll just share some thoughts I had with you. It definitely felt like a step down from most of his films. There wasn't anything revolutionary about the film. The beginning seemed to lag for a good while. It eventually picked up steam during the heist portion of the movie, but that in itself didn't really seem to have anything new to add to that genre. The were some really nice long shots in the film (I'm a huge fan of artistically staged lengthy takes), the car pulling into the empty lot on the other side of the fence is a good example. I will say tho, that there were some long shots that seemed to be stretched out for no apparent reason other than just to do it. The acting was solid. The characters were a mix. Jackie was stuck in a dead end job for somewhere around twenty years and yet she proved to be quite the master mind by the end of the movie. Kind of makes you wonder why she wasn't able to advance in her career. Jackson's character was well played and was indeed intriguing, but after a while I kind of wished he would leave me alone. It's not a bad movie, but not one I would recommend to someone else. These are just my thoughts on this particular project. If you're interested in the film I'd urge you to see it and make your own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black Sheep of the Tarantino Family, Jackie's More Substance-Minded Than Style-Blinded
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Easily Quentin Tarantino's most mature work, which admittedly isn't saying much for a director who brought us the Five Point Palm Exploding Heart Technique and a literal blast of adrenaline to the heart. That's not to say his films have ever lacked in substance - rather, I think the true depth of their character is merely overshadowed by those visceral moments of graphic excess and their stylish methods of delivery. Jackie Brown, instead, manages to step out from that bloody shadow and shine on its own volition. Its lingering close-ups and long doses of heady silence give the impression that the plot is moving slowly, when in fact it's going roughly a mile a minute. Tarantino just wants us to savor the performances of his all-star cast and the tangle of plot threads that surrounds them before forcing our heads out the window and punching the gas in the last twenty minutes. Along the way, he subtly, efficiently grazes a gamut of emotions that leaves us deeply invested in the (often untimely) fate of each character. Rich, complex and rewarding, it's not as flashy as Pulp Fiction or Reservoir Dogs, but it's every bit as excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly enjoyable crime caper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tarantino is often derided by his dismissives as an over zealous, pop-culturally obsessed schizoid with a penchant for fetishizing violence and, oddly enough, feet. But in this 1997 adaptation of the Elmore Leonard novel, and hot off the heels off the watershed event that was Pulp Fiction three years prior, he chose to follow up his electric filmography by incorporating a slightly more complex and elegant plot in the form of a heist caper. What sets it apart from other entries in the genre (and subsequent adaptations of Leonard works by the likes of other gen X indie directors like Soderbergh), is Tarantino's unique combination of cinema homage and pastiche that gives the proceedings a fresh and vibrant aura. Tarantino skillfully employs elements of blaxploitation through choice soundtrack, camera work, and elegant casting. Pam Grier in the eponymous title role as a middle aged Afro-American woman attempting to emerge out on top of a crime sting is not only a headstrong and intelligently spunky protagonist, but through the course of the film she offers an acute sensitivity to her situation that adds a gravity to the story. coupled with a subtle turn by Robert Forster, in a similair comeback role to John Travolta in Pulp, as an aging, jaded bail bondsman who is injected with a burst of vitalic romantic interest in Jackie Brown, and the subsequent bonding that grows between them offers Tarantino his most empathetically human and thematic material thus far. But the most entertaining turn in from the cast is Samuel L Jackson as the fast-talking, foul mouthed thug who isn't quite as clever of a criminal as he thinks he is. The often witty and hilarious dialogue exchanges between he, Bridget Fonda, and an unassuming Robert DeNiro as a bumbling, apathetic accomplice is amusing and carries the film deftly onward, even when it threatens to be dragged down by the slightly dry plot. But there is a noticeable lack of cloying pop cultural references in the script that Tarantino is known for. Instead, it is all just great character acting, and he manages to make the mundane a roller coaster of verbal levity. The look of the picture is great, with skillfully composed shots and fine tuned audio, with a killer soundtrack to top it off. Jackie Brown is a tightly made film that delivers in its black humor and a feel good tale of one sassy feminist throwback getting the better of her clueless colleagues, and learning a little bit of mid life wisdom along the way. Highly recommended for fans of well constructed and stylish crime capers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Tarantino Crime Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pam Grier, Samuel L. Jackson, Robert Forster, Robert De Niro, Michael Keaton, Michael Bowen, Chris Tucker, Tommy 'Tiny' Lister and Bridget Fonda star in Quentin Tarantino's 1997 crime thriller based on a novel, "Rum Punch." This begins with flight attendant, Jackie Brown (Grier) who gets arrested for possession of drugs and a large amount of cash. She learns that her gun-dealing friend, Ordell Robbie (Jackson) set her up and decides to get back at him. Forster plays bail bondsman, Max Cherry who is hired by Ordell to bail her out of jail for 10 grand. Soon, Jackie meets Max who not only falls for her, but helps her steal Ordell's cash. Keaton plays FBI agent, Ray Nicollete, Bowen plays his partner, Mark Dargus, De Niro plays Ordell's pal, Lois Gara, Fonda plays Ordell's mistress, Melanie Ralston, Tucker (Friday) plays Ordell's friend, Beaumont Livingston and Lister (Friday) plays Max's assistant, Winston. This is a good film with a great cast that also has a nice tribute to 70's films & music. I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Excitement or Violence You Would Look For In a Tarantino Film,But Still Really Good,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Brown is a terrific movie with a very well developed storyline like all Quentin Tarantino's movies and a very talented cast.I certainly didn't enjoy it as much as Tarantino's previous work,Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction,it wasn't as violent,action packed or as exciting as them and I was a bit disappointed by it,but it still is a really good movie.This focuses a lot more on characters and dialogue,which didn't bother me because I really liked these characters and the dialogue was very well written.The cast are all fantastic,Pam Grier and Robert Forster both did a fantastic job,but the best performances had to be Samuel L Jackson and Robert De Niro,their both some of my favourite actors,they always get really interested in their characters,and this is no exception.Fans of Quentin Tarantino will be disappointed by Jackie Brown,but its still a very good,character driven movie. Jackie Brown (Pam Grier) gets involved with an arms dealer and the police force after a few mistakes she made in the past that brought her into jail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quentin, you owe us an apology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    videorama-759-859391
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When first hearing of this title, you would of expected another Pulp Fiction. Sadly here you;re very mistaken. You've been very short changed I'm afraid. Working from Elmore Leonard's novel, Quentin must of been self conscious in his telling of this nothing impressive tale. There's hardly any Tarantino humor or VIOLENCE. We have a few stretched out scenes, wasted ones, of little significance, ones that take place in Jackson's Venice beach apartment. We can tell he's held back here, as if to honor or not disrespect crime author, Leonard's book. Pam Grier playing the title, one of the many great performances, is a 44 year old black woman trying to make ends meat, by earning her undeserved share of money made off selling guns, that her boss, Ordell Robbie sells. Jackson is fun to watch in this, playing bad good, in reverse to the much gentler and reserved teacher he played in 187. When Grier is arrested by the feds, she has her own way of snaking out of it, outwitting authorities, while hatching a plan to rip off Ordeal. You gotta admire the courage and strength of the character, but the storytelling just seems to be prolonged. There's not many surprises in the thriller department either. We know what each character wants, whether he/she is good or bad. They're an open book. Deniro was fun to watch as as ex parolee friend of Jackson, who lags around in Jackson's apartment with skinny bikini bodied pot smoking Mel (Fonda). Her murder in the car park was a shock. On the whole Jackie Brown was a bitter disappointment when seeing it in the cinema. This disappointing feature almost had me wondering if I was in the right cinema. I enjoyed it more second time around on video, but this Tarantino flick is a two an hour flick that could of easily been told in 90 minutes. It's just a prolonged story with a lot of flat, not much happening scenes. If Tarantino did it his way, minus Leonard's' influence, we would of had a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the less Tarantinesque of Tarantino's movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow I missed 'Jackie Brown' - a Tarantino movie made in 1997 which takes in his directing career a chronological place between 'Pulp Fiction' and the two 'Kill Bill' movies. It is to some extent the less Tarantinesque of the Tarantino movies - 150 minutes of solid film making, a violent gangster movie very much in tone with the 90s, but lacking the excesses and the sarcasm of his greatest films. I am sure though that many other folks will consider it the best or one of the best films in his career, exactly for the same reasons I did not like it completely. Great acting by Samuel L. Jackson, Robert De Niro, Bridget Fonda and Palm Grier. Excellent soul music soundtrack - Tarantino's mobsters have a special taste for music, did you notice?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Authentic and well acted but it drags on for far too long
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kluseba
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino is a man between genius and madness who has created some of the best movies ever but also a few true Fails in my opinion. "Jackie Brown" is just between both extremes for me and is maybe his most unspectacular film to date. On the positive side, this movie is Tarantino's most organic one until now. The characters are more credible than usual, the dialogues aren't all too over the top and the story line is quite easy to follow. The movie includes no special effects, shock moments or unexpected twists and feels surprisingly down to earth for a Quentin Tarantino movie. From that point of view, it's a quite unique movie from him. The acting is authentic and very well done. Pam Grier plays an attractive and intelligent lady in her forties who starts the movie as a victim just to become the one who plays with each other character around her. Samuel L. Jackson does a convincing role as superficial but not dumb gangster. Robert Forster plays a bondsman and smart gentleman with a lot of charisma as well. He's the actor I somehow like the most in this movie. In addition to the movie's authentic mood and the great acting, the soundtrack is as always quite convincing as well and introduces us to many great Afroamerican musicians. I must though admit that I preferred by far the soundtracks of other Tarantino movies such as "Kill Bill" or "Django Unchained" for example. On the other side, the movie definitely has its lengths as many Tarantino movies. There are some more or less important endless dialogues that should have been shortened in my opinion. This movie would have just been fine with a running time between ninety and one-hundred-five minutes in my opinion. Apart of that, the story is not only down to earth but also quite unspectacular and there isn't that much going on in two hours and a half. The movie feels a little bit too simple at some points. Apart of the acting, the movie lacks of a true highlight. The killing scenes are really unspectacular and you don't see very much. It's the same thing for one single and quite boring sex scene. The movie is supposed to have a few humorous moments but they really aren't all that memorable. The showdown in the mall also lacks tension. It shows us the same scene from three different views which gets quite redundant. The only truly gripping moments in this movie are the first E encounter between Pam Grier and Samuel L. Jackson in her apartment and the scene when Robert Forster and Samuel L. Jackson go to the Office of the bondsman. In the end, this film could have been a standout movie in Tranatino's career because it's quite different from what he usually does. The film though fails from that point of view and drags on far too long and turns out to be quite unspectacular or even boring at some points. It all feels more like a theatre play where convincing dialogues by solid actors matter but not much more. I have seen far worse but also far better movies and I would only recommend this flick to die hard fans of Quentin Tarantino's works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this 1 star because I had to give it something. I really REALLY hated what I saw of this movie. I didn't actually last till the end. I was going to try and then I decided I had more important things to do with my time, like wash some clothes and feed the dogs. I adore Tarantino films. This one was a complete dud. Self-indulgent nonsense about characters I couldn't care less about talking about stuff that really doesn't matter. All the dialogue was slow & dragged on and on pointlessly. There was no action to speak of and the plot was thin and uninteresting. Really, don't waste your time. And please, if you're a Tarantino fan, don't poison your appreciation for his work by watching this stinker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Brown getting' down!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike dewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may be old news now, but Quentin T. showed out in this fast and sassy maxi-scam caper flick. He couldn't have hired a better acting ensemble to pull this off, to wit, Pam Grier, Robert Forster, Sammy J., Bobby D., Brigid F., Chris Tucker, Michael K., etc. For starters, I think this is the best performance of Pam G's career: she exhibits a multi-dimensional persona here I have never seen her pull off before. For example, notice how she effortlessly segues from the street-savvy demeanor whilst in the company of Sammy J., etc., to the middle-class, nice girl, good-diction modus operandi when she's in the company of the the likes of Robert F. She shows how tight her game really is and isn't afraid to do whatever it takes to pull off her intended caper. Robert F., mild of manner and well composed, is cast as the antithesis of the Sammy J. character who is a down-and-dirty, bombastic rascal. Notice how Robert F's character, a white bail-bondsman, effortlessly mixes in well with people of color without being obsequious or trying to be hip: He is merely himself and lets that fact set the tone for whatever may ensue. Sammy J. is his usual awesome self, with great support from Bobby D. and Brigid F. That unholy trio makes sparks fly as the drama unfolds. Notice how Bobby D's character slowly shifts gears from a mellow understated ex-con to a violent shooter when he becomes unduly provoked: a nice touch from Mr. DeNiro. Quentin T's usually crisp directorial skills are in evidence here, as his cutting in and moving back and forth in time work very well. His rewinds in time allow the viewer to see the same scenes from another vantage point so that one can see the logical progression of events from several angles. All that and an awesome, cleverly positioned soundtrack that kicks much booty! How about "Across 110th Street" at the ending? Did she "get across" or what?! This is my favorite Quentin T. film: ya gotta check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some thoughts...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artistgp
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll refrain from summarizing the entire film because you've either already seen it or you're interested in watching the story. Instead I'll just share some thoughts I had with you. It definitely felt like a step down from most of his films. There wasn't anything revolutionary about the film. The beginning seemed to lag for a good while. It eventually picked up steam during the heist portion of the movie, but that in itself didn't really seem to have anything new to add to that genre. The were some really nice long shots in the film (I'm a huge fan of artistically staged lengthy takes), the car pulling into the empty lot on the other side of the fence is a good example. I will say tho, that there were some long shots that seemed to be stretched out for no apparent reason other than just to do it. The acting was solid. The characters were a mix. Jackie was stuck in a dead end job for somewhere around twenty years and yet she proved to be quite the master mind by the end of the movie. Kind of makes you wonder why she wasn't able to advance in her career. Jackson's character was well played and was indeed intriguing, but after a while I kind of wished he would leave me alone. It's not a bad movie, but not one I would recommend to someone else. These are just my thoughts on this particular project. If you're interested in the film I'd urge you to see it and make your own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black Sheep of the Tarantino Family, Jackie's More Substance-Minded Than Style-Blinded
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Easily Quentin Tarantino's most mature work, which admittedly isn't saying much for a director who brought us the Five Point Palm Exploding Heart Technique and a literal blast of adrenaline to the heart. That's not to say his films have ever lacked in substance - rather, I think the true depth of their character is merely overshadowed by those visceral moments of graphic excess and their stylish methods of delivery. Jackie Brown, instead, manages to step out from that bloody shadow and shine on its own volition. Its lingering close-ups and long doses of heady silence give the impression that the plot is moving slowly, when in fact it's going roughly a mile a minute. Tarantino just wants us to savor the performances of his all-star cast and the tangle of plot threads that surrounds them before forcing our heads out the window and punching the gas in the last twenty minutes. Along the way, he subtly, efficiently grazes a gamut of emotions that leaves us deeply invested in the (often untimely) fate of each character. Rich, complex and rewarding, it's not as flashy as Pulp Fiction or Reservoir Dogs, but it's every bit as excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly enjoyable crime caper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tarantino is often derided by his dismissives as an over zealous, pop-culturally obsessed schizoid with a penchant for fetishizing violence and, oddly enough, feet. But in this 1997 adaptation of the Elmore Leonard novel, and hot off the heels off the watershed event that was Pulp Fiction three years prior, he chose to follow up his electric filmography by incorporating a slightly more complex and elegant plot in the form of a heist caper. What sets it apart from other entries in the genre (and subsequent adaptations of Leonard works by the likes of other gen X indie directors like Soderbergh), is Tarantino's unique combination of cinema homage and pastiche that gives the proceedings a fresh and vibrant aura. Tarantino skillfully employs elements of blaxploitation through choice soundtrack, camera work, and elegant casting. Pam Grier in the eponymous title role as a middle aged Afro-American woman attempting to emerge out on top of a crime sting is not only a headstrong and intelligently spunky protagonist, but through the course of the film she offers an acute sensitivity to her situation that adds a gravity to the story. coupled with a subtle turn by Robert Forster, in a similair comeback role to John Travolta in Pulp, as an aging, jaded bail bondsman who is injected with a burst of vitalic romantic interest in Jackie Brown, and the subsequent bonding that grows between them offers Tarantino his most empathetically human and thematic material thus far. But the most entertaining turn in from the cast is Samuel L Jackson as the fast-talking, foul mouthed thug who isn't quite as clever of a criminal as he thinks he is. The often witty and hilarious dialogue exchanges between he, Bridget Fonda, and an unassuming Robert DeNiro as a bumbling, apathetic accomplice is amusing and carries the film deftly onward, even when it threatens to be dragged down by the slightly dry plot. But there is a noticeable lack of cloying pop cultural references in the script that Tarantino is known for. Instead, it is all just great character acting, and he manages to make the mundane a roller coaster of verbal levity. The look of the picture is great, with skillfully composed shots and fine tuned audio, with a killer soundtrack to top it off. Jackie Brown is a tightly made film that delivers in its black humor and a feel good tale of one sassy feminist throwback getting the better of her clueless colleagues, and learning a little bit of mid life wisdom along the way. Highly recommended for fans of well constructed and stylish crime capers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Tarantino Crime Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pam Grier, Samuel L. Jackson, Robert Forster, Robert De Niro, Michael Keaton, Michael Bowen, Chris Tucker, Tommy 'Tiny' Lister and Bridget Fonda star in Quentin Tarantino's 1997 crime thriller based on a novel, "Rum Punch." This begins with flight attendant, Jackie Brown (Grier) who gets arrested for possession of drugs and a large amount of cash. She learns that her gun-dealing friend, Ordell Robbie (Jackson) set her up and decides to get back at him. Forster plays bail bondsman, Max Cherry who is hired by Ordell to bail her out of jail for 10 grand. Soon, Jackie meets Max who not only falls for her, but helps her steal Ordell's cash. Keaton plays FBI agent, Ray Nicollete, Bowen plays his partner, Mark Dargus, De Niro plays Ordell's pal, Lois Gara, Fonda plays Ordell's mistress, Melanie Ralston, Tucker (Friday) plays Ordell's friend, Beaumont Livingston and Lister (Friday) plays Max's assistant, Winston. This is a good film with a great cast that also has a nice tribute to 70's films & music. I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Excitement or Violence You Would Look For In a Tarantino Film,But Still Really Good,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Brown is a terrific movie with a very well developed storyline like all Quentin Tarantino's movies and a very talented cast.I certainly didn't enjoy it as much as Tarantino's previous work,Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction,it wasn't as violent,action packed or as exciting as them and I was a bit disappointed by it,but it still is a really good movie.This focuses a lot more on characters and dialogue,which didn't bother me because I really liked these characters and the dialogue was very well written.The cast are all fantastic,Pam Grier and Robert Forster both did a fantastic job,but the best performances had to be Samuel L Jackson and Robert De Niro,their both some of my favourite actors,they always get really interested in their characters,and this is no exception.Fans of Quentin Tarantino will be disappointed by Jackie Brown,but its still a very good,character driven movie. Jackie Brown (Pam Grier) gets involved with an arms dealer and the police force after a few mistakes she made in the past that brought her into jail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quentin, you owe us an apology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    videorama-759-859391
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When first hearing of this title, you would of expected another Pulp Fiction. Sadly here you;re very mistaken. You've been very short changed I'm afraid. Working from Elmore Leonard's novel, Quentin must of been self conscious in his telling of this nothing impressive tale. There's hardly any Tarantino humor or VIOLENCE. We have a few stretched out scenes, wasted ones, of little significance, ones that take place in Jackson's Venice beach apartment. We can tell he's held back here, as if to honor or not disrespect crime author, Leonard's book. Pam Grier playing the title, one of the many great performances, is a 44 year old black woman trying to make ends meat, by earning her undeserved share of money made off selling guns, that her boss, Ordell Robbie sells. Jackson is fun to watch in this, playing bad good, in reverse to the much gentler and reserved teacher he played in 187. When Grier is arrested by the feds, she has her own way of snaking out of it, outwitting authorities, while hatching a plan to rip off Ordeal. You gotta admire the courage and strength of the character, but the storytelling just seems to be prolonged. There's not many surprises in the thriller department either. We know what each character wants, whether he/she is good or bad. They're an open book. Deniro was fun to watch as as ex parolee friend of Jackson, who lags around in Jackson's apartment with skinny bikini bodied pot smoking Mel (Fonda). Her murder in the car park was a shock. On the whole Jackie Brown was a bitter disappointment when seeing it in the cinema. This disappointing feature almost had me wondering if I was in the right cinema. I enjoyed it more second time around on video, but this Tarantino flick is a two an hour flick that could of easily been told in 90 minutes. It's just a prolonged story with a lot of flat, not much happening scenes. If Tarantino did it his way, minus Leonard's' influence, we would of had a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the less Tarantinesque of Tarantino's movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow I missed 'Jackie Brown' - a Tarantino movie made in 1997 which takes in his directing career a chronological place between 'Pulp Fiction' and the two 'Kill Bill' movies. It is to some extent the less Tarantinesque of the Tarantino movies - 150 minutes of solid film making, a violent gangster movie very much in tone with the 90s, but lacking the excesses and the sarcasm of his greatest films. I am sure though that many other folks will consider it the best or one of the best films in his career, exactly for the same reasons I did not like it completely. Great acting by Samuel L. Jackson, Robert De Niro, Bridget Fonda and Palm Grier. Excellent soul music soundtrack - Tarantino's mobsters have a special taste for music, did you notice?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Authentic and well acted but it drags on for far too long
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kluseba
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino is a man between genius and madness who has created some of the best movies ever but also a few true Fails in my opinion. "Jackie Brown" is just between both extremes for me and is maybe his most unspectacular film to date. On the positive side, this movie is Tarantino's most organic one until now. The characters are more credible than usual, the dialogues aren't all too over the top and the story line is quite easy to follow. The movie includes no special effects, shock moments or unexpected twists and feels surprisingly down to earth for a Quentin Tarantino movie. From that point of view, it's a quite unique movie from him. The acting is authentic and very well done. Pam Grier plays an attractive and intelligent lady in her forties who starts the movie as a victim just to become the one who plays with each other character around her. Samuel L. Jackson does a convincing role as superficial but not dumb gangster. Robert Forster plays a bondsman and smart gentleman with a lot of charisma as well. He's the actor I somehow like the most in this movie. In addition to the movie's authentic mood and the great acting, the soundtrack is as always quite convincing as well and introduces us to many great Afroamerican musicians. I must though admit that I preferred by far the soundtracks of other Tarantino movies such as "Kill Bill" or "Django Unchained" for example. On the other side, the movie definitely has its lengths as many Tarantino movies. There are some more or less important endless dialogues that should have been shortened in my opinion. This movie would have just been fine with a running time between ninety and one-hundred-five minutes in my opinion. Apart of that, the story is not only down to earth but also quite unspectacular and there isn't that much going on in two hours and a half. The movie feels a little bit too simple at some points. Apart of the acting, the movie lacks of a true highlight. The killing scenes are really unspectacular and you don't see very much. It's the same thing for one single and quite boring sex scene. The movie is supposed to have a few humorous moments but they really aren't all that memorable. The showdown in the mall also lacks tension. It shows us the same scene from three different views which gets quite redundant. The only truly gripping moments in this movie are the first E encounter between Pam Grier and Samuel L. Jackson in her apartment and the scene when Robert Forster and Samuel L. Jackson go to the Office of the bondsman. In the end, this film could have been a standout movie in Tranatino's career because it's quite different from what he usually does. The film though fails from that point of view and drags on far too long and turns out to be quite unspectacular or even boring at some points. It all feels more like a theatre play where convincing dialogues by solid actors matter but not much more. I have seen far worse but also far better movies and I would only recommend this flick to die hard fans of Quentin Tarantino's works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this 1 star because I had to give it something. I really REALLY hated what I saw of this movie. I didn't actually last till the end. I was going to try and then I decided I had more important things to do with my time, like wash some clothes and feed the dogs. I adore Tarantino films. This one was a complete dud. Self-indulgent nonsense about characters I couldn't care less about talking about stuff that really doesn't matter. All the dialogue was slow & dragged on and on pointlessly. There was no action to speak of and the plot was thin and uninteresting. Really, don't waste your time. And please, if you're a Tarantino fan, don't poison your appreciation for his work by watching this stinker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Brown getting' down!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike dewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may be old news now, but Quentin T. showed out in this fast and sassy maxi-scam caper flick. He couldn't have hired a better acting ensemble to pull this off, to wit, Pam Grier, Robert Forster, Sammy J., Bobby D., Brigid F., Chris Tucker, Michael K., etc. For starters, I think this is the best performance of Pam G's career: she exhibits a multi-dimensional persona here I have never seen her pull off before. For example, notice how she effortlessly segues from the street-savvy demeanor whilst in the company of Sammy J., etc., to the middle-class, nice girl, good-diction modus operandi when she's in the company of the the likes of Robert F. She shows how tight her game really is and isn't afraid to do whatever it takes to pull off her intended caper. Robert F., mild of manner and well composed, is cast as the antithesis of the Sammy J. character who is a down-and-dirty, bombastic rascal. Notice how Robert F's character, a white bail-bondsman, effortlessly mixes in well with people of color without being obsequious or trying to be hip: He is merely himself and lets that fact set the tone for whatever may ensue. Sammy J. is his usual awesome self, with great support from Bobby D. and Brigid F. That unholy trio makes sparks fly as the drama unfolds. Notice how Bobby D's character slowly shifts gears from a mellow understated ex-con to a violent shooter when he becomes unduly provoked: a nice touch from Mr. DeNiro. Quentin T's usually crisp directorial skills are in evidence here, as his cutting in and moving back and forth in time work very well. His rewinds in time allow the viewer to see the same scenes from another vantage point so that one can see the logical progression of events from several angles. All that and an awesome, cleverly positioned soundtrack that kicks much booty! How about "Across 110th Street" at the ending? Did she "get across" or what?! This is my favorite Quentin T. film: ya gotta check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some thoughts...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artistgp
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll refrain from summarizing the entire film because you've either already seen it or you're interested in watching the story. Instead I'll just share some thoughts I had with you. It definitely felt like a step down from most of his films. There wasn't anything revolutionary about the film. The beginning seemed to lag for a good while. It eventually picked up steam during the heist portion of the movie, but that in itself didn't really seem to have anything new to add to that genre. The were some really nice long shots in the film (I'm a huge fan of artistically staged lengthy takes), the car pulling into the empty lot on the other side of the fence is a good example. I will say tho, that there were some long shots that seemed to be stretched out for no apparent reason other than just to do it. The acting was solid. The characters were a mix. Jackie was stuck in a dead end job for somewhere around twenty years and yet she proved to be quite the master mind by the end of the movie. Kind of makes you wonder why she wasn't able to advance in her career. Jackson's character was well played and was indeed intriguing, but after a while I kind of wished he would leave me alone. It's not a bad movie, but not one I would recommend to someone else. These are just my thoughts on this particular project. If you're interested in the film I'd urge you to see it and make your own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black Sheep of the Tarantino Family, Jackie's More Substance-Minded Than Style-Blinded
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Easily Quentin Tarantino's most mature work, which admittedly isn't saying much for a director who brought us the Five Point Palm Exploding Heart Technique and a literal blast of adrenaline to the heart. That's not to say his films have ever lacked in substance - rather, I think the true depth of their character is merely overshadowed by those visceral moments of graphic excess and their stylish methods of delivery. Jackie Brown, instead, manages to step out from that bloody shadow and shine on its own volition. Its lingering close-ups and long doses of heady silence give the impression that the plot is moving slowly, when in fact it's going roughly a mile a minute. Tarantino just wants us to savor the performances of his all-star cast and the tangle of plot threads that surrounds them before forcing our heads out the window and punching the gas in the last twenty minutes. Along the way, he subtly, efficiently grazes a gamut of emotions that leaves us deeply invested in the (often untimely) fate of each character. Rich, complex and rewarding, it's not as flashy as Pulp Fiction or Reservoir Dogs, but it's every bit as excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly enjoyable crime caper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tarantino is often derided by his dismissives as an over zealous, pop-culturally obsessed schizoid with a penchant for fetishizing violence and, oddly enough, feet. But in this 1997 adaptation of the Elmore Leonard novel, and hot off the heels off the watershed event that was Pulp Fiction three years prior, he chose to follow up his electric filmography by incorporating a slightly more complex and elegant plot in the form of a heist caper. What sets it apart from other entries in the genre (and subsequent adaptations of Leonard works by the likes of other gen X indie directors like Soderbergh), is Tarantino's unique combination of cinema homage and pastiche that gives the proceedings a fresh and vibrant aura. Tarantino skillfully employs elements of blaxploitation through choice soundtrack, camera work, and elegant casting. Pam Grier in the eponymous title role as a middle aged Afro-American woman attempting to emerge out on top of a crime sting is not only a headstrong and intelligently spunky protagonist, but through the course of the film she offers an acute sensitivity to her situation that adds a gravity to the story. coupled with a subtle turn by Robert Forster, in a similair comeback role to John Travolta in Pulp, as an aging, jaded bail bondsman who is injected with a burst of vitalic romantic interest in Jackie Brown, and the subsequent bonding that grows between them offers Tarantino his most empathetically human and thematic material thus far. But the most entertaining turn in from the cast is Samuel L Jackson as the fast-talking, foul mouthed thug who isn't quite as clever of a criminal as he thinks he is. The often witty and hilarious dialogue exchanges between he, Bridget Fonda, and an unassuming Robert DeNiro as a bumbling, apathetic accomplice is amusing and carries the film deftly onward, even when it threatens to be dragged down by the slightly dry plot. But there is a noticeable lack of cloying pop cultural references in the script that Tarantino is known for. Instead, it is all just great character acting, and he manages to make the mundane a roller coaster of verbal levity. The look of the picture is great, with skillfully composed shots and fine tuned audio, with a killer soundtrack to top it off. Jackie Brown is a tightly made film that delivers in its black humor and a feel good tale of one sassy feminist throwback getting the better of her clueless colleagues, and learning a little bit of mid life wisdom along the way. Highly recommended for fans of well constructed and stylish crime capers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Tarantino Crime Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pam Grier, Samuel L. Jackson, Robert Forster, Robert De Niro, Michael Keaton, Michael Bowen, Chris Tucker, Tommy 'Tiny' Lister and Bridget Fonda star in Quentin Tarantino's 1997 crime thriller based on a novel, "Rum Punch." This begins with flight attendant, Jackie Brown (Grier) who gets arrested for possession of drugs and a large amount of cash. She learns that her gun-dealing friend, Ordell Robbie (Jackson) set her up and decides to get back at him. Forster plays bail bondsman, Max Cherry who is hired by Ordell to bail her out of jail for 10 grand. Soon, Jackie meets Max who not only falls for her, but helps her steal Ordell's cash. Keaton plays FBI agent, Ray Nicollete, Bowen plays his partner, Mark Dargus, De Niro plays Ordell's pal, Lois Gara, Fonda plays Ordell's mistress, Melanie Ralston, Tucker (Friday) plays Ordell's friend, Beaumont Livingston and Lister (Friday) plays Max's assistant, Winston. This is a good film with a great cast that also has a nice tribute to 70's films & music. I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Excitement or Violence You Would Look For In a Tarantino Film,But Still Really Good,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Brown is a terrific movie with a very well developed storyline like all Quentin Tarantino's movies and a very talented cast.I certainly didn't enjoy it as much as Tarantino's previous work,Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction,it wasn't as violent,action packed or as exciting as them and I was a bit disappointed by it,but it still is a really good movie.This focuses a lot more on characters and dialogue,which didn't bother me because I really liked these characters and the dialogue was very well written.The cast are all fantastic,Pam Grier and Robert Forster both did a fantastic job,but the best performances had to be Samuel L Jackson and Robert De Niro,their both some of my favourite actors,they always get really interested in their characters,and this is no exception.Fans of Quentin Tarantino will be disappointed by Jackie Brown,but its still a very good,character driven movie. Jackie Brown (Pam Grier) gets involved with an arms dealer and the police force after a few mistakes she made in the past that brought her into jail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quentin, you owe us an apology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    videorama-759-859391
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When first hearing of this title, you would of expected another Pulp Fiction. Sadly here you;re very mistaken. You've been very short changed I'm afraid. Working from Elmore Leonard's novel, Quentin must of been self conscious in his telling of this nothing impressive tale. There's hardly any Tarantino humor or VIOLENCE. We have a few stretched out scenes, wasted ones, of little significance, ones that take place in Jackson's Venice beach apartment. We can tell he's held back here, as if to honor or not disrespect crime author, Leonard's book. Pam Grier playing the title, one of the many great performances, is a 44 year old black woman trying to make ends meat, by earning her undeserved share of money made off selling guns, that her boss, Ordell Robbie sells. Jackson is fun to watch in this, playing bad good, in reverse to the much gentler and reserved teacher he played in 187. When Grier is arrested by the feds, she has her own way of snaking out of it, outwitting authorities, while hatching a plan to rip off Ordeal. You gotta admire the courage and strength of the character, but the storytelling just seems to be prolonged. There's not many surprises in the thriller department either. We know what each character wants, whether he/she is good or bad. They're an open book. Deniro was fun to watch as as ex parolee friend of Jackson, who lags around in Jackson's apartment with skinny bikini bodied pot smoking Mel (Fonda). Her murder in the car park was a shock. On the whole Jackie Brown was a bitter disappointment when seeing it in the cinema. This disappointing feature almost had me wondering if I was in the right cinema. I enjoyed it more second time around on video, but this Tarantino flick is a two an hour flick that could of easily been told in 90 minutes. It's just a prolonged story with a lot of flat, not much happening scenes. If Tarantino did it his way, minus Leonard's' influence, we would of had a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the less Tarantinesque of Tarantino's movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow I missed 'Jackie Brown' - a Tarantino movie made in 1997 which takes in his directing career a chronological place between 'Pulp Fiction' and the two 'Kill Bill' movies. It is to some extent the less Tarantinesque of the Tarantino movies - 150 minutes of solid film making, a violent gangster movie very much in tone with the 90s, but lacking the excesses and the sarcasm of his greatest films. I am sure though that many other folks will consider it the best or one of the best films in his career, exactly for the same reasons I did not like it completely. Great acting by Samuel L. Jackson, Robert De Niro, Bridget Fonda and Palm Grier. Excellent soul music soundtrack - Tarantino's mobsters have a special taste for music, did you notice?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Authentic and well acted but it drags on for far too long
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kluseba
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino is a man between genius and madness who has created some of the best movies ever but also a few true Fails in my opinion. "Jackie Brown" is just between both extremes for me and is maybe his most unspectacular film to date. On the positive side, this movie is Tarantino's most organic one until now. The characters are more credible than usual, the dialogues aren't all too over the top and the story line is quite easy to follow. The movie includes no special effects, shock moments or unexpected twists and feels surprisingly down to earth for a Quentin Tarantino movie. From that point of view, it's a quite unique movie from him. The acting is authentic and very well done. Pam Grier plays an attractive and intelligent lady in her forties who starts the movie as a victim just to become the one who plays with each other character around her. Samuel L. Jackson does a convincing role as superficial but not dumb gangster. Robert Forster plays a bondsman and smart gentleman with a lot of charisma as well. He's the actor I somehow like the most in this movie. In addition to the movie's authentic mood and the great acting, the soundtrack is as always quite convincing as well and introduces us to many great Afroamerican musicians. I must though admit that I preferred by far the soundtracks of other Tarantino movies such as "Kill Bill" or "Django Unchained" for example. On the other side, the movie definitely has its lengths as many Tarantino movies. There are some more or less important endless dialogues that should have been shortened in my opinion. This movie would have just been fine with a running time between ninety and one-hundred-five minutes in my opinion. Apart of that, the story is not only down to earth but also quite unspectacular and there isn't that much going on in two hours and a half. The movie feels a little bit too simple at some points. Apart of the acting, the movie lacks of a true highlight. The killing scenes are really unspectacular and you don't see very much. It's the same thing for one single and quite boring sex scene. The movie is supposed to have a few humorous moments but they really aren't all that memorable. The showdown in the mall also lacks tension. It shows us the same scene from three different views which gets quite redundant. The only truly gripping moments in this movie are the first E encounter between Pam Grier and Samuel L. Jackson in her apartment and the scene when Robert Forster and Samuel L. Jackson go to the Office of the bondsman. In the end, this film could have been a standout movie in Tranatino's career because it's quite different from what he usually does. The film though fails from that point of view and drags on far too long and turns out to be quite unspectacular or even boring at some points. It all feels more like a theatre play where convincing dialogues by solid actors matter but not much more. I have seen far worse but also far better movies and I would only recommend this flick to die hard fans of Quentin Tarantino's works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this 1 star because I had to give it something. I really REALLY hated what I saw of this movie. I didn't actually last till the end. I was going to try and then I decided I had more important things to do with my time, like wash some clothes and feed the dogs. I adore Tarantino films. This one was a complete dud. Self-indulgent nonsense about characters I couldn't care less about talking about stuff that really doesn't matter. All the dialogue was slow & dragged on and on pointlessly. There was no action to speak of and the plot was thin and uninteresting. Really, don't waste your time. And please, if you're a Tarantino fan, don't poison your appreciation for his work by watching this stinker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Brown getting' down!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike dewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may be old news now, but Quentin T. showed out in this fast and sassy maxi-scam caper flick. He couldn't have hired a better acting ensemble to pull this off, to wit, Pam Grier, Robert Forster, Sammy J., Bobby D., Brigid F., Chris Tucker, Michael K., etc. For starters, I think this is the best performance of Pam G's career: she exhibits a multi-dimensional persona here I have never seen her pull off before. For example, notice how she effortlessly segues from the street-savvy demeanor whilst in the company of Sammy J., etc., to the middle-class, nice girl, good-diction modus operandi when she's in the company of the the likes of Robert F. She shows how tight her game really is and isn't afraid to do whatever it takes to pull off her intended caper. Robert F., mild of manner and well composed, is cast as the antithesis of the Sammy J. character who is a down-and-dirty, bombastic rascal. Notice how Robert F's character, a white bail-bondsman, effortlessly mixes in well with people of color without being obsequious or trying to be hip: He is merely himself and lets that fact set the tone for whatever may ensue. Sammy J. is his usual awesome self, with great support from Bobby D. and Brigid F. That unholy trio makes sparks fly as the drama unfolds. Notice how Bobby D's character slowly shifts gears from a mellow understated ex-con to a violent shooter when he becomes unduly provoked: a nice touch from Mr. DeNiro. Quentin T's usually crisp directorial skills are in evidence here, as his cutting in and moving back and forth in time work very well. His rewinds in time allow the viewer to see the same scenes from another vantage point so that one can see the logical progression of events from several angles. All that and an awesome, cleverly positioned soundtrack that kicks much booty! How about "Across 110th Street" at the ending? Did she "get across" or what?! This is my favorite Quentin T. film: ya gotta check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some thoughts...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artistgp
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll refrain from summarizing the entire film because you've either already seen it or you're interested in watching the story. Instead I'll just share some thoughts I had with you. It definitely felt like a step down from most of his films. There wasn't anything revolutionary about the film. The beginning seemed to lag for a good while. It eventually picked up steam during the heist portion of the movie, but that in itself didn't really seem to have anything new to add to that genre. The were some really nice long shots in the film (I'm a huge fan of artistically staged lengthy takes), the car pulling into the empty lot on the other side of the fence is a good example. I will say tho, that there were some long shots that seemed to be stretched out for no apparent reason other than just to do it. The acting was solid. The characters were a mix. Jackie was stuck in a dead end job for somewhere around twenty years and yet she proved to be quite the master mind by the end of the movie. Kind of makes you wonder why she wasn't able to advance in her career. Jackson's character was well played and was indeed intriguing, but after a while I kind of wished he would leave me alone. It's not a bad movie, but not one I would recommend to someone else. These are just my thoughts on this particular project. If you're interested in the film I'd urge you to see it and make your own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black Sheep of the Tarantino Family, Jackie's More Substance-Minded Than Style-Blinded
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Easily Quentin Tarantino's most mature work, which admittedly isn't saying much for a director who brought us the Five Point Palm Exploding Heart Technique and a literal blast of adrenaline to the heart. That's not to say his films have ever lacked in substance - rather, I think the true depth of their character is merely overshadowed by those visceral moments of graphic excess and their stylish methods of delivery. Jackie Brown, instead, manages to step out from that bloody shadow and shine on its own volition. Its lingering close-ups and long doses of heady silence give the impression that the plot is moving slowly, when in fact it's going roughly a mile a minute. Tarantino just wants us to savor the performances of his all-star cast and the tangle of plot threads that surrounds them before forcing our heads out the window and punching the gas in the last twenty minutes. Along the way, he subtly, efficiently grazes a gamut of emotions that leaves us deeply invested in the (often untimely) fate of each character. Rich, complex and rewarding, it's not as flashy as Pulp Fiction or Reservoir Dogs, but it's every bit as excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly enjoyable crime caper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tarantino is often derided by his dismissives as an over zealous, pop-culturally obsessed schizoid with a penchant for fetishizing violence and, oddly enough, feet. But in this 1997 adaptation of the Elmore Leonard novel, and hot off the heels off the watershed event that was Pulp Fiction three years prior, he chose to follow up his electric filmography by incorporating a slightly more complex and elegant plot in the form of a heist caper. What sets it apart from other entries in the genre (and subsequent adaptations of Leonard works by the likes of other gen X indie directors like Soderbergh), is Tarantino's unique combination of cinema homage and pastiche that gives the proceedings a fresh and vibrant aura. Tarantino skillfully employs elements of blaxploitation through choice soundtrack, camera work, and elegant casting. Pam Grier in the eponymous title role as a middle aged Afro-American woman attempting to emerge out on top of a crime sting is not only a headstrong and intelligently spunky protagonist, but through the course of the film she offers an acute sensitivity to her situation that adds a gravity to the story. coupled with a subtle turn by Robert Forster, in a similair comeback role to John Travolta in Pulp, as an aging, jaded bail bondsman who is injected with a burst of vitalic romantic interest in Jackie Brown, and the subsequent bonding that grows between them offers Tarantino his most empathetically human and thematic material thus far. But the most entertaining turn in from the cast is Samuel L Jackson as the fast-talking, foul mouthed thug who isn't quite as clever of a criminal as he thinks he is. The often witty and hilarious dialogue exchanges between he, Bridget Fonda, and an unassuming Robert DeNiro as a bumbling, apathetic accomplice is amusing and carries the film deftly onward, even when it threatens to be dragged down by the slightly dry plot. But there is a noticeable lack of cloying pop cultural references in the script that Tarantino is known for. Instead, it is all just great character acting, and he manages to make the mundane a roller coaster of verbal levity. The look of the picture is great, with skillfully composed shots and fine tuned audio, with a killer soundtrack to top it off. Jackie Brown is a tightly made film that delivers in its black humor and a feel good tale of one sassy feminist throwback getting the better of her clueless colleagues, and learning a little bit of mid life wisdom along the way. Highly recommended for fans of well constructed and stylish crime capers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Tarantino Crime Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pam Grier, Samuel L. Jackson, Robert Forster, Robert De Niro, Michael Keaton, Michael Bowen, Chris Tucker, Tommy 'Tiny' Lister and Bridget Fonda star in Quentin Tarantino's 1997 crime thriller based on a novel, "Rum Punch." This begins with flight attendant, Jackie Brown (Grier) who gets arrested for possession of drugs and a large amount of cash. She learns that her gun-dealing friend, Ordell Robbie (Jackson) set her up and decides to get back at him. Forster plays bail bondsman, Max Cherry who is hired by Ordell to bail her out of jail for 10 grand. Soon, Jackie meets Max who not only falls for her, but helps her steal Ordell's cash. Keaton plays FBI agent, Ray Nicollete, Bowen plays his partner, Mark Dargus, De Niro plays Ordell's pal, Lois Gara, Fonda plays Ordell's mistress, Melanie Ralston, Tucker (Friday) plays Ordell's friend, Beaumont Livingston and Lister (Friday) plays Max's assistant, Winston. This is a good film with a great cast that also has a nice tribute to 70's films & music. I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Excitement or Violence You Would Look For In a Tarantino Film,But Still Really Good,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Brown is a terrific movie with a very well developed storyline like all Quentin Tarantino's movies and a very talented cast.I certainly didn't enjoy it as much as Tarantino's previous work,Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction,it wasn't as violent,action packed or as exciting as them and I was a bit disappointed by it,but it still is a really good movie.This focuses a lot more on characters and dialogue,which didn't bother me because I really liked these characters and the dialogue was very well written.The cast are all fantastic,Pam Grier and Robert Forster both did a fantastic job,but the best performances had to be Samuel L Jackson and Robert De Niro,their both some of my favourite actors,they always get really interested in their characters,and this is no exception.Fans of Quentin Tarantino will be disappointed by Jackie Brown,but its still a very good,character driven movie. Jackie Brown (Pam Grier) gets involved with an arms dealer and the police force after a few mistakes she made in the past that brought her into jail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quentin, you owe us an apology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    videorama-759-859391
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When first hearing of this title, you would of expected another Pulp Fiction. Sadly here you;re very mistaken. You've been very short changed I'm afraid. Working from Elmore Leonard's novel, Quentin must of been self conscious in his telling of this nothing impressive tale. There's hardly any Tarantino humor or VIOLENCE. We have a few stretched out scenes, wasted ones, of little significance, ones that take place in Jackson's Venice beach apartment. We can tell he's held back here, as if to honor or not disrespect crime author, Leonard's book. Pam Grier playing the title, one of the many great performances, is a 44 year old black woman trying to make ends meat, by earning her undeserved share of money made off selling guns, that her boss, Ordell Robbie sells. Jackson is fun to watch in this, playing bad good, in reverse to the much gentler and reserved teacher he played in 187. When Grier is arrested by the feds, she has her own way of snaking out of it, outwitting authorities, while hatching a plan to rip off Ordeal. You gotta admire the courage and strength of the character, but the storytelling just seems to be prolonged. There's not many surprises in the thriller department either. We know what each character wants, whether he/she is good or bad. They're an open book. Deniro was fun to watch as as ex parolee friend of Jackson, who lags around in Jackson's apartment with skinny bikini bodied pot smoking Mel (Fonda). Her murder in the car park was a shock. On the whole Jackie Brown was a bitter disappointment when seeing it in the cinema. This disappointing feature almost had me wondering if I was in the right cinema. I enjoyed it more second time around on video, but this Tarantino flick is a two an hour flick that could of easily been told in 90 minutes. It's just a prolonged story with a lot of flat, not much happening scenes. If Tarantino did it his way, minus Leonard's' influence, we would of had a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the less Tarantinesque of Tarantino's movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow I missed 'Jackie Brown' - a Tarantino movie made in 1997 which takes in his directing career a chronological place between 'Pulp Fiction' and the two 'Kill Bill' movies. It is to some extent the less Tarantinesque of the Tarantino movies - 150 minutes of solid film making, a violent gangster movie very much in tone with the 90s, but lacking the excesses and the sarcasm of his greatest films. I am sure though that many other folks will consider it the best or one of the best films in his career, exactly for the same reasons I did not like it completely. Great acting by Samuel L. Jackson, Robert De Niro, Bridget Fonda and Palm Grier. Excellent soul music soundtrack - Tarantino's mobsters have a special taste for music, did you notice?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Authentic and well acted but it drags on for far too long
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kluseba
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino is a man between genius and madness who has created some of the best movies ever but also a few true Fails in my opinion. "Jackie Brown" is just between both extremes for me and is maybe his most unspectacular film to date. On the positive side, this movie is Tarantino's most organic one until now. The characters are more credible than usual, the dialogues aren't all too over the top and the story line is quite easy to follow. The movie includes no special effects, shock moments or unexpected twists and feels surprisingly down to earth for a Quentin Tarantino movie. From that point of view, it's a quite unique movie from him. The acting is authentic and very well done. Pam Grier plays an attractive and intelligent lady in her forties who starts the movie as a victim just to become the one who plays with each other character around her. Samuel L. Jackson does a convincing role as superficial but not dumb gangster. Robert Forster plays a bondsman and smart gentleman with a lot of charisma as well. He's the actor I somehow like the most in this movie. In addition to the movie's authentic mood and the great acting, the soundtrack is as always quite convincing as well and introduces us to many great Afroamerican musicians. I must though admit that I preferred by far the soundtracks of other Tarantino movies such as "Kill Bill" or "Django Unchained" for example. On the other side, the movie definitely has its lengths as many Tarantino movies. There are some more or less important endless dialogues that should have been shortened in my opinion. This movie would have just been fine with a running time between ninety and one-hundred-five minutes in my opinion. Apart of that, the story is not only down to earth but also quite unspectacular and there isn't that much going on in two hours and a half. The movie feels a little bit too simple at some points. Apart of the acting, the movie lacks of a true highlight. The killing scenes are really unspectacular and you don't see very much. It's the same thing for one single and quite boring sex scene. The movie is supposed to have a few humorous moments but they really aren't all that memorable. The showdown in the mall also lacks tension. It shows us the same scene from three different views which gets quite redundant. The only truly gripping moments in this movie are the first E encounter between Pam Grier and Samuel L. Jackson in her apartment and the scene when Robert Forster and Samuel L. Jackson go to the Office of the bondsman. In the end, this film could have been a standout movie in Tranatino's career because it's quite different from what he usually does. The film though fails from that point of view and drags on far too long and turns out to be quite unspectacular or even boring at some points. It all feels more like a theatre play where convincing dialogues by solid actors matter but not much more. I have seen far worse but also far better movies and I would only recommend this flick to die hard fans of Quentin Tarantino's works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this 1 star because I had to give it something. I really REALLY hated what I saw of this movie. I didn't actually last till the end. I was going to try and then I decided I had more important things to do with my time, like wash some clothes and feed the dogs. I adore Tarantino films. This one was a complete dud. Self-indulgent nonsense about characters I couldn't care less about talking about stuff that really doesn't matter. All the dialogue was slow & dragged on and on pointlessly. There was no action to speak of and the plot was thin and uninteresting. Really, don't waste your time. And please, if you're a Tarantino fan, don't poison your appreciation for his work by watching this stinker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Brown getting' down!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike dewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may be old news now, but Quentin T. showed out in this fast and sassy maxi-scam caper flick. He couldn't have hired a better acting ensemble to pull this off, to wit, Pam Grier, Robert Forster, Sammy J., Bobby D., Brigid F., Chris Tucker, Michael K., etc. For starters, I think this is the best performance of Pam G's career: she exhibits a multi-dimensional persona here I have never seen her pull off before. For example, notice how she effortlessly segues from the street-savvy demeanor whilst in the company of Sammy J., etc., to the middle-class, nice girl, good-diction modus operandi when she's in the company of the the likes of Robert F. She shows how tight her game really is and isn't afraid to do whatever it takes to pull off her intended caper. Robert F., mild of manner and well composed, is cast as the antithesis of the Sammy J. character who is a down-and-dirty, bombastic rascal. Notice how Robert F's character, a white bail-bondsman, effortlessly mixes in well with people of color without being obsequious or trying to be hip: He is merely himself and lets that fact set the tone for whatever may ensue. Sammy J. is his usual awesome self, with great support from Bobby D. and Brigid F. That unholy trio makes sparks fly as the drama unfolds. Notice how Bobby D's character slowly shifts gears from a mellow understated ex-con to a violent shooter when he becomes unduly provoked: a nice touch from Mr. DeNiro. Quentin T's usually crisp directorial skills are in evidence here, as his cutting in and moving back and forth in time work very well. His rewinds in time allow the viewer to see the same scenes from another vantage point so that one can see the logical progression of events from several angles. All that and an awesome, cleverly positioned soundtrack that kicks much booty! How about "Across 110th Street" at the ending? Did she "get across" or what?! This is my favorite Quentin T. film: ya gotta check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some thoughts...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artistgp
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll refrain from summarizing the entire film because you've either already seen it or you're interested in watching the story. Instead I'll just share some thoughts I had with you. It definitely felt like a step down from most of his films. There wasn't anything revolutionary about the film. The beginning seemed to lag for a good while. It eventually picked up steam during the heist portion of the movie, but that in itself didn't really seem to have anything new to add to that genre. The were some really nice long shots in the film (I'm a huge fan of artistically staged lengthy takes), the car pulling into the empty lot on the other side of the fence is a good example. I will say tho, that there were some long shots that seemed to be stretched out for no apparent reason other than just to do it. The acting was solid. The characters were a mix. Jackie was stuck in a dead end job for somewhere around twenty years and yet she proved to be quite the master mind by the end of the movie. Kind of makes you wonder why she wasn't able to advance in her career. Jackson's character was well played and was indeed intriguing, but after a while I kind of wished he would leave me alone. It's not a bad movie, but not one I would recommend to someone else. These are just my thoughts on this particular project. If you're interested in the film I'd urge you to see it and make your own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black Sheep of the Tarantino Family, Jackie's More Substance-Minded Than Style-Blinded
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Easily Quentin Tarantino's most mature work, which admittedly isn't saying much for a director who brought us the Five Point Palm Exploding Heart Technique and a literal blast of adrenaline to the heart. That's not to say his films have ever lacked in substance - rather, I think the true depth of their character is merely overshadowed by those visceral moments of graphic excess and their stylish methods of delivery. Jackie Brown, instead, manages to step out from that bloody shadow and shine on its own volition. Its lingering close-ups and long doses of heady silence give the impression that the plot is moving slowly, when in fact it's going roughly a mile a minute. Tarantino just wants us to savor the performances of his all-star cast and the tangle of plot threads that surrounds them before forcing our heads out the window and punching the gas in the last twenty minutes. Along the way, he subtly, efficiently grazes a gamut of emotions that leaves us deeply invested in the (often untimely) fate of each character. Rich, complex and rewarding, it's not as flashy as Pulp Fiction or Reservoir Dogs, but it's every bit as excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly enjoyable crime caper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tarantino is often derided by his dismissives as an over zealous, pop-culturally obsessed schizoid with a penchant for fetishizing violence and, oddly enough, feet. But in this 1997 adaptation of the Elmore Leonard novel, and hot off the heels off the watershed event that was Pulp Fiction three years prior, he chose to follow up his electric filmography by incorporating a slightly more complex and elegant plot in the form of a heist caper. What sets it apart from other entries in the genre (and subsequent adaptations of Leonard works by the likes of other gen X indie directors like Soderbergh), is Tarantino's unique combination of cinema homage and pastiche that gives the proceedings a fresh and vibrant aura. Tarantino skillfully employs elements of blaxploitation through choice soundtrack, camera work, and elegant casting. Pam Grier in the eponymous title role as a middle aged Afro-American woman attempting to emerge out on top of a crime sting is not only a headstrong and intelligently spunky protagonist, but through the course of the film she offers an acute sensitivity to her situation that adds a gravity to the story. coupled with a subtle turn by Robert Forster, in a similair comeback role to John Travolta in Pulp, as an aging, jaded bail bondsman who is injected with a burst of vitalic romantic interest in Jackie Brown, and the subsequent bonding that grows between them offers Tarantino his most empathetically human and thematic material thus far. But the most entertaining turn in from the cast is Samuel L Jackson as the fast-talking, foul mouthed thug who isn't quite as clever of a criminal as he thinks he is. The often witty and hilarious dialogue exchanges between he, Bridget Fonda, and an unassuming Robert DeNiro as a bumbling, apathetic accomplice is amusing and carries the film deftly onward, even when it threatens to be dragged down by the slightly dry plot. But there is a noticeable lack of cloying pop cultural references in the script that Tarantino is known for. Instead, it is all just great character acting, and he manages to make the mundane a roller coaster of verbal levity. The look of the picture is great, with skillfully composed shots and fine tuned audio, with a killer soundtrack to top it off. Jackie Brown is a tightly made film that delivers in its black humor and a feel good tale of one sassy feminist throwback getting the better of her clueless colleagues, and learning a little bit of mid life wisdom along the way. Highly recommended for fans of well constructed and stylish crime capers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Tarantino Crime Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pam Grier, Samuel L. Jackson, Robert Forster, Robert De Niro, Michael Keaton, Michael Bowen, Chris Tucker, Tommy 'Tiny' Lister and Bridget Fonda star in Quentin Tarantino's 1997 crime thriller based on a novel, "Rum Punch." This begins with flight attendant, Jackie Brown (Grier) who gets arrested for possession of drugs and a large amount of cash. She learns that her gun-dealing friend, Ordell Robbie (Jackson) set her up and decides to get back at him. Forster plays bail bondsman, Max Cherry who is hired by Ordell to bail her out of jail for 10 grand. Soon, Jackie meets Max who not only falls for her, but helps her steal Ordell's cash. Keaton plays FBI agent, Ray Nicollete, Bowen plays his partner, Mark Dargus, De Niro plays Ordell's pal, Lois Gara, Fonda plays Ordell's mistress, Melanie Ralston, Tucker (Friday) plays Ordell's friend, Beaumont Livingston and Lister (Friday) plays Max's assistant, Winston. This is a good film with a great cast that also has a nice tribute to 70's films & music. I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Excitement or Violence You Would Look For In a Tarantino Film,But Still Really Good,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Brown is a terrific movie with a very well developed storyline like all Quentin Tarantino's movies and a very talented cast.I certainly didn't enjoy it as much as Tarantino's previous work,Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction,it wasn't as violent,action packed or as exciting as them and I was a bit disappointed by it,but it still is a really good movie.This focuses a lot more on characters and dialogue,which didn't bother me because I really liked these characters and the dialogue was very well written.The cast are all fantastic,Pam Grier and Robert Forster both did a fantastic job,but the best performances had to be Samuel L Jackson and Robert De Niro,their both some of my favourite actors,they always get really interested in their characters,and this is no exception.Fans of Quentin Tarantino will be disappointed by Jackie Brown,but its still a very good,character driven movie. Jackie Brown (Pam Grier) gets involved with an arms dealer and the police force after a few mistakes she made in the past that brought her into jail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quentin, you owe us an apology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    videorama-759-859391
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When first hearing of this title, you would of expected another Pulp Fiction. Sadly here you;re very mistaken. You've been very short changed I'm afraid. Working from Elmore Leonard's novel, Quentin must of been self conscious in his telling of this nothing impressive tale. There's hardly any Tarantino humor or VIOLENCE. We have a few stretched out scenes, wasted ones, of little significance, ones that take place in Jackson's Venice beach apartment. We can tell he's held back here, as if to honor or not disrespect crime author, Leonard's book. Pam Grier playing the title, one of the many great performances, is a 44 year old black woman trying to make ends meat, by earning her undeserved share of money made off selling guns, that her boss, Ordell Robbie sells. Jackson is fun to watch in this, playing bad good, in reverse to the much gentler and reserved teacher he played in 187. When Grier is arrested by the feds, she has her own way of snaking out of it, outwitting authorities, while hatching a plan to rip off Ordeal. You gotta admire the courage and strength of the character, but the storytelling just seems to be prolonged. There's not many surprises in the thriller department either. We know what each character wants, whether he/she is good or bad. They're an open book. Deniro was fun to watch as as ex parolee friend of Jackson, who lags around in Jackson's apartment with skinny bikini bodied pot smoking Mel (Fonda). Her murder in the car park was a shock. On the whole Jackie Brown was a bitter disappointment when seeing it in the cinema. This disappointing feature almost had me wondering if I was in the right cinema. I enjoyed it more second time around on video, but this Tarantino flick is a two an hour flick that could of easily been told in 90 minutes. It's just a prolonged story with a lot of flat, not much happening scenes. If Tarantino did it his way, minus Leonard's' influence, we would of had a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the less Tarantinesque of Tarantino's movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow I missed 'Jackie Brown' - a Tarantino movie made in 1997 which takes in his directing career a chronological place between 'Pulp Fiction' and the two 'Kill Bill' movies. It is to some extent the less Tarantinesque of the Tarantino movies - 150 minutes of solid film making, a violent gangster movie very much in tone with the 90s, but lacking the excesses and the sarcasm of his greatest films. I am sure though that many other folks will consider it the best or one of the best films in his career, exactly for the same reasons I did not like it completely. Great acting by Samuel L. Jackson, Robert De Niro, Bridget Fonda and Palm Grier. Excellent soul music soundtrack - Tarantino's mobsters have a special taste for music, did you notice?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Authentic and well acted but it drags on for far too long
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kluseba
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino is a man between genius and madness who has created some of the best movies ever but also a few true Fails in my opinion. "Jackie Brown" is just between both extremes for me and is maybe his most unspectacular film to date. On the positive side, this movie is Tarantino's most organic one until now. The characters are more credible than usual, the dialogues aren't all too over the top and the story line is quite easy to follow. The movie includes no special effects, shock moments or unexpected twists and feels surprisingly down to earth for a Quentin Tarantino movie. From that point of view, it's a quite unique movie from him. The acting is authentic and very well done. Pam Grier plays an attractive and intelligent lady in her forties who starts the movie as a victim just to become the one who plays with each other character around her. Samuel L. Jackson does a convincing role as superficial but not dumb gangster. Robert Forster plays a bondsman and smart gentleman with a lot of charisma as well. He's the actor I somehow like the most in this movie. In addition to the movie's authentic mood and the great acting, the soundtrack is as always quite convincing as well and introduces us to many great Afroamerican musicians. I must though admit that I preferred by far the soundtracks of other Tarantino movies such as "Kill Bill" or "Django Unchained" for example. On the other side, the movie definitely has its lengths as many Tarantino movies. There are some more or less important endless dialogues that should have been shortened in my opinion. This movie would have just been fine with a running time between ninety and one-hundred-five minutes in my opinion. Apart of that, the story is not only down to earth but also quite unspectacular and there isn't that much going on in two hours and a half. The movie feels a little bit too simple at some points. Apart of the acting, the movie lacks of a true highlight. The killing scenes are really unspectacular and you don't see very much. It's the same thing for one single and quite boring sex scene. The movie is supposed to have a few humorous moments but they really aren't all that memorable. The showdown in the mall also lacks tension. It shows us the same scene from three different views which gets quite redundant. The only truly gripping moments in this movie are the first E encounter between Pam Grier and Samuel L. Jackson in her apartment and the scene when Robert Forster and Samuel L. Jackson go to the Office of the bondsman. In the end, this film could have been a standout movie in Tranatino's career because it's quite different from what he usually does. The film though fails from that point of view and drags on far too long and turns out to be quite unspectacular or even boring at some points. It all feels more like a theatre play where convincing dialogues by solid actors matter but not much more. I have seen far worse but also far better movies and I would only recommend this flick to die hard fans of Quentin Tarantino's works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this 1 star because I had to give it something. I really REALLY hated what I saw of this movie. I didn't actually last till the end. I was going to try and then I decided I had more important things to do with my time, like wash some clothes and feed the dogs. I adore Tarantino films. This one was a complete dud. Self-indulgent nonsense about characters I couldn't care less about talking about stuff that really doesn't matter. All the dialogue was slow & dragged on and on pointlessly. There was no action to speak of and the plot was thin and uninteresting. Really, don't waste your time. And please, if you're a Tarantino fan, don't poison your appreciation for his work by watching this stinker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Brown getting' down!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike dewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may be old news now, but Quentin T. showed out in this fast and sassy maxi-scam caper flick. He couldn't have hired a better acting ensemble to pull this off, to wit, Pam Grier, Robert Forster, Sammy J., Bobby D., Brigid F., Chris Tucker, Michael K., etc. For starters, I think this is the best performance of Pam G's career: she exhibits a multi-dimensional persona here I have never seen her pull off before. For example, notice how she effortlessly segues from the street-savvy demeanor whilst in the company of Sammy J., etc., to the middle-class, nice girl, good-diction modus operandi when she's in the company of the the likes of Robert F. She shows how tight her game really is and isn't afraid to do whatever it takes to pull off her intended caper. Robert F., mild of manner and well composed, is cast as the antithesis of the Sammy J. character who is a down-and-dirty, bombastic rascal. Notice how Robert F's character, a white bail-bondsman, effortlessly mixes in well with people of color without being obsequious or trying to be hip: He is merely himself and lets that fact set the tone for whatever may ensue. Sammy J. is his usual awesome self, with great support from Bobby D. and Brigid F. That unholy trio makes sparks fly as the drama unfolds. Notice how Bobby D's character slowly shifts gears from a mellow understated ex-con to a violent shooter when he becomes unduly provoked: a nice touch from Mr. DeNiro. Quentin T's usually crisp directorial skills are in evidence here, as his cutting in and moving back and forth in time work very well. His rewinds in time allow the viewer to see the same scenes from another vantage point so that one can see the logical progression of events from several angles. All that and an awesome, cleverly positioned soundtrack that kicks much booty! How about "Across 110th Street" at the ending? Did she "get across" or what?! This is my favorite Quentin T. film: ya gotta check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some thoughts...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artistgp
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll refrain from summarizing the entire film because you've either already seen it or you're interested in watching the story. Instead I'll just share some thoughts I had with you. It definitely felt like a step down from most of his films. There wasn't anything revolutionary about the film. The beginning seemed to lag for a good while. It eventually picked up steam during the heist portion of the movie, but that in itself didn't really seem to have anything new to add to that genre. The were some really nice long shots in the film (I'm a huge fan of artistically staged lengthy takes), the car pulling into the empty lot on the other side of the fence is a good example. I will say tho, that there were some long shots that seemed to be stretched out for no apparent reason other than just to do it. The acting was solid. The characters were a mix. Jackie was stuck in a dead end job for somewhere around twenty years and yet she proved to be quite the master mind by the end of the movie. Kind of makes you wonder why she wasn't able to advance in her career. Jackson's character was well played and was indeed intriguing, but after a while I kind of wished he would leave me alone. It's not a bad movie, but not one I would recommend to someone else. These are just my thoughts on this particular project. If you're interested in the film I'd urge you to see it and make your own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black Sheep of the Tarantino Family, Jackie's More Substance-Minded Than Style-Blinded
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Easily Quentin Tarantino's most mature work, which admittedly isn't saying much for a director who brought us the Five Point Palm Exploding Heart Technique and a literal blast of adrenaline to the heart. That's not to say his films have ever lacked in substance - rather, I think the true depth of their character is merely overshadowed by those visceral moments of graphic excess and their stylish methods of delivery. Jackie Brown, instead, manages to step out from that bloody shadow and shine on its own volition. Its lingering close-ups and long doses of heady silence give the impression that the plot is moving slowly, when in fact it's going roughly a mile a minute. Tarantino just wants us to savor the performances of his all-star cast and the tangle of plot threads that surrounds them before forcing our heads out the window and punching the gas in the last twenty minutes. Along the way, he subtly, efficiently grazes a gamut of emotions that leaves us deeply invested in the (often untimely) fate of each character. Rich, complex and rewarding, it's not as flashy as Pulp Fiction or Reservoir Dogs, but it's every bit as excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly enjoyable crime caper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tarantino is often derided by his dismissives as an over zealous, pop-culturally obsessed schizoid with a penchant for fetishizing violence and, oddly enough, feet. But in this 1997 adaptation of the Elmore Leonard novel, and hot off the heels off the watershed event that was Pulp Fiction three years prior, he chose to follow up his electric filmography by incorporating a slightly more complex and elegant plot in the form of a heist caper. What sets it apart from other entries in the genre (and subsequent adaptations of Leonard works by the likes of other gen X indie directors like Soderbergh), is Tarantino's unique combination of cinema homage and pastiche that gives the proceedings a fresh and vibrant aura. Tarantino skillfully employs elements of blaxploitation through choice soundtrack, camera work, and elegant casting. Pam Grier in the eponymous title role as a middle aged Afro-American woman attempting to emerge out on top of a crime sting is not only a headstrong and intelligently spunky protagonist, but through the course of the film she offers an acute sensitivity to her situation that adds a gravity to the story. coupled with a subtle turn by Robert Forster, in a similair comeback role to John Travolta in Pulp, as an aging, jaded bail bondsman who is injected with a burst of vitalic romantic interest in Jackie Brown, and the subsequent bonding that grows between them offers Tarantino his most empathetically human and thematic material thus far. But the most entertaining turn in from the cast is Samuel L Jackson as the fast-talking, foul mouthed thug who isn't quite as clever of a criminal as he thinks he is. The often witty and hilarious dialogue exchanges between he, Bridget Fonda, and an unassuming Robert DeNiro as a bumbling, apathetic accomplice is amusing and carries the film deftly onward, even when it threatens to be dragged down by the slightly dry plot. But there is a noticeable lack of cloying pop cultural references in the script that Tarantino is known for. Instead, it is all just great character acting, and he manages to make the mundane a roller coaster of verbal levity. The look of the picture is great, with skillfully composed shots and fine tuned audio, with a killer soundtrack to top it off. Jackie Brown is a tightly made film that delivers in its black humor and a feel good tale of one sassy feminist throwback getting the better of her clueless colleagues, and learning a little bit of mid life wisdom along the way. Highly recommended for fans of well constructed and stylish crime capers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Tarantino Crime Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pam Grier, Samuel L. Jackson, Robert Forster, Robert De Niro, Michael Keaton, Michael Bowen, Chris Tucker, Tommy 'Tiny' Lister and Bridget Fonda star in Quentin Tarantino's 1997 crime thriller based on a novel, "Rum Punch." This begins with flight attendant, Jackie Brown (Grier) who gets arrested for possession of drugs and a large amount of cash. She learns that her gun-dealing friend, Ordell Robbie (Jackson) set her up and decides to get back at him. Forster plays bail bondsman, Max Cherry who is hired by Ordell to bail her out of jail for 10 grand. Soon, Jackie meets Max who not only falls for her, but helps her steal Ordell's cash. Keaton plays FBI agent, Ray Nicollete, Bowen plays his partner, Mark Dargus, De Niro plays Ordell's pal, Lois Gara, Fonda plays Ordell's mistress, Melanie Ralston, Tucker (Friday) plays Ordell's friend, Beaumont Livingston and Lister (Friday) plays Max's assistant, Winston. This is a good film with a great cast that also has a nice tribute to 70's films & music. I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Excitement or Violence You Would Look For In a Tarantino Film,But Still Really Good,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Brown is a terrific movie with a very well developed storyline like all Quentin Tarantino's movies and a very talented cast.I certainly didn't enjoy it as much as Tarantino's previous work,Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction,it wasn't as violent,action packed or as exciting as them and I was a bit disappointed by it,but it still is a really good movie.This focuses a lot more on characters and dialogue,which didn't bother me because I really liked these characters and the dialogue was very well written.The cast are all fantastic,Pam Grier and Robert Forster both did a fantastic job,but the best performances had to be Samuel L Jackson and Robert De Niro,their both some of my favourite actors,they always get really interested in their characters,and this is no exception.Fans of Quentin Tarantino will be disappointed by Jackie Brown,but its still a very good,character driven movie. Jackie Brown (Pam Grier) gets involved with an arms dealer and the police force after a few mistakes she made in the past that brought her into jail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quentin, you owe us an apology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    videorama-759-859391
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When first hearing of this title, you would of expected another Pulp Fiction. Sadly here you;re very mistaken. You've been very short changed I'm afraid. Working from Elmore Leonard's novel, Quentin must of been self conscious in his telling of this nothing impressive tale. There's hardly any Tarantino humor or VIOLENCE. We have a few stretched out scenes, wasted ones, of little significance, ones that take place in Jackson's Venice beach apartment. We can tell he's held back here, as if to honor or not disrespect crime author, Leonard's book. Pam Grier playing the title, one of the many great performances, is a 44 year old black woman trying to make ends meat, by earning her undeserved share of money made off selling guns, that her boss, Ordell Robbie sells. Jackson is fun to watch in this, playing bad good, in reverse to the much gentler and reserved teacher he played in 187. When Grier is arrested by the feds, she has her own way of snaking out of it, outwitting authorities, while hatching a plan to rip off Ordeal. You gotta admire the courage and strength of the character, but the storytelling just seems to be prolonged. There's not many surprises in the thriller department either. We know what each character wants, whether he/she is good or bad. They're an open book. Deniro was fun to watch as as ex parolee friend of Jackson, who lags around in Jackson's apartment with skinny bikini bodied pot smoking Mel (Fonda). Her murder in the car park was a shock. On the whole Jackie Brown was a bitter disappointment when seeing it in the cinema. This disappointing feature almost had me wondering if I was in the right cinema. I enjoyed it more second time around on video, but this Tarantino flick is a two an hour flick that could of easily been told in 90 minutes. It's just a prolonged story with a lot of flat, not much happening scenes. If Tarantino did it his way, minus Leonard's' influence, we would of had a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the less Tarantinesque of Tarantino's movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow I missed 'Jackie Brown' - a Tarantino movie made in 1997 which takes in his directing career a chronological place between 'Pulp Fiction' and the two 'Kill Bill' movies. It is to some extent the less Tarantinesque of the Tarantino movies - 150 minutes of solid film making, a violent gangster movie very much in tone with the 90s, but lacking the excesses and the sarcasm of his greatest films. I am sure though that many other folks will consider it the best or one of the best films in his career, exactly for the same reasons I did not like it completely. Great acting by Samuel L. Jackson, Robert De Niro, Bridget Fonda and Palm Grier. Excellent soul music soundtrack - Tarantino's mobsters have a special taste for music, did you notice?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Authentic and well acted but it drags on for far too long
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kluseba
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino is a man between genius and madness who has created some of the best movies ever but also a few true Fails in my opinion. "Jackie Brown" is just between both extremes for me and is maybe his most unspectacular film to date. On the positive side, this movie is Tarantino's most organic one until now. The characters are more credible than usual, the dialogues aren't all too over the top and the story line is quite easy to follow. The movie includes no special effects, shock moments or unexpected twists and feels surprisingly down to earth for a Quentin Tarantino movie. From that point of view, it's a quite unique movie from him. The acting is authentic and very well done. Pam Grier plays an attractive and intelligent lady in her forties who starts the movie as a victim just to become the one who plays with each other character around her. Samuel L. Jackson does a convincing role as superficial but not dumb gangster. Robert Forster plays a bondsman and smart gentleman with a lot of charisma as well. He's the actor I somehow like the most in this movie. In addition to the movie's authentic mood and the great acting, the soundtrack is as always quite convincing as well and introduces us to many great Afroamerican musicians. I must though admit that I preferred by far the soundtracks of other Tarantino movies such as "Kill Bill" or "Django Unchained" for example. On the other side, the movie definitely has its lengths as many Tarantino movies. There are some more or less important endless dialogues that should have been shortened in my opinion. This movie would have just been fine with a running time between ninety and one-hundred-five minutes in my opinion. Apart of that, the story is not only down to earth but also quite unspectacular and there isn't that much going on in two hours and a half. The movie feels a little bit too simple at some points. Apart of the acting, the movie lacks of a true highlight. The killing scenes are really unspectacular and you don't see very much. It's the same thing for one single and quite boring sex scene. The movie is supposed to have a few humorous moments but they really aren't all that memorable. The showdown in the mall also lacks tension. It shows us the same scene from three different views which gets quite redundant. The only truly gripping moments in this movie are the first E encounter between Pam Grier and Samuel L. Jackson in her apartment and the scene when Robert Forster and Samuel L. Jackson go to the Office of the bondsman. In the end, this film could have been a standout movie in Tranatino's career because it's quite different from what he usually does. The film though fails from that point of view and drags on far too long and turns out to be quite unspectacular or even boring at some points. It all feels more like a theatre play where convincing dialogues by solid actors matter but not much more. I have seen far worse but also far better movies and I would only recommend this flick to die hard fans of Quentin Tarantino's works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this 1 star because I had to give it something. I really REALLY hated what I saw of this movie. I didn't actually last till the end. I was going to try and then I decided I had more important things to do with my time, like wash some clothes and feed the dogs. I adore Tarantino films. This one was a complete dud. Self-indulgent nonsense about characters I couldn't care less about talking about stuff that really doesn't matter. All the dialogue was slow & dragged on and on pointlessly. There was no action to speak of and the plot was thin and uninteresting. Really, don't waste your time. And please, if you're a Tarantino fan, don't poison your appreciation for his work by watching this stinker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Brown getting' down!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike dewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may be old news now, but Quentin T. showed out in this fast and sassy maxi-scam caper flick. He couldn't have hired a better acting ensemble to pull this off, to wit, Pam Grier, Robert Forster, Sammy J., Bobby D., Brigid F., Chris Tucker, Michael K., etc. For starters, I think this is the best performance of Pam G's career: she exhibits a multi-dimensional persona here I have never seen her pull off before. For example, notice how she effortlessly segues from the street-savvy demeanor whilst in the company of Sammy J., etc., to the middle-class, nice girl, good-diction modus operandi when she's in the company of the the likes of Robert F. She shows how tight her game really is and isn't afraid to do whatever it takes to pull off her intended caper. Robert F., mild of manner and well composed, is cast as the antithesis of the Sammy J. character who is a down-and-dirty, bombastic rascal. Notice how Robert F's character, a white bail-bondsman, effortlessly mixes in well with people of color without being obsequious or trying to be hip: He is merely himself and lets that fact set the tone for whatever may ensue. Sammy J. is his usual awesome self, with great support from Bobby D. and Brigid F. That unholy trio makes sparks fly as the drama unfolds. Notice how Bobby D's character slowly shifts gears from a mellow understated ex-con to a violent shooter when he becomes unduly provoked: a nice touch from Mr. DeNiro. Quentin T's usually crisp directorial skills are in evidence here, as his cutting in and moving back and forth in time work very well. His rewinds in time allow the viewer to see the same scenes from another vantage point so that one can see the logical progression of events from several angles. All that and an awesome, cleverly positioned soundtrack that kicks much booty! How about "Across 110th Street" at the ending? Did she "get across" or what?! This is my favorite Quentin T. film: ya gotta check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some thoughts...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artistgp
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll refrain from summarizing the entire film because you've either already seen it or you're interested in watching the story. Instead I'll just share some thoughts I had with you. It definitely felt like a step down from most of his films. There wasn't anything revolutionary about the film. The beginning seemed to lag for a good while. It eventually picked up steam during the heist portion of the movie, but that in itself didn't really seem to have anything new to add to that genre. The were some really nice long shots in the film (I'm a huge fan of artistically staged lengthy takes), the car pulling into the empty lot on the other side of the fence is a good example. I will say tho, that there were some long shots that seemed to be stretched out for no apparent reason other than just to do it. The acting was solid. The characters were a mix. Jackie was stuck in a dead end job for somewhere around twenty years and yet she proved to be quite the master mind by the end of the movie. Kind of makes you wonder why she wasn't able to advance in her career. Jackson's character was well played and was indeed intriguing, but after a while I kind of wished he would leave me alone. It's not a bad movie, but not one I would recommend to someone else. These are just my thoughts on this particular project. If you're interested in the film I'd urge you to see it and make your own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black Sheep of the Tarantino Family, Jackie's More Substance-Minded Than Style-Blinded
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Easily Quentin Tarantino's most mature work, which admittedly isn't saying much for a director who brought us the Five Point Palm Exploding Heart Technique and a literal blast of adrenaline to the heart. That's not to say his films have ever lacked in substance - rather, I think the true depth of their character is merely overshadowed by those visceral moments of graphic excess and their stylish methods of delivery. Jackie Brown, instead, manages to step out from that bloody shadow and shine on its own volition. Its lingering close-ups and long doses of heady silence give the impression that the plot is moving slowly, when in fact it's going roughly a mile a minute. Tarantino just wants us to savor the performances of his all-star cast and the tangle of plot threads that surrounds them before forcing our heads out the window and punching the gas in the last twenty minutes. Along the way, he subtly, efficiently grazes a gamut of emotions that leaves us deeply invested in the (often untimely) fate of each character. Rich, complex and rewarding, it's not as flashy as Pulp Fiction or Reservoir Dogs, but it's every bit as excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly enjoyable crime caper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tarantino is often derided by his dismissives as an over zealous, pop-culturally obsessed schizoid with a penchant for fetishizing violence and, oddly enough, feet. But in this 1997 adaptation of the Elmore Leonard novel, and hot off the heels off the watershed event that was Pulp Fiction three years prior, he chose to follow up his electric filmography by incorporating a slightly more complex and elegant plot in the form of a heist caper. What sets it apart from other entries in the genre (and subsequent adaptations of Leonard works by the likes of other gen X indie directors like Soderbergh), is Tarantino's unique combination of cinema homage and pastiche that gives the proceedings a fresh and vibrant aura. Tarantino skillfully employs elements of blaxploitation through choice soundtrack, camera work, and elegant casting. Pam Grier in the eponymous title role as a middle aged Afro-American woman attempting to emerge out on top of a crime sting is not only a headstrong and intelligently spunky protagonist, but through the course of the film she offers an acute sensitivity to her situation that adds a gravity to the story. coupled with a subtle turn by Robert Forster, in a similair comeback role to John Travolta in Pulp, as an aging, jaded bail bondsman who is injected with a burst of vitalic romantic interest in Jackie Brown, and the subsequent bonding that grows between them offers Tarantino his most empathetically human and thematic material thus far. But the most entertaining turn in from the cast is Samuel L Jackson as the fast-talking, foul mouthed thug who isn't quite as clever of a criminal as he thinks he is. The often witty and hilarious dialogue exchanges between he, Bridget Fonda, and an unassuming Robert DeNiro as a bumbling, apathetic accomplice is amusing and carries the film deftly onward, even when it threatens to be dragged down by the slightly dry plot. But there is a noticeable lack of cloying pop cultural references in the script that Tarantino is known for. Instead, it is all just great character acting, and he manages to make the mundane a roller coaster of verbal levity. The look of the picture is great, with skillfully composed shots and fine tuned audio, with a killer soundtrack to top it off. Jackie Brown is a tightly made film that delivers in its black humor and a feel good tale of one sassy feminist throwback getting the better of her clueless colleagues, and learning a little bit of mid life wisdom along the way. Highly recommended for fans of well constructed and stylish crime capers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Tarantino Crime Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pam Grier, Samuel L. Jackson, Robert Forster, Robert De Niro, Michael Keaton, Michael Bowen, Chris Tucker, Tommy 'Tiny' Lister and Bridget Fonda star in Quentin Tarantino's 1997 crime thriller based on a novel, "Rum Punch." This begins with flight attendant, Jackie Brown (Grier) who gets arrested for possession of drugs and a large amount of cash. She learns that her gun-dealing friend, Ordell Robbie (Jackson) set her up and decides to get back at him. Forster plays bail bondsman, Max Cherry who is hired by Ordell to bail her out of jail for 10 grand. Soon, Jackie meets Max who not only falls for her, but helps her steal Ordell's cash. Keaton plays FBI agent, Ray Nicollete, Bowen plays his partner, Mark Dargus, De Niro plays Ordell's pal, Lois Gara, Fonda plays Ordell's mistress, Melanie Ralston, Tucker (Friday) plays Ordell's friend, Beaumont Livingston and Lister (Friday) plays Max's assistant, Winston. This is a good film with a great cast that also has a nice tribute to 70's films & music. I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Excitement or Violence You Would Look For In a Tarantino Film,But Still Really Good,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Brown is a terrific movie with a very well developed storyline like all Quentin Tarantino's movies and a very talented cast.I certainly didn't enjoy it as much as Tarantino's previous work,Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction,it wasn't as violent,action packed or as exciting as them and I was a bit disappointed by it,but it still is a really good movie.This focuses a lot more on characters and dialogue,which didn't bother me because I really liked these characters and the dialogue was very well written.The cast are all fantastic,Pam Grier and Robert Forster both did a fantastic job,but the best performances had to be Samuel L Jackson and Robert De Niro,their both some of my favourite actors,they always get really interested in their characters,and this is no exception.Fans of Quentin Tarantino will be disappointed by Jackie Brown,but its still a very good,character driven movie. Jackie Brown (Pam Grier) gets involved with an arms dealer and the police force after a few mistakes she made in the past that brought her into jail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quentin, you owe us an apology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    videorama-759-859391
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When first hearing of this title, you would of expected another Pulp Fiction. Sadly here you;re very mistaken. You've been very short changed I'm afraid. Working from Elmore Leonard's novel, Quentin must of been self conscious in his telling of this nothing impressive tale. There's hardly any Tarantino humor or VIOLENCE. We have a few stretched out scenes, wasted ones, of little significance, ones that take place in Jackson's Venice beach apartment. We can tell he's held back here, as if to honor or not disrespect crime author, Leonard's book. Pam Grier playing the title, one of the many great performances, is a 44 year old black woman trying to make ends meat, by earning her undeserved share of money made off selling guns, that her boss, Ordell Robbie sells. Jackson is fun to watch in this, playing bad good, in reverse to the much gentler and reserved teacher he played in 187. When Grier is arrested by the feds, she has her own way of snaking out of it, outwitting authorities, while hatching a plan to rip off Ordeal. You gotta admire the courage and strength of the character, but the storytelling just seems to be prolonged. There's not many surprises in the thriller department either. We know what each character wants, whether he/she is good or bad. They're an open book. Deniro was fun to watch as as ex parolee friend of Jackson, who lags around in Jackson's apartment with skinny bikini bodied pot smoking Mel (Fonda). Her murder in the car park was a shock. On the whole Jackie Brown was a bitter disappointment when seeing it in the cinema. This disappointing feature almost had me wondering if I was in the right cinema. I enjoyed it more second time around on video, but this Tarantino flick is a two an hour flick that could of easily been told in 90 minutes. It's just a prolonged story with a lot of flat, not much happening scenes. If Tarantino did it his way, minus Leonard's' influence, we would of had a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the less Tarantinesque of Tarantino's movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Somehow I missed 'Jackie Brown' - a Tarantino movie made in 1997 which takes in his directing career a chronological place between 'Pulp Fiction' and the two 'Kill Bill' movies. It is to some extent the less Tarantinesque of the Tarantino movies - 150 minutes of solid film making, a violent gangster movie very much in tone with the 90s, but lacking the excesses and the sarcasm of his greatest films. I am sure though that many other folks will consider it the best or one of the best films in his career, exactly for the same reasons I did not like it completely. Great acting by Samuel L. Jackson, Robert De Niro, Bridget Fonda and Palm Grier. Excellent soul music soundtrack - Tarantino's mobsters have a special taste for music, did you notice?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Authentic and well acted but it drags on for far too long
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kluseba
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quentin Tarantino is a man between genius and madness who has created some of the best movies ever but also a few true Fails in my opinion. "Jackie Brown" is just between both extremes for me and is maybe his most unspectacular film to date. On the positive side, this movie is Tarantino's most organic one until now. The characters are more credible than usual, the dialogues aren't all too over the top and the story line is quite easy to follow. The movie includes no special effects, shock moments or unexpected twists and feels surprisingly down to earth for a Quentin Tarantino movie. From that point of view, it's a quite unique movie from him. The acting is authentic and very well done. Pam Grier plays an attractive and intelligent lady in her forties who starts the movie as a victim just to become the one who plays with each other character around her. Samuel L. Jackson does a convincing role as superficial but not dumb gangster. Robert Forster plays a bondsman and smart gentleman with a lot of charisma as well. He's the actor I somehow like the most in this movie. In addition to the movie's authentic mood and the great acting, the soundtrack is as always quite convincing as well and introduces us to many great Afroamerican musicians. I must though admit that I preferred by far the soundtracks of other Tarantino movies such as "Kill Bill" or "Django Unchained" for example. On the other side, the movie definitely has its lengths as many Tarantino movies. There are some more or less important endless dialogues that should have been shortened in my opinion. This movie would have just been fine with a running time between ninety and one-hundred-five minutes in my opinion. Apart of that, the story is not only down to earth but also quite unspectacular and there isn't that much going on in two hours and a half. The movie feels a little bit too simple at some points. Apart of the acting, the movie lacks of a true highlight. The killing scenes are really unspectacular and you don't see very much. It's the same thing for one single and quite boring sex scene. The movie is supposed to have a few humorous moments but they really aren't all that memorable. The showdown in the mall also lacks tension. It shows us the same scene from three different views which gets quite redundant. The only truly gripping moments in this movie are the first E encounter between Pam Grier and Samuel L. Jackson in her apartment and the scene when Robert Forster and Samuel L. Jackson go to the Office of the bondsman. In the end, this film could have been a standout movie in Tranatino's career because it's quite different from what he usually does. The film though fails from that point of view and drags on far too long and turns out to be quite unspectacular or even boring at some points. It all feels more like a theatre play where convincing dialogues by solid actors matter but not much more. I have seen far worse but also far better movies and I would only recommend this flick to die hard fans of Quentin Tarantino's works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this 1 star because I had to give it something. I really REALLY hated what I saw of this movie. I didn't actually last till the end. I was going to try and then I decided I had more important things to do with my time, like wash some clothes and feed the dogs. I adore Tarantino films. This one was a complete dud. Self-indulgent nonsense about characters I couldn't care less about talking about stuff that really doesn't matter. All the dialogue was slow & dragged on and on pointlessly. There was no action to speak of and the plot was thin and uninteresting. Really, don't waste your time. And please, if you're a Tarantino fan, don't poison your appreciation for his work by watching this stinker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Brown getting' down!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike dewey
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It may be old news now, but Quentin T. showed out in this fast and sassy maxi-scam caper flick. He couldn't have hired a better acting ensemble to pull this off, to wit, Pam Grier, Robert Forster, Sammy J., Bobby D., Brigid F., Chris Tucker, Michael K., etc. For starters, I think this is the best performance of Pam G's career: she exhibits a multi-dimensional persona here I have never seen her pull off before. For example, notice how she effortlessly segues from the street-savvy demeanor whilst in the company of Sammy J., etc., to the middle-class, nice girl, good-diction modus operandi when she's in the company of the the likes of Robert F. She shows how tight her game really is and isn't afraid to do whatever it takes to pull off her intended caper. Robert F., mild of manner and well composed, is cast as the antithesis of the Sammy J. character who is a down-and-dirty, bombastic rascal. Notice how Robert F's character, a white bail-bondsman, effortlessly mixes in well with people of color without being obsequious or trying to be hip: He is merely himself and lets that fact set the tone for whatever may ensue. Sammy J. is his usual awesome self, with great support from Bobby D. and Brigid F. That unholy trio makes sparks fly as the drama unfolds. Notice how Bobby D's character slowly shifts gears from a mellow understated ex-con to a violent shooter when he becomes unduly provoked: a nice touch from Mr. DeNiro. Quentin T's usually crisp directorial skills are in evidence here, as his cutting in and moving back and forth in time work very well. His rewinds in time allow the viewer to see the same scenes from another vantage point so that one can see the logical progression of events from several angles. All that and an awesome, cleverly positioned soundtrack that kicks much booty! How about "Across 110th Street" at the ending? Did she "get across" or what?! This is my favorite Quentin T. film: ya gotta check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some thoughts...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artistgp
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll refrain from summarizing the entire film because you've either already seen it or you're interested in watching the story. Instead I'll just share some thoughts I had with you. It definitely felt like a step down from most of his films. There wasn't anything revolutionary about the film. The beginning seemed to lag for a good while. It eventually picked up steam during the heist portion of the movie, but that in itself didn't really seem to have anything new to add to that genre. The were some really nice long shots in the film (I'm a huge fan of artistically staged lengthy takes), the car pulling into the empty lot on the other side of the fence is a good example. I will say tho, that there were some long shots that seemed to be stretched out for no apparent reason other than just to do it. The acting was solid. The characters were a mix. Jackie was stuck in a dead end job for somewhere around twenty years and yet she proved to be quite the master mind by the end of the movie. Kind of makes you wonder why she wasn't able to advance in her career. Jackson's character was well played and was indeed intriguing, but after a while I kind of wished he would leave me alone. It's not a bad movie, but not one I would recommend to someone else. These are just my thoughts on this particular project. If you're interested in the film I'd urge you to see it and make your own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black Sheep of the Tarantino Family, Jackie's More Substance-Minded Than Style-Blinded
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Easily Quentin Tarantino's most mature work, which admittedly isn't saying much for a director who brought us the Five Point Palm Exploding Heart Technique and a literal blast of adrenaline to the heart. That's not to say his films have ever lacked in substance - rather, I think the true depth of their character is merely overshadowed by those visceral moments of graphic excess and their stylish methods of delivery. Jackie Brown, instead, manages to step out from that bloody shadow and shine on its own volition. Its lingering close-ups and long doses of heady silence give the impression that the plot is moving slowly, when in fact it's going roughly a mile a minute. Tarantino just wants us to savor the performances of his all-star cast and the tangle of plot threads that surrounds them before forcing our heads out the window and punching the gas in the last twenty minutes. Along the way, he subtly, efficiently grazes a gamut of emotions that leaves us deeply invested in the (often untimely) fate of each character. Rich, complex and rewarding, it's not as flashy as Pulp Fiction or Reservoir Dogs, but it's every bit as excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly enjoyable crime caper
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tarantino is often derided by his dismissives as an over zealous, pop-culturally obsessed schizoid with a penchant for fetishizing violence and, oddly enough, feet. But in this 1997 adaptation of the Elmore Leonard novel, and hot off the heels off the watershed event that was Pulp Fiction three years prior, he chose to follow up his electric filmography by incorporating a slightly more complex and elegant plot in the form of a heist caper. What sets it apart from other entries in the genre (and subsequent adaptations of Leonard works by the likes of other gen X indie directors like Soderbergh), is Tarantino's unique combination of cinema homage and pastiche that gives the proceedings a fresh and vibrant aura. Tarantino skillfully employs elements of blaxploitation through choice soundtrack, camera work, and elegant casting. Pam Grier in the eponymous title role as a middle aged Afro-American woman attempting to emerge out on top of a crime sting is not only a headstrong and intelligently spunky protagonist, but through the course of the film she offers an acute sensitivity to her situation that adds a gravity to the story. coupled with a subtle turn by Robert Forster, in a similair comeback role to John Travolta in Pulp, as an aging, jaded bail bondsman who is injected with a burst of vitalic romantic interest in Jackie Brown, and the subsequent bonding that grows between them offers Tarantino his most empathetically human and thematic material thus far. But the most entertaining turn in from the cast is Samuel L Jackson as the fast-talking, foul mouthed thug who isn't quite as clever of a criminal as he thinks he is. The often witty and hilarious dialogue exchanges between he, Bridget Fonda, and an unassuming Robert DeNiro as a bumbling, apathetic accomplice is amusing and carries the film deftly onward, even when it threatens to be dragged down by the slightly dry plot. But there is a noticeable lack of cloying pop cultural references in the script that Tarantino is known for. Instead, it is all just great character acting, and he manages to make the mundane a roller coaster of verbal levity. The look of the picture is great, with skillfully composed shots and fine tuned audio, with a killer soundtrack to top it off. Jackie Brown is a tightly made film that delivers in its black humor and a feel good tale of one sassy feminist throwback getting the better of her clueless colleagues, and learning a little bit of mid life wisdom along the way. Highly recommended for fans of well constructed and stylish crime capers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
