<filme>
 <id>
  347
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120885
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Mera Coincid&ecirc;ncia
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Shortly before an election, a spin-doctor and a Hollywood producer join efforts to fabricate a war in order to cover up a presidential sex scandal.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  After being caught in a scandalous situation days before the election, the president does not seem to have much of a chance of being re-elected. One of his advisers contacts a top Hollywood producer in order to manufacture a war in Albania that the president can heroically end, all through mass media.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   hollywood
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   scandal
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   spin doctor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cover up
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Barry Levinson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Larry Beinhart
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Hilary Henkin
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dustin Hoffman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert De Niro
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Anne Heche
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sly Political Satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The U.S, President has just been exposed in a sex scandal not long before the next election. Rather than resign or take responsibility, White House spin doctors(led by Robert De Nero & Anne Heche) instead contact a Hollywood producer(Dustin Hoffman, quite funny) to direct an elaborate hoaxed war with Albania, in hopes that the nation will rally behind their incumbent president, and forget/forgive the sex scandal. Things get complicated when a "war hero"(Woody Harrelson) turns out to be a psychopath, and later on when the director insists on putting it on his resume... Ingenious satire by director Barry Levinson is extremely clever & knowing, since it wouldn't be that difficult to pull off a hoax on the American people if handled properly, and had the complicity of the media behind it. Not many people to identify with here, so it is emotionally detached, but such a dead-on portrayal of media and government complicity that it doesn't matter. "Good Old Shoe" is a prime example of what I mean. Also appreciated it's non-partisanship stance, since this scenario would apply to either side.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb on every front, the script, the acting and the directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ayal Oren
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very close to perfect ten, but I won't dwell on the reasons I've got this one rated 9.5 rather than 10. I simply want to point out the aspect that most people forget when referring to this movie. Everybody notices the wit of the script, everybody notices the superb acting of Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro. Well I want to point two less noticed aspects of this movie. Anne Heche, doing a perfect job as the perfect yes woman, the counterpoint of Hoffman and De Niro, the audience of their escapades, admiring them when they work their magic, getting angry at them when it all seems to fall apart - being the exact balance against which the two are to be compared. The other hardly ever noticed aspect of this movie is the brilliant work of Barry Levinson - it's not only the guiding of every actor and every actress, not only the perfect pacing of the plot - it's the amazing control he exerts over the look of the film. The lighting and color control of this film are of the highest class ever achieved in cinema, an aspect not commonly present in American cinema who pays much more attention to the story and often neglects its design. Have one more look at this film and pay attention to the way people are getting swallowed by the background shadows or of how they emerge from these shadows and then think of the fact that the entire film is about the shadow game of politics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie and wish more people would see it, would love to see it as a remake today !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    texaschamelion
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie with my Dad when it came out on VHS. Being a very political minded man he instilled family values as well as pride for our country. We loved this movie as he also taught us when we were kids "big brother is always watching" and told us we as citizens of this nation should not walk blindly through life, take nothing for granted especially to not accept the idea that the government and media wouldn't possibly lie to us,there are reasons we do not know everything.I laughed so much during this movie and told him he was correct. I thought this movie was very well done and would absolutely love to see a remake come out in the very near future given the state of our government today and how many "sheeple" are in existence who need to wake up and see things for what they really are. I wish i had just a dollar for every time in my life i have said "all i will say is wag the dog"!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Albania's hard to rhyme"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Hollywood produced and White House sanctioned war and the hilarious marketing of their political lies carry this "truer to life than we'd like to believe" comedy. Robert DeNiro & Dustin Hoffman are up to the task and leave plenty of room for the supporting folks. Gotta love the Willie Nelson music scenes and Dennis Leary's usual train of thought shtick. The Directors' mansion voting excuse banter is priceless for those who shutter at every liberal actor speech on democracy. Barry Levinson's eventual prophetic presidency sex scandal and the result is an underrated political comedy with great entertainment legs. There is no B-3 Bomber. I don't know how these rumors get started! Uh, we do!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Nothing..........Hardly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before elections, a spin-doctor and a Hollywood producer join efforts to "fabricate" a war in order to cover-up a presidential sex scandal. If you ask me, this is nothing....hardly. This movie is hardly nothing, it is an excellent movie, a great political satire! Wag The Dog is a hilarious political satire movie, and it ranks as one of the best movies of 1997, as well as one of the best movies that Robert De Niro has made since 1995. Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro are superb in this movie, with the former getting an Oscar nomination for Best Actor. The acting in the movie is great, and the writing is witty and clever too, and renowned director Barry Levinson's directing of this movie is superb too, so this movie is pretty superb all in all! I didn't like this movie just because it had Robert De Niro in it, I enjoyed it for many other reasons too, such as the plot, he acting from Dustin Hoffman and other cast members, Barry Levinson's directing, and numerous funny scenes in the movie, such as the commercial filming scene, and the scene where Willie Nelson is told to come up with a campaign song, and many other scenes too. Robert De Niro is one of the greatest actors who has ever lived, and he's one of my favorite actors, and not only that, but this movie is one of his best since Casino. Dustin Hoffman is a great actor too, and this movie in my opinion is one of the best movies that he has ever made, but that's not the end of it, this is one of the best movies that Barry Levinson has ever directed. All in all, the entire cast and crew did a fine job at working on this great movie! By the way, a repeated line in this movie is: "This is nothing!" This movie isn't nothing, it's definitely something, it's something great, funny, as well as witty and clever! Robert De Niro is a living sensation, he can play numerous roles, he can play both serious and comedy roles, and be great in them too, as this movie is certainly proof of that, as he is great in this movie, and at the same time, he is both funny and serious, which makes things even better. This is one of those movies that you should watch whenever you are trying to forget about your troubles on Election Day, as it's a perfect political satire which gives a look at how presidential campaigns actually are, they really are operated by people working for the candidates, who uses stories to make them look good or bad. So if you are looking for a great political satire film to watch, then watch Barry Levinson's Wag The Dog, as it is one of the best and most ingenious political satires of all time! I send my applauds and congratulations to Dustin Hoffman, Robert De Niro, Barry Levinson, and the rest of the cast and crew for all of their hard work on this movie, as this movie is something, it's not nothing, it's something, something wonderful! So get ready for a political satire movie that will deliver some laughs, that's Wag The Dog, a great movie brought to you by Barry Levinson, and starring Robert De Niro and Dustin Hoffman. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Clever Satire It Purports To Be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The President is up for reelection and he gets caught in a sex scandal with a young girl. What to do? After a lot of talk among his staff, they rope in Hollywood people to create a completely phony war in Albania to distract public attention, using artificial media. Sounds hokey? Well, yes. The movie refers to Reagan's military invasion of the island nation of Grenada shortly after a terrorist bomb killed hundreds of US troops stationed in Beirut, the claim being that Reagan was trying to distract the public from the troops being killed. Never mind that the Grenada invasion was real, and certainly did not distract the news media from the Beirut bombing. Also, even in the days when the Internet wasn't widely used, there's no way a completely fictional military action would not have been exposed shortly afterward. But the movie does allow for that. They then use a convicted dangerous felon to play a soldier left behind in the supposed war, which would distract the public anew. If you can believe that a completely fictional military action would be widely reported in the major news media and somebody not quickly reveal the hoax for what it is, this movie might be for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie had a lot of potential but failed to deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D Mac
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a lot of talent wasted in this movie. I must say that my wife and had a difficult time watching it all. After 45 minutes we were no longer engaged in the story. I was expecting satire but not silly slapstick. They could have done so much with this movie and this cast. A lot of time was spent drilling down on minute aspects of the "scheme" and I felt they were flogging a point endlessly. For example, the producer wanted a kitten in a scene and several minutes was spent on him complaining until he got the kitten he was looking for. The movie develops very slowly, almost painfully so. The conflict between the conspirators and the CIA was very artificial with a conclusion that made no sense. I am guessing the idea was to make all government agencies, as well as politicians, look foolish.The movie succeeded in doing so this but in the end, the whole story was pretty foolish and lacked anything that would maintain interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have laughed more if my TV was off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Warren
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woah, woah, woah.... I'm seeing the term "brilliant satire" being tossed around in these reviews far too much. (I think I saw a comparison to Dr. Strangelove! I hope Kubrick hunts you down and punches you in the face). This was one of the worst movies I've ever seen. As for plot, it is essentially the same thing as Canadian Bacon (2 years prior, imo infinitely times funnier and smarter than this). Which is not necessarily a bad thing if it weren't so haphazardly thrown together. The movie begins a bit in medias res, and awkwardly introduces you to the situation and this Albanian idea without a single laugh. Robert Di Nero (who I usually like) is clearly just playing a poorly developed caricature of himself; Dennis Hoffman (who I love) is occasionally good for a chuckle, but the whole "producer" persona and dialogue just gets old, boring, and unrelatable after the first scene; and then there's this 'who are you?' Anne Heche character who's only purpose in the story is to praise Di Nero's character for his brilliance (cause he's not actually brilliant! O trolololol that's hilarious....) Then these characters (who we could not care less about or relate to) go on a bunch of farcical adventures, which would usually be a dynamite recipe for comedy, but again, we just don't care about or even understand these characters and their motivations Overall this movie might not be the worst satire ever, but it certainly is an awful movie  proof that good actors and a good idea cannot make up for a hideous screen play.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's funny because it's true ... it's sad for the same reasons ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's fascinating how the September 11th attacks out-dated everything, making the first Gulf War as far in memories as the Vietnam one. People are less to blame than the media-centric system that knew how to deal with the public emotion, and the key thing is that emotion has a short-term memory. George W. Bush could get away with the second Gulf War on the basis of fallacious arguments just by exploiting the September 11 trauma, and any attempt to question his choices could immediately lead to anti-patriotic accusations. And this emotional exploitation is the basis of Barry Levinson's "Wag the Dog", a hilarious satire in the same vein of sharpness than such masterpieces as "Network" or "Dr. Strangelove", and as prophetic. In August 1998, Bill Clinton confessed of having had inappropriate conduct with Monica Lewinsky, a few days later, terrorist strongholds were bombed in Africa in response to the attack of the American Embassy in Tanzania. Replace "Monica Lewinsky" by a Firefly girl, "Africa" by Albania, "Clinton" by an unknown President, and you have the basic plot of "Wag the Dog", and by 'plot', I mean the story the way it is shown on TV to the American audience. Yet "Wag the Dog" is less about the plot than the plotters. "Wag the Dog" starts with a crisis, the President has been caught with an underage girl and his opponents prepared an accusing videotape clip using 'Thank Heaven for Little Girls' as musical background, 11 days before the election, if the President's men, lead by a woman, Winifred Ames (Anne Heche) don't come up with an idea and quick, the President is screwed, and his lame "We don't change horses in midstream" campaign won't help. They call Conrad Brean, a spin-doctor; played by Robert De Niro. He comes up with the most likely idea to distract the audience from a scandal: a war, the easiest catalysis of sentimentalism and emotions through sheer patriotism. As long as people would be thirsty for magnificent displays of solidarity and humanity, incarnated by these "We are the World"-like songs, it would be easy to manipulate them. So let's start with rumors about a B3-bomber, "There's no B3-bomber", "Great, even deny its existence". Barry Levinson's film hooks us to Brean's smartness so well that we even forget that the President would indeed deserve to lose these elections. It already starts to work on us. "If the tail was smarter than the dog it would wag the dog", the dog is the audience, give them what they want and they will bite it. It's all a matter of storytelling. As a screenwriter student, I was taught that what counts the most in a story is the idea: the premise, then comes the plot, and then the storytelling, all count but it all starts with the idea. The war was the idea, but then the rest of the plot comes up very fluidly. In Albania, why? Why not? Who knows about it anyway? Who knew about Afghanistan, Iraq or Vietnam anyway? What matters is that a country shows as a potential threat, to what? To the United States, to its lifestyle, its values  the plan can't fail, the whole storyline comes us so fluidly that the scandal is almost forgotten. But we live in a media-centric society, people need images, they can't rely their emotional involvements on rumors, on unseen stuff. Time for the second protagonist of the film to make his flamboyant entrance; it's Dustin Hoffman in an electrifying performance as Stanley Motts, the producer. He's as passionate, dedicated and enthusiastic about producing as Depp in "Ed Wood" except that he has talent, and this is why the team hires him. He constructs a war with archive footage, sound effects and a young actress to play an Albanian refugee (Kirsten Dunst). People need a gimmick, like the stray cat in Vito Corleone's hands: give her a kitten. Motts understands very well how the identification process works, it asks for symbols, for colors, for memorable stuff, like the raising of the flags in Iwo-Jima or the naked girl in Vietnam. "Wag the Dog" makes us laugh for the same reasons "Network" angered us. Yet, as funny and goofy as it is, the Oscar-nominated script (the second nomination along with Hoffman) never takes its original premise for granted and takes us to unexpected and realistic twists without losing this capacity to surprise. At one point, the CIA, bought by the other side, makes a surprising statement: there's no war anymore, and Brean suddenly abandons the whole plot because it's over, how so? He "saw it on TV", TV is the Alpha and Omega; the "Network" days are not over. This is where Motts surpasses his mentor, with his unforgettable catchphrase "This is nothing", the war won't be over until he says when it's over. The war was just a pivotal moment, but like every story, you need a second pivot: how about a hostage, a war hero, a man who was kept prisoner. Abandoned like an old-shoe, how about a folk song titled "Old Shoe", a soldier whose name starts with "Shoe", like William Schumann (Woody Harrelson), you would believe this is really nothing. The saddest thing about the film is that even after watching this, the tail still wags us as we allowed many pseudo wars to happen. So even if it isn't the first political film to highlight the connection between politics and media-manipulation, it's the most related to our time. It's also a remarkably insightful film about the creative process of storytelling and a job passion, Moss is too obsessed by his talent that he'll never accept the idea of not taking credit from it, while Brean is the straight man who takes everything so normally he reminded me of another expert from a same year's movie, Tommy Lee Jones in "Men in Black", except that Brean's underworld is much scarier.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a satire, and a scary one at that
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the president is involved in scandal shortly before the election, a Hollywood producer is brought in to manufacture a war in Albania to distract from the scandal and that the President can end. "Wag the Dog" has a great premise that was prescient; before the film was released, President Clinton was involved in the sex scandal with Monica Lewinsky, and he threatened military action in Iraq. The really frightening thing is that in one of the clips shown in the film, a young woman wearing Monica's beret can be seen. It reminded me a little of the situation when Alfred Hitchcock was filming "Notorious," and his Mcguffin was the uranium to make an atom bomb being hidden in wine bottles. It was entirely innocent on his part, but the FBI had him under surveillance for months wondering what he knew about the uranium stores in South America that actually existed.. Dustin Hoffman is Stanley Motss, the producer brought in by political adviser Conrad Bean (Robert DeNiro) to produce the war. Anne Heche plays a presidential aide, and the film also includes William H. Macy, Kirsten Dunst, Andrea Martin, Denis Leary, and Willie Nelson. The sad thing is that I suppose all this is possible, despite some obvious holes in the David Mamet-Hilary Henkin script. The media can certainly manipulate, and why wouldn't gullible people believe what they are being shown? Maybe it's based on the premise that the American people are fairly dumb, and if you don't agree with that, you probably won't like it. Nevertheless, "Wag the Dog" puts forth a provocative idea and gets you thinking, and it's great to see Hoffman and DeNiro as two clever albeit sleazy people who believe the end justifies the means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sly Political Satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The U.S, President has just been exposed in a sex scandal not long before the next election. Rather than resign or take responsibility, White House spin doctors(led by Robert De Nero & Anne Heche) instead contact a Hollywood producer(Dustin Hoffman, quite funny) to direct an elaborate hoaxed war with Albania, in hopes that the nation will rally behind their incumbent president, and forget/forgive the sex scandal. Things get complicated when a "war hero"(Woody Harrelson) turns out to be a psychopath, and later on when the director insists on putting it on his resume... Ingenious satire by director Barry Levinson is extremely clever & knowing, since it wouldn't be that difficult to pull off a hoax on the American people if handled properly, and had the complicity of the media behind it. Not many people to identify with here, so it is emotionally detached, but such a dead-on portrayal of media and government complicity that it doesn't matter. "Good Old Shoe" is a prime example of what I mean. Also appreciated it's non-partisanship stance, since this scenario would apply to either side.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb on every front, the script, the acting and the directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ayal Oren
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very close to perfect ten, but I won't dwell on the reasons I've got this one rated 9.5 rather than 10. I simply want to point out the aspect that most people forget when referring to this movie. Everybody notices the wit of the script, everybody notices the superb acting of Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro. Well I want to point two less noticed aspects of this movie. Anne Heche, doing a perfect job as the perfect yes woman, the counterpoint of Hoffman and De Niro, the audience of their escapades, admiring them when they work their magic, getting angry at them when it all seems to fall apart - being the exact balance against which the two are to be compared. The other hardly ever noticed aspect of this movie is the brilliant work of Barry Levinson - it's not only the guiding of every actor and every actress, not only the perfect pacing of the plot - it's the amazing control he exerts over the look of the film. The lighting and color control of this film are of the highest class ever achieved in cinema, an aspect not commonly present in American cinema who pays much more attention to the story and often neglects its design. Have one more look at this film and pay attention to the way people are getting swallowed by the background shadows or of how they emerge from these shadows and then think of the fact that the entire film is about the shadow game of politics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie and wish more people would see it, would love to see it as a remake today !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    texaschamelion
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie with my Dad when it came out on VHS. Being a very political minded man he instilled family values as well as pride for our country. We loved this movie as he also taught us when we were kids "big brother is always watching" and told us we as citizens of this nation should not walk blindly through life, take nothing for granted especially to not accept the idea that the government and media wouldn't possibly lie to us,there are reasons we do not know everything.I laughed so much during this movie and told him he was correct. I thought this movie was very well done and would absolutely love to see a remake come out in the very near future given the state of our government today and how many "sheeple" are in existence who need to wake up and see things for what they really are. I wish i had just a dollar for every time in my life i have said "all i will say is wag the dog"!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Albania's hard to rhyme"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Hollywood produced and White House sanctioned war and the hilarious marketing of their political lies carry this "truer to life than we'd like to believe" comedy. Robert DeNiro & Dustin Hoffman are up to the task and leave plenty of room for the supporting folks. Gotta love the Willie Nelson music scenes and Dennis Leary's usual train of thought shtick. The Directors' mansion voting excuse banter is priceless for those who shutter at every liberal actor speech on democracy. Barry Levinson's eventual prophetic presidency sex scandal and the result is an underrated political comedy with great entertainment legs. There is no B-3 Bomber. I don't know how these rumors get started! Uh, we do!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Nothing..........Hardly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before elections, a spin-doctor and a Hollywood producer join efforts to "fabricate" a war in order to cover-up a presidential sex scandal. If you ask me, this is nothing....hardly. This movie is hardly nothing, it is an excellent movie, a great political satire! Wag The Dog is a hilarious political satire movie, and it ranks as one of the best movies of 1997, as well as one of the best movies that Robert De Niro has made since 1995. Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro are superb in this movie, with the former getting an Oscar nomination for Best Actor. The acting in the movie is great, and the writing is witty and clever too, and renowned director Barry Levinson's directing of this movie is superb too, so this movie is pretty superb all in all! I didn't like this movie just because it had Robert De Niro in it, I enjoyed it for many other reasons too, such as the plot, he acting from Dustin Hoffman and other cast members, Barry Levinson's directing, and numerous funny scenes in the movie, such as the commercial filming scene, and the scene where Willie Nelson is told to come up with a campaign song, and many other scenes too. Robert De Niro is one of the greatest actors who has ever lived, and he's one of my favorite actors, and not only that, but this movie is one of his best since Casino. Dustin Hoffman is a great actor too, and this movie in my opinion is one of the best movies that he has ever made, but that's not the end of it, this is one of the best movies that Barry Levinson has ever directed. All in all, the entire cast and crew did a fine job at working on this great movie! By the way, a repeated line in this movie is: "This is nothing!" This movie isn't nothing, it's definitely something, it's something great, funny, as well as witty and clever! Robert De Niro is a living sensation, he can play numerous roles, he can play both serious and comedy roles, and be great in them too, as this movie is certainly proof of that, as he is great in this movie, and at the same time, he is both funny and serious, which makes things even better. This is one of those movies that you should watch whenever you are trying to forget about your troubles on Election Day, as it's a perfect political satire which gives a look at how presidential campaigns actually are, they really are operated by people working for the candidates, who uses stories to make them look good or bad. So if you are looking for a great political satire film to watch, then watch Barry Levinson's Wag The Dog, as it is one of the best and most ingenious political satires of all time! I send my applauds and congratulations to Dustin Hoffman, Robert De Niro, Barry Levinson, and the rest of the cast and crew for all of their hard work on this movie, as this movie is something, it's not nothing, it's something, something wonderful! So get ready for a political satire movie that will deliver some laughs, that's Wag The Dog, a great movie brought to you by Barry Levinson, and starring Robert De Niro and Dustin Hoffman. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Clever Satire It Purports To Be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The President is up for reelection and he gets caught in a sex scandal with a young girl. What to do? After a lot of talk among his staff, they rope in Hollywood people to create a completely phony war in Albania to distract public attention, using artificial media. Sounds hokey? Well, yes. The movie refers to Reagan's military invasion of the island nation of Grenada shortly after a terrorist bomb killed hundreds of US troops stationed in Beirut, the claim being that Reagan was trying to distract the public from the troops being killed. Never mind that the Grenada invasion was real, and certainly did not distract the news media from the Beirut bombing. Also, even in the days when the Internet wasn't widely used, there's no way a completely fictional military action would not have been exposed shortly afterward. But the movie does allow for that. They then use a convicted dangerous felon to play a soldier left behind in the supposed war, which would distract the public anew. If you can believe that a completely fictional military action would be widely reported in the major news media and somebody not quickly reveal the hoax for what it is, this movie might be for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie had a lot of potential but failed to deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D Mac
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a lot of talent wasted in this movie. I must say that my wife and had a difficult time watching it all. After 45 minutes we were no longer engaged in the story. I was expecting satire but not silly slapstick. They could have done so much with this movie and this cast. A lot of time was spent drilling down on minute aspects of the "scheme" and I felt they were flogging a point endlessly. For example, the producer wanted a kitten in a scene and several minutes was spent on him complaining until he got the kitten he was looking for. The movie develops very slowly, almost painfully so. The conflict between the conspirators and the CIA was very artificial with a conclusion that made no sense. I am guessing the idea was to make all government agencies, as well as politicians, look foolish.The movie succeeded in doing so this but in the end, the whole story was pretty foolish and lacked anything that would maintain interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have laughed more if my TV was off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Warren
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woah, woah, woah.... I'm seeing the term "brilliant satire" being tossed around in these reviews far too much. (I think I saw a comparison to Dr. Strangelove! I hope Kubrick hunts you down and punches you in the face). This was one of the worst movies I've ever seen. As for plot, it is essentially the same thing as Canadian Bacon (2 years prior, imo infinitely times funnier and smarter than this). Which is not necessarily a bad thing if it weren't so haphazardly thrown together. The movie begins a bit in medias res, and awkwardly introduces you to the situation and this Albanian idea without a single laugh. Robert Di Nero (who I usually like) is clearly just playing a poorly developed caricature of himself; Dennis Hoffman (who I love) is occasionally good for a chuckle, but the whole "producer" persona and dialogue just gets old, boring, and unrelatable after the first scene; and then there's this 'who are you?' Anne Heche character who's only purpose in the story is to praise Di Nero's character for his brilliance (cause he's not actually brilliant! O trolololol that's hilarious....) Then these characters (who we could not care less about or relate to) go on a bunch of farcical adventures, which would usually be a dynamite recipe for comedy, but again, we just don't care about or even understand these characters and their motivations Overall this movie might not be the worst satire ever, but it certainly is an awful movie  proof that good actors and a good idea cannot make up for a hideous screen play.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's funny because it's true ... it's sad for the same reasons ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's fascinating how the September 11th attacks out-dated everything, making the first Gulf War as far in memories as the Vietnam one. People are less to blame than the media-centric system that knew how to deal with the public emotion, and the key thing is that emotion has a short-term memory. George W. Bush could get away with the second Gulf War on the basis of fallacious arguments just by exploiting the September 11 trauma, and any attempt to question his choices could immediately lead to anti-patriotic accusations. And this emotional exploitation is the basis of Barry Levinson's "Wag the Dog", a hilarious satire in the same vein of sharpness than such masterpieces as "Network" or "Dr. Strangelove", and as prophetic. In August 1998, Bill Clinton confessed of having had inappropriate conduct with Monica Lewinsky, a few days later, terrorist strongholds were bombed in Africa in response to the attack of the American Embassy in Tanzania. Replace "Monica Lewinsky" by a Firefly girl, "Africa" by Albania, "Clinton" by an unknown President, and you have the basic plot of "Wag the Dog", and by 'plot', I mean the story the way it is shown on TV to the American audience. Yet "Wag the Dog" is less about the plot than the plotters. "Wag the Dog" starts with a crisis, the President has been caught with an underage girl and his opponents prepared an accusing videotape clip using 'Thank Heaven for Little Girls' as musical background, 11 days before the election, if the President's men, lead by a woman, Winifred Ames (Anne Heche) don't come up with an idea and quick, the President is screwed, and his lame "We don't change horses in midstream" campaign won't help. They call Conrad Brean, a spin-doctor; played by Robert De Niro. He comes up with the most likely idea to distract the audience from a scandal: a war, the easiest catalysis of sentimentalism and emotions through sheer patriotism. As long as people would be thirsty for magnificent displays of solidarity and humanity, incarnated by these "We are the World"-like songs, it would be easy to manipulate them. So let's start with rumors about a B3-bomber, "There's no B3-bomber", "Great, even deny its existence". Barry Levinson's film hooks us to Brean's smartness so well that we even forget that the President would indeed deserve to lose these elections. It already starts to work on us. "If the tail was smarter than the dog it would wag the dog", the dog is the audience, give them what they want and they will bite it. It's all a matter of storytelling. As a screenwriter student, I was taught that what counts the most in a story is the idea: the premise, then comes the plot, and then the storytelling, all count but it all starts with the idea. The war was the idea, but then the rest of the plot comes up very fluidly. In Albania, why? Why not? Who knows about it anyway? Who knew about Afghanistan, Iraq or Vietnam anyway? What matters is that a country shows as a potential threat, to what? To the United States, to its lifestyle, its values  the plan can't fail, the whole storyline comes us so fluidly that the scandal is almost forgotten. But we live in a media-centric society, people need images, they can't rely their emotional involvements on rumors, on unseen stuff. Time for the second protagonist of the film to make his flamboyant entrance; it's Dustin Hoffman in an electrifying performance as Stanley Motts, the producer. He's as passionate, dedicated and enthusiastic about producing as Depp in "Ed Wood" except that he has talent, and this is why the team hires him. He constructs a war with archive footage, sound effects and a young actress to play an Albanian refugee (Kirsten Dunst). People need a gimmick, like the stray cat in Vito Corleone's hands: give her a kitten. Motts understands very well how the identification process works, it asks for symbols, for colors, for memorable stuff, like the raising of the flags in Iwo-Jima or the naked girl in Vietnam. "Wag the Dog" makes us laugh for the same reasons "Network" angered us. Yet, as funny and goofy as it is, the Oscar-nominated script (the second nomination along with Hoffman) never takes its original premise for granted and takes us to unexpected and realistic twists without losing this capacity to surprise. At one point, the CIA, bought by the other side, makes a surprising statement: there's no war anymore, and Brean suddenly abandons the whole plot because it's over, how so? He "saw it on TV", TV is the Alpha and Omega; the "Network" days are not over. This is where Motts surpasses his mentor, with his unforgettable catchphrase "This is nothing", the war won't be over until he says when it's over. The war was just a pivotal moment, but like every story, you need a second pivot: how about a hostage, a war hero, a man who was kept prisoner. Abandoned like an old-shoe, how about a folk song titled "Old Shoe", a soldier whose name starts with "Shoe", like William Schumann (Woody Harrelson), you would believe this is really nothing. The saddest thing about the film is that even after watching this, the tail still wags us as we allowed many pseudo wars to happen. So even if it isn't the first political film to highlight the connection between politics and media-manipulation, it's the most related to our time. It's also a remarkably insightful film about the creative process of storytelling and a job passion, Moss is too obsessed by his talent that he'll never accept the idea of not taking credit from it, while Brean is the straight man who takes everything so normally he reminded me of another expert from a same year's movie, Tommy Lee Jones in "Men in Black", except that Brean's underworld is much scarier.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a satire, and a scary one at that
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the president is involved in scandal shortly before the election, a Hollywood producer is brought in to manufacture a war in Albania to distract from the scandal and that the President can end. "Wag the Dog" has a great premise that was prescient; before the film was released, President Clinton was involved in the sex scandal with Monica Lewinsky, and he threatened military action in Iraq. The really frightening thing is that in one of the clips shown in the film, a young woman wearing Monica's beret can be seen. It reminded me a little of the situation when Alfred Hitchcock was filming "Notorious," and his Mcguffin was the uranium to make an atom bomb being hidden in wine bottles. It was entirely innocent on his part, but the FBI had him under surveillance for months wondering what he knew about the uranium stores in South America that actually existed.. Dustin Hoffman is Stanley Motss, the producer brought in by political adviser Conrad Bean (Robert DeNiro) to produce the war. Anne Heche plays a presidential aide, and the film also includes William H. Macy, Kirsten Dunst, Andrea Martin, Denis Leary, and Willie Nelson. The sad thing is that I suppose all this is possible, despite some obvious holes in the David Mamet-Hilary Henkin script. The media can certainly manipulate, and why wouldn't gullible people believe what they are being shown? Maybe it's based on the premise that the American people are fairly dumb, and if you don't agree with that, you probably won't like it. Nevertheless, "Wag the Dog" puts forth a provocative idea and gets you thinking, and it's great to see Hoffman and DeNiro as two clever albeit sleazy people who believe the end justifies the means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sly Political Satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The U.S, President has just been exposed in a sex scandal not long before the next election. Rather than resign or take responsibility, White House spin doctors(led by Robert De Nero & Anne Heche) instead contact a Hollywood producer(Dustin Hoffman, quite funny) to direct an elaborate hoaxed war with Albania, in hopes that the nation will rally behind their incumbent president, and forget/forgive the sex scandal. Things get complicated when a "war hero"(Woody Harrelson) turns out to be a psychopath, and later on when the director insists on putting it on his resume... Ingenious satire by director Barry Levinson is extremely clever & knowing, since it wouldn't be that difficult to pull off a hoax on the American people if handled properly, and had the complicity of the media behind it. Not many people to identify with here, so it is emotionally detached, but such a dead-on portrayal of media and government complicity that it doesn't matter. "Good Old Shoe" is a prime example of what I mean. Also appreciated it's non-partisanship stance, since this scenario would apply to either side.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb on every front, the script, the acting and the directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ayal Oren
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very close to perfect ten, but I won't dwell on the reasons I've got this one rated 9.5 rather than 10. I simply want to point out the aspect that most people forget when referring to this movie. Everybody notices the wit of the script, everybody notices the superb acting of Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro. Well I want to point two less noticed aspects of this movie. Anne Heche, doing a perfect job as the perfect yes woman, the counterpoint of Hoffman and De Niro, the audience of their escapades, admiring them when they work their magic, getting angry at them when it all seems to fall apart - being the exact balance against which the two are to be compared. The other hardly ever noticed aspect of this movie is the brilliant work of Barry Levinson - it's not only the guiding of every actor and every actress, not only the perfect pacing of the plot - it's the amazing control he exerts over the look of the film. The lighting and color control of this film are of the highest class ever achieved in cinema, an aspect not commonly present in American cinema who pays much more attention to the story and often neglects its design. Have one more look at this film and pay attention to the way people are getting swallowed by the background shadows or of how they emerge from these shadows and then think of the fact that the entire film is about the shadow game of politics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie and wish more people would see it, would love to see it as a remake today !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    texaschamelion
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie with my Dad when it came out on VHS. Being a very political minded man he instilled family values as well as pride for our country. We loved this movie as he also taught us when we were kids "big brother is always watching" and told us we as citizens of this nation should not walk blindly through life, take nothing for granted especially to not accept the idea that the government and media wouldn't possibly lie to us,there are reasons we do not know everything.I laughed so much during this movie and told him he was correct. I thought this movie was very well done and would absolutely love to see a remake come out in the very near future given the state of our government today and how many "sheeple" are in existence who need to wake up and see things for what they really are. I wish i had just a dollar for every time in my life i have said "all i will say is wag the dog"!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Albania's hard to rhyme"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Hollywood produced and White House sanctioned war and the hilarious marketing of their political lies carry this "truer to life than we'd like to believe" comedy. Robert DeNiro & Dustin Hoffman are up to the task and leave plenty of room for the supporting folks. Gotta love the Willie Nelson music scenes and Dennis Leary's usual train of thought shtick. The Directors' mansion voting excuse banter is priceless for those who shutter at every liberal actor speech on democracy. Barry Levinson's eventual prophetic presidency sex scandal and the result is an underrated political comedy with great entertainment legs. There is no B-3 Bomber. I don't know how these rumors get started! Uh, we do!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Nothing..........Hardly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before elections, a spin-doctor and a Hollywood producer join efforts to "fabricate" a war in order to cover-up a presidential sex scandal. If you ask me, this is nothing....hardly. This movie is hardly nothing, it is an excellent movie, a great political satire! Wag The Dog is a hilarious political satire movie, and it ranks as one of the best movies of 1997, as well as one of the best movies that Robert De Niro has made since 1995. Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro are superb in this movie, with the former getting an Oscar nomination for Best Actor. The acting in the movie is great, and the writing is witty and clever too, and renowned director Barry Levinson's directing of this movie is superb too, so this movie is pretty superb all in all! I didn't like this movie just because it had Robert De Niro in it, I enjoyed it for many other reasons too, such as the plot, he acting from Dustin Hoffman and other cast members, Barry Levinson's directing, and numerous funny scenes in the movie, such as the commercial filming scene, and the scene where Willie Nelson is told to come up with a campaign song, and many other scenes too. Robert De Niro is one of the greatest actors who has ever lived, and he's one of my favorite actors, and not only that, but this movie is one of his best since Casino. Dustin Hoffman is a great actor too, and this movie in my opinion is one of the best movies that he has ever made, but that's not the end of it, this is one of the best movies that Barry Levinson has ever directed. All in all, the entire cast and crew did a fine job at working on this great movie! By the way, a repeated line in this movie is: "This is nothing!" This movie isn't nothing, it's definitely something, it's something great, funny, as well as witty and clever! Robert De Niro is a living sensation, he can play numerous roles, he can play both serious and comedy roles, and be great in them too, as this movie is certainly proof of that, as he is great in this movie, and at the same time, he is both funny and serious, which makes things even better. This is one of those movies that you should watch whenever you are trying to forget about your troubles on Election Day, as it's a perfect political satire which gives a look at how presidential campaigns actually are, they really are operated by people working for the candidates, who uses stories to make them look good or bad. So if you are looking for a great political satire film to watch, then watch Barry Levinson's Wag The Dog, as it is one of the best and most ingenious political satires of all time! I send my applauds and congratulations to Dustin Hoffman, Robert De Niro, Barry Levinson, and the rest of the cast and crew for all of their hard work on this movie, as this movie is something, it's not nothing, it's something, something wonderful! So get ready for a political satire movie that will deliver some laughs, that's Wag The Dog, a great movie brought to you by Barry Levinson, and starring Robert De Niro and Dustin Hoffman. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Clever Satire It Purports To Be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The President is up for reelection and he gets caught in a sex scandal with a young girl. What to do? After a lot of talk among his staff, they rope in Hollywood people to create a completely phony war in Albania to distract public attention, using artificial media. Sounds hokey? Well, yes. The movie refers to Reagan's military invasion of the island nation of Grenada shortly after a terrorist bomb killed hundreds of US troops stationed in Beirut, the claim being that Reagan was trying to distract the public from the troops being killed. Never mind that the Grenada invasion was real, and certainly did not distract the news media from the Beirut bombing. Also, even in the days when the Internet wasn't widely used, there's no way a completely fictional military action would not have been exposed shortly afterward. But the movie does allow for that. They then use a convicted dangerous felon to play a soldier left behind in the supposed war, which would distract the public anew. If you can believe that a completely fictional military action would be widely reported in the major news media and somebody not quickly reveal the hoax for what it is, this movie might be for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie had a lot of potential but failed to deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D Mac
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a lot of talent wasted in this movie. I must say that my wife and had a difficult time watching it all. After 45 minutes we were no longer engaged in the story. I was expecting satire but not silly slapstick. They could have done so much with this movie and this cast. A lot of time was spent drilling down on minute aspects of the "scheme" and I felt they were flogging a point endlessly. For example, the producer wanted a kitten in a scene and several minutes was spent on him complaining until he got the kitten he was looking for. The movie develops very slowly, almost painfully so. The conflict between the conspirators and the CIA was very artificial with a conclusion that made no sense. I am guessing the idea was to make all government agencies, as well as politicians, look foolish.The movie succeeded in doing so this but in the end, the whole story was pretty foolish and lacked anything that would maintain interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have laughed more if my TV was off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Warren
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woah, woah, woah.... I'm seeing the term "brilliant satire" being tossed around in these reviews far too much. (I think I saw a comparison to Dr. Strangelove! I hope Kubrick hunts you down and punches you in the face). This was one of the worst movies I've ever seen. As for plot, it is essentially the same thing as Canadian Bacon (2 years prior, imo infinitely times funnier and smarter than this). Which is not necessarily a bad thing if it weren't so haphazardly thrown together. The movie begins a bit in medias res, and awkwardly introduces you to the situation and this Albanian idea without a single laugh. Robert Di Nero (who I usually like) is clearly just playing a poorly developed caricature of himself; Dennis Hoffman (who I love) is occasionally good for a chuckle, but the whole "producer" persona and dialogue just gets old, boring, and unrelatable after the first scene; and then there's this 'who are you?' Anne Heche character who's only purpose in the story is to praise Di Nero's character for his brilliance (cause he's not actually brilliant! O trolololol that's hilarious....) Then these characters (who we could not care less about or relate to) go on a bunch of farcical adventures, which would usually be a dynamite recipe for comedy, but again, we just don't care about or even understand these characters and their motivations Overall this movie might not be the worst satire ever, but it certainly is an awful movie  proof that good actors and a good idea cannot make up for a hideous screen play.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's funny because it's true ... it's sad for the same reasons ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's fascinating how the September 11th attacks out-dated everything, making the first Gulf War as far in memories as the Vietnam one. People are less to blame than the media-centric system that knew how to deal with the public emotion, and the key thing is that emotion has a short-term memory. George W. Bush could get away with the second Gulf War on the basis of fallacious arguments just by exploiting the September 11 trauma, and any attempt to question his choices could immediately lead to anti-patriotic accusations. And this emotional exploitation is the basis of Barry Levinson's "Wag the Dog", a hilarious satire in the same vein of sharpness than such masterpieces as "Network" or "Dr. Strangelove", and as prophetic. In August 1998, Bill Clinton confessed of having had inappropriate conduct with Monica Lewinsky, a few days later, terrorist strongholds were bombed in Africa in response to the attack of the American Embassy in Tanzania. Replace "Monica Lewinsky" by a Firefly girl, "Africa" by Albania, "Clinton" by an unknown President, and you have the basic plot of "Wag the Dog", and by 'plot', I mean the story the way it is shown on TV to the American audience. Yet "Wag the Dog" is less about the plot than the plotters. "Wag the Dog" starts with a crisis, the President has been caught with an underage girl and his opponents prepared an accusing videotape clip using 'Thank Heaven for Little Girls' as musical background, 11 days before the election, if the President's men, lead by a woman, Winifred Ames (Anne Heche) don't come up with an idea and quick, the President is screwed, and his lame "We don't change horses in midstream" campaign won't help. They call Conrad Brean, a spin-doctor; played by Robert De Niro. He comes up with the most likely idea to distract the audience from a scandal: a war, the easiest catalysis of sentimentalism and emotions through sheer patriotism. As long as people would be thirsty for magnificent displays of solidarity and humanity, incarnated by these "We are the World"-like songs, it would be easy to manipulate them. So let's start with rumors about a B3-bomber, "There's no B3-bomber", "Great, even deny its existence". Barry Levinson's film hooks us to Brean's smartness so well that we even forget that the President would indeed deserve to lose these elections. It already starts to work on us. "If the tail was smarter than the dog it would wag the dog", the dog is the audience, give them what they want and they will bite it. It's all a matter of storytelling. As a screenwriter student, I was taught that what counts the most in a story is the idea: the premise, then comes the plot, and then the storytelling, all count but it all starts with the idea. The war was the idea, but then the rest of the plot comes up very fluidly. In Albania, why? Why not? Who knows about it anyway? Who knew about Afghanistan, Iraq or Vietnam anyway? What matters is that a country shows as a potential threat, to what? To the United States, to its lifestyle, its values  the plan can't fail, the whole storyline comes us so fluidly that the scandal is almost forgotten. But we live in a media-centric society, people need images, they can't rely their emotional involvements on rumors, on unseen stuff. Time for the second protagonist of the film to make his flamboyant entrance; it's Dustin Hoffman in an electrifying performance as Stanley Motts, the producer. He's as passionate, dedicated and enthusiastic about producing as Depp in "Ed Wood" except that he has talent, and this is why the team hires him. He constructs a war with archive footage, sound effects and a young actress to play an Albanian refugee (Kirsten Dunst). People need a gimmick, like the stray cat in Vito Corleone's hands: give her a kitten. Motts understands very well how the identification process works, it asks for symbols, for colors, for memorable stuff, like the raising of the flags in Iwo-Jima or the naked girl in Vietnam. "Wag the Dog" makes us laugh for the same reasons "Network" angered us. Yet, as funny and goofy as it is, the Oscar-nominated script (the second nomination along with Hoffman) never takes its original premise for granted and takes us to unexpected and realistic twists without losing this capacity to surprise. At one point, the CIA, bought by the other side, makes a surprising statement: there's no war anymore, and Brean suddenly abandons the whole plot because it's over, how so? He "saw it on TV", TV is the Alpha and Omega; the "Network" days are not over. This is where Motts surpasses his mentor, with his unforgettable catchphrase "This is nothing", the war won't be over until he says when it's over. The war was just a pivotal moment, but like every story, you need a second pivot: how about a hostage, a war hero, a man who was kept prisoner. Abandoned like an old-shoe, how about a folk song titled "Old Shoe", a soldier whose name starts with "Shoe", like William Schumann (Woody Harrelson), you would believe this is really nothing. The saddest thing about the film is that even after watching this, the tail still wags us as we allowed many pseudo wars to happen. So even if it isn't the first political film to highlight the connection between politics and media-manipulation, it's the most related to our time. It's also a remarkably insightful film about the creative process of storytelling and a job passion, Moss is too obsessed by his talent that he'll never accept the idea of not taking credit from it, while Brean is the straight man who takes everything so normally he reminded me of another expert from a same year's movie, Tommy Lee Jones in "Men in Black", except that Brean's underworld is much scarier.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a satire, and a scary one at that
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the president is involved in scandal shortly before the election, a Hollywood producer is brought in to manufacture a war in Albania to distract from the scandal and that the President can end. "Wag the Dog" has a great premise that was prescient; before the film was released, President Clinton was involved in the sex scandal with Monica Lewinsky, and he threatened military action in Iraq. The really frightening thing is that in one of the clips shown in the film, a young woman wearing Monica's beret can be seen. It reminded me a little of the situation when Alfred Hitchcock was filming "Notorious," and his Mcguffin was the uranium to make an atom bomb being hidden in wine bottles. It was entirely innocent on his part, but the FBI had him under surveillance for months wondering what he knew about the uranium stores in South America that actually existed.. Dustin Hoffman is Stanley Motss, the producer brought in by political adviser Conrad Bean (Robert DeNiro) to produce the war. Anne Heche plays a presidential aide, and the film also includes William H. Macy, Kirsten Dunst, Andrea Martin, Denis Leary, and Willie Nelson. The sad thing is that I suppose all this is possible, despite some obvious holes in the David Mamet-Hilary Henkin script. The media can certainly manipulate, and why wouldn't gullible people believe what they are being shown? Maybe it's based on the premise that the American people are fairly dumb, and if you don't agree with that, you probably won't like it. Nevertheless, "Wag the Dog" puts forth a provocative idea and gets you thinking, and it's great to see Hoffman and DeNiro as two clever albeit sleazy people who believe the end justifies the means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sly Political Satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The U.S, President has just been exposed in a sex scandal not long before the next election. Rather than resign or take responsibility, White House spin doctors(led by Robert De Nero & Anne Heche) instead contact a Hollywood producer(Dustin Hoffman, quite funny) to direct an elaborate hoaxed war with Albania, in hopes that the nation will rally behind their incumbent president, and forget/forgive the sex scandal. Things get complicated when a "war hero"(Woody Harrelson) turns out to be a psychopath, and later on when the director insists on putting it on his resume... Ingenious satire by director Barry Levinson is extremely clever & knowing, since it wouldn't be that difficult to pull off a hoax on the American people if handled properly, and had the complicity of the media behind it. Not many people to identify with here, so it is emotionally detached, but such a dead-on portrayal of media and government complicity that it doesn't matter. "Good Old Shoe" is a prime example of what I mean. Also appreciated it's non-partisanship stance, since this scenario would apply to either side.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb on every front, the script, the acting and the directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ayal Oren
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very close to perfect ten, but I won't dwell on the reasons I've got this one rated 9.5 rather than 10. I simply want to point out the aspect that most people forget when referring to this movie. Everybody notices the wit of the script, everybody notices the superb acting of Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro. Well I want to point two less noticed aspects of this movie. Anne Heche, doing a perfect job as the perfect yes woman, the counterpoint of Hoffman and De Niro, the audience of their escapades, admiring them when they work their magic, getting angry at them when it all seems to fall apart - being the exact balance against which the two are to be compared. The other hardly ever noticed aspect of this movie is the brilliant work of Barry Levinson - it's not only the guiding of every actor and every actress, not only the perfect pacing of the plot - it's the amazing control he exerts over the look of the film. The lighting and color control of this film are of the highest class ever achieved in cinema, an aspect not commonly present in American cinema who pays much more attention to the story and often neglects its design. Have one more look at this film and pay attention to the way people are getting swallowed by the background shadows or of how they emerge from these shadows and then think of the fact that the entire film is about the shadow game of politics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie and wish more people would see it, would love to see it as a remake today !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    texaschamelion
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie with my Dad when it came out on VHS. Being a very political minded man he instilled family values as well as pride for our country. We loved this movie as he also taught us when we were kids "big brother is always watching" and told us we as citizens of this nation should not walk blindly through life, take nothing for granted especially to not accept the idea that the government and media wouldn't possibly lie to us,there are reasons we do not know everything.I laughed so much during this movie and told him he was correct. I thought this movie was very well done and would absolutely love to see a remake come out in the very near future given the state of our government today and how many "sheeple" are in existence who need to wake up and see things for what they really are. I wish i had just a dollar for every time in my life i have said "all i will say is wag the dog"!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Albania's hard to rhyme"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Hollywood produced and White House sanctioned war and the hilarious marketing of their political lies carry this "truer to life than we'd like to believe" comedy. Robert DeNiro & Dustin Hoffman are up to the task and leave plenty of room for the supporting folks. Gotta love the Willie Nelson music scenes and Dennis Leary's usual train of thought shtick. The Directors' mansion voting excuse banter is priceless for those who shutter at every liberal actor speech on democracy. Barry Levinson's eventual prophetic presidency sex scandal and the result is an underrated political comedy with great entertainment legs. There is no B-3 Bomber. I don't know how these rumors get started! Uh, we do!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Nothing..........Hardly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before elections, a spin-doctor and a Hollywood producer join efforts to "fabricate" a war in order to cover-up a presidential sex scandal. If you ask me, this is nothing....hardly. This movie is hardly nothing, it is an excellent movie, a great political satire! Wag The Dog is a hilarious political satire movie, and it ranks as one of the best movies of 1997, as well as one of the best movies that Robert De Niro has made since 1995. Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro are superb in this movie, with the former getting an Oscar nomination for Best Actor. The acting in the movie is great, and the writing is witty and clever too, and renowned director Barry Levinson's directing of this movie is superb too, so this movie is pretty superb all in all! I didn't like this movie just because it had Robert De Niro in it, I enjoyed it for many other reasons too, such as the plot, he acting from Dustin Hoffman and other cast members, Barry Levinson's directing, and numerous funny scenes in the movie, such as the commercial filming scene, and the scene where Willie Nelson is told to come up with a campaign song, and many other scenes too. Robert De Niro is one of the greatest actors who has ever lived, and he's one of my favorite actors, and not only that, but this movie is one of his best since Casino. Dustin Hoffman is a great actor too, and this movie in my opinion is one of the best movies that he has ever made, but that's not the end of it, this is one of the best movies that Barry Levinson has ever directed. All in all, the entire cast and crew did a fine job at working on this great movie! By the way, a repeated line in this movie is: "This is nothing!" This movie isn't nothing, it's definitely something, it's something great, funny, as well as witty and clever! Robert De Niro is a living sensation, he can play numerous roles, he can play both serious and comedy roles, and be great in them too, as this movie is certainly proof of that, as he is great in this movie, and at the same time, he is both funny and serious, which makes things even better. This is one of those movies that you should watch whenever you are trying to forget about your troubles on Election Day, as it's a perfect political satire which gives a look at how presidential campaigns actually are, they really are operated by people working for the candidates, who uses stories to make them look good or bad. So if you are looking for a great political satire film to watch, then watch Barry Levinson's Wag The Dog, as it is one of the best and most ingenious political satires of all time! I send my applauds and congratulations to Dustin Hoffman, Robert De Niro, Barry Levinson, and the rest of the cast and crew for all of their hard work on this movie, as this movie is something, it's not nothing, it's something, something wonderful! So get ready for a political satire movie that will deliver some laughs, that's Wag The Dog, a great movie brought to you by Barry Levinson, and starring Robert De Niro and Dustin Hoffman. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Clever Satire It Purports To Be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The President is up for reelection and he gets caught in a sex scandal with a young girl. What to do? After a lot of talk among his staff, they rope in Hollywood people to create a completely phony war in Albania to distract public attention, using artificial media. Sounds hokey? Well, yes. The movie refers to Reagan's military invasion of the island nation of Grenada shortly after a terrorist bomb killed hundreds of US troops stationed in Beirut, the claim being that Reagan was trying to distract the public from the troops being killed. Never mind that the Grenada invasion was real, and certainly did not distract the news media from the Beirut bombing. Also, even in the days when the Internet wasn't widely used, there's no way a completely fictional military action would not have been exposed shortly afterward. But the movie does allow for that. They then use a convicted dangerous felon to play a soldier left behind in the supposed war, which would distract the public anew. If you can believe that a completely fictional military action would be widely reported in the major news media and somebody not quickly reveal the hoax for what it is, this movie might be for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie had a lot of potential but failed to deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D Mac
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a lot of talent wasted in this movie. I must say that my wife and had a difficult time watching it all. After 45 minutes we were no longer engaged in the story. I was expecting satire but not silly slapstick. They could have done so much with this movie and this cast. A lot of time was spent drilling down on minute aspects of the "scheme" and I felt they were flogging a point endlessly. For example, the producer wanted a kitten in a scene and several minutes was spent on him complaining until he got the kitten he was looking for. The movie develops very slowly, almost painfully so. The conflict between the conspirators and the CIA was very artificial with a conclusion that made no sense. I am guessing the idea was to make all government agencies, as well as politicians, look foolish.The movie succeeded in doing so this but in the end, the whole story was pretty foolish and lacked anything that would maintain interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have laughed more if my TV was off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Warren
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woah, woah, woah.... I'm seeing the term "brilliant satire" being tossed around in these reviews far too much. (I think I saw a comparison to Dr. Strangelove! I hope Kubrick hunts you down and punches you in the face). This was one of the worst movies I've ever seen. As for plot, it is essentially the same thing as Canadian Bacon (2 years prior, imo infinitely times funnier and smarter than this). Which is not necessarily a bad thing if it weren't so haphazardly thrown together. The movie begins a bit in medias res, and awkwardly introduces you to the situation and this Albanian idea without a single laugh. Robert Di Nero (who I usually like) is clearly just playing a poorly developed caricature of himself; Dennis Hoffman (who I love) is occasionally good for a chuckle, but the whole "producer" persona and dialogue just gets old, boring, and unrelatable after the first scene; and then there's this 'who are you?' Anne Heche character who's only purpose in the story is to praise Di Nero's character for his brilliance (cause he's not actually brilliant! O trolololol that's hilarious....) Then these characters (who we could not care less about or relate to) go on a bunch of farcical adventures, which would usually be a dynamite recipe for comedy, but again, we just don't care about or even understand these characters and their motivations Overall this movie might not be the worst satire ever, but it certainly is an awful movie  proof that good actors and a good idea cannot make up for a hideous screen play.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's funny because it's true ... it's sad for the same reasons ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's fascinating how the September 11th attacks out-dated everything, making the first Gulf War as far in memories as the Vietnam one. People are less to blame than the media-centric system that knew how to deal with the public emotion, and the key thing is that emotion has a short-term memory. George W. Bush could get away with the second Gulf War on the basis of fallacious arguments just by exploiting the September 11 trauma, and any attempt to question his choices could immediately lead to anti-patriotic accusations. And this emotional exploitation is the basis of Barry Levinson's "Wag the Dog", a hilarious satire in the same vein of sharpness than such masterpieces as "Network" or "Dr. Strangelove", and as prophetic. In August 1998, Bill Clinton confessed of having had inappropriate conduct with Monica Lewinsky, a few days later, terrorist strongholds were bombed in Africa in response to the attack of the American Embassy in Tanzania. Replace "Monica Lewinsky" by a Firefly girl, "Africa" by Albania, "Clinton" by an unknown President, and you have the basic plot of "Wag the Dog", and by 'plot', I mean the story the way it is shown on TV to the American audience. Yet "Wag the Dog" is less about the plot than the plotters. "Wag the Dog" starts with a crisis, the President has been caught with an underage girl and his opponents prepared an accusing videotape clip using 'Thank Heaven for Little Girls' as musical background, 11 days before the election, if the President's men, lead by a woman, Winifred Ames (Anne Heche) don't come up with an idea and quick, the President is screwed, and his lame "We don't change horses in midstream" campaign won't help. They call Conrad Brean, a spin-doctor; played by Robert De Niro. He comes up with the most likely idea to distract the audience from a scandal: a war, the easiest catalysis of sentimentalism and emotions through sheer patriotism. As long as people would be thirsty for magnificent displays of solidarity and humanity, incarnated by these "We are the World"-like songs, it would be easy to manipulate them. So let's start with rumors about a B3-bomber, "There's no B3-bomber", "Great, even deny its existence". Barry Levinson's film hooks us to Brean's smartness so well that we even forget that the President would indeed deserve to lose these elections. It already starts to work on us. "If the tail was smarter than the dog it would wag the dog", the dog is the audience, give them what they want and they will bite it. It's all a matter of storytelling. As a screenwriter student, I was taught that what counts the most in a story is the idea: the premise, then comes the plot, and then the storytelling, all count but it all starts with the idea. The war was the idea, but then the rest of the plot comes up very fluidly. In Albania, why? Why not? Who knows about it anyway? Who knew about Afghanistan, Iraq or Vietnam anyway? What matters is that a country shows as a potential threat, to what? To the United States, to its lifestyle, its values  the plan can't fail, the whole storyline comes us so fluidly that the scandal is almost forgotten. But we live in a media-centric society, people need images, they can't rely their emotional involvements on rumors, on unseen stuff. Time for the second protagonist of the film to make his flamboyant entrance; it's Dustin Hoffman in an electrifying performance as Stanley Motts, the producer. He's as passionate, dedicated and enthusiastic about producing as Depp in "Ed Wood" except that he has talent, and this is why the team hires him. He constructs a war with archive footage, sound effects and a young actress to play an Albanian refugee (Kirsten Dunst). People need a gimmick, like the stray cat in Vito Corleone's hands: give her a kitten. Motts understands very well how the identification process works, it asks for symbols, for colors, for memorable stuff, like the raising of the flags in Iwo-Jima or the naked girl in Vietnam. "Wag the Dog" makes us laugh for the same reasons "Network" angered us. Yet, as funny and goofy as it is, the Oscar-nominated script (the second nomination along with Hoffman) never takes its original premise for granted and takes us to unexpected and realistic twists without losing this capacity to surprise. At one point, the CIA, bought by the other side, makes a surprising statement: there's no war anymore, and Brean suddenly abandons the whole plot because it's over, how so? He "saw it on TV", TV is the Alpha and Omega; the "Network" days are not over. This is where Motts surpasses his mentor, with his unforgettable catchphrase "This is nothing", the war won't be over until he says when it's over. The war was just a pivotal moment, but like every story, you need a second pivot: how about a hostage, a war hero, a man who was kept prisoner. Abandoned like an old-shoe, how about a folk song titled "Old Shoe", a soldier whose name starts with "Shoe", like William Schumann (Woody Harrelson), you would believe this is really nothing. The saddest thing about the film is that even after watching this, the tail still wags us as we allowed many pseudo wars to happen. So even if it isn't the first political film to highlight the connection between politics and media-manipulation, it's the most related to our time. It's also a remarkably insightful film about the creative process of storytelling and a job passion, Moss is too obsessed by his talent that he'll never accept the idea of not taking credit from it, while Brean is the straight man who takes everything so normally he reminded me of another expert from a same year's movie, Tommy Lee Jones in "Men in Black", except that Brean's underworld is much scarier.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a satire, and a scary one at that
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the president is involved in scandal shortly before the election, a Hollywood producer is brought in to manufacture a war in Albania to distract from the scandal and that the President can end. "Wag the Dog" has a great premise that was prescient; before the film was released, President Clinton was involved in the sex scandal with Monica Lewinsky, and he threatened military action in Iraq. The really frightening thing is that in one of the clips shown in the film, a young woman wearing Monica's beret can be seen. It reminded me a little of the situation when Alfred Hitchcock was filming "Notorious," and his Mcguffin was the uranium to make an atom bomb being hidden in wine bottles. It was entirely innocent on his part, but the FBI had him under surveillance for months wondering what he knew about the uranium stores in South America that actually existed.. Dustin Hoffman is Stanley Motss, the producer brought in by political adviser Conrad Bean (Robert DeNiro) to produce the war. Anne Heche plays a presidential aide, and the film also includes William H. Macy, Kirsten Dunst, Andrea Martin, Denis Leary, and Willie Nelson. The sad thing is that I suppose all this is possible, despite some obvious holes in the David Mamet-Hilary Henkin script. The media can certainly manipulate, and why wouldn't gullible people believe what they are being shown? Maybe it's based on the premise that the American people are fairly dumb, and if you don't agree with that, you probably won't like it. Nevertheless, "Wag the Dog" puts forth a provocative idea and gets you thinking, and it's great to see Hoffman and DeNiro as two clever albeit sleazy people who believe the end justifies the means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sly Political Satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The U.S, President has just been exposed in a sex scandal not long before the next election. Rather than resign or take responsibility, White House spin doctors(led by Robert De Nero & Anne Heche) instead contact a Hollywood producer(Dustin Hoffman, quite funny) to direct an elaborate hoaxed war with Albania, in hopes that the nation will rally behind their incumbent president, and forget/forgive the sex scandal. Things get complicated when a "war hero"(Woody Harrelson) turns out to be a psychopath, and later on when the director insists on putting it on his resume... Ingenious satire by director Barry Levinson is extremely clever & knowing, since it wouldn't be that difficult to pull off a hoax on the American people if handled properly, and had the complicity of the media behind it. Not many people to identify with here, so it is emotionally detached, but such a dead-on portrayal of media and government complicity that it doesn't matter. "Good Old Shoe" is a prime example of what I mean. Also appreciated it's non-partisanship stance, since this scenario would apply to either side.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb on every front, the script, the acting and the directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ayal Oren
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very close to perfect ten, but I won't dwell on the reasons I've got this one rated 9.5 rather than 10. I simply want to point out the aspect that most people forget when referring to this movie. Everybody notices the wit of the script, everybody notices the superb acting of Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro. Well I want to point two less noticed aspects of this movie. Anne Heche, doing a perfect job as the perfect yes woman, the counterpoint of Hoffman and De Niro, the audience of their escapades, admiring them when they work their magic, getting angry at them when it all seems to fall apart - being the exact balance against which the two are to be compared. The other hardly ever noticed aspect of this movie is the brilliant work of Barry Levinson - it's not only the guiding of every actor and every actress, not only the perfect pacing of the plot - it's the amazing control he exerts over the look of the film. The lighting and color control of this film are of the highest class ever achieved in cinema, an aspect not commonly present in American cinema who pays much more attention to the story and often neglects its design. Have one more look at this film and pay attention to the way people are getting swallowed by the background shadows or of how they emerge from these shadows and then think of the fact that the entire film is about the shadow game of politics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie and wish more people would see it, would love to see it as a remake today !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    texaschamelion
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie with my Dad when it came out on VHS. Being a very political minded man he instilled family values as well as pride for our country. We loved this movie as he also taught us when we were kids "big brother is always watching" and told us we as citizens of this nation should not walk blindly through life, take nothing for granted especially to not accept the idea that the government and media wouldn't possibly lie to us,there are reasons we do not know everything.I laughed so much during this movie and told him he was correct. I thought this movie was very well done and would absolutely love to see a remake come out in the very near future given the state of our government today and how many "sheeple" are in existence who need to wake up and see things for what they really are. I wish i had just a dollar for every time in my life i have said "all i will say is wag the dog"!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Albania's hard to rhyme"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Hollywood produced and White House sanctioned war and the hilarious marketing of their political lies carry this "truer to life than we'd like to believe" comedy. Robert DeNiro & Dustin Hoffman are up to the task and leave plenty of room for the supporting folks. Gotta love the Willie Nelson music scenes and Dennis Leary's usual train of thought shtick. The Directors' mansion voting excuse banter is priceless for those who shutter at every liberal actor speech on democracy. Barry Levinson's eventual prophetic presidency sex scandal and the result is an underrated political comedy with great entertainment legs. There is no B-3 Bomber. I don't know how these rumors get started! Uh, we do!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Nothing..........Hardly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before elections, a spin-doctor and a Hollywood producer join efforts to "fabricate" a war in order to cover-up a presidential sex scandal. If you ask me, this is nothing....hardly. This movie is hardly nothing, it is an excellent movie, a great political satire! Wag The Dog is a hilarious political satire movie, and it ranks as one of the best movies of 1997, as well as one of the best movies that Robert De Niro has made since 1995. Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro are superb in this movie, with the former getting an Oscar nomination for Best Actor. The acting in the movie is great, and the writing is witty and clever too, and renowned director Barry Levinson's directing of this movie is superb too, so this movie is pretty superb all in all! I didn't like this movie just because it had Robert De Niro in it, I enjoyed it for many other reasons too, such as the plot, he acting from Dustin Hoffman and other cast members, Barry Levinson's directing, and numerous funny scenes in the movie, such as the commercial filming scene, and the scene where Willie Nelson is told to come up with a campaign song, and many other scenes too. Robert De Niro is one of the greatest actors who has ever lived, and he's one of my favorite actors, and not only that, but this movie is one of his best since Casino. Dustin Hoffman is a great actor too, and this movie in my opinion is one of the best movies that he has ever made, but that's not the end of it, this is one of the best movies that Barry Levinson has ever directed. All in all, the entire cast and crew did a fine job at working on this great movie! By the way, a repeated line in this movie is: "This is nothing!" This movie isn't nothing, it's definitely something, it's something great, funny, as well as witty and clever! Robert De Niro is a living sensation, he can play numerous roles, he can play both serious and comedy roles, and be great in them too, as this movie is certainly proof of that, as he is great in this movie, and at the same time, he is both funny and serious, which makes things even better. This is one of those movies that you should watch whenever you are trying to forget about your troubles on Election Day, as it's a perfect political satire which gives a look at how presidential campaigns actually are, they really are operated by people working for the candidates, who uses stories to make them look good or bad. So if you are looking for a great political satire film to watch, then watch Barry Levinson's Wag The Dog, as it is one of the best and most ingenious political satires of all time! I send my applauds and congratulations to Dustin Hoffman, Robert De Niro, Barry Levinson, and the rest of the cast and crew for all of their hard work on this movie, as this movie is something, it's not nothing, it's something, something wonderful! So get ready for a political satire movie that will deliver some laughs, that's Wag The Dog, a great movie brought to you by Barry Levinson, and starring Robert De Niro and Dustin Hoffman. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Clever Satire It Purports To Be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The President is up for reelection and he gets caught in a sex scandal with a young girl. What to do? After a lot of talk among his staff, they rope in Hollywood people to create a completely phony war in Albania to distract public attention, using artificial media. Sounds hokey? Well, yes. The movie refers to Reagan's military invasion of the island nation of Grenada shortly after a terrorist bomb killed hundreds of US troops stationed in Beirut, the claim being that Reagan was trying to distract the public from the troops being killed. Never mind that the Grenada invasion was real, and certainly did not distract the news media from the Beirut bombing. Also, even in the days when the Internet wasn't widely used, there's no way a completely fictional military action would not have been exposed shortly afterward. But the movie does allow for that. They then use a convicted dangerous felon to play a soldier left behind in the supposed war, which would distract the public anew. If you can believe that a completely fictional military action would be widely reported in the major news media and somebody not quickly reveal the hoax for what it is, this movie might be for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie had a lot of potential but failed to deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D Mac
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a lot of talent wasted in this movie. I must say that my wife and had a difficult time watching it all. After 45 minutes we were no longer engaged in the story. I was expecting satire but not silly slapstick. They could have done so much with this movie and this cast. A lot of time was spent drilling down on minute aspects of the "scheme" and I felt they were flogging a point endlessly. For example, the producer wanted a kitten in a scene and several minutes was spent on him complaining until he got the kitten he was looking for. The movie develops very slowly, almost painfully so. The conflict between the conspirators and the CIA was very artificial with a conclusion that made no sense. I am guessing the idea was to make all government agencies, as well as politicians, look foolish.The movie succeeded in doing so this but in the end, the whole story was pretty foolish and lacked anything that would maintain interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have laughed more if my TV was off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Warren
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woah, woah, woah.... I'm seeing the term "brilliant satire" being tossed around in these reviews far too much. (I think I saw a comparison to Dr. Strangelove! I hope Kubrick hunts you down and punches you in the face). This was one of the worst movies I've ever seen. As for plot, it is essentially the same thing as Canadian Bacon (2 years prior, imo infinitely times funnier and smarter than this). Which is not necessarily a bad thing if it weren't so haphazardly thrown together. The movie begins a bit in medias res, and awkwardly introduces you to the situation and this Albanian idea without a single laugh. Robert Di Nero (who I usually like) is clearly just playing a poorly developed caricature of himself; Dennis Hoffman (who I love) is occasionally good for a chuckle, but the whole "producer" persona and dialogue just gets old, boring, and unrelatable after the first scene; and then there's this 'who are you?' Anne Heche character who's only purpose in the story is to praise Di Nero's character for his brilliance (cause he's not actually brilliant! O trolololol that's hilarious....) Then these characters (who we could not care less about or relate to) go on a bunch of farcical adventures, which would usually be a dynamite recipe for comedy, but again, we just don't care about or even understand these characters and their motivations Overall this movie might not be the worst satire ever, but it certainly is an awful movie  proof that good actors and a good idea cannot make up for a hideous screen play.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's funny because it's true ... it's sad for the same reasons ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's fascinating how the September 11th attacks out-dated everything, making the first Gulf War as far in memories as the Vietnam one. People are less to blame than the media-centric system that knew how to deal with the public emotion, and the key thing is that emotion has a short-term memory. George W. Bush could get away with the second Gulf War on the basis of fallacious arguments just by exploiting the September 11 trauma, and any attempt to question his choices could immediately lead to anti-patriotic accusations. And this emotional exploitation is the basis of Barry Levinson's "Wag the Dog", a hilarious satire in the same vein of sharpness than such masterpieces as "Network" or "Dr. Strangelove", and as prophetic. In August 1998, Bill Clinton confessed of having had inappropriate conduct with Monica Lewinsky, a few days later, terrorist strongholds were bombed in Africa in response to the attack of the American Embassy in Tanzania. Replace "Monica Lewinsky" by a Firefly girl, "Africa" by Albania, "Clinton" by an unknown President, and you have the basic plot of "Wag the Dog", and by 'plot', I mean the story the way it is shown on TV to the American audience. Yet "Wag the Dog" is less about the plot than the plotters. "Wag the Dog" starts with a crisis, the President has been caught with an underage girl and his opponents prepared an accusing videotape clip using 'Thank Heaven for Little Girls' as musical background, 11 days before the election, if the President's men, lead by a woman, Winifred Ames (Anne Heche) don't come up with an idea and quick, the President is screwed, and his lame "We don't change horses in midstream" campaign won't help. They call Conrad Brean, a spin-doctor; played by Robert De Niro. He comes up with the most likely idea to distract the audience from a scandal: a war, the easiest catalysis of sentimentalism and emotions through sheer patriotism. As long as people would be thirsty for magnificent displays of solidarity and humanity, incarnated by these "We are the World"-like songs, it would be easy to manipulate them. So let's start with rumors about a B3-bomber, "There's no B3-bomber", "Great, even deny its existence". Barry Levinson's film hooks us to Brean's smartness so well that we even forget that the President would indeed deserve to lose these elections. It already starts to work on us. "If the tail was smarter than the dog it would wag the dog", the dog is the audience, give them what they want and they will bite it. It's all a matter of storytelling. As a screenwriter student, I was taught that what counts the most in a story is the idea: the premise, then comes the plot, and then the storytelling, all count but it all starts with the idea. The war was the idea, but then the rest of the plot comes up very fluidly. In Albania, why? Why not? Who knows about it anyway? Who knew about Afghanistan, Iraq or Vietnam anyway? What matters is that a country shows as a potential threat, to what? To the United States, to its lifestyle, its values  the plan can't fail, the whole storyline comes us so fluidly that the scandal is almost forgotten. But we live in a media-centric society, people need images, they can't rely their emotional involvements on rumors, on unseen stuff. Time for the second protagonist of the film to make his flamboyant entrance; it's Dustin Hoffman in an electrifying performance as Stanley Motts, the producer. He's as passionate, dedicated and enthusiastic about producing as Depp in "Ed Wood" except that he has talent, and this is why the team hires him. He constructs a war with archive footage, sound effects and a young actress to play an Albanian refugee (Kirsten Dunst). People need a gimmick, like the stray cat in Vito Corleone's hands: give her a kitten. Motts understands very well how the identification process works, it asks for symbols, for colors, for memorable stuff, like the raising of the flags in Iwo-Jima or the naked girl in Vietnam. "Wag the Dog" makes us laugh for the same reasons "Network" angered us. Yet, as funny and goofy as it is, the Oscar-nominated script (the second nomination along with Hoffman) never takes its original premise for granted and takes us to unexpected and realistic twists without losing this capacity to surprise. At one point, the CIA, bought by the other side, makes a surprising statement: there's no war anymore, and Brean suddenly abandons the whole plot because it's over, how so? He "saw it on TV", TV is the Alpha and Omega; the "Network" days are not over. This is where Motts surpasses his mentor, with his unforgettable catchphrase "This is nothing", the war won't be over until he says when it's over. The war was just a pivotal moment, but like every story, you need a second pivot: how about a hostage, a war hero, a man who was kept prisoner. Abandoned like an old-shoe, how about a folk song titled "Old Shoe", a soldier whose name starts with "Shoe", like William Schumann (Woody Harrelson), you would believe this is really nothing. The saddest thing about the film is that even after watching this, the tail still wags us as we allowed many pseudo wars to happen. So even if it isn't the first political film to highlight the connection between politics and media-manipulation, it's the most related to our time. It's also a remarkably insightful film about the creative process of storytelling and a job passion, Moss is too obsessed by his talent that he'll never accept the idea of not taking credit from it, while Brean is the straight man who takes everything so normally he reminded me of another expert from a same year's movie, Tommy Lee Jones in "Men in Black", except that Brean's underworld is much scarier.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a satire, and a scary one at that
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the president is involved in scandal shortly before the election, a Hollywood producer is brought in to manufacture a war in Albania to distract from the scandal and that the President can end. "Wag the Dog" has a great premise that was prescient; before the film was released, President Clinton was involved in the sex scandal with Monica Lewinsky, and he threatened military action in Iraq. The really frightening thing is that in one of the clips shown in the film, a young woman wearing Monica's beret can be seen. It reminded me a little of the situation when Alfred Hitchcock was filming "Notorious," and his Mcguffin was the uranium to make an atom bomb being hidden in wine bottles. It was entirely innocent on his part, but the FBI had him under surveillance for months wondering what he knew about the uranium stores in South America that actually existed.. Dustin Hoffman is Stanley Motss, the producer brought in by political adviser Conrad Bean (Robert DeNiro) to produce the war. Anne Heche plays a presidential aide, and the film also includes William H. Macy, Kirsten Dunst, Andrea Martin, Denis Leary, and Willie Nelson. The sad thing is that I suppose all this is possible, despite some obvious holes in the David Mamet-Hilary Henkin script. The media can certainly manipulate, and why wouldn't gullible people believe what they are being shown? Maybe it's based on the premise that the American people are fairly dumb, and if you don't agree with that, you probably won't like it. Nevertheless, "Wag the Dog" puts forth a provocative idea and gets you thinking, and it's great to see Hoffman and DeNiro as two clever albeit sleazy people who believe the end justifies the means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sly Political Satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The U.S, President has just been exposed in a sex scandal not long before the next election. Rather than resign or take responsibility, White House spin doctors(led by Robert De Nero & Anne Heche) instead contact a Hollywood producer(Dustin Hoffman, quite funny) to direct an elaborate hoaxed war with Albania, in hopes that the nation will rally behind their incumbent president, and forget/forgive the sex scandal. Things get complicated when a "war hero"(Woody Harrelson) turns out to be a psychopath, and later on when the director insists on putting it on his resume... Ingenious satire by director Barry Levinson is extremely clever & knowing, since it wouldn't be that difficult to pull off a hoax on the American people if handled properly, and had the complicity of the media behind it. Not many people to identify with here, so it is emotionally detached, but such a dead-on portrayal of media and government complicity that it doesn't matter. "Good Old Shoe" is a prime example of what I mean. Also appreciated it's non-partisanship stance, since this scenario would apply to either side.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb on every front, the script, the acting and the directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ayal Oren
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very close to perfect ten, but I won't dwell on the reasons I've got this one rated 9.5 rather than 10. I simply want to point out the aspect that most people forget when referring to this movie. Everybody notices the wit of the script, everybody notices the superb acting of Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro. Well I want to point two less noticed aspects of this movie. Anne Heche, doing a perfect job as the perfect yes woman, the counterpoint of Hoffman and De Niro, the audience of their escapades, admiring them when they work their magic, getting angry at them when it all seems to fall apart - being the exact balance against which the two are to be compared. The other hardly ever noticed aspect of this movie is the brilliant work of Barry Levinson - it's not only the guiding of every actor and every actress, not only the perfect pacing of the plot - it's the amazing control he exerts over the look of the film. The lighting and color control of this film are of the highest class ever achieved in cinema, an aspect not commonly present in American cinema who pays much more attention to the story and often neglects its design. Have one more look at this film and pay attention to the way people are getting swallowed by the background shadows or of how they emerge from these shadows and then think of the fact that the entire film is about the shadow game of politics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie and wish more people would see it, would love to see it as a remake today !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    texaschamelion
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie with my Dad when it came out on VHS. Being a very political minded man he instilled family values as well as pride for our country. We loved this movie as he also taught us when we were kids "big brother is always watching" and told us we as citizens of this nation should not walk blindly through life, take nothing for granted especially to not accept the idea that the government and media wouldn't possibly lie to us,there are reasons we do not know everything.I laughed so much during this movie and told him he was correct. I thought this movie was very well done and would absolutely love to see a remake come out in the very near future given the state of our government today and how many "sheeple" are in existence who need to wake up and see things for what they really are. I wish i had just a dollar for every time in my life i have said "all i will say is wag the dog"!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Albania's hard to rhyme"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Hollywood produced and White House sanctioned war and the hilarious marketing of their political lies carry this "truer to life than we'd like to believe" comedy. Robert DeNiro & Dustin Hoffman are up to the task and leave plenty of room for the supporting folks. Gotta love the Willie Nelson music scenes and Dennis Leary's usual train of thought shtick. The Directors' mansion voting excuse banter is priceless for those who shutter at every liberal actor speech on democracy. Barry Levinson's eventual prophetic presidency sex scandal and the result is an underrated political comedy with great entertainment legs. There is no B-3 Bomber. I don't know how these rumors get started! Uh, we do!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Nothing..........Hardly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before elections, a spin-doctor and a Hollywood producer join efforts to "fabricate" a war in order to cover-up a presidential sex scandal. If you ask me, this is nothing....hardly. This movie is hardly nothing, it is an excellent movie, a great political satire! Wag The Dog is a hilarious political satire movie, and it ranks as one of the best movies of 1997, as well as one of the best movies that Robert De Niro has made since 1995. Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro are superb in this movie, with the former getting an Oscar nomination for Best Actor. The acting in the movie is great, and the writing is witty and clever too, and renowned director Barry Levinson's directing of this movie is superb too, so this movie is pretty superb all in all! I didn't like this movie just because it had Robert De Niro in it, I enjoyed it for many other reasons too, such as the plot, he acting from Dustin Hoffman and other cast members, Barry Levinson's directing, and numerous funny scenes in the movie, such as the commercial filming scene, and the scene where Willie Nelson is told to come up with a campaign song, and many other scenes too. Robert De Niro is one of the greatest actors who has ever lived, and he's one of my favorite actors, and not only that, but this movie is one of his best since Casino. Dustin Hoffman is a great actor too, and this movie in my opinion is one of the best movies that he has ever made, but that's not the end of it, this is one of the best movies that Barry Levinson has ever directed. All in all, the entire cast and crew did a fine job at working on this great movie! By the way, a repeated line in this movie is: "This is nothing!" This movie isn't nothing, it's definitely something, it's something great, funny, as well as witty and clever! Robert De Niro is a living sensation, he can play numerous roles, he can play both serious and comedy roles, and be great in them too, as this movie is certainly proof of that, as he is great in this movie, and at the same time, he is both funny and serious, which makes things even better. This is one of those movies that you should watch whenever you are trying to forget about your troubles on Election Day, as it's a perfect political satire which gives a look at how presidential campaigns actually are, they really are operated by people working for the candidates, who uses stories to make them look good or bad. So if you are looking for a great political satire film to watch, then watch Barry Levinson's Wag The Dog, as it is one of the best and most ingenious political satires of all time! I send my applauds and congratulations to Dustin Hoffman, Robert De Niro, Barry Levinson, and the rest of the cast and crew for all of their hard work on this movie, as this movie is something, it's not nothing, it's something, something wonderful! So get ready for a political satire movie that will deliver some laughs, that's Wag The Dog, a great movie brought to you by Barry Levinson, and starring Robert De Niro and Dustin Hoffman. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Clever Satire It Purports To Be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The President is up for reelection and he gets caught in a sex scandal with a young girl. What to do? After a lot of talk among his staff, they rope in Hollywood people to create a completely phony war in Albania to distract public attention, using artificial media. Sounds hokey? Well, yes. The movie refers to Reagan's military invasion of the island nation of Grenada shortly after a terrorist bomb killed hundreds of US troops stationed in Beirut, the claim being that Reagan was trying to distract the public from the troops being killed. Never mind that the Grenada invasion was real, and certainly did not distract the news media from the Beirut bombing. Also, even in the days when the Internet wasn't widely used, there's no way a completely fictional military action would not have been exposed shortly afterward. But the movie does allow for that. They then use a convicted dangerous felon to play a soldier left behind in the supposed war, which would distract the public anew. If you can believe that a completely fictional military action would be widely reported in the major news media and somebody not quickly reveal the hoax for what it is, this movie might be for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie had a lot of potential but failed to deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D Mac
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a lot of talent wasted in this movie. I must say that my wife and had a difficult time watching it all. After 45 minutes we were no longer engaged in the story. I was expecting satire but not silly slapstick. They could have done so much with this movie and this cast. A lot of time was spent drilling down on minute aspects of the "scheme" and I felt they were flogging a point endlessly. For example, the producer wanted a kitten in a scene and several minutes was spent on him complaining until he got the kitten he was looking for. The movie develops very slowly, almost painfully so. The conflict between the conspirators and the CIA was very artificial with a conclusion that made no sense. I am guessing the idea was to make all government agencies, as well as politicians, look foolish.The movie succeeded in doing so this but in the end, the whole story was pretty foolish and lacked anything that would maintain interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have laughed more if my TV was off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Warren
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woah, woah, woah.... I'm seeing the term "brilliant satire" being tossed around in these reviews far too much. (I think I saw a comparison to Dr. Strangelove! I hope Kubrick hunts you down and punches you in the face). This was one of the worst movies I've ever seen. As for plot, it is essentially the same thing as Canadian Bacon (2 years prior, imo infinitely times funnier and smarter than this). Which is not necessarily a bad thing if it weren't so haphazardly thrown together. The movie begins a bit in medias res, and awkwardly introduces you to the situation and this Albanian idea without a single laugh. Robert Di Nero (who I usually like) is clearly just playing a poorly developed caricature of himself; Dennis Hoffman (who I love) is occasionally good for a chuckle, but the whole "producer" persona and dialogue just gets old, boring, and unrelatable after the first scene; and then there's this 'who are you?' Anne Heche character who's only purpose in the story is to praise Di Nero's character for his brilliance (cause he's not actually brilliant! O trolololol that's hilarious....) Then these characters (who we could not care less about or relate to) go on a bunch of farcical adventures, which would usually be a dynamite recipe for comedy, but again, we just don't care about or even understand these characters and their motivations Overall this movie might not be the worst satire ever, but it certainly is an awful movie  proof that good actors and a good idea cannot make up for a hideous screen play.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's funny because it's true ... it's sad for the same reasons ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's fascinating how the September 11th attacks out-dated everything, making the first Gulf War as far in memories as the Vietnam one. People are less to blame than the media-centric system that knew how to deal with the public emotion, and the key thing is that emotion has a short-term memory. George W. Bush could get away with the second Gulf War on the basis of fallacious arguments just by exploiting the September 11 trauma, and any attempt to question his choices could immediately lead to anti-patriotic accusations. And this emotional exploitation is the basis of Barry Levinson's "Wag the Dog", a hilarious satire in the same vein of sharpness than such masterpieces as "Network" or "Dr. Strangelove", and as prophetic. In August 1998, Bill Clinton confessed of having had inappropriate conduct with Monica Lewinsky, a few days later, terrorist strongholds were bombed in Africa in response to the attack of the American Embassy in Tanzania. Replace "Monica Lewinsky" by a Firefly girl, "Africa" by Albania, "Clinton" by an unknown President, and you have the basic plot of "Wag the Dog", and by 'plot', I mean the story the way it is shown on TV to the American audience. Yet "Wag the Dog" is less about the plot than the plotters. "Wag the Dog" starts with a crisis, the President has been caught with an underage girl and his opponents prepared an accusing videotape clip using 'Thank Heaven for Little Girls' as musical background, 11 days before the election, if the President's men, lead by a woman, Winifred Ames (Anne Heche) don't come up with an idea and quick, the President is screwed, and his lame "We don't change horses in midstream" campaign won't help. They call Conrad Brean, a spin-doctor; played by Robert De Niro. He comes up with the most likely idea to distract the audience from a scandal: a war, the easiest catalysis of sentimentalism and emotions through sheer patriotism. As long as people would be thirsty for magnificent displays of solidarity and humanity, incarnated by these "We are the World"-like songs, it would be easy to manipulate them. So let's start with rumors about a B3-bomber, "There's no B3-bomber", "Great, even deny its existence". Barry Levinson's film hooks us to Brean's smartness so well that we even forget that the President would indeed deserve to lose these elections. It already starts to work on us. "If the tail was smarter than the dog it would wag the dog", the dog is the audience, give them what they want and they will bite it. It's all a matter of storytelling. As a screenwriter student, I was taught that what counts the most in a story is the idea: the premise, then comes the plot, and then the storytelling, all count but it all starts with the idea. The war was the idea, but then the rest of the plot comes up very fluidly. In Albania, why? Why not? Who knows about it anyway? Who knew about Afghanistan, Iraq or Vietnam anyway? What matters is that a country shows as a potential threat, to what? To the United States, to its lifestyle, its values  the plan can't fail, the whole storyline comes us so fluidly that the scandal is almost forgotten. But we live in a media-centric society, people need images, they can't rely their emotional involvements on rumors, on unseen stuff. Time for the second protagonist of the film to make his flamboyant entrance; it's Dustin Hoffman in an electrifying performance as Stanley Motts, the producer. He's as passionate, dedicated and enthusiastic about producing as Depp in "Ed Wood" except that he has talent, and this is why the team hires him. He constructs a war with archive footage, sound effects and a young actress to play an Albanian refugee (Kirsten Dunst). People need a gimmick, like the stray cat in Vito Corleone's hands: give her a kitten. Motts understands very well how the identification process works, it asks for symbols, for colors, for memorable stuff, like the raising of the flags in Iwo-Jima or the naked girl in Vietnam. "Wag the Dog" makes us laugh for the same reasons "Network" angered us. Yet, as funny and goofy as it is, the Oscar-nominated script (the second nomination along with Hoffman) never takes its original premise for granted and takes us to unexpected and realistic twists without losing this capacity to surprise. At one point, the CIA, bought by the other side, makes a surprising statement: there's no war anymore, and Brean suddenly abandons the whole plot because it's over, how so? He "saw it on TV", TV is the Alpha and Omega; the "Network" days are not over. This is where Motts surpasses his mentor, with his unforgettable catchphrase "This is nothing", the war won't be over until he says when it's over. The war was just a pivotal moment, but like every story, you need a second pivot: how about a hostage, a war hero, a man who was kept prisoner. Abandoned like an old-shoe, how about a folk song titled "Old Shoe", a soldier whose name starts with "Shoe", like William Schumann (Woody Harrelson), you would believe this is really nothing. The saddest thing about the film is that even after watching this, the tail still wags us as we allowed many pseudo wars to happen. So even if it isn't the first political film to highlight the connection between politics and media-manipulation, it's the most related to our time. It's also a remarkably insightful film about the creative process of storytelling and a job passion, Moss is too obsessed by his talent that he'll never accept the idea of not taking credit from it, while Brean is the straight man who takes everything so normally he reminded me of another expert from a same year's movie, Tommy Lee Jones in "Men in Black", except that Brean's underworld is much scarier.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a satire, and a scary one at that
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the president is involved in scandal shortly before the election, a Hollywood producer is brought in to manufacture a war in Albania to distract from the scandal and that the President can end. "Wag the Dog" has a great premise that was prescient; before the film was released, President Clinton was involved in the sex scandal with Monica Lewinsky, and he threatened military action in Iraq. The really frightening thing is that in one of the clips shown in the film, a young woman wearing Monica's beret can be seen. It reminded me a little of the situation when Alfred Hitchcock was filming "Notorious," and his Mcguffin was the uranium to make an atom bomb being hidden in wine bottles. It was entirely innocent on his part, but the FBI had him under surveillance for months wondering what he knew about the uranium stores in South America that actually existed.. Dustin Hoffman is Stanley Motss, the producer brought in by political adviser Conrad Bean (Robert DeNiro) to produce the war. Anne Heche plays a presidential aide, and the film also includes William H. Macy, Kirsten Dunst, Andrea Martin, Denis Leary, and Willie Nelson. The sad thing is that I suppose all this is possible, despite some obvious holes in the David Mamet-Hilary Henkin script. The media can certainly manipulate, and why wouldn't gullible people believe what they are being shown? Maybe it's based on the premise that the American people are fairly dumb, and if you don't agree with that, you probably won't like it. Nevertheless, "Wag the Dog" puts forth a provocative idea and gets you thinking, and it's great to see Hoffman and DeNiro as two clever albeit sleazy people who believe the end justifies the means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sly Political Satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The U.S, President has just been exposed in a sex scandal not long before the next election. Rather than resign or take responsibility, White House spin doctors(led by Robert De Nero & Anne Heche) instead contact a Hollywood producer(Dustin Hoffman, quite funny) to direct an elaborate hoaxed war with Albania, in hopes that the nation will rally behind their incumbent president, and forget/forgive the sex scandal. Things get complicated when a "war hero"(Woody Harrelson) turns out to be a psychopath, and later on when the director insists on putting it on his resume... Ingenious satire by director Barry Levinson is extremely clever & knowing, since it wouldn't be that difficult to pull off a hoax on the American people if handled properly, and had the complicity of the media behind it. Not many people to identify with here, so it is emotionally detached, but such a dead-on portrayal of media and government complicity that it doesn't matter. "Good Old Shoe" is a prime example of what I mean. Also appreciated it's non-partisanship stance, since this scenario would apply to either side.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb on every front, the script, the acting and the directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ayal Oren
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very close to perfect ten, but I won't dwell on the reasons I've got this one rated 9.5 rather than 10. I simply want to point out the aspect that most people forget when referring to this movie. Everybody notices the wit of the script, everybody notices the superb acting of Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro. Well I want to point two less noticed aspects of this movie. Anne Heche, doing a perfect job as the perfect yes woman, the counterpoint of Hoffman and De Niro, the audience of their escapades, admiring them when they work their magic, getting angry at them when it all seems to fall apart - being the exact balance against which the two are to be compared. The other hardly ever noticed aspect of this movie is the brilliant work of Barry Levinson - it's not only the guiding of every actor and every actress, not only the perfect pacing of the plot - it's the amazing control he exerts over the look of the film. The lighting and color control of this film are of the highest class ever achieved in cinema, an aspect not commonly present in American cinema who pays much more attention to the story and often neglects its design. Have one more look at this film and pay attention to the way people are getting swallowed by the background shadows or of how they emerge from these shadows and then think of the fact that the entire film is about the shadow game of politics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie and wish more people would see it, would love to see it as a remake today !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    texaschamelion
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie with my Dad when it came out on VHS. Being a very political minded man he instilled family values as well as pride for our country. We loved this movie as he also taught us when we were kids "big brother is always watching" and told us we as citizens of this nation should not walk blindly through life, take nothing for granted especially to not accept the idea that the government and media wouldn't possibly lie to us,there are reasons we do not know everything.I laughed so much during this movie and told him he was correct. I thought this movie was very well done and would absolutely love to see a remake come out in the very near future given the state of our government today and how many "sheeple" are in existence who need to wake up and see things for what they really are. I wish i had just a dollar for every time in my life i have said "all i will say is wag the dog"!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Albania's hard to rhyme"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Hollywood produced and White House sanctioned war and the hilarious marketing of their political lies carry this "truer to life than we'd like to believe" comedy. Robert DeNiro & Dustin Hoffman are up to the task and leave plenty of room for the supporting folks. Gotta love the Willie Nelson music scenes and Dennis Leary's usual train of thought shtick. The Directors' mansion voting excuse banter is priceless for those who shutter at every liberal actor speech on democracy. Barry Levinson's eventual prophetic presidency sex scandal and the result is an underrated political comedy with great entertainment legs. There is no B-3 Bomber. I don't know how these rumors get started! Uh, we do!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Nothing..........Hardly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before elections, a spin-doctor and a Hollywood producer join efforts to "fabricate" a war in order to cover-up a presidential sex scandal. If you ask me, this is nothing....hardly. This movie is hardly nothing, it is an excellent movie, a great political satire! Wag The Dog is a hilarious political satire movie, and it ranks as one of the best movies of 1997, as well as one of the best movies that Robert De Niro has made since 1995. Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro are superb in this movie, with the former getting an Oscar nomination for Best Actor. The acting in the movie is great, and the writing is witty and clever too, and renowned director Barry Levinson's directing of this movie is superb too, so this movie is pretty superb all in all! I didn't like this movie just because it had Robert De Niro in it, I enjoyed it for many other reasons too, such as the plot, he acting from Dustin Hoffman and other cast members, Barry Levinson's directing, and numerous funny scenes in the movie, such as the commercial filming scene, and the scene where Willie Nelson is told to come up with a campaign song, and many other scenes too. Robert De Niro is one of the greatest actors who has ever lived, and he's one of my favorite actors, and not only that, but this movie is one of his best since Casino. Dustin Hoffman is a great actor too, and this movie in my opinion is one of the best movies that he has ever made, but that's not the end of it, this is one of the best movies that Barry Levinson has ever directed. All in all, the entire cast and crew did a fine job at working on this great movie! By the way, a repeated line in this movie is: "This is nothing!" This movie isn't nothing, it's definitely something, it's something great, funny, as well as witty and clever! Robert De Niro is a living sensation, he can play numerous roles, he can play both serious and comedy roles, and be great in them too, as this movie is certainly proof of that, as he is great in this movie, and at the same time, he is both funny and serious, which makes things even better. This is one of those movies that you should watch whenever you are trying to forget about your troubles on Election Day, as it's a perfect political satire which gives a look at how presidential campaigns actually are, they really are operated by people working for the candidates, who uses stories to make them look good or bad. So if you are looking for a great political satire film to watch, then watch Barry Levinson's Wag The Dog, as it is one of the best and most ingenious political satires of all time! I send my applauds and congratulations to Dustin Hoffman, Robert De Niro, Barry Levinson, and the rest of the cast and crew for all of their hard work on this movie, as this movie is something, it's not nothing, it's something, something wonderful! So get ready for a political satire movie that will deliver some laughs, that's Wag The Dog, a great movie brought to you by Barry Levinson, and starring Robert De Niro and Dustin Hoffman. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Clever Satire It Purports To Be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The President is up for reelection and he gets caught in a sex scandal with a young girl. What to do? After a lot of talk among his staff, they rope in Hollywood people to create a completely phony war in Albania to distract public attention, using artificial media. Sounds hokey? Well, yes. The movie refers to Reagan's military invasion of the island nation of Grenada shortly after a terrorist bomb killed hundreds of US troops stationed in Beirut, the claim being that Reagan was trying to distract the public from the troops being killed. Never mind that the Grenada invasion was real, and certainly did not distract the news media from the Beirut bombing. Also, even in the days when the Internet wasn't widely used, there's no way a completely fictional military action would not have been exposed shortly afterward. But the movie does allow for that. They then use a convicted dangerous felon to play a soldier left behind in the supposed war, which would distract the public anew. If you can believe that a completely fictional military action would be widely reported in the major news media and somebody not quickly reveal the hoax for what it is, this movie might be for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie had a lot of potential but failed to deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D Mac
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a lot of talent wasted in this movie. I must say that my wife and had a difficult time watching it all. After 45 minutes we were no longer engaged in the story. I was expecting satire but not silly slapstick. They could have done so much with this movie and this cast. A lot of time was spent drilling down on minute aspects of the "scheme" and I felt they were flogging a point endlessly. For example, the producer wanted a kitten in a scene and several minutes was spent on him complaining until he got the kitten he was looking for. The movie develops very slowly, almost painfully so. The conflict between the conspirators and the CIA was very artificial with a conclusion that made no sense. I am guessing the idea was to make all government agencies, as well as politicians, look foolish.The movie succeeded in doing so this but in the end, the whole story was pretty foolish and lacked anything that would maintain interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have laughed more if my TV was off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Warren
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woah, woah, woah.... I'm seeing the term "brilliant satire" being tossed around in these reviews far too much. (I think I saw a comparison to Dr. Strangelove! I hope Kubrick hunts you down and punches you in the face). This was one of the worst movies I've ever seen. As for plot, it is essentially the same thing as Canadian Bacon (2 years prior, imo infinitely times funnier and smarter than this). Which is not necessarily a bad thing if it weren't so haphazardly thrown together. The movie begins a bit in medias res, and awkwardly introduces you to the situation and this Albanian idea without a single laugh. Robert Di Nero (who I usually like) is clearly just playing a poorly developed caricature of himself; Dennis Hoffman (who I love) is occasionally good for a chuckle, but the whole "producer" persona and dialogue just gets old, boring, and unrelatable after the first scene; and then there's this 'who are you?' Anne Heche character who's only purpose in the story is to praise Di Nero's character for his brilliance (cause he's not actually brilliant! O trolololol that's hilarious....) Then these characters (who we could not care less about or relate to) go on a bunch of farcical adventures, which would usually be a dynamite recipe for comedy, but again, we just don't care about or even understand these characters and their motivations Overall this movie might not be the worst satire ever, but it certainly is an awful movie  proof that good actors and a good idea cannot make up for a hideous screen play.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's funny because it's true ... it's sad for the same reasons ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's fascinating how the September 11th attacks out-dated everything, making the first Gulf War as far in memories as the Vietnam one. People are less to blame than the media-centric system that knew how to deal with the public emotion, and the key thing is that emotion has a short-term memory. George W. Bush could get away with the second Gulf War on the basis of fallacious arguments just by exploiting the September 11 trauma, and any attempt to question his choices could immediately lead to anti-patriotic accusations. And this emotional exploitation is the basis of Barry Levinson's "Wag the Dog", a hilarious satire in the same vein of sharpness than such masterpieces as "Network" or "Dr. Strangelove", and as prophetic. In August 1998, Bill Clinton confessed of having had inappropriate conduct with Monica Lewinsky, a few days later, terrorist strongholds were bombed in Africa in response to the attack of the American Embassy in Tanzania. Replace "Monica Lewinsky" by a Firefly girl, "Africa" by Albania, "Clinton" by an unknown President, and you have the basic plot of "Wag the Dog", and by 'plot', I mean the story the way it is shown on TV to the American audience. Yet "Wag the Dog" is less about the plot than the plotters. "Wag the Dog" starts with a crisis, the President has been caught with an underage girl and his opponents prepared an accusing videotape clip using 'Thank Heaven for Little Girls' as musical background, 11 days before the election, if the President's men, lead by a woman, Winifred Ames (Anne Heche) don't come up with an idea and quick, the President is screwed, and his lame "We don't change horses in midstream" campaign won't help. They call Conrad Brean, a spin-doctor; played by Robert De Niro. He comes up with the most likely idea to distract the audience from a scandal: a war, the easiest catalysis of sentimentalism and emotions through sheer patriotism. As long as people would be thirsty for magnificent displays of solidarity and humanity, incarnated by these "We are the World"-like songs, it would be easy to manipulate them. So let's start with rumors about a B3-bomber, "There's no B3-bomber", "Great, even deny its existence". Barry Levinson's film hooks us to Brean's smartness so well that we even forget that the President would indeed deserve to lose these elections. It already starts to work on us. "If the tail was smarter than the dog it would wag the dog", the dog is the audience, give them what they want and they will bite it. It's all a matter of storytelling. As a screenwriter student, I was taught that what counts the most in a story is the idea: the premise, then comes the plot, and then the storytelling, all count but it all starts with the idea. The war was the idea, but then the rest of the plot comes up very fluidly. In Albania, why? Why not? Who knows about it anyway? Who knew about Afghanistan, Iraq or Vietnam anyway? What matters is that a country shows as a potential threat, to what? To the United States, to its lifestyle, its values  the plan can't fail, the whole storyline comes us so fluidly that the scandal is almost forgotten. But we live in a media-centric society, people need images, they can't rely their emotional involvements on rumors, on unseen stuff. Time for the second protagonist of the film to make his flamboyant entrance; it's Dustin Hoffman in an electrifying performance as Stanley Motts, the producer. He's as passionate, dedicated and enthusiastic about producing as Depp in "Ed Wood" except that he has talent, and this is why the team hires him. He constructs a war with archive footage, sound effects and a young actress to play an Albanian refugee (Kirsten Dunst). People need a gimmick, like the stray cat in Vito Corleone's hands: give her a kitten. Motts understands very well how the identification process works, it asks for symbols, for colors, for memorable stuff, like the raising of the flags in Iwo-Jima or the naked girl in Vietnam. "Wag the Dog" makes us laugh for the same reasons "Network" angered us. Yet, as funny and goofy as it is, the Oscar-nominated script (the second nomination along with Hoffman) never takes its original premise for granted and takes us to unexpected and realistic twists without losing this capacity to surprise. At one point, the CIA, bought by the other side, makes a surprising statement: there's no war anymore, and Brean suddenly abandons the whole plot because it's over, how so? He "saw it on TV", TV is the Alpha and Omega; the "Network" days are not over. This is where Motts surpasses his mentor, with his unforgettable catchphrase "This is nothing", the war won't be over until he says when it's over. The war was just a pivotal moment, but like every story, you need a second pivot: how about a hostage, a war hero, a man who was kept prisoner. Abandoned like an old-shoe, how about a folk song titled "Old Shoe", a soldier whose name starts with "Shoe", like William Schumann (Woody Harrelson), you would believe this is really nothing. The saddest thing about the film is that even after watching this, the tail still wags us as we allowed many pseudo wars to happen. So even if it isn't the first political film to highlight the connection between politics and media-manipulation, it's the most related to our time. It's also a remarkably insightful film about the creative process of storytelling and a job passion, Moss is too obsessed by his talent that he'll never accept the idea of not taking credit from it, while Brean is the straight man who takes everything so normally he reminded me of another expert from a same year's movie, Tommy Lee Jones in "Men in Black", except that Brean's underworld is much scarier.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a satire, and a scary one at that
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the president is involved in scandal shortly before the election, a Hollywood producer is brought in to manufacture a war in Albania to distract from the scandal and that the President can end. "Wag the Dog" has a great premise that was prescient; before the film was released, President Clinton was involved in the sex scandal with Monica Lewinsky, and he threatened military action in Iraq. The really frightening thing is that in one of the clips shown in the film, a young woman wearing Monica's beret can be seen. It reminded me a little of the situation when Alfred Hitchcock was filming "Notorious," and his Mcguffin was the uranium to make an atom bomb being hidden in wine bottles. It was entirely innocent on his part, but the FBI had him under surveillance for months wondering what he knew about the uranium stores in South America that actually existed.. Dustin Hoffman is Stanley Motss, the producer brought in by political adviser Conrad Bean (Robert DeNiro) to produce the war. Anne Heche plays a presidential aide, and the film also includes William H. Macy, Kirsten Dunst, Andrea Martin, Denis Leary, and Willie Nelson. The sad thing is that I suppose all this is possible, despite some obvious holes in the David Mamet-Hilary Henkin script. The media can certainly manipulate, and why wouldn't gullible people believe what they are being shown? Maybe it's based on the premise that the American people are fairly dumb, and if you don't agree with that, you probably won't like it. Nevertheless, "Wag the Dog" puts forth a provocative idea and gets you thinking, and it's great to see Hoffman and DeNiro as two clever albeit sleazy people who believe the end justifies the means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sly Political Satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The U.S, President has just been exposed in a sex scandal not long before the next election. Rather than resign or take responsibility, White House spin doctors(led by Robert De Nero & Anne Heche) instead contact a Hollywood producer(Dustin Hoffman, quite funny) to direct an elaborate hoaxed war with Albania, in hopes that the nation will rally behind their incumbent president, and forget/forgive the sex scandal. Things get complicated when a "war hero"(Woody Harrelson) turns out to be a psychopath, and later on when the director insists on putting it on his resume... Ingenious satire by director Barry Levinson is extremely clever & knowing, since it wouldn't be that difficult to pull off a hoax on the American people if handled properly, and had the complicity of the media behind it. Not many people to identify with here, so it is emotionally detached, but such a dead-on portrayal of media and government complicity that it doesn't matter. "Good Old Shoe" is a prime example of what I mean. Also appreciated it's non-partisanship stance, since this scenario would apply to either side.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb on every front, the script, the acting and the directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ayal Oren
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very close to perfect ten, but I won't dwell on the reasons I've got this one rated 9.5 rather than 10. I simply want to point out the aspect that most people forget when referring to this movie. Everybody notices the wit of the script, everybody notices the superb acting of Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro. Well I want to point two less noticed aspects of this movie. Anne Heche, doing a perfect job as the perfect yes woman, the counterpoint of Hoffman and De Niro, the audience of their escapades, admiring them when they work their magic, getting angry at them when it all seems to fall apart - being the exact balance against which the two are to be compared. The other hardly ever noticed aspect of this movie is the brilliant work of Barry Levinson - it's not only the guiding of every actor and every actress, not only the perfect pacing of the plot - it's the amazing control he exerts over the look of the film. The lighting and color control of this film are of the highest class ever achieved in cinema, an aspect not commonly present in American cinema who pays much more attention to the story and often neglects its design. Have one more look at this film and pay attention to the way people are getting swallowed by the background shadows or of how they emerge from these shadows and then think of the fact that the entire film is about the shadow game of politics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie and wish more people would see it, would love to see it as a remake today !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    texaschamelion
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie with my Dad when it came out on VHS. Being a very political minded man he instilled family values as well as pride for our country. We loved this movie as he also taught us when we were kids "big brother is always watching" and told us we as citizens of this nation should not walk blindly through life, take nothing for granted especially to not accept the idea that the government and media wouldn't possibly lie to us,there are reasons we do not know everything.I laughed so much during this movie and told him he was correct. I thought this movie was very well done and would absolutely love to see a remake come out in the very near future given the state of our government today and how many "sheeple" are in existence who need to wake up and see things for what they really are. I wish i had just a dollar for every time in my life i have said "all i will say is wag the dog"!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Albania's hard to rhyme"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Hollywood produced and White House sanctioned war and the hilarious marketing of their political lies carry this "truer to life than we'd like to believe" comedy. Robert DeNiro & Dustin Hoffman are up to the task and leave plenty of room for the supporting folks. Gotta love the Willie Nelson music scenes and Dennis Leary's usual train of thought shtick. The Directors' mansion voting excuse banter is priceless for those who shutter at every liberal actor speech on democracy. Barry Levinson's eventual prophetic presidency sex scandal and the result is an underrated political comedy with great entertainment legs. There is no B-3 Bomber. I don't know how these rumors get started! Uh, we do!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Nothing..........Hardly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before elections, a spin-doctor and a Hollywood producer join efforts to "fabricate" a war in order to cover-up a presidential sex scandal. If you ask me, this is nothing....hardly. This movie is hardly nothing, it is an excellent movie, a great political satire! Wag The Dog is a hilarious political satire movie, and it ranks as one of the best movies of 1997, as well as one of the best movies that Robert De Niro has made since 1995. Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro are superb in this movie, with the former getting an Oscar nomination for Best Actor. The acting in the movie is great, and the writing is witty and clever too, and renowned director Barry Levinson's directing of this movie is superb too, so this movie is pretty superb all in all! I didn't like this movie just because it had Robert De Niro in it, I enjoyed it for many other reasons too, such as the plot, he acting from Dustin Hoffman and other cast members, Barry Levinson's directing, and numerous funny scenes in the movie, such as the commercial filming scene, and the scene where Willie Nelson is told to come up with a campaign song, and many other scenes too. Robert De Niro is one of the greatest actors who has ever lived, and he's one of my favorite actors, and not only that, but this movie is one of his best since Casino. Dustin Hoffman is a great actor too, and this movie in my opinion is one of the best movies that he has ever made, but that's not the end of it, this is one of the best movies that Barry Levinson has ever directed. All in all, the entire cast and crew did a fine job at working on this great movie! By the way, a repeated line in this movie is: "This is nothing!" This movie isn't nothing, it's definitely something, it's something great, funny, as well as witty and clever! Robert De Niro is a living sensation, he can play numerous roles, he can play both serious and comedy roles, and be great in them too, as this movie is certainly proof of that, as he is great in this movie, and at the same time, he is both funny and serious, which makes things even better. This is one of those movies that you should watch whenever you are trying to forget about your troubles on Election Day, as it's a perfect political satire which gives a look at how presidential campaigns actually are, they really are operated by people working for the candidates, who uses stories to make them look good or bad. So if you are looking for a great political satire film to watch, then watch Barry Levinson's Wag The Dog, as it is one of the best and most ingenious political satires of all time! I send my applauds and congratulations to Dustin Hoffman, Robert De Niro, Barry Levinson, and the rest of the cast and crew for all of their hard work on this movie, as this movie is something, it's not nothing, it's something, something wonderful! So get ready for a political satire movie that will deliver some laughs, that's Wag The Dog, a great movie brought to you by Barry Levinson, and starring Robert De Niro and Dustin Hoffman. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Clever Satire It Purports To Be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The President is up for reelection and he gets caught in a sex scandal with a young girl. What to do? After a lot of talk among his staff, they rope in Hollywood people to create a completely phony war in Albania to distract public attention, using artificial media. Sounds hokey? Well, yes. The movie refers to Reagan's military invasion of the island nation of Grenada shortly after a terrorist bomb killed hundreds of US troops stationed in Beirut, the claim being that Reagan was trying to distract the public from the troops being killed. Never mind that the Grenada invasion was real, and certainly did not distract the news media from the Beirut bombing. Also, even in the days when the Internet wasn't widely used, there's no way a completely fictional military action would not have been exposed shortly afterward. But the movie does allow for that. They then use a convicted dangerous felon to play a soldier left behind in the supposed war, which would distract the public anew. If you can believe that a completely fictional military action would be widely reported in the major news media and somebody not quickly reveal the hoax for what it is, this movie might be for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie had a lot of potential but failed to deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D Mac
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a lot of talent wasted in this movie. I must say that my wife and had a difficult time watching it all. After 45 minutes we were no longer engaged in the story. I was expecting satire but not silly slapstick. They could have done so much with this movie and this cast. A lot of time was spent drilling down on minute aspects of the "scheme" and I felt they were flogging a point endlessly. For example, the producer wanted a kitten in a scene and several minutes was spent on him complaining until he got the kitten he was looking for. The movie develops very slowly, almost painfully so. The conflict between the conspirators and the CIA was very artificial with a conclusion that made no sense. I am guessing the idea was to make all government agencies, as well as politicians, look foolish.The movie succeeded in doing so this but in the end, the whole story was pretty foolish and lacked anything that would maintain interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have laughed more if my TV was off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Warren
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woah, woah, woah.... I'm seeing the term "brilliant satire" being tossed around in these reviews far too much. (I think I saw a comparison to Dr. Strangelove! I hope Kubrick hunts you down and punches you in the face). This was one of the worst movies I've ever seen. As for plot, it is essentially the same thing as Canadian Bacon (2 years prior, imo infinitely times funnier and smarter than this). Which is not necessarily a bad thing if it weren't so haphazardly thrown together. The movie begins a bit in medias res, and awkwardly introduces you to the situation and this Albanian idea without a single laugh. Robert Di Nero (who I usually like) is clearly just playing a poorly developed caricature of himself; Dennis Hoffman (who I love) is occasionally good for a chuckle, but the whole "producer" persona and dialogue just gets old, boring, and unrelatable after the first scene; and then there's this 'who are you?' Anne Heche character who's only purpose in the story is to praise Di Nero's character for his brilliance (cause he's not actually brilliant! O trolololol that's hilarious....) Then these characters (who we could not care less about or relate to) go on a bunch of farcical adventures, which would usually be a dynamite recipe for comedy, but again, we just don't care about or even understand these characters and their motivations Overall this movie might not be the worst satire ever, but it certainly is an awful movie  proof that good actors and a good idea cannot make up for a hideous screen play.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's funny because it's true ... it's sad for the same reasons ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's fascinating how the September 11th attacks out-dated everything, making the first Gulf War as far in memories as the Vietnam one. People are less to blame than the media-centric system that knew how to deal with the public emotion, and the key thing is that emotion has a short-term memory. George W. Bush could get away with the second Gulf War on the basis of fallacious arguments just by exploiting the September 11 trauma, and any attempt to question his choices could immediately lead to anti-patriotic accusations. And this emotional exploitation is the basis of Barry Levinson's "Wag the Dog", a hilarious satire in the same vein of sharpness than such masterpieces as "Network" or "Dr. Strangelove", and as prophetic. In August 1998, Bill Clinton confessed of having had inappropriate conduct with Monica Lewinsky, a few days later, terrorist strongholds were bombed in Africa in response to the attack of the American Embassy in Tanzania. Replace "Monica Lewinsky" by a Firefly girl, "Africa" by Albania, "Clinton" by an unknown President, and you have the basic plot of "Wag the Dog", and by 'plot', I mean the story the way it is shown on TV to the American audience. Yet "Wag the Dog" is less about the plot than the plotters. "Wag the Dog" starts with a crisis, the President has been caught with an underage girl and his opponents prepared an accusing videotape clip using 'Thank Heaven for Little Girls' as musical background, 11 days before the election, if the President's men, lead by a woman, Winifred Ames (Anne Heche) don't come up with an idea and quick, the President is screwed, and his lame "We don't change horses in midstream" campaign won't help. They call Conrad Brean, a spin-doctor; played by Robert De Niro. He comes up with the most likely idea to distract the audience from a scandal: a war, the easiest catalysis of sentimentalism and emotions through sheer patriotism. As long as people would be thirsty for magnificent displays of solidarity and humanity, incarnated by these "We are the World"-like songs, it would be easy to manipulate them. So let's start with rumors about a B3-bomber, "There's no B3-bomber", "Great, even deny its existence". Barry Levinson's film hooks us to Brean's smartness so well that we even forget that the President would indeed deserve to lose these elections. It already starts to work on us. "If the tail was smarter than the dog it would wag the dog", the dog is the audience, give them what they want and they will bite it. It's all a matter of storytelling. As a screenwriter student, I was taught that what counts the most in a story is the idea: the premise, then comes the plot, and then the storytelling, all count but it all starts with the idea. The war was the idea, but then the rest of the plot comes up very fluidly. In Albania, why? Why not? Who knows about it anyway? Who knew about Afghanistan, Iraq or Vietnam anyway? What matters is that a country shows as a potential threat, to what? To the United States, to its lifestyle, its values  the plan can't fail, the whole storyline comes us so fluidly that the scandal is almost forgotten. But we live in a media-centric society, people need images, they can't rely their emotional involvements on rumors, on unseen stuff. Time for the second protagonist of the film to make his flamboyant entrance; it's Dustin Hoffman in an electrifying performance as Stanley Motts, the producer. He's as passionate, dedicated and enthusiastic about producing as Depp in "Ed Wood" except that he has talent, and this is why the team hires him. He constructs a war with archive footage, sound effects and a young actress to play an Albanian refugee (Kirsten Dunst). People need a gimmick, like the stray cat in Vito Corleone's hands: give her a kitten. Motts understands very well how the identification process works, it asks for symbols, for colors, for memorable stuff, like the raising of the flags in Iwo-Jima or the naked girl in Vietnam. "Wag the Dog" makes us laugh for the same reasons "Network" angered us. Yet, as funny and goofy as it is, the Oscar-nominated script (the second nomination along with Hoffman) never takes its original premise for granted and takes us to unexpected and realistic twists without losing this capacity to surprise. At one point, the CIA, bought by the other side, makes a surprising statement: there's no war anymore, and Brean suddenly abandons the whole plot because it's over, how so? He "saw it on TV", TV is the Alpha and Omega; the "Network" days are not over. This is where Motts surpasses his mentor, with his unforgettable catchphrase "This is nothing", the war won't be over until he says when it's over. The war was just a pivotal moment, but like every story, you need a second pivot: how about a hostage, a war hero, a man who was kept prisoner. Abandoned like an old-shoe, how about a folk song titled "Old Shoe", a soldier whose name starts with "Shoe", like William Schumann (Woody Harrelson), you would believe this is really nothing. The saddest thing about the film is that even after watching this, the tail still wags us as we allowed many pseudo wars to happen. So even if it isn't the first political film to highlight the connection between politics and media-manipulation, it's the most related to our time. It's also a remarkably insightful film about the creative process of storytelling and a job passion, Moss is too obsessed by his talent that he'll never accept the idea of not taking credit from it, while Brean is the straight man who takes everything so normally he reminded me of another expert from a same year's movie, Tommy Lee Jones in "Men in Black", except that Brean's underworld is much scarier.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a satire, and a scary one at that
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the president is involved in scandal shortly before the election, a Hollywood producer is brought in to manufacture a war in Albania to distract from the scandal and that the President can end. "Wag the Dog" has a great premise that was prescient; before the film was released, President Clinton was involved in the sex scandal with Monica Lewinsky, and he threatened military action in Iraq. The really frightening thing is that in one of the clips shown in the film, a young woman wearing Monica's beret can be seen. It reminded me a little of the situation when Alfred Hitchcock was filming "Notorious," and his Mcguffin was the uranium to make an atom bomb being hidden in wine bottles. It was entirely innocent on his part, but the FBI had him under surveillance for months wondering what he knew about the uranium stores in South America that actually existed.. Dustin Hoffman is Stanley Motss, the producer brought in by political adviser Conrad Bean (Robert DeNiro) to produce the war. Anne Heche plays a presidential aide, and the film also includes William H. Macy, Kirsten Dunst, Andrea Martin, Denis Leary, and Willie Nelson. The sad thing is that I suppose all this is possible, despite some obvious holes in the David Mamet-Hilary Henkin script. The media can certainly manipulate, and why wouldn't gullible people believe what they are being shown? Maybe it's based on the premise that the American people are fairly dumb, and if you don't agree with that, you probably won't like it. Nevertheless, "Wag the Dog" puts forth a provocative idea and gets you thinking, and it's great to see Hoffman and DeNiro as two clever albeit sleazy people who believe the end justifies the means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sly Political Satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The U.S, President has just been exposed in a sex scandal not long before the next election. Rather than resign or take responsibility, White House spin doctors(led by Robert De Nero & Anne Heche) instead contact a Hollywood producer(Dustin Hoffman, quite funny) to direct an elaborate hoaxed war with Albania, in hopes that the nation will rally behind their incumbent president, and forget/forgive the sex scandal. Things get complicated when a "war hero"(Woody Harrelson) turns out to be a psychopath, and later on when the director insists on putting it on his resume... Ingenious satire by director Barry Levinson is extremely clever & knowing, since it wouldn't be that difficult to pull off a hoax on the American people if handled properly, and had the complicity of the media behind it. Not many people to identify with here, so it is emotionally detached, but such a dead-on portrayal of media and government complicity that it doesn't matter. "Good Old Shoe" is a prime example of what I mean. Also appreciated it's non-partisanship stance, since this scenario would apply to either side.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb on every front, the script, the acting and the directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ayal Oren
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very close to perfect ten, but I won't dwell on the reasons I've got this one rated 9.5 rather than 10. I simply want to point out the aspect that most people forget when referring to this movie. Everybody notices the wit of the script, everybody notices the superb acting of Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro. Well I want to point two less noticed aspects of this movie. Anne Heche, doing a perfect job as the perfect yes woman, the counterpoint of Hoffman and De Niro, the audience of their escapades, admiring them when they work their magic, getting angry at them when it all seems to fall apart - being the exact balance against which the two are to be compared. The other hardly ever noticed aspect of this movie is the brilliant work of Barry Levinson - it's not only the guiding of every actor and every actress, not only the perfect pacing of the plot - it's the amazing control he exerts over the look of the film. The lighting and color control of this film are of the highest class ever achieved in cinema, an aspect not commonly present in American cinema who pays much more attention to the story and often neglects its design. Have one more look at this film and pay attention to the way people are getting swallowed by the background shadows or of how they emerge from these shadows and then think of the fact that the entire film is about the shadow game of politics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie and wish more people would see it, would love to see it as a remake today !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    texaschamelion
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie with my Dad when it came out on VHS. Being a very political minded man he instilled family values as well as pride for our country. We loved this movie as he also taught us when we were kids "big brother is always watching" and told us we as citizens of this nation should not walk blindly through life, take nothing for granted especially to not accept the idea that the government and media wouldn't possibly lie to us,there are reasons we do not know everything.I laughed so much during this movie and told him he was correct. I thought this movie was very well done and would absolutely love to see a remake come out in the very near future given the state of our government today and how many "sheeple" are in existence who need to wake up and see things for what they really are. I wish i had just a dollar for every time in my life i have said "all i will say is wag the dog"!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Albania's hard to rhyme"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Hollywood produced and White House sanctioned war and the hilarious marketing of their political lies carry this "truer to life than we'd like to believe" comedy. Robert DeNiro & Dustin Hoffman are up to the task and leave plenty of room for the supporting folks. Gotta love the Willie Nelson music scenes and Dennis Leary's usual train of thought shtick. The Directors' mansion voting excuse banter is priceless for those who shutter at every liberal actor speech on democracy. Barry Levinson's eventual prophetic presidency sex scandal and the result is an underrated political comedy with great entertainment legs. There is no B-3 Bomber. I don't know how these rumors get started! Uh, we do!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Nothing..........Hardly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before elections, a spin-doctor and a Hollywood producer join efforts to "fabricate" a war in order to cover-up a presidential sex scandal. If you ask me, this is nothing....hardly. This movie is hardly nothing, it is an excellent movie, a great political satire! Wag The Dog is a hilarious political satire movie, and it ranks as one of the best movies of 1997, as well as one of the best movies that Robert De Niro has made since 1995. Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro are superb in this movie, with the former getting an Oscar nomination for Best Actor. The acting in the movie is great, and the writing is witty and clever too, and renowned director Barry Levinson's directing of this movie is superb too, so this movie is pretty superb all in all! I didn't like this movie just because it had Robert De Niro in it, I enjoyed it for many other reasons too, such as the plot, he acting from Dustin Hoffman and other cast members, Barry Levinson's directing, and numerous funny scenes in the movie, such as the commercial filming scene, and the scene where Willie Nelson is told to come up with a campaign song, and many other scenes too. Robert De Niro is one of the greatest actors who has ever lived, and he's one of my favorite actors, and not only that, but this movie is one of his best since Casino. Dustin Hoffman is a great actor too, and this movie in my opinion is one of the best movies that he has ever made, but that's not the end of it, this is one of the best movies that Barry Levinson has ever directed. All in all, the entire cast and crew did a fine job at working on this great movie! By the way, a repeated line in this movie is: "This is nothing!" This movie isn't nothing, it's definitely something, it's something great, funny, as well as witty and clever! Robert De Niro is a living sensation, he can play numerous roles, he can play both serious and comedy roles, and be great in them too, as this movie is certainly proof of that, as he is great in this movie, and at the same time, he is both funny and serious, which makes things even better. This is one of those movies that you should watch whenever you are trying to forget about your troubles on Election Day, as it's a perfect political satire which gives a look at how presidential campaigns actually are, they really are operated by people working for the candidates, who uses stories to make them look good or bad. So if you are looking for a great political satire film to watch, then watch Barry Levinson's Wag The Dog, as it is one of the best and most ingenious political satires of all time! I send my applauds and congratulations to Dustin Hoffman, Robert De Niro, Barry Levinson, and the rest of the cast and crew for all of their hard work on this movie, as this movie is something, it's not nothing, it's something, something wonderful! So get ready for a political satire movie that will deliver some laughs, that's Wag The Dog, a great movie brought to you by Barry Levinson, and starring Robert De Niro and Dustin Hoffman. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Clever Satire It Purports To Be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The President is up for reelection and he gets caught in a sex scandal with a young girl. What to do? After a lot of talk among his staff, they rope in Hollywood people to create a completely phony war in Albania to distract public attention, using artificial media. Sounds hokey? Well, yes. The movie refers to Reagan's military invasion of the island nation of Grenada shortly after a terrorist bomb killed hundreds of US troops stationed in Beirut, the claim being that Reagan was trying to distract the public from the troops being killed. Never mind that the Grenada invasion was real, and certainly did not distract the news media from the Beirut bombing. Also, even in the days when the Internet wasn't widely used, there's no way a completely fictional military action would not have been exposed shortly afterward. But the movie does allow for that. They then use a convicted dangerous felon to play a soldier left behind in the supposed war, which would distract the public anew. If you can believe that a completely fictional military action would be widely reported in the major news media and somebody not quickly reveal the hoax for what it is, this movie might be for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie had a lot of potential but failed to deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D Mac
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a lot of talent wasted in this movie. I must say that my wife and had a difficult time watching it all. After 45 minutes we were no longer engaged in the story. I was expecting satire but not silly slapstick. They could have done so much with this movie and this cast. A lot of time was spent drilling down on minute aspects of the "scheme" and I felt they were flogging a point endlessly. For example, the producer wanted a kitten in a scene and several minutes was spent on him complaining until he got the kitten he was looking for. The movie develops very slowly, almost painfully so. The conflict between the conspirators and the CIA was very artificial with a conclusion that made no sense. I am guessing the idea was to make all government agencies, as well as politicians, look foolish.The movie succeeded in doing so this but in the end, the whole story was pretty foolish and lacked anything that would maintain interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have laughed more if my TV was off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Warren
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woah, woah, woah.... I'm seeing the term "brilliant satire" being tossed around in these reviews far too much. (I think I saw a comparison to Dr. Strangelove! I hope Kubrick hunts you down and punches you in the face). This was one of the worst movies I've ever seen. As for plot, it is essentially the same thing as Canadian Bacon (2 years prior, imo infinitely times funnier and smarter than this). Which is not necessarily a bad thing if it weren't so haphazardly thrown together. The movie begins a bit in medias res, and awkwardly introduces you to the situation and this Albanian idea without a single laugh. Robert Di Nero (who I usually like) is clearly just playing a poorly developed caricature of himself; Dennis Hoffman (who I love) is occasionally good for a chuckle, but the whole "producer" persona and dialogue just gets old, boring, and unrelatable after the first scene; and then there's this 'who are you?' Anne Heche character who's only purpose in the story is to praise Di Nero's character for his brilliance (cause he's not actually brilliant! O trolololol that's hilarious....) Then these characters (who we could not care less about or relate to) go on a bunch of farcical adventures, which would usually be a dynamite recipe for comedy, but again, we just don't care about or even understand these characters and their motivations Overall this movie might not be the worst satire ever, but it certainly is an awful movie  proof that good actors and a good idea cannot make up for a hideous screen play.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's funny because it's true ... it's sad for the same reasons ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's fascinating how the September 11th attacks out-dated everything, making the first Gulf War as far in memories as the Vietnam one. People are less to blame than the media-centric system that knew how to deal with the public emotion, and the key thing is that emotion has a short-term memory. George W. Bush could get away with the second Gulf War on the basis of fallacious arguments just by exploiting the September 11 trauma, and any attempt to question his choices could immediately lead to anti-patriotic accusations. And this emotional exploitation is the basis of Barry Levinson's "Wag the Dog", a hilarious satire in the same vein of sharpness than such masterpieces as "Network" or "Dr. Strangelove", and as prophetic. In August 1998, Bill Clinton confessed of having had inappropriate conduct with Monica Lewinsky, a few days later, terrorist strongholds were bombed in Africa in response to the attack of the American Embassy in Tanzania. Replace "Monica Lewinsky" by a Firefly girl, "Africa" by Albania, "Clinton" by an unknown President, and you have the basic plot of "Wag the Dog", and by 'plot', I mean the story the way it is shown on TV to the American audience. Yet "Wag the Dog" is less about the plot than the plotters. "Wag the Dog" starts with a crisis, the President has been caught with an underage girl and his opponents prepared an accusing videotape clip using 'Thank Heaven for Little Girls' as musical background, 11 days before the election, if the President's men, lead by a woman, Winifred Ames (Anne Heche) don't come up with an idea and quick, the President is screwed, and his lame "We don't change horses in midstream" campaign won't help. They call Conrad Brean, a spin-doctor; played by Robert De Niro. He comes up with the most likely idea to distract the audience from a scandal: a war, the easiest catalysis of sentimentalism and emotions through sheer patriotism. As long as people would be thirsty for magnificent displays of solidarity and humanity, incarnated by these "We are the World"-like songs, it would be easy to manipulate them. So let's start with rumors about a B3-bomber, "There's no B3-bomber", "Great, even deny its existence". Barry Levinson's film hooks us to Brean's smartness so well that we even forget that the President would indeed deserve to lose these elections. It already starts to work on us. "If the tail was smarter than the dog it would wag the dog", the dog is the audience, give them what they want and they will bite it. It's all a matter of storytelling. As a screenwriter student, I was taught that what counts the most in a story is the idea: the premise, then comes the plot, and then the storytelling, all count but it all starts with the idea. The war was the idea, but then the rest of the plot comes up very fluidly. In Albania, why? Why not? Who knows about it anyway? Who knew about Afghanistan, Iraq or Vietnam anyway? What matters is that a country shows as a potential threat, to what? To the United States, to its lifestyle, its values  the plan can't fail, the whole storyline comes us so fluidly that the scandal is almost forgotten. But we live in a media-centric society, people need images, they can't rely their emotional involvements on rumors, on unseen stuff. Time for the second protagonist of the film to make his flamboyant entrance; it's Dustin Hoffman in an electrifying performance as Stanley Motts, the producer. He's as passionate, dedicated and enthusiastic about producing as Depp in "Ed Wood" except that he has talent, and this is why the team hires him. He constructs a war with archive footage, sound effects and a young actress to play an Albanian refugee (Kirsten Dunst). People need a gimmick, like the stray cat in Vito Corleone's hands: give her a kitten. Motts understands very well how the identification process works, it asks for symbols, for colors, for memorable stuff, like the raising of the flags in Iwo-Jima or the naked girl in Vietnam. "Wag the Dog" makes us laugh for the same reasons "Network" angered us. Yet, as funny and goofy as it is, the Oscar-nominated script (the second nomination along with Hoffman) never takes its original premise for granted and takes us to unexpected and realistic twists without losing this capacity to surprise. At one point, the CIA, bought by the other side, makes a surprising statement: there's no war anymore, and Brean suddenly abandons the whole plot because it's over, how so? He "saw it on TV", TV is the Alpha and Omega; the "Network" days are not over. This is where Motts surpasses his mentor, with his unforgettable catchphrase "This is nothing", the war won't be over until he says when it's over. The war was just a pivotal moment, but like every story, you need a second pivot: how about a hostage, a war hero, a man who was kept prisoner. Abandoned like an old-shoe, how about a folk song titled "Old Shoe", a soldier whose name starts with "Shoe", like William Schumann (Woody Harrelson), you would believe this is really nothing. The saddest thing about the film is that even after watching this, the tail still wags us as we allowed many pseudo wars to happen. So even if it isn't the first political film to highlight the connection between politics and media-manipulation, it's the most related to our time. It's also a remarkably insightful film about the creative process of storytelling and a job passion, Moss is too obsessed by his talent that he'll never accept the idea of not taking credit from it, while Brean is the straight man who takes everything so normally he reminded me of another expert from a same year's movie, Tommy Lee Jones in "Men in Black", except that Brean's underworld is much scarier.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a satire, and a scary one at that
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the president is involved in scandal shortly before the election, a Hollywood producer is brought in to manufacture a war in Albania to distract from the scandal and that the President can end. "Wag the Dog" has a great premise that was prescient; before the film was released, President Clinton was involved in the sex scandal with Monica Lewinsky, and he threatened military action in Iraq. The really frightening thing is that in one of the clips shown in the film, a young woman wearing Monica's beret can be seen. It reminded me a little of the situation when Alfred Hitchcock was filming "Notorious," and his Mcguffin was the uranium to make an atom bomb being hidden in wine bottles. It was entirely innocent on his part, but the FBI had him under surveillance for months wondering what he knew about the uranium stores in South America that actually existed.. Dustin Hoffman is Stanley Motss, the producer brought in by political adviser Conrad Bean (Robert DeNiro) to produce the war. Anne Heche plays a presidential aide, and the film also includes William H. Macy, Kirsten Dunst, Andrea Martin, Denis Leary, and Willie Nelson. The sad thing is that I suppose all this is possible, despite some obvious holes in the David Mamet-Hilary Henkin script. The media can certainly manipulate, and why wouldn't gullible people believe what they are being shown? Maybe it's based on the premise that the American people are fairly dumb, and if you don't agree with that, you probably won't like it. Nevertheless, "Wag the Dog" puts forth a provocative idea and gets you thinking, and it's great to see Hoffman and DeNiro as two clever albeit sleazy people who believe the end justifies the means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sly Political Satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The U.S, President has just been exposed in a sex scandal not long before the next election. Rather than resign or take responsibility, White House spin doctors(led by Robert De Nero & Anne Heche) instead contact a Hollywood producer(Dustin Hoffman, quite funny) to direct an elaborate hoaxed war with Albania, in hopes that the nation will rally behind their incumbent president, and forget/forgive the sex scandal. Things get complicated when a "war hero"(Woody Harrelson) turns out to be a psychopath, and later on when the director insists on putting it on his resume... Ingenious satire by director Barry Levinson is extremely clever & knowing, since it wouldn't be that difficult to pull off a hoax on the American people if handled properly, and had the complicity of the media behind it. Not many people to identify with here, so it is emotionally detached, but such a dead-on portrayal of media and government complicity that it doesn't matter. "Good Old Shoe" is a prime example of what I mean. Also appreciated it's non-partisanship stance, since this scenario would apply to either side.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb on every front, the script, the acting and the directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ayal Oren
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's very close to perfect ten, but I won't dwell on the reasons I've got this one rated 9.5 rather than 10. I simply want to point out the aspect that most people forget when referring to this movie. Everybody notices the wit of the script, everybody notices the superb acting of Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro. Well I want to point two less noticed aspects of this movie. Anne Heche, doing a perfect job as the perfect yes woman, the counterpoint of Hoffman and De Niro, the audience of their escapades, admiring them when they work their magic, getting angry at them when it all seems to fall apart - being the exact balance against which the two are to be compared. The other hardly ever noticed aspect of this movie is the brilliant work of Barry Levinson - it's not only the guiding of every actor and every actress, not only the perfect pacing of the plot - it's the amazing control he exerts over the look of the film. The lighting and color control of this film are of the highest class ever achieved in cinema, an aspect not commonly present in American cinema who pays much more attention to the story and often neglects its design. Have one more look at this film and pay attention to the way people are getting swallowed by the background shadows or of how they emerge from these shadows and then think of the fact that the entire film is about the shadow game of politics.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie and wish more people would see it, would love to see it as a remake today !!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    texaschamelion
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie with my Dad when it came out on VHS. Being a very political minded man he instilled family values as well as pride for our country. We loved this movie as he also taught us when we were kids "big brother is always watching" and told us we as citizens of this nation should not walk blindly through life, take nothing for granted especially to not accept the idea that the government and media wouldn't possibly lie to us,there are reasons we do not know everything.I laughed so much during this movie and told him he was correct. I thought this movie was very well done and would absolutely love to see a remake come out in the very near future given the state of our government today and how many "sheeple" are in existence who need to wake up and see things for what they really are. I wish i had just a dollar for every time in my life i have said "all i will say is wag the dog"!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Albania's hard to rhyme"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Hollywood produced and White House sanctioned war and the hilarious marketing of their political lies carry this "truer to life than we'd like to believe" comedy. Robert DeNiro & Dustin Hoffman are up to the task and leave plenty of room for the supporting folks. Gotta love the Willie Nelson music scenes and Dennis Leary's usual train of thought shtick. The Directors' mansion voting excuse banter is priceless for those who shutter at every liberal actor speech on democracy. Barry Levinson's eventual prophetic presidency sex scandal and the result is an underrated political comedy with great entertainment legs. There is no B-3 Bomber. I don't know how these rumors get started! Uh, we do!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is Nothing..........Hardly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before elections, a spin-doctor and a Hollywood producer join efforts to "fabricate" a war in order to cover-up a presidential sex scandal. If you ask me, this is nothing....hardly. This movie is hardly nothing, it is an excellent movie, a great political satire! Wag The Dog is a hilarious political satire movie, and it ranks as one of the best movies of 1997, as well as one of the best movies that Robert De Niro has made since 1995. Dustin Hoffman and Robert De Niro are superb in this movie, with the former getting an Oscar nomination for Best Actor. The acting in the movie is great, and the writing is witty and clever too, and renowned director Barry Levinson's directing of this movie is superb too, so this movie is pretty superb all in all! I didn't like this movie just because it had Robert De Niro in it, I enjoyed it for many other reasons too, such as the plot, he acting from Dustin Hoffman and other cast members, Barry Levinson's directing, and numerous funny scenes in the movie, such as the commercial filming scene, and the scene where Willie Nelson is told to come up with a campaign song, and many other scenes too. Robert De Niro is one of the greatest actors who has ever lived, and he's one of my favorite actors, and not only that, but this movie is one of his best since Casino. Dustin Hoffman is a great actor too, and this movie in my opinion is one of the best movies that he has ever made, but that's not the end of it, this is one of the best movies that Barry Levinson has ever directed. All in all, the entire cast and crew did a fine job at working on this great movie! By the way, a repeated line in this movie is: "This is nothing!" This movie isn't nothing, it's definitely something, it's something great, funny, as well as witty and clever! Robert De Niro is a living sensation, he can play numerous roles, he can play both serious and comedy roles, and be great in them too, as this movie is certainly proof of that, as he is great in this movie, and at the same time, he is both funny and serious, which makes things even better. This is one of those movies that you should watch whenever you are trying to forget about your troubles on Election Day, as it's a perfect political satire which gives a look at how presidential campaigns actually are, they really are operated by people working for the candidates, who uses stories to make them look good or bad. So if you are looking for a great political satire film to watch, then watch Barry Levinson's Wag The Dog, as it is one of the best and most ingenious political satires of all time! I send my applauds and congratulations to Dustin Hoffman, Robert De Niro, Barry Levinson, and the rest of the cast and crew for all of their hard work on this movie, as this movie is something, it's not nothing, it's something, something wonderful! So get ready for a political satire movie that will deliver some laughs, that's Wag The Dog, a great movie brought to you by Barry Levinson, and starring Robert De Niro and Dustin Hoffman. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not The Clever Satire It Purports To Be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The President is up for reelection and he gets caught in a sex scandal with a young girl. What to do? After a lot of talk among his staff, they rope in Hollywood people to create a completely phony war in Albania to distract public attention, using artificial media. Sounds hokey? Well, yes. The movie refers to Reagan's military invasion of the island nation of Grenada shortly after a terrorist bomb killed hundreds of US troops stationed in Beirut, the claim being that Reagan was trying to distract the public from the troops being killed. Never mind that the Grenada invasion was real, and certainly did not distract the news media from the Beirut bombing. Also, even in the days when the Internet wasn't widely used, there's no way a completely fictional military action would not have been exposed shortly afterward. But the movie does allow for that. They then use a convicted dangerous felon to play a soldier left behind in the supposed war, which would distract the public anew. If you can believe that a completely fictional military action would be widely reported in the major news media and somebody not quickly reveal the hoax for what it is, this movie might be for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie had a lot of potential but failed to deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D Mac
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a lot of talent wasted in this movie. I must say that my wife and had a difficult time watching it all. After 45 minutes we were no longer engaged in the story. I was expecting satire but not silly slapstick. They could have done so much with this movie and this cast. A lot of time was spent drilling down on minute aspects of the "scheme" and I felt they were flogging a point endlessly. For example, the producer wanted a kitten in a scene and several minutes was spent on him complaining until he got the kitten he was looking for. The movie develops very slowly, almost painfully so. The conflict between the conspirators and the CIA was very artificial with a conclusion that made no sense. I am guessing the idea was to make all government agencies, as well as politicians, look foolish.The movie succeeded in doing so this but in the end, the whole story was pretty foolish and lacked anything that would maintain interest.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would have laughed more if my TV was off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Warren
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Woah, woah, woah.... I'm seeing the term "brilliant satire" being tossed around in these reviews far too much. (I think I saw a comparison to Dr. Strangelove! I hope Kubrick hunts you down and punches you in the face). This was one of the worst movies I've ever seen. As for plot, it is essentially the same thing as Canadian Bacon (2 years prior, imo infinitely times funnier and smarter than this). Which is not necessarily a bad thing if it weren't so haphazardly thrown together. The movie begins a bit in medias res, and awkwardly introduces you to the situation and this Albanian idea without a single laugh. Robert Di Nero (who I usually like) is clearly just playing a poorly developed caricature of himself; Dennis Hoffman (who I love) is occasionally good for a chuckle, but the whole "producer" persona and dialogue just gets old, boring, and unrelatable after the first scene; and then there's this 'who are you?' Anne Heche character who's only purpose in the story is to praise Di Nero's character for his brilliance (cause he's not actually brilliant! O trolololol that's hilarious....) Then these characters (who we could not care less about or relate to) go on a bunch of farcical adventures, which would usually be a dynamite recipe for comedy, but again, we just don't care about or even understand these characters and their motivations Overall this movie might not be the worst satire ever, but it certainly is an awful movie  proof that good actors and a good idea cannot make up for a hideous screen play.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's funny because it's true ... it's sad for the same reasons ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's fascinating how the September 11th attacks out-dated everything, making the first Gulf War as far in memories as the Vietnam one. People are less to blame than the media-centric system that knew how to deal with the public emotion, and the key thing is that emotion has a short-term memory. George W. Bush could get away with the second Gulf War on the basis of fallacious arguments just by exploiting the September 11 trauma, and any attempt to question his choices could immediately lead to anti-patriotic accusations. And this emotional exploitation is the basis of Barry Levinson's "Wag the Dog", a hilarious satire in the same vein of sharpness than such masterpieces as "Network" or "Dr. Strangelove", and as prophetic. In August 1998, Bill Clinton confessed of having had inappropriate conduct with Monica Lewinsky, a few days later, terrorist strongholds were bombed in Africa in response to the attack of the American Embassy in Tanzania. Replace "Monica Lewinsky" by a Firefly girl, "Africa" by Albania, "Clinton" by an unknown President, and you have the basic plot of "Wag the Dog", and by 'plot', I mean the story the way it is shown on TV to the American audience. Yet "Wag the Dog" is less about the plot than the plotters. "Wag the Dog" starts with a crisis, the President has been caught with an underage girl and his opponents prepared an accusing videotape clip using 'Thank Heaven for Little Girls' as musical background, 11 days before the election, if the President's men, lead by a woman, Winifred Ames (Anne Heche) don't come up with an idea and quick, the President is screwed, and his lame "We don't change horses in midstream" campaign won't help. They call Conrad Brean, a spin-doctor; played by Robert De Niro. He comes up with the most likely idea to distract the audience from a scandal: a war, the easiest catalysis of sentimentalism and emotions through sheer patriotism. As long as people would be thirsty for magnificent displays of solidarity and humanity, incarnated by these "We are the World"-like songs, it would be easy to manipulate them. So let's start with rumors about a B3-bomber, "There's no B3-bomber", "Great, even deny its existence". Barry Levinson's film hooks us to Brean's smartness so well that we even forget that the President would indeed deserve to lose these elections. It already starts to work on us. "If the tail was smarter than the dog it would wag the dog", the dog is the audience, give them what they want and they will bite it. It's all a matter of storytelling. As a screenwriter student, I was taught that what counts the most in a story is the idea: the premise, then comes the plot, and then the storytelling, all count but it all starts with the idea. The war was the idea, but then the rest of the plot comes up very fluidly. In Albania, why? Why not? Who knows about it anyway? Who knew about Afghanistan, Iraq or Vietnam anyway? What matters is that a country shows as a potential threat, to what? To the United States, to its lifestyle, its values  the plan can't fail, the whole storyline comes us so fluidly that the scandal is almost forgotten. But we live in a media-centric society, people need images, they can't rely their emotional involvements on rumors, on unseen stuff. Time for the second protagonist of the film to make his flamboyant entrance; it's Dustin Hoffman in an electrifying performance as Stanley Motts, the producer. He's as passionate, dedicated and enthusiastic about producing as Depp in "Ed Wood" except that he has talent, and this is why the team hires him. He constructs a war with archive footage, sound effects and a young actress to play an Albanian refugee (Kirsten Dunst). People need a gimmick, like the stray cat in Vito Corleone's hands: give her a kitten. Motts understands very well how the identification process works, it asks for symbols, for colors, for memorable stuff, like the raising of the flags in Iwo-Jima or the naked girl in Vietnam. "Wag the Dog" makes us laugh for the same reasons "Network" angered us. Yet, as funny and goofy as it is, the Oscar-nominated script (the second nomination along with Hoffman) never takes its original premise for granted and takes us to unexpected and realistic twists without losing this capacity to surprise. At one point, the CIA, bought by the other side, makes a surprising statement: there's no war anymore, and Brean suddenly abandons the whole plot because it's over, how so? He "saw it on TV", TV is the Alpha and Omega; the "Network" days are not over. This is where Motts surpasses his mentor, with his unforgettable catchphrase "This is nothing", the war won't be over until he says when it's over. The war was just a pivotal moment, but like every story, you need a second pivot: how about a hostage, a war hero, a man who was kept prisoner. Abandoned like an old-shoe, how about a folk song titled "Old Shoe", a soldier whose name starts with "Shoe", like William Schumann (Woody Harrelson), you would believe this is really nothing. The saddest thing about the film is that even after watching this, the tail still wags us as we allowed many pseudo wars to happen. So even if it isn't the first political film to highlight the connection between politics and media-manipulation, it's the most related to our time. It's also a remarkably insightful film about the creative process of storytelling and a job passion, Moss is too obsessed by his talent that he'll never accept the idea of not taking credit from it, while Brean is the straight man who takes everything so normally he reminded me of another expert from a same year's movie, Tommy Lee Jones in "Men in Black", except that Brean's underworld is much scarier.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a satire, and a scary one at that
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the president is involved in scandal shortly before the election, a Hollywood producer is brought in to manufacture a war in Albania to distract from the scandal and that the President can end. "Wag the Dog" has a great premise that was prescient; before the film was released, President Clinton was involved in the sex scandal with Monica Lewinsky, and he threatened military action in Iraq. The really frightening thing is that in one of the clips shown in the film, a young woman wearing Monica's beret can be seen. It reminded me a little of the situation when Alfred Hitchcock was filming "Notorious," and his Mcguffin was the uranium to make an atom bomb being hidden in wine bottles. It was entirely innocent on his part, but the FBI had him under surveillance for months wondering what he knew about the uranium stores in South America that actually existed.. Dustin Hoffman is Stanley Motss, the producer brought in by political adviser Conrad Bean (Robert DeNiro) to produce the war. Anne Heche plays a presidential aide, and the film also includes William H. Macy, Kirsten Dunst, Andrea Martin, Denis Leary, and Willie Nelson. The sad thing is that I suppose all this is possible, despite some obvious holes in the David Mamet-Hilary Henkin script. The media can certainly manipulate, and why wouldn't gullible people believe what they are being shown? Maybe it's based on the premise that the American people are fairly dumb, and if you don't agree with that, you probably won't like it. Nevertheless, "Wag the Dog" puts forth a provocative idea and gets you thinking, and it's great to see Hoffman and DeNiro as two clever albeit sleazy people who believe the end justifies the means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
