<filme>
 <id>
  352
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120185
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Mundo das Spice Girls
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  3.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  World famous pop group The Spice Girls zip around London in their luxurious double decker tour bus having various adventures and performing for their fans.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Climb aboard the double decker Spice Bus and get ready for a madcap musical adventure with the sexy phenomenons of pop - the Spice Girls. An encounter with extra-terrestrials, a night in a haunted castle, and a moment of truth in a maternity ward are just a few of the escapades the endeavored upon as the Girls gear up for their first live concert at London's Royal Albert Hall.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   concert
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   spice girl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bus
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tabloid
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pregnant
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Bob Spiers
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Spice Girls
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Kim Fuller
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Melanie Brown
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Emma Bunton
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Melanie Chisholm
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teenybopper's Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I'm a 51 year old guy, and know this movie is (mostly) for teen girls, but I thought it was fun, especially when cute Emma Bunton and hot Victoria Adams (Beckham) were on screen. The S-Girls travel the world on their cool British bus show-casing their music (and their voluptuous bodies) and helping humankind get through the proverbial trials and tribulations of daily life. They even help deliver a baby! Wow! These chicks can do everything! Good songs, solid choreography, and a colorful presentation boosts this movie above Mundanesville. Cool movie, but cameos by John Elton and Hamburger Loaf were not needed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So What Do You Want? How About An Actual Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spice World (1997) 1/2 (out of 4) This here is pretty much a variation on A HARD DAY'S NIGHT but this time instead of John, Paul, George and Ringo we get Baby, Sporty, Ginger, Posh and Scary. Most movies made feature a credit that will read something to the effect of "story by..." but not this one. No, that credit is actually replaced by one that reads "idea by..." and that pretty much tells you everything you need to know. Really? The biggest pop female pop band that the world has ever seen and one that apparently made between $600-$800 million can only come up with a movie based on an idea? I guess it really doesn't matter that SPICE WORLD has been called one of the worst movies ever made because their fans ate it up when it was released and apparently they are still very fond of it. I guess if I was a die-hard fan of the group then I'd enjoy seeing them in anything no matter how bad it actually was. What makes this film so bad is that there really doesn't seem to be any idea of what this movie is supposed to be about. I'm sure it was an attempt to milk the success of the band and that's understandable. I just wish we had actually gotten a backstage look at the lives they were going through or at least gave us some sort of realistic look at the band. Instead we basically just get one long music video where the girls play their music and get to try on many different outfits. Nothing the five girls say are funny. Nothing they say is very interesting. In fact, nothing they do is all that entertaining. The movie actually reaches a level where it becomes painful to sit through it any longer. Heck, the girls can even lip-sync their songs and that well. SPICE WORLD doesn't quite earn a BOMB ranking thanks in large part to the girls being cute and wearing tight clothes but you can look at a magazine for this. The film itself is quite bad and sadly it never reaches a level to where you can just laugh at it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant fun movie for any Spice Girls fan!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexstinks
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film so much! I was brought up in the 90s listening to the Spice Girls and I was obsessed with them! I remember a family member bought me this on VHS and I loved it! It was just fun! Clearly it's not the type of movie that's supposed to be taken seriously. It is just supposed to be more of a spoof movie about the Spice Girls! I love the songs, costumes, crazy scenes! I also really enjoyed the cameo appearances from Meatloaf, Elton John and co. It was exciting for my as a child watching this. I love it even now! Brings back great memories! I can't fault it for what it is! It is just a piece of light hearted fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have heard nothing but negative things for this movie. But A friend of mine on YouTube named Cinema Sickness recommended this movie. So I bought it for a whopping 25 cents and here are my thoughts. The film is just about the 5 Spice Girls who try to help their friend deliver her first baby all while they are trying to get ready for a very big live performance. This is pretty stupid but you know what I had a lot of fun with it. If you are taking this movie to seriously well than you are not going to have any fun with any other movie. Although it is a very strange idea to make a movie about the Spice Girls. But Hey they made a movie about Hannah Montana and Justin Bieber so anything is possible.Plus I think that this movie is a little to risqu&eacute; for a PG Rating. I say check out this movie for some fun. This review is dedicated to Cinema Sickness(Your Welcome);). Rated PG For Some Vulgarity, Brief Nudity And Language. 1hr 33min/93min. ***1/2/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The oldest profession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Easton
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once upon a time there were The Spice Girls. They introduced us to 'girl power', a thinly disguised effort to use sex to sell manufactured pop music, potato chips and fizzy drinks to little kids and morons. And then there was this travesty of a movie. This is very much like other exploitation movies made to cash in on popular music groups in the past, but with all the good elements removed. There is nothing redeemable about this whatsoever, it's pure trash, and since the 'music' of The Spice Girls has no longevity neither does this. If you want to pick this up along with the girl's entire back catalogue of CDs, I recommend checking out the bargain bins in charity shops. You shouldn't have a problem finding it all, and then at least something positive will have come out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Gem - You need to look closely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanja_van_huet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was doubtful about this movie but my daughter insisted we watch it together. I was amazed at how art house it was  with throw backs to the old Beatles movie genre and other madcap '70's and 80's productions (Thunderbirds, the Monkees, etc). Apart from the catchy music and the generally enjoyable overacting  the all star cast makes it a genuine 'spot the actor' vehicle. (For example: this from http://filmbabble. blogspot.com/2007/06/20 -great-modern-movie-cameos.html : "Elvis Costello as a bartender and credited as 'Himself' Costello plays a nice tongue-in-cheek note as the Girls talk about their possible flash-in-the-pan prospects".) It spoofs everything about those bad movies we loved to watch  model buses jumping over model bridges, E.T. (the Movie) in 'bad green coats', the Magical Mystery Tour amazing bus, media moguls (Rupert Murdoch anyone?), Hollywood 'run and go' action movies, over-sexed Italian dancers etc. The more I watched the more I saw. I drove my daughter crazy pointing out ... 'hey that is a takeoff from ...'. If you are studying cinema or just have a movie trivia interest, Spice World certainly gives you more to argue about than Citizen Kain (sorry Orsen) or Pret-a-Porter (apologies to Robert too). If this movie was written by the Directors wife  she was a movie buff. It is better than you think!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool off the spice girls...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charlotte Younge
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, like all you fellow IMDb members, I'm a lover of a movies. But once in a while, a film like this should be making people laugh, not moan about the million things wrong with it. I haven't watched this flick in ages, but yesterday I was in a "take-a-look-at-stuff-from-the-past" mood, found the tape whilst doing my spring cleaning, and so I popped the tape in. I was a little biased the last time I watched it, being an 8 year old Spice Girls fanatic, but this time I took the film into serious consideration. Don't you get it? It's a satire about film making... And with the fabulous cameos (Elvis Costello, Elton John, MEATLOAF!! just to name a few..)how could you not love it? Just a teensy bit? Trust me, the British know film, and they know what they're doing with this one. Instead of showing one "real" side of the spice girls, they've shoved 50 years of stereotypical rubbish into one movie. You've got people trying to make a movie, a documentary, and the tabloids trying to break the girls apart, along with aliens, hot Italian models and random deja vus. All in one. So, cool off IMDb... if you don't take yourself too seriously and want to step back into the 90s for a good laugh, watch this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and light! A Good feel movie about Pop stars lives...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alain-aouad
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has everything related to the pop life in it, a comedic thrilling ride in the lives of a pop star band! The paparazzi, the fame, the fans, the back clash, the media, the managers, the shows and of course the greatest girl band the world has and will ever see: The Spice Girls! The Spice girls in a way gathered all the pop life elements in their movie, mocking even themselves, they tried to show the world that this is all a fun ride and you must enjoy every minute of it while it lasts, and this is what they did in their 2 years world domination rally! You can't watch this movie though if you're a pop music or Spice Girls hater, if you are into pop and into light comedy and cheesy jokes then this movie is for your eyes only (a little wink to Roger Moore's cameo). Relax, get your best friend with whom you spent most of the 90's hearing ace of base and Take that on your CD player and enjoy this movie for old times sake! Now the acting, the plot, the script etc... They all fade into the background when you've got the Spice girls up front doing their thing! So stop complaining about this movie, it is not just another Oscar Submission, its supposed to be a funny ride and a silly joke for God's sake, lighten up and enjoy it for what it is!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The good, the bad, the Spice World movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dancingqueensw4
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a bit of a film fanatic, I was always of the opinion that no matter what the film, good or bad, it's worth watching. You can delight in the great ones and laugh at the ones that were really really awful. This film changed that opinion. I tried, but unlike any other film, I could not find it funny that I wasted my time watching it. It has NO plot. The acting was not just bad, it was so bad it made their singing ability look good... and they were playing themselves! Really, how hard can that be? Don't get me wrong, I'm aware it was suppose to be silly and not taken seriously, but I'm pretty sure it was also suppose to be entertaining... which it wasn't. It just bounced from boring scene to boring scene not linking them in anyway. Even if you like the spice girls, no amount of nostalgia would be worth watching this film. If you're looking for a walk down memory lane your better off watching Bugsy Malone, Labyrinth, Moonwalker, pretty much anything from the early 90s. Besides, this film made me forget what I liked about the spice girls in the first place. After watching this film, I went from a secret fan, to seeing the spice girls as the people that got me to spend my time and money on the worst film ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Spiced Up My Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tiffxrawr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film when I was seven and I still love it today. I think that for any Spice Girls fan, this was a great movie. The acting may not have been Oscar worthy, but I feel they did a great job making their audience laugh acting as themselves. Though some of the scenes could be considered corny or out of place, this film was overall very entertaining to its target audience: the fans. It is not for everyone. Just as I will never love the movie Purple Rain as much as my mother did due to her generation's love for Prince, not many will love Spice World the way Spice Girls fans do. The Spice Girls were positive role models in the 90's for girls like me. Scary Spice inspired me to love my huge curly hair. Sporty Spice inspired me to embrace my inner tom-boy. Their songs were catchy and widely popular for a while. Their movie venture may not have been as successful as their songs. However, it was not a total flop. Spice World had a wacky but interesting story line and a few compelling sub-story lines. This will always be considered one of my favorite movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teenybopper's Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I'm a 51 year old guy, and know this movie is (mostly) for teen girls, but I thought it was fun, especially when cute Emma Bunton and hot Victoria Adams (Beckham) were on screen. The S-Girls travel the world on their cool British bus show-casing their music (and their voluptuous bodies) and helping humankind get through the proverbial trials and tribulations of daily life. They even help deliver a baby! Wow! These chicks can do everything! Good songs, solid choreography, and a colorful presentation boosts this movie above Mundanesville. Cool movie, but cameos by John Elton and Hamburger Loaf were not needed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So What Do You Want? How About An Actual Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spice World (1997) 1/2 (out of 4) This here is pretty much a variation on A HARD DAY'S NIGHT but this time instead of John, Paul, George and Ringo we get Baby, Sporty, Ginger, Posh and Scary. Most movies made feature a credit that will read something to the effect of "story by..." but not this one. No, that credit is actually replaced by one that reads "idea by..." and that pretty much tells you everything you need to know. Really? The biggest pop female pop band that the world has ever seen and one that apparently made between $600-$800 million can only come up with a movie based on an idea? I guess it really doesn't matter that SPICE WORLD has been called one of the worst movies ever made because their fans ate it up when it was released and apparently they are still very fond of it. I guess if I was a die-hard fan of the group then I'd enjoy seeing them in anything no matter how bad it actually was. What makes this film so bad is that there really doesn't seem to be any idea of what this movie is supposed to be about. I'm sure it was an attempt to milk the success of the band and that's understandable. I just wish we had actually gotten a backstage look at the lives they were going through or at least gave us some sort of realistic look at the band. Instead we basically just get one long music video where the girls play their music and get to try on many different outfits. Nothing the five girls say are funny. Nothing they say is very interesting. In fact, nothing they do is all that entertaining. The movie actually reaches a level where it becomes painful to sit through it any longer. Heck, the girls can even lip-sync their songs and that well. SPICE WORLD doesn't quite earn a BOMB ranking thanks in large part to the girls being cute and wearing tight clothes but you can look at a magazine for this. The film itself is quite bad and sadly it never reaches a level to where you can just laugh at it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant fun movie for any Spice Girls fan!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexstinks
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film so much! I was brought up in the 90s listening to the Spice Girls and I was obsessed with them! I remember a family member bought me this on VHS and I loved it! It was just fun! Clearly it's not the type of movie that's supposed to be taken seriously. It is just supposed to be more of a spoof movie about the Spice Girls! I love the songs, costumes, crazy scenes! I also really enjoyed the cameo appearances from Meatloaf, Elton John and co. It was exciting for my as a child watching this. I love it even now! Brings back great memories! I can't fault it for what it is! It is just a piece of light hearted fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have heard nothing but negative things for this movie. But A friend of mine on YouTube named Cinema Sickness recommended this movie. So I bought it for a whopping 25 cents and here are my thoughts. The film is just about the 5 Spice Girls who try to help their friend deliver her first baby all while they are trying to get ready for a very big live performance. This is pretty stupid but you know what I had a lot of fun with it. If you are taking this movie to seriously well than you are not going to have any fun with any other movie. Although it is a very strange idea to make a movie about the Spice Girls. But Hey they made a movie about Hannah Montana and Justin Bieber so anything is possible.Plus I think that this movie is a little to risqu&eacute; for a PG Rating. I say check out this movie for some fun. This review is dedicated to Cinema Sickness(Your Welcome);). Rated PG For Some Vulgarity, Brief Nudity And Language. 1hr 33min/93min. ***1/2/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The oldest profession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Easton
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once upon a time there were The Spice Girls. They introduced us to 'girl power', a thinly disguised effort to use sex to sell manufactured pop music, potato chips and fizzy drinks to little kids and morons. And then there was this travesty of a movie. This is very much like other exploitation movies made to cash in on popular music groups in the past, but with all the good elements removed. There is nothing redeemable about this whatsoever, it's pure trash, and since the 'music' of The Spice Girls has no longevity neither does this. If you want to pick this up along with the girl's entire back catalogue of CDs, I recommend checking out the bargain bins in charity shops. You shouldn't have a problem finding it all, and then at least something positive will have come out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Gem - You need to look closely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanja_van_huet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was doubtful about this movie but my daughter insisted we watch it together. I was amazed at how art house it was  with throw backs to the old Beatles movie genre and other madcap '70's and 80's productions (Thunderbirds, the Monkees, etc). Apart from the catchy music and the generally enjoyable overacting  the all star cast makes it a genuine 'spot the actor' vehicle. (For example: this from http://filmbabble. blogspot.com/2007/06/20 -great-modern-movie-cameos.html : "Elvis Costello as a bartender and credited as 'Himself' Costello plays a nice tongue-in-cheek note as the Girls talk about their possible flash-in-the-pan prospects".) It spoofs everything about those bad movies we loved to watch  model buses jumping over model bridges, E.T. (the Movie) in 'bad green coats', the Magical Mystery Tour amazing bus, media moguls (Rupert Murdoch anyone?), Hollywood 'run and go' action movies, over-sexed Italian dancers etc. The more I watched the more I saw. I drove my daughter crazy pointing out ... 'hey that is a takeoff from ...'. If you are studying cinema or just have a movie trivia interest, Spice World certainly gives you more to argue about than Citizen Kain (sorry Orsen) or Pret-a-Porter (apologies to Robert too). If this movie was written by the Directors wife  she was a movie buff. It is better than you think!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool off the spice girls...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charlotte Younge
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, like all you fellow IMDb members, I'm a lover of a movies. But once in a while, a film like this should be making people laugh, not moan about the million things wrong with it. I haven't watched this flick in ages, but yesterday I was in a "take-a-look-at-stuff-from-the-past" mood, found the tape whilst doing my spring cleaning, and so I popped the tape in. I was a little biased the last time I watched it, being an 8 year old Spice Girls fanatic, but this time I took the film into serious consideration. Don't you get it? It's a satire about film making... And with the fabulous cameos (Elvis Costello, Elton John, MEATLOAF!! just to name a few..)how could you not love it? Just a teensy bit? Trust me, the British know film, and they know what they're doing with this one. Instead of showing one "real" side of the spice girls, they've shoved 50 years of stereotypical rubbish into one movie. You've got people trying to make a movie, a documentary, and the tabloids trying to break the girls apart, along with aliens, hot Italian models and random deja vus. All in one. So, cool off IMDb... if you don't take yourself too seriously and want to step back into the 90s for a good laugh, watch this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and light! A Good feel movie about Pop stars lives...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alain-aouad
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has everything related to the pop life in it, a comedic thrilling ride in the lives of a pop star band! The paparazzi, the fame, the fans, the back clash, the media, the managers, the shows and of course the greatest girl band the world has and will ever see: The Spice Girls! The Spice girls in a way gathered all the pop life elements in their movie, mocking even themselves, they tried to show the world that this is all a fun ride and you must enjoy every minute of it while it lasts, and this is what they did in their 2 years world domination rally! You can't watch this movie though if you're a pop music or Spice Girls hater, if you are into pop and into light comedy and cheesy jokes then this movie is for your eyes only (a little wink to Roger Moore's cameo). Relax, get your best friend with whom you spent most of the 90's hearing ace of base and Take that on your CD player and enjoy this movie for old times sake! Now the acting, the plot, the script etc... They all fade into the background when you've got the Spice girls up front doing their thing! So stop complaining about this movie, it is not just another Oscar Submission, its supposed to be a funny ride and a silly joke for God's sake, lighten up and enjoy it for what it is!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The good, the bad, the Spice World movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dancingqueensw4
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a bit of a film fanatic, I was always of the opinion that no matter what the film, good or bad, it's worth watching. You can delight in the great ones and laugh at the ones that were really really awful. This film changed that opinion. I tried, but unlike any other film, I could not find it funny that I wasted my time watching it. It has NO plot. The acting was not just bad, it was so bad it made their singing ability look good... and they were playing themselves! Really, how hard can that be? Don't get me wrong, I'm aware it was suppose to be silly and not taken seriously, but I'm pretty sure it was also suppose to be entertaining... which it wasn't. It just bounced from boring scene to boring scene not linking them in anyway. Even if you like the spice girls, no amount of nostalgia would be worth watching this film. If you're looking for a walk down memory lane your better off watching Bugsy Malone, Labyrinth, Moonwalker, pretty much anything from the early 90s. Besides, this film made me forget what I liked about the spice girls in the first place. After watching this film, I went from a secret fan, to seeing the spice girls as the people that got me to spend my time and money on the worst film ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Spiced Up My Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tiffxrawr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film when I was seven and I still love it today. I think that for any Spice Girls fan, this was a great movie. The acting may not have been Oscar worthy, but I feel they did a great job making their audience laugh acting as themselves. Though some of the scenes could be considered corny or out of place, this film was overall very entertaining to its target audience: the fans. It is not for everyone. Just as I will never love the movie Purple Rain as much as my mother did due to her generation's love for Prince, not many will love Spice World the way Spice Girls fans do. The Spice Girls were positive role models in the 90's for girls like me. Scary Spice inspired me to love my huge curly hair. Sporty Spice inspired me to embrace my inner tom-boy. Their songs were catchy and widely popular for a while. Their movie venture may not have been as successful as their songs. However, it was not a total flop. Spice World had a wacky but interesting story line and a few compelling sub-story lines. This will always be considered one of my favorite movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teenybopper's Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I'm a 51 year old guy, and know this movie is (mostly) for teen girls, but I thought it was fun, especially when cute Emma Bunton and hot Victoria Adams (Beckham) were on screen. The S-Girls travel the world on their cool British bus show-casing their music (and their voluptuous bodies) and helping humankind get through the proverbial trials and tribulations of daily life. They even help deliver a baby! Wow! These chicks can do everything! Good songs, solid choreography, and a colorful presentation boosts this movie above Mundanesville. Cool movie, but cameos by John Elton and Hamburger Loaf were not needed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So What Do You Want? How About An Actual Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spice World (1997) 1/2 (out of 4) This here is pretty much a variation on A HARD DAY'S NIGHT but this time instead of John, Paul, George and Ringo we get Baby, Sporty, Ginger, Posh and Scary. Most movies made feature a credit that will read something to the effect of "story by..." but not this one. No, that credit is actually replaced by one that reads "idea by..." and that pretty much tells you everything you need to know. Really? The biggest pop female pop band that the world has ever seen and one that apparently made between $600-$800 million can only come up with a movie based on an idea? I guess it really doesn't matter that SPICE WORLD has been called one of the worst movies ever made because their fans ate it up when it was released and apparently they are still very fond of it. I guess if I was a die-hard fan of the group then I'd enjoy seeing them in anything no matter how bad it actually was. What makes this film so bad is that there really doesn't seem to be any idea of what this movie is supposed to be about. I'm sure it was an attempt to milk the success of the band and that's understandable. I just wish we had actually gotten a backstage look at the lives they were going through or at least gave us some sort of realistic look at the band. Instead we basically just get one long music video where the girls play their music and get to try on many different outfits. Nothing the five girls say are funny. Nothing they say is very interesting. In fact, nothing they do is all that entertaining. The movie actually reaches a level where it becomes painful to sit through it any longer. Heck, the girls can even lip-sync their songs and that well. SPICE WORLD doesn't quite earn a BOMB ranking thanks in large part to the girls being cute and wearing tight clothes but you can look at a magazine for this. The film itself is quite bad and sadly it never reaches a level to where you can just laugh at it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant fun movie for any Spice Girls fan!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexstinks
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film so much! I was brought up in the 90s listening to the Spice Girls and I was obsessed with them! I remember a family member bought me this on VHS and I loved it! It was just fun! Clearly it's not the type of movie that's supposed to be taken seriously. It is just supposed to be more of a spoof movie about the Spice Girls! I love the songs, costumes, crazy scenes! I also really enjoyed the cameo appearances from Meatloaf, Elton John and co. It was exciting for my as a child watching this. I love it even now! Brings back great memories! I can't fault it for what it is! It is just a piece of light hearted fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have heard nothing but negative things for this movie. But A friend of mine on YouTube named Cinema Sickness recommended this movie. So I bought it for a whopping 25 cents and here are my thoughts. The film is just about the 5 Spice Girls who try to help their friend deliver her first baby all while they are trying to get ready for a very big live performance. This is pretty stupid but you know what I had a lot of fun with it. If you are taking this movie to seriously well than you are not going to have any fun with any other movie. Although it is a very strange idea to make a movie about the Spice Girls. But Hey they made a movie about Hannah Montana and Justin Bieber so anything is possible.Plus I think that this movie is a little to risqu&eacute; for a PG Rating. I say check out this movie for some fun. This review is dedicated to Cinema Sickness(Your Welcome);). Rated PG For Some Vulgarity, Brief Nudity And Language. 1hr 33min/93min. ***1/2/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The oldest profession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Easton
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once upon a time there were The Spice Girls. They introduced us to 'girl power', a thinly disguised effort to use sex to sell manufactured pop music, potato chips and fizzy drinks to little kids and morons. And then there was this travesty of a movie. This is very much like other exploitation movies made to cash in on popular music groups in the past, but with all the good elements removed. There is nothing redeemable about this whatsoever, it's pure trash, and since the 'music' of The Spice Girls has no longevity neither does this. If you want to pick this up along with the girl's entire back catalogue of CDs, I recommend checking out the bargain bins in charity shops. You shouldn't have a problem finding it all, and then at least something positive will have come out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Gem - You need to look closely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanja_van_huet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was doubtful about this movie but my daughter insisted we watch it together. I was amazed at how art house it was  with throw backs to the old Beatles movie genre and other madcap '70's and 80's productions (Thunderbirds, the Monkees, etc). Apart from the catchy music and the generally enjoyable overacting  the all star cast makes it a genuine 'spot the actor' vehicle. (For example: this from http://filmbabble. blogspot.com/2007/06/20 -great-modern-movie-cameos.html : "Elvis Costello as a bartender and credited as 'Himself' Costello plays a nice tongue-in-cheek note as the Girls talk about their possible flash-in-the-pan prospects".) It spoofs everything about those bad movies we loved to watch  model buses jumping over model bridges, E.T. (the Movie) in 'bad green coats', the Magical Mystery Tour amazing bus, media moguls (Rupert Murdoch anyone?), Hollywood 'run and go' action movies, over-sexed Italian dancers etc. The more I watched the more I saw. I drove my daughter crazy pointing out ... 'hey that is a takeoff from ...'. If you are studying cinema or just have a movie trivia interest, Spice World certainly gives you more to argue about than Citizen Kain (sorry Orsen) or Pret-a-Porter (apologies to Robert too). If this movie was written by the Directors wife  she was a movie buff. It is better than you think!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool off the spice girls...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charlotte Younge
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, like all you fellow IMDb members, I'm a lover of a movies. But once in a while, a film like this should be making people laugh, not moan about the million things wrong with it. I haven't watched this flick in ages, but yesterday I was in a "take-a-look-at-stuff-from-the-past" mood, found the tape whilst doing my spring cleaning, and so I popped the tape in. I was a little biased the last time I watched it, being an 8 year old Spice Girls fanatic, but this time I took the film into serious consideration. Don't you get it? It's a satire about film making... And with the fabulous cameos (Elvis Costello, Elton John, MEATLOAF!! just to name a few..)how could you not love it? Just a teensy bit? Trust me, the British know film, and they know what they're doing with this one. Instead of showing one "real" side of the spice girls, they've shoved 50 years of stereotypical rubbish into one movie. You've got people trying to make a movie, a documentary, and the tabloids trying to break the girls apart, along with aliens, hot Italian models and random deja vus. All in one. So, cool off IMDb... if you don't take yourself too seriously and want to step back into the 90s for a good laugh, watch this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and light! A Good feel movie about Pop stars lives...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alain-aouad
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has everything related to the pop life in it, a comedic thrilling ride in the lives of a pop star band! The paparazzi, the fame, the fans, the back clash, the media, the managers, the shows and of course the greatest girl band the world has and will ever see: The Spice Girls! The Spice girls in a way gathered all the pop life elements in their movie, mocking even themselves, they tried to show the world that this is all a fun ride and you must enjoy every minute of it while it lasts, and this is what they did in their 2 years world domination rally! You can't watch this movie though if you're a pop music or Spice Girls hater, if you are into pop and into light comedy and cheesy jokes then this movie is for your eyes only (a little wink to Roger Moore's cameo). Relax, get your best friend with whom you spent most of the 90's hearing ace of base and Take that on your CD player and enjoy this movie for old times sake! Now the acting, the plot, the script etc... They all fade into the background when you've got the Spice girls up front doing their thing! So stop complaining about this movie, it is not just another Oscar Submission, its supposed to be a funny ride and a silly joke for God's sake, lighten up and enjoy it for what it is!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The good, the bad, the Spice World movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dancingqueensw4
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a bit of a film fanatic, I was always of the opinion that no matter what the film, good or bad, it's worth watching. You can delight in the great ones and laugh at the ones that were really really awful. This film changed that opinion. I tried, but unlike any other film, I could not find it funny that I wasted my time watching it. It has NO plot. The acting was not just bad, it was so bad it made their singing ability look good... and they were playing themselves! Really, how hard can that be? Don't get me wrong, I'm aware it was suppose to be silly and not taken seriously, but I'm pretty sure it was also suppose to be entertaining... which it wasn't. It just bounced from boring scene to boring scene not linking them in anyway. Even if you like the spice girls, no amount of nostalgia would be worth watching this film. If you're looking for a walk down memory lane your better off watching Bugsy Malone, Labyrinth, Moonwalker, pretty much anything from the early 90s. Besides, this film made me forget what I liked about the spice girls in the first place. After watching this film, I went from a secret fan, to seeing the spice girls as the people that got me to spend my time and money on the worst film ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Spiced Up My Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tiffxrawr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film when I was seven and I still love it today. I think that for any Spice Girls fan, this was a great movie. The acting may not have been Oscar worthy, but I feel they did a great job making their audience laugh acting as themselves. Though some of the scenes could be considered corny or out of place, this film was overall very entertaining to its target audience: the fans. It is not for everyone. Just as I will never love the movie Purple Rain as much as my mother did due to her generation's love for Prince, not many will love Spice World the way Spice Girls fans do. The Spice Girls were positive role models in the 90's for girls like me. Scary Spice inspired me to love my huge curly hair. Sporty Spice inspired me to embrace my inner tom-boy. Their songs were catchy and widely popular for a while. Their movie venture may not have been as successful as their songs. However, it was not a total flop. Spice World had a wacky but interesting story line and a few compelling sub-story lines. This will always be considered one of my favorite movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teenybopper's Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I'm a 51 year old guy, and know this movie is (mostly) for teen girls, but I thought it was fun, especially when cute Emma Bunton and hot Victoria Adams (Beckham) were on screen. The S-Girls travel the world on their cool British bus show-casing their music (and their voluptuous bodies) and helping humankind get through the proverbial trials and tribulations of daily life. They even help deliver a baby! Wow! These chicks can do everything! Good songs, solid choreography, and a colorful presentation boosts this movie above Mundanesville. Cool movie, but cameos by John Elton and Hamburger Loaf were not needed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So What Do You Want? How About An Actual Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spice World (1997) 1/2 (out of 4) This here is pretty much a variation on A HARD DAY'S NIGHT but this time instead of John, Paul, George and Ringo we get Baby, Sporty, Ginger, Posh and Scary. Most movies made feature a credit that will read something to the effect of "story by..." but not this one. No, that credit is actually replaced by one that reads "idea by..." and that pretty much tells you everything you need to know. Really? The biggest pop female pop band that the world has ever seen and one that apparently made between $600-$800 million can only come up with a movie based on an idea? I guess it really doesn't matter that SPICE WORLD has been called one of the worst movies ever made because their fans ate it up when it was released and apparently they are still very fond of it. I guess if I was a die-hard fan of the group then I'd enjoy seeing them in anything no matter how bad it actually was. What makes this film so bad is that there really doesn't seem to be any idea of what this movie is supposed to be about. I'm sure it was an attempt to milk the success of the band and that's understandable. I just wish we had actually gotten a backstage look at the lives they were going through or at least gave us some sort of realistic look at the band. Instead we basically just get one long music video where the girls play their music and get to try on many different outfits. Nothing the five girls say are funny. Nothing they say is very interesting. In fact, nothing they do is all that entertaining. The movie actually reaches a level where it becomes painful to sit through it any longer. Heck, the girls can even lip-sync their songs and that well. SPICE WORLD doesn't quite earn a BOMB ranking thanks in large part to the girls being cute and wearing tight clothes but you can look at a magazine for this. The film itself is quite bad and sadly it never reaches a level to where you can just laugh at it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant fun movie for any Spice Girls fan!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexstinks
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film so much! I was brought up in the 90s listening to the Spice Girls and I was obsessed with them! I remember a family member bought me this on VHS and I loved it! It was just fun! Clearly it's not the type of movie that's supposed to be taken seriously. It is just supposed to be more of a spoof movie about the Spice Girls! I love the songs, costumes, crazy scenes! I also really enjoyed the cameo appearances from Meatloaf, Elton John and co. It was exciting for my as a child watching this. I love it even now! Brings back great memories! I can't fault it for what it is! It is just a piece of light hearted fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have heard nothing but negative things for this movie. But A friend of mine on YouTube named Cinema Sickness recommended this movie. So I bought it for a whopping 25 cents and here are my thoughts. The film is just about the 5 Spice Girls who try to help their friend deliver her first baby all while they are trying to get ready for a very big live performance. This is pretty stupid but you know what I had a lot of fun with it. If you are taking this movie to seriously well than you are not going to have any fun with any other movie. Although it is a very strange idea to make a movie about the Spice Girls. But Hey they made a movie about Hannah Montana and Justin Bieber so anything is possible.Plus I think that this movie is a little to risqu&eacute; for a PG Rating. I say check out this movie for some fun. This review is dedicated to Cinema Sickness(Your Welcome);). Rated PG For Some Vulgarity, Brief Nudity And Language. 1hr 33min/93min. ***1/2/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The oldest profession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Easton
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once upon a time there were The Spice Girls. They introduced us to 'girl power', a thinly disguised effort to use sex to sell manufactured pop music, potato chips and fizzy drinks to little kids and morons. And then there was this travesty of a movie. This is very much like other exploitation movies made to cash in on popular music groups in the past, but with all the good elements removed. There is nothing redeemable about this whatsoever, it's pure trash, and since the 'music' of The Spice Girls has no longevity neither does this. If you want to pick this up along with the girl's entire back catalogue of CDs, I recommend checking out the bargain bins in charity shops. You shouldn't have a problem finding it all, and then at least something positive will have come out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Gem - You need to look closely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanja_van_huet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was doubtful about this movie but my daughter insisted we watch it together. I was amazed at how art house it was  with throw backs to the old Beatles movie genre and other madcap '70's and 80's productions (Thunderbirds, the Monkees, etc). Apart from the catchy music and the generally enjoyable overacting  the all star cast makes it a genuine 'spot the actor' vehicle. (For example: this from http://filmbabble. blogspot.com/2007/06/20 -great-modern-movie-cameos.html : "Elvis Costello as a bartender and credited as 'Himself' Costello plays a nice tongue-in-cheek note as the Girls talk about their possible flash-in-the-pan prospects".) It spoofs everything about those bad movies we loved to watch  model buses jumping over model bridges, E.T. (the Movie) in 'bad green coats', the Magical Mystery Tour amazing bus, media moguls (Rupert Murdoch anyone?), Hollywood 'run and go' action movies, over-sexed Italian dancers etc. The more I watched the more I saw. I drove my daughter crazy pointing out ... 'hey that is a takeoff from ...'. If you are studying cinema or just have a movie trivia interest, Spice World certainly gives you more to argue about than Citizen Kain (sorry Orsen) or Pret-a-Porter (apologies to Robert too). If this movie was written by the Directors wife  she was a movie buff. It is better than you think!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool off the spice girls...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charlotte Younge
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, like all you fellow IMDb members, I'm a lover of a movies. But once in a while, a film like this should be making people laugh, not moan about the million things wrong with it. I haven't watched this flick in ages, but yesterday I was in a "take-a-look-at-stuff-from-the-past" mood, found the tape whilst doing my spring cleaning, and so I popped the tape in. I was a little biased the last time I watched it, being an 8 year old Spice Girls fanatic, but this time I took the film into serious consideration. Don't you get it? It's a satire about film making... And with the fabulous cameos (Elvis Costello, Elton John, MEATLOAF!! just to name a few..)how could you not love it? Just a teensy bit? Trust me, the British know film, and they know what they're doing with this one. Instead of showing one "real" side of the spice girls, they've shoved 50 years of stereotypical rubbish into one movie. You've got people trying to make a movie, a documentary, and the tabloids trying to break the girls apart, along with aliens, hot Italian models and random deja vus. All in one. So, cool off IMDb... if you don't take yourself too seriously and want to step back into the 90s for a good laugh, watch this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and light! A Good feel movie about Pop stars lives...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alain-aouad
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has everything related to the pop life in it, a comedic thrilling ride in the lives of a pop star band! The paparazzi, the fame, the fans, the back clash, the media, the managers, the shows and of course the greatest girl band the world has and will ever see: The Spice Girls! The Spice girls in a way gathered all the pop life elements in their movie, mocking even themselves, they tried to show the world that this is all a fun ride and you must enjoy every minute of it while it lasts, and this is what they did in their 2 years world domination rally! You can't watch this movie though if you're a pop music or Spice Girls hater, if you are into pop and into light comedy and cheesy jokes then this movie is for your eyes only (a little wink to Roger Moore's cameo). Relax, get your best friend with whom you spent most of the 90's hearing ace of base and Take that on your CD player and enjoy this movie for old times sake! Now the acting, the plot, the script etc... They all fade into the background when you've got the Spice girls up front doing their thing! So stop complaining about this movie, it is not just another Oscar Submission, its supposed to be a funny ride and a silly joke for God's sake, lighten up and enjoy it for what it is!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The good, the bad, the Spice World movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dancingqueensw4
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a bit of a film fanatic, I was always of the opinion that no matter what the film, good or bad, it's worth watching. You can delight in the great ones and laugh at the ones that were really really awful. This film changed that opinion. I tried, but unlike any other film, I could not find it funny that I wasted my time watching it. It has NO plot. The acting was not just bad, it was so bad it made their singing ability look good... and they were playing themselves! Really, how hard can that be? Don't get me wrong, I'm aware it was suppose to be silly and not taken seriously, but I'm pretty sure it was also suppose to be entertaining... which it wasn't. It just bounced from boring scene to boring scene not linking them in anyway. Even if you like the spice girls, no amount of nostalgia would be worth watching this film. If you're looking for a walk down memory lane your better off watching Bugsy Malone, Labyrinth, Moonwalker, pretty much anything from the early 90s. Besides, this film made me forget what I liked about the spice girls in the first place. After watching this film, I went from a secret fan, to seeing the spice girls as the people that got me to spend my time and money on the worst film ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Spiced Up My Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tiffxrawr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film when I was seven and I still love it today. I think that for any Spice Girls fan, this was a great movie. The acting may not have been Oscar worthy, but I feel they did a great job making their audience laugh acting as themselves. Though some of the scenes could be considered corny or out of place, this film was overall very entertaining to its target audience: the fans. It is not for everyone. Just as I will never love the movie Purple Rain as much as my mother did due to her generation's love for Prince, not many will love Spice World the way Spice Girls fans do. The Spice Girls were positive role models in the 90's for girls like me. Scary Spice inspired me to love my huge curly hair. Sporty Spice inspired me to embrace my inner tom-boy. Their songs were catchy and widely popular for a while. Their movie venture may not have been as successful as their songs. However, it was not a total flop. Spice World had a wacky but interesting story line and a few compelling sub-story lines. This will always be considered one of my favorite movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teenybopper's Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I'm a 51 year old guy, and know this movie is (mostly) for teen girls, but I thought it was fun, especially when cute Emma Bunton and hot Victoria Adams (Beckham) were on screen. The S-Girls travel the world on their cool British bus show-casing their music (and their voluptuous bodies) and helping humankind get through the proverbial trials and tribulations of daily life. They even help deliver a baby! Wow! These chicks can do everything! Good songs, solid choreography, and a colorful presentation boosts this movie above Mundanesville. Cool movie, but cameos by John Elton and Hamburger Loaf were not needed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So What Do You Want? How About An Actual Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spice World (1997) 1/2 (out of 4) This here is pretty much a variation on A HARD DAY'S NIGHT but this time instead of John, Paul, George and Ringo we get Baby, Sporty, Ginger, Posh and Scary. Most movies made feature a credit that will read something to the effect of "story by..." but not this one. No, that credit is actually replaced by one that reads "idea by..." and that pretty much tells you everything you need to know. Really? The biggest pop female pop band that the world has ever seen and one that apparently made between $600-$800 million can only come up with a movie based on an idea? I guess it really doesn't matter that SPICE WORLD has been called one of the worst movies ever made because their fans ate it up when it was released and apparently they are still very fond of it. I guess if I was a die-hard fan of the group then I'd enjoy seeing them in anything no matter how bad it actually was. What makes this film so bad is that there really doesn't seem to be any idea of what this movie is supposed to be about. I'm sure it was an attempt to milk the success of the band and that's understandable. I just wish we had actually gotten a backstage look at the lives they were going through or at least gave us some sort of realistic look at the band. Instead we basically just get one long music video where the girls play their music and get to try on many different outfits. Nothing the five girls say are funny. Nothing they say is very interesting. In fact, nothing they do is all that entertaining. The movie actually reaches a level where it becomes painful to sit through it any longer. Heck, the girls can even lip-sync their songs and that well. SPICE WORLD doesn't quite earn a BOMB ranking thanks in large part to the girls being cute and wearing tight clothes but you can look at a magazine for this. The film itself is quite bad and sadly it never reaches a level to where you can just laugh at it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant fun movie for any Spice Girls fan!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexstinks
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film so much! I was brought up in the 90s listening to the Spice Girls and I was obsessed with them! I remember a family member bought me this on VHS and I loved it! It was just fun! Clearly it's not the type of movie that's supposed to be taken seriously. It is just supposed to be more of a spoof movie about the Spice Girls! I love the songs, costumes, crazy scenes! I also really enjoyed the cameo appearances from Meatloaf, Elton John and co. It was exciting for my as a child watching this. I love it even now! Brings back great memories! I can't fault it for what it is! It is just a piece of light hearted fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have heard nothing but negative things for this movie. But A friend of mine on YouTube named Cinema Sickness recommended this movie. So I bought it for a whopping 25 cents and here are my thoughts. The film is just about the 5 Spice Girls who try to help their friend deliver her first baby all while they are trying to get ready for a very big live performance. This is pretty stupid but you know what I had a lot of fun with it. If you are taking this movie to seriously well than you are not going to have any fun with any other movie. Although it is a very strange idea to make a movie about the Spice Girls. But Hey they made a movie about Hannah Montana and Justin Bieber so anything is possible.Plus I think that this movie is a little to risqu&eacute; for a PG Rating. I say check out this movie for some fun. This review is dedicated to Cinema Sickness(Your Welcome);). Rated PG For Some Vulgarity, Brief Nudity And Language. 1hr 33min/93min. ***1/2/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The oldest profession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Easton
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once upon a time there were The Spice Girls. They introduced us to 'girl power', a thinly disguised effort to use sex to sell manufactured pop music, potato chips and fizzy drinks to little kids and morons. And then there was this travesty of a movie. This is very much like other exploitation movies made to cash in on popular music groups in the past, but with all the good elements removed. There is nothing redeemable about this whatsoever, it's pure trash, and since the 'music' of The Spice Girls has no longevity neither does this. If you want to pick this up along with the girl's entire back catalogue of CDs, I recommend checking out the bargain bins in charity shops. You shouldn't have a problem finding it all, and then at least something positive will have come out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Gem - You need to look closely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanja_van_huet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was doubtful about this movie but my daughter insisted we watch it together. I was amazed at how art house it was  with throw backs to the old Beatles movie genre and other madcap '70's and 80's productions (Thunderbirds, the Monkees, etc). Apart from the catchy music and the generally enjoyable overacting  the all star cast makes it a genuine 'spot the actor' vehicle. (For example: this from http://filmbabble. blogspot.com/2007/06/20 -great-modern-movie-cameos.html : "Elvis Costello as a bartender and credited as 'Himself' Costello plays a nice tongue-in-cheek note as the Girls talk about their possible flash-in-the-pan prospects".) It spoofs everything about those bad movies we loved to watch  model buses jumping over model bridges, E.T. (the Movie) in 'bad green coats', the Magical Mystery Tour amazing bus, media moguls (Rupert Murdoch anyone?), Hollywood 'run and go' action movies, over-sexed Italian dancers etc. The more I watched the more I saw. I drove my daughter crazy pointing out ... 'hey that is a takeoff from ...'. If you are studying cinema or just have a movie trivia interest, Spice World certainly gives you more to argue about than Citizen Kain (sorry Orsen) or Pret-a-Porter (apologies to Robert too). If this movie was written by the Directors wife  she was a movie buff. It is better than you think!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool off the spice girls...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charlotte Younge
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, like all you fellow IMDb members, I'm a lover of a movies. But once in a while, a film like this should be making people laugh, not moan about the million things wrong with it. I haven't watched this flick in ages, but yesterday I was in a "take-a-look-at-stuff-from-the-past" mood, found the tape whilst doing my spring cleaning, and so I popped the tape in. I was a little biased the last time I watched it, being an 8 year old Spice Girls fanatic, but this time I took the film into serious consideration. Don't you get it? It's a satire about film making... And with the fabulous cameos (Elvis Costello, Elton John, MEATLOAF!! just to name a few..)how could you not love it? Just a teensy bit? Trust me, the British know film, and they know what they're doing with this one. Instead of showing one "real" side of the spice girls, they've shoved 50 years of stereotypical rubbish into one movie. You've got people trying to make a movie, a documentary, and the tabloids trying to break the girls apart, along with aliens, hot Italian models and random deja vus. All in one. So, cool off IMDb... if you don't take yourself too seriously and want to step back into the 90s for a good laugh, watch this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and light! A Good feel movie about Pop stars lives...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alain-aouad
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has everything related to the pop life in it, a comedic thrilling ride in the lives of a pop star band! The paparazzi, the fame, the fans, the back clash, the media, the managers, the shows and of course the greatest girl band the world has and will ever see: The Spice Girls! The Spice girls in a way gathered all the pop life elements in their movie, mocking even themselves, they tried to show the world that this is all a fun ride and you must enjoy every minute of it while it lasts, and this is what they did in their 2 years world domination rally! You can't watch this movie though if you're a pop music or Spice Girls hater, if you are into pop and into light comedy and cheesy jokes then this movie is for your eyes only (a little wink to Roger Moore's cameo). Relax, get your best friend with whom you spent most of the 90's hearing ace of base and Take that on your CD player and enjoy this movie for old times sake! Now the acting, the plot, the script etc... They all fade into the background when you've got the Spice girls up front doing their thing! So stop complaining about this movie, it is not just another Oscar Submission, its supposed to be a funny ride and a silly joke for God's sake, lighten up and enjoy it for what it is!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The good, the bad, the Spice World movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dancingqueensw4
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a bit of a film fanatic, I was always of the opinion that no matter what the film, good or bad, it's worth watching. You can delight in the great ones and laugh at the ones that were really really awful. This film changed that opinion. I tried, but unlike any other film, I could not find it funny that I wasted my time watching it. It has NO plot. The acting was not just bad, it was so bad it made their singing ability look good... and they were playing themselves! Really, how hard can that be? Don't get me wrong, I'm aware it was suppose to be silly and not taken seriously, but I'm pretty sure it was also suppose to be entertaining... which it wasn't. It just bounced from boring scene to boring scene not linking them in anyway. Even if you like the spice girls, no amount of nostalgia would be worth watching this film. If you're looking for a walk down memory lane your better off watching Bugsy Malone, Labyrinth, Moonwalker, pretty much anything from the early 90s. Besides, this film made me forget what I liked about the spice girls in the first place. After watching this film, I went from a secret fan, to seeing the spice girls as the people that got me to spend my time and money on the worst film ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Spiced Up My Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tiffxrawr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film when I was seven and I still love it today. I think that for any Spice Girls fan, this was a great movie. The acting may not have been Oscar worthy, but I feel they did a great job making their audience laugh acting as themselves. Though some of the scenes could be considered corny or out of place, this film was overall very entertaining to its target audience: the fans. It is not for everyone. Just as I will never love the movie Purple Rain as much as my mother did due to her generation's love for Prince, not many will love Spice World the way Spice Girls fans do. The Spice Girls were positive role models in the 90's for girls like me. Scary Spice inspired me to love my huge curly hair. Sporty Spice inspired me to embrace my inner tom-boy. Their songs were catchy and widely popular for a while. Their movie venture may not have been as successful as their songs. However, it was not a total flop. Spice World had a wacky but interesting story line and a few compelling sub-story lines. This will always be considered one of my favorite movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teenybopper's Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I'm a 51 year old guy, and know this movie is (mostly) for teen girls, but I thought it was fun, especially when cute Emma Bunton and hot Victoria Adams (Beckham) were on screen. The S-Girls travel the world on their cool British bus show-casing their music (and their voluptuous bodies) and helping humankind get through the proverbial trials and tribulations of daily life. They even help deliver a baby! Wow! These chicks can do everything! Good songs, solid choreography, and a colorful presentation boosts this movie above Mundanesville. Cool movie, but cameos by John Elton and Hamburger Loaf were not needed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So What Do You Want? How About An Actual Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spice World (1997) 1/2 (out of 4) This here is pretty much a variation on A HARD DAY'S NIGHT but this time instead of John, Paul, George and Ringo we get Baby, Sporty, Ginger, Posh and Scary. Most movies made feature a credit that will read something to the effect of "story by..." but not this one. No, that credit is actually replaced by one that reads "idea by..." and that pretty much tells you everything you need to know. Really? The biggest pop female pop band that the world has ever seen and one that apparently made between $600-$800 million can only come up with a movie based on an idea? I guess it really doesn't matter that SPICE WORLD has been called one of the worst movies ever made because their fans ate it up when it was released and apparently they are still very fond of it. I guess if I was a die-hard fan of the group then I'd enjoy seeing them in anything no matter how bad it actually was. What makes this film so bad is that there really doesn't seem to be any idea of what this movie is supposed to be about. I'm sure it was an attempt to milk the success of the band and that's understandable. I just wish we had actually gotten a backstage look at the lives they were going through or at least gave us some sort of realistic look at the band. Instead we basically just get one long music video where the girls play their music and get to try on many different outfits. Nothing the five girls say are funny. Nothing they say is very interesting. In fact, nothing they do is all that entertaining. The movie actually reaches a level where it becomes painful to sit through it any longer. Heck, the girls can even lip-sync their songs and that well. SPICE WORLD doesn't quite earn a BOMB ranking thanks in large part to the girls being cute and wearing tight clothes but you can look at a magazine for this. The film itself is quite bad and sadly it never reaches a level to where you can just laugh at it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant fun movie for any Spice Girls fan!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexstinks
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film so much! I was brought up in the 90s listening to the Spice Girls and I was obsessed with them! I remember a family member bought me this on VHS and I loved it! It was just fun! Clearly it's not the type of movie that's supposed to be taken seriously. It is just supposed to be more of a spoof movie about the Spice Girls! I love the songs, costumes, crazy scenes! I also really enjoyed the cameo appearances from Meatloaf, Elton John and co. It was exciting for my as a child watching this. I love it even now! Brings back great memories! I can't fault it for what it is! It is just a piece of light hearted fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have heard nothing but negative things for this movie. But A friend of mine on YouTube named Cinema Sickness recommended this movie. So I bought it for a whopping 25 cents and here are my thoughts. The film is just about the 5 Spice Girls who try to help their friend deliver her first baby all while they are trying to get ready for a very big live performance. This is pretty stupid but you know what I had a lot of fun with it. If you are taking this movie to seriously well than you are not going to have any fun with any other movie. Although it is a very strange idea to make a movie about the Spice Girls. But Hey they made a movie about Hannah Montana and Justin Bieber so anything is possible.Plus I think that this movie is a little to risqu&eacute; for a PG Rating. I say check out this movie for some fun. This review is dedicated to Cinema Sickness(Your Welcome);). Rated PG For Some Vulgarity, Brief Nudity And Language. 1hr 33min/93min. ***1/2/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The oldest profession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Easton
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once upon a time there were The Spice Girls. They introduced us to 'girl power', a thinly disguised effort to use sex to sell manufactured pop music, potato chips and fizzy drinks to little kids and morons. And then there was this travesty of a movie. This is very much like other exploitation movies made to cash in on popular music groups in the past, but with all the good elements removed. There is nothing redeemable about this whatsoever, it's pure trash, and since the 'music' of The Spice Girls has no longevity neither does this. If you want to pick this up along with the girl's entire back catalogue of CDs, I recommend checking out the bargain bins in charity shops. You shouldn't have a problem finding it all, and then at least something positive will have come out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Gem - You need to look closely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanja_van_huet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was doubtful about this movie but my daughter insisted we watch it together. I was amazed at how art house it was  with throw backs to the old Beatles movie genre and other madcap '70's and 80's productions (Thunderbirds, the Monkees, etc). Apart from the catchy music and the generally enjoyable overacting  the all star cast makes it a genuine 'spot the actor' vehicle. (For example: this from http://filmbabble. blogspot.com/2007/06/20 -great-modern-movie-cameos.html : "Elvis Costello as a bartender and credited as 'Himself' Costello plays a nice tongue-in-cheek note as the Girls talk about their possible flash-in-the-pan prospects".) It spoofs everything about those bad movies we loved to watch  model buses jumping over model bridges, E.T. (the Movie) in 'bad green coats', the Magical Mystery Tour amazing bus, media moguls (Rupert Murdoch anyone?), Hollywood 'run and go' action movies, over-sexed Italian dancers etc. The more I watched the more I saw. I drove my daughter crazy pointing out ... 'hey that is a takeoff from ...'. If you are studying cinema or just have a movie trivia interest, Spice World certainly gives you more to argue about than Citizen Kain (sorry Orsen) or Pret-a-Porter (apologies to Robert too). If this movie was written by the Directors wife  she was a movie buff. It is better than you think!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool off the spice girls...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charlotte Younge
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, like all you fellow IMDb members, I'm a lover of a movies. But once in a while, a film like this should be making people laugh, not moan about the million things wrong with it. I haven't watched this flick in ages, but yesterday I was in a "take-a-look-at-stuff-from-the-past" mood, found the tape whilst doing my spring cleaning, and so I popped the tape in. I was a little biased the last time I watched it, being an 8 year old Spice Girls fanatic, but this time I took the film into serious consideration. Don't you get it? It's a satire about film making... And with the fabulous cameos (Elvis Costello, Elton John, MEATLOAF!! just to name a few..)how could you not love it? Just a teensy bit? Trust me, the British know film, and they know what they're doing with this one. Instead of showing one "real" side of the spice girls, they've shoved 50 years of stereotypical rubbish into one movie. You've got people trying to make a movie, a documentary, and the tabloids trying to break the girls apart, along with aliens, hot Italian models and random deja vus. All in one. So, cool off IMDb... if you don't take yourself too seriously and want to step back into the 90s for a good laugh, watch this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and light! A Good feel movie about Pop stars lives...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alain-aouad
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has everything related to the pop life in it, a comedic thrilling ride in the lives of a pop star band! The paparazzi, the fame, the fans, the back clash, the media, the managers, the shows and of course the greatest girl band the world has and will ever see: The Spice Girls! The Spice girls in a way gathered all the pop life elements in their movie, mocking even themselves, they tried to show the world that this is all a fun ride and you must enjoy every minute of it while it lasts, and this is what they did in their 2 years world domination rally! You can't watch this movie though if you're a pop music or Spice Girls hater, if you are into pop and into light comedy and cheesy jokes then this movie is for your eyes only (a little wink to Roger Moore's cameo). Relax, get your best friend with whom you spent most of the 90's hearing ace of base and Take that on your CD player and enjoy this movie for old times sake! Now the acting, the plot, the script etc... They all fade into the background when you've got the Spice girls up front doing their thing! So stop complaining about this movie, it is not just another Oscar Submission, its supposed to be a funny ride and a silly joke for God's sake, lighten up and enjoy it for what it is!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The good, the bad, the Spice World movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dancingqueensw4
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a bit of a film fanatic, I was always of the opinion that no matter what the film, good or bad, it's worth watching. You can delight in the great ones and laugh at the ones that were really really awful. This film changed that opinion. I tried, but unlike any other film, I could not find it funny that I wasted my time watching it. It has NO plot. The acting was not just bad, it was so bad it made their singing ability look good... and they were playing themselves! Really, how hard can that be? Don't get me wrong, I'm aware it was suppose to be silly and not taken seriously, but I'm pretty sure it was also suppose to be entertaining... which it wasn't. It just bounced from boring scene to boring scene not linking them in anyway. Even if you like the spice girls, no amount of nostalgia would be worth watching this film. If you're looking for a walk down memory lane your better off watching Bugsy Malone, Labyrinth, Moonwalker, pretty much anything from the early 90s. Besides, this film made me forget what I liked about the spice girls in the first place. After watching this film, I went from a secret fan, to seeing the spice girls as the people that got me to spend my time and money on the worst film ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Spiced Up My Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tiffxrawr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film when I was seven and I still love it today. I think that for any Spice Girls fan, this was a great movie. The acting may not have been Oscar worthy, but I feel they did a great job making their audience laugh acting as themselves. Though some of the scenes could be considered corny or out of place, this film was overall very entertaining to its target audience: the fans. It is not for everyone. Just as I will never love the movie Purple Rain as much as my mother did due to her generation's love for Prince, not many will love Spice World the way Spice Girls fans do. The Spice Girls were positive role models in the 90's for girls like me. Scary Spice inspired me to love my huge curly hair. Sporty Spice inspired me to embrace my inner tom-boy. Their songs were catchy and widely popular for a while. Their movie venture may not have been as successful as their songs. However, it was not a total flop. Spice World had a wacky but interesting story line and a few compelling sub-story lines. This will always be considered one of my favorite movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teenybopper's Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I'm a 51 year old guy, and know this movie is (mostly) for teen girls, but I thought it was fun, especially when cute Emma Bunton and hot Victoria Adams (Beckham) were on screen. The S-Girls travel the world on their cool British bus show-casing their music (and their voluptuous bodies) and helping humankind get through the proverbial trials and tribulations of daily life. They even help deliver a baby! Wow! These chicks can do everything! Good songs, solid choreography, and a colorful presentation boosts this movie above Mundanesville. Cool movie, but cameos by John Elton and Hamburger Loaf were not needed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So What Do You Want? How About An Actual Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spice World (1997) 1/2 (out of 4) This here is pretty much a variation on A HARD DAY'S NIGHT but this time instead of John, Paul, George and Ringo we get Baby, Sporty, Ginger, Posh and Scary. Most movies made feature a credit that will read something to the effect of "story by..." but not this one. No, that credit is actually replaced by one that reads "idea by..." and that pretty much tells you everything you need to know. Really? The biggest pop female pop band that the world has ever seen and one that apparently made between $600-$800 million can only come up with a movie based on an idea? I guess it really doesn't matter that SPICE WORLD has been called one of the worst movies ever made because their fans ate it up when it was released and apparently they are still very fond of it. I guess if I was a die-hard fan of the group then I'd enjoy seeing them in anything no matter how bad it actually was. What makes this film so bad is that there really doesn't seem to be any idea of what this movie is supposed to be about. I'm sure it was an attempt to milk the success of the band and that's understandable. I just wish we had actually gotten a backstage look at the lives they were going through or at least gave us some sort of realistic look at the band. Instead we basically just get one long music video where the girls play their music and get to try on many different outfits. Nothing the five girls say are funny. Nothing they say is very interesting. In fact, nothing they do is all that entertaining. The movie actually reaches a level where it becomes painful to sit through it any longer. Heck, the girls can even lip-sync their songs and that well. SPICE WORLD doesn't quite earn a BOMB ranking thanks in large part to the girls being cute and wearing tight clothes but you can look at a magazine for this. The film itself is quite bad and sadly it never reaches a level to where you can just laugh at it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant fun movie for any Spice Girls fan!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexstinks
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film so much! I was brought up in the 90s listening to the Spice Girls and I was obsessed with them! I remember a family member bought me this on VHS and I loved it! It was just fun! Clearly it's not the type of movie that's supposed to be taken seriously. It is just supposed to be more of a spoof movie about the Spice Girls! I love the songs, costumes, crazy scenes! I also really enjoyed the cameo appearances from Meatloaf, Elton John and co. It was exciting for my as a child watching this. I love it even now! Brings back great memories! I can't fault it for what it is! It is just a piece of light hearted fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have heard nothing but negative things for this movie. But A friend of mine on YouTube named Cinema Sickness recommended this movie. So I bought it for a whopping 25 cents and here are my thoughts. The film is just about the 5 Spice Girls who try to help their friend deliver her first baby all while they are trying to get ready for a very big live performance. This is pretty stupid but you know what I had a lot of fun with it. If you are taking this movie to seriously well than you are not going to have any fun with any other movie. Although it is a very strange idea to make a movie about the Spice Girls. But Hey they made a movie about Hannah Montana and Justin Bieber so anything is possible.Plus I think that this movie is a little to risqu&eacute; for a PG Rating. I say check out this movie for some fun. This review is dedicated to Cinema Sickness(Your Welcome);). Rated PG For Some Vulgarity, Brief Nudity And Language. 1hr 33min/93min. ***1/2/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The oldest profession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Easton
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once upon a time there were The Spice Girls. They introduced us to 'girl power', a thinly disguised effort to use sex to sell manufactured pop music, potato chips and fizzy drinks to little kids and morons. And then there was this travesty of a movie. This is very much like other exploitation movies made to cash in on popular music groups in the past, but with all the good elements removed. There is nothing redeemable about this whatsoever, it's pure trash, and since the 'music' of The Spice Girls has no longevity neither does this. If you want to pick this up along with the girl's entire back catalogue of CDs, I recommend checking out the bargain bins in charity shops. You shouldn't have a problem finding it all, and then at least something positive will have come out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Gem - You need to look closely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanja_van_huet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was doubtful about this movie but my daughter insisted we watch it together. I was amazed at how art house it was  with throw backs to the old Beatles movie genre and other madcap '70's and 80's productions (Thunderbirds, the Monkees, etc). Apart from the catchy music and the generally enjoyable overacting  the all star cast makes it a genuine 'spot the actor' vehicle. (For example: this from http://filmbabble. blogspot.com/2007/06/20 -great-modern-movie-cameos.html : "Elvis Costello as a bartender and credited as 'Himself' Costello plays a nice tongue-in-cheek note as the Girls talk about their possible flash-in-the-pan prospects".) It spoofs everything about those bad movies we loved to watch  model buses jumping over model bridges, E.T. (the Movie) in 'bad green coats', the Magical Mystery Tour amazing bus, media moguls (Rupert Murdoch anyone?), Hollywood 'run and go' action movies, over-sexed Italian dancers etc. The more I watched the more I saw. I drove my daughter crazy pointing out ... 'hey that is a takeoff from ...'. If you are studying cinema or just have a movie trivia interest, Spice World certainly gives you more to argue about than Citizen Kain (sorry Orsen) or Pret-a-Porter (apologies to Robert too). If this movie was written by the Directors wife  she was a movie buff. It is better than you think!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool off the spice girls...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charlotte Younge
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, like all you fellow IMDb members, I'm a lover of a movies. But once in a while, a film like this should be making people laugh, not moan about the million things wrong with it. I haven't watched this flick in ages, but yesterday I was in a "take-a-look-at-stuff-from-the-past" mood, found the tape whilst doing my spring cleaning, and so I popped the tape in. I was a little biased the last time I watched it, being an 8 year old Spice Girls fanatic, but this time I took the film into serious consideration. Don't you get it? It's a satire about film making... And with the fabulous cameos (Elvis Costello, Elton John, MEATLOAF!! just to name a few..)how could you not love it? Just a teensy bit? Trust me, the British know film, and they know what they're doing with this one. Instead of showing one "real" side of the spice girls, they've shoved 50 years of stereotypical rubbish into one movie. You've got people trying to make a movie, a documentary, and the tabloids trying to break the girls apart, along with aliens, hot Italian models and random deja vus. All in one. So, cool off IMDb... if you don't take yourself too seriously and want to step back into the 90s for a good laugh, watch this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and light! A Good feel movie about Pop stars lives...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alain-aouad
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has everything related to the pop life in it, a comedic thrilling ride in the lives of a pop star band! The paparazzi, the fame, the fans, the back clash, the media, the managers, the shows and of course the greatest girl band the world has and will ever see: The Spice Girls! The Spice girls in a way gathered all the pop life elements in their movie, mocking even themselves, they tried to show the world that this is all a fun ride and you must enjoy every minute of it while it lasts, and this is what they did in their 2 years world domination rally! You can't watch this movie though if you're a pop music or Spice Girls hater, if you are into pop and into light comedy and cheesy jokes then this movie is for your eyes only (a little wink to Roger Moore's cameo). Relax, get your best friend with whom you spent most of the 90's hearing ace of base and Take that on your CD player and enjoy this movie for old times sake! Now the acting, the plot, the script etc... They all fade into the background when you've got the Spice girls up front doing their thing! So stop complaining about this movie, it is not just another Oscar Submission, its supposed to be a funny ride and a silly joke for God's sake, lighten up and enjoy it for what it is!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The good, the bad, the Spice World movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dancingqueensw4
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a bit of a film fanatic, I was always of the opinion that no matter what the film, good or bad, it's worth watching. You can delight in the great ones and laugh at the ones that were really really awful. This film changed that opinion. I tried, but unlike any other film, I could not find it funny that I wasted my time watching it. It has NO plot. The acting was not just bad, it was so bad it made their singing ability look good... and they were playing themselves! Really, how hard can that be? Don't get me wrong, I'm aware it was suppose to be silly and not taken seriously, but I'm pretty sure it was also suppose to be entertaining... which it wasn't. It just bounced from boring scene to boring scene not linking them in anyway. Even if you like the spice girls, no amount of nostalgia would be worth watching this film. If you're looking for a walk down memory lane your better off watching Bugsy Malone, Labyrinth, Moonwalker, pretty much anything from the early 90s. Besides, this film made me forget what I liked about the spice girls in the first place. After watching this film, I went from a secret fan, to seeing the spice girls as the people that got me to spend my time and money on the worst film ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Spiced Up My Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tiffxrawr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film when I was seven and I still love it today. I think that for any Spice Girls fan, this was a great movie. The acting may not have been Oscar worthy, but I feel they did a great job making their audience laugh acting as themselves. Though some of the scenes could be considered corny or out of place, this film was overall very entertaining to its target audience: the fans. It is not for everyone. Just as I will never love the movie Purple Rain as much as my mother did due to her generation's love for Prince, not many will love Spice World the way Spice Girls fans do. The Spice Girls were positive role models in the 90's for girls like me. Scary Spice inspired me to love my huge curly hair. Sporty Spice inspired me to embrace my inner tom-boy. Their songs were catchy and widely popular for a while. Their movie venture may not have been as successful as their songs. However, it was not a total flop. Spice World had a wacky but interesting story line and a few compelling sub-story lines. This will always be considered one of my favorite movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teenybopper's Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I'm a 51 year old guy, and know this movie is (mostly) for teen girls, but I thought it was fun, especially when cute Emma Bunton and hot Victoria Adams (Beckham) were on screen. The S-Girls travel the world on their cool British bus show-casing their music (and their voluptuous bodies) and helping humankind get through the proverbial trials and tribulations of daily life. They even help deliver a baby! Wow! These chicks can do everything! Good songs, solid choreography, and a colorful presentation boosts this movie above Mundanesville. Cool movie, but cameos by John Elton and Hamburger Loaf were not needed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So What Do You Want? How About An Actual Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spice World (1997) 1/2 (out of 4) This here is pretty much a variation on A HARD DAY'S NIGHT but this time instead of John, Paul, George and Ringo we get Baby, Sporty, Ginger, Posh and Scary. Most movies made feature a credit that will read something to the effect of "story by..." but not this one. No, that credit is actually replaced by one that reads "idea by..." and that pretty much tells you everything you need to know. Really? The biggest pop female pop band that the world has ever seen and one that apparently made between $600-$800 million can only come up with a movie based on an idea? I guess it really doesn't matter that SPICE WORLD has been called one of the worst movies ever made because their fans ate it up when it was released and apparently they are still very fond of it. I guess if I was a die-hard fan of the group then I'd enjoy seeing them in anything no matter how bad it actually was. What makes this film so bad is that there really doesn't seem to be any idea of what this movie is supposed to be about. I'm sure it was an attempt to milk the success of the band and that's understandable. I just wish we had actually gotten a backstage look at the lives they were going through or at least gave us some sort of realistic look at the band. Instead we basically just get one long music video where the girls play their music and get to try on many different outfits. Nothing the five girls say are funny. Nothing they say is very interesting. In fact, nothing they do is all that entertaining. The movie actually reaches a level where it becomes painful to sit through it any longer. Heck, the girls can even lip-sync their songs and that well. SPICE WORLD doesn't quite earn a BOMB ranking thanks in large part to the girls being cute and wearing tight clothes but you can look at a magazine for this. The film itself is quite bad and sadly it never reaches a level to where you can just laugh at it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant fun movie for any Spice Girls fan!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexstinks
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film so much! I was brought up in the 90s listening to the Spice Girls and I was obsessed with them! I remember a family member bought me this on VHS and I loved it! It was just fun! Clearly it's not the type of movie that's supposed to be taken seriously. It is just supposed to be more of a spoof movie about the Spice Girls! I love the songs, costumes, crazy scenes! I also really enjoyed the cameo appearances from Meatloaf, Elton John and co. It was exciting for my as a child watching this. I love it even now! Brings back great memories! I can't fault it for what it is! It is just a piece of light hearted fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have heard nothing but negative things for this movie. But A friend of mine on YouTube named Cinema Sickness recommended this movie. So I bought it for a whopping 25 cents and here are my thoughts. The film is just about the 5 Spice Girls who try to help their friend deliver her first baby all while they are trying to get ready for a very big live performance. This is pretty stupid but you know what I had a lot of fun with it. If you are taking this movie to seriously well than you are not going to have any fun with any other movie. Although it is a very strange idea to make a movie about the Spice Girls. But Hey they made a movie about Hannah Montana and Justin Bieber so anything is possible.Plus I think that this movie is a little to risqu&eacute; for a PG Rating. I say check out this movie for some fun. This review is dedicated to Cinema Sickness(Your Welcome);). Rated PG For Some Vulgarity, Brief Nudity And Language. 1hr 33min/93min. ***1/2/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The oldest profession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Easton
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once upon a time there were The Spice Girls. They introduced us to 'girl power', a thinly disguised effort to use sex to sell manufactured pop music, potato chips and fizzy drinks to little kids and morons. And then there was this travesty of a movie. This is very much like other exploitation movies made to cash in on popular music groups in the past, but with all the good elements removed. There is nothing redeemable about this whatsoever, it's pure trash, and since the 'music' of The Spice Girls has no longevity neither does this. If you want to pick this up along with the girl's entire back catalogue of CDs, I recommend checking out the bargain bins in charity shops. You shouldn't have a problem finding it all, and then at least something positive will have come out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Gem - You need to look closely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanja_van_huet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was doubtful about this movie but my daughter insisted we watch it together. I was amazed at how art house it was  with throw backs to the old Beatles movie genre and other madcap '70's and 80's productions (Thunderbirds, the Monkees, etc). Apart from the catchy music and the generally enjoyable overacting  the all star cast makes it a genuine 'spot the actor' vehicle. (For example: this from http://filmbabble. blogspot.com/2007/06/20 -great-modern-movie-cameos.html : "Elvis Costello as a bartender and credited as 'Himself' Costello plays a nice tongue-in-cheek note as the Girls talk about their possible flash-in-the-pan prospects".) It spoofs everything about those bad movies we loved to watch  model buses jumping over model bridges, E.T. (the Movie) in 'bad green coats', the Magical Mystery Tour amazing bus, media moguls (Rupert Murdoch anyone?), Hollywood 'run and go' action movies, over-sexed Italian dancers etc. The more I watched the more I saw. I drove my daughter crazy pointing out ... 'hey that is a takeoff from ...'. If you are studying cinema or just have a movie trivia interest, Spice World certainly gives you more to argue about than Citizen Kain (sorry Orsen) or Pret-a-Porter (apologies to Robert too). If this movie was written by the Directors wife  she was a movie buff. It is better than you think!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool off the spice girls...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charlotte Younge
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, like all you fellow IMDb members, I'm a lover of a movies. But once in a while, a film like this should be making people laugh, not moan about the million things wrong with it. I haven't watched this flick in ages, but yesterday I was in a "take-a-look-at-stuff-from-the-past" mood, found the tape whilst doing my spring cleaning, and so I popped the tape in. I was a little biased the last time I watched it, being an 8 year old Spice Girls fanatic, but this time I took the film into serious consideration. Don't you get it? It's a satire about film making... And with the fabulous cameos (Elvis Costello, Elton John, MEATLOAF!! just to name a few..)how could you not love it? Just a teensy bit? Trust me, the British know film, and they know what they're doing with this one. Instead of showing one "real" side of the spice girls, they've shoved 50 years of stereotypical rubbish into one movie. You've got people trying to make a movie, a documentary, and the tabloids trying to break the girls apart, along with aliens, hot Italian models and random deja vus. All in one. So, cool off IMDb... if you don't take yourself too seriously and want to step back into the 90s for a good laugh, watch this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and light! A Good feel movie about Pop stars lives...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alain-aouad
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has everything related to the pop life in it, a comedic thrilling ride in the lives of a pop star band! The paparazzi, the fame, the fans, the back clash, the media, the managers, the shows and of course the greatest girl band the world has and will ever see: The Spice Girls! The Spice girls in a way gathered all the pop life elements in their movie, mocking even themselves, they tried to show the world that this is all a fun ride and you must enjoy every minute of it while it lasts, and this is what they did in their 2 years world domination rally! You can't watch this movie though if you're a pop music or Spice Girls hater, if you are into pop and into light comedy and cheesy jokes then this movie is for your eyes only (a little wink to Roger Moore's cameo). Relax, get your best friend with whom you spent most of the 90's hearing ace of base and Take that on your CD player and enjoy this movie for old times sake! Now the acting, the plot, the script etc... They all fade into the background when you've got the Spice girls up front doing their thing! So stop complaining about this movie, it is not just another Oscar Submission, its supposed to be a funny ride and a silly joke for God's sake, lighten up and enjoy it for what it is!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The good, the bad, the Spice World movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dancingqueensw4
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a bit of a film fanatic, I was always of the opinion that no matter what the film, good or bad, it's worth watching. You can delight in the great ones and laugh at the ones that were really really awful. This film changed that opinion. I tried, but unlike any other film, I could not find it funny that I wasted my time watching it. It has NO plot. The acting was not just bad, it was so bad it made their singing ability look good... and they were playing themselves! Really, how hard can that be? Don't get me wrong, I'm aware it was suppose to be silly and not taken seriously, but I'm pretty sure it was also suppose to be entertaining... which it wasn't. It just bounced from boring scene to boring scene not linking them in anyway. Even if you like the spice girls, no amount of nostalgia would be worth watching this film. If you're looking for a walk down memory lane your better off watching Bugsy Malone, Labyrinth, Moonwalker, pretty much anything from the early 90s. Besides, this film made me forget what I liked about the spice girls in the first place. After watching this film, I went from a secret fan, to seeing the spice girls as the people that got me to spend my time and money on the worst film ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Spiced Up My Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tiffxrawr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film when I was seven and I still love it today. I think that for any Spice Girls fan, this was a great movie. The acting may not have been Oscar worthy, but I feel they did a great job making their audience laugh acting as themselves. Though some of the scenes could be considered corny or out of place, this film was overall very entertaining to its target audience: the fans. It is not for everyone. Just as I will never love the movie Purple Rain as much as my mother did due to her generation's love for Prince, not many will love Spice World the way Spice Girls fans do. The Spice Girls were positive role models in the 90's for girls like me. Scary Spice inspired me to love my huge curly hair. Sporty Spice inspired me to embrace my inner tom-boy. Their songs were catchy and widely popular for a while. Their movie venture may not have been as successful as their songs. However, it was not a total flop. Spice World had a wacky but interesting story line and a few compelling sub-story lines. This will always be considered one of my favorite movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teenybopper's Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I'm a 51 year old guy, and know this movie is (mostly) for teen girls, but I thought it was fun, especially when cute Emma Bunton and hot Victoria Adams (Beckham) were on screen. The S-Girls travel the world on their cool British bus show-casing their music (and their voluptuous bodies) and helping humankind get through the proverbial trials and tribulations of daily life. They even help deliver a baby! Wow! These chicks can do everything! Good songs, solid choreography, and a colorful presentation boosts this movie above Mundanesville. Cool movie, but cameos by John Elton and Hamburger Loaf were not needed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So What Do You Want? How About An Actual Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spice World (1997) 1/2 (out of 4) This here is pretty much a variation on A HARD DAY'S NIGHT but this time instead of John, Paul, George and Ringo we get Baby, Sporty, Ginger, Posh and Scary. Most movies made feature a credit that will read something to the effect of "story by..." but not this one. No, that credit is actually replaced by one that reads "idea by..." and that pretty much tells you everything you need to know. Really? The biggest pop female pop band that the world has ever seen and one that apparently made between $600-$800 million can only come up with a movie based on an idea? I guess it really doesn't matter that SPICE WORLD has been called one of the worst movies ever made because their fans ate it up when it was released and apparently they are still very fond of it. I guess if I was a die-hard fan of the group then I'd enjoy seeing them in anything no matter how bad it actually was. What makes this film so bad is that there really doesn't seem to be any idea of what this movie is supposed to be about. I'm sure it was an attempt to milk the success of the band and that's understandable. I just wish we had actually gotten a backstage look at the lives they were going through or at least gave us some sort of realistic look at the band. Instead we basically just get one long music video where the girls play their music and get to try on many different outfits. Nothing the five girls say are funny. Nothing they say is very interesting. In fact, nothing they do is all that entertaining. The movie actually reaches a level where it becomes painful to sit through it any longer. Heck, the girls can even lip-sync their songs and that well. SPICE WORLD doesn't quite earn a BOMB ranking thanks in large part to the girls being cute and wearing tight clothes but you can look at a magazine for this. The film itself is quite bad and sadly it never reaches a level to where you can just laugh at it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant fun movie for any Spice Girls fan!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexstinks
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film so much! I was brought up in the 90s listening to the Spice Girls and I was obsessed with them! I remember a family member bought me this on VHS and I loved it! It was just fun! Clearly it's not the type of movie that's supposed to be taken seriously. It is just supposed to be more of a spoof movie about the Spice Girls! I love the songs, costumes, crazy scenes! I also really enjoyed the cameo appearances from Meatloaf, Elton John and co. It was exciting for my as a child watching this. I love it even now! Brings back great memories! I can't fault it for what it is! It is just a piece of light hearted fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have heard nothing but negative things for this movie. But A friend of mine on YouTube named Cinema Sickness recommended this movie. So I bought it for a whopping 25 cents and here are my thoughts. The film is just about the 5 Spice Girls who try to help their friend deliver her first baby all while they are trying to get ready for a very big live performance. This is pretty stupid but you know what I had a lot of fun with it. If you are taking this movie to seriously well than you are not going to have any fun with any other movie. Although it is a very strange idea to make a movie about the Spice Girls. But Hey they made a movie about Hannah Montana and Justin Bieber so anything is possible.Plus I think that this movie is a little to risqu&eacute; for a PG Rating. I say check out this movie for some fun. This review is dedicated to Cinema Sickness(Your Welcome);). Rated PG For Some Vulgarity, Brief Nudity And Language. 1hr 33min/93min. ***1/2/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The oldest profession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Easton
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once upon a time there were The Spice Girls. They introduced us to 'girl power', a thinly disguised effort to use sex to sell manufactured pop music, potato chips and fizzy drinks to little kids and morons. And then there was this travesty of a movie. This is very much like other exploitation movies made to cash in on popular music groups in the past, but with all the good elements removed. There is nothing redeemable about this whatsoever, it's pure trash, and since the 'music' of The Spice Girls has no longevity neither does this. If you want to pick this up along with the girl's entire back catalogue of CDs, I recommend checking out the bargain bins in charity shops. You shouldn't have a problem finding it all, and then at least something positive will have come out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Gem - You need to look closely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanja_van_huet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was doubtful about this movie but my daughter insisted we watch it together. I was amazed at how art house it was  with throw backs to the old Beatles movie genre and other madcap '70's and 80's productions (Thunderbirds, the Monkees, etc). Apart from the catchy music and the generally enjoyable overacting  the all star cast makes it a genuine 'spot the actor' vehicle. (For example: this from http://filmbabble. blogspot.com/2007/06/20 -great-modern-movie-cameos.html : "Elvis Costello as a bartender and credited as 'Himself' Costello plays a nice tongue-in-cheek note as the Girls talk about their possible flash-in-the-pan prospects".) It spoofs everything about those bad movies we loved to watch  model buses jumping over model bridges, E.T. (the Movie) in 'bad green coats', the Magical Mystery Tour amazing bus, media moguls (Rupert Murdoch anyone?), Hollywood 'run and go' action movies, over-sexed Italian dancers etc. The more I watched the more I saw. I drove my daughter crazy pointing out ... 'hey that is a takeoff from ...'. If you are studying cinema or just have a movie trivia interest, Spice World certainly gives you more to argue about than Citizen Kain (sorry Orsen) or Pret-a-Porter (apologies to Robert too). If this movie was written by the Directors wife  she was a movie buff. It is better than you think!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool off the spice girls...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charlotte Younge
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, like all you fellow IMDb members, I'm a lover of a movies. But once in a while, a film like this should be making people laugh, not moan about the million things wrong with it. I haven't watched this flick in ages, but yesterday I was in a "take-a-look-at-stuff-from-the-past" mood, found the tape whilst doing my spring cleaning, and so I popped the tape in. I was a little biased the last time I watched it, being an 8 year old Spice Girls fanatic, but this time I took the film into serious consideration. Don't you get it? It's a satire about film making... And with the fabulous cameos (Elvis Costello, Elton John, MEATLOAF!! just to name a few..)how could you not love it? Just a teensy bit? Trust me, the British know film, and they know what they're doing with this one. Instead of showing one "real" side of the spice girls, they've shoved 50 years of stereotypical rubbish into one movie. You've got people trying to make a movie, a documentary, and the tabloids trying to break the girls apart, along with aliens, hot Italian models and random deja vus. All in one. So, cool off IMDb... if you don't take yourself too seriously and want to step back into the 90s for a good laugh, watch this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and light! A Good feel movie about Pop stars lives...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alain-aouad
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has everything related to the pop life in it, a comedic thrilling ride in the lives of a pop star band! The paparazzi, the fame, the fans, the back clash, the media, the managers, the shows and of course the greatest girl band the world has and will ever see: The Spice Girls! The Spice girls in a way gathered all the pop life elements in their movie, mocking even themselves, they tried to show the world that this is all a fun ride and you must enjoy every minute of it while it lasts, and this is what they did in their 2 years world domination rally! You can't watch this movie though if you're a pop music or Spice Girls hater, if you are into pop and into light comedy and cheesy jokes then this movie is for your eyes only (a little wink to Roger Moore's cameo). Relax, get your best friend with whom you spent most of the 90's hearing ace of base and Take that on your CD player and enjoy this movie for old times sake! Now the acting, the plot, the script etc... They all fade into the background when you've got the Spice girls up front doing their thing! So stop complaining about this movie, it is not just another Oscar Submission, its supposed to be a funny ride and a silly joke for God's sake, lighten up and enjoy it for what it is!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The good, the bad, the Spice World movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dancingqueensw4
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a bit of a film fanatic, I was always of the opinion that no matter what the film, good or bad, it's worth watching. You can delight in the great ones and laugh at the ones that were really really awful. This film changed that opinion. I tried, but unlike any other film, I could not find it funny that I wasted my time watching it. It has NO plot. The acting was not just bad, it was so bad it made their singing ability look good... and they were playing themselves! Really, how hard can that be? Don't get me wrong, I'm aware it was suppose to be silly and not taken seriously, but I'm pretty sure it was also suppose to be entertaining... which it wasn't. It just bounced from boring scene to boring scene not linking them in anyway. Even if you like the spice girls, no amount of nostalgia would be worth watching this film. If you're looking for a walk down memory lane your better off watching Bugsy Malone, Labyrinth, Moonwalker, pretty much anything from the early 90s. Besides, this film made me forget what I liked about the spice girls in the first place. After watching this film, I went from a secret fan, to seeing the spice girls as the people that got me to spend my time and money on the worst film ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Spiced Up My Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tiffxrawr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film when I was seven and I still love it today. I think that for any Spice Girls fan, this was a great movie. The acting may not have been Oscar worthy, but I feel they did a great job making their audience laugh acting as themselves. Though some of the scenes could be considered corny or out of place, this film was overall very entertaining to its target audience: the fans. It is not for everyone. Just as I will never love the movie Purple Rain as much as my mother did due to her generation's love for Prince, not many will love Spice World the way Spice Girls fans do. The Spice Girls were positive role models in the 90's for girls like me. Scary Spice inspired me to love my huge curly hair. Sporty Spice inspired me to embrace my inner tom-boy. Their songs were catchy and widely popular for a while. Their movie venture may not have been as successful as their songs. However, it was not a total flop. Spice World had a wacky but interesting story line and a few compelling sub-story lines. This will always be considered one of my favorite movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teenybopper's Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I'm a 51 year old guy, and know this movie is (mostly) for teen girls, but I thought it was fun, especially when cute Emma Bunton and hot Victoria Adams (Beckham) were on screen. The S-Girls travel the world on their cool British bus show-casing their music (and their voluptuous bodies) and helping humankind get through the proverbial trials and tribulations of daily life. They even help deliver a baby! Wow! These chicks can do everything! Good songs, solid choreography, and a colorful presentation boosts this movie above Mundanesville. Cool movie, but cameos by John Elton and Hamburger Loaf were not needed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So What Do You Want? How About An Actual Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spice World (1997) 1/2 (out of 4) This here is pretty much a variation on A HARD DAY'S NIGHT but this time instead of John, Paul, George and Ringo we get Baby, Sporty, Ginger, Posh and Scary. Most movies made feature a credit that will read something to the effect of "story by..." but not this one. No, that credit is actually replaced by one that reads "idea by..." and that pretty much tells you everything you need to know. Really? The biggest pop female pop band that the world has ever seen and one that apparently made between $600-$800 million can only come up with a movie based on an idea? I guess it really doesn't matter that SPICE WORLD has been called one of the worst movies ever made because their fans ate it up when it was released and apparently they are still very fond of it. I guess if I was a die-hard fan of the group then I'd enjoy seeing them in anything no matter how bad it actually was. What makes this film so bad is that there really doesn't seem to be any idea of what this movie is supposed to be about. I'm sure it was an attempt to milk the success of the band and that's understandable. I just wish we had actually gotten a backstage look at the lives they were going through or at least gave us some sort of realistic look at the band. Instead we basically just get one long music video where the girls play their music and get to try on many different outfits. Nothing the five girls say are funny. Nothing they say is very interesting. In fact, nothing they do is all that entertaining. The movie actually reaches a level where it becomes painful to sit through it any longer. Heck, the girls can even lip-sync their songs and that well. SPICE WORLD doesn't quite earn a BOMB ranking thanks in large part to the girls being cute and wearing tight clothes but you can look at a magazine for this. The film itself is quite bad and sadly it never reaches a level to where you can just laugh at it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant fun movie for any Spice Girls fan!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alexstinks
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film so much! I was brought up in the 90s listening to the Spice Girls and I was obsessed with them! I remember a family member bought me this on VHS and I loved it! It was just fun! Clearly it's not the type of movie that's supposed to be taken seriously. It is just supposed to be more of a spoof movie about the Spice Girls! I love the songs, costumes, crazy scenes! I also really enjoyed the cameo appearances from Meatloaf, Elton John and co. It was exciting for my as a child watching this. I love it even now! Brings back great memories! I can't fault it for what it is! It is just a piece of light hearted fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kylehaines96
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have heard nothing but negative things for this movie. But A friend of mine on YouTube named Cinema Sickness recommended this movie. So I bought it for a whopping 25 cents and here are my thoughts. The film is just about the 5 Spice Girls who try to help their friend deliver her first baby all while they are trying to get ready for a very big live performance. This is pretty stupid but you know what I had a lot of fun with it. If you are taking this movie to seriously well than you are not going to have any fun with any other movie. Although it is a very strange idea to make a movie about the Spice Girls. But Hey they made a movie about Hannah Montana and Justin Bieber so anything is possible.Plus I think that this movie is a little to risqu&eacute; for a PG Rating. I say check out this movie for some fun. This review is dedicated to Cinema Sickness(Your Welcome);). Rated PG For Some Vulgarity, Brief Nudity And Language. 1hr 33min/93min. ***1/2/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The oldest profession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Easton
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once upon a time there were The Spice Girls. They introduced us to 'girl power', a thinly disguised effort to use sex to sell manufactured pop music, potato chips and fizzy drinks to little kids and morons. And then there was this travesty of a movie. This is very much like other exploitation movies made to cash in on popular music groups in the past, but with all the good elements removed. There is nothing redeemable about this whatsoever, it's pure trash, and since the 'music' of The Spice Girls has no longevity neither does this. If you want to pick this up along with the girl's entire back catalogue of CDs, I recommend checking out the bargain bins in charity shops. You shouldn't have a problem finding it all, and then at least something positive will have come out of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hidden Gem - You need to look closely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanja_van_huet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was doubtful about this movie but my daughter insisted we watch it together. I was amazed at how art house it was  with throw backs to the old Beatles movie genre and other madcap '70's and 80's productions (Thunderbirds, the Monkees, etc). Apart from the catchy music and the generally enjoyable overacting  the all star cast makes it a genuine 'spot the actor' vehicle. (For example: this from http://filmbabble. blogspot.com/2007/06/20 -great-modern-movie-cameos.html : "Elvis Costello as a bartender and credited as 'Himself' Costello plays a nice tongue-in-cheek note as the Girls talk about their possible flash-in-the-pan prospects".) It spoofs everything about those bad movies we loved to watch  model buses jumping over model bridges, E.T. (the Movie) in 'bad green coats', the Magical Mystery Tour amazing bus, media moguls (Rupert Murdoch anyone?), Hollywood 'run and go' action movies, over-sexed Italian dancers etc. The more I watched the more I saw. I drove my daughter crazy pointing out ... 'hey that is a takeoff from ...'. If you are studying cinema or just have a movie trivia interest, Spice World certainly gives you more to argue about than Citizen Kain (sorry Orsen) or Pret-a-Porter (apologies to Robert too). If this movie was written by the Directors wife  she was a movie buff. It is better than you think!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cool off the spice girls...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charlotte Younge
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, like all you fellow IMDb members, I'm a lover of a movies. But once in a while, a film like this should be making people laugh, not moan about the million things wrong with it. I haven't watched this flick in ages, but yesterday I was in a "take-a-look-at-stuff-from-the-past" mood, found the tape whilst doing my spring cleaning, and so I popped the tape in. I was a little biased the last time I watched it, being an 8 year old Spice Girls fanatic, but this time I took the film into serious consideration. Don't you get it? It's a satire about film making... And with the fabulous cameos (Elvis Costello, Elton John, MEATLOAF!! just to name a few..)how could you not love it? Just a teensy bit? Trust me, the British know film, and they know what they're doing with this one. Instead of showing one "real" side of the spice girls, they've shoved 50 years of stereotypical rubbish into one movie. You've got people trying to make a movie, a documentary, and the tabloids trying to break the girls apart, along with aliens, hot Italian models and random deja vus. All in one. So, cool off IMDb... if you don't take yourself too seriously and want to step back into the 90s for a good laugh, watch this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and light! A Good feel movie about Pop stars lives...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alain-aouad
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has everything related to the pop life in it, a comedic thrilling ride in the lives of a pop star band! The paparazzi, the fame, the fans, the back clash, the media, the managers, the shows and of course the greatest girl band the world has and will ever see: The Spice Girls! The Spice girls in a way gathered all the pop life elements in their movie, mocking even themselves, they tried to show the world that this is all a fun ride and you must enjoy every minute of it while it lasts, and this is what they did in their 2 years world domination rally! You can't watch this movie though if you're a pop music or Spice Girls hater, if you are into pop and into light comedy and cheesy jokes then this movie is for your eyes only (a little wink to Roger Moore's cameo). Relax, get your best friend with whom you spent most of the 90's hearing ace of base and Take that on your CD player and enjoy this movie for old times sake! Now the acting, the plot, the script etc... They all fade into the background when you've got the Spice girls up front doing their thing! So stop complaining about this movie, it is not just another Oscar Submission, its supposed to be a funny ride and a silly joke for God's sake, lighten up and enjoy it for what it is!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The good, the bad, the Spice World movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dancingqueensw4
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a bit of a film fanatic, I was always of the opinion that no matter what the film, good or bad, it's worth watching. You can delight in the great ones and laugh at the ones that were really really awful. This film changed that opinion. I tried, but unlike any other film, I could not find it funny that I wasted my time watching it. It has NO plot. The acting was not just bad, it was so bad it made their singing ability look good... and they were playing themselves! Really, how hard can that be? Don't get me wrong, I'm aware it was suppose to be silly and not taken seriously, but I'm pretty sure it was also suppose to be entertaining... which it wasn't. It just bounced from boring scene to boring scene not linking them in anyway. Even if you like the spice girls, no amount of nostalgia would be worth watching this film. If you're looking for a walk down memory lane your better off watching Bugsy Malone, Labyrinth, Moonwalker, pretty much anything from the early 90s. Besides, this film made me forget what I liked about the spice girls in the first place. After watching this film, I went from a secret fan, to seeing the spice girls as the people that got me to spend my time and money on the worst film ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Spiced Up My Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tiffxrawr
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this film when I was seven and I still love it today. I think that for any Spice Girls fan, this was a great movie. The acting may not have been Oscar worthy, but I feel they did a great job making their audience laugh acting as themselves. Though some of the scenes could be considered corny or out of place, this film was overall very entertaining to its target audience: the fans. It is not for everyone. Just as I will never love the movie Purple Rain as much as my mother did due to her generation's love for Prince, not many will love Spice World the way Spice Girls fans do. The Spice Girls were positive role models in the 90's for girls like me. Scary Spice inspired me to love my huge curly hair. Sporty Spice inspired me to embrace my inner tom-boy. Their songs were catchy and widely popular for a while. Their movie venture may not have been as successful as their songs. However, it was not a total flop. Spice World had a wacky but interesting story line and a few compelling sub-story lines. This will always be considered one of my favorite movies
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
