<filme>
 <id>
  361
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119365
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Incognito
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Harry Donovan is an art forger who paints fake Rembrandt picture for $500,000. The girl he meets and gets into bed with in Paris, Marieke, turns out to be an arts expert Harry's clients are... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Harry Donovan is an art forger who paints fake Rembrandt picture for $500,000. The girl he meets and gets into bed with in Paris, Marieke, turns out to be an arts expert Harry's clients are using to check the counterfeit picture he painted.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   art
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   rembrandt
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   forger
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female nudity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Badham
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jordan Katz
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jason Patric
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ir&egrave;ne Jacob
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Thomas Lockyer
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a film for everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a film about art. and its roots as way to survive. a film about Rembrandt in a special style. and a love story. short - a clever film with elements of art history, thriller, crumbs of Hitchcock and full of beautiful images. not sophisticated but far to be disappointed. not special but far of waste of time.a perfect target for entertainment and, in same time, a lesson about beauty in not ordinary mode. adventures, secrets, various battles , good actors and flavor of correct work. its public - many slices of interest. because action near love, art near chase, conspiracies near industry of fake masterpieces, delicate homage to Rembrand near need to survive and, a beautiful couple are ingredients for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Acceptable Art Forgery thriller Starring Jason Patric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dfwforeignbuff
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Donovan is an art forger who paints fake Rembrandt picture for $500,000. The girl he meets & gets into bed with in Paris, Marieke turns out to be an arts expert. Harry's clients are using to check the counterfeit picture he painted. I knew this was going going to be a class A film but it does give a good the peek into the world of Art, Art History & Art Forgery. Anyone who considers themselves curious about Rembr&t, his place in the art world, & the art world's place in history will enjoy this movie. There are some interesting moments in this film, particularly for those who love art. The movie is actually much more complicated that the short summary I have provided. Jordan Katz's screenplay is full of authoritative, fascinating facts about how art is variously made, copied, authenticated & exposed as fake. 'Incognito' could serve as a handy tool for teaching courses in the detection of art forgery. Directed by John Badham, a Hollywood hack with a decent commercial track record (Saturday Night Fever, Short Circuit, War Games, Stakeout) Jason Patrick is really good in his role Patric is believable in his role as a suffering artist & skillfully shifts from unlikable to sympathetic. ; Irene Jacob is also good as his girlfriend (she is known for her films with Krzysztof Kieslowski) Rod Steiger plays a small role but still has the staying power of the great actor we know. The romance with Jacobs, who plays, Marieke van den Broeck, reminds us of a "39 Steps" Hitchcock kind of way. The European locales (Dutch, Spanish,Parisian) are very much like paintings & the director & cinematographer did a good job here. Too bad the DVD transfer was so poor. The film is well-directed. I found the DVD transfer poor & grainy etc. I guess in 1997 transfers were not as good as now. The movie looked pretty poor on my big screen HDTV. I think this film had limited release fared poorly & was sent right to DVD. Really I don't know why as it really a pretty acceptable thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Clever, Very Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fr8nk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You are roped into this movie within the first few minutes. It is very clever, entertaining, historical and informative. The acting is superb. I've watched this movie four times so far and would watch it again tonight to share it with someone special. My wife never watches a movie more than once but has viewed this one three times. Her comment was that there is something about this movie that makes you want to see it again. They should have eliminated the scene with the telephone booth because the lock on the outside of the booth made no sense at all. I don't know what they were thinking. But if you can overlook this one flaw you are in for a real treat. Ignore the few pans above and trust the people that gave it good reviews. My recommendation is that you buy the movie instead of renting it because you will want to watch it again and again. By the way, this is the first movie I have ever been tempted to submit a review for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total nonsense.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art forgery cloned into a James Bond" movie, with an utterly bad script. Coincidences abound, and everything seems totally contrived, like they started out with the ridiculous court scene, and then tried to make everything fit leading up to it. To think that a judge and jury would sit "spellbound" for hours on end watching Jason Patric paint a "masterpiece" in an afternoon is beyond ridiculous. And speaking of Jason Patric, his character is so unlikable that the only one to sympathize with is the long suffering audience. Rod Steiger is totally wasted, and so was my hour and forty eight minutes, watching this total nonsense. - Merk
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fails to Deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davegering
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has art forgery, romance and evasion from the law. It is the type of movie that I should like, but after a promising start, it fails to deliver very well on any of the themes. The forgery aspect is handled fairly well, although the writers seem not to have heard of diffraction spectroscopy or any of the other post-xray methods in use which would probably have detected the forgery without difficulty. This is the sort of oversight one could forgive if the other story elements were handled better. As Cecil B. DeMille once observed when a plot hole was pointed out to him, nobody will notice if you keep the movie going, because "you can't see the teeth on a buzzsaw." That is only true, however, when the saw is turned on and the teeth are in motion. In this film, the romance never feels right, and only serves to slow down the action. And when the buzzsaw is stopped, you can see the teeth. Similarly, the evasion segments amount to little more than darting out of windows and ducking into alleyways. Never very credible, it finally leads to a courtroom sequence which is pure rubbish, and a fairytale conclusion which would have embarrassed Walt Disney. I wanted to like this movie, and I tried to like it. Unfortunately, it failed to help me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, sad, sad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verdigris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I add to those little reviews I read? My rating speaks for itself; I'll just say it's been a couple of (more likely half-a-dozen)years since i saw it; and let me tell you I had to find it here, using the search engine... having been reminded of it by yet another oldie i watched on TV the other day. You get it? I couldn't even remember its title, but i vividly remembered - longed for - both leads' acting; the fairy-tale like plot. To me (and I'm glad to a handful of other viewers)this film is "something else", really. Pity those directors, those same creators haven't come up with more of the same. ...Well, it's pretty logical, given its dainty ephemeral character... PS. I have yet to obtain the actual DVD :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pleasant surprise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ruuk
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this piece on Czech TV. Although it was somewhat spoiled by translation, it caught my attention from the beginning till the finale. The cooperation of editing and screenplay is very good, it made me feel like watching some James Bond movies ... except this one was based on art, of course. I also loved the pace of this pleasantly surprising film, it flew with no significant faults. There are many films on TV in our country and majority of them are pure crap. Especially when you see them on midnight hour. This one was really pleasant and I am glad I spent my time with it. 7/10 Really watchable !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Different, But Like The Fake Painting You Know It Could Be Better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although sometimes way too slow-moving and not as involving as it should have been, this film was almost a "keeper" in my collection. The story was different, and I liked it, about an artist producing a fake Rembrandt. Jason Patric, an interesting and underrated actor, played the role on the con 'artist,' so to speak. Appealing-looking Irene Jacob, played the female lead. She was likable, unlike Patric's character. There are some interesting moments in this film, particularly for those who love art. There also are a few nice shots of Jacob that should please most male viewers. Overall, nothing that super but decent and worth a rental. It's different, I'll say that.....but don't expect a lot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Upscale Brit Crime Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's not as bad as I'd expected. It's one of those British crime dramas in which people walk around in Saville Row suits, visit Paris and Spain at will, and drive Jaguars -- and the plot centers around a fake Rembrandt painted by Jason Patric, who is double crossed by a couple of co-conspirators and aided by art expert Irene Jacob. The sociologist Dean Maccannel, in his book "The Tourist: A New Theory of the Leisure Class", has a delightful anecdote about a group of young American tourists in the Louvre or the Prado or someplace, noticing that a number of paintings were designated as having been executed by P. ignotus, Latin for "painter unknown." The kids loved P. Ignotus's work, rushing from hanging to hanging, exclaiming, "Oh, here's another one by Ignotus!" This has nothing to do with the movie unless I want to squeeze it in by saying that I was reminded of Maccannel's story by an argument the fakers are having near the beginning of the film. The production of this fake has taken a long time and Patric has not signed it as Rembrandt van Rijn. The others (who are supposed to be art experts) want him to sign it so they can be sure they'll palm it off as the real thing. But Patric knows (as they should) that not every artist signs every one of his works, Rembrandt included. Without the signature it is less likely to be obviously faked. (I think Michelangelo signed only one of his works, La Pieta, although flamboyantly.) It's kind of interesting to watch Patric fake the painting. Looks convincing enough to me, and I once won a prize for window painting in the 8th grade. The rest of the movie -- with the thieves and murderers in pursuit of Patric and Jacobs -- is kind of routine, with one or two scenes very redolent of Hitchcock. But there's nothing spectacularly WRONG with it. It simply doesn't seem too original and hasn't much in the way of sparkle. Except for Irene Jacob, the art expert who falls for Jason Patric for reasons that escape me because he looks quite ordinary. SHE doesn't though. I think it was Anthony Burgess who remarked of a chapter in James Joyce's Ulysses that "it may be gibberish but it's English gibberish." Something like that could be said of Jacob's face. She has even features but they are distinctly French even features. She has deep unripe-olive eyes, is not glamorized in any way, but is nevertheless striking, like the girl in a senior high school class that was only available to the captain of the football team. She has a slender modelesque figure with matching breasts. Badham, the director, is tasteful enough to have her disrobe on camera. The film ends in a trial which is pretty tense and enjoyable, although not in the slightest believable. On trial for murder, Patric has a chance to prove his innocence by reproducing the faked Rembrandt in court, which he can do in a jiffy. One afternoon, in fact. He is well on his way to succeeding, to the dismay of the prosecution and the satisfaction of his counsel, when he stops, throws his palette down, and refuses to go on because "Only Rembrandt can paint Rembrandt." Faking someone else's painting hasn't bothered him a whit before and, man, does this epiphany come at the wrong time. No matter. It's kind of enjoyable. Worth watching if it comes up but not worth working for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite surprising
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sveknu
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a typical B-thriller that airs on a Friday night. Because of that, my expectations for the movie weren't exactly huge. But I really felt enjoyed when watching this, it was in fact quite exciting. The story about a an art forger who fakes a Rembrandt picture is a quite good one, and was a relieving difference from most other B-thrillers. Although I doubt that the way he fakes the painting is possible in real life, it was very well made for this film. Remember, it's only a movie. The acting is mediocre. Not good, but not bad either. That doesn't matter much here, because it's the story that makes this a pretty good movie. The film takes place in Europe, something I liked for a change.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a film for everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a film about art. and its roots as way to survive. a film about Rembrandt in a special style. and a love story. short - a clever film with elements of art history, thriller, crumbs of Hitchcock and full of beautiful images. not sophisticated but far to be disappointed. not special but far of waste of time.a perfect target for entertainment and, in same time, a lesson about beauty in not ordinary mode. adventures, secrets, various battles , good actors and flavor of correct work. its public - many slices of interest. because action near love, art near chase, conspiracies near industry of fake masterpieces, delicate homage to Rembrand near need to survive and, a beautiful couple are ingredients for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Acceptable Art Forgery thriller Starring Jason Patric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dfwforeignbuff
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Donovan is an art forger who paints fake Rembrandt picture for $500,000. The girl he meets & gets into bed with in Paris, Marieke turns out to be an arts expert. Harry's clients are using to check the counterfeit picture he painted. I knew this was going going to be a class A film but it does give a good the peek into the world of Art, Art History & Art Forgery. Anyone who considers themselves curious about Rembr&t, his place in the art world, & the art world's place in history will enjoy this movie. There are some interesting moments in this film, particularly for those who love art. The movie is actually much more complicated that the short summary I have provided. Jordan Katz's screenplay is full of authoritative, fascinating facts about how art is variously made, copied, authenticated & exposed as fake. 'Incognito' could serve as a handy tool for teaching courses in the detection of art forgery. Directed by John Badham, a Hollywood hack with a decent commercial track record (Saturday Night Fever, Short Circuit, War Games, Stakeout) Jason Patrick is really good in his role Patric is believable in his role as a suffering artist & skillfully shifts from unlikable to sympathetic. ; Irene Jacob is also good as his girlfriend (she is known for her films with Krzysztof Kieslowski) Rod Steiger plays a small role but still has the staying power of the great actor we know. The romance with Jacobs, who plays, Marieke van den Broeck, reminds us of a "39 Steps" Hitchcock kind of way. The European locales (Dutch, Spanish,Parisian) are very much like paintings & the director & cinematographer did a good job here. Too bad the DVD transfer was so poor. The film is well-directed. I found the DVD transfer poor & grainy etc. I guess in 1997 transfers were not as good as now. The movie looked pretty poor on my big screen HDTV. I think this film had limited release fared poorly & was sent right to DVD. Really I don't know why as it really a pretty acceptable thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Clever, Very Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fr8nk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You are roped into this movie within the first few minutes. It is very clever, entertaining, historical and informative. The acting is superb. I've watched this movie four times so far and would watch it again tonight to share it with someone special. My wife never watches a movie more than once but has viewed this one three times. Her comment was that there is something about this movie that makes you want to see it again. They should have eliminated the scene with the telephone booth because the lock on the outside of the booth made no sense at all. I don't know what they were thinking. But if you can overlook this one flaw you are in for a real treat. Ignore the few pans above and trust the people that gave it good reviews. My recommendation is that you buy the movie instead of renting it because you will want to watch it again and again. By the way, this is the first movie I have ever been tempted to submit a review for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total nonsense.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art forgery cloned into a James Bond" movie, with an utterly bad script. Coincidences abound, and everything seems totally contrived, like they started out with the ridiculous court scene, and then tried to make everything fit leading up to it. To think that a judge and jury would sit "spellbound" for hours on end watching Jason Patric paint a "masterpiece" in an afternoon is beyond ridiculous. And speaking of Jason Patric, his character is so unlikable that the only one to sympathize with is the long suffering audience. Rod Steiger is totally wasted, and so was my hour and forty eight minutes, watching this total nonsense. - Merk
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fails to Deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davegering
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has art forgery, romance and evasion from the law. It is the type of movie that I should like, but after a promising start, it fails to deliver very well on any of the themes. The forgery aspect is handled fairly well, although the writers seem not to have heard of diffraction spectroscopy or any of the other post-xray methods in use which would probably have detected the forgery without difficulty. This is the sort of oversight one could forgive if the other story elements were handled better. As Cecil B. DeMille once observed when a plot hole was pointed out to him, nobody will notice if you keep the movie going, because "you can't see the teeth on a buzzsaw." That is only true, however, when the saw is turned on and the teeth are in motion. In this film, the romance never feels right, and only serves to slow down the action. And when the buzzsaw is stopped, you can see the teeth. Similarly, the evasion segments amount to little more than darting out of windows and ducking into alleyways. Never very credible, it finally leads to a courtroom sequence which is pure rubbish, and a fairytale conclusion which would have embarrassed Walt Disney. I wanted to like this movie, and I tried to like it. Unfortunately, it failed to help me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, sad, sad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verdigris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I add to those little reviews I read? My rating speaks for itself; I'll just say it's been a couple of (more likely half-a-dozen)years since i saw it; and let me tell you I had to find it here, using the search engine... having been reminded of it by yet another oldie i watched on TV the other day. You get it? I couldn't even remember its title, but i vividly remembered - longed for - both leads' acting; the fairy-tale like plot. To me (and I'm glad to a handful of other viewers)this film is "something else", really. Pity those directors, those same creators haven't come up with more of the same. ...Well, it's pretty logical, given its dainty ephemeral character... PS. I have yet to obtain the actual DVD :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pleasant surprise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ruuk
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this piece on Czech TV. Although it was somewhat spoiled by translation, it caught my attention from the beginning till the finale. The cooperation of editing and screenplay is very good, it made me feel like watching some James Bond movies ... except this one was based on art, of course. I also loved the pace of this pleasantly surprising film, it flew with no significant faults. There are many films on TV in our country and majority of them are pure crap. Especially when you see them on midnight hour. This one was really pleasant and I am glad I spent my time with it. 7/10 Really watchable !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Different, But Like The Fake Painting You Know It Could Be Better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although sometimes way too slow-moving and not as involving as it should have been, this film was almost a "keeper" in my collection. The story was different, and I liked it, about an artist producing a fake Rembrandt. Jason Patric, an interesting and underrated actor, played the role on the con 'artist,' so to speak. Appealing-looking Irene Jacob, played the female lead. She was likable, unlike Patric's character. There are some interesting moments in this film, particularly for those who love art. There also are a few nice shots of Jacob that should please most male viewers. Overall, nothing that super but decent and worth a rental. It's different, I'll say that.....but don't expect a lot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Upscale Brit Crime Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's not as bad as I'd expected. It's one of those British crime dramas in which people walk around in Saville Row suits, visit Paris and Spain at will, and drive Jaguars -- and the plot centers around a fake Rembrandt painted by Jason Patric, who is double crossed by a couple of co-conspirators and aided by art expert Irene Jacob. The sociologist Dean Maccannel, in his book "The Tourist: A New Theory of the Leisure Class", has a delightful anecdote about a group of young American tourists in the Louvre or the Prado or someplace, noticing that a number of paintings were designated as having been executed by P. ignotus, Latin for "painter unknown." The kids loved P. Ignotus's work, rushing from hanging to hanging, exclaiming, "Oh, here's another one by Ignotus!" This has nothing to do with the movie unless I want to squeeze it in by saying that I was reminded of Maccannel's story by an argument the fakers are having near the beginning of the film. The production of this fake has taken a long time and Patric has not signed it as Rembrandt van Rijn. The others (who are supposed to be art experts) want him to sign it so they can be sure they'll palm it off as the real thing. But Patric knows (as they should) that not every artist signs every one of his works, Rembrandt included. Without the signature it is less likely to be obviously faked. (I think Michelangelo signed only one of his works, La Pieta, although flamboyantly.) It's kind of interesting to watch Patric fake the painting. Looks convincing enough to me, and I once won a prize for window painting in the 8th grade. The rest of the movie -- with the thieves and murderers in pursuit of Patric and Jacobs -- is kind of routine, with one or two scenes very redolent of Hitchcock. But there's nothing spectacularly WRONG with it. It simply doesn't seem too original and hasn't much in the way of sparkle. Except for Irene Jacob, the art expert who falls for Jason Patric for reasons that escape me because he looks quite ordinary. SHE doesn't though. I think it was Anthony Burgess who remarked of a chapter in James Joyce's Ulysses that "it may be gibberish but it's English gibberish." Something like that could be said of Jacob's face. She has even features but they are distinctly French even features. She has deep unripe-olive eyes, is not glamorized in any way, but is nevertheless striking, like the girl in a senior high school class that was only available to the captain of the football team. She has a slender modelesque figure with matching breasts. Badham, the director, is tasteful enough to have her disrobe on camera. The film ends in a trial which is pretty tense and enjoyable, although not in the slightest believable. On trial for murder, Patric has a chance to prove his innocence by reproducing the faked Rembrandt in court, which he can do in a jiffy. One afternoon, in fact. He is well on his way to succeeding, to the dismay of the prosecution and the satisfaction of his counsel, when he stops, throws his palette down, and refuses to go on because "Only Rembrandt can paint Rembrandt." Faking someone else's painting hasn't bothered him a whit before and, man, does this epiphany come at the wrong time. No matter. It's kind of enjoyable. Worth watching if it comes up but not worth working for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite surprising
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sveknu
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a typical B-thriller that airs on a Friday night. Because of that, my expectations for the movie weren't exactly huge. But I really felt enjoyed when watching this, it was in fact quite exciting. The story about a an art forger who fakes a Rembrandt picture is a quite good one, and was a relieving difference from most other B-thrillers. Although I doubt that the way he fakes the painting is possible in real life, it was very well made for this film. Remember, it's only a movie. The acting is mediocre. Not good, but not bad either. That doesn't matter much here, because it's the story that makes this a pretty good movie. The film takes place in Europe, something I liked for a change.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a film for everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a film about art. and its roots as way to survive. a film about Rembrandt in a special style. and a love story. short - a clever film with elements of art history, thriller, crumbs of Hitchcock and full of beautiful images. not sophisticated but far to be disappointed. not special but far of waste of time.a perfect target for entertainment and, in same time, a lesson about beauty in not ordinary mode. adventures, secrets, various battles , good actors and flavor of correct work. its public - many slices of interest. because action near love, art near chase, conspiracies near industry of fake masterpieces, delicate homage to Rembrand near need to survive and, a beautiful couple are ingredients for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Acceptable Art Forgery thriller Starring Jason Patric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dfwforeignbuff
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Donovan is an art forger who paints fake Rembrandt picture for $500,000. The girl he meets & gets into bed with in Paris, Marieke turns out to be an arts expert. Harry's clients are using to check the counterfeit picture he painted. I knew this was going going to be a class A film but it does give a good the peek into the world of Art, Art History & Art Forgery. Anyone who considers themselves curious about Rembr&t, his place in the art world, & the art world's place in history will enjoy this movie. There are some interesting moments in this film, particularly for those who love art. The movie is actually much more complicated that the short summary I have provided. Jordan Katz's screenplay is full of authoritative, fascinating facts about how art is variously made, copied, authenticated & exposed as fake. 'Incognito' could serve as a handy tool for teaching courses in the detection of art forgery. Directed by John Badham, a Hollywood hack with a decent commercial track record (Saturday Night Fever, Short Circuit, War Games, Stakeout) Jason Patrick is really good in his role Patric is believable in his role as a suffering artist & skillfully shifts from unlikable to sympathetic. ; Irene Jacob is also good as his girlfriend (she is known for her films with Krzysztof Kieslowski) Rod Steiger plays a small role but still has the staying power of the great actor we know. The romance with Jacobs, who plays, Marieke van den Broeck, reminds us of a "39 Steps" Hitchcock kind of way. The European locales (Dutch, Spanish,Parisian) are very much like paintings & the director & cinematographer did a good job here. Too bad the DVD transfer was so poor. The film is well-directed. I found the DVD transfer poor & grainy etc. I guess in 1997 transfers were not as good as now. The movie looked pretty poor on my big screen HDTV. I think this film had limited release fared poorly & was sent right to DVD. Really I don't know why as it really a pretty acceptable thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Clever, Very Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fr8nk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You are roped into this movie within the first few minutes. It is very clever, entertaining, historical and informative. The acting is superb. I've watched this movie four times so far and would watch it again tonight to share it with someone special. My wife never watches a movie more than once but has viewed this one three times. Her comment was that there is something about this movie that makes you want to see it again. They should have eliminated the scene with the telephone booth because the lock on the outside of the booth made no sense at all. I don't know what they were thinking. But if you can overlook this one flaw you are in for a real treat. Ignore the few pans above and trust the people that gave it good reviews. My recommendation is that you buy the movie instead of renting it because you will want to watch it again and again. By the way, this is the first movie I have ever been tempted to submit a review for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total nonsense.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art forgery cloned into a James Bond" movie, with an utterly bad script. Coincidences abound, and everything seems totally contrived, like they started out with the ridiculous court scene, and then tried to make everything fit leading up to it. To think that a judge and jury would sit "spellbound" for hours on end watching Jason Patric paint a "masterpiece" in an afternoon is beyond ridiculous. And speaking of Jason Patric, his character is so unlikable that the only one to sympathize with is the long suffering audience. Rod Steiger is totally wasted, and so was my hour and forty eight minutes, watching this total nonsense. - Merk
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fails to Deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davegering
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has art forgery, romance and evasion from the law. It is the type of movie that I should like, but after a promising start, it fails to deliver very well on any of the themes. The forgery aspect is handled fairly well, although the writers seem not to have heard of diffraction spectroscopy or any of the other post-xray methods in use which would probably have detected the forgery without difficulty. This is the sort of oversight one could forgive if the other story elements were handled better. As Cecil B. DeMille once observed when a plot hole was pointed out to him, nobody will notice if you keep the movie going, because "you can't see the teeth on a buzzsaw." That is only true, however, when the saw is turned on and the teeth are in motion. In this film, the romance never feels right, and only serves to slow down the action. And when the buzzsaw is stopped, you can see the teeth. Similarly, the evasion segments amount to little more than darting out of windows and ducking into alleyways. Never very credible, it finally leads to a courtroom sequence which is pure rubbish, and a fairytale conclusion which would have embarrassed Walt Disney. I wanted to like this movie, and I tried to like it. Unfortunately, it failed to help me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, sad, sad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verdigris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I add to those little reviews I read? My rating speaks for itself; I'll just say it's been a couple of (more likely half-a-dozen)years since i saw it; and let me tell you I had to find it here, using the search engine... having been reminded of it by yet another oldie i watched on TV the other day. You get it? I couldn't even remember its title, but i vividly remembered - longed for - both leads' acting; the fairy-tale like plot. To me (and I'm glad to a handful of other viewers)this film is "something else", really. Pity those directors, those same creators haven't come up with more of the same. ...Well, it's pretty logical, given its dainty ephemeral character... PS. I have yet to obtain the actual DVD :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pleasant surprise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ruuk
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this piece on Czech TV. Although it was somewhat spoiled by translation, it caught my attention from the beginning till the finale. The cooperation of editing and screenplay is very good, it made me feel like watching some James Bond movies ... except this one was based on art, of course. I also loved the pace of this pleasantly surprising film, it flew with no significant faults. There are many films on TV in our country and majority of them are pure crap. Especially when you see them on midnight hour. This one was really pleasant and I am glad I spent my time with it. 7/10 Really watchable !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Different, But Like The Fake Painting You Know It Could Be Better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although sometimes way too slow-moving and not as involving as it should have been, this film was almost a "keeper" in my collection. The story was different, and I liked it, about an artist producing a fake Rembrandt. Jason Patric, an interesting and underrated actor, played the role on the con 'artist,' so to speak. Appealing-looking Irene Jacob, played the female lead. She was likable, unlike Patric's character. There are some interesting moments in this film, particularly for those who love art. There also are a few nice shots of Jacob that should please most male viewers. Overall, nothing that super but decent and worth a rental. It's different, I'll say that.....but don't expect a lot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Upscale Brit Crime Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's not as bad as I'd expected. It's one of those British crime dramas in which people walk around in Saville Row suits, visit Paris and Spain at will, and drive Jaguars -- and the plot centers around a fake Rembrandt painted by Jason Patric, who is double crossed by a couple of co-conspirators and aided by art expert Irene Jacob. The sociologist Dean Maccannel, in his book "The Tourist: A New Theory of the Leisure Class", has a delightful anecdote about a group of young American tourists in the Louvre or the Prado or someplace, noticing that a number of paintings were designated as having been executed by P. ignotus, Latin for "painter unknown." The kids loved P. Ignotus's work, rushing from hanging to hanging, exclaiming, "Oh, here's another one by Ignotus!" This has nothing to do with the movie unless I want to squeeze it in by saying that I was reminded of Maccannel's story by an argument the fakers are having near the beginning of the film. The production of this fake has taken a long time and Patric has not signed it as Rembrandt van Rijn. The others (who are supposed to be art experts) want him to sign it so they can be sure they'll palm it off as the real thing. But Patric knows (as they should) that not every artist signs every one of his works, Rembrandt included. Without the signature it is less likely to be obviously faked. (I think Michelangelo signed only one of his works, La Pieta, although flamboyantly.) It's kind of interesting to watch Patric fake the painting. Looks convincing enough to me, and I once won a prize for window painting in the 8th grade. The rest of the movie -- with the thieves and murderers in pursuit of Patric and Jacobs -- is kind of routine, with one or two scenes very redolent of Hitchcock. But there's nothing spectacularly WRONG with it. It simply doesn't seem too original and hasn't much in the way of sparkle. Except for Irene Jacob, the art expert who falls for Jason Patric for reasons that escape me because he looks quite ordinary. SHE doesn't though. I think it was Anthony Burgess who remarked of a chapter in James Joyce's Ulysses that "it may be gibberish but it's English gibberish." Something like that could be said of Jacob's face. She has even features but they are distinctly French even features. She has deep unripe-olive eyes, is not glamorized in any way, but is nevertheless striking, like the girl in a senior high school class that was only available to the captain of the football team. She has a slender modelesque figure with matching breasts. Badham, the director, is tasteful enough to have her disrobe on camera. The film ends in a trial which is pretty tense and enjoyable, although not in the slightest believable. On trial for murder, Patric has a chance to prove his innocence by reproducing the faked Rembrandt in court, which he can do in a jiffy. One afternoon, in fact. He is well on his way to succeeding, to the dismay of the prosecution and the satisfaction of his counsel, when he stops, throws his palette down, and refuses to go on because "Only Rembrandt can paint Rembrandt." Faking someone else's painting hasn't bothered him a whit before and, man, does this epiphany come at the wrong time. No matter. It's kind of enjoyable. Worth watching if it comes up but not worth working for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite surprising
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sveknu
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a typical B-thriller that airs on a Friday night. Because of that, my expectations for the movie weren't exactly huge. But I really felt enjoyed when watching this, it was in fact quite exciting. The story about a an art forger who fakes a Rembrandt picture is a quite good one, and was a relieving difference from most other B-thrillers. Although I doubt that the way he fakes the painting is possible in real life, it was very well made for this film. Remember, it's only a movie. The acting is mediocre. Not good, but not bad either. That doesn't matter much here, because it's the story that makes this a pretty good movie. The film takes place in Europe, something I liked for a change.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a film for everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a film about art. and its roots as way to survive. a film about Rembrandt in a special style. and a love story. short - a clever film with elements of art history, thriller, crumbs of Hitchcock and full of beautiful images. not sophisticated but far to be disappointed. not special but far of waste of time.a perfect target for entertainment and, in same time, a lesson about beauty in not ordinary mode. adventures, secrets, various battles , good actors and flavor of correct work. its public - many slices of interest. because action near love, art near chase, conspiracies near industry of fake masterpieces, delicate homage to Rembrand near need to survive and, a beautiful couple are ingredients for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Acceptable Art Forgery thriller Starring Jason Patric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dfwforeignbuff
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harry Donovan is an art forger who paints fake Rembrandt picture for $500,000. The girl he meets & gets into bed with in Paris, Marieke turns out to be an arts expert. Harry's clients are using to check the counterfeit picture he painted. I knew this was going going to be a class A film but it does give a good the peek into the world of Art, Art History & Art Forgery. Anyone who considers themselves curious about Rembr&t, his place in the art world, & the art world's place in history will enjoy this movie. There are some interesting moments in this film, particularly for those who love art. The movie is actually much more complicated that the short summary I have provided. Jordan Katz's screenplay is full of authoritative, fascinating facts about how art is variously made, copied, authenticated & exposed as fake. 'Incognito' could serve as a handy tool for teaching courses in the detection of art forgery. Directed by John Badham, a Hollywood hack with a decent commercial track record (Saturday Night Fever, Short Circuit, War Games, Stakeout) Jason Patrick is really good in his role Patric is believable in his role as a suffering artist & skillfully shifts from unlikable to sympathetic. ; Irene Jacob is also good as his girlfriend (she is known for her films with Krzysztof Kieslowski) Rod Steiger plays a small role but still has the staying power of the great actor we know. The romance with Jacobs, who plays, Marieke van den Broeck, reminds us of a "39 Steps" Hitchcock kind of way. The European locales (Dutch, Spanish,Parisian) are very much like paintings & the director & cinematographer did a good job here. Too bad the DVD transfer was so poor. The film is well-directed. I found the DVD transfer poor & grainy etc. I guess in 1997 transfers were not as good as now. The movie looked pretty poor on my big screen HDTV. I think this film had limited release fared poorly & was sent right to DVD. Really I don't know why as it really a pretty acceptable thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Clever, Very Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fr8nk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You are roped into this movie within the first few minutes. It is very clever, entertaining, historical and informative. The acting is superb. I've watched this movie four times so far and would watch it again tonight to share it with someone special. My wife never watches a movie more than once but has viewed this one three times. Her comment was that there is something about this movie that makes you want to see it again. They should have eliminated the scene with the telephone booth because the lock on the outside of the booth made no sense at all. I don't know what they were thinking. But if you can overlook this one flaw you are in for a real treat. Ignore the few pans above and trust the people that gave it good reviews. My recommendation is that you buy the movie instead of renting it because you will want to watch it again and again. By the way, this is the first movie I have ever been tempted to submit a review for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total nonsense.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art forgery cloned into a James Bond" movie, with an utterly bad script. Coincidences abound, and everything seems totally contrived, like they started out with the ridiculous court scene, and then tried to make everything fit leading up to it. To think that a judge and jury would sit "spellbound" for hours on end watching Jason Patric paint a "masterpiece" in an afternoon is beyond ridiculous. And speaking of Jason Patric, his character is so unlikable that the only one to sympathize with is the long suffering audience. Rod Steiger is totally wasted, and so was my hour and forty eight minutes, watching this total nonsense. - Merk
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fails to Deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davegering
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has art forgery, romance and evasion from the law. It is the type of movie that I should like, but after a promising start, it fails to deliver very well on any of the themes. The forgery aspect is handled fairly well, although the writers seem not to have heard of diffraction spectroscopy or any of the other post-xray methods in use which would probably have detected the forgery without difficulty. This is the sort of oversight one could forgive if the other story elements were handled better. As Cecil B. DeMille once observed when a plot hole was pointed out to him, nobody will notice if you keep the movie going, because "you can't see the teeth on a buzzsaw." That is only true, however, when the saw is turned on and the teeth are in motion. In this film, the romance never feels right, and only serves to slow down the action. And when the buzzsaw is stopped, you can see the teeth. Similarly, the evasion segments amount to little more than darting out of windows and ducking into alleyways. Never very credible, it finally leads to a courtroom sequence which is pure rubbish, and a fairytale conclusion which would have embarrassed Walt Disney. I wanted to like this movie, and I tried to like it. Unfortunately, it failed to help me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sad, sad, sad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verdigris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I add to those little reviews I read? My rating speaks for itself; I'll just say it's been a couple of (more likely half-a-dozen)years since i saw it; and let me tell you I had to find it here, using the search engine... having been reminded of it by yet another oldie i watched on TV the other day. You get it? I couldn't even remember its title, but i vividly remembered - longed for - both leads' acting; the fairy-tale like plot. To me (and I'm glad to a handful of other viewers)this film is "something else", really. Pity those directors, those same creators haven't come up with more of the same. ...Well, it's pretty logical, given its dainty ephemeral character... PS. I have yet to obtain the actual DVD :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pleasant surprise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ruuk
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this piece on Czech TV. Although it was somewhat spoiled by translation, it caught my attention from the beginning till the finale. The cooperation of editing and screenplay is very good, it made me feel like watching some James Bond movies ... except this one was based on art, of course. I also loved the pace of this pleasantly surprising film, it flew with no significant faults. There are many films on TV in our country and majority of them are pure crap. Especially when you see them on midnight hour. This one was really pleasant and I am glad I spent my time with it. 7/10 Really watchable !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Different, But Like The Fake Painting You Know It Could Be Better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although sometimes way too slow-moving and not as involving as it should have been, this film was almost a "keeper" in my collection. The story was different, and I liked it, about an artist producing a fake Rembrandt. Jason Patric, an interesting and underrated actor, played the role on the con 'artist,' so to speak. Appealing-looking Irene Jacob, played the female lead. She was likable, unlike Patric's character. There are some interesting moments in this film, particularly for those who love art. There also are a few nice shots of Jacob that should please most male viewers. Overall, nothing that super but decent and worth a rental. It's different, I'll say that.....but don't expect a lot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Upscale Brit Crime Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's not as bad as I'd expected. It's one of those British crime dramas in which people walk around in Saville Row suits, visit Paris and Spain at will, and drive Jaguars -- and the plot centers around a fake Rembrandt painted by Jason Patric, who is double crossed by a couple of co-conspirators and aided by art expert Irene Jacob. The sociologist Dean Maccannel, in his book "The Tourist: A New Theory of the Leisure Class", has a delightful anecdote about a group of young American tourists in the Louvre or the Prado or someplace, noticing that a number of paintings were designated as having been executed by P. ignotus, Latin for "painter unknown." The kids loved P. Ignotus's work, rushing from hanging to hanging, exclaiming, "Oh, here's another one by Ignotus!" This has nothing to do with the movie unless I want to squeeze it in by saying that I was reminded of Maccannel's story by an argument the fakers are having near the beginning of the film. The production of this fake has taken a long time and Patric has not signed it as Rembrandt van Rijn. The others (who are supposed to be art experts) want him to sign it so they can be sure they'll palm it off as the real thing. But Patric knows (as they should) that not every artist signs every one of his works, Rembrandt included. Without the signature it is less likely to be obviously faked. (I think Michelangelo signed only one of his works, La Pieta, although flamboyantly.) It's kind of interesting to watch Patric fake the painting. Looks convincing enough to me, and I once won a prize for window painting in the 8th grade. The rest of the movie -- with the thieves and murderers in pursuit of Patric and Jacobs -- is kind of routine, with one or two scenes very redolent of Hitchcock. But there's nothing spectacularly WRONG with it. It simply doesn't seem too original and hasn't much in the way of sparkle. Except for Irene Jacob, the art expert who falls for Jason Patric for reasons that escape me because he looks quite ordinary. SHE doesn't though. I think it was Anthony Burgess who remarked of a chapter in James Joyce's Ulysses that "it may be gibberish but it's English gibberish." Something like that could be said of Jacob's face. She has even features but they are distinctly French even features. She has deep unripe-olive eyes, is not glamorized in any way, but is nevertheless striking, like the girl in a senior high school class that was only available to the captain of the football team. She has a slender modelesque figure with matching breasts. Badham, the director, is tasteful enough to have her disrobe on camera. The film ends in a trial which is pretty tense and enjoyable, although not in the slightest believable. On trial for murder, Patric has a chance to prove his innocence by reproducing the faked Rembrandt in court, which he can do in a jiffy. One afternoon, in fact. He is well on his way to succeeding, to the dismay of the prosecution and the satisfaction of his counsel, when he stops, throws his palette down, and refuses to go on because "Only Rembrandt can paint Rembrandt." Faking someone else's painting hasn't bothered him a whit before and, man, does this epiphany come at the wrong time. No matter. It's kind of enjoyable. Worth watching if it comes up but not worth working for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite surprising
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sveknu
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a typical B-thriller that airs on a Friday night. Because of that, my expectations for the movie weren't exactly huge. But I really felt enjoyed when watching this, it was in fact quite exciting. The story about a an art forger who fakes a Rembrandt picture is a quite good one, and was a relieving difference from most other B-thrillers. Although I doubt that the way he fakes the painting is possible in real life, it was very well made for this film. Remember, it's only a movie. The acting is mediocre. Not good, but not bad either. That doesn't matter much here, because it's the story that makes this a pretty good movie. The film takes place in Europe, something I liked for a change.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
