<filme>
 <id>
  364
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112281
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Ace Ventura 2 - Um Maluco na &Aacute;frica
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Pet detective Ace Ventura comes out of retirement to investigate the disappearance of a rare white bat, the symbol of an African tribe.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Ace Ventura, emerging from self-imposed exile in a remote Himalayan hideaway, travels to Africa with explorer Fulton Greenwall to find a sacred bat which is told will avert a war between with Wachootoo and Wachati tribes. Of course, when Ace gets involved, all hell breaks loose...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   africa
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   african tribe
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dead animal
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Steve Oedekerk
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jack Bernstein
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Steve Oedekerk
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jim Carrey
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ian McNeice
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Simon Callow
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey Love Him or Hate Him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kikabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey is one of those actors you will find yourself either adoring or hating. He does not ever "underact." This movie made me laugh so hard I cried (even after the fifth time!) From the robot rhino scene to the monopoly guy Jim knows how to be hilarious. I saw the first one (liked it allot) and have to say this one is way better! I am a huge fan of Carrey. I don't think there are many people who can make such a variety of facial expressions. The only reason this is not a ten is because there is (as usual with Carrey) some inappropriate stuff thrown in. But if your love laughing and you love Jim, this movie will fit you "Like a glove!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure Pet Detective Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This inevitable sequel finds Jim Carrey reprises his role as the title character Ace Ventura, a detective who specializes in retrieval of tame or captive animals in Ace Ventura:When Nature Calls. Ian McNeice,Simon Callow,Maynard Eziashi,Bob Gunton,Sophie Okonedo and Tommy Davidson play key supporting roles.His latest case, the disappearance of a rare African white bat, draws him out of his spiritual retreat at a Tibetan monastery following the tragic outcome of his previous case. Ace Ventura is on assignment in Africa to prevent a tribal war by saving a white bat sacred to both sides. Along the way, he nearly sleeps with a seductive African princess before her wedding, experiences astral projection with an enlightened monkey, masturbates, collects bat dung and, last but not least, is birthed by a mechanical rhino. Often short on taste, the film is nonetheless full of good spirit and plenty of genuine belly laughs particularly during the fight scene with a diminutive tribal champion. Not for every taste, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is either hilarious or insufferable, depending on the viewer's opinion of Carrey's unique brand of slapstick and sight gags. If you're ready to laugh like a pack of hyenas, if you want more fun than an industrial-sized barrel of monkeys, you know what to do.Watch this film for that reason and also for guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Racist and stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    almbjaer-107-905553
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a kid I loved the first Ace Ventura movie. I remember not being as fond of the second one but that was mainly because I loved the first one so much. I've then rewatched the first one and actually thought it was kind of funny. Today I rewatched the second movie and seriously, it's just appallingly racist and stupid. It basically repeats the famous lines from the first movie (really, like a glove etc) and in between, it depicts people in Africa like a 50s documentary. If anyone thinks this movie is really funny, they should never be allowed to watch a movie again. Basically, they should forfeit their sight and give it to blind people so that they can use it to watch better movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but doesn't live up to the original,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura When Nature Calls is a good,funny movie,but doesn't live up to the original movie,it would probably be a lot better if it didn't have Ace Ventura Pet Detective to compare to.Jim Carrey usually saves these movies with his high energy and comedy,I felt to same way about Me,Myself and Irene,they just would not be the same without Jim Carrey,because he is one of my favorite actors and never fails to make me laugh.Currently the only sequel Jim Carrey has ever done. Ace Ventura (Jim Carrey) comes out of retirement to help find a missing white bat who is the symbol of an African tribe.He finds himself in more trouble than he expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Almost Perfect Sequel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A year before this sequel, we were introduced to Ace Ventura; a rude, wise cracking pet detective who has the reputation for being the ONLY pet detective. Guess what? He's back and still has every quality he had in the original. I know, it sounds like there's a catch here. Well there is not-at least with Jim Carrey's character. I did not like this movie as much as the original for one reason and one reason only. No it wasn't that Courtney Cox didn't reprise her role as Melissa Robinson. That I can deal with. My problem was that the story involved some characters that made Ace Ventura's character seem stupid. What made the original funny was that Ace Ventura was on top of his game. He knew what he was doing and how he was doing it. What also made it funny was that nobody ELSE knew what he was doing and although it seemed strange, Ventura got the job done. This occurred throughout the entire first film. And that's how it goes for most of this movie. The part of the movie that I think either did not need to be added or could have been modified was when Ace Ventura was among the African Tribes. What was so hard for me grasp was that in the first movie, they took a smart crazy detective and put him around a bunch of normal people that understood nothing of what he did. When Ventura is around the Tribe members, he is the dumb crazy detective. Why do I say this? Because Jim Carrey's character does not speak their language. It is this major flaw of why some of the laughs fail in this movie for me. For example, when Ventura starts to eat the food at the tribe's festival, he does not realize what he was eating until he is told what it really was. I thought Ventura was the smart one here? The whole point of the first film was so that the joke would be on everyone else; now the roles are switched? Why? Does the laugh really need to be on our comedic hero? It was at that point I started to wonder whether Ace really knew what he was doing. Of course these kinds of instances did not happen all the time. There were many parts where Ventura was surrounded by upper class people who thought they were better than he was and just like the first film he proved them wrong with a snotty remark and an obscene gesture. That's the old Ace I know! That is what made Ace Ventura such a character. Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is almost a perfect sequel. It still has good laughs but it is dumbed down by its mediocre screenplay. It is because of this that Ace Ventura does not seem always on top of everyone else like he was in the first film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the reasons not to make a sequel..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mbat19
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura pet detective was a surprise hit which of course means it would lead to the inevitable sequel and voila here it is Ace Ventura When Nature Calls. Unfortunately, they should not have answered. While the first Ace Ventura was entertaining light and charming in its ways and was dumb and knew it was dumb and played off of it, this one tries way too hard and the jokes for the most part fall flat and some fall very very flat to the point that the movie is almost racist in parts. If you must see an ace ventura double feature, see the first one twice. My true rating for this is a zero, but their scale does not go that low.. This one is for the birds..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wildly uneven Carrey vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I consider Ace Ventura When Nature Calls to be the 'acid test' for Jim Carrey devotees who claim unconditional love for the man's work: anyone who can sit through this film in its entirety without feeling even the slightest tinge of annoyance at Carrey's wildly unrestrained performance, which sees the manic star seemingly knowing no bounds when it comes to acting the fool, genuinely deserves the perhaps rather dubious honour of being dubbed a true 'Super Fan'. As to whether the film should be considered by your more casual Carrey fan, I say give it a go if you're feeling brave: its worth enduring the embarrassingly bad moments to be able to savour the genuinely funny bits, which very occasionally border on comic genius (just try keeping a straight face as Carrey escapes from his mechanical rhino disguise or goes head to head in combat with a savage African native). 5.5, rounded up to 6 for having a monkey tied to a raft, a masturbation gag in a PG flick (try explaining that one to the kids!), and the Monopoly guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gravy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neenahhh
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! It's kind of on the same level as the first movie. Both movies made me laugh out loud. This film features your different kind of humor. The humor in these films isn't your usual fast wit kind. It's the slapstick kind of comedy where things actually happen. People were hit, people were made fun of, people had stuff done to them, etc. It also includes crude humor. Different and kind of rude, but still hilarious. The plot wasn't exactly A+, but the humor made up for it. I mean, really. It did. Jim Carrey saved this movie. Jim Carrey was really perfect for this role. Crazy-ass Ace Ventura. Who else can play such a part?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Actually, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is not quite as bad as this summary suggests. Though that is not to say that this film is good, for me it isn't. The film does look good, it was interesting to see the likes of Simon Callow and he especially does bring some dignity and like in the first Jim Carrey does a fine job carrying the film. However the plot is very predictable and flimsy, and the direction lacks the energy and imagination of that of the first. The film also could have done with being longer consequently some of the characters lacked credibility. Also the pace is not as snappy and smart, when the humour fell flat(like it did one too many times) it felt like a balloon had been popped. The slapstick is very juvenile here, while the script is more childish than sophisticated and for me that was a bad idea. Overall, disappointing but thanks to Carrey it is at least watchable if nothing to go wild about. 4/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much much much better than the first one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rare bat is stolen from a tribe in the jungle and Ventura is called in to find it. He soon learns that the bat isn't his motives for being there, but he is actually there for something else completely at which time his true detective skills surface so he can get to the bottom of this. This movie made me laugh a few times, which the first didn't. I still think it is a horrible movie with a lot of over the top acting and so stupid that only a 5 year old should watch it. It had a couple laughs though so I can't completely hate it. Steve did such a better job directing than the guy from the first one. This movie actually had a better story, better settings, the antics were less and it was more serious, It had much more to offer. The movie was bad but several things made me like it enough to give it a higher rating than part 1, which I gave 1 out of 10 stars. I liked the parody of Cliffhanger, I loved the joke made referencing the Twilight Zone episode with William Shatner, I loved the part where he wears the little man around his neck to mock the woman with the fur and I laughed at him squeezing out of a tiny hole in the butt of a rubber Rhino. The acting was better, Carrey went from 350 grand on the first film to 5 million on this one. Adawale had a small role and I think he is a great actor and Tommy Davidson who had worked many times with Carrey on IN LIVING COLOR did a great job as the tiny warrior. These two movies were big, and spawned so many catch phrases but it just isn't my thing - my true vote is 1.5 out of 10 stars but I went ahead and gave it 2 here on IMDb to let myself know in the future that I liked it better than the first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey Love Him or Hate Him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kikabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey is one of those actors you will find yourself either adoring or hating. He does not ever "underact." This movie made me laugh so hard I cried (even after the fifth time!) From the robot rhino scene to the monopoly guy Jim knows how to be hilarious. I saw the first one (liked it allot) and have to say this one is way better! I am a huge fan of Carrey. I don't think there are many people who can make such a variety of facial expressions. The only reason this is not a ten is because there is (as usual with Carrey) some inappropriate stuff thrown in. But if your love laughing and you love Jim, this movie will fit you "Like a glove!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure Pet Detective Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This inevitable sequel finds Jim Carrey reprises his role as the title character Ace Ventura, a detective who specializes in retrieval of tame or captive animals in Ace Ventura:When Nature Calls. Ian McNeice,Simon Callow,Maynard Eziashi,Bob Gunton,Sophie Okonedo and Tommy Davidson play key supporting roles.His latest case, the disappearance of a rare African white bat, draws him out of his spiritual retreat at a Tibetan monastery following the tragic outcome of his previous case. Ace Ventura is on assignment in Africa to prevent a tribal war by saving a white bat sacred to both sides. Along the way, he nearly sleeps with a seductive African princess before her wedding, experiences astral projection with an enlightened monkey, masturbates, collects bat dung and, last but not least, is birthed by a mechanical rhino. Often short on taste, the film is nonetheless full of good spirit and plenty of genuine belly laughs particularly during the fight scene with a diminutive tribal champion. Not for every taste, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is either hilarious or insufferable, depending on the viewer's opinion of Carrey's unique brand of slapstick and sight gags. If you're ready to laugh like a pack of hyenas, if you want more fun than an industrial-sized barrel of monkeys, you know what to do.Watch this film for that reason and also for guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Racist and stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    almbjaer-107-905553
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a kid I loved the first Ace Ventura movie. I remember not being as fond of the second one but that was mainly because I loved the first one so much. I've then rewatched the first one and actually thought it was kind of funny. Today I rewatched the second movie and seriously, it's just appallingly racist and stupid. It basically repeats the famous lines from the first movie (really, like a glove etc) and in between, it depicts people in Africa like a 50s documentary. If anyone thinks this movie is really funny, they should never be allowed to watch a movie again. Basically, they should forfeit their sight and give it to blind people so that they can use it to watch better movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but doesn't live up to the original,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura When Nature Calls is a good,funny movie,but doesn't live up to the original movie,it would probably be a lot better if it didn't have Ace Ventura Pet Detective to compare to.Jim Carrey usually saves these movies with his high energy and comedy,I felt to same way about Me,Myself and Irene,they just would not be the same without Jim Carrey,because he is one of my favorite actors and never fails to make me laugh.Currently the only sequel Jim Carrey has ever done. Ace Ventura (Jim Carrey) comes out of retirement to help find a missing white bat who is the symbol of an African tribe.He finds himself in more trouble than he expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Almost Perfect Sequel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A year before this sequel, we were introduced to Ace Ventura; a rude, wise cracking pet detective who has the reputation for being the ONLY pet detective. Guess what? He's back and still has every quality he had in the original. I know, it sounds like there's a catch here. Well there is not-at least with Jim Carrey's character. I did not like this movie as much as the original for one reason and one reason only. No it wasn't that Courtney Cox didn't reprise her role as Melissa Robinson. That I can deal with. My problem was that the story involved some characters that made Ace Ventura's character seem stupid. What made the original funny was that Ace Ventura was on top of his game. He knew what he was doing and how he was doing it. What also made it funny was that nobody ELSE knew what he was doing and although it seemed strange, Ventura got the job done. This occurred throughout the entire first film. And that's how it goes for most of this movie. The part of the movie that I think either did not need to be added or could have been modified was when Ace Ventura was among the African Tribes. What was so hard for me grasp was that in the first movie, they took a smart crazy detective and put him around a bunch of normal people that understood nothing of what he did. When Ventura is around the Tribe members, he is the dumb crazy detective. Why do I say this? Because Jim Carrey's character does not speak their language. It is this major flaw of why some of the laughs fail in this movie for me. For example, when Ventura starts to eat the food at the tribe's festival, he does not realize what he was eating until he is told what it really was. I thought Ventura was the smart one here? The whole point of the first film was so that the joke would be on everyone else; now the roles are switched? Why? Does the laugh really need to be on our comedic hero? It was at that point I started to wonder whether Ace really knew what he was doing. Of course these kinds of instances did not happen all the time. There were many parts where Ventura was surrounded by upper class people who thought they were better than he was and just like the first film he proved them wrong with a snotty remark and an obscene gesture. That's the old Ace I know! That is what made Ace Ventura such a character. Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is almost a perfect sequel. It still has good laughs but it is dumbed down by its mediocre screenplay. It is because of this that Ace Ventura does not seem always on top of everyone else like he was in the first film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the reasons not to make a sequel..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mbat19
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura pet detective was a surprise hit which of course means it would lead to the inevitable sequel and voila here it is Ace Ventura When Nature Calls. Unfortunately, they should not have answered. While the first Ace Ventura was entertaining light and charming in its ways and was dumb and knew it was dumb and played off of it, this one tries way too hard and the jokes for the most part fall flat and some fall very very flat to the point that the movie is almost racist in parts. If you must see an ace ventura double feature, see the first one twice. My true rating for this is a zero, but their scale does not go that low.. This one is for the birds..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wildly uneven Carrey vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I consider Ace Ventura When Nature Calls to be the 'acid test' for Jim Carrey devotees who claim unconditional love for the man's work: anyone who can sit through this film in its entirety without feeling even the slightest tinge of annoyance at Carrey's wildly unrestrained performance, which sees the manic star seemingly knowing no bounds when it comes to acting the fool, genuinely deserves the perhaps rather dubious honour of being dubbed a true 'Super Fan'. As to whether the film should be considered by your more casual Carrey fan, I say give it a go if you're feeling brave: its worth enduring the embarrassingly bad moments to be able to savour the genuinely funny bits, which very occasionally border on comic genius (just try keeping a straight face as Carrey escapes from his mechanical rhino disguise or goes head to head in combat with a savage African native). 5.5, rounded up to 6 for having a monkey tied to a raft, a masturbation gag in a PG flick (try explaining that one to the kids!), and the Monopoly guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gravy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neenahhh
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! It's kind of on the same level as the first movie. Both movies made me laugh out loud. This film features your different kind of humor. The humor in these films isn't your usual fast wit kind. It's the slapstick kind of comedy where things actually happen. People were hit, people were made fun of, people had stuff done to them, etc. It also includes crude humor. Different and kind of rude, but still hilarious. The plot wasn't exactly A+, but the humor made up for it. I mean, really. It did. Jim Carrey saved this movie. Jim Carrey was really perfect for this role. Crazy-ass Ace Ventura. Who else can play such a part?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Actually, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is not quite as bad as this summary suggests. Though that is not to say that this film is good, for me it isn't. The film does look good, it was interesting to see the likes of Simon Callow and he especially does bring some dignity and like in the first Jim Carrey does a fine job carrying the film. However the plot is very predictable and flimsy, and the direction lacks the energy and imagination of that of the first. The film also could have done with being longer consequently some of the characters lacked credibility. Also the pace is not as snappy and smart, when the humour fell flat(like it did one too many times) it felt like a balloon had been popped. The slapstick is very juvenile here, while the script is more childish than sophisticated and for me that was a bad idea. Overall, disappointing but thanks to Carrey it is at least watchable if nothing to go wild about. 4/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much much much better than the first one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rare bat is stolen from a tribe in the jungle and Ventura is called in to find it. He soon learns that the bat isn't his motives for being there, but he is actually there for something else completely at which time his true detective skills surface so he can get to the bottom of this. This movie made me laugh a few times, which the first didn't. I still think it is a horrible movie with a lot of over the top acting and so stupid that only a 5 year old should watch it. It had a couple laughs though so I can't completely hate it. Steve did such a better job directing than the guy from the first one. This movie actually had a better story, better settings, the antics were less and it was more serious, It had much more to offer. The movie was bad but several things made me like it enough to give it a higher rating than part 1, which I gave 1 out of 10 stars. I liked the parody of Cliffhanger, I loved the joke made referencing the Twilight Zone episode with William Shatner, I loved the part where he wears the little man around his neck to mock the woman with the fur and I laughed at him squeezing out of a tiny hole in the butt of a rubber Rhino. The acting was better, Carrey went from 350 grand on the first film to 5 million on this one. Adawale had a small role and I think he is a great actor and Tommy Davidson who had worked many times with Carrey on IN LIVING COLOR did a great job as the tiny warrior. These two movies were big, and spawned so many catch phrases but it just isn't my thing - my true vote is 1.5 out of 10 stars but I went ahead and gave it 2 here on IMDb to let myself know in the future that I liked it better than the first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey Love Him or Hate Him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kikabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey is one of those actors you will find yourself either adoring or hating. He does not ever "underact." This movie made me laugh so hard I cried (even after the fifth time!) From the robot rhino scene to the monopoly guy Jim knows how to be hilarious. I saw the first one (liked it allot) and have to say this one is way better! I am a huge fan of Carrey. I don't think there are many people who can make such a variety of facial expressions. The only reason this is not a ten is because there is (as usual with Carrey) some inappropriate stuff thrown in. But if your love laughing and you love Jim, this movie will fit you "Like a glove!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure Pet Detective Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This inevitable sequel finds Jim Carrey reprises his role as the title character Ace Ventura, a detective who specializes in retrieval of tame or captive animals in Ace Ventura:When Nature Calls. Ian McNeice,Simon Callow,Maynard Eziashi,Bob Gunton,Sophie Okonedo and Tommy Davidson play key supporting roles.His latest case, the disappearance of a rare African white bat, draws him out of his spiritual retreat at a Tibetan monastery following the tragic outcome of his previous case. Ace Ventura is on assignment in Africa to prevent a tribal war by saving a white bat sacred to both sides. Along the way, he nearly sleeps with a seductive African princess before her wedding, experiences astral projection with an enlightened monkey, masturbates, collects bat dung and, last but not least, is birthed by a mechanical rhino. Often short on taste, the film is nonetheless full of good spirit and plenty of genuine belly laughs particularly during the fight scene with a diminutive tribal champion. Not for every taste, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is either hilarious or insufferable, depending on the viewer's opinion of Carrey's unique brand of slapstick and sight gags. If you're ready to laugh like a pack of hyenas, if you want more fun than an industrial-sized barrel of monkeys, you know what to do.Watch this film for that reason and also for guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Racist and stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    almbjaer-107-905553
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a kid I loved the first Ace Ventura movie. I remember not being as fond of the second one but that was mainly because I loved the first one so much. I've then rewatched the first one and actually thought it was kind of funny. Today I rewatched the second movie and seriously, it's just appallingly racist and stupid. It basically repeats the famous lines from the first movie (really, like a glove etc) and in between, it depicts people in Africa like a 50s documentary. If anyone thinks this movie is really funny, they should never be allowed to watch a movie again. Basically, they should forfeit their sight and give it to blind people so that they can use it to watch better movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but doesn't live up to the original,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura When Nature Calls is a good,funny movie,but doesn't live up to the original movie,it would probably be a lot better if it didn't have Ace Ventura Pet Detective to compare to.Jim Carrey usually saves these movies with his high energy and comedy,I felt to same way about Me,Myself and Irene,they just would not be the same without Jim Carrey,because he is one of my favorite actors and never fails to make me laugh.Currently the only sequel Jim Carrey has ever done. Ace Ventura (Jim Carrey) comes out of retirement to help find a missing white bat who is the symbol of an African tribe.He finds himself in more trouble than he expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Almost Perfect Sequel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A year before this sequel, we were introduced to Ace Ventura; a rude, wise cracking pet detective who has the reputation for being the ONLY pet detective. Guess what? He's back and still has every quality he had in the original. I know, it sounds like there's a catch here. Well there is not-at least with Jim Carrey's character. I did not like this movie as much as the original for one reason and one reason only. No it wasn't that Courtney Cox didn't reprise her role as Melissa Robinson. That I can deal with. My problem was that the story involved some characters that made Ace Ventura's character seem stupid. What made the original funny was that Ace Ventura was on top of his game. He knew what he was doing and how he was doing it. What also made it funny was that nobody ELSE knew what he was doing and although it seemed strange, Ventura got the job done. This occurred throughout the entire first film. And that's how it goes for most of this movie. The part of the movie that I think either did not need to be added or could have been modified was when Ace Ventura was among the African Tribes. What was so hard for me grasp was that in the first movie, they took a smart crazy detective and put him around a bunch of normal people that understood nothing of what he did. When Ventura is around the Tribe members, he is the dumb crazy detective. Why do I say this? Because Jim Carrey's character does not speak their language. It is this major flaw of why some of the laughs fail in this movie for me. For example, when Ventura starts to eat the food at the tribe's festival, he does not realize what he was eating until he is told what it really was. I thought Ventura was the smart one here? The whole point of the first film was so that the joke would be on everyone else; now the roles are switched? Why? Does the laugh really need to be on our comedic hero? It was at that point I started to wonder whether Ace really knew what he was doing. Of course these kinds of instances did not happen all the time. There were many parts where Ventura was surrounded by upper class people who thought they were better than he was and just like the first film he proved them wrong with a snotty remark and an obscene gesture. That's the old Ace I know! That is what made Ace Ventura such a character. Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is almost a perfect sequel. It still has good laughs but it is dumbed down by its mediocre screenplay. It is because of this that Ace Ventura does not seem always on top of everyone else like he was in the first film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the reasons not to make a sequel..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mbat19
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura pet detective was a surprise hit which of course means it would lead to the inevitable sequel and voila here it is Ace Ventura When Nature Calls. Unfortunately, they should not have answered. While the first Ace Ventura was entertaining light and charming in its ways and was dumb and knew it was dumb and played off of it, this one tries way too hard and the jokes for the most part fall flat and some fall very very flat to the point that the movie is almost racist in parts. If you must see an ace ventura double feature, see the first one twice. My true rating for this is a zero, but their scale does not go that low.. This one is for the birds..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wildly uneven Carrey vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I consider Ace Ventura When Nature Calls to be the 'acid test' for Jim Carrey devotees who claim unconditional love for the man's work: anyone who can sit through this film in its entirety without feeling even the slightest tinge of annoyance at Carrey's wildly unrestrained performance, which sees the manic star seemingly knowing no bounds when it comes to acting the fool, genuinely deserves the perhaps rather dubious honour of being dubbed a true 'Super Fan'. As to whether the film should be considered by your more casual Carrey fan, I say give it a go if you're feeling brave: its worth enduring the embarrassingly bad moments to be able to savour the genuinely funny bits, which very occasionally border on comic genius (just try keeping a straight face as Carrey escapes from his mechanical rhino disguise or goes head to head in combat with a savage African native). 5.5, rounded up to 6 for having a monkey tied to a raft, a masturbation gag in a PG flick (try explaining that one to the kids!), and the Monopoly guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gravy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neenahhh
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! It's kind of on the same level as the first movie. Both movies made me laugh out loud. This film features your different kind of humor. The humor in these films isn't your usual fast wit kind. It's the slapstick kind of comedy where things actually happen. People were hit, people were made fun of, people had stuff done to them, etc. It also includes crude humor. Different and kind of rude, but still hilarious. The plot wasn't exactly A+, but the humor made up for it. I mean, really. It did. Jim Carrey saved this movie. Jim Carrey was really perfect for this role. Crazy-ass Ace Ventura. Who else can play such a part?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Actually, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is not quite as bad as this summary suggests. Though that is not to say that this film is good, for me it isn't. The film does look good, it was interesting to see the likes of Simon Callow and he especially does bring some dignity and like in the first Jim Carrey does a fine job carrying the film. However the plot is very predictable and flimsy, and the direction lacks the energy and imagination of that of the first. The film also could have done with being longer consequently some of the characters lacked credibility. Also the pace is not as snappy and smart, when the humour fell flat(like it did one too many times) it felt like a balloon had been popped. The slapstick is very juvenile here, while the script is more childish than sophisticated and for me that was a bad idea. Overall, disappointing but thanks to Carrey it is at least watchable if nothing to go wild about. 4/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much much much better than the first one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rare bat is stolen from a tribe in the jungle and Ventura is called in to find it. He soon learns that the bat isn't his motives for being there, but he is actually there for something else completely at which time his true detective skills surface so he can get to the bottom of this. This movie made me laugh a few times, which the first didn't. I still think it is a horrible movie with a lot of over the top acting and so stupid that only a 5 year old should watch it. It had a couple laughs though so I can't completely hate it. Steve did such a better job directing than the guy from the first one. This movie actually had a better story, better settings, the antics were less and it was more serious, It had much more to offer. The movie was bad but several things made me like it enough to give it a higher rating than part 1, which I gave 1 out of 10 stars. I liked the parody of Cliffhanger, I loved the joke made referencing the Twilight Zone episode with William Shatner, I loved the part where he wears the little man around his neck to mock the woman with the fur and I laughed at him squeezing out of a tiny hole in the butt of a rubber Rhino. The acting was better, Carrey went from 350 grand on the first film to 5 million on this one. Adawale had a small role and I think he is a great actor and Tommy Davidson who had worked many times with Carrey on IN LIVING COLOR did a great job as the tiny warrior. These two movies were big, and spawned so many catch phrases but it just isn't my thing - my true vote is 1.5 out of 10 stars but I went ahead and gave it 2 here on IMDb to let myself know in the future that I liked it better than the first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey Love Him or Hate Him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kikabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey is one of those actors you will find yourself either adoring or hating. He does not ever "underact." This movie made me laugh so hard I cried (even after the fifth time!) From the robot rhino scene to the monopoly guy Jim knows how to be hilarious. I saw the first one (liked it allot) and have to say this one is way better! I am a huge fan of Carrey. I don't think there are many people who can make such a variety of facial expressions. The only reason this is not a ten is because there is (as usual with Carrey) some inappropriate stuff thrown in. But if your love laughing and you love Jim, this movie will fit you "Like a glove!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure Pet Detective Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This inevitable sequel finds Jim Carrey reprises his role as the title character Ace Ventura, a detective who specializes in retrieval of tame or captive animals in Ace Ventura:When Nature Calls. Ian McNeice,Simon Callow,Maynard Eziashi,Bob Gunton,Sophie Okonedo and Tommy Davidson play key supporting roles.His latest case, the disappearance of a rare African white bat, draws him out of his spiritual retreat at a Tibetan monastery following the tragic outcome of his previous case. Ace Ventura is on assignment in Africa to prevent a tribal war by saving a white bat sacred to both sides. Along the way, he nearly sleeps with a seductive African princess before her wedding, experiences astral projection with an enlightened monkey, masturbates, collects bat dung and, last but not least, is birthed by a mechanical rhino. Often short on taste, the film is nonetheless full of good spirit and plenty of genuine belly laughs particularly during the fight scene with a diminutive tribal champion. Not for every taste, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is either hilarious or insufferable, depending on the viewer's opinion of Carrey's unique brand of slapstick and sight gags. If you're ready to laugh like a pack of hyenas, if you want more fun than an industrial-sized barrel of monkeys, you know what to do.Watch this film for that reason and also for guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Racist and stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    almbjaer-107-905553
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a kid I loved the first Ace Ventura movie. I remember not being as fond of the second one but that was mainly because I loved the first one so much. I've then rewatched the first one and actually thought it was kind of funny. Today I rewatched the second movie and seriously, it's just appallingly racist and stupid. It basically repeats the famous lines from the first movie (really, like a glove etc) and in between, it depicts people in Africa like a 50s documentary. If anyone thinks this movie is really funny, they should never be allowed to watch a movie again. Basically, they should forfeit their sight and give it to blind people so that they can use it to watch better movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but doesn't live up to the original,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura When Nature Calls is a good,funny movie,but doesn't live up to the original movie,it would probably be a lot better if it didn't have Ace Ventura Pet Detective to compare to.Jim Carrey usually saves these movies with his high energy and comedy,I felt to same way about Me,Myself and Irene,they just would not be the same without Jim Carrey,because he is one of my favorite actors and never fails to make me laugh.Currently the only sequel Jim Carrey has ever done. Ace Ventura (Jim Carrey) comes out of retirement to help find a missing white bat who is the symbol of an African tribe.He finds himself in more trouble than he expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Almost Perfect Sequel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A year before this sequel, we were introduced to Ace Ventura; a rude, wise cracking pet detective who has the reputation for being the ONLY pet detective. Guess what? He's back and still has every quality he had in the original. I know, it sounds like there's a catch here. Well there is not-at least with Jim Carrey's character. I did not like this movie as much as the original for one reason and one reason only. No it wasn't that Courtney Cox didn't reprise her role as Melissa Robinson. That I can deal with. My problem was that the story involved some characters that made Ace Ventura's character seem stupid. What made the original funny was that Ace Ventura was on top of his game. He knew what he was doing and how he was doing it. What also made it funny was that nobody ELSE knew what he was doing and although it seemed strange, Ventura got the job done. This occurred throughout the entire first film. And that's how it goes for most of this movie. The part of the movie that I think either did not need to be added or could have been modified was when Ace Ventura was among the African Tribes. What was so hard for me grasp was that in the first movie, they took a smart crazy detective and put him around a bunch of normal people that understood nothing of what he did. When Ventura is around the Tribe members, he is the dumb crazy detective. Why do I say this? Because Jim Carrey's character does not speak their language. It is this major flaw of why some of the laughs fail in this movie for me. For example, when Ventura starts to eat the food at the tribe's festival, he does not realize what he was eating until he is told what it really was. I thought Ventura was the smart one here? The whole point of the first film was so that the joke would be on everyone else; now the roles are switched? Why? Does the laugh really need to be on our comedic hero? It was at that point I started to wonder whether Ace really knew what he was doing. Of course these kinds of instances did not happen all the time. There were many parts where Ventura was surrounded by upper class people who thought they were better than he was and just like the first film he proved them wrong with a snotty remark and an obscene gesture. That's the old Ace I know! That is what made Ace Ventura such a character. Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is almost a perfect sequel. It still has good laughs but it is dumbed down by its mediocre screenplay. It is because of this that Ace Ventura does not seem always on top of everyone else like he was in the first film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the reasons not to make a sequel..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mbat19
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura pet detective was a surprise hit which of course means it would lead to the inevitable sequel and voila here it is Ace Ventura When Nature Calls. Unfortunately, they should not have answered. While the first Ace Ventura was entertaining light and charming in its ways and was dumb and knew it was dumb and played off of it, this one tries way too hard and the jokes for the most part fall flat and some fall very very flat to the point that the movie is almost racist in parts. If you must see an ace ventura double feature, see the first one twice. My true rating for this is a zero, but their scale does not go that low.. This one is for the birds..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wildly uneven Carrey vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I consider Ace Ventura When Nature Calls to be the 'acid test' for Jim Carrey devotees who claim unconditional love for the man's work: anyone who can sit through this film in its entirety without feeling even the slightest tinge of annoyance at Carrey's wildly unrestrained performance, which sees the manic star seemingly knowing no bounds when it comes to acting the fool, genuinely deserves the perhaps rather dubious honour of being dubbed a true 'Super Fan'. As to whether the film should be considered by your more casual Carrey fan, I say give it a go if you're feeling brave: its worth enduring the embarrassingly bad moments to be able to savour the genuinely funny bits, which very occasionally border on comic genius (just try keeping a straight face as Carrey escapes from his mechanical rhino disguise or goes head to head in combat with a savage African native). 5.5, rounded up to 6 for having a monkey tied to a raft, a masturbation gag in a PG flick (try explaining that one to the kids!), and the Monopoly guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gravy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neenahhh
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! It's kind of on the same level as the first movie. Both movies made me laugh out loud. This film features your different kind of humor. The humor in these films isn't your usual fast wit kind. It's the slapstick kind of comedy where things actually happen. People were hit, people were made fun of, people had stuff done to them, etc. It also includes crude humor. Different and kind of rude, but still hilarious. The plot wasn't exactly A+, but the humor made up for it. I mean, really. It did. Jim Carrey saved this movie. Jim Carrey was really perfect for this role. Crazy-ass Ace Ventura. Who else can play such a part?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Actually, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is not quite as bad as this summary suggests. Though that is not to say that this film is good, for me it isn't. The film does look good, it was interesting to see the likes of Simon Callow and he especially does bring some dignity and like in the first Jim Carrey does a fine job carrying the film. However the plot is very predictable and flimsy, and the direction lacks the energy and imagination of that of the first. The film also could have done with being longer consequently some of the characters lacked credibility. Also the pace is not as snappy and smart, when the humour fell flat(like it did one too many times) it felt like a balloon had been popped. The slapstick is very juvenile here, while the script is more childish than sophisticated and for me that was a bad idea. Overall, disappointing but thanks to Carrey it is at least watchable if nothing to go wild about. 4/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much much much better than the first one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rare bat is stolen from a tribe in the jungle and Ventura is called in to find it. He soon learns that the bat isn't his motives for being there, but he is actually there for something else completely at which time his true detective skills surface so he can get to the bottom of this. This movie made me laugh a few times, which the first didn't. I still think it is a horrible movie with a lot of over the top acting and so stupid that only a 5 year old should watch it. It had a couple laughs though so I can't completely hate it. Steve did such a better job directing than the guy from the first one. This movie actually had a better story, better settings, the antics were less and it was more serious, It had much more to offer. The movie was bad but several things made me like it enough to give it a higher rating than part 1, which I gave 1 out of 10 stars. I liked the parody of Cliffhanger, I loved the joke made referencing the Twilight Zone episode with William Shatner, I loved the part where he wears the little man around his neck to mock the woman with the fur and I laughed at him squeezing out of a tiny hole in the butt of a rubber Rhino. The acting was better, Carrey went from 350 grand on the first film to 5 million on this one. Adawale had a small role and I think he is a great actor and Tommy Davidson who had worked many times with Carrey on IN LIVING COLOR did a great job as the tiny warrior. These two movies were big, and spawned so many catch phrases but it just isn't my thing - my true vote is 1.5 out of 10 stars but I went ahead and gave it 2 here on IMDb to let myself know in the future that I liked it better than the first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey Love Him or Hate Him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kikabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey is one of those actors you will find yourself either adoring or hating. He does not ever "underact." This movie made me laugh so hard I cried (even after the fifth time!) From the robot rhino scene to the monopoly guy Jim knows how to be hilarious. I saw the first one (liked it allot) and have to say this one is way better! I am a huge fan of Carrey. I don't think there are many people who can make such a variety of facial expressions. The only reason this is not a ten is because there is (as usual with Carrey) some inappropriate stuff thrown in. But if your love laughing and you love Jim, this movie will fit you "Like a glove!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure Pet Detective Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This inevitable sequel finds Jim Carrey reprises his role as the title character Ace Ventura, a detective who specializes in retrieval of tame or captive animals in Ace Ventura:When Nature Calls. Ian McNeice,Simon Callow,Maynard Eziashi,Bob Gunton,Sophie Okonedo and Tommy Davidson play key supporting roles.His latest case, the disappearance of a rare African white bat, draws him out of his spiritual retreat at a Tibetan monastery following the tragic outcome of his previous case. Ace Ventura is on assignment in Africa to prevent a tribal war by saving a white bat sacred to both sides. Along the way, he nearly sleeps with a seductive African princess before her wedding, experiences astral projection with an enlightened monkey, masturbates, collects bat dung and, last but not least, is birthed by a mechanical rhino. Often short on taste, the film is nonetheless full of good spirit and plenty of genuine belly laughs particularly during the fight scene with a diminutive tribal champion. Not for every taste, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is either hilarious or insufferable, depending on the viewer's opinion of Carrey's unique brand of slapstick and sight gags. If you're ready to laugh like a pack of hyenas, if you want more fun than an industrial-sized barrel of monkeys, you know what to do.Watch this film for that reason and also for guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Racist and stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    almbjaer-107-905553
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a kid I loved the first Ace Ventura movie. I remember not being as fond of the second one but that was mainly because I loved the first one so much. I've then rewatched the first one and actually thought it was kind of funny. Today I rewatched the second movie and seriously, it's just appallingly racist and stupid. It basically repeats the famous lines from the first movie (really, like a glove etc) and in between, it depicts people in Africa like a 50s documentary. If anyone thinks this movie is really funny, they should never be allowed to watch a movie again. Basically, they should forfeit their sight and give it to blind people so that they can use it to watch better movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but doesn't live up to the original,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura When Nature Calls is a good,funny movie,but doesn't live up to the original movie,it would probably be a lot better if it didn't have Ace Ventura Pet Detective to compare to.Jim Carrey usually saves these movies with his high energy and comedy,I felt to same way about Me,Myself and Irene,they just would not be the same without Jim Carrey,because he is one of my favorite actors and never fails to make me laugh.Currently the only sequel Jim Carrey has ever done. Ace Ventura (Jim Carrey) comes out of retirement to help find a missing white bat who is the symbol of an African tribe.He finds himself in more trouble than he expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Almost Perfect Sequel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A year before this sequel, we were introduced to Ace Ventura; a rude, wise cracking pet detective who has the reputation for being the ONLY pet detective. Guess what? He's back and still has every quality he had in the original. I know, it sounds like there's a catch here. Well there is not-at least with Jim Carrey's character. I did not like this movie as much as the original for one reason and one reason only. No it wasn't that Courtney Cox didn't reprise her role as Melissa Robinson. That I can deal with. My problem was that the story involved some characters that made Ace Ventura's character seem stupid. What made the original funny was that Ace Ventura was on top of his game. He knew what he was doing and how he was doing it. What also made it funny was that nobody ELSE knew what he was doing and although it seemed strange, Ventura got the job done. This occurred throughout the entire first film. And that's how it goes for most of this movie. The part of the movie that I think either did not need to be added or could have been modified was when Ace Ventura was among the African Tribes. What was so hard for me grasp was that in the first movie, they took a smart crazy detective and put him around a bunch of normal people that understood nothing of what he did. When Ventura is around the Tribe members, he is the dumb crazy detective. Why do I say this? Because Jim Carrey's character does not speak their language. It is this major flaw of why some of the laughs fail in this movie for me. For example, when Ventura starts to eat the food at the tribe's festival, he does not realize what he was eating until he is told what it really was. I thought Ventura was the smart one here? The whole point of the first film was so that the joke would be on everyone else; now the roles are switched? Why? Does the laugh really need to be on our comedic hero? It was at that point I started to wonder whether Ace really knew what he was doing. Of course these kinds of instances did not happen all the time. There were many parts where Ventura was surrounded by upper class people who thought they were better than he was and just like the first film he proved them wrong with a snotty remark and an obscene gesture. That's the old Ace I know! That is what made Ace Ventura such a character. Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is almost a perfect sequel. It still has good laughs but it is dumbed down by its mediocre screenplay. It is because of this that Ace Ventura does not seem always on top of everyone else like he was in the first film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the reasons not to make a sequel..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mbat19
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura pet detective was a surprise hit which of course means it would lead to the inevitable sequel and voila here it is Ace Ventura When Nature Calls. Unfortunately, they should not have answered. While the first Ace Ventura was entertaining light and charming in its ways and was dumb and knew it was dumb and played off of it, this one tries way too hard and the jokes for the most part fall flat and some fall very very flat to the point that the movie is almost racist in parts. If you must see an ace ventura double feature, see the first one twice. My true rating for this is a zero, but their scale does not go that low.. This one is for the birds..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wildly uneven Carrey vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I consider Ace Ventura When Nature Calls to be the 'acid test' for Jim Carrey devotees who claim unconditional love for the man's work: anyone who can sit through this film in its entirety without feeling even the slightest tinge of annoyance at Carrey's wildly unrestrained performance, which sees the manic star seemingly knowing no bounds when it comes to acting the fool, genuinely deserves the perhaps rather dubious honour of being dubbed a true 'Super Fan'. As to whether the film should be considered by your more casual Carrey fan, I say give it a go if you're feeling brave: its worth enduring the embarrassingly bad moments to be able to savour the genuinely funny bits, which very occasionally border on comic genius (just try keeping a straight face as Carrey escapes from his mechanical rhino disguise or goes head to head in combat with a savage African native). 5.5, rounded up to 6 for having a monkey tied to a raft, a masturbation gag in a PG flick (try explaining that one to the kids!), and the Monopoly guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gravy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neenahhh
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! It's kind of on the same level as the first movie. Both movies made me laugh out loud. This film features your different kind of humor. The humor in these films isn't your usual fast wit kind. It's the slapstick kind of comedy where things actually happen. People were hit, people were made fun of, people had stuff done to them, etc. It also includes crude humor. Different and kind of rude, but still hilarious. The plot wasn't exactly A+, but the humor made up for it. I mean, really. It did. Jim Carrey saved this movie. Jim Carrey was really perfect for this role. Crazy-ass Ace Ventura. Who else can play such a part?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Actually, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is not quite as bad as this summary suggests. Though that is not to say that this film is good, for me it isn't. The film does look good, it was interesting to see the likes of Simon Callow and he especially does bring some dignity and like in the first Jim Carrey does a fine job carrying the film. However the plot is very predictable and flimsy, and the direction lacks the energy and imagination of that of the first. The film also could have done with being longer consequently some of the characters lacked credibility. Also the pace is not as snappy and smart, when the humour fell flat(like it did one too many times) it felt like a balloon had been popped. The slapstick is very juvenile here, while the script is more childish than sophisticated and for me that was a bad idea. Overall, disappointing but thanks to Carrey it is at least watchable if nothing to go wild about. 4/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much much much better than the first one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rare bat is stolen from a tribe in the jungle and Ventura is called in to find it. He soon learns that the bat isn't his motives for being there, but he is actually there for something else completely at which time his true detective skills surface so he can get to the bottom of this. This movie made me laugh a few times, which the first didn't. I still think it is a horrible movie with a lot of over the top acting and so stupid that only a 5 year old should watch it. It had a couple laughs though so I can't completely hate it. Steve did such a better job directing than the guy from the first one. This movie actually had a better story, better settings, the antics were less and it was more serious, It had much more to offer. The movie was bad but several things made me like it enough to give it a higher rating than part 1, which I gave 1 out of 10 stars. I liked the parody of Cliffhanger, I loved the joke made referencing the Twilight Zone episode with William Shatner, I loved the part where he wears the little man around his neck to mock the woman with the fur and I laughed at him squeezing out of a tiny hole in the butt of a rubber Rhino. The acting was better, Carrey went from 350 grand on the first film to 5 million on this one. Adawale had a small role and I think he is a great actor and Tommy Davidson who had worked many times with Carrey on IN LIVING COLOR did a great job as the tiny warrior. These two movies were big, and spawned so many catch phrases but it just isn't my thing - my true vote is 1.5 out of 10 stars but I went ahead and gave it 2 here on IMDb to let myself know in the future that I liked it better than the first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey Love Him or Hate Him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kikabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey is one of those actors you will find yourself either adoring or hating. He does not ever "underact." This movie made me laugh so hard I cried (even after the fifth time!) From the robot rhino scene to the monopoly guy Jim knows how to be hilarious. I saw the first one (liked it allot) and have to say this one is way better! I am a huge fan of Carrey. I don't think there are many people who can make such a variety of facial expressions. The only reason this is not a ten is because there is (as usual with Carrey) some inappropriate stuff thrown in. But if your love laughing and you love Jim, this movie will fit you "Like a glove!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure Pet Detective Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This inevitable sequel finds Jim Carrey reprises his role as the title character Ace Ventura, a detective who specializes in retrieval of tame or captive animals in Ace Ventura:When Nature Calls. Ian McNeice,Simon Callow,Maynard Eziashi,Bob Gunton,Sophie Okonedo and Tommy Davidson play key supporting roles.His latest case, the disappearance of a rare African white bat, draws him out of his spiritual retreat at a Tibetan monastery following the tragic outcome of his previous case. Ace Ventura is on assignment in Africa to prevent a tribal war by saving a white bat sacred to both sides. Along the way, he nearly sleeps with a seductive African princess before her wedding, experiences astral projection with an enlightened monkey, masturbates, collects bat dung and, last but not least, is birthed by a mechanical rhino. Often short on taste, the film is nonetheless full of good spirit and plenty of genuine belly laughs particularly during the fight scene with a diminutive tribal champion. Not for every taste, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is either hilarious or insufferable, depending on the viewer's opinion of Carrey's unique brand of slapstick and sight gags. If you're ready to laugh like a pack of hyenas, if you want more fun than an industrial-sized barrel of monkeys, you know what to do.Watch this film for that reason and also for guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Racist and stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    almbjaer-107-905553
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a kid I loved the first Ace Ventura movie. I remember not being as fond of the second one but that was mainly because I loved the first one so much. I've then rewatched the first one and actually thought it was kind of funny. Today I rewatched the second movie and seriously, it's just appallingly racist and stupid. It basically repeats the famous lines from the first movie (really, like a glove etc) and in between, it depicts people in Africa like a 50s documentary. If anyone thinks this movie is really funny, they should never be allowed to watch a movie again. Basically, they should forfeit their sight and give it to blind people so that they can use it to watch better movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but doesn't live up to the original,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura When Nature Calls is a good,funny movie,but doesn't live up to the original movie,it would probably be a lot better if it didn't have Ace Ventura Pet Detective to compare to.Jim Carrey usually saves these movies with his high energy and comedy,I felt to same way about Me,Myself and Irene,they just would not be the same without Jim Carrey,because he is one of my favorite actors and never fails to make me laugh.Currently the only sequel Jim Carrey has ever done. Ace Ventura (Jim Carrey) comes out of retirement to help find a missing white bat who is the symbol of an African tribe.He finds himself in more trouble than he expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Almost Perfect Sequel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A year before this sequel, we were introduced to Ace Ventura; a rude, wise cracking pet detective who has the reputation for being the ONLY pet detective. Guess what? He's back and still has every quality he had in the original. I know, it sounds like there's a catch here. Well there is not-at least with Jim Carrey's character. I did not like this movie as much as the original for one reason and one reason only. No it wasn't that Courtney Cox didn't reprise her role as Melissa Robinson. That I can deal with. My problem was that the story involved some characters that made Ace Ventura's character seem stupid. What made the original funny was that Ace Ventura was on top of his game. He knew what he was doing and how he was doing it. What also made it funny was that nobody ELSE knew what he was doing and although it seemed strange, Ventura got the job done. This occurred throughout the entire first film. And that's how it goes for most of this movie. The part of the movie that I think either did not need to be added or could have been modified was when Ace Ventura was among the African Tribes. What was so hard for me grasp was that in the first movie, they took a smart crazy detective and put him around a bunch of normal people that understood nothing of what he did. When Ventura is around the Tribe members, he is the dumb crazy detective. Why do I say this? Because Jim Carrey's character does not speak their language. It is this major flaw of why some of the laughs fail in this movie for me. For example, when Ventura starts to eat the food at the tribe's festival, he does not realize what he was eating until he is told what it really was. I thought Ventura was the smart one here? The whole point of the first film was so that the joke would be on everyone else; now the roles are switched? Why? Does the laugh really need to be on our comedic hero? It was at that point I started to wonder whether Ace really knew what he was doing. Of course these kinds of instances did not happen all the time. There were many parts where Ventura was surrounded by upper class people who thought they were better than he was and just like the first film he proved them wrong with a snotty remark and an obscene gesture. That's the old Ace I know! That is what made Ace Ventura such a character. Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is almost a perfect sequel. It still has good laughs but it is dumbed down by its mediocre screenplay. It is because of this that Ace Ventura does not seem always on top of everyone else like he was in the first film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the reasons not to make a sequel..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mbat19
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura pet detective was a surprise hit which of course means it would lead to the inevitable sequel and voila here it is Ace Ventura When Nature Calls. Unfortunately, they should not have answered. While the first Ace Ventura was entertaining light and charming in its ways and was dumb and knew it was dumb and played off of it, this one tries way too hard and the jokes for the most part fall flat and some fall very very flat to the point that the movie is almost racist in parts. If you must see an ace ventura double feature, see the first one twice. My true rating for this is a zero, but their scale does not go that low.. This one is for the birds..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wildly uneven Carrey vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I consider Ace Ventura When Nature Calls to be the 'acid test' for Jim Carrey devotees who claim unconditional love for the man's work: anyone who can sit through this film in its entirety without feeling even the slightest tinge of annoyance at Carrey's wildly unrestrained performance, which sees the manic star seemingly knowing no bounds when it comes to acting the fool, genuinely deserves the perhaps rather dubious honour of being dubbed a true 'Super Fan'. As to whether the film should be considered by your more casual Carrey fan, I say give it a go if you're feeling brave: its worth enduring the embarrassingly bad moments to be able to savour the genuinely funny bits, which very occasionally border on comic genius (just try keeping a straight face as Carrey escapes from his mechanical rhino disguise or goes head to head in combat with a savage African native). 5.5, rounded up to 6 for having a monkey tied to a raft, a masturbation gag in a PG flick (try explaining that one to the kids!), and the Monopoly guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gravy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neenahhh
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! It's kind of on the same level as the first movie. Both movies made me laugh out loud. This film features your different kind of humor. The humor in these films isn't your usual fast wit kind. It's the slapstick kind of comedy where things actually happen. People were hit, people were made fun of, people had stuff done to them, etc. It also includes crude humor. Different and kind of rude, but still hilarious. The plot wasn't exactly A+, but the humor made up for it. I mean, really. It did. Jim Carrey saved this movie. Jim Carrey was really perfect for this role. Crazy-ass Ace Ventura. Who else can play such a part?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Actually, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is not quite as bad as this summary suggests. Though that is not to say that this film is good, for me it isn't. The film does look good, it was interesting to see the likes of Simon Callow and he especially does bring some dignity and like in the first Jim Carrey does a fine job carrying the film. However the plot is very predictable and flimsy, and the direction lacks the energy and imagination of that of the first. The film also could have done with being longer consequently some of the characters lacked credibility. Also the pace is not as snappy and smart, when the humour fell flat(like it did one too many times) it felt like a balloon had been popped. The slapstick is very juvenile here, while the script is more childish than sophisticated and for me that was a bad idea. Overall, disappointing but thanks to Carrey it is at least watchable if nothing to go wild about. 4/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much much much better than the first one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rare bat is stolen from a tribe in the jungle and Ventura is called in to find it. He soon learns that the bat isn't his motives for being there, but he is actually there for something else completely at which time his true detective skills surface so he can get to the bottom of this. This movie made me laugh a few times, which the first didn't. I still think it is a horrible movie with a lot of over the top acting and so stupid that only a 5 year old should watch it. It had a couple laughs though so I can't completely hate it. Steve did such a better job directing than the guy from the first one. This movie actually had a better story, better settings, the antics were less and it was more serious, It had much more to offer. The movie was bad but several things made me like it enough to give it a higher rating than part 1, which I gave 1 out of 10 stars. I liked the parody of Cliffhanger, I loved the joke made referencing the Twilight Zone episode with William Shatner, I loved the part where he wears the little man around his neck to mock the woman with the fur and I laughed at him squeezing out of a tiny hole in the butt of a rubber Rhino. The acting was better, Carrey went from 350 grand on the first film to 5 million on this one. Adawale had a small role and I think he is a great actor and Tommy Davidson who had worked many times with Carrey on IN LIVING COLOR did a great job as the tiny warrior. These two movies were big, and spawned so many catch phrases but it just isn't my thing - my true vote is 1.5 out of 10 stars but I went ahead and gave it 2 here on IMDb to let myself know in the future that I liked it better than the first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey Love Him or Hate Him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kikabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey is one of those actors you will find yourself either adoring or hating. He does not ever "underact." This movie made me laugh so hard I cried (even after the fifth time!) From the robot rhino scene to the monopoly guy Jim knows how to be hilarious. I saw the first one (liked it allot) and have to say this one is way better! I am a huge fan of Carrey. I don't think there are many people who can make such a variety of facial expressions. The only reason this is not a ten is because there is (as usual with Carrey) some inappropriate stuff thrown in. But if your love laughing and you love Jim, this movie will fit you "Like a glove!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure Pet Detective Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This inevitable sequel finds Jim Carrey reprises his role as the title character Ace Ventura, a detective who specializes in retrieval of tame or captive animals in Ace Ventura:When Nature Calls. Ian McNeice,Simon Callow,Maynard Eziashi,Bob Gunton,Sophie Okonedo and Tommy Davidson play key supporting roles.His latest case, the disappearance of a rare African white bat, draws him out of his spiritual retreat at a Tibetan monastery following the tragic outcome of his previous case. Ace Ventura is on assignment in Africa to prevent a tribal war by saving a white bat sacred to both sides. Along the way, he nearly sleeps with a seductive African princess before her wedding, experiences astral projection with an enlightened monkey, masturbates, collects bat dung and, last but not least, is birthed by a mechanical rhino. Often short on taste, the film is nonetheless full of good spirit and plenty of genuine belly laughs particularly during the fight scene with a diminutive tribal champion. Not for every taste, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is either hilarious or insufferable, depending on the viewer's opinion of Carrey's unique brand of slapstick and sight gags. If you're ready to laugh like a pack of hyenas, if you want more fun than an industrial-sized barrel of monkeys, you know what to do.Watch this film for that reason and also for guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Racist and stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    almbjaer-107-905553
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a kid I loved the first Ace Ventura movie. I remember not being as fond of the second one but that was mainly because I loved the first one so much. I've then rewatched the first one and actually thought it was kind of funny. Today I rewatched the second movie and seriously, it's just appallingly racist and stupid. It basically repeats the famous lines from the first movie (really, like a glove etc) and in between, it depicts people in Africa like a 50s documentary. If anyone thinks this movie is really funny, they should never be allowed to watch a movie again. Basically, they should forfeit their sight and give it to blind people so that they can use it to watch better movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but doesn't live up to the original,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura When Nature Calls is a good,funny movie,but doesn't live up to the original movie,it would probably be a lot better if it didn't have Ace Ventura Pet Detective to compare to.Jim Carrey usually saves these movies with his high energy and comedy,I felt to same way about Me,Myself and Irene,they just would not be the same without Jim Carrey,because he is one of my favorite actors and never fails to make me laugh.Currently the only sequel Jim Carrey has ever done. Ace Ventura (Jim Carrey) comes out of retirement to help find a missing white bat who is the symbol of an African tribe.He finds himself in more trouble than he expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Almost Perfect Sequel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A year before this sequel, we were introduced to Ace Ventura; a rude, wise cracking pet detective who has the reputation for being the ONLY pet detective. Guess what? He's back and still has every quality he had in the original. I know, it sounds like there's a catch here. Well there is not-at least with Jim Carrey's character. I did not like this movie as much as the original for one reason and one reason only. No it wasn't that Courtney Cox didn't reprise her role as Melissa Robinson. That I can deal with. My problem was that the story involved some characters that made Ace Ventura's character seem stupid. What made the original funny was that Ace Ventura was on top of his game. He knew what he was doing and how he was doing it. What also made it funny was that nobody ELSE knew what he was doing and although it seemed strange, Ventura got the job done. This occurred throughout the entire first film. And that's how it goes for most of this movie. The part of the movie that I think either did not need to be added or could have been modified was when Ace Ventura was among the African Tribes. What was so hard for me grasp was that in the first movie, they took a smart crazy detective and put him around a bunch of normal people that understood nothing of what he did. When Ventura is around the Tribe members, he is the dumb crazy detective. Why do I say this? Because Jim Carrey's character does not speak their language. It is this major flaw of why some of the laughs fail in this movie for me. For example, when Ventura starts to eat the food at the tribe's festival, he does not realize what he was eating until he is told what it really was. I thought Ventura was the smart one here? The whole point of the first film was so that the joke would be on everyone else; now the roles are switched? Why? Does the laugh really need to be on our comedic hero? It was at that point I started to wonder whether Ace really knew what he was doing. Of course these kinds of instances did not happen all the time. There were many parts where Ventura was surrounded by upper class people who thought they were better than he was and just like the first film he proved them wrong with a snotty remark and an obscene gesture. That's the old Ace I know! That is what made Ace Ventura such a character. Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is almost a perfect sequel. It still has good laughs but it is dumbed down by its mediocre screenplay. It is because of this that Ace Ventura does not seem always on top of everyone else like he was in the first film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the reasons not to make a sequel..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mbat19
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura pet detective was a surprise hit which of course means it would lead to the inevitable sequel and voila here it is Ace Ventura When Nature Calls. Unfortunately, they should not have answered. While the first Ace Ventura was entertaining light and charming in its ways and was dumb and knew it was dumb and played off of it, this one tries way too hard and the jokes for the most part fall flat and some fall very very flat to the point that the movie is almost racist in parts. If you must see an ace ventura double feature, see the first one twice. My true rating for this is a zero, but their scale does not go that low.. This one is for the birds..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wildly uneven Carrey vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I consider Ace Ventura When Nature Calls to be the 'acid test' for Jim Carrey devotees who claim unconditional love for the man's work: anyone who can sit through this film in its entirety without feeling even the slightest tinge of annoyance at Carrey's wildly unrestrained performance, which sees the manic star seemingly knowing no bounds when it comes to acting the fool, genuinely deserves the perhaps rather dubious honour of being dubbed a true 'Super Fan'. As to whether the film should be considered by your more casual Carrey fan, I say give it a go if you're feeling brave: its worth enduring the embarrassingly bad moments to be able to savour the genuinely funny bits, which very occasionally border on comic genius (just try keeping a straight face as Carrey escapes from his mechanical rhino disguise or goes head to head in combat with a savage African native). 5.5, rounded up to 6 for having a monkey tied to a raft, a masturbation gag in a PG flick (try explaining that one to the kids!), and the Monopoly guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gravy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neenahhh
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! It's kind of on the same level as the first movie. Both movies made me laugh out loud. This film features your different kind of humor. The humor in these films isn't your usual fast wit kind. It's the slapstick kind of comedy where things actually happen. People were hit, people were made fun of, people had stuff done to them, etc. It also includes crude humor. Different and kind of rude, but still hilarious. The plot wasn't exactly A+, but the humor made up for it. I mean, really. It did. Jim Carrey saved this movie. Jim Carrey was really perfect for this role. Crazy-ass Ace Ventura. Who else can play such a part?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Actually, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is not quite as bad as this summary suggests. Though that is not to say that this film is good, for me it isn't. The film does look good, it was interesting to see the likes of Simon Callow and he especially does bring some dignity and like in the first Jim Carrey does a fine job carrying the film. However the plot is very predictable and flimsy, and the direction lacks the energy and imagination of that of the first. The film also could have done with being longer consequently some of the characters lacked credibility. Also the pace is not as snappy and smart, when the humour fell flat(like it did one too many times) it felt like a balloon had been popped. The slapstick is very juvenile here, while the script is more childish than sophisticated and for me that was a bad idea. Overall, disappointing but thanks to Carrey it is at least watchable if nothing to go wild about. 4/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much much much better than the first one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rare bat is stolen from a tribe in the jungle and Ventura is called in to find it. He soon learns that the bat isn't his motives for being there, but he is actually there for something else completely at which time his true detective skills surface so he can get to the bottom of this. This movie made me laugh a few times, which the first didn't. I still think it is a horrible movie with a lot of over the top acting and so stupid that only a 5 year old should watch it. It had a couple laughs though so I can't completely hate it. Steve did such a better job directing than the guy from the first one. This movie actually had a better story, better settings, the antics were less and it was more serious, It had much more to offer. The movie was bad but several things made me like it enough to give it a higher rating than part 1, which I gave 1 out of 10 stars. I liked the parody of Cliffhanger, I loved the joke made referencing the Twilight Zone episode with William Shatner, I loved the part where he wears the little man around his neck to mock the woman with the fur and I laughed at him squeezing out of a tiny hole in the butt of a rubber Rhino. The acting was better, Carrey went from 350 grand on the first film to 5 million on this one. Adawale had a small role and I think he is a great actor and Tommy Davidson who had worked many times with Carrey on IN LIVING COLOR did a great job as the tiny warrior. These two movies were big, and spawned so many catch phrases but it just isn't my thing - my true vote is 1.5 out of 10 stars but I went ahead and gave it 2 here on IMDb to let myself know in the future that I liked it better than the first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey Love Him or Hate Him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kikabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey is one of those actors you will find yourself either adoring or hating. He does not ever "underact." This movie made me laugh so hard I cried (even after the fifth time!) From the robot rhino scene to the monopoly guy Jim knows how to be hilarious. I saw the first one (liked it allot) and have to say this one is way better! I am a huge fan of Carrey. I don't think there are many people who can make such a variety of facial expressions. The only reason this is not a ten is because there is (as usual with Carrey) some inappropriate stuff thrown in. But if your love laughing and you love Jim, this movie will fit you "Like a glove!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure Pet Detective Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This inevitable sequel finds Jim Carrey reprises his role as the title character Ace Ventura, a detective who specializes in retrieval of tame or captive animals in Ace Ventura:When Nature Calls. Ian McNeice,Simon Callow,Maynard Eziashi,Bob Gunton,Sophie Okonedo and Tommy Davidson play key supporting roles.His latest case, the disappearance of a rare African white bat, draws him out of his spiritual retreat at a Tibetan monastery following the tragic outcome of his previous case. Ace Ventura is on assignment in Africa to prevent a tribal war by saving a white bat sacred to both sides. Along the way, he nearly sleeps with a seductive African princess before her wedding, experiences astral projection with an enlightened monkey, masturbates, collects bat dung and, last but not least, is birthed by a mechanical rhino. Often short on taste, the film is nonetheless full of good spirit and plenty of genuine belly laughs particularly during the fight scene with a diminutive tribal champion. Not for every taste, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is either hilarious or insufferable, depending on the viewer's opinion of Carrey's unique brand of slapstick and sight gags. If you're ready to laugh like a pack of hyenas, if you want more fun than an industrial-sized barrel of monkeys, you know what to do.Watch this film for that reason and also for guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Racist and stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    almbjaer-107-905553
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a kid I loved the first Ace Ventura movie. I remember not being as fond of the second one but that was mainly because I loved the first one so much. I've then rewatched the first one and actually thought it was kind of funny. Today I rewatched the second movie and seriously, it's just appallingly racist and stupid. It basically repeats the famous lines from the first movie (really, like a glove etc) and in between, it depicts people in Africa like a 50s documentary. If anyone thinks this movie is really funny, they should never be allowed to watch a movie again. Basically, they should forfeit their sight and give it to blind people so that they can use it to watch better movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but doesn't live up to the original,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura When Nature Calls is a good,funny movie,but doesn't live up to the original movie,it would probably be a lot better if it didn't have Ace Ventura Pet Detective to compare to.Jim Carrey usually saves these movies with his high energy and comedy,I felt to same way about Me,Myself and Irene,they just would not be the same without Jim Carrey,because he is one of my favorite actors and never fails to make me laugh.Currently the only sequel Jim Carrey has ever done. Ace Ventura (Jim Carrey) comes out of retirement to help find a missing white bat who is the symbol of an African tribe.He finds himself in more trouble than he expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Almost Perfect Sequel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A year before this sequel, we were introduced to Ace Ventura; a rude, wise cracking pet detective who has the reputation for being the ONLY pet detective. Guess what? He's back and still has every quality he had in the original. I know, it sounds like there's a catch here. Well there is not-at least with Jim Carrey's character. I did not like this movie as much as the original for one reason and one reason only. No it wasn't that Courtney Cox didn't reprise her role as Melissa Robinson. That I can deal with. My problem was that the story involved some characters that made Ace Ventura's character seem stupid. What made the original funny was that Ace Ventura was on top of his game. He knew what he was doing and how he was doing it. What also made it funny was that nobody ELSE knew what he was doing and although it seemed strange, Ventura got the job done. This occurred throughout the entire first film. And that's how it goes for most of this movie. The part of the movie that I think either did not need to be added or could have been modified was when Ace Ventura was among the African Tribes. What was so hard for me grasp was that in the first movie, they took a smart crazy detective and put him around a bunch of normal people that understood nothing of what he did. When Ventura is around the Tribe members, he is the dumb crazy detective. Why do I say this? Because Jim Carrey's character does not speak their language. It is this major flaw of why some of the laughs fail in this movie for me. For example, when Ventura starts to eat the food at the tribe's festival, he does not realize what he was eating until he is told what it really was. I thought Ventura was the smart one here? The whole point of the first film was so that the joke would be on everyone else; now the roles are switched? Why? Does the laugh really need to be on our comedic hero? It was at that point I started to wonder whether Ace really knew what he was doing. Of course these kinds of instances did not happen all the time. There were many parts where Ventura was surrounded by upper class people who thought they were better than he was and just like the first film he proved them wrong with a snotty remark and an obscene gesture. That's the old Ace I know! That is what made Ace Ventura such a character. Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is almost a perfect sequel. It still has good laughs but it is dumbed down by its mediocre screenplay. It is because of this that Ace Ventura does not seem always on top of everyone else like he was in the first film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the reasons not to make a sequel..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mbat19
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura pet detective was a surprise hit which of course means it would lead to the inevitable sequel and voila here it is Ace Ventura When Nature Calls. Unfortunately, they should not have answered. While the first Ace Ventura was entertaining light and charming in its ways and was dumb and knew it was dumb and played off of it, this one tries way too hard and the jokes for the most part fall flat and some fall very very flat to the point that the movie is almost racist in parts. If you must see an ace ventura double feature, see the first one twice. My true rating for this is a zero, but their scale does not go that low.. This one is for the birds..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wildly uneven Carrey vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I consider Ace Ventura When Nature Calls to be the 'acid test' for Jim Carrey devotees who claim unconditional love for the man's work: anyone who can sit through this film in its entirety without feeling even the slightest tinge of annoyance at Carrey's wildly unrestrained performance, which sees the manic star seemingly knowing no bounds when it comes to acting the fool, genuinely deserves the perhaps rather dubious honour of being dubbed a true 'Super Fan'. As to whether the film should be considered by your more casual Carrey fan, I say give it a go if you're feeling brave: its worth enduring the embarrassingly bad moments to be able to savour the genuinely funny bits, which very occasionally border on comic genius (just try keeping a straight face as Carrey escapes from his mechanical rhino disguise or goes head to head in combat with a savage African native). 5.5, rounded up to 6 for having a monkey tied to a raft, a masturbation gag in a PG flick (try explaining that one to the kids!), and the Monopoly guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gravy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neenahhh
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! It's kind of on the same level as the first movie. Both movies made me laugh out loud. This film features your different kind of humor. The humor in these films isn't your usual fast wit kind. It's the slapstick kind of comedy where things actually happen. People were hit, people were made fun of, people had stuff done to them, etc. It also includes crude humor. Different and kind of rude, but still hilarious. The plot wasn't exactly A+, but the humor made up for it. I mean, really. It did. Jim Carrey saved this movie. Jim Carrey was really perfect for this role. Crazy-ass Ace Ventura. Who else can play such a part?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Actually, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is not quite as bad as this summary suggests. Though that is not to say that this film is good, for me it isn't. The film does look good, it was interesting to see the likes of Simon Callow and he especially does bring some dignity and like in the first Jim Carrey does a fine job carrying the film. However the plot is very predictable and flimsy, and the direction lacks the energy and imagination of that of the first. The film also could have done with being longer consequently some of the characters lacked credibility. Also the pace is not as snappy and smart, when the humour fell flat(like it did one too many times) it felt like a balloon had been popped. The slapstick is very juvenile here, while the script is more childish than sophisticated and for me that was a bad idea. Overall, disappointing but thanks to Carrey it is at least watchable if nothing to go wild about. 4/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much much much better than the first one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rare bat is stolen from a tribe in the jungle and Ventura is called in to find it. He soon learns that the bat isn't his motives for being there, but he is actually there for something else completely at which time his true detective skills surface so he can get to the bottom of this. This movie made me laugh a few times, which the first didn't. I still think it is a horrible movie with a lot of over the top acting and so stupid that only a 5 year old should watch it. It had a couple laughs though so I can't completely hate it. Steve did such a better job directing than the guy from the first one. This movie actually had a better story, better settings, the antics were less and it was more serious, It had much more to offer. The movie was bad but several things made me like it enough to give it a higher rating than part 1, which I gave 1 out of 10 stars. I liked the parody of Cliffhanger, I loved the joke made referencing the Twilight Zone episode with William Shatner, I loved the part where he wears the little man around his neck to mock the woman with the fur and I laughed at him squeezing out of a tiny hole in the butt of a rubber Rhino. The acting was better, Carrey went from 350 grand on the first film to 5 million on this one. Adawale had a small role and I think he is a great actor and Tommy Davidson who had worked many times with Carrey on IN LIVING COLOR did a great job as the tiny warrior. These two movies were big, and spawned so many catch phrases but it just isn't my thing - my true vote is 1.5 out of 10 stars but I went ahead and gave it 2 here on IMDb to let myself know in the future that I liked it better than the first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey Love Him or Hate Him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kikabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey is one of those actors you will find yourself either adoring or hating. He does not ever "underact." This movie made me laugh so hard I cried (even after the fifth time!) From the robot rhino scene to the monopoly guy Jim knows how to be hilarious. I saw the first one (liked it allot) and have to say this one is way better! I am a huge fan of Carrey. I don't think there are many people who can make such a variety of facial expressions. The only reason this is not a ten is because there is (as usual with Carrey) some inappropriate stuff thrown in. But if your love laughing and you love Jim, this movie will fit you "Like a glove!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure Pet Detective Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This inevitable sequel finds Jim Carrey reprises his role as the title character Ace Ventura, a detective who specializes in retrieval of tame or captive animals in Ace Ventura:When Nature Calls. Ian McNeice,Simon Callow,Maynard Eziashi,Bob Gunton,Sophie Okonedo and Tommy Davidson play key supporting roles.His latest case, the disappearance of a rare African white bat, draws him out of his spiritual retreat at a Tibetan monastery following the tragic outcome of his previous case. Ace Ventura is on assignment in Africa to prevent a tribal war by saving a white bat sacred to both sides. Along the way, he nearly sleeps with a seductive African princess before her wedding, experiences astral projection with an enlightened monkey, masturbates, collects bat dung and, last but not least, is birthed by a mechanical rhino. Often short on taste, the film is nonetheless full of good spirit and plenty of genuine belly laughs particularly during the fight scene with a diminutive tribal champion. Not for every taste, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is either hilarious or insufferable, depending on the viewer's opinion of Carrey's unique brand of slapstick and sight gags. If you're ready to laugh like a pack of hyenas, if you want more fun than an industrial-sized barrel of monkeys, you know what to do.Watch this film for that reason and also for guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Racist and stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    almbjaer-107-905553
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a kid I loved the first Ace Ventura movie. I remember not being as fond of the second one but that was mainly because I loved the first one so much. I've then rewatched the first one and actually thought it was kind of funny. Today I rewatched the second movie and seriously, it's just appallingly racist and stupid. It basically repeats the famous lines from the first movie (really, like a glove etc) and in between, it depicts people in Africa like a 50s documentary. If anyone thinks this movie is really funny, they should never be allowed to watch a movie again. Basically, they should forfeit their sight and give it to blind people so that they can use it to watch better movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but doesn't live up to the original,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura When Nature Calls is a good,funny movie,but doesn't live up to the original movie,it would probably be a lot better if it didn't have Ace Ventura Pet Detective to compare to.Jim Carrey usually saves these movies with his high energy and comedy,I felt to same way about Me,Myself and Irene,they just would not be the same without Jim Carrey,because he is one of my favorite actors and never fails to make me laugh.Currently the only sequel Jim Carrey has ever done. Ace Ventura (Jim Carrey) comes out of retirement to help find a missing white bat who is the symbol of an African tribe.He finds himself in more trouble than he expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Almost Perfect Sequel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A year before this sequel, we were introduced to Ace Ventura; a rude, wise cracking pet detective who has the reputation for being the ONLY pet detective. Guess what? He's back and still has every quality he had in the original. I know, it sounds like there's a catch here. Well there is not-at least with Jim Carrey's character. I did not like this movie as much as the original for one reason and one reason only. No it wasn't that Courtney Cox didn't reprise her role as Melissa Robinson. That I can deal with. My problem was that the story involved some characters that made Ace Ventura's character seem stupid. What made the original funny was that Ace Ventura was on top of his game. He knew what he was doing and how he was doing it. What also made it funny was that nobody ELSE knew what he was doing and although it seemed strange, Ventura got the job done. This occurred throughout the entire first film. And that's how it goes for most of this movie. The part of the movie that I think either did not need to be added or could have been modified was when Ace Ventura was among the African Tribes. What was so hard for me grasp was that in the first movie, they took a smart crazy detective and put him around a bunch of normal people that understood nothing of what he did. When Ventura is around the Tribe members, he is the dumb crazy detective. Why do I say this? Because Jim Carrey's character does not speak their language. It is this major flaw of why some of the laughs fail in this movie for me. For example, when Ventura starts to eat the food at the tribe's festival, he does not realize what he was eating until he is told what it really was. I thought Ventura was the smart one here? The whole point of the first film was so that the joke would be on everyone else; now the roles are switched? Why? Does the laugh really need to be on our comedic hero? It was at that point I started to wonder whether Ace really knew what he was doing. Of course these kinds of instances did not happen all the time. There were many parts where Ventura was surrounded by upper class people who thought they were better than he was and just like the first film he proved them wrong with a snotty remark and an obscene gesture. That's the old Ace I know! That is what made Ace Ventura such a character. Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is almost a perfect sequel. It still has good laughs but it is dumbed down by its mediocre screenplay. It is because of this that Ace Ventura does not seem always on top of everyone else like he was in the first film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the reasons not to make a sequel..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mbat19
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura pet detective was a surprise hit which of course means it would lead to the inevitable sequel and voila here it is Ace Ventura When Nature Calls. Unfortunately, they should not have answered. While the first Ace Ventura was entertaining light and charming in its ways and was dumb and knew it was dumb and played off of it, this one tries way too hard and the jokes for the most part fall flat and some fall very very flat to the point that the movie is almost racist in parts. If you must see an ace ventura double feature, see the first one twice. My true rating for this is a zero, but their scale does not go that low.. This one is for the birds..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wildly uneven Carrey vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I consider Ace Ventura When Nature Calls to be the 'acid test' for Jim Carrey devotees who claim unconditional love for the man's work: anyone who can sit through this film in its entirety without feeling even the slightest tinge of annoyance at Carrey's wildly unrestrained performance, which sees the manic star seemingly knowing no bounds when it comes to acting the fool, genuinely deserves the perhaps rather dubious honour of being dubbed a true 'Super Fan'. As to whether the film should be considered by your more casual Carrey fan, I say give it a go if you're feeling brave: its worth enduring the embarrassingly bad moments to be able to savour the genuinely funny bits, which very occasionally border on comic genius (just try keeping a straight face as Carrey escapes from his mechanical rhino disguise or goes head to head in combat with a savage African native). 5.5, rounded up to 6 for having a monkey tied to a raft, a masturbation gag in a PG flick (try explaining that one to the kids!), and the Monopoly guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gravy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neenahhh
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! It's kind of on the same level as the first movie. Both movies made me laugh out loud. This film features your different kind of humor. The humor in these films isn't your usual fast wit kind. It's the slapstick kind of comedy where things actually happen. People were hit, people were made fun of, people had stuff done to them, etc. It also includes crude humor. Different and kind of rude, but still hilarious. The plot wasn't exactly A+, but the humor made up for it. I mean, really. It did. Jim Carrey saved this movie. Jim Carrey was really perfect for this role. Crazy-ass Ace Ventura. Who else can play such a part?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Actually, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is not quite as bad as this summary suggests. Though that is not to say that this film is good, for me it isn't. The film does look good, it was interesting to see the likes of Simon Callow and he especially does bring some dignity and like in the first Jim Carrey does a fine job carrying the film. However the plot is very predictable and flimsy, and the direction lacks the energy and imagination of that of the first. The film also could have done with being longer consequently some of the characters lacked credibility. Also the pace is not as snappy and smart, when the humour fell flat(like it did one too many times) it felt like a balloon had been popped. The slapstick is very juvenile here, while the script is more childish than sophisticated and for me that was a bad idea. Overall, disappointing but thanks to Carrey it is at least watchable if nothing to go wild about. 4/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much much much better than the first one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rare bat is stolen from a tribe in the jungle and Ventura is called in to find it. He soon learns that the bat isn't his motives for being there, but he is actually there for something else completely at which time his true detective skills surface so he can get to the bottom of this. This movie made me laugh a few times, which the first didn't. I still think it is a horrible movie with a lot of over the top acting and so stupid that only a 5 year old should watch it. It had a couple laughs though so I can't completely hate it. Steve did such a better job directing than the guy from the first one. This movie actually had a better story, better settings, the antics were less and it was more serious, It had much more to offer. The movie was bad but several things made me like it enough to give it a higher rating than part 1, which I gave 1 out of 10 stars. I liked the parody of Cliffhanger, I loved the joke made referencing the Twilight Zone episode with William Shatner, I loved the part where he wears the little man around his neck to mock the woman with the fur and I laughed at him squeezing out of a tiny hole in the butt of a rubber Rhino. The acting was better, Carrey went from 350 grand on the first film to 5 million on this one. Adawale had a small role and I think he is a great actor and Tommy Davidson who had worked many times with Carrey on IN LIVING COLOR did a great job as the tiny warrior. These two movies were big, and spawned so many catch phrases but it just isn't my thing - my true vote is 1.5 out of 10 stars but I went ahead and gave it 2 here on IMDb to let myself know in the future that I liked it better than the first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jim Carrey Love Him or Hate Him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kikabeth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey is one of those actors you will find yourself either adoring or hating. He does not ever "underact." This movie made me laugh so hard I cried (even after the fifth time!) From the robot rhino scene to the monopoly guy Jim knows how to be hilarious. I saw the first one (liked it allot) and have to say this one is way better! I am a huge fan of Carrey. I don't think there are many people who can make such a variety of facial expressions. The only reason this is not a ten is because there is (as usual with Carrey) some inappropriate stuff thrown in. But if your love laughing and you love Jim, this movie will fit you "Like a glove!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Guilty Pleasure Pet Detective Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This inevitable sequel finds Jim Carrey reprises his role as the title character Ace Ventura, a detective who specializes in retrieval of tame or captive animals in Ace Ventura:When Nature Calls. Ian McNeice,Simon Callow,Maynard Eziashi,Bob Gunton,Sophie Okonedo and Tommy Davidson play key supporting roles.His latest case, the disappearance of a rare African white bat, draws him out of his spiritual retreat at a Tibetan monastery following the tragic outcome of his previous case. Ace Ventura is on assignment in Africa to prevent a tribal war by saving a white bat sacred to both sides. Along the way, he nearly sleeps with a seductive African princess before her wedding, experiences astral projection with an enlightened monkey, masturbates, collects bat dung and, last but not least, is birthed by a mechanical rhino. Often short on taste, the film is nonetheless full of good spirit and plenty of genuine belly laughs particularly during the fight scene with a diminutive tribal champion. Not for every taste, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is either hilarious or insufferable, depending on the viewer's opinion of Carrey's unique brand of slapstick and sight gags. If you're ready to laugh like a pack of hyenas, if you want more fun than an industrial-sized barrel of monkeys, you know what to do.Watch this film for that reason and also for guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Racist and stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    almbjaer-107-905553
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a kid I loved the first Ace Ventura movie. I remember not being as fond of the second one but that was mainly because I loved the first one so much. I've then rewatched the first one and actually thought it was kind of funny. Today I rewatched the second movie and seriously, it's just appallingly racist and stupid. It basically repeats the famous lines from the first movie (really, like a glove etc) and in between, it depicts people in Africa like a 50s documentary. If anyone thinks this movie is really funny, they should never be allowed to watch a movie again. Basically, they should forfeit their sight and give it to blind people so that they can use it to watch better movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but doesn't live up to the original,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura When Nature Calls is a good,funny movie,but doesn't live up to the original movie,it would probably be a lot better if it didn't have Ace Ventura Pet Detective to compare to.Jim Carrey usually saves these movies with his high energy and comedy,I felt to same way about Me,Myself and Irene,they just would not be the same without Jim Carrey,because he is one of my favorite actors and never fails to make me laugh.Currently the only sequel Jim Carrey has ever done. Ace Ventura (Jim Carrey) comes out of retirement to help find a missing white bat who is the symbol of an African tribe.He finds himself in more trouble than he expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Almost Perfect Sequel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A year before this sequel, we were introduced to Ace Ventura; a rude, wise cracking pet detective who has the reputation for being the ONLY pet detective. Guess what? He's back and still has every quality he had in the original. I know, it sounds like there's a catch here. Well there is not-at least with Jim Carrey's character. I did not like this movie as much as the original for one reason and one reason only. No it wasn't that Courtney Cox didn't reprise her role as Melissa Robinson. That I can deal with. My problem was that the story involved some characters that made Ace Ventura's character seem stupid. What made the original funny was that Ace Ventura was on top of his game. He knew what he was doing and how he was doing it. What also made it funny was that nobody ELSE knew what he was doing and although it seemed strange, Ventura got the job done. This occurred throughout the entire first film. And that's how it goes for most of this movie. The part of the movie that I think either did not need to be added or could have been modified was when Ace Ventura was among the African Tribes. What was so hard for me grasp was that in the first movie, they took a smart crazy detective and put him around a bunch of normal people that understood nothing of what he did. When Ventura is around the Tribe members, he is the dumb crazy detective. Why do I say this? Because Jim Carrey's character does not speak their language. It is this major flaw of why some of the laughs fail in this movie for me. For example, when Ventura starts to eat the food at the tribe's festival, he does not realize what he was eating until he is told what it really was. I thought Ventura was the smart one here? The whole point of the first film was so that the joke would be on everyone else; now the roles are switched? Why? Does the laugh really need to be on our comedic hero? It was at that point I started to wonder whether Ace really knew what he was doing. Of course these kinds of instances did not happen all the time. There were many parts where Ventura was surrounded by upper class people who thought they were better than he was and just like the first film he proved them wrong with a snotty remark and an obscene gesture. That's the old Ace I know! That is what made Ace Ventura such a character. Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is almost a perfect sequel. It still has good laughs but it is dumbed down by its mediocre screenplay. It is because of this that Ace Ventura does not seem always on top of everyone else like he was in the first film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the reasons not to make a sequel..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mbat19
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ace Ventura pet detective was a surprise hit which of course means it would lead to the inevitable sequel and voila here it is Ace Ventura When Nature Calls. Unfortunately, they should not have answered. While the first Ace Ventura was entertaining light and charming in its ways and was dumb and knew it was dumb and played off of it, this one tries way too hard and the jokes for the most part fall flat and some fall very very flat to the point that the movie is almost racist in parts. If you must see an ace ventura double feature, see the first one twice. My true rating for this is a zero, but their scale does not go that low.. This one is for the birds..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wildly uneven Carrey vehicle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I consider Ace Ventura When Nature Calls to be the 'acid test' for Jim Carrey devotees who claim unconditional love for the man's work: anyone who can sit through this film in its entirety without feeling even the slightest tinge of annoyance at Carrey's wildly unrestrained performance, which sees the manic star seemingly knowing no bounds when it comes to acting the fool, genuinely deserves the perhaps rather dubious honour of being dubbed a true 'Super Fan'. As to whether the film should be considered by your more casual Carrey fan, I say give it a go if you're feeling brave: its worth enduring the embarrassingly bad moments to be able to savour the genuinely funny bits, which very occasionally border on comic genius (just try keeping a straight face as Carrey escapes from his mechanical rhino disguise or goes head to head in combat with a savage African native). 5.5, rounded up to 6 for having a monkey tied to a raft, a masturbation gag in a PG flick (try explaining that one to the kids!), and the Monopoly guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gravy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neenahhh
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was hilarious! It's kind of on the same level as the first movie. Both movies made me laugh out loud. This film features your different kind of humor. The humor in these films isn't your usual fast wit kind. It's the slapstick kind of comedy where things actually happen. People were hit, people were made fun of, people had stuff done to them, etc. It also includes crude humor. Different and kind of rude, but still hilarious. The plot wasn't exactly A+, but the humor made up for it. I mean, really. It did. Jim Carrey saved this movie. Jim Carrey was really perfect for this role. Crazy-ass Ace Ventura. Who else can play such a part?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Actually, Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls is not quite as bad as this summary suggests. Though that is not to say that this film is good, for me it isn't. The film does look good, it was interesting to see the likes of Simon Callow and he especially does bring some dignity and like in the first Jim Carrey does a fine job carrying the film. However the plot is very predictable and flimsy, and the direction lacks the energy and imagination of that of the first. The film also could have done with being longer consequently some of the characters lacked credibility. Also the pace is not as snappy and smart, when the humour fell flat(like it did one too many times) it felt like a balloon had been popped. The slapstick is very juvenile here, while the script is more childish than sophisticated and for me that was a bad idea. Overall, disappointing but thanks to Carrey it is at least watchable if nothing to go wild about. 4/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much much much better than the first one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A rare bat is stolen from a tribe in the jungle and Ventura is called in to find it. He soon learns that the bat isn't his motives for being there, but he is actually there for something else completely at which time his true detective skills surface so he can get to the bottom of this. This movie made me laugh a few times, which the first didn't. I still think it is a horrible movie with a lot of over the top acting and so stupid that only a 5 year old should watch it. It had a couple laughs though so I can't completely hate it. Steve did such a better job directing than the guy from the first one. This movie actually had a better story, better settings, the antics were less and it was more serious, It had much more to offer. The movie was bad but several things made me like it enough to give it a higher rating than part 1, which I gave 1 out of 10 stars. I liked the parody of Cliffhanger, I loved the joke made referencing the Twilight Zone episode with William Shatner, I loved the part where he wears the little man around his neck to mock the woman with the fur and I laughed at him squeezing out of a tiny hole in the butt of a rubber Rhino. The acting was better, Carrey went from 350 grand on the first film to 5 million on this one. Adawale had a small role and I think he is a great actor and Tommy Davidson who had worked many times with Carrey on IN LIVING COLOR did a great job as the tiny warrior. These two movies were big, and spawned so many catch phrases but it just isn't my thing - my true vote is 1.5 out of 10 stars but I went ahead and gave it 2 here on IMDb to let myself know in the future that I liked it better than the first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
