<filme>
 <id>
  365
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114168
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Energia Pura
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young bald albino boy with unique powers shakes up the rural community he lives in.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  When sheriff Barnum investigates the death of an elderly rural resident, he discovers a teenage grandson living in the basement. Raised by his grandparents, he has experienced the world only through books, never leaving the family farm. He is sent to a state home for boys where he has trouble fitting in socially. His odd appearance and unusual abilities cause the small town residents to fear and ridicule him. However, not all are afraid. Some begin to view his potential and gifts with wonderment.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   albino
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sheriff
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mutant
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tragic event
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Victor Salva
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Victor Salva
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Mary Steenburgen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sean Patrick Flanery
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lance Henriksen
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden jewel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick-verdoolaeghe
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't is see this movie before? It is one of those hidden jewels you stumble upon after looking for a good movie and have to dig trough the dirt. So i'm not going to give a big review here. JUST SEE IT. IT IS MORE THEN WORTH IT! GIVE IT AN Oscar OK have to give an bigger review here otherwise it won't stick. So why is this film so unappreciated in movie-land? It has everything a good movie should have. A good original story, well known and good actors, good screen shots, moving music and some minimal special effects. It has so many layers without being predictable and over the top like some of the Hollywood movies. Well people you should give it more points. Let's do it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A powerful and unforgettable story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very rare gem of a movie. In a time when movies have a lot of fx to cover up a weak story, to graphic unnecessary violence and sex. Powder basically shows a pure and unique individual that is not accepted in today's society that has become jaded with discrimination, and overall being afraid of someone who looks different. There are several important elements in the movie. There is the paranormal factor that challenges what we know of science and the the human mind can achieve, the extent of human cruelty, love and forgiveness, and a hope that we may advance beyond technology. The most of all, raw emotion the reaches deep into the heart and leaves a impression that will stay with you. What also makes this movie great is that even though it is not a true story it could be. The idea of being different because of looks or something that makes you stand out from the status quo of the different groups, where we can all relate to. This movie achieves this in a powerful, passionate and inspirational way. This movie makes you sit back and take in everything, showing us what the world may be if we stop judging one another and start to accept our uniqueness. What also is shown in this movie is just that just because someone may be different with looks or how they act that they are some weaker or a part of the undesirables. Who time and again in this movie seem to show us that perception needs to be changed. One scene where we find out he has the highest I.Q. ever recorded.,to a scene where a hunter shoots a deer and powder touches the deer and the hunter and shows him the pain the deer feels before he dies that has a profound effect on the hunter. Another scene where Powder helps the local sheriff understand what his dying wife wants, which is to just reconcile with his son. You have a movie that looks like it could be a Carrie type movie but ends up showing the sad inability to treat Powder with any sense of humanity and dignity. No matter what he stays his pure positive self in some scenes showing the error of our ways and then in the end makes a final act that hopefully makes people want to change for the better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent and thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Look to the skies, especially for lightning bolts which appear repeatedly in Powder. The name is used on a high school aged boy to describe his pasty white skin. Jeremy(Sean Patrick Flanery) is an albino who has a magnet in his brain which causes strange things to happen when he shows up. His mother died shortly after his birth during a severe thunderstorm. His father left him with his grandparents and he did farm work and lived in a basement, reading every book available to him. After grandpa dies, the boy is taken by the state. He is placed in a high school and the physics teacher, Donald Ripley(Jeff Goldblum) tests him and is astounded that his i.q. is off the charts; a teenage Einstein is in school. The other students quickly resent him as an oddity. Jeremy hears a gunshot and when he goes to investigate, sees a doe on the ground, wounded and dying. Powder places his hand on the animal and his other hand on the deputy who shot it and his body sends the emotions of the deer into the officer. His perspective on hunting are forever changed. Word spreads through the town and another cop asks him to use his telepathic ability to communicate with his wife, who is close to death. He helps them with valuable insight. His schoolmates continue to taunt him and before it ends Powder delivers an important message in humanity. Flanery shows great range as the title character; hard to believe that he later played a vigilante lunatic in Boondock Saints. He makes this film work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total lack of empathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tl12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those you do not like or get the movie or those who feel it's stupid have one thing in common. They never grew up with a disability that made them the perpetual outsider. The one who was jeered at, constantly denigrated, beat up by groups (never just one person). In real life there is no Mary Steenburgen to stand up for them. In most cases the adults and authority figures turn a blind eye and in the worse cases join in. I do know. I grew up as a disabled person. I went through all the bigotry, ignorant taunts and carried the weight of the hate those around me felt for me, for some over which I had no control. Those people in my life and the same type here lack a important trait that makes us human, EMPATHY.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powder - One of the BEST.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George D. Dodge
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, Powder is one of the best movies ever made in regards to its message. It deals with the ridiculousness of prejudice, bigotry, false judgements, animal cruelty, love of nature, love of mankind, love of life, and love of your fellow man. This movie is filled with love, IF, and I say IF you can "see" it. It is right in front of you. All you have to do, is really "watch" and "listen" to the movie. The acting is excellent. The music is excellent. The story is excellent and easy to follow. Cinematography is excellent. Directing is excellent also. It is a true winner. I wish more movies like this were being made. The world needs them, especially in this day and age. .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, get over it - it's a great love story!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pandaloonie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not all love stories are guy-girl. This is just a huge human love story. And I LOVED it! Set the popcorn on refill mode and keep a keg of beer and a whole bunch of Kleenex at hand for the ending. First off, if Lance Henriksen reads the back of a toilet paper roll, sign me up and put me in the front row. The man delivers 110% to whatever role he is given. Period. Second, Ms Mary is a home girl, so props to her. Period. The rest of the cast I thought were superb. Again, period. This is a genuine feel-good movie and I highly recommend it. I am not going to give any spoilers for that would - spoil it. But let me say that as an avid movie watcher (older than most of you lot) this one had me hooked first to last. And I did not anticipate the ending though if I could it would have not been better. Go forth and enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle and moving film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Casey Dillard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie holds a very special place in my heart since I was young. Victor Salva, it seems, had at least one good story in him and this, though in some ways sappy, was certainly it. The treatment of the main character makes it hard to watch at times because it can feel very bleak and hopeless, but it is balanced out by the tenderness of the characters who do accept him and offer him hope and kindness. The acting is excellent in this film and the cast is to be commended for not turning the script into something sickly or too predictable. The ending brought me to tears and maybe felt like an easy way out, but it did feel appropriate. All in all, I'd suggest that anyone watch it at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but not powerful enough to be great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, here's another story about a different person in a world that is prejudicial against what's not "normal", who most of the time is very misunderstood except for few people out there who really want to help and also want to understand how magnificent this person is. And this person has supernatural powers, this time involving electricity and an enormous memory capacity, memorizing book quotations from start to finish. Powder (Sean Patrick Flanery) is this person, an albino with extraordinary powers who was left alone in the world after his grandparents death, and now having to deal with the world outside of the basement where he lived, hidden of the eyes of everybody. Target of the prejudice of almost everybody, the only friends he has are the Sheriff (Lance Henriksen), a psychologist (Mary Steenburgen), a teacher (Jeff Goldblum) and a girl (Melissa Lahlitah Crider), intrigued by his mysterious gift. And again, it's a story about seeing the most difficult thing of all: the inside of someone rather than the physical appearance and learn what people have to say, discover their magic and be comprehensible to what this people are. The movie deserves some praise? Yes. In the best possible way the story was well presented but the film's magic comes from some of the situations where the great special effects are a real fun; the great casting never disappoints, all very good. But something tells me again and again that I've seen this story better developed in countless films and somehow the electricity, the vibrations coming from this flick weren't good enough to pass through my heart and make me feel something unexperienced or highly intelligent. It's just good and that's it. It tries to set some emotion but hardly succeeds in such task. Jerry Goldsmith musical score is sweeter than sugar, a little bit excessive at points. And it's a mystery to me that an albino attracted such negative attention from people like in this film, I mean, Southerns never saw one in life? If Jeremy/Powder was painted in blue I would believe in a frightened reaction from the crowd but an albino? It's more common than having Smurfs statues in your garden. It brings some positive light in showing that evolution/technology must be viewed in a lesser degree than the designs of the human spirit, and Powder does represent that but it stops right there. No more lessons to be learned, no more deeper thoughts to share. "Powder" is a nice film, very watchable, good to look at it but don't go with high expectations. The best film directed by Victor Salva so far, if we consider the weak "Jeepers Creepers" series. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disgraceful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    unendurable_lampoonery
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well, at first i enjoyed this movie to an extent, then found out about the director's (Victor Selva) horrible past. a confessed child molester, he compares himself to the main character of this film, this is how he felt in jail, well I'm sorry, an albino has a lot less choice than a dirty pedophile who actually molested a child while making his first movie, the horrible over rated clown house. this movie would actually be good if the director did not write the main character based of himself, a dirty old man. disgraceful director, and a bad person to even compare himself to an amazingly powerful character, this movie is mediocre, at best, it would be better if i had not have read the directors statements on this movie. 3-10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful story, simply...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yoann Larrieu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the story of a very special young man, too pure for this world. Some indications are very interesting: like the day he describes as the worst of his life; the way he communicates with other people, and specifically, the way he candidly reacts to aggression and violence...: and ultimately, what he's really referring to when he says he "wants to go home". Eventually, being so pure and suffocating in this corrupt, blasphemous world; and clearly embodying the moral and purity figures and healing ability of Jesus Christ; he nonetheless longs to experience the tangible world, with all its intact qualities and various wonders - while always being torn away from them at some point by the dread of man's evil and cruelty. A unique character in fiction; resembling some great figures, while never replicating them; a very powerful and "pure" story - and I give this a 9/10 because though the depth is there, and the ideas are beautiful; the "form" of the film and certain scenes remain things that could have been done better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden jewel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick-verdoolaeghe
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't is see this movie before? It is one of those hidden jewels you stumble upon after looking for a good movie and have to dig trough the dirt. So i'm not going to give a big review here. JUST SEE IT. IT IS MORE THEN WORTH IT! GIVE IT AN Oscar OK have to give an bigger review here otherwise it won't stick. So why is this film so unappreciated in movie-land? It has everything a good movie should have. A good original story, well known and good actors, good screen shots, moving music and some minimal special effects. It has so many layers without being predictable and over the top like some of the Hollywood movies. Well people you should give it more points. Let's do it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A powerful and unforgettable story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very rare gem of a movie. In a time when movies have a lot of fx to cover up a weak story, to graphic unnecessary violence and sex. Powder basically shows a pure and unique individual that is not accepted in today's society that has become jaded with discrimination, and overall being afraid of someone who looks different. There are several important elements in the movie. There is the paranormal factor that challenges what we know of science and the the human mind can achieve, the extent of human cruelty, love and forgiveness, and a hope that we may advance beyond technology. The most of all, raw emotion the reaches deep into the heart and leaves a impression that will stay with you. What also makes this movie great is that even though it is not a true story it could be. The idea of being different because of looks or something that makes you stand out from the status quo of the different groups, where we can all relate to. This movie achieves this in a powerful, passionate and inspirational way. This movie makes you sit back and take in everything, showing us what the world may be if we stop judging one another and start to accept our uniqueness. What also is shown in this movie is just that just because someone may be different with looks or how they act that they are some weaker or a part of the undesirables. Who time and again in this movie seem to show us that perception needs to be changed. One scene where we find out he has the highest I.Q. ever recorded.,to a scene where a hunter shoots a deer and powder touches the deer and the hunter and shows him the pain the deer feels before he dies that has a profound effect on the hunter. Another scene where Powder helps the local sheriff understand what his dying wife wants, which is to just reconcile with his son. You have a movie that looks like it could be a Carrie type movie but ends up showing the sad inability to treat Powder with any sense of humanity and dignity. No matter what he stays his pure positive self in some scenes showing the error of our ways and then in the end makes a final act that hopefully makes people want to change for the better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent and thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Look to the skies, especially for lightning bolts which appear repeatedly in Powder. The name is used on a high school aged boy to describe his pasty white skin. Jeremy(Sean Patrick Flanery) is an albino who has a magnet in his brain which causes strange things to happen when he shows up. His mother died shortly after his birth during a severe thunderstorm. His father left him with his grandparents and he did farm work and lived in a basement, reading every book available to him. After grandpa dies, the boy is taken by the state. He is placed in a high school and the physics teacher, Donald Ripley(Jeff Goldblum) tests him and is astounded that his i.q. is off the charts; a teenage Einstein is in school. The other students quickly resent him as an oddity. Jeremy hears a gunshot and when he goes to investigate, sees a doe on the ground, wounded and dying. Powder places his hand on the animal and his other hand on the deputy who shot it and his body sends the emotions of the deer into the officer. His perspective on hunting are forever changed. Word spreads through the town and another cop asks him to use his telepathic ability to communicate with his wife, who is close to death. He helps them with valuable insight. His schoolmates continue to taunt him and before it ends Powder delivers an important message in humanity. Flanery shows great range as the title character; hard to believe that he later played a vigilante lunatic in Boondock Saints. He makes this film work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total lack of empathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tl12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those you do not like or get the movie or those who feel it's stupid have one thing in common. They never grew up with a disability that made them the perpetual outsider. The one who was jeered at, constantly denigrated, beat up by groups (never just one person). In real life there is no Mary Steenburgen to stand up for them. In most cases the adults and authority figures turn a blind eye and in the worse cases join in. I do know. I grew up as a disabled person. I went through all the bigotry, ignorant taunts and carried the weight of the hate those around me felt for me, for some over which I had no control. Those people in my life and the same type here lack a important trait that makes us human, EMPATHY.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powder - One of the BEST.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George D. Dodge
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, Powder is one of the best movies ever made in regards to its message. It deals with the ridiculousness of prejudice, bigotry, false judgements, animal cruelty, love of nature, love of mankind, love of life, and love of your fellow man. This movie is filled with love, IF, and I say IF you can "see" it. It is right in front of you. All you have to do, is really "watch" and "listen" to the movie. The acting is excellent. The music is excellent. The story is excellent and easy to follow. Cinematography is excellent. Directing is excellent also. It is a true winner. I wish more movies like this were being made. The world needs them, especially in this day and age. .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, get over it - it's a great love story!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pandaloonie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not all love stories are guy-girl. This is just a huge human love story. And I LOVED it! Set the popcorn on refill mode and keep a keg of beer and a whole bunch of Kleenex at hand for the ending. First off, if Lance Henriksen reads the back of a toilet paper roll, sign me up and put me in the front row. The man delivers 110% to whatever role he is given. Period. Second, Ms Mary is a home girl, so props to her. Period. The rest of the cast I thought were superb. Again, period. This is a genuine feel-good movie and I highly recommend it. I am not going to give any spoilers for that would - spoil it. But let me say that as an avid movie watcher (older than most of you lot) this one had me hooked first to last. And I did not anticipate the ending though if I could it would have not been better. Go forth and enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle and moving film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Casey Dillard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie holds a very special place in my heart since I was young. Victor Salva, it seems, had at least one good story in him and this, though in some ways sappy, was certainly it. The treatment of the main character makes it hard to watch at times because it can feel very bleak and hopeless, but it is balanced out by the tenderness of the characters who do accept him and offer him hope and kindness. The acting is excellent in this film and the cast is to be commended for not turning the script into something sickly or too predictable. The ending brought me to tears and maybe felt like an easy way out, but it did feel appropriate. All in all, I'd suggest that anyone watch it at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but not powerful enough to be great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, here's another story about a different person in a world that is prejudicial against what's not "normal", who most of the time is very misunderstood except for few people out there who really want to help and also want to understand how magnificent this person is. And this person has supernatural powers, this time involving electricity and an enormous memory capacity, memorizing book quotations from start to finish. Powder (Sean Patrick Flanery) is this person, an albino with extraordinary powers who was left alone in the world after his grandparents death, and now having to deal with the world outside of the basement where he lived, hidden of the eyes of everybody. Target of the prejudice of almost everybody, the only friends he has are the Sheriff (Lance Henriksen), a psychologist (Mary Steenburgen), a teacher (Jeff Goldblum) and a girl (Melissa Lahlitah Crider), intrigued by his mysterious gift. And again, it's a story about seeing the most difficult thing of all: the inside of someone rather than the physical appearance and learn what people have to say, discover their magic and be comprehensible to what this people are. The movie deserves some praise? Yes. In the best possible way the story was well presented but the film's magic comes from some of the situations where the great special effects are a real fun; the great casting never disappoints, all very good. But something tells me again and again that I've seen this story better developed in countless films and somehow the electricity, the vibrations coming from this flick weren't good enough to pass through my heart and make me feel something unexperienced or highly intelligent. It's just good and that's it. It tries to set some emotion but hardly succeeds in such task. Jerry Goldsmith musical score is sweeter than sugar, a little bit excessive at points. And it's a mystery to me that an albino attracted such negative attention from people like in this film, I mean, Southerns never saw one in life? If Jeremy/Powder was painted in blue I would believe in a frightened reaction from the crowd but an albino? It's more common than having Smurfs statues in your garden. It brings some positive light in showing that evolution/technology must be viewed in a lesser degree than the designs of the human spirit, and Powder does represent that but it stops right there. No more lessons to be learned, no more deeper thoughts to share. "Powder" is a nice film, very watchable, good to look at it but don't go with high expectations. The best film directed by Victor Salva so far, if we consider the weak "Jeepers Creepers" series. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disgraceful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    unendurable_lampoonery
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well, at first i enjoyed this movie to an extent, then found out about the director's (Victor Selva) horrible past. a confessed child molester, he compares himself to the main character of this film, this is how he felt in jail, well I'm sorry, an albino has a lot less choice than a dirty pedophile who actually molested a child while making his first movie, the horrible over rated clown house. this movie would actually be good if the director did not write the main character based of himself, a dirty old man. disgraceful director, and a bad person to even compare himself to an amazingly powerful character, this movie is mediocre, at best, it would be better if i had not have read the directors statements on this movie. 3-10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful story, simply...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yoann Larrieu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the story of a very special young man, too pure for this world. Some indications are very interesting: like the day he describes as the worst of his life; the way he communicates with other people, and specifically, the way he candidly reacts to aggression and violence...: and ultimately, what he's really referring to when he says he "wants to go home". Eventually, being so pure and suffocating in this corrupt, blasphemous world; and clearly embodying the moral and purity figures and healing ability of Jesus Christ; he nonetheless longs to experience the tangible world, with all its intact qualities and various wonders - while always being torn away from them at some point by the dread of man's evil and cruelty. A unique character in fiction; resembling some great figures, while never replicating them; a very powerful and "pure" story - and I give this a 9/10 because though the depth is there, and the ideas are beautiful; the "form" of the film and certain scenes remain things that could have been done better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden jewel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick-verdoolaeghe
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't is see this movie before? It is one of those hidden jewels you stumble upon after looking for a good movie and have to dig trough the dirt. So i'm not going to give a big review here. JUST SEE IT. IT IS MORE THEN WORTH IT! GIVE IT AN Oscar OK have to give an bigger review here otherwise it won't stick. So why is this film so unappreciated in movie-land? It has everything a good movie should have. A good original story, well known and good actors, good screen shots, moving music and some minimal special effects. It has so many layers without being predictable and over the top like some of the Hollywood movies. Well people you should give it more points. Let's do it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A powerful and unforgettable story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very rare gem of a movie. In a time when movies have a lot of fx to cover up a weak story, to graphic unnecessary violence and sex. Powder basically shows a pure and unique individual that is not accepted in today's society that has become jaded with discrimination, and overall being afraid of someone who looks different. There are several important elements in the movie. There is the paranormal factor that challenges what we know of science and the the human mind can achieve, the extent of human cruelty, love and forgiveness, and a hope that we may advance beyond technology. The most of all, raw emotion the reaches deep into the heart and leaves a impression that will stay with you. What also makes this movie great is that even though it is not a true story it could be. The idea of being different because of looks or something that makes you stand out from the status quo of the different groups, where we can all relate to. This movie achieves this in a powerful, passionate and inspirational way. This movie makes you sit back and take in everything, showing us what the world may be if we stop judging one another and start to accept our uniqueness. What also is shown in this movie is just that just because someone may be different with looks or how they act that they are some weaker or a part of the undesirables. Who time and again in this movie seem to show us that perception needs to be changed. One scene where we find out he has the highest I.Q. ever recorded.,to a scene where a hunter shoots a deer and powder touches the deer and the hunter and shows him the pain the deer feels before he dies that has a profound effect on the hunter. Another scene where Powder helps the local sheriff understand what his dying wife wants, which is to just reconcile with his son. You have a movie that looks like it could be a Carrie type movie but ends up showing the sad inability to treat Powder with any sense of humanity and dignity. No matter what he stays his pure positive self in some scenes showing the error of our ways and then in the end makes a final act that hopefully makes people want to change for the better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent and thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Look to the skies, especially for lightning bolts which appear repeatedly in Powder. The name is used on a high school aged boy to describe his pasty white skin. Jeremy(Sean Patrick Flanery) is an albino who has a magnet in his brain which causes strange things to happen when he shows up. His mother died shortly after his birth during a severe thunderstorm. His father left him with his grandparents and he did farm work and lived in a basement, reading every book available to him. After grandpa dies, the boy is taken by the state. He is placed in a high school and the physics teacher, Donald Ripley(Jeff Goldblum) tests him and is astounded that his i.q. is off the charts; a teenage Einstein is in school. The other students quickly resent him as an oddity. Jeremy hears a gunshot and when he goes to investigate, sees a doe on the ground, wounded and dying. Powder places his hand on the animal and his other hand on the deputy who shot it and his body sends the emotions of the deer into the officer. His perspective on hunting are forever changed. Word spreads through the town and another cop asks him to use his telepathic ability to communicate with his wife, who is close to death. He helps them with valuable insight. His schoolmates continue to taunt him and before it ends Powder delivers an important message in humanity. Flanery shows great range as the title character; hard to believe that he later played a vigilante lunatic in Boondock Saints. He makes this film work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total lack of empathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tl12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those you do not like or get the movie or those who feel it's stupid have one thing in common. They never grew up with a disability that made them the perpetual outsider. The one who was jeered at, constantly denigrated, beat up by groups (never just one person). In real life there is no Mary Steenburgen to stand up for them. In most cases the adults and authority figures turn a blind eye and in the worse cases join in. I do know. I grew up as a disabled person. I went through all the bigotry, ignorant taunts and carried the weight of the hate those around me felt for me, for some over which I had no control. Those people in my life and the same type here lack a important trait that makes us human, EMPATHY.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powder - One of the BEST.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George D. Dodge
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, Powder is one of the best movies ever made in regards to its message. It deals with the ridiculousness of prejudice, bigotry, false judgements, animal cruelty, love of nature, love of mankind, love of life, and love of your fellow man. This movie is filled with love, IF, and I say IF you can "see" it. It is right in front of you. All you have to do, is really "watch" and "listen" to the movie. The acting is excellent. The music is excellent. The story is excellent and easy to follow. Cinematography is excellent. Directing is excellent also. It is a true winner. I wish more movies like this were being made. The world needs them, especially in this day and age. .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, get over it - it's a great love story!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pandaloonie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not all love stories are guy-girl. This is just a huge human love story. And I LOVED it! Set the popcorn on refill mode and keep a keg of beer and a whole bunch of Kleenex at hand for the ending. First off, if Lance Henriksen reads the back of a toilet paper roll, sign me up and put me in the front row. The man delivers 110% to whatever role he is given. Period. Second, Ms Mary is a home girl, so props to her. Period. The rest of the cast I thought were superb. Again, period. This is a genuine feel-good movie and I highly recommend it. I am not going to give any spoilers for that would - spoil it. But let me say that as an avid movie watcher (older than most of you lot) this one had me hooked first to last. And I did not anticipate the ending though if I could it would have not been better. Go forth and enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle and moving film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Casey Dillard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie holds a very special place in my heart since I was young. Victor Salva, it seems, had at least one good story in him and this, though in some ways sappy, was certainly it. The treatment of the main character makes it hard to watch at times because it can feel very bleak and hopeless, but it is balanced out by the tenderness of the characters who do accept him and offer him hope and kindness. The acting is excellent in this film and the cast is to be commended for not turning the script into something sickly or too predictable. The ending brought me to tears and maybe felt like an easy way out, but it did feel appropriate. All in all, I'd suggest that anyone watch it at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but not powerful enough to be great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, here's another story about a different person in a world that is prejudicial against what's not "normal", who most of the time is very misunderstood except for few people out there who really want to help and also want to understand how magnificent this person is. And this person has supernatural powers, this time involving electricity and an enormous memory capacity, memorizing book quotations from start to finish. Powder (Sean Patrick Flanery) is this person, an albino with extraordinary powers who was left alone in the world after his grandparents death, and now having to deal with the world outside of the basement where he lived, hidden of the eyes of everybody. Target of the prejudice of almost everybody, the only friends he has are the Sheriff (Lance Henriksen), a psychologist (Mary Steenburgen), a teacher (Jeff Goldblum) and a girl (Melissa Lahlitah Crider), intrigued by his mysterious gift. And again, it's a story about seeing the most difficult thing of all: the inside of someone rather than the physical appearance and learn what people have to say, discover their magic and be comprehensible to what this people are. The movie deserves some praise? Yes. In the best possible way the story was well presented but the film's magic comes from some of the situations where the great special effects are a real fun; the great casting never disappoints, all very good. But something tells me again and again that I've seen this story better developed in countless films and somehow the electricity, the vibrations coming from this flick weren't good enough to pass through my heart and make me feel something unexperienced or highly intelligent. It's just good and that's it. It tries to set some emotion but hardly succeeds in such task. Jerry Goldsmith musical score is sweeter than sugar, a little bit excessive at points. And it's a mystery to me that an albino attracted such negative attention from people like in this film, I mean, Southerns never saw one in life? If Jeremy/Powder was painted in blue I would believe in a frightened reaction from the crowd but an albino? It's more common than having Smurfs statues in your garden. It brings some positive light in showing that evolution/technology must be viewed in a lesser degree than the designs of the human spirit, and Powder does represent that but it stops right there. No more lessons to be learned, no more deeper thoughts to share. "Powder" is a nice film, very watchable, good to look at it but don't go with high expectations. The best film directed by Victor Salva so far, if we consider the weak "Jeepers Creepers" series. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disgraceful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    unendurable_lampoonery
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well, at first i enjoyed this movie to an extent, then found out about the director's (Victor Selva) horrible past. a confessed child molester, he compares himself to the main character of this film, this is how he felt in jail, well I'm sorry, an albino has a lot less choice than a dirty pedophile who actually molested a child while making his first movie, the horrible over rated clown house. this movie would actually be good if the director did not write the main character based of himself, a dirty old man. disgraceful director, and a bad person to even compare himself to an amazingly powerful character, this movie is mediocre, at best, it would be better if i had not have read the directors statements on this movie. 3-10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful story, simply...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yoann Larrieu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the story of a very special young man, too pure for this world. Some indications are very interesting: like the day he describes as the worst of his life; the way he communicates with other people, and specifically, the way he candidly reacts to aggression and violence...: and ultimately, what he's really referring to when he says he "wants to go home". Eventually, being so pure and suffocating in this corrupt, blasphemous world; and clearly embodying the moral and purity figures and healing ability of Jesus Christ; he nonetheless longs to experience the tangible world, with all its intact qualities and various wonders - while always being torn away from them at some point by the dread of man's evil and cruelty. A unique character in fiction; resembling some great figures, while never replicating them; a very powerful and "pure" story - and I give this a 9/10 because though the depth is there, and the ideas are beautiful; the "form" of the film and certain scenes remain things that could have been done better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden jewel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick-verdoolaeghe
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't is see this movie before? It is one of those hidden jewels you stumble upon after looking for a good movie and have to dig trough the dirt. So i'm not going to give a big review here. JUST SEE IT. IT IS MORE THEN WORTH IT! GIVE IT AN Oscar OK have to give an bigger review here otherwise it won't stick. So why is this film so unappreciated in movie-land? It has everything a good movie should have. A good original story, well known and good actors, good screen shots, moving music and some minimal special effects. It has so many layers without being predictable and over the top like some of the Hollywood movies. Well people you should give it more points. Let's do it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A powerful and unforgettable story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very rare gem of a movie. In a time when movies have a lot of fx to cover up a weak story, to graphic unnecessary violence and sex. Powder basically shows a pure and unique individual that is not accepted in today's society that has become jaded with discrimination, and overall being afraid of someone who looks different. There are several important elements in the movie. There is the paranormal factor that challenges what we know of science and the the human mind can achieve, the extent of human cruelty, love and forgiveness, and a hope that we may advance beyond technology. The most of all, raw emotion the reaches deep into the heart and leaves a impression that will stay with you. What also makes this movie great is that even though it is not a true story it could be. The idea of being different because of looks or something that makes you stand out from the status quo of the different groups, where we can all relate to. This movie achieves this in a powerful, passionate and inspirational way. This movie makes you sit back and take in everything, showing us what the world may be if we stop judging one another and start to accept our uniqueness. What also is shown in this movie is just that just because someone may be different with looks or how they act that they are some weaker or a part of the undesirables. Who time and again in this movie seem to show us that perception needs to be changed. One scene where we find out he has the highest I.Q. ever recorded.,to a scene where a hunter shoots a deer and powder touches the deer and the hunter and shows him the pain the deer feels before he dies that has a profound effect on the hunter. Another scene where Powder helps the local sheriff understand what his dying wife wants, which is to just reconcile with his son. You have a movie that looks like it could be a Carrie type movie but ends up showing the sad inability to treat Powder with any sense of humanity and dignity. No matter what he stays his pure positive self in some scenes showing the error of our ways and then in the end makes a final act that hopefully makes people want to change for the better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent and thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Look to the skies, especially for lightning bolts which appear repeatedly in Powder. The name is used on a high school aged boy to describe his pasty white skin. Jeremy(Sean Patrick Flanery) is an albino who has a magnet in his brain which causes strange things to happen when he shows up. His mother died shortly after his birth during a severe thunderstorm. His father left him with his grandparents and he did farm work and lived in a basement, reading every book available to him. After grandpa dies, the boy is taken by the state. He is placed in a high school and the physics teacher, Donald Ripley(Jeff Goldblum) tests him and is astounded that his i.q. is off the charts; a teenage Einstein is in school. The other students quickly resent him as an oddity. Jeremy hears a gunshot and when he goes to investigate, sees a doe on the ground, wounded and dying. Powder places his hand on the animal and his other hand on the deputy who shot it and his body sends the emotions of the deer into the officer. His perspective on hunting are forever changed. Word spreads through the town and another cop asks him to use his telepathic ability to communicate with his wife, who is close to death. He helps them with valuable insight. His schoolmates continue to taunt him and before it ends Powder delivers an important message in humanity. Flanery shows great range as the title character; hard to believe that he later played a vigilante lunatic in Boondock Saints. He makes this film work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total lack of empathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tl12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those you do not like or get the movie or those who feel it's stupid have one thing in common. They never grew up with a disability that made them the perpetual outsider. The one who was jeered at, constantly denigrated, beat up by groups (never just one person). In real life there is no Mary Steenburgen to stand up for them. In most cases the adults and authority figures turn a blind eye and in the worse cases join in. I do know. I grew up as a disabled person. I went through all the bigotry, ignorant taunts and carried the weight of the hate those around me felt for me, for some over which I had no control. Those people in my life and the same type here lack a important trait that makes us human, EMPATHY.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powder - One of the BEST.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George D. Dodge
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, Powder is one of the best movies ever made in regards to its message. It deals with the ridiculousness of prejudice, bigotry, false judgements, animal cruelty, love of nature, love of mankind, love of life, and love of your fellow man. This movie is filled with love, IF, and I say IF you can "see" it. It is right in front of you. All you have to do, is really "watch" and "listen" to the movie. The acting is excellent. The music is excellent. The story is excellent and easy to follow. Cinematography is excellent. Directing is excellent also. It is a true winner. I wish more movies like this were being made. The world needs them, especially in this day and age. .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, get over it - it's a great love story!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pandaloonie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not all love stories are guy-girl. This is just a huge human love story. And I LOVED it! Set the popcorn on refill mode and keep a keg of beer and a whole bunch of Kleenex at hand for the ending. First off, if Lance Henriksen reads the back of a toilet paper roll, sign me up and put me in the front row. The man delivers 110% to whatever role he is given. Period. Second, Ms Mary is a home girl, so props to her. Period. The rest of the cast I thought were superb. Again, period. This is a genuine feel-good movie and I highly recommend it. I am not going to give any spoilers for that would - spoil it. But let me say that as an avid movie watcher (older than most of you lot) this one had me hooked first to last. And I did not anticipate the ending though if I could it would have not been better. Go forth and enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle and moving film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Casey Dillard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie holds a very special place in my heart since I was young. Victor Salva, it seems, had at least one good story in him and this, though in some ways sappy, was certainly it. The treatment of the main character makes it hard to watch at times because it can feel very bleak and hopeless, but it is balanced out by the tenderness of the characters who do accept him and offer him hope and kindness. The acting is excellent in this film and the cast is to be commended for not turning the script into something sickly or too predictable. The ending brought me to tears and maybe felt like an easy way out, but it did feel appropriate. All in all, I'd suggest that anyone watch it at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but not powerful enough to be great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, here's another story about a different person in a world that is prejudicial against what's not "normal", who most of the time is very misunderstood except for few people out there who really want to help and also want to understand how magnificent this person is. And this person has supernatural powers, this time involving electricity and an enormous memory capacity, memorizing book quotations from start to finish. Powder (Sean Patrick Flanery) is this person, an albino with extraordinary powers who was left alone in the world after his grandparents death, and now having to deal with the world outside of the basement where he lived, hidden of the eyes of everybody. Target of the prejudice of almost everybody, the only friends he has are the Sheriff (Lance Henriksen), a psychologist (Mary Steenburgen), a teacher (Jeff Goldblum) and a girl (Melissa Lahlitah Crider), intrigued by his mysterious gift. And again, it's a story about seeing the most difficult thing of all: the inside of someone rather than the physical appearance and learn what people have to say, discover their magic and be comprehensible to what this people are. The movie deserves some praise? Yes. In the best possible way the story was well presented but the film's magic comes from some of the situations where the great special effects are a real fun; the great casting never disappoints, all very good. But something tells me again and again that I've seen this story better developed in countless films and somehow the electricity, the vibrations coming from this flick weren't good enough to pass through my heart and make me feel something unexperienced or highly intelligent. It's just good and that's it. It tries to set some emotion but hardly succeeds in such task. Jerry Goldsmith musical score is sweeter than sugar, a little bit excessive at points. And it's a mystery to me that an albino attracted such negative attention from people like in this film, I mean, Southerns never saw one in life? If Jeremy/Powder was painted in blue I would believe in a frightened reaction from the crowd but an albino? It's more common than having Smurfs statues in your garden. It brings some positive light in showing that evolution/technology must be viewed in a lesser degree than the designs of the human spirit, and Powder does represent that but it stops right there. No more lessons to be learned, no more deeper thoughts to share. "Powder" is a nice film, very watchable, good to look at it but don't go with high expectations. The best film directed by Victor Salva so far, if we consider the weak "Jeepers Creepers" series. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disgraceful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    unendurable_lampoonery
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well, at first i enjoyed this movie to an extent, then found out about the director's (Victor Selva) horrible past. a confessed child molester, he compares himself to the main character of this film, this is how he felt in jail, well I'm sorry, an albino has a lot less choice than a dirty pedophile who actually molested a child while making his first movie, the horrible over rated clown house. this movie would actually be good if the director did not write the main character based of himself, a dirty old man. disgraceful director, and a bad person to even compare himself to an amazingly powerful character, this movie is mediocre, at best, it would be better if i had not have read the directors statements on this movie. 3-10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful story, simply...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yoann Larrieu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the story of a very special young man, too pure for this world. Some indications are very interesting: like the day he describes as the worst of his life; the way he communicates with other people, and specifically, the way he candidly reacts to aggression and violence...: and ultimately, what he's really referring to when he says he "wants to go home". Eventually, being so pure and suffocating in this corrupt, blasphemous world; and clearly embodying the moral and purity figures and healing ability of Jesus Christ; he nonetheless longs to experience the tangible world, with all its intact qualities and various wonders - while always being torn away from them at some point by the dread of man's evil and cruelty. A unique character in fiction; resembling some great figures, while never replicating them; a very powerful and "pure" story - and I give this a 9/10 because though the depth is there, and the ideas are beautiful; the "form" of the film and certain scenes remain things that could have been done better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden jewel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick-verdoolaeghe
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't is see this movie before? It is one of those hidden jewels you stumble upon after looking for a good movie and have to dig trough the dirt. So i'm not going to give a big review here. JUST SEE IT. IT IS MORE THEN WORTH IT! GIVE IT AN Oscar OK have to give an bigger review here otherwise it won't stick. So why is this film so unappreciated in movie-land? It has everything a good movie should have. A good original story, well known and good actors, good screen shots, moving music and some minimal special effects. It has so many layers without being predictable and over the top like some of the Hollywood movies. Well people you should give it more points. Let's do it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A powerful and unforgettable story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very rare gem of a movie. In a time when movies have a lot of fx to cover up a weak story, to graphic unnecessary violence and sex. Powder basically shows a pure and unique individual that is not accepted in today's society that has become jaded with discrimination, and overall being afraid of someone who looks different. There are several important elements in the movie. There is the paranormal factor that challenges what we know of science and the the human mind can achieve, the extent of human cruelty, love and forgiveness, and a hope that we may advance beyond technology. The most of all, raw emotion the reaches deep into the heart and leaves a impression that will stay with you. What also makes this movie great is that even though it is not a true story it could be. The idea of being different because of looks or something that makes you stand out from the status quo of the different groups, where we can all relate to. This movie achieves this in a powerful, passionate and inspirational way. This movie makes you sit back and take in everything, showing us what the world may be if we stop judging one another and start to accept our uniqueness. What also is shown in this movie is just that just because someone may be different with looks or how they act that they are some weaker or a part of the undesirables. Who time and again in this movie seem to show us that perception needs to be changed. One scene where we find out he has the highest I.Q. ever recorded.,to a scene where a hunter shoots a deer and powder touches the deer and the hunter and shows him the pain the deer feels before he dies that has a profound effect on the hunter. Another scene where Powder helps the local sheriff understand what his dying wife wants, which is to just reconcile with his son. You have a movie that looks like it could be a Carrie type movie but ends up showing the sad inability to treat Powder with any sense of humanity and dignity. No matter what he stays his pure positive self in some scenes showing the error of our ways and then in the end makes a final act that hopefully makes people want to change for the better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent and thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Look to the skies, especially for lightning bolts which appear repeatedly in Powder. The name is used on a high school aged boy to describe his pasty white skin. Jeremy(Sean Patrick Flanery) is an albino who has a magnet in his brain which causes strange things to happen when he shows up. His mother died shortly after his birth during a severe thunderstorm. His father left him with his grandparents and he did farm work and lived in a basement, reading every book available to him. After grandpa dies, the boy is taken by the state. He is placed in a high school and the physics teacher, Donald Ripley(Jeff Goldblum) tests him and is astounded that his i.q. is off the charts; a teenage Einstein is in school. The other students quickly resent him as an oddity. Jeremy hears a gunshot and when he goes to investigate, sees a doe on the ground, wounded and dying. Powder places his hand on the animal and his other hand on the deputy who shot it and his body sends the emotions of the deer into the officer. His perspective on hunting are forever changed. Word spreads through the town and another cop asks him to use his telepathic ability to communicate with his wife, who is close to death. He helps them with valuable insight. His schoolmates continue to taunt him and before it ends Powder delivers an important message in humanity. Flanery shows great range as the title character; hard to believe that he later played a vigilante lunatic in Boondock Saints. He makes this film work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total lack of empathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tl12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those you do not like or get the movie or those who feel it's stupid have one thing in common. They never grew up with a disability that made them the perpetual outsider. The one who was jeered at, constantly denigrated, beat up by groups (never just one person). In real life there is no Mary Steenburgen to stand up for them. In most cases the adults and authority figures turn a blind eye and in the worse cases join in. I do know. I grew up as a disabled person. I went through all the bigotry, ignorant taunts and carried the weight of the hate those around me felt for me, for some over which I had no control. Those people in my life and the same type here lack a important trait that makes us human, EMPATHY.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powder - One of the BEST.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George D. Dodge
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, Powder is one of the best movies ever made in regards to its message. It deals with the ridiculousness of prejudice, bigotry, false judgements, animal cruelty, love of nature, love of mankind, love of life, and love of your fellow man. This movie is filled with love, IF, and I say IF you can "see" it. It is right in front of you. All you have to do, is really "watch" and "listen" to the movie. The acting is excellent. The music is excellent. The story is excellent and easy to follow. Cinematography is excellent. Directing is excellent also. It is a true winner. I wish more movies like this were being made. The world needs them, especially in this day and age. .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, get over it - it's a great love story!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pandaloonie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not all love stories are guy-girl. This is just a huge human love story. And I LOVED it! Set the popcorn on refill mode and keep a keg of beer and a whole bunch of Kleenex at hand for the ending. First off, if Lance Henriksen reads the back of a toilet paper roll, sign me up and put me in the front row. The man delivers 110% to whatever role he is given. Period. Second, Ms Mary is a home girl, so props to her. Period. The rest of the cast I thought were superb. Again, period. This is a genuine feel-good movie and I highly recommend it. I am not going to give any spoilers for that would - spoil it. But let me say that as an avid movie watcher (older than most of you lot) this one had me hooked first to last. And I did not anticipate the ending though if I could it would have not been better. Go forth and enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle and moving film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Casey Dillard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie holds a very special place in my heart since I was young. Victor Salva, it seems, had at least one good story in him and this, though in some ways sappy, was certainly it. The treatment of the main character makes it hard to watch at times because it can feel very bleak and hopeless, but it is balanced out by the tenderness of the characters who do accept him and offer him hope and kindness. The acting is excellent in this film and the cast is to be commended for not turning the script into something sickly or too predictable. The ending brought me to tears and maybe felt like an easy way out, but it did feel appropriate. All in all, I'd suggest that anyone watch it at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but not powerful enough to be great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, here's another story about a different person in a world that is prejudicial against what's not "normal", who most of the time is very misunderstood except for few people out there who really want to help and also want to understand how magnificent this person is. And this person has supernatural powers, this time involving electricity and an enormous memory capacity, memorizing book quotations from start to finish. Powder (Sean Patrick Flanery) is this person, an albino with extraordinary powers who was left alone in the world after his grandparents death, and now having to deal with the world outside of the basement where he lived, hidden of the eyes of everybody. Target of the prejudice of almost everybody, the only friends he has are the Sheriff (Lance Henriksen), a psychologist (Mary Steenburgen), a teacher (Jeff Goldblum) and a girl (Melissa Lahlitah Crider), intrigued by his mysterious gift. And again, it's a story about seeing the most difficult thing of all: the inside of someone rather than the physical appearance and learn what people have to say, discover their magic and be comprehensible to what this people are. The movie deserves some praise? Yes. In the best possible way the story was well presented but the film's magic comes from some of the situations where the great special effects are a real fun; the great casting never disappoints, all very good. But something tells me again and again that I've seen this story better developed in countless films and somehow the electricity, the vibrations coming from this flick weren't good enough to pass through my heart and make me feel something unexperienced or highly intelligent. It's just good and that's it. It tries to set some emotion but hardly succeeds in such task. Jerry Goldsmith musical score is sweeter than sugar, a little bit excessive at points. And it's a mystery to me that an albino attracted such negative attention from people like in this film, I mean, Southerns never saw one in life? If Jeremy/Powder was painted in blue I would believe in a frightened reaction from the crowd but an albino? It's more common than having Smurfs statues in your garden. It brings some positive light in showing that evolution/technology must be viewed in a lesser degree than the designs of the human spirit, and Powder does represent that but it stops right there. No more lessons to be learned, no more deeper thoughts to share. "Powder" is a nice film, very watchable, good to look at it but don't go with high expectations. The best film directed by Victor Salva so far, if we consider the weak "Jeepers Creepers" series. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disgraceful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    unendurable_lampoonery
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well, at first i enjoyed this movie to an extent, then found out about the director's (Victor Selva) horrible past. a confessed child molester, he compares himself to the main character of this film, this is how he felt in jail, well I'm sorry, an albino has a lot less choice than a dirty pedophile who actually molested a child while making his first movie, the horrible over rated clown house. this movie would actually be good if the director did not write the main character based of himself, a dirty old man. disgraceful director, and a bad person to even compare himself to an amazingly powerful character, this movie is mediocre, at best, it would be better if i had not have read the directors statements on this movie. 3-10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful story, simply...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yoann Larrieu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the story of a very special young man, too pure for this world. Some indications are very interesting: like the day he describes as the worst of his life; the way he communicates with other people, and specifically, the way he candidly reacts to aggression and violence...: and ultimately, what he's really referring to when he says he "wants to go home". Eventually, being so pure and suffocating in this corrupt, blasphemous world; and clearly embodying the moral and purity figures and healing ability of Jesus Christ; he nonetheless longs to experience the tangible world, with all its intact qualities and various wonders - while always being torn away from them at some point by the dread of man's evil and cruelty. A unique character in fiction; resembling some great figures, while never replicating them; a very powerful and "pure" story - and I give this a 9/10 because though the depth is there, and the ideas are beautiful; the "form" of the film and certain scenes remain things that could have been done better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden jewel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick-verdoolaeghe
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't is see this movie before? It is one of those hidden jewels you stumble upon after looking for a good movie and have to dig trough the dirt. So i'm not going to give a big review here. JUST SEE IT. IT IS MORE THEN WORTH IT! GIVE IT AN Oscar OK have to give an bigger review here otherwise it won't stick. So why is this film so unappreciated in movie-land? It has everything a good movie should have. A good original story, well known and good actors, good screen shots, moving music and some minimal special effects. It has so many layers without being predictable and over the top like some of the Hollywood movies. Well people you should give it more points. Let's do it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A powerful and unforgettable story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very rare gem of a movie. In a time when movies have a lot of fx to cover up a weak story, to graphic unnecessary violence and sex. Powder basically shows a pure and unique individual that is not accepted in today's society that has become jaded with discrimination, and overall being afraid of someone who looks different. There are several important elements in the movie. There is the paranormal factor that challenges what we know of science and the the human mind can achieve, the extent of human cruelty, love and forgiveness, and a hope that we may advance beyond technology. The most of all, raw emotion the reaches deep into the heart and leaves a impression that will stay with you. What also makes this movie great is that even though it is not a true story it could be. The idea of being different because of looks or something that makes you stand out from the status quo of the different groups, where we can all relate to. This movie achieves this in a powerful, passionate and inspirational way. This movie makes you sit back and take in everything, showing us what the world may be if we stop judging one another and start to accept our uniqueness. What also is shown in this movie is just that just because someone may be different with looks or how they act that they are some weaker or a part of the undesirables. Who time and again in this movie seem to show us that perception needs to be changed. One scene where we find out he has the highest I.Q. ever recorded.,to a scene where a hunter shoots a deer and powder touches the deer and the hunter and shows him the pain the deer feels before he dies that has a profound effect on the hunter. Another scene where Powder helps the local sheriff understand what his dying wife wants, which is to just reconcile with his son. You have a movie that looks like it could be a Carrie type movie but ends up showing the sad inability to treat Powder with any sense of humanity and dignity. No matter what he stays his pure positive self in some scenes showing the error of our ways and then in the end makes a final act that hopefully makes people want to change for the better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent and thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Look to the skies, especially for lightning bolts which appear repeatedly in Powder. The name is used on a high school aged boy to describe his pasty white skin. Jeremy(Sean Patrick Flanery) is an albino who has a magnet in his brain which causes strange things to happen when he shows up. His mother died shortly after his birth during a severe thunderstorm. His father left him with his grandparents and he did farm work and lived in a basement, reading every book available to him. After grandpa dies, the boy is taken by the state. He is placed in a high school and the physics teacher, Donald Ripley(Jeff Goldblum) tests him and is astounded that his i.q. is off the charts; a teenage Einstein is in school. The other students quickly resent him as an oddity. Jeremy hears a gunshot and when he goes to investigate, sees a doe on the ground, wounded and dying. Powder places his hand on the animal and his other hand on the deputy who shot it and his body sends the emotions of the deer into the officer. His perspective on hunting are forever changed. Word spreads through the town and another cop asks him to use his telepathic ability to communicate with his wife, who is close to death. He helps them with valuable insight. His schoolmates continue to taunt him and before it ends Powder delivers an important message in humanity. Flanery shows great range as the title character; hard to believe that he later played a vigilante lunatic in Boondock Saints. He makes this film work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total lack of empathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tl12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those you do not like or get the movie or those who feel it's stupid have one thing in common. They never grew up with a disability that made them the perpetual outsider. The one who was jeered at, constantly denigrated, beat up by groups (never just one person). In real life there is no Mary Steenburgen to stand up for them. In most cases the adults and authority figures turn a blind eye and in the worse cases join in. I do know. I grew up as a disabled person. I went through all the bigotry, ignorant taunts and carried the weight of the hate those around me felt for me, for some over which I had no control. Those people in my life and the same type here lack a important trait that makes us human, EMPATHY.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powder - One of the BEST.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George D. Dodge
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, Powder is one of the best movies ever made in regards to its message. It deals with the ridiculousness of prejudice, bigotry, false judgements, animal cruelty, love of nature, love of mankind, love of life, and love of your fellow man. This movie is filled with love, IF, and I say IF you can "see" it. It is right in front of you. All you have to do, is really "watch" and "listen" to the movie. The acting is excellent. The music is excellent. The story is excellent and easy to follow. Cinematography is excellent. Directing is excellent also. It is a true winner. I wish more movies like this were being made. The world needs them, especially in this day and age. .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, get over it - it's a great love story!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pandaloonie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not all love stories are guy-girl. This is just a huge human love story. And I LOVED it! Set the popcorn on refill mode and keep a keg of beer and a whole bunch of Kleenex at hand for the ending. First off, if Lance Henriksen reads the back of a toilet paper roll, sign me up and put me in the front row. The man delivers 110% to whatever role he is given. Period. Second, Ms Mary is a home girl, so props to her. Period. The rest of the cast I thought were superb. Again, period. This is a genuine feel-good movie and I highly recommend it. I am not going to give any spoilers for that would - spoil it. But let me say that as an avid movie watcher (older than most of you lot) this one had me hooked first to last. And I did not anticipate the ending though if I could it would have not been better. Go forth and enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle and moving film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Casey Dillard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie holds a very special place in my heart since I was young. Victor Salva, it seems, had at least one good story in him and this, though in some ways sappy, was certainly it. The treatment of the main character makes it hard to watch at times because it can feel very bleak and hopeless, but it is balanced out by the tenderness of the characters who do accept him and offer him hope and kindness. The acting is excellent in this film and the cast is to be commended for not turning the script into something sickly or too predictable. The ending brought me to tears and maybe felt like an easy way out, but it did feel appropriate. All in all, I'd suggest that anyone watch it at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but not powerful enough to be great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, here's another story about a different person in a world that is prejudicial against what's not "normal", who most of the time is very misunderstood except for few people out there who really want to help and also want to understand how magnificent this person is. And this person has supernatural powers, this time involving electricity and an enormous memory capacity, memorizing book quotations from start to finish. Powder (Sean Patrick Flanery) is this person, an albino with extraordinary powers who was left alone in the world after his grandparents death, and now having to deal with the world outside of the basement where he lived, hidden of the eyes of everybody. Target of the prejudice of almost everybody, the only friends he has are the Sheriff (Lance Henriksen), a psychologist (Mary Steenburgen), a teacher (Jeff Goldblum) and a girl (Melissa Lahlitah Crider), intrigued by his mysterious gift. And again, it's a story about seeing the most difficult thing of all: the inside of someone rather than the physical appearance and learn what people have to say, discover their magic and be comprehensible to what this people are. The movie deserves some praise? Yes. In the best possible way the story was well presented but the film's magic comes from some of the situations where the great special effects are a real fun; the great casting never disappoints, all very good. But something tells me again and again that I've seen this story better developed in countless films and somehow the electricity, the vibrations coming from this flick weren't good enough to pass through my heart and make me feel something unexperienced or highly intelligent. It's just good and that's it. It tries to set some emotion but hardly succeeds in such task. Jerry Goldsmith musical score is sweeter than sugar, a little bit excessive at points. And it's a mystery to me that an albino attracted such negative attention from people like in this film, I mean, Southerns never saw one in life? If Jeremy/Powder was painted in blue I would believe in a frightened reaction from the crowd but an albino? It's more common than having Smurfs statues in your garden. It brings some positive light in showing that evolution/technology must be viewed in a lesser degree than the designs of the human spirit, and Powder does represent that but it stops right there. No more lessons to be learned, no more deeper thoughts to share. "Powder" is a nice film, very watchable, good to look at it but don't go with high expectations. The best film directed by Victor Salva so far, if we consider the weak "Jeepers Creepers" series. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disgraceful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    unendurable_lampoonery
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well, at first i enjoyed this movie to an extent, then found out about the director's (Victor Selva) horrible past. a confessed child molester, he compares himself to the main character of this film, this is how he felt in jail, well I'm sorry, an albino has a lot less choice than a dirty pedophile who actually molested a child while making his first movie, the horrible over rated clown house. this movie would actually be good if the director did not write the main character based of himself, a dirty old man. disgraceful director, and a bad person to even compare himself to an amazingly powerful character, this movie is mediocre, at best, it would be better if i had not have read the directors statements on this movie. 3-10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful story, simply...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yoann Larrieu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the story of a very special young man, too pure for this world. Some indications are very interesting: like the day he describes as the worst of his life; the way he communicates with other people, and specifically, the way he candidly reacts to aggression and violence...: and ultimately, what he's really referring to when he says he "wants to go home". Eventually, being so pure and suffocating in this corrupt, blasphemous world; and clearly embodying the moral and purity figures and healing ability of Jesus Christ; he nonetheless longs to experience the tangible world, with all its intact qualities and various wonders - while always being torn away from them at some point by the dread of man's evil and cruelty. A unique character in fiction; resembling some great figures, while never replicating them; a very powerful and "pure" story - and I give this a 9/10 because though the depth is there, and the ideas are beautiful; the "form" of the film and certain scenes remain things that could have been done better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden jewel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick-verdoolaeghe
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't is see this movie before? It is one of those hidden jewels you stumble upon after looking for a good movie and have to dig trough the dirt. So i'm not going to give a big review here. JUST SEE IT. IT IS MORE THEN WORTH IT! GIVE IT AN Oscar OK have to give an bigger review here otherwise it won't stick. So why is this film so unappreciated in movie-land? It has everything a good movie should have. A good original story, well known and good actors, good screen shots, moving music and some minimal special effects. It has so many layers without being predictable and over the top like some of the Hollywood movies. Well people you should give it more points. Let's do it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A powerful and unforgettable story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very rare gem of a movie. In a time when movies have a lot of fx to cover up a weak story, to graphic unnecessary violence and sex. Powder basically shows a pure and unique individual that is not accepted in today's society that has become jaded with discrimination, and overall being afraid of someone who looks different. There are several important elements in the movie. There is the paranormal factor that challenges what we know of science and the the human mind can achieve, the extent of human cruelty, love and forgiveness, and a hope that we may advance beyond technology. The most of all, raw emotion the reaches deep into the heart and leaves a impression that will stay with you. What also makes this movie great is that even though it is not a true story it could be. The idea of being different because of looks or something that makes you stand out from the status quo of the different groups, where we can all relate to. This movie achieves this in a powerful, passionate and inspirational way. This movie makes you sit back and take in everything, showing us what the world may be if we stop judging one another and start to accept our uniqueness. What also is shown in this movie is just that just because someone may be different with looks or how they act that they are some weaker or a part of the undesirables. Who time and again in this movie seem to show us that perception needs to be changed. One scene where we find out he has the highest I.Q. ever recorded.,to a scene where a hunter shoots a deer and powder touches the deer and the hunter and shows him the pain the deer feels before he dies that has a profound effect on the hunter. Another scene where Powder helps the local sheriff understand what his dying wife wants, which is to just reconcile with his son. You have a movie that looks like it could be a Carrie type movie but ends up showing the sad inability to treat Powder with any sense of humanity and dignity. No matter what he stays his pure positive self in some scenes showing the error of our ways and then in the end makes a final act that hopefully makes people want to change for the better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent and thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Look to the skies, especially for lightning bolts which appear repeatedly in Powder. The name is used on a high school aged boy to describe his pasty white skin. Jeremy(Sean Patrick Flanery) is an albino who has a magnet in his brain which causes strange things to happen when he shows up. His mother died shortly after his birth during a severe thunderstorm. His father left him with his grandparents and he did farm work and lived in a basement, reading every book available to him. After grandpa dies, the boy is taken by the state. He is placed in a high school and the physics teacher, Donald Ripley(Jeff Goldblum) tests him and is astounded that his i.q. is off the charts; a teenage Einstein is in school. The other students quickly resent him as an oddity. Jeremy hears a gunshot and when he goes to investigate, sees a doe on the ground, wounded and dying. Powder places his hand on the animal and his other hand on the deputy who shot it and his body sends the emotions of the deer into the officer. His perspective on hunting are forever changed. Word spreads through the town and another cop asks him to use his telepathic ability to communicate with his wife, who is close to death. He helps them with valuable insight. His schoolmates continue to taunt him and before it ends Powder delivers an important message in humanity. Flanery shows great range as the title character; hard to believe that he later played a vigilante lunatic in Boondock Saints. He makes this film work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total lack of empathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tl12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those you do not like or get the movie or those who feel it's stupid have one thing in common. They never grew up with a disability that made them the perpetual outsider. The one who was jeered at, constantly denigrated, beat up by groups (never just one person). In real life there is no Mary Steenburgen to stand up for them. In most cases the adults and authority figures turn a blind eye and in the worse cases join in. I do know. I grew up as a disabled person. I went through all the bigotry, ignorant taunts and carried the weight of the hate those around me felt for me, for some over which I had no control. Those people in my life and the same type here lack a important trait that makes us human, EMPATHY.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powder - One of the BEST.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George D. Dodge
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, Powder is one of the best movies ever made in regards to its message. It deals with the ridiculousness of prejudice, bigotry, false judgements, animal cruelty, love of nature, love of mankind, love of life, and love of your fellow man. This movie is filled with love, IF, and I say IF you can "see" it. It is right in front of you. All you have to do, is really "watch" and "listen" to the movie. The acting is excellent. The music is excellent. The story is excellent and easy to follow. Cinematography is excellent. Directing is excellent also. It is a true winner. I wish more movies like this were being made. The world needs them, especially in this day and age. .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, get over it - it's a great love story!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pandaloonie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not all love stories are guy-girl. This is just a huge human love story. And I LOVED it! Set the popcorn on refill mode and keep a keg of beer and a whole bunch of Kleenex at hand for the ending. First off, if Lance Henriksen reads the back of a toilet paper roll, sign me up and put me in the front row. The man delivers 110% to whatever role he is given. Period. Second, Ms Mary is a home girl, so props to her. Period. The rest of the cast I thought were superb. Again, period. This is a genuine feel-good movie and I highly recommend it. I am not going to give any spoilers for that would - spoil it. But let me say that as an avid movie watcher (older than most of you lot) this one had me hooked first to last. And I did not anticipate the ending though if I could it would have not been better. Go forth and enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle and moving film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Casey Dillard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie holds a very special place in my heart since I was young. Victor Salva, it seems, had at least one good story in him and this, though in some ways sappy, was certainly it. The treatment of the main character makes it hard to watch at times because it can feel very bleak and hopeless, but it is balanced out by the tenderness of the characters who do accept him and offer him hope and kindness. The acting is excellent in this film and the cast is to be commended for not turning the script into something sickly or too predictable. The ending brought me to tears and maybe felt like an easy way out, but it did feel appropriate. All in all, I'd suggest that anyone watch it at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but not powerful enough to be great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, here's another story about a different person in a world that is prejudicial against what's not "normal", who most of the time is very misunderstood except for few people out there who really want to help and also want to understand how magnificent this person is. And this person has supernatural powers, this time involving electricity and an enormous memory capacity, memorizing book quotations from start to finish. Powder (Sean Patrick Flanery) is this person, an albino with extraordinary powers who was left alone in the world after his grandparents death, and now having to deal with the world outside of the basement where he lived, hidden of the eyes of everybody. Target of the prejudice of almost everybody, the only friends he has are the Sheriff (Lance Henriksen), a psychologist (Mary Steenburgen), a teacher (Jeff Goldblum) and a girl (Melissa Lahlitah Crider), intrigued by his mysterious gift. And again, it's a story about seeing the most difficult thing of all: the inside of someone rather than the physical appearance and learn what people have to say, discover their magic and be comprehensible to what this people are. The movie deserves some praise? Yes. In the best possible way the story was well presented but the film's magic comes from some of the situations where the great special effects are a real fun; the great casting never disappoints, all very good. But something tells me again and again that I've seen this story better developed in countless films and somehow the electricity, the vibrations coming from this flick weren't good enough to pass through my heart and make me feel something unexperienced or highly intelligent. It's just good and that's it. It tries to set some emotion but hardly succeeds in such task. Jerry Goldsmith musical score is sweeter than sugar, a little bit excessive at points. And it's a mystery to me that an albino attracted such negative attention from people like in this film, I mean, Southerns never saw one in life? If Jeremy/Powder was painted in blue I would believe in a frightened reaction from the crowd but an albino? It's more common than having Smurfs statues in your garden. It brings some positive light in showing that evolution/technology must be viewed in a lesser degree than the designs of the human spirit, and Powder does represent that but it stops right there. No more lessons to be learned, no more deeper thoughts to share. "Powder" is a nice film, very watchable, good to look at it but don't go with high expectations. The best film directed by Victor Salva so far, if we consider the weak "Jeepers Creepers" series. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disgraceful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    unendurable_lampoonery
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well, at first i enjoyed this movie to an extent, then found out about the director's (Victor Selva) horrible past. a confessed child molester, he compares himself to the main character of this film, this is how he felt in jail, well I'm sorry, an albino has a lot less choice than a dirty pedophile who actually molested a child while making his first movie, the horrible over rated clown house. this movie would actually be good if the director did not write the main character based of himself, a dirty old man. disgraceful director, and a bad person to even compare himself to an amazingly powerful character, this movie is mediocre, at best, it would be better if i had not have read the directors statements on this movie. 3-10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful story, simply...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yoann Larrieu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the story of a very special young man, too pure for this world. Some indications are very interesting: like the day he describes as the worst of his life; the way he communicates with other people, and specifically, the way he candidly reacts to aggression and violence...: and ultimately, what he's really referring to when he says he "wants to go home". Eventually, being so pure and suffocating in this corrupt, blasphemous world; and clearly embodying the moral and purity figures and healing ability of Jesus Christ; he nonetheless longs to experience the tangible world, with all its intact qualities and various wonders - while always being torn away from them at some point by the dread of man's evil and cruelty. A unique character in fiction; resembling some great figures, while never replicating them; a very powerful and "pure" story - and I give this a 9/10 because though the depth is there, and the ideas are beautiful; the "form" of the film and certain scenes remain things that could have been done better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden jewel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick-verdoolaeghe
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't is see this movie before? It is one of those hidden jewels you stumble upon after looking for a good movie and have to dig trough the dirt. So i'm not going to give a big review here. JUST SEE IT. IT IS MORE THEN WORTH IT! GIVE IT AN Oscar OK have to give an bigger review here otherwise it won't stick. So why is this film so unappreciated in movie-land? It has everything a good movie should have. A good original story, well known and good actors, good screen shots, moving music and some minimal special effects. It has so many layers without being predictable and over the top like some of the Hollywood movies. Well people you should give it more points. Let's do it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A powerful and unforgettable story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very rare gem of a movie. In a time when movies have a lot of fx to cover up a weak story, to graphic unnecessary violence and sex. Powder basically shows a pure and unique individual that is not accepted in today's society that has become jaded with discrimination, and overall being afraid of someone who looks different. There are several important elements in the movie. There is the paranormal factor that challenges what we know of science and the the human mind can achieve, the extent of human cruelty, love and forgiveness, and a hope that we may advance beyond technology. The most of all, raw emotion the reaches deep into the heart and leaves a impression that will stay with you. What also makes this movie great is that even though it is not a true story it could be. The idea of being different because of looks or something that makes you stand out from the status quo of the different groups, where we can all relate to. This movie achieves this in a powerful, passionate and inspirational way. This movie makes you sit back and take in everything, showing us what the world may be if we stop judging one another and start to accept our uniqueness. What also is shown in this movie is just that just because someone may be different with looks or how they act that they are some weaker or a part of the undesirables. Who time and again in this movie seem to show us that perception needs to be changed. One scene where we find out he has the highest I.Q. ever recorded.,to a scene where a hunter shoots a deer and powder touches the deer and the hunter and shows him the pain the deer feels before he dies that has a profound effect on the hunter. Another scene where Powder helps the local sheriff understand what his dying wife wants, which is to just reconcile with his son. You have a movie that looks like it could be a Carrie type movie but ends up showing the sad inability to treat Powder with any sense of humanity and dignity. No matter what he stays his pure positive self in some scenes showing the error of our ways and then in the end makes a final act that hopefully makes people want to change for the better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent and thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Look to the skies, especially for lightning bolts which appear repeatedly in Powder. The name is used on a high school aged boy to describe his pasty white skin. Jeremy(Sean Patrick Flanery) is an albino who has a magnet in his brain which causes strange things to happen when he shows up. His mother died shortly after his birth during a severe thunderstorm. His father left him with his grandparents and he did farm work and lived in a basement, reading every book available to him. After grandpa dies, the boy is taken by the state. He is placed in a high school and the physics teacher, Donald Ripley(Jeff Goldblum) tests him and is astounded that his i.q. is off the charts; a teenage Einstein is in school. The other students quickly resent him as an oddity. Jeremy hears a gunshot and when he goes to investigate, sees a doe on the ground, wounded and dying. Powder places his hand on the animal and his other hand on the deputy who shot it and his body sends the emotions of the deer into the officer. His perspective on hunting are forever changed. Word spreads through the town and another cop asks him to use his telepathic ability to communicate with his wife, who is close to death. He helps them with valuable insight. His schoolmates continue to taunt him and before it ends Powder delivers an important message in humanity. Flanery shows great range as the title character; hard to believe that he later played a vigilante lunatic in Boondock Saints. He makes this film work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total lack of empathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tl12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those you do not like or get the movie or those who feel it's stupid have one thing in common. They never grew up with a disability that made them the perpetual outsider. The one who was jeered at, constantly denigrated, beat up by groups (never just one person). In real life there is no Mary Steenburgen to stand up for them. In most cases the adults and authority figures turn a blind eye and in the worse cases join in. I do know. I grew up as a disabled person. I went through all the bigotry, ignorant taunts and carried the weight of the hate those around me felt for me, for some over which I had no control. Those people in my life and the same type here lack a important trait that makes us human, EMPATHY.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powder - One of the BEST.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George D. Dodge
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, Powder is one of the best movies ever made in regards to its message. It deals with the ridiculousness of prejudice, bigotry, false judgements, animal cruelty, love of nature, love of mankind, love of life, and love of your fellow man. This movie is filled with love, IF, and I say IF you can "see" it. It is right in front of you. All you have to do, is really "watch" and "listen" to the movie. The acting is excellent. The music is excellent. The story is excellent and easy to follow. Cinematography is excellent. Directing is excellent also. It is a true winner. I wish more movies like this were being made. The world needs them, especially in this day and age. .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, get over it - it's a great love story!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pandaloonie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not all love stories are guy-girl. This is just a huge human love story. And I LOVED it! Set the popcorn on refill mode and keep a keg of beer and a whole bunch of Kleenex at hand for the ending. First off, if Lance Henriksen reads the back of a toilet paper roll, sign me up and put me in the front row. The man delivers 110% to whatever role he is given. Period. Second, Ms Mary is a home girl, so props to her. Period. The rest of the cast I thought were superb. Again, period. This is a genuine feel-good movie and I highly recommend it. I am not going to give any spoilers for that would - spoil it. But let me say that as an avid movie watcher (older than most of you lot) this one had me hooked first to last. And I did not anticipate the ending though if I could it would have not been better. Go forth and enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle and moving film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Casey Dillard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie holds a very special place in my heart since I was young. Victor Salva, it seems, had at least one good story in him and this, though in some ways sappy, was certainly it. The treatment of the main character makes it hard to watch at times because it can feel very bleak and hopeless, but it is balanced out by the tenderness of the characters who do accept him and offer him hope and kindness. The acting is excellent in this film and the cast is to be commended for not turning the script into something sickly or too predictable. The ending brought me to tears and maybe felt like an easy way out, but it did feel appropriate. All in all, I'd suggest that anyone watch it at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but not powerful enough to be great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, here's another story about a different person in a world that is prejudicial against what's not "normal", who most of the time is very misunderstood except for few people out there who really want to help and also want to understand how magnificent this person is. And this person has supernatural powers, this time involving electricity and an enormous memory capacity, memorizing book quotations from start to finish. Powder (Sean Patrick Flanery) is this person, an albino with extraordinary powers who was left alone in the world after his grandparents death, and now having to deal with the world outside of the basement where he lived, hidden of the eyes of everybody. Target of the prejudice of almost everybody, the only friends he has are the Sheriff (Lance Henriksen), a psychologist (Mary Steenburgen), a teacher (Jeff Goldblum) and a girl (Melissa Lahlitah Crider), intrigued by his mysterious gift. And again, it's a story about seeing the most difficult thing of all: the inside of someone rather than the physical appearance and learn what people have to say, discover their magic and be comprehensible to what this people are. The movie deserves some praise? Yes. In the best possible way the story was well presented but the film's magic comes from some of the situations where the great special effects are a real fun; the great casting never disappoints, all very good. But something tells me again and again that I've seen this story better developed in countless films and somehow the electricity, the vibrations coming from this flick weren't good enough to pass through my heart and make me feel something unexperienced or highly intelligent. It's just good and that's it. It tries to set some emotion but hardly succeeds in such task. Jerry Goldsmith musical score is sweeter than sugar, a little bit excessive at points. And it's a mystery to me that an albino attracted such negative attention from people like in this film, I mean, Southerns never saw one in life? If Jeremy/Powder was painted in blue I would believe in a frightened reaction from the crowd but an albino? It's more common than having Smurfs statues in your garden. It brings some positive light in showing that evolution/technology must be viewed in a lesser degree than the designs of the human spirit, and Powder does represent that but it stops right there. No more lessons to be learned, no more deeper thoughts to share. "Powder" is a nice film, very watchable, good to look at it but don't go with high expectations. The best film directed by Victor Salva so far, if we consider the weak "Jeepers Creepers" series. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disgraceful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    unendurable_lampoonery
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well, at first i enjoyed this movie to an extent, then found out about the director's (Victor Selva) horrible past. a confessed child molester, he compares himself to the main character of this film, this is how he felt in jail, well I'm sorry, an albino has a lot less choice than a dirty pedophile who actually molested a child while making his first movie, the horrible over rated clown house. this movie would actually be good if the director did not write the main character based of himself, a dirty old man. disgraceful director, and a bad person to even compare himself to an amazingly powerful character, this movie is mediocre, at best, it would be better if i had not have read the directors statements on this movie. 3-10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful story, simply...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yoann Larrieu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the story of a very special young man, too pure for this world. Some indications are very interesting: like the day he describes as the worst of his life; the way he communicates with other people, and specifically, the way he candidly reacts to aggression and violence...: and ultimately, what he's really referring to when he says he "wants to go home". Eventually, being so pure and suffocating in this corrupt, blasphemous world; and clearly embodying the moral and purity figures and healing ability of Jesus Christ; he nonetheless longs to experience the tangible world, with all its intact qualities and various wonders - while always being torn away from them at some point by the dread of man's evil and cruelty. A unique character in fiction; resembling some great figures, while never replicating them; a very powerful and "pure" story - and I give this a 9/10 because though the depth is there, and the ideas are beautiful; the "form" of the film and certain scenes remain things that could have been done better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden jewel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick-verdoolaeghe
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't is see this movie before? It is one of those hidden jewels you stumble upon after looking for a good movie and have to dig trough the dirt. So i'm not going to give a big review here. JUST SEE IT. IT IS MORE THEN WORTH IT! GIVE IT AN Oscar OK have to give an bigger review here otherwise it won't stick. So why is this film so unappreciated in movie-land? It has everything a good movie should have. A good original story, well known and good actors, good screen shots, moving music and some minimal special effects. It has so many layers without being predictable and over the top like some of the Hollywood movies. Well people you should give it more points. Let's do it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A powerful and unforgettable story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very rare gem of a movie. In a time when movies have a lot of fx to cover up a weak story, to graphic unnecessary violence and sex. Powder basically shows a pure and unique individual that is not accepted in today's society that has become jaded with discrimination, and overall being afraid of someone who looks different. There are several important elements in the movie. There is the paranormal factor that challenges what we know of science and the the human mind can achieve, the extent of human cruelty, love and forgiveness, and a hope that we may advance beyond technology. The most of all, raw emotion the reaches deep into the heart and leaves a impression that will stay with you. What also makes this movie great is that even though it is not a true story it could be. The idea of being different because of looks or something that makes you stand out from the status quo of the different groups, where we can all relate to. This movie achieves this in a powerful, passionate and inspirational way. This movie makes you sit back and take in everything, showing us what the world may be if we stop judging one another and start to accept our uniqueness. What also is shown in this movie is just that just because someone may be different with looks or how they act that they are some weaker or a part of the undesirables. Who time and again in this movie seem to show us that perception needs to be changed. One scene where we find out he has the highest I.Q. ever recorded.,to a scene where a hunter shoots a deer and powder touches the deer and the hunter and shows him the pain the deer feels before he dies that has a profound effect on the hunter. Another scene where Powder helps the local sheriff understand what his dying wife wants, which is to just reconcile with his son. You have a movie that looks like it could be a Carrie type movie but ends up showing the sad inability to treat Powder with any sense of humanity and dignity. No matter what he stays his pure positive self in some scenes showing the error of our ways and then in the end makes a final act that hopefully makes people want to change for the better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent and thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Look to the skies, especially for lightning bolts which appear repeatedly in Powder. The name is used on a high school aged boy to describe his pasty white skin. Jeremy(Sean Patrick Flanery) is an albino who has a magnet in his brain which causes strange things to happen when he shows up. His mother died shortly after his birth during a severe thunderstorm. His father left him with his grandparents and he did farm work and lived in a basement, reading every book available to him. After grandpa dies, the boy is taken by the state. He is placed in a high school and the physics teacher, Donald Ripley(Jeff Goldblum) tests him and is astounded that his i.q. is off the charts; a teenage Einstein is in school. The other students quickly resent him as an oddity. Jeremy hears a gunshot and when he goes to investigate, sees a doe on the ground, wounded and dying. Powder places his hand on the animal and his other hand on the deputy who shot it and his body sends the emotions of the deer into the officer. His perspective on hunting are forever changed. Word spreads through the town and another cop asks him to use his telepathic ability to communicate with his wife, who is close to death. He helps them with valuable insight. His schoolmates continue to taunt him and before it ends Powder delivers an important message in humanity. Flanery shows great range as the title character; hard to believe that he later played a vigilante lunatic in Boondock Saints. He makes this film work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total lack of empathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tl12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those you do not like or get the movie or those who feel it's stupid have one thing in common. They never grew up with a disability that made them the perpetual outsider. The one who was jeered at, constantly denigrated, beat up by groups (never just one person). In real life there is no Mary Steenburgen to stand up for them. In most cases the adults and authority figures turn a blind eye and in the worse cases join in. I do know. I grew up as a disabled person. I went through all the bigotry, ignorant taunts and carried the weight of the hate those around me felt for me, for some over which I had no control. Those people in my life and the same type here lack a important trait that makes us human, EMPATHY.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powder - One of the BEST.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George D. Dodge
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, Powder is one of the best movies ever made in regards to its message. It deals with the ridiculousness of prejudice, bigotry, false judgements, animal cruelty, love of nature, love of mankind, love of life, and love of your fellow man. This movie is filled with love, IF, and I say IF you can "see" it. It is right in front of you. All you have to do, is really "watch" and "listen" to the movie. The acting is excellent. The music is excellent. The story is excellent and easy to follow. Cinematography is excellent. Directing is excellent also. It is a true winner. I wish more movies like this were being made. The world needs them, especially in this day and age. .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, get over it - it's a great love story!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pandaloonie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not all love stories are guy-girl. This is just a huge human love story. And I LOVED it! Set the popcorn on refill mode and keep a keg of beer and a whole bunch of Kleenex at hand for the ending. First off, if Lance Henriksen reads the back of a toilet paper roll, sign me up and put me in the front row. The man delivers 110% to whatever role he is given. Period. Second, Ms Mary is a home girl, so props to her. Period. The rest of the cast I thought were superb. Again, period. This is a genuine feel-good movie and I highly recommend it. I am not going to give any spoilers for that would - spoil it. But let me say that as an avid movie watcher (older than most of you lot) this one had me hooked first to last. And I did not anticipate the ending though if I could it would have not been better. Go forth and enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle and moving film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Casey Dillard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie holds a very special place in my heart since I was young. Victor Salva, it seems, had at least one good story in him and this, though in some ways sappy, was certainly it. The treatment of the main character makes it hard to watch at times because it can feel very bleak and hopeless, but it is balanced out by the tenderness of the characters who do accept him and offer him hope and kindness. The acting is excellent in this film and the cast is to be commended for not turning the script into something sickly or too predictable. The ending brought me to tears and maybe felt like an easy way out, but it did feel appropriate. All in all, I'd suggest that anyone watch it at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but not powerful enough to be great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, here's another story about a different person in a world that is prejudicial against what's not "normal", who most of the time is very misunderstood except for few people out there who really want to help and also want to understand how magnificent this person is. And this person has supernatural powers, this time involving electricity and an enormous memory capacity, memorizing book quotations from start to finish. Powder (Sean Patrick Flanery) is this person, an albino with extraordinary powers who was left alone in the world after his grandparents death, and now having to deal with the world outside of the basement where he lived, hidden of the eyes of everybody. Target of the prejudice of almost everybody, the only friends he has are the Sheriff (Lance Henriksen), a psychologist (Mary Steenburgen), a teacher (Jeff Goldblum) and a girl (Melissa Lahlitah Crider), intrigued by his mysterious gift. And again, it's a story about seeing the most difficult thing of all: the inside of someone rather than the physical appearance and learn what people have to say, discover their magic and be comprehensible to what this people are. The movie deserves some praise? Yes. In the best possible way the story was well presented but the film's magic comes from some of the situations where the great special effects are a real fun; the great casting never disappoints, all very good. But something tells me again and again that I've seen this story better developed in countless films and somehow the electricity, the vibrations coming from this flick weren't good enough to pass through my heart and make me feel something unexperienced or highly intelligent. It's just good and that's it. It tries to set some emotion but hardly succeeds in such task. Jerry Goldsmith musical score is sweeter than sugar, a little bit excessive at points. And it's a mystery to me that an albino attracted such negative attention from people like in this film, I mean, Southerns never saw one in life? If Jeremy/Powder was painted in blue I would believe in a frightened reaction from the crowd but an albino? It's more common than having Smurfs statues in your garden. It brings some positive light in showing that evolution/technology must be viewed in a lesser degree than the designs of the human spirit, and Powder does represent that but it stops right there. No more lessons to be learned, no more deeper thoughts to share. "Powder" is a nice film, very watchable, good to look at it but don't go with high expectations. The best film directed by Victor Salva so far, if we consider the weak "Jeepers Creepers" series. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disgraceful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    unendurable_lampoonery
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well, at first i enjoyed this movie to an extent, then found out about the director's (Victor Selva) horrible past. a confessed child molester, he compares himself to the main character of this film, this is how he felt in jail, well I'm sorry, an albino has a lot less choice than a dirty pedophile who actually molested a child while making his first movie, the horrible over rated clown house. this movie would actually be good if the director did not write the main character based of himself, a dirty old man. disgraceful director, and a bad person to even compare himself to an amazingly powerful character, this movie is mediocre, at best, it would be better if i had not have read the directors statements on this movie. 3-10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful story, simply...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yoann Larrieu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the story of a very special young man, too pure for this world. Some indications are very interesting: like the day he describes as the worst of his life; the way he communicates with other people, and specifically, the way he candidly reacts to aggression and violence...: and ultimately, what he's really referring to when he says he "wants to go home". Eventually, being so pure and suffocating in this corrupt, blasphemous world; and clearly embodying the moral and purity figures and healing ability of Jesus Christ; he nonetheless longs to experience the tangible world, with all its intact qualities and various wonders - while always being torn away from them at some point by the dread of man's evil and cruelty. A unique character in fiction; resembling some great figures, while never replicating them; a very powerful and "pure" story - and I give this a 9/10 because though the depth is there, and the ideas are beautiful; the "form" of the film and certain scenes remain things that could have been done better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a hidden jewel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick-verdoolaeghe
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't is see this movie before? It is one of those hidden jewels you stumble upon after looking for a good movie and have to dig trough the dirt. So i'm not going to give a big review here. JUST SEE IT. IT IS MORE THEN WORTH IT! GIVE IT AN Oscar OK have to give an bigger review here otherwise it won't stick. So why is this film so unappreciated in movie-land? It has everything a good movie should have. A good original story, well known and good actors, good screen shots, moving music and some minimal special effects. It has so many layers without being predictable and over the top like some of the Hollywood movies. Well people you should give it more points. Let's do it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A powerful and unforgettable story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very rare gem of a movie. In a time when movies have a lot of fx to cover up a weak story, to graphic unnecessary violence and sex. Powder basically shows a pure and unique individual that is not accepted in today's society that has become jaded with discrimination, and overall being afraid of someone who looks different. There are several important elements in the movie. There is the paranormal factor that challenges what we know of science and the the human mind can achieve, the extent of human cruelty, love and forgiveness, and a hope that we may advance beyond technology. The most of all, raw emotion the reaches deep into the heart and leaves a impression that will stay with you. What also makes this movie great is that even though it is not a true story it could be. The idea of being different because of looks or something that makes you stand out from the status quo of the different groups, where we can all relate to. This movie achieves this in a powerful, passionate and inspirational way. This movie makes you sit back and take in everything, showing us what the world may be if we stop judging one another and start to accept our uniqueness. What also is shown in this movie is just that just because someone may be different with looks or how they act that they are some weaker or a part of the undesirables. Who time and again in this movie seem to show us that perception needs to be changed. One scene where we find out he has the highest I.Q. ever recorded.,to a scene where a hunter shoots a deer and powder touches the deer and the hunter and shows him the pain the deer feels before he dies that has a profound effect on the hunter. Another scene where Powder helps the local sheriff understand what his dying wife wants, which is to just reconcile with his son. You have a movie that looks like it could be a Carrie type movie but ends up showing the sad inability to treat Powder with any sense of humanity and dignity. No matter what he stays his pure positive self in some scenes showing the error of our ways and then in the end makes a final act that hopefully makes people want to change for the better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent and thought provoking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Look to the skies, especially for lightning bolts which appear repeatedly in Powder. The name is used on a high school aged boy to describe his pasty white skin. Jeremy(Sean Patrick Flanery) is an albino who has a magnet in his brain which causes strange things to happen when he shows up. His mother died shortly after his birth during a severe thunderstorm. His father left him with his grandparents and he did farm work and lived in a basement, reading every book available to him. After grandpa dies, the boy is taken by the state. He is placed in a high school and the physics teacher, Donald Ripley(Jeff Goldblum) tests him and is astounded that his i.q. is off the charts; a teenage Einstein is in school. The other students quickly resent him as an oddity. Jeremy hears a gunshot and when he goes to investigate, sees a doe on the ground, wounded and dying. Powder places his hand on the animal and his other hand on the deputy who shot it and his body sends the emotions of the deer into the officer. His perspective on hunting are forever changed. Word spreads through the town and another cop asks him to use his telepathic ability to communicate with his wife, who is close to death. He helps them with valuable insight. His schoolmates continue to taunt him and before it ends Powder delivers an important message in humanity. Flanery shows great range as the title character; hard to believe that he later played a vigilante lunatic in Boondock Saints. He makes this film work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Total lack of empathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tl12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those you do not like or get the movie or those who feel it's stupid have one thing in common. They never grew up with a disability that made them the perpetual outsider. The one who was jeered at, constantly denigrated, beat up by groups (never just one person). In real life there is no Mary Steenburgen to stand up for them. In most cases the adults and authority figures turn a blind eye and in the worse cases join in. I do know. I grew up as a disabled person. I went through all the bigotry, ignorant taunts and carried the weight of the hate those around me felt for me, for some over which I had no control. Those people in my life and the same type here lack a important trait that makes us human, EMPATHY.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powder - One of the BEST.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George D. Dodge
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion, Powder is one of the best movies ever made in regards to its message. It deals with the ridiculousness of prejudice, bigotry, false judgements, animal cruelty, love of nature, love of mankind, love of life, and love of your fellow man. This movie is filled with love, IF, and I say IF you can "see" it. It is right in front of you. All you have to do, is really "watch" and "listen" to the movie. The acting is excellent. The music is excellent. The story is excellent and easy to follow. Cinematography is excellent. Directing is excellent also. It is a true winner. I wish more movies like this were being made. The world needs them, especially in this day and age. .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, get over it - it's a great love story!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pandaloonie
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not all love stories are guy-girl. This is just a huge human love story. And I LOVED it! Set the popcorn on refill mode and keep a keg of beer and a whole bunch of Kleenex at hand for the ending. First off, if Lance Henriksen reads the back of a toilet paper roll, sign me up and put me in the front row. The man delivers 110% to whatever role he is given. Period. Second, Ms Mary is a home girl, so props to her. Period. The rest of the cast I thought were superb. Again, period. This is a genuine feel-good movie and I highly recommend it. I am not going to give any spoilers for that would - spoil it. But let me say that as an avid movie watcher (older than most of you lot) this one had me hooked first to last. And I did not anticipate the ending though if I could it would have not been better. Go forth and enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle and moving film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Casey Dillard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie holds a very special place in my heart since I was young. Victor Salva, it seems, had at least one good story in him and this, though in some ways sappy, was certainly it. The treatment of the main character makes it hard to watch at times because it can feel very bleak and hopeless, but it is balanced out by the tenderness of the characters who do accept him and offer him hope and kindness. The acting is excellent in this film and the cast is to be commended for not turning the script into something sickly or too predictable. The ending brought me to tears and maybe felt like an easy way out, but it did feel appropriate. All in all, I'd suggest that anyone watch it at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good but not powerful enough to be great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, here's another story about a different person in a world that is prejudicial against what's not "normal", who most of the time is very misunderstood except for few people out there who really want to help and also want to understand how magnificent this person is. And this person has supernatural powers, this time involving electricity and an enormous memory capacity, memorizing book quotations from start to finish. Powder (Sean Patrick Flanery) is this person, an albino with extraordinary powers who was left alone in the world after his grandparents death, and now having to deal with the world outside of the basement where he lived, hidden of the eyes of everybody. Target of the prejudice of almost everybody, the only friends he has are the Sheriff (Lance Henriksen), a psychologist (Mary Steenburgen), a teacher (Jeff Goldblum) and a girl (Melissa Lahlitah Crider), intrigued by his mysterious gift. And again, it's a story about seeing the most difficult thing of all: the inside of someone rather than the physical appearance and learn what people have to say, discover their magic and be comprehensible to what this people are. The movie deserves some praise? Yes. In the best possible way the story was well presented but the film's magic comes from some of the situations where the great special effects are a real fun; the great casting never disappoints, all very good. But something tells me again and again that I've seen this story better developed in countless films and somehow the electricity, the vibrations coming from this flick weren't good enough to pass through my heart and make me feel something unexperienced or highly intelligent. It's just good and that's it. It tries to set some emotion but hardly succeeds in such task. Jerry Goldsmith musical score is sweeter than sugar, a little bit excessive at points. And it's a mystery to me that an albino attracted such negative attention from people like in this film, I mean, Southerns never saw one in life? If Jeremy/Powder was painted in blue I would believe in a frightened reaction from the crowd but an albino? It's more common than having Smurfs statues in your garden. It brings some positive light in showing that evolution/technology must be viewed in a lesser degree than the designs of the human spirit, and Powder does represent that but it stops right there. No more lessons to be learned, no more deeper thoughts to share. "Powder" is a nice film, very watchable, good to look at it but don't go with high expectations. The best film directed by Victor Salva so far, if we consider the weak "Jeepers Creepers" series. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    disgraceful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    unendurable_lampoonery
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well, at first i enjoyed this movie to an extent, then found out about the director's (Victor Selva) horrible past. a confessed child molester, he compares himself to the main character of this film, this is how he felt in jail, well I'm sorry, an albino has a lot less choice than a dirty pedophile who actually molested a child while making his first movie, the horrible over rated clown house. this movie would actually be good if the director did not write the main character based of himself, a dirty old man. disgraceful director, and a bad person to even compare himself to an amazingly powerful character, this movie is mediocre, at best, it would be better if i had not have read the directors statements on this movie. 3-10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful story, simply...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yoann Larrieu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the story of a very special young man, too pure for this world. Some indications are very interesting: like the day he describes as the worst of his life; the way he communicates with other people, and specifically, the way he candidly reacts to aggression and violence...: and ultimately, what he's really referring to when he says he "wants to go home". Eventually, being so pure and suffocating in this corrupt, blasphemous world; and clearly embodying the moral and purity figures and healing ability of Jesus Christ; he nonetheless longs to experience the tangible world, with all its intact qualities and various wonders - while always being torn away from them at some point by the dread of man's evil and cruelty. A unique character in fiction; resembling some great figures, while never replicating them; a very powerful and "pure" story - and I give this a 9/10 because though the depth is there, and the ideas are beautiful; the "form" of the film and certain scenes remain things that could have been done better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
