<filme>
 <id>
  368
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115683
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Malucos Por Natureza
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Moronic best friends get themselves locked inside the Bio-Dome, a science experiment, along with a group of environmental scientists for one year.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Bud and Doyle are two losers who are doing nothing with their lives. Both of their girlfriends are actively involved in saving the environment, but the two friends could care less about saving the Earth. One day, when a group of scientists begin a mission to live inside a "Bio-Dome" for a year without outside contact, Bud and Doyle mistakingly become part of the project themselves. The two must then learn how to protect the Earth and help the scientists complete their mission.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bio dome
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   loser
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   trapped
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   environmental
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   marijuana
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jason Bloom
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Adam Leff
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Mitchell Peck
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Pauly Shore
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Stephen Baldwin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   William Atherton
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could be used for torture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PhilipVier
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hardly gets any worse than Bio-Dome. Truly this is one of the worst films ever made, and I really hate it with all my heart. Everyone who worked on this abomination should be thrown in a concentration camp, and be experimented on for the rest of their unnatural lives. This film is supposed to be a comedy, but it's not. Not one single line of dialogue is funny, every performance is terrible, and the plot is virtually non-existent. The film revolves around two main characters, who are locked in the "Bio-Dome". They are played by Pauly Shore and Stephen Baldwin, who both do a terrible job. Their acting is beyond dreadful, their characters are complete lunatics, and not one single thing they say, or do is even remotely funny. The same goes for the other idiots who appeared in this picture. It's really a mystery to me why some people like this rubbish. It's like it was made by some sick person, who wanted to create the best torture method to be used in Guantanamo Bay. There was nothing in this film that I liked. I would rather fight Wladimir Klitschko in a bare-knuckle boxing match, than watch this piece of excrement ever again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very stupid, and not funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Carlstrom
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bio-Dome is very bad, and clich&eacute;. Actually, one of the most clich&eacute; pieces I've ever seen. Let's start at the script. The script is awful, pointing out the most obvious things, Pauly Shore just isn't bright in this film. Personally, this film has to have one of the worst scripts I think they've ever used for a film, honestly. The acting is decent, not good or bad, but decent. Some parts fell victim to bad acting, but I just feel that couldn't really be helped, ya' know? But, I didn't really like the cast, so this film is bad without me caring. The humor is just straight up, not funny. I didn't laugh once throughout, I was just thinking about all the horrible goofs, and gags they put in this film. This film wasn't funny at all. If you're looking for a comedy, this just won't cut it. And finally, the camera work. I guess the camera work is okay. It really could of been less dull, but I guess it'll pass. Overall, this films garbage. I highly recommend you stay away from this film. Bio-Dome gets a 1/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    squuuiiirreeellllyyyy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shinya Aoki
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only haters and old people review movies. I had to make an account to say that the movie didn't get worse, they just got older and forgot how to laugh at dumb things. Bio-dome is an awesome stoner comedy to watch with your friends as are all of Pauly Shore's movies. Squuuuiiirreeelllyyyyy!!!! So don't listen to all these reviews, you can even tell by how they type how lame of a person they are. It's funny all the haters come on to review movies that weren't made for them. The only reason the movie doesn't have better reviews is because people that enjoy these films are too busy out having fun with life and not writing bad things about everything they didn't enjoy online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bud and Doyle's Awful Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Two twits from Tucson," pompous Pauly Shore (as Bud Macintosh) and brain-dead Stephen Baldwin (as Doyle Johnson), have a fight with their girlfriends and go out for a drive on "Earth Day". In the Arizona desert, Mr. Baldwin needs to find a place to urinate. He is unable "cork it" outside and must use a bathroom. They stop at "Bio-Dome" thinking it is a new mall, and are trapped inside. This is an environmentally controlled facility, where five scientists are being sealed for a year. The supporting cast, sets, photography and opening credits are okay. More annoying than funny, the co-leads make you wonder how they became movie stars. ** Bio-Dome (1/12/96) Jason Bloom ~ Pauly Shore, Stephen Baldwin, William Atherton, Joey Adams
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    are you high?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    warning: this movie very dumb. pauly shore bad actor. pauly shore not actor, anyway. steve baldwin only little better than pauly shore. me only watched movie because me so bored, me had nothing else to do. me pray you will never be that bored. only good thing in movie is joey lauren adams. she hot. she have nice boobs, great legs, and sexy voice. me like joey lauren adams. me can take steve baldwin for few minutes. me hope pauly shore get picked up by giant bird and dropped in ocean. this a very dumb movie. no watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Frat Boys Look Smarter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm just going to come out and say it: I hate Bio-Dome and I often wondered why this stupid movie should have never been made. This movie is like a poor man's version of Dumb and Dumber, only that this movie has no comedy. First, the main heroes are nothing but a couple of idiots. They make Harry and Lloyd from Dumb and Dumber look like Albert Einstein and Alexander Graham Bell. They even make Bill and Ted from Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure look like Thomas Edison and Benjamin Franklin! Every time these two numb nuts talk, I feel like I'm getting my head shoved in a pile of horse diarrhea. What, were these guys dropped on their heads when they were babies? Second, the jokes are never funny. One joke involves a mom trying to drown her kid as an excuse for teaching her kid how to breath under water for a long time. Another one involves the two morons sexually violating two girls. And then there's yet another scene where a clown gets shot in broad daylight. I'm sorry, were any of these jokes supposed to be funny? OF COURSE NOT!! You're killing comedy movie! You're a comedy killer! You're a... comecidal(That's a word combining comedy with homicidal) maniac! Like North, Kazaam, The Super Mario Bros Movie, and the Titanic Animated Trilogy, every scene is so cringe-inducing, so heartless, so disgusting, and so idiotic that it makes me feel uncleaned as I watched it. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go take a shower because I feel dirty after watching this giant-sized brain tumor that is Bio-Dome.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bio-Dumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Buttongoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching the film "Bio-Dome" you feel much better about your intelligence. The major flaws with the film including the fact that the two main characters* never become serious. The film's jokes were corny and overused, and nearly every thing the characters would do were just eye-rollers rather than laughs. The dialogue was rather corny and I did manage to chuckle when one of the characters said "we need to save the bio-dome". I recommend after watching this movie, to watch an Oscar-winning movie so this garbage can be cleared from your mind. I give this movie a 2.4, because in order to receive a 1, the film must have horrible editing or be a disgusting porno. (Side notes:) *I have no desire to respect this film and it's character's names.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Sherman tank.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bud and Doyle are two losers who are doing nothing with their lives. Both of their girlfriends are actively involved in saving the environment, but the two friends could care less about saving the Earth. One day, when a group of scientists begin a mission to live inside a "Bio-Dome" for a year without outside contact, Bud and Doyle mistakingly become part of the project themselves. The two must then learn how to protect the Earth and help the scientists complete their mission.... First off, if you're not a fan of Pauly Shore, stop reading and do something else. I like Shore and his movies, they do their job and provide entertainment and are never boring, no matter how moronic they appear to be. This was one reason for me to watch this movie, the second was to see the biggest career nosedive in recent memory. Hello Stephen Baldwin. One minute, your in an Oscar winning movie, next your Playing Garth to Shores Wayne. It's silly stuff, but it's never boring and it's heart is in the right place. Shore seems to be having a whale of a time, which shows he loves his work, just like Sandler. The biggest surprise in this movie is that the guy you think will be a sleaze (Atherton, who clearly is in Ghostbusters and Die Hard 1&2) is quite lenient with the pair for the majority of the movie, which is good, because it has some originality to it. But all in all, it's a dumb movie, offering nothing new into the stoner buddy comedy, but it has some charm to it, and the cast have great chemistry and there is a message to all of this. it's never dull like a lot of comedies, but it's not for everyones taste. If you like a good 'bad' movie, you could do a lot 'worse'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A grade mindless movie power!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spaceboystevie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is all you can expect from a film staring Pauly Shore and has everything you would want from a movie that was created to be watched with beer, pizza and mates. The acting, plot and script are miles from decent, but are more than adequate for a film of this style. Lets face it you don't want to watch high brow, intellectually stimulating films every night. Some times it's good to put on a movie you don't need to concentrate on, have fun chatting to friends, have a drink and say "aaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhh" every time someone makes a joke about sex. The Godfather this is not, but a film to put on when you are not in the mood for thinking and fancy a chuckle, few do it better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh my!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    searchingcirclesend
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love this movie as a kid, and now I have no idea why. Maybe it's because, at the age of 10, I enjoyed watching grown men act younger than me. Look back on your own childhood and you likely enjoyed a few movies with that quality for that very reason. There is not one funny part in this movie. Seriously, not one. I've even re-watched it stoned (let's be honest, it was probably made to be viewed that way) just to see if the altered perception would make it any better, and it actually killed my buzz. Pauly Shore and one of the Baldwins that's not Alec seem to be in a pissing contest to see who can come off as more talentless. In the end, it's too close to call, so they both win (or lose, however you wanna look at it). The only reason I gave this movie 2 stars is because I tend to throw in an extra star if there is nostalgia associated with it. If you're in the mood for this kind of movie, you'd be better off watching Encino Man, even if you've seen it already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could be used for torture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PhilipVier
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hardly gets any worse than Bio-Dome. Truly this is one of the worst films ever made, and I really hate it with all my heart. Everyone who worked on this abomination should be thrown in a concentration camp, and be experimented on for the rest of their unnatural lives. This film is supposed to be a comedy, but it's not. Not one single line of dialogue is funny, every performance is terrible, and the plot is virtually non-existent. The film revolves around two main characters, who are locked in the "Bio-Dome". They are played by Pauly Shore and Stephen Baldwin, who both do a terrible job. Their acting is beyond dreadful, their characters are complete lunatics, and not one single thing they say, or do is even remotely funny. The same goes for the other idiots who appeared in this picture. It's really a mystery to me why some people like this rubbish. It's like it was made by some sick person, who wanted to create the best torture method to be used in Guantanamo Bay. There was nothing in this film that I liked. I would rather fight Wladimir Klitschko in a bare-knuckle boxing match, than watch this piece of excrement ever again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very stupid, and not funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Carlstrom
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bio-Dome is very bad, and clich&eacute;. Actually, one of the most clich&eacute; pieces I've ever seen. Let's start at the script. The script is awful, pointing out the most obvious things, Pauly Shore just isn't bright in this film. Personally, this film has to have one of the worst scripts I think they've ever used for a film, honestly. The acting is decent, not good or bad, but decent. Some parts fell victim to bad acting, but I just feel that couldn't really be helped, ya' know? But, I didn't really like the cast, so this film is bad without me caring. The humor is just straight up, not funny. I didn't laugh once throughout, I was just thinking about all the horrible goofs, and gags they put in this film. This film wasn't funny at all. If you're looking for a comedy, this just won't cut it. And finally, the camera work. I guess the camera work is okay. It really could of been less dull, but I guess it'll pass. Overall, this films garbage. I highly recommend you stay away from this film. Bio-Dome gets a 1/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    squuuiiirreeellllyyyy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shinya Aoki
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only haters and old people review movies. I had to make an account to say that the movie didn't get worse, they just got older and forgot how to laugh at dumb things. Bio-dome is an awesome stoner comedy to watch with your friends as are all of Pauly Shore's movies. Squuuuiiirreeelllyyyyy!!!! So don't listen to all these reviews, you can even tell by how they type how lame of a person they are. It's funny all the haters come on to review movies that weren't made for them. The only reason the movie doesn't have better reviews is because people that enjoy these films are too busy out having fun with life and not writing bad things about everything they didn't enjoy online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bud and Doyle's Awful Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Two twits from Tucson," pompous Pauly Shore (as Bud Macintosh) and brain-dead Stephen Baldwin (as Doyle Johnson), have a fight with their girlfriends and go out for a drive on "Earth Day". In the Arizona desert, Mr. Baldwin needs to find a place to urinate. He is unable "cork it" outside and must use a bathroom. They stop at "Bio-Dome" thinking it is a new mall, and are trapped inside. This is an environmentally controlled facility, where five scientists are being sealed for a year. The supporting cast, sets, photography and opening credits are okay. More annoying than funny, the co-leads make you wonder how they became movie stars. ** Bio-Dome (1/12/96) Jason Bloom ~ Pauly Shore, Stephen Baldwin, William Atherton, Joey Adams
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    are you high?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    warning: this movie very dumb. pauly shore bad actor. pauly shore not actor, anyway. steve baldwin only little better than pauly shore. me only watched movie because me so bored, me had nothing else to do. me pray you will never be that bored. only good thing in movie is joey lauren adams. she hot. she have nice boobs, great legs, and sexy voice. me like joey lauren adams. me can take steve baldwin for few minutes. me hope pauly shore get picked up by giant bird and dropped in ocean. this a very dumb movie. no watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Frat Boys Look Smarter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm just going to come out and say it: I hate Bio-Dome and I often wondered why this stupid movie should have never been made. This movie is like a poor man's version of Dumb and Dumber, only that this movie has no comedy. First, the main heroes are nothing but a couple of idiots. They make Harry and Lloyd from Dumb and Dumber look like Albert Einstein and Alexander Graham Bell. They even make Bill and Ted from Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure look like Thomas Edison and Benjamin Franklin! Every time these two numb nuts talk, I feel like I'm getting my head shoved in a pile of horse diarrhea. What, were these guys dropped on their heads when they were babies? Second, the jokes are never funny. One joke involves a mom trying to drown her kid as an excuse for teaching her kid how to breath under water for a long time. Another one involves the two morons sexually violating two girls. And then there's yet another scene where a clown gets shot in broad daylight. I'm sorry, were any of these jokes supposed to be funny? OF COURSE NOT!! You're killing comedy movie! You're a comedy killer! You're a... comecidal(That's a word combining comedy with homicidal) maniac! Like North, Kazaam, The Super Mario Bros Movie, and the Titanic Animated Trilogy, every scene is so cringe-inducing, so heartless, so disgusting, and so idiotic that it makes me feel uncleaned as I watched it. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go take a shower because I feel dirty after watching this giant-sized brain tumor that is Bio-Dome.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bio-Dumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Buttongoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching the film "Bio-Dome" you feel much better about your intelligence. The major flaws with the film including the fact that the two main characters* never become serious. The film's jokes were corny and overused, and nearly every thing the characters would do were just eye-rollers rather than laughs. The dialogue was rather corny and I did manage to chuckle when one of the characters said "we need to save the bio-dome". I recommend after watching this movie, to watch an Oscar-winning movie so this garbage can be cleared from your mind. I give this movie a 2.4, because in order to receive a 1, the film must have horrible editing or be a disgusting porno. (Side notes:) *I have no desire to respect this film and it's character's names.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Sherman tank.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bud and Doyle are two losers who are doing nothing with their lives. Both of their girlfriends are actively involved in saving the environment, but the two friends could care less about saving the Earth. One day, when a group of scientists begin a mission to live inside a "Bio-Dome" for a year without outside contact, Bud and Doyle mistakingly become part of the project themselves. The two must then learn how to protect the Earth and help the scientists complete their mission.... First off, if you're not a fan of Pauly Shore, stop reading and do something else. I like Shore and his movies, they do their job and provide entertainment and are never boring, no matter how moronic they appear to be. This was one reason for me to watch this movie, the second was to see the biggest career nosedive in recent memory. Hello Stephen Baldwin. One minute, your in an Oscar winning movie, next your Playing Garth to Shores Wayne. It's silly stuff, but it's never boring and it's heart is in the right place. Shore seems to be having a whale of a time, which shows he loves his work, just like Sandler. The biggest surprise in this movie is that the guy you think will be a sleaze (Atherton, who clearly is in Ghostbusters and Die Hard 1&2) is quite lenient with the pair for the majority of the movie, which is good, because it has some originality to it. But all in all, it's a dumb movie, offering nothing new into the stoner buddy comedy, but it has some charm to it, and the cast have great chemistry and there is a message to all of this. it's never dull like a lot of comedies, but it's not for everyones taste. If you like a good 'bad' movie, you could do a lot 'worse'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A grade mindless movie power!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spaceboystevie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is all you can expect from a film staring Pauly Shore and has everything you would want from a movie that was created to be watched with beer, pizza and mates. The acting, plot and script are miles from decent, but are more than adequate for a film of this style. Lets face it you don't want to watch high brow, intellectually stimulating films every night. Some times it's good to put on a movie you don't need to concentrate on, have fun chatting to friends, have a drink and say "aaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhh" every time someone makes a joke about sex. The Godfather this is not, but a film to put on when you are not in the mood for thinking and fancy a chuckle, few do it better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh my!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    searchingcirclesend
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love this movie as a kid, and now I have no idea why. Maybe it's because, at the age of 10, I enjoyed watching grown men act younger than me. Look back on your own childhood and you likely enjoyed a few movies with that quality for that very reason. There is not one funny part in this movie. Seriously, not one. I've even re-watched it stoned (let's be honest, it was probably made to be viewed that way) just to see if the altered perception would make it any better, and it actually killed my buzz. Pauly Shore and one of the Baldwins that's not Alec seem to be in a pissing contest to see who can come off as more talentless. In the end, it's too close to call, so they both win (or lose, however you wanna look at it). The only reason I gave this movie 2 stars is because I tend to throw in an extra star if there is nostalgia associated with it. If you're in the mood for this kind of movie, you'd be better off watching Encino Man, even if you've seen it already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could be used for torture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PhilipVier
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hardly gets any worse than Bio-Dome. Truly this is one of the worst films ever made, and I really hate it with all my heart. Everyone who worked on this abomination should be thrown in a concentration camp, and be experimented on for the rest of their unnatural lives. This film is supposed to be a comedy, but it's not. Not one single line of dialogue is funny, every performance is terrible, and the plot is virtually non-existent. The film revolves around two main characters, who are locked in the "Bio-Dome". They are played by Pauly Shore and Stephen Baldwin, who both do a terrible job. Their acting is beyond dreadful, their characters are complete lunatics, and not one single thing they say, or do is even remotely funny. The same goes for the other idiots who appeared in this picture. It's really a mystery to me why some people like this rubbish. It's like it was made by some sick person, who wanted to create the best torture method to be used in Guantanamo Bay. There was nothing in this film that I liked. I would rather fight Wladimir Klitschko in a bare-knuckle boxing match, than watch this piece of excrement ever again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very stupid, and not funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Carlstrom
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bio-Dome is very bad, and clich&eacute;. Actually, one of the most clich&eacute; pieces I've ever seen. Let's start at the script. The script is awful, pointing out the most obvious things, Pauly Shore just isn't bright in this film. Personally, this film has to have one of the worst scripts I think they've ever used for a film, honestly. The acting is decent, not good or bad, but decent. Some parts fell victim to bad acting, but I just feel that couldn't really be helped, ya' know? But, I didn't really like the cast, so this film is bad without me caring. The humor is just straight up, not funny. I didn't laugh once throughout, I was just thinking about all the horrible goofs, and gags they put in this film. This film wasn't funny at all. If you're looking for a comedy, this just won't cut it. And finally, the camera work. I guess the camera work is okay. It really could of been less dull, but I guess it'll pass. Overall, this films garbage. I highly recommend you stay away from this film. Bio-Dome gets a 1/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    squuuiiirreeellllyyyy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shinya Aoki
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only haters and old people review movies. I had to make an account to say that the movie didn't get worse, they just got older and forgot how to laugh at dumb things. Bio-dome is an awesome stoner comedy to watch with your friends as are all of Pauly Shore's movies. Squuuuiiirreeelllyyyyy!!!! So don't listen to all these reviews, you can even tell by how they type how lame of a person they are. It's funny all the haters come on to review movies that weren't made for them. The only reason the movie doesn't have better reviews is because people that enjoy these films are too busy out having fun with life and not writing bad things about everything they didn't enjoy online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bud and Doyle's Awful Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Two twits from Tucson," pompous Pauly Shore (as Bud Macintosh) and brain-dead Stephen Baldwin (as Doyle Johnson), have a fight with their girlfriends and go out for a drive on "Earth Day". In the Arizona desert, Mr. Baldwin needs to find a place to urinate. He is unable "cork it" outside and must use a bathroom. They stop at "Bio-Dome" thinking it is a new mall, and are trapped inside. This is an environmentally controlled facility, where five scientists are being sealed for a year. The supporting cast, sets, photography and opening credits are okay. More annoying than funny, the co-leads make you wonder how they became movie stars. ** Bio-Dome (1/12/96) Jason Bloom ~ Pauly Shore, Stephen Baldwin, William Atherton, Joey Adams
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    are you high?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    warning: this movie very dumb. pauly shore bad actor. pauly shore not actor, anyway. steve baldwin only little better than pauly shore. me only watched movie because me so bored, me had nothing else to do. me pray you will never be that bored. only good thing in movie is joey lauren adams. she hot. she have nice boobs, great legs, and sexy voice. me like joey lauren adams. me can take steve baldwin for few minutes. me hope pauly shore get picked up by giant bird and dropped in ocean. this a very dumb movie. no watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Frat Boys Look Smarter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm just going to come out and say it: I hate Bio-Dome and I often wondered why this stupid movie should have never been made. This movie is like a poor man's version of Dumb and Dumber, only that this movie has no comedy. First, the main heroes are nothing but a couple of idiots. They make Harry and Lloyd from Dumb and Dumber look like Albert Einstein and Alexander Graham Bell. They even make Bill and Ted from Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure look like Thomas Edison and Benjamin Franklin! Every time these two numb nuts talk, I feel like I'm getting my head shoved in a pile of horse diarrhea. What, were these guys dropped on their heads when they were babies? Second, the jokes are never funny. One joke involves a mom trying to drown her kid as an excuse for teaching her kid how to breath under water for a long time. Another one involves the two morons sexually violating two girls. And then there's yet another scene where a clown gets shot in broad daylight. I'm sorry, were any of these jokes supposed to be funny? OF COURSE NOT!! You're killing comedy movie! You're a comedy killer! You're a... comecidal(That's a word combining comedy with homicidal) maniac! Like North, Kazaam, The Super Mario Bros Movie, and the Titanic Animated Trilogy, every scene is so cringe-inducing, so heartless, so disgusting, and so idiotic that it makes me feel uncleaned as I watched it. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go take a shower because I feel dirty after watching this giant-sized brain tumor that is Bio-Dome.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bio-Dumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Buttongoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching the film "Bio-Dome" you feel much better about your intelligence. The major flaws with the film including the fact that the two main characters* never become serious. The film's jokes were corny and overused, and nearly every thing the characters would do were just eye-rollers rather than laughs. The dialogue was rather corny and I did manage to chuckle when one of the characters said "we need to save the bio-dome". I recommend after watching this movie, to watch an Oscar-winning movie so this garbage can be cleared from your mind. I give this movie a 2.4, because in order to receive a 1, the film must have horrible editing or be a disgusting porno. (Side notes:) *I have no desire to respect this film and it's character's names.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Sherman tank.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bud and Doyle are two losers who are doing nothing with their lives. Both of their girlfriends are actively involved in saving the environment, but the two friends could care less about saving the Earth. One day, when a group of scientists begin a mission to live inside a "Bio-Dome" for a year without outside contact, Bud and Doyle mistakingly become part of the project themselves. The two must then learn how to protect the Earth and help the scientists complete their mission.... First off, if you're not a fan of Pauly Shore, stop reading and do something else. I like Shore and his movies, they do their job and provide entertainment and are never boring, no matter how moronic they appear to be. This was one reason for me to watch this movie, the second was to see the biggest career nosedive in recent memory. Hello Stephen Baldwin. One minute, your in an Oscar winning movie, next your Playing Garth to Shores Wayne. It's silly stuff, but it's never boring and it's heart is in the right place. Shore seems to be having a whale of a time, which shows he loves his work, just like Sandler. The biggest surprise in this movie is that the guy you think will be a sleaze (Atherton, who clearly is in Ghostbusters and Die Hard 1&2) is quite lenient with the pair for the majority of the movie, which is good, because it has some originality to it. But all in all, it's a dumb movie, offering nothing new into the stoner buddy comedy, but it has some charm to it, and the cast have great chemistry and there is a message to all of this. it's never dull like a lot of comedies, but it's not for everyones taste. If you like a good 'bad' movie, you could do a lot 'worse'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A grade mindless movie power!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spaceboystevie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is all you can expect from a film staring Pauly Shore and has everything you would want from a movie that was created to be watched with beer, pizza and mates. The acting, plot and script are miles from decent, but are more than adequate for a film of this style. Lets face it you don't want to watch high brow, intellectually stimulating films every night. Some times it's good to put on a movie you don't need to concentrate on, have fun chatting to friends, have a drink and say "aaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhh" every time someone makes a joke about sex. The Godfather this is not, but a film to put on when you are not in the mood for thinking and fancy a chuckle, few do it better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh my!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    searchingcirclesend
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love this movie as a kid, and now I have no idea why. Maybe it's because, at the age of 10, I enjoyed watching grown men act younger than me. Look back on your own childhood and you likely enjoyed a few movies with that quality for that very reason. There is not one funny part in this movie. Seriously, not one. I've even re-watched it stoned (let's be honest, it was probably made to be viewed that way) just to see if the altered perception would make it any better, and it actually killed my buzz. Pauly Shore and one of the Baldwins that's not Alec seem to be in a pissing contest to see who can come off as more talentless. In the end, it's too close to call, so they both win (or lose, however you wanna look at it). The only reason I gave this movie 2 stars is because I tend to throw in an extra star if there is nostalgia associated with it. If you're in the mood for this kind of movie, you'd be better off watching Encino Man, even if you've seen it already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could be used for torture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PhilipVier
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hardly gets any worse than Bio-Dome. Truly this is one of the worst films ever made, and I really hate it with all my heart. Everyone who worked on this abomination should be thrown in a concentration camp, and be experimented on for the rest of their unnatural lives. This film is supposed to be a comedy, but it's not. Not one single line of dialogue is funny, every performance is terrible, and the plot is virtually non-existent. The film revolves around two main characters, who are locked in the "Bio-Dome". They are played by Pauly Shore and Stephen Baldwin, who both do a terrible job. Their acting is beyond dreadful, their characters are complete lunatics, and not one single thing they say, or do is even remotely funny. The same goes for the other idiots who appeared in this picture. It's really a mystery to me why some people like this rubbish. It's like it was made by some sick person, who wanted to create the best torture method to be used in Guantanamo Bay. There was nothing in this film that I liked. I would rather fight Wladimir Klitschko in a bare-knuckle boxing match, than watch this piece of excrement ever again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very stupid, and not funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Carlstrom
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bio-Dome is very bad, and clich&eacute;. Actually, one of the most clich&eacute; pieces I've ever seen. Let's start at the script. The script is awful, pointing out the most obvious things, Pauly Shore just isn't bright in this film. Personally, this film has to have one of the worst scripts I think they've ever used for a film, honestly. The acting is decent, not good or bad, but decent. Some parts fell victim to bad acting, but I just feel that couldn't really be helped, ya' know? But, I didn't really like the cast, so this film is bad without me caring. The humor is just straight up, not funny. I didn't laugh once throughout, I was just thinking about all the horrible goofs, and gags they put in this film. This film wasn't funny at all. If you're looking for a comedy, this just won't cut it. And finally, the camera work. I guess the camera work is okay. It really could of been less dull, but I guess it'll pass. Overall, this films garbage. I highly recommend you stay away from this film. Bio-Dome gets a 1/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    squuuiiirreeellllyyyy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shinya Aoki
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only haters and old people review movies. I had to make an account to say that the movie didn't get worse, they just got older and forgot how to laugh at dumb things. Bio-dome is an awesome stoner comedy to watch with your friends as are all of Pauly Shore's movies. Squuuuiiirreeelllyyyyy!!!! So don't listen to all these reviews, you can even tell by how they type how lame of a person they are. It's funny all the haters come on to review movies that weren't made for them. The only reason the movie doesn't have better reviews is because people that enjoy these films are too busy out having fun with life and not writing bad things about everything they didn't enjoy online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bud and Doyle's Awful Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Two twits from Tucson," pompous Pauly Shore (as Bud Macintosh) and brain-dead Stephen Baldwin (as Doyle Johnson), have a fight with their girlfriends and go out for a drive on "Earth Day". In the Arizona desert, Mr. Baldwin needs to find a place to urinate. He is unable "cork it" outside and must use a bathroom. They stop at "Bio-Dome" thinking it is a new mall, and are trapped inside. This is an environmentally controlled facility, where five scientists are being sealed for a year. The supporting cast, sets, photography and opening credits are okay. More annoying than funny, the co-leads make you wonder how they became movie stars. ** Bio-Dome (1/12/96) Jason Bloom ~ Pauly Shore, Stephen Baldwin, William Atherton, Joey Adams
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    are you high?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    warning: this movie very dumb. pauly shore bad actor. pauly shore not actor, anyway. steve baldwin only little better than pauly shore. me only watched movie because me so bored, me had nothing else to do. me pray you will never be that bored. only good thing in movie is joey lauren adams. she hot. she have nice boobs, great legs, and sexy voice. me like joey lauren adams. me can take steve baldwin for few minutes. me hope pauly shore get picked up by giant bird and dropped in ocean. this a very dumb movie. no watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Frat Boys Look Smarter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm just going to come out and say it: I hate Bio-Dome and I often wondered why this stupid movie should have never been made. This movie is like a poor man's version of Dumb and Dumber, only that this movie has no comedy. First, the main heroes are nothing but a couple of idiots. They make Harry and Lloyd from Dumb and Dumber look like Albert Einstein and Alexander Graham Bell. They even make Bill and Ted from Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure look like Thomas Edison and Benjamin Franklin! Every time these two numb nuts talk, I feel like I'm getting my head shoved in a pile of horse diarrhea. What, were these guys dropped on their heads when they were babies? Second, the jokes are never funny. One joke involves a mom trying to drown her kid as an excuse for teaching her kid how to breath under water for a long time. Another one involves the two morons sexually violating two girls. And then there's yet another scene where a clown gets shot in broad daylight. I'm sorry, were any of these jokes supposed to be funny? OF COURSE NOT!! You're killing comedy movie! You're a comedy killer! You're a... comecidal(That's a word combining comedy with homicidal) maniac! Like North, Kazaam, The Super Mario Bros Movie, and the Titanic Animated Trilogy, every scene is so cringe-inducing, so heartless, so disgusting, and so idiotic that it makes me feel uncleaned as I watched it. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go take a shower because I feel dirty after watching this giant-sized brain tumor that is Bio-Dome.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bio-Dumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Buttongoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching the film "Bio-Dome" you feel much better about your intelligence. The major flaws with the film including the fact that the two main characters* never become serious. The film's jokes were corny and overused, and nearly every thing the characters would do were just eye-rollers rather than laughs. The dialogue was rather corny and I did manage to chuckle when one of the characters said "we need to save the bio-dome". I recommend after watching this movie, to watch an Oscar-winning movie so this garbage can be cleared from your mind. I give this movie a 2.4, because in order to receive a 1, the film must have horrible editing or be a disgusting porno. (Side notes:) *I have no desire to respect this film and it's character's names.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Sherman tank.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bud and Doyle are two losers who are doing nothing with their lives. Both of their girlfriends are actively involved in saving the environment, but the two friends could care less about saving the Earth. One day, when a group of scientists begin a mission to live inside a "Bio-Dome" for a year without outside contact, Bud and Doyle mistakingly become part of the project themselves. The two must then learn how to protect the Earth and help the scientists complete their mission.... First off, if you're not a fan of Pauly Shore, stop reading and do something else. I like Shore and his movies, they do their job and provide entertainment and are never boring, no matter how moronic they appear to be. This was one reason for me to watch this movie, the second was to see the biggest career nosedive in recent memory. Hello Stephen Baldwin. One minute, your in an Oscar winning movie, next your Playing Garth to Shores Wayne. It's silly stuff, but it's never boring and it's heart is in the right place. Shore seems to be having a whale of a time, which shows he loves his work, just like Sandler. The biggest surprise in this movie is that the guy you think will be a sleaze (Atherton, who clearly is in Ghostbusters and Die Hard 1&2) is quite lenient with the pair for the majority of the movie, which is good, because it has some originality to it. But all in all, it's a dumb movie, offering nothing new into the stoner buddy comedy, but it has some charm to it, and the cast have great chemistry and there is a message to all of this. it's never dull like a lot of comedies, but it's not for everyones taste. If you like a good 'bad' movie, you could do a lot 'worse'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A grade mindless movie power!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spaceboystevie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is all you can expect from a film staring Pauly Shore and has everything you would want from a movie that was created to be watched with beer, pizza and mates. The acting, plot and script are miles from decent, but are more than adequate for a film of this style. Lets face it you don't want to watch high brow, intellectually stimulating films every night. Some times it's good to put on a movie you don't need to concentrate on, have fun chatting to friends, have a drink and say "aaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhh" every time someone makes a joke about sex. The Godfather this is not, but a film to put on when you are not in the mood for thinking and fancy a chuckle, few do it better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh my!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    searchingcirclesend
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love this movie as a kid, and now I have no idea why. Maybe it's because, at the age of 10, I enjoyed watching grown men act younger than me. Look back on your own childhood and you likely enjoyed a few movies with that quality for that very reason. There is not one funny part in this movie. Seriously, not one. I've even re-watched it stoned (let's be honest, it was probably made to be viewed that way) just to see if the altered perception would make it any better, and it actually killed my buzz. Pauly Shore and one of the Baldwins that's not Alec seem to be in a pissing contest to see who can come off as more talentless. In the end, it's too close to call, so they both win (or lose, however you wanna look at it). The only reason I gave this movie 2 stars is because I tend to throw in an extra star if there is nostalgia associated with it. If you're in the mood for this kind of movie, you'd be better off watching Encino Man, even if you've seen it already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could be used for torture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PhilipVier
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hardly gets any worse than Bio-Dome. Truly this is one of the worst films ever made, and I really hate it with all my heart. Everyone who worked on this abomination should be thrown in a concentration camp, and be experimented on for the rest of their unnatural lives. This film is supposed to be a comedy, but it's not. Not one single line of dialogue is funny, every performance is terrible, and the plot is virtually non-existent. The film revolves around two main characters, who are locked in the "Bio-Dome". They are played by Pauly Shore and Stephen Baldwin, who both do a terrible job. Their acting is beyond dreadful, their characters are complete lunatics, and not one single thing they say, or do is even remotely funny. The same goes for the other idiots who appeared in this picture. It's really a mystery to me why some people like this rubbish. It's like it was made by some sick person, who wanted to create the best torture method to be used in Guantanamo Bay. There was nothing in this film that I liked. I would rather fight Wladimir Klitschko in a bare-knuckle boxing match, than watch this piece of excrement ever again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very stupid, and not funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Carlstrom
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bio-Dome is very bad, and clich&eacute;. Actually, one of the most clich&eacute; pieces I've ever seen. Let's start at the script. The script is awful, pointing out the most obvious things, Pauly Shore just isn't bright in this film. Personally, this film has to have one of the worst scripts I think they've ever used for a film, honestly. The acting is decent, not good or bad, but decent. Some parts fell victim to bad acting, but I just feel that couldn't really be helped, ya' know? But, I didn't really like the cast, so this film is bad without me caring. The humor is just straight up, not funny. I didn't laugh once throughout, I was just thinking about all the horrible goofs, and gags they put in this film. This film wasn't funny at all. If you're looking for a comedy, this just won't cut it. And finally, the camera work. I guess the camera work is okay. It really could of been less dull, but I guess it'll pass. Overall, this films garbage. I highly recommend you stay away from this film. Bio-Dome gets a 1/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    squuuiiirreeellllyyyy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shinya Aoki
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only haters and old people review movies. I had to make an account to say that the movie didn't get worse, they just got older and forgot how to laugh at dumb things. Bio-dome is an awesome stoner comedy to watch with your friends as are all of Pauly Shore's movies. Squuuuiiirreeelllyyyyy!!!! So don't listen to all these reviews, you can even tell by how they type how lame of a person they are. It's funny all the haters come on to review movies that weren't made for them. The only reason the movie doesn't have better reviews is because people that enjoy these films are too busy out having fun with life and not writing bad things about everything they didn't enjoy online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bud and Doyle's Awful Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Two twits from Tucson," pompous Pauly Shore (as Bud Macintosh) and brain-dead Stephen Baldwin (as Doyle Johnson), have a fight with their girlfriends and go out for a drive on "Earth Day". In the Arizona desert, Mr. Baldwin needs to find a place to urinate. He is unable "cork it" outside and must use a bathroom. They stop at "Bio-Dome" thinking it is a new mall, and are trapped inside. This is an environmentally controlled facility, where five scientists are being sealed for a year. The supporting cast, sets, photography and opening credits are okay. More annoying than funny, the co-leads make you wonder how they became movie stars. ** Bio-Dome (1/12/96) Jason Bloom ~ Pauly Shore, Stephen Baldwin, William Atherton, Joey Adams
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    are you high?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    warning: this movie very dumb. pauly shore bad actor. pauly shore not actor, anyway. steve baldwin only little better than pauly shore. me only watched movie because me so bored, me had nothing else to do. me pray you will never be that bored. only good thing in movie is joey lauren adams. she hot. she have nice boobs, great legs, and sexy voice. me like joey lauren adams. me can take steve baldwin for few minutes. me hope pauly shore get picked up by giant bird and dropped in ocean. this a very dumb movie. no watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Frat Boys Look Smarter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm just going to come out and say it: I hate Bio-Dome and I often wondered why this stupid movie should have never been made. This movie is like a poor man's version of Dumb and Dumber, only that this movie has no comedy. First, the main heroes are nothing but a couple of idiots. They make Harry and Lloyd from Dumb and Dumber look like Albert Einstein and Alexander Graham Bell. They even make Bill and Ted from Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure look like Thomas Edison and Benjamin Franklin! Every time these two numb nuts talk, I feel like I'm getting my head shoved in a pile of horse diarrhea. What, were these guys dropped on their heads when they were babies? Second, the jokes are never funny. One joke involves a mom trying to drown her kid as an excuse for teaching her kid how to breath under water for a long time. Another one involves the two morons sexually violating two girls. And then there's yet another scene where a clown gets shot in broad daylight. I'm sorry, were any of these jokes supposed to be funny? OF COURSE NOT!! You're killing comedy movie! You're a comedy killer! You're a... comecidal(That's a word combining comedy with homicidal) maniac! Like North, Kazaam, The Super Mario Bros Movie, and the Titanic Animated Trilogy, every scene is so cringe-inducing, so heartless, so disgusting, and so idiotic that it makes me feel uncleaned as I watched it. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go take a shower because I feel dirty after watching this giant-sized brain tumor that is Bio-Dome.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bio-Dumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Buttongoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching the film "Bio-Dome" you feel much better about your intelligence. The major flaws with the film including the fact that the two main characters* never become serious. The film's jokes were corny and overused, and nearly every thing the characters would do were just eye-rollers rather than laughs. The dialogue was rather corny and I did manage to chuckle when one of the characters said "we need to save the bio-dome". I recommend after watching this movie, to watch an Oscar-winning movie so this garbage can be cleared from your mind. I give this movie a 2.4, because in order to receive a 1, the film must have horrible editing or be a disgusting porno. (Side notes:) *I have no desire to respect this film and it's character's names.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Sherman tank.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bud and Doyle are two losers who are doing nothing with their lives. Both of their girlfriends are actively involved in saving the environment, but the two friends could care less about saving the Earth. One day, when a group of scientists begin a mission to live inside a "Bio-Dome" for a year without outside contact, Bud and Doyle mistakingly become part of the project themselves. The two must then learn how to protect the Earth and help the scientists complete their mission.... First off, if you're not a fan of Pauly Shore, stop reading and do something else. I like Shore and his movies, they do their job and provide entertainment and are never boring, no matter how moronic they appear to be. This was one reason for me to watch this movie, the second was to see the biggest career nosedive in recent memory. Hello Stephen Baldwin. One minute, your in an Oscar winning movie, next your Playing Garth to Shores Wayne. It's silly stuff, but it's never boring and it's heart is in the right place. Shore seems to be having a whale of a time, which shows he loves his work, just like Sandler. The biggest surprise in this movie is that the guy you think will be a sleaze (Atherton, who clearly is in Ghostbusters and Die Hard 1&2) is quite lenient with the pair for the majority of the movie, which is good, because it has some originality to it. But all in all, it's a dumb movie, offering nothing new into the stoner buddy comedy, but it has some charm to it, and the cast have great chemistry and there is a message to all of this. it's never dull like a lot of comedies, but it's not for everyones taste. If you like a good 'bad' movie, you could do a lot 'worse'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A grade mindless movie power!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spaceboystevie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is all you can expect from a film staring Pauly Shore and has everything you would want from a movie that was created to be watched with beer, pizza and mates. The acting, plot and script are miles from decent, but are more than adequate for a film of this style. Lets face it you don't want to watch high brow, intellectually stimulating films every night. Some times it's good to put on a movie you don't need to concentrate on, have fun chatting to friends, have a drink and say "aaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhh" every time someone makes a joke about sex. The Godfather this is not, but a film to put on when you are not in the mood for thinking and fancy a chuckle, few do it better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh my!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    searchingcirclesend
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love this movie as a kid, and now I have no idea why. Maybe it's because, at the age of 10, I enjoyed watching grown men act younger than me. Look back on your own childhood and you likely enjoyed a few movies with that quality for that very reason. There is not one funny part in this movie. Seriously, not one. I've even re-watched it stoned (let's be honest, it was probably made to be viewed that way) just to see if the altered perception would make it any better, and it actually killed my buzz. Pauly Shore and one of the Baldwins that's not Alec seem to be in a pissing contest to see who can come off as more talentless. In the end, it's too close to call, so they both win (or lose, however you wanna look at it). The only reason I gave this movie 2 stars is because I tend to throw in an extra star if there is nostalgia associated with it. If you're in the mood for this kind of movie, you'd be better off watching Encino Man, even if you've seen it already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could be used for torture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PhilipVier
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hardly gets any worse than Bio-Dome. Truly this is one of the worst films ever made, and I really hate it with all my heart. Everyone who worked on this abomination should be thrown in a concentration camp, and be experimented on for the rest of their unnatural lives. This film is supposed to be a comedy, but it's not. Not one single line of dialogue is funny, every performance is terrible, and the plot is virtually non-existent. The film revolves around two main characters, who are locked in the "Bio-Dome". They are played by Pauly Shore and Stephen Baldwin, who both do a terrible job. Their acting is beyond dreadful, their characters are complete lunatics, and not one single thing they say, or do is even remotely funny. The same goes for the other idiots who appeared in this picture. It's really a mystery to me why some people like this rubbish. It's like it was made by some sick person, who wanted to create the best torture method to be used in Guantanamo Bay. There was nothing in this film that I liked. I would rather fight Wladimir Klitschko in a bare-knuckle boxing match, than watch this piece of excrement ever again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very stupid, and not funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Carlstrom
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bio-Dome is very bad, and clich&eacute;. Actually, one of the most clich&eacute; pieces I've ever seen. Let's start at the script. The script is awful, pointing out the most obvious things, Pauly Shore just isn't bright in this film. Personally, this film has to have one of the worst scripts I think they've ever used for a film, honestly. The acting is decent, not good or bad, but decent. Some parts fell victim to bad acting, but I just feel that couldn't really be helped, ya' know? But, I didn't really like the cast, so this film is bad without me caring. The humor is just straight up, not funny. I didn't laugh once throughout, I was just thinking about all the horrible goofs, and gags they put in this film. This film wasn't funny at all. If you're looking for a comedy, this just won't cut it. And finally, the camera work. I guess the camera work is okay. It really could of been less dull, but I guess it'll pass. Overall, this films garbage. I highly recommend you stay away from this film. Bio-Dome gets a 1/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    squuuiiirreeellllyyyy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shinya Aoki
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only haters and old people review movies. I had to make an account to say that the movie didn't get worse, they just got older and forgot how to laugh at dumb things. Bio-dome is an awesome stoner comedy to watch with your friends as are all of Pauly Shore's movies. Squuuuiiirreeelllyyyyy!!!! So don't listen to all these reviews, you can even tell by how they type how lame of a person they are. It's funny all the haters come on to review movies that weren't made for them. The only reason the movie doesn't have better reviews is because people that enjoy these films are too busy out having fun with life and not writing bad things about everything they didn't enjoy online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bud and Doyle's Awful Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Two twits from Tucson," pompous Pauly Shore (as Bud Macintosh) and brain-dead Stephen Baldwin (as Doyle Johnson), have a fight with their girlfriends and go out for a drive on "Earth Day". In the Arizona desert, Mr. Baldwin needs to find a place to urinate. He is unable "cork it" outside and must use a bathroom. They stop at "Bio-Dome" thinking it is a new mall, and are trapped inside. This is an environmentally controlled facility, where five scientists are being sealed for a year. The supporting cast, sets, photography and opening credits are okay. More annoying than funny, the co-leads make you wonder how they became movie stars. ** Bio-Dome (1/12/96) Jason Bloom ~ Pauly Shore, Stephen Baldwin, William Atherton, Joey Adams
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    are you high?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    warning: this movie very dumb. pauly shore bad actor. pauly shore not actor, anyway. steve baldwin only little better than pauly shore. me only watched movie because me so bored, me had nothing else to do. me pray you will never be that bored. only good thing in movie is joey lauren adams. she hot. she have nice boobs, great legs, and sexy voice. me like joey lauren adams. me can take steve baldwin for few minutes. me hope pauly shore get picked up by giant bird and dropped in ocean. this a very dumb movie. no watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Frat Boys Look Smarter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm just going to come out and say it: I hate Bio-Dome and I often wondered why this stupid movie should have never been made. This movie is like a poor man's version of Dumb and Dumber, only that this movie has no comedy. First, the main heroes are nothing but a couple of idiots. They make Harry and Lloyd from Dumb and Dumber look like Albert Einstein and Alexander Graham Bell. They even make Bill and Ted from Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure look like Thomas Edison and Benjamin Franklin! Every time these two numb nuts talk, I feel like I'm getting my head shoved in a pile of horse diarrhea. What, were these guys dropped on their heads when they were babies? Second, the jokes are never funny. One joke involves a mom trying to drown her kid as an excuse for teaching her kid how to breath under water for a long time. Another one involves the two morons sexually violating two girls. And then there's yet another scene where a clown gets shot in broad daylight. I'm sorry, were any of these jokes supposed to be funny? OF COURSE NOT!! You're killing comedy movie! You're a comedy killer! You're a... comecidal(That's a word combining comedy with homicidal) maniac! Like North, Kazaam, The Super Mario Bros Movie, and the Titanic Animated Trilogy, every scene is so cringe-inducing, so heartless, so disgusting, and so idiotic that it makes me feel uncleaned as I watched it. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go take a shower because I feel dirty after watching this giant-sized brain tumor that is Bio-Dome.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bio-Dumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Buttongoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching the film "Bio-Dome" you feel much better about your intelligence. The major flaws with the film including the fact that the two main characters* never become serious. The film's jokes were corny and overused, and nearly every thing the characters would do were just eye-rollers rather than laughs. The dialogue was rather corny and I did manage to chuckle when one of the characters said "we need to save the bio-dome". I recommend after watching this movie, to watch an Oscar-winning movie so this garbage can be cleared from your mind. I give this movie a 2.4, because in order to receive a 1, the film must have horrible editing or be a disgusting porno. (Side notes:) *I have no desire to respect this film and it's character's names.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Sherman tank.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bud and Doyle are two losers who are doing nothing with their lives. Both of their girlfriends are actively involved in saving the environment, but the two friends could care less about saving the Earth. One day, when a group of scientists begin a mission to live inside a "Bio-Dome" for a year without outside contact, Bud and Doyle mistakingly become part of the project themselves. The two must then learn how to protect the Earth and help the scientists complete their mission.... First off, if you're not a fan of Pauly Shore, stop reading and do something else. I like Shore and his movies, they do their job and provide entertainment and are never boring, no matter how moronic they appear to be. This was one reason for me to watch this movie, the second was to see the biggest career nosedive in recent memory. Hello Stephen Baldwin. One minute, your in an Oscar winning movie, next your Playing Garth to Shores Wayne. It's silly stuff, but it's never boring and it's heart is in the right place. Shore seems to be having a whale of a time, which shows he loves his work, just like Sandler. The biggest surprise in this movie is that the guy you think will be a sleaze (Atherton, who clearly is in Ghostbusters and Die Hard 1&2) is quite lenient with the pair for the majority of the movie, which is good, because it has some originality to it. But all in all, it's a dumb movie, offering nothing new into the stoner buddy comedy, but it has some charm to it, and the cast have great chemistry and there is a message to all of this. it's never dull like a lot of comedies, but it's not for everyones taste. If you like a good 'bad' movie, you could do a lot 'worse'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A grade mindless movie power!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spaceboystevie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is all you can expect from a film staring Pauly Shore and has everything you would want from a movie that was created to be watched with beer, pizza and mates. The acting, plot and script are miles from decent, but are more than adequate for a film of this style. Lets face it you don't want to watch high brow, intellectually stimulating films every night. Some times it's good to put on a movie you don't need to concentrate on, have fun chatting to friends, have a drink and say "aaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhh" every time someone makes a joke about sex. The Godfather this is not, but a film to put on when you are not in the mood for thinking and fancy a chuckle, few do it better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh my!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    searchingcirclesend
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love this movie as a kid, and now I have no idea why. Maybe it's because, at the age of 10, I enjoyed watching grown men act younger than me. Look back on your own childhood and you likely enjoyed a few movies with that quality for that very reason. There is not one funny part in this movie. Seriously, not one. I've even re-watched it stoned (let's be honest, it was probably made to be viewed that way) just to see if the altered perception would make it any better, and it actually killed my buzz. Pauly Shore and one of the Baldwins that's not Alec seem to be in a pissing contest to see who can come off as more talentless. In the end, it's too close to call, so they both win (or lose, however you wanna look at it). The only reason I gave this movie 2 stars is because I tend to throw in an extra star if there is nostalgia associated with it. If you're in the mood for this kind of movie, you'd be better off watching Encino Man, even if you've seen it already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could be used for torture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PhilipVier
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hardly gets any worse than Bio-Dome. Truly this is one of the worst films ever made, and I really hate it with all my heart. Everyone who worked on this abomination should be thrown in a concentration camp, and be experimented on for the rest of their unnatural lives. This film is supposed to be a comedy, but it's not. Not one single line of dialogue is funny, every performance is terrible, and the plot is virtually non-existent. The film revolves around two main characters, who are locked in the "Bio-Dome". They are played by Pauly Shore and Stephen Baldwin, who both do a terrible job. Their acting is beyond dreadful, their characters are complete lunatics, and not one single thing they say, or do is even remotely funny. The same goes for the other idiots who appeared in this picture. It's really a mystery to me why some people like this rubbish. It's like it was made by some sick person, who wanted to create the best torture method to be used in Guantanamo Bay. There was nothing in this film that I liked. I would rather fight Wladimir Klitschko in a bare-knuckle boxing match, than watch this piece of excrement ever again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very stupid, and not funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Carlstrom
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bio-Dome is very bad, and clich&eacute;. Actually, one of the most clich&eacute; pieces I've ever seen. Let's start at the script. The script is awful, pointing out the most obvious things, Pauly Shore just isn't bright in this film. Personally, this film has to have one of the worst scripts I think they've ever used for a film, honestly. The acting is decent, not good or bad, but decent. Some parts fell victim to bad acting, but I just feel that couldn't really be helped, ya' know? But, I didn't really like the cast, so this film is bad without me caring. The humor is just straight up, not funny. I didn't laugh once throughout, I was just thinking about all the horrible goofs, and gags they put in this film. This film wasn't funny at all. If you're looking for a comedy, this just won't cut it. And finally, the camera work. I guess the camera work is okay. It really could of been less dull, but I guess it'll pass. Overall, this films garbage. I highly recommend you stay away from this film. Bio-Dome gets a 1/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    squuuiiirreeellllyyyy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shinya Aoki
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only haters and old people review movies. I had to make an account to say that the movie didn't get worse, they just got older and forgot how to laugh at dumb things. Bio-dome is an awesome stoner comedy to watch with your friends as are all of Pauly Shore's movies. Squuuuiiirreeelllyyyyy!!!! So don't listen to all these reviews, you can even tell by how they type how lame of a person they are. It's funny all the haters come on to review movies that weren't made for them. The only reason the movie doesn't have better reviews is because people that enjoy these films are too busy out having fun with life and not writing bad things about everything they didn't enjoy online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bud and Doyle's Awful Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Two twits from Tucson," pompous Pauly Shore (as Bud Macintosh) and brain-dead Stephen Baldwin (as Doyle Johnson), have a fight with their girlfriends and go out for a drive on "Earth Day". In the Arizona desert, Mr. Baldwin needs to find a place to urinate. He is unable "cork it" outside and must use a bathroom. They stop at "Bio-Dome" thinking it is a new mall, and are trapped inside. This is an environmentally controlled facility, where five scientists are being sealed for a year. The supporting cast, sets, photography and opening credits are okay. More annoying than funny, the co-leads make you wonder how they became movie stars. ** Bio-Dome (1/12/96) Jason Bloom ~ Pauly Shore, Stephen Baldwin, William Atherton, Joey Adams
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    are you high?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    warning: this movie very dumb. pauly shore bad actor. pauly shore not actor, anyway. steve baldwin only little better than pauly shore. me only watched movie because me so bored, me had nothing else to do. me pray you will never be that bored. only good thing in movie is joey lauren adams. she hot. she have nice boobs, great legs, and sexy voice. me like joey lauren adams. me can take steve baldwin for few minutes. me hope pauly shore get picked up by giant bird and dropped in ocean. this a very dumb movie. no watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Frat Boys Look Smarter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm just going to come out and say it: I hate Bio-Dome and I often wondered why this stupid movie should have never been made. This movie is like a poor man's version of Dumb and Dumber, only that this movie has no comedy. First, the main heroes are nothing but a couple of idiots. They make Harry and Lloyd from Dumb and Dumber look like Albert Einstein and Alexander Graham Bell. They even make Bill and Ted from Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure look like Thomas Edison and Benjamin Franklin! Every time these two numb nuts talk, I feel like I'm getting my head shoved in a pile of horse diarrhea. What, were these guys dropped on their heads when they were babies? Second, the jokes are never funny. One joke involves a mom trying to drown her kid as an excuse for teaching her kid how to breath under water for a long time. Another one involves the two morons sexually violating two girls. And then there's yet another scene where a clown gets shot in broad daylight. I'm sorry, were any of these jokes supposed to be funny? OF COURSE NOT!! You're killing comedy movie! You're a comedy killer! You're a... comecidal(That's a word combining comedy with homicidal) maniac! Like North, Kazaam, The Super Mario Bros Movie, and the Titanic Animated Trilogy, every scene is so cringe-inducing, so heartless, so disgusting, and so idiotic that it makes me feel uncleaned as I watched it. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go take a shower because I feel dirty after watching this giant-sized brain tumor that is Bio-Dome.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bio-Dumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Buttongoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching the film "Bio-Dome" you feel much better about your intelligence. The major flaws with the film including the fact that the two main characters* never become serious. The film's jokes were corny and overused, and nearly every thing the characters would do were just eye-rollers rather than laughs. The dialogue was rather corny and I did manage to chuckle when one of the characters said "we need to save the bio-dome". I recommend after watching this movie, to watch an Oscar-winning movie so this garbage can be cleared from your mind. I give this movie a 2.4, because in order to receive a 1, the film must have horrible editing or be a disgusting porno. (Side notes:) *I have no desire to respect this film and it's character's names.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Sherman tank.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bud and Doyle are two losers who are doing nothing with their lives. Both of their girlfriends are actively involved in saving the environment, but the two friends could care less about saving the Earth. One day, when a group of scientists begin a mission to live inside a "Bio-Dome" for a year without outside contact, Bud and Doyle mistakingly become part of the project themselves. The two must then learn how to protect the Earth and help the scientists complete their mission.... First off, if you're not a fan of Pauly Shore, stop reading and do something else. I like Shore and his movies, they do their job and provide entertainment and are never boring, no matter how moronic they appear to be. This was one reason for me to watch this movie, the second was to see the biggest career nosedive in recent memory. Hello Stephen Baldwin. One minute, your in an Oscar winning movie, next your Playing Garth to Shores Wayne. It's silly stuff, but it's never boring and it's heart is in the right place. Shore seems to be having a whale of a time, which shows he loves his work, just like Sandler. The biggest surprise in this movie is that the guy you think will be a sleaze (Atherton, who clearly is in Ghostbusters and Die Hard 1&2) is quite lenient with the pair for the majority of the movie, which is good, because it has some originality to it. But all in all, it's a dumb movie, offering nothing new into the stoner buddy comedy, but it has some charm to it, and the cast have great chemistry and there is a message to all of this. it's never dull like a lot of comedies, but it's not for everyones taste. If you like a good 'bad' movie, you could do a lot 'worse'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A grade mindless movie power!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spaceboystevie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is all you can expect from a film staring Pauly Shore and has everything you would want from a movie that was created to be watched with beer, pizza and mates. The acting, plot and script are miles from decent, but are more than adequate for a film of this style. Lets face it you don't want to watch high brow, intellectually stimulating films every night. Some times it's good to put on a movie you don't need to concentrate on, have fun chatting to friends, have a drink and say "aaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhh" every time someone makes a joke about sex. The Godfather this is not, but a film to put on when you are not in the mood for thinking and fancy a chuckle, few do it better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh my!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    searchingcirclesend
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love this movie as a kid, and now I have no idea why. Maybe it's because, at the age of 10, I enjoyed watching grown men act younger than me. Look back on your own childhood and you likely enjoyed a few movies with that quality for that very reason. There is not one funny part in this movie. Seriously, not one. I've even re-watched it stoned (let's be honest, it was probably made to be viewed that way) just to see if the altered perception would make it any better, and it actually killed my buzz. Pauly Shore and one of the Baldwins that's not Alec seem to be in a pissing contest to see who can come off as more talentless. In the end, it's too close to call, so they both win (or lose, however you wanna look at it). The only reason I gave this movie 2 stars is because I tend to throw in an extra star if there is nostalgia associated with it. If you're in the mood for this kind of movie, you'd be better off watching Encino Man, even if you've seen it already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could be used for torture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PhilipVier
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hardly gets any worse than Bio-Dome. Truly this is one of the worst films ever made, and I really hate it with all my heart. Everyone who worked on this abomination should be thrown in a concentration camp, and be experimented on for the rest of their unnatural lives. This film is supposed to be a comedy, but it's not. Not one single line of dialogue is funny, every performance is terrible, and the plot is virtually non-existent. The film revolves around two main characters, who are locked in the "Bio-Dome". They are played by Pauly Shore and Stephen Baldwin, who both do a terrible job. Their acting is beyond dreadful, their characters are complete lunatics, and not one single thing they say, or do is even remotely funny. The same goes for the other idiots who appeared in this picture. It's really a mystery to me why some people like this rubbish. It's like it was made by some sick person, who wanted to create the best torture method to be used in Guantanamo Bay. There was nothing in this film that I liked. I would rather fight Wladimir Klitschko in a bare-knuckle boxing match, than watch this piece of excrement ever again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very stupid, and not funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Carlstrom
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bio-Dome is very bad, and clich&eacute;. Actually, one of the most clich&eacute; pieces I've ever seen. Let's start at the script. The script is awful, pointing out the most obvious things, Pauly Shore just isn't bright in this film. Personally, this film has to have one of the worst scripts I think they've ever used for a film, honestly. The acting is decent, not good or bad, but decent. Some parts fell victim to bad acting, but I just feel that couldn't really be helped, ya' know? But, I didn't really like the cast, so this film is bad without me caring. The humor is just straight up, not funny. I didn't laugh once throughout, I was just thinking about all the horrible goofs, and gags they put in this film. This film wasn't funny at all. If you're looking for a comedy, this just won't cut it. And finally, the camera work. I guess the camera work is okay. It really could of been less dull, but I guess it'll pass. Overall, this films garbage. I highly recommend you stay away from this film. Bio-Dome gets a 1/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    squuuiiirreeellllyyyy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shinya Aoki
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only haters and old people review movies. I had to make an account to say that the movie didn't get worse, they just got older and forgot how to laugh at dumb things. Bio-dome is an awesome stoner comedy to watch with your friends as are all of Pauly Shore's movies. Squuuuiiirreeelllyyyyy!!!! So don't listen to all these reviews, you can even tell by how they type how lame of a person they are. It's funny all the haters come on to review movies that weren't made for them. The only reason the movie doesn't have better reviews is because people that enjoy these films are too busy out having fun with life and not writing bad things about everything they didn't enjoy online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bud and Doyle's Awful Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Two twits from Tucson," pompous Pauly Shore (as Bud Macintosh) and brain-dead Stephen Baldwin (as Doyle Johnson), have a fight with their girlfriends and go out for a drive on "Earth Day". In the Arizona desert, Mr. Baldwin needs to find a place to urinate. He is unable "cork it" outside and must use a bathroom. They stop at "Bio-Dome" thinking it is a new mall, and are trapped inside. This is an environmentally controlled facility, where five scientists are being sealed for a year. The supporting cast, sets, photography and opening credits are okay. More annoying than funny, the co-leads make you wonder how they became movie stars. ** Bio-Dome (1/12/96) Jason Bloom ~ Pauly Shore, Stephen Baldwin, William Atherton, Joey Adams
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    are you high?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    warning: this movie very dumb. pauly shore bad actor. pauly shore not actor, anyway. steve baldwin only little better than pauly shore. me only watched movie because me so bored, me had nothing else to do. me pray you will never be that bored. only good thing in movie is joey lauren adams. she hot. she have nice boobs, great legs, and sexy voice. me like joey lauren adams. me can take steve baldwin for few minutes. me hope pauly shore get picked up by giant bird and dropped in ocean. this a very dumb movie. no watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Frat Boys Look Smarter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm just going to come out and say it: I hate Bio-Dome and I often wondered why this stupid movie should have never been made. This movie is like a poor man's version of Dumb and Dumber, only that this movie has no comedy. First, the main heroes are nothing but a couple of idiots. They make Harry and Lloyd from Dumb and Dumber look like Albert Einstein and Alexander Graham Bell. They even make Bill and Ted from Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure look like Thomas Edison and Benjamin Franklin! Every time these two numb nuts talk, I feel like I'm getting my head shoved in a pile of horse diarrhea. What, were these guys dropped on their heads when they were babies? Second, the jokes are never funny. One joke involves a mom trying to drown her kid as an excuse for teaching her kid how to breath under water for a long time. Another one involves the two morons sexually violating two girls. And then there's yet another scene where a clown gets shot in broad daylight. I'm sorry, were any of these jokes supposed to be funny? OF COURSE NOT!! You're killing comedy movie! You're a comedy killer! You're a... comecidal(That's a word combining comedy with homicidal) maniac! Like North, Kazaam, The Super Mario Bros Movie, and the Titanic Animated Trilogy, every scene is so cringe-inducing, so heartless, so disgusting, and so idiotic that it makes me feel uncleaned as I watched it. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go take a shower because I feel dirty after watching this giant-sized brain tumor that is Bio-Dome.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bio-Dumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Buttongoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching the film "Bio-Dome" you feel much better about your intelligence. The major flaws with the film including the fact that the two main characters* never become serious. The film's jokes were corny and overused, and nearly every thing the characters would do were just eye-rollers rather than laughs. The dialogue was rather corny and I did manage to chuckle when one of the characters said "we need to save the bio-dome". I recommend after watching this movie, to watch an Oscar-winning movie so this garbage can be cleared from your mind. I give this movie a 2.4, because in order to receive a 1, the film must have horrible editing or be a disgusting porno. (Side notes:) *I have no desire to respect this film and it's character's names.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Sherman tank.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bud and Doyle are two losers who are doing nothing with their lives. Both of their girlfriends are actively involved in saving the environment, but the two friends could care less about saving the Earth. One day, when a group of scientists begin a mission to live inside a "Bio-Dome" for a year without outside contact, Bud and Doyle mistakingly become part of the project themselves. The two must then learn how to protect the Earth and help the scientists complete their mission.... First off, if you're not a fan of Pauly Shore, stop reading and do something else. I like Shore and his movies, they do their job and provide entertainment and are never boring, no matter how moronic they appear to be. This was one reason for me to watch this movie, the second was to see the biggest career nosedive in recent memory. Hello Stephen Baldwin. One minute, your in an Oscar winning movie, next your Playing Garth to Shores Wayne. It's silly stuff, but it's never boring and it's heart is in the right place. Shore seems to be having a whale of a time, which shows he loves his work, just like Sandler. The biggest surprise in this movie is that the guy you think will be a sleaze (Atherton, who clearly is in Ghostbusters and Die Hard 1&2) is quite lenient with the pair for the majority of the movie, which is good, because it has some originality to it. But all in all, it's a dumb movie, offering nothing new into the stoner buddy comedy, but it has some charm to it, and the cast have great chemistry and there is a message to all of this. it's never dull like a lot of comedies, but it's not for everyones taste. If you like a good 'bad' movie, you could do a lot 'worse'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A grade mindless movie power!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spaceboystevie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is all you can expect from a film staring Pauly Shore and has everything you would want from a movie that was created to be watched with beer, pizza and mates. The acting, plot and script are miles from decent, but are more than adequate for a film of this style. Lets face it you don't want to watch high brow, intellectually stimulating films every night. Some times it's good to put on a movie you don't need to concentrate on, have fun chatting to friends, have a drink and say "aaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhh" every time someone makes a joke about sex. The Godfather this is not, but a film to put on when you are not in the mood for thinking and fancy a chuckle, few do it better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh my!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    searchingcirclesend
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love this movie as a kid, and now I have no idea why. Maybe it's because, at the age of 10, I enjoyed watching grown men act younger than me. Look back on your own childhood and you likely enjoyed a few movies with that quality for that very reason. There is not one funny part in this movie. Seriously, not one. I've even re-watched it stoned (let's be honest, it was probably made to be viewed that way) just to see if the altered perception would make it any better, and it actually killed my buzz. Pauly Shore and one of the Baldwins that's not Alec seem to be in a pissing contest to see who can come off as more talentless. In the end, it's too close to call, so they both win (or lose, however you wanna look at it). The only reason I gave this movie 2 stars is because I tend to throw in an extra star if there is nostalgia associated with it. If you're in the mood for this kind of movie, you'd be better off watching Encino Man, even if you've seen it already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could be used for torture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PhilipVier
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hardly gets any worse than Bio-Dome. Truly this is one of the worst films ever made, and I really hate it with all my heart. Everyone who worked on this abomination should be thrown in a concentration camp, and be experimented on for the rest of their unnatural lives. This film is supposed to be a comedy, but it's not. Not one single line of dialogue is funny, every performance is terrible, and the plot is virtually non-existent. The film revolves around two main characters, who are locked in the "Bio-Dome". They are played by Pauly Shore and Stephen Baldwin, who both do a terrible job. Their acting is beyond dreadful, their characters are complete lunatics, and not one single thing they say, or do is even remotely funny. The same goes for the other idiots who appeared in this picture. It's really a mystery to me why some people like this rubbish. It's like it was made by some sick person, who wanted to create the best torture method to be used in Guantanamo Bay. There was nothing in this film that I liked. I would rather fight Wladimir Klitschko in a bare-knuckle boxing match, than watch this piece of excrement ever again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very stupid, and not funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Carlstrom
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bio-Dome is very bad, and clich&eacute;. Actually, one of the most clich&eacute; pieces I've ever seen. Let's start at the script. The script is awful, pointing out the most obvious things, Pauly Shore just isn't bright in this film. Personally, this film has to have one of the worst scripts I think they've ever used for a film, honestly. The acting is decent, not good or bad, but decent. Some parts fell victim to bad acting, but I just feel that couldn't really be helped, ya' know? But, I didn't really like the cast, so this film is bad without me caring. The humor is just straight up, not funny. I didn't laugh once throughout, I was just thinking about all the horrible goofs, and gags they put in this film. This film wasn't funny at all. If you're looking for a comedy, this just won't cut it. And finally, the camera work. I guess the camera work is okay. It really could of been less dull, but I guess it'll pass. Overall, this films garbage. I highly recommend you stay away from this film. Bio-Dome gets a 1/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    squuuiiirreeellllyyyy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shinya Aoki
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only haters and old people review movies. I had to make an account to say that the movie didn't get worse, they just got older and forgot how to laugh at dumb things. Bio-dome is an awesome stoner comedy to watch with your friends as are all of Pauly Shore's movies. Squuuuiiirreeelllyyyyy!!!! So don't listen to all these reviews, you can even tell by how they type how lame of a person they are. It's funny all the haters come on to review movies that weren't made for them. The only reason the movie doesn't have better reviews is because people that enjoy these films are too busy out having fun with life and not writing bad things about everything they didn't enjoy online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bud and Doyle's Awful Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Two twits from Tucson," pompous Pauly Shore (as Bud Macintosh) and brain-dead Stephen Baldwin (as Doyle Johnson), have a fight with their girlfriends and go out for a drive on "Earth Day". In the Arizona desert, Mr. Baldwin needs to find a place to urinate. He is unable "cork it" outside and must use a bathroom. They stop at "Bio-Dome" thinking it is a new mall, and are trapped inside. This is an environmentally controlled facility, where five scientists are being sealed for a year. The supporting cast, sets, photography and opening credits are okay. More annoying than funny, the co-leads make you wonder how they became movie stars. ** Bio-Dome (1/12/96) Jason Bloom ~ Pauly Shore, Stephen Baldwin, William Atherton, Joey Adams
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    are you high?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    warning: this movie very dumb. pauly shore bad actor. pauly shore not actor, anyway. steve baldwin only little better than pauly shore. me only watched movie because me so bored, me had nothing else to do. me pray you will never be that bored. only good thing in movie is joey lauren adams. she hot. she have nice boobs, great legs, and sexy voice. me like joey lauren adams. me can take steve baldwin for few minutes. me hope pauly shore get picked up by giant bird and dropped in ocean. this a very dumb movie. no watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Frat Boys Look Smarter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm just going to come out and say it: I hate Bio-Dome and I often wondered why this stupid movie should have never been made. This movie is like a poor man's version of Dumb and Dumber, only that this movie has no comedy. First, the main heroes are nothing but a couple of idiots. They make Harry and Lloyd from Dumb and Dumber look like Albert Einstein and Alexander Graham Bell. They even make Bill and Ted from Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure look like Thomas Edison and Benjamin Franklin! Every time these two numb nuts talk, I feel like I'm getting my head shoved in a pile of horse diarrhea. What, were these guys dropped on their heads when they were babies? Second, the jokes are never funny. One joke involves a mom trying to drown her kid as an excuse for teaching her kid how to breath under water for a long time. Another one involves the two morons sexually violating two girls. And then there's yet another scene where a clown gets shot in broad daylight. I'm sorry, were any of these jokes supposed to be funny? OF COURSE NOT!! You're killing comedy movie! You're a comedy killer! You're a... comecidal(That's a word combining comedy with homicidal) maniac! Like North, Kazaam, The Super Mario Bros Movie, and the Titanic Animated Trilogy, every scene is so cringe-inducing, so heartless, so disgusting, and so idiotic that it makes me feel uncleaned as I watched it. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go take a shower because I feel dirty after watching this giant-sized brain tumor that is Bio-Dome.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bio-Dumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Buttongoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching the film "Bio-Dome" you feel much better about your intelligence. The major flaws with the film including the fact that the two main characters* never become serious. The film's jokes were corny and overused, and nearly every thing the characters would do were just eye-rollers rather than laughs. The dialogue was rather corny and I did manage to chuckle when one of the characters said "we need to save the bio-dome". I recommend after watching this movie, to watch an Oscar-winning movie so this garbage can be cleared from your mind. I give this movie a 2.4, because in order to receive a 1, the film must have horrible editing or be a disgusting porno. (Side notes:) *I have no desire to respect this film and it's character's names.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Sherman tank.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bud and Doyle are two losers who are doing nothing with their lives. Both of their girlfriends are actively involved in saving the environment, but the two friends could care less about saving the Earth. One day, when a group of scientists begin a mission to live inside a "Bio-Dome" for a year without outside contact, Bud and Doyle mistakingly become part of the project themselves. The two must then learn how to protect the Earth and help the scientists complete their mission.... First off, if you're not a fan of Pauly Shore, stop reading and do something else. I like Shore and his movies, they do their job and provide entertainment and are never boring, no matter how moronic they appear to be. This was one reason for me to watch this movie, the second was to see the biggest career nosedive in recent memory. Hello Stephen Baldwin. One minute, your in an Oscar winning movie, next your Playing Garth to Shores Wayne. It's silly stuff, but it's never boring and it's heart is in the right place. Shore seems to be having a whale of a time, which shows he loves his work, just like Sandler. The biggest surprise in this movie is that the guy you think will be a sleaze (Atherton, who clearly is in Ghostbusters and Die Hard 1&2) is quite lenient with the pair for the majority of the movie, which is good, because it has some originality to it. But all in all, it's a dumb movie, offering nothing new into the stoner buddy comedy, but it has some charm to it, and the cast have great chemistry and there is a message to all of this. it's never dull like a lot of comedies, but it's not for everyones taste. If you like a good 'bad' movie, you could do a lot 'worse'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A grade mindless movie power!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spaceboystevie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is all you can expect from a film staring Pauly Shore and has everything you would want from a movie that was created to be watched with beer, pizza and mates. The acting, plot and script are miles from decent, but are more than adequate for a film of this style. Lets face it you don't want to watch high brow, intellectually stimulating films every night. Some times it's good to put on a movie you don't need to concentrate on, have fun chatting to friends, have a drink and say "aaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhh" every time someone makes a joke about sex. The Godfather this is not, but a film to put on when you are not in the mood for thinking and fancy a chuckle, few do it better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh my!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    searchingcirclesend
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love this movie as a kid, and now I have no idea why. Maybe it's because, at the age of 10, I enjoyed watching grown men act younger than me. Look back on your own childhood and you likely enjoyed a few movies with that quality for that very reason. There is not one funny part in this movie. Seriously, not one. I've even re-watched it stoned (let's be honest, it was probably made to be viewed that way) just to see if the altered perception would make it any better, and it actually killed my buzz. Pauly Shore and one of the Baldwins that's not Alec seem to be in a pissing contest to see who can come off as more talentless. In the end, it's too close to call, so they both win (or lose, however you wanna look at it). The only reason I gave this movie 2 stars is because I tend to throw in an extra star if there is nostalgia associated with it. If you're in the mood for this kind of movie, you'd be better off watching Encino Man, even if you've seen it already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could be used for torture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PhilipVier
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It hardly gets any worse than Bio-Dome. Truly this is one of the worst films ever made, and I really hate it with all my heart. Everyone who worked on this abomination should be thrown in a concentration camp, and be experimented on for the rest of their unnatural lives. This film is supposed to be a comedy, but it's not. Not one single line of dialogue is funny, every performance is terrible, and the plot is virtually non-existent. The film revolves around two main characters, who are locked in the "Bio-Dome". They are played by Pauly Shore and Stephen Baldwin, who both do a terrible job. Their acting is beyond dreadful, their characters are complete lunatics, and not one single thing they say, or do is even remotely funny. The same goes for the other idiots who appeared in this picture. It's really a mystery to me why some people like this rubbish. It's like it was made by some sick person, who wanted to create the best torture method to be used in Guantanamo Bay. There was nothing in this film that I liked. I would rather fight Wladimir Klitschko in a bare-knuckle boxing match, than watch this piece of excrement ever again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very stupid, and not funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Carlstrom
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bio-Dome is very bad, and clich&eacute;. Actually, one of the most clich&eacute; pieces I've ever seen. Let's start at the script. The script is awful, pointing out the most obvious things, Pauly Shore just isn't bright in this film. Personally, this film has to have one of the worst scripts I think they've ever used for a film, honestly. The acting is decent, not good or bad, but decent. Some parts fell victim to bad acting, but I just feel that couldn't really be helped, ya' know? But, I didn't really like the cast, so this film is bad without me caring. The humor is just straight up, not funny. I didn't laugh once throughout, I was just thinking about all the horrible goofs, and gags they put in this film. This film wasn't funny at all. If you're looking for a comedy, this just won't cut it. And finally, the camera work. I guess the camera work is okay. It really could of been less dull, but I guess it'll pass. Overall, this films garbage. I highly recommend you stay away from this film. Bio-Dome gets a 1/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    squuuiiirreeellllyyyy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shinya Aoki
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only haters and old people review movies. I had to make an account to say that the movie didn't get worse, they just got older and forgot how to laugh at dumb things. Bio-dome is an awesome stoner comedy to watch with your friends as are all of Pauly Shore's movies. Squuuuiiirreeelllyyyyy!!!! So don't listen to all these reviews, you can even tell by how they type how lame of a person they are. It's funny all the haters come on to review movies that weren't made for them. The only reason the movie doesn't have better reviews is because people that enjoy these films are too busy out having fun with life and not writing bad things about everything they didn't enjoy online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bud and Doyle's Awful Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Two twits from Tucson," pompous Pauly Shore (as Bud Macintosh) and brain-dead Stephen Baldwin (as Doyle Johnson), have a fight with their girlfriends and go out for a drive on "Earth Day". In the Arizona desert, Mr. Baldwin needs to find a place to urinate. He is unable "cork it" outside and must use a bathroom. They stop at "Bio-Dome" thinking it is a new mall, and are trapped inside. This is an environmentally controlled facility, where five scientists are being sealed for a year. The supporting cast, sets, photography and opening credits are okay. More annoying than funny, the co-leads make you wonder how they became movie stars. ** Bio-Dome (1/12/96) Jason Bloom ~ Pauly Shore, Stephen Baldwin, William Atherton, Joey Adams
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    are you high?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew_Capitano
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    warning: this movie very dumb. pauly shore bad actor. pauly shore not actor, anyway. steve baldwin only little better than pauly shore. me only watched movie because me so bored, me had nothing else to do. me pray you will never be that bored. only good thing in movie is joey lauren adams. she hot. she have nice boobs, great legs, and sexy voice. me like joey lauren adams. me can take steve baldwin for few minutes. me hope pauly shore get picked up by giant bird and dropped in ocean. this a very dumb movie. no watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Frat Boys Look Smarter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    anthony-rigoni
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm just going to come out and say it: I hate Bio-Dome and I often wondered why this stupid movie should have never been made. This movie is like a poor man's version of Dumb and Dumber, only that this movie has no comedy. First, the main heroes are nothing but a couple of idiots. They make Harry and Lloyd from Dumb and Dumber look like Albert Einstein and Alexander Graham Bell. They even make Bill and Ted from Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure look like Thomas Edison and Benjamin Franklin! Every time these two numb nuts talk, I feel like I'm getting my head shoved in a pile of horse diarrhea. What, were these guys dropped on their heads when they were babies? Second, the jokes are never funny. One joke involves a mom trying to drown her kid as an excuse for teaching her kid how to breath under water for a long time. Another one involves the two morons sexually violating two girls. And then there's yet another scene where a clown gets shot in broad daylight. I'm sorry, were any of these jokes supposed to be funny? OF COURSE NOT!! You're killing comedy movie! You're a comedy killer! You're a... comecidal(That's a word combining comedy with homicidal) maniac! Like North, Kazaam, The Super Mario Bros Movie, and the Titanic Animated Trilogy, every scene is so cringe-inducing, so heartless, so disgusting, and so idiotic that it makes me feel uncleaned as I watched it. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go take a shower because I feel dirty after watching this giant-sized brain tumor that is Bio-Dome.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bio-Dumb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Buttongoo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching the film "Bio-Dome" you feel much better about your intelligence. The major flaws with the film including the fact that the two main characters* never become serious. The film's jokes were corny and overused, and nearly every thing the characters would do were just eye-rollers rather than laughs. The dialogue was rather corny and I did manage to chuckle when one of the characters said "we need to save the bio-dome". I recommend after watching this movie, to watch an Oscar-winning movie so this garbage can be cleared from your mind. I give this movie a 2.4, because in order to receive a 1, the film must have horrible editing or be a disgusting porno. (Side notes:) *I have no desire to respect this film and it's character's names.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Sherman tank.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bud and Doyle are two losers who are doing nothing with their lives. Both of their girlfriends are actively involved in saving the environment, but the two friends could care less about saving the Earth. One day, when a group of scientists begin a mission to live inside a "Bio-Dome" for a year without outside contact, Bud and Doyle mistakingly become part of the project themselves. The two must then learn how to protect the Earth and help the scientists complete their mission.... First off, if you're not a fan of Pauly Shore, stop reading and do something else. I like Shore and his movies, they do their job and provide entertainment and are never boring, no matter how moronic they appear to be. This was one reason for me to watch this movie, the second was to see the biggest career nosedive in recent memory. Hello Stephen Baldwin. One minute, your in an Oscar winning movie, next your Playing Garth to Shores Wayne. It's silly stuff, but it's never boring and it's heart is in the right place. Shore seems to be having a whale of a time, which shows he loves his work, just like Sandler. The biggest surprise in this movie is that the guy you think will be a sleaze (Atherton, who clearly is in Ghostbusters and Die Hard 1&2) is quite lenient with the pair for the majority of the movie, which is good, because it has some originality to it. But all in all, it's a dumb movie, offering nothing new into the stoner buddy comedy, but it has some charm to it, and the cast have great chemistry and there is a message to all of this. it's never dull like a lot of comedies, but it's not for everyones taste. If you like a good 'bad' movie, you could do a lot 'worse'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A grade mindless movie power!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spaceboystevie
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is all you can expect from a film staring Pauly Shore and has everything you would want from a movie that was created to be watched with beer, pizza and mates. The acting, plot and script are miles from decent, but are more than adequate for a film of this style. Lets face it you don't want to watch high brow, intellectually stimulating films every night. Some times it's good to put on a movie you don't need to concentrate on, have fun chatting to friends, have a drink and say "aaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhh" every time someone makes a joke about sex. The Godfather this is not, but a film to put on when you are not in the mood for thinking and fancy a chuckle, few do it better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh my!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    searchingcirclesend
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love this movie as a kid, and now I have no idea why. Maybe it's because, at the age of 10, I enjoyed watching grown men act younger than me. Look back on your own childhood and you likely enjoyed a few movies with that quality for that very reason. There is not one funny part in this movie. Seriously, not one. I've even re-watched it stoned (let's be honest, it was probably made to be viewed that way) just to see if the altered perception would make it any better, and it actually killed my buzz. Pauly Shore and one of the Baldwins that's not Alec seem to be in a pissing contest to see who can come off as more talentless. In the end, it's too close to call, so they both win (or lose, however you wanna look at it). The only reason I gave this movie 2 stars is because I tend to throw in an extra star if there is nostalgia associated with it. If you're in the mood for this kind of movie, you'd be better off watching Encino Man, even if you've seen it already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
