<filme>
 <id>
  370
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117002
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Segredo de Mary Reilly
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A housemaid falls in love with Dr. Jekyll and his darkly mysterious counterpart, Mr. Hyde.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  We are somewhere in England in the 19th century. A Pretty housemaid works in a nice house, which is Dr. Jekyll's house. Mary Reilly think she found her best job, because she is poor and the doctor is well-known and rich. The film tells the 'Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde' story as a woman sees the two men, one of them is good and the other is evil. And she loves them ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   housemaid
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   19th century
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   servant
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   prostitution
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   split personality
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Stephen Frears
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Valerie Martin
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Christopher Hampton
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Julia Roberts
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Malkovich
  </ator>
  <ator>
   George Cole
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Next up, The Time Machine told from the perspective of the traveller's postman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here's the tale of a scientist who descends into madness when a potion he creates splits his personality in two, told from the point of view of... his maid. What a strange choice. The movie is less interested in Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde than the woman who brings him his tea. Well, okay. Amongst the film's other misjudged elements are Julia Roberts' absolutely appalling Irish accent ('Ah, ye banged yer heed') and approximately nine hours worth of her looking sullen and hearing mysterious goings on. It's a boring film, drab and dreary. Glenn Close turns in a truly bizarre performance as a madam and John Malkovich is well cast as the-- I was about to say as the title character, herp derp  but they can't liven this thing up when the most interesting parts of the story are on the outskirts of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    correct work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    recreation of Victorian atmosphere. version of old story. inspired cast. ivory skin of central character. and John Malkovich. a film like a visit in museum. each piece on perfect place, each step as key for a treasure. strange flavor, cold touch. and air of love story. maybe, it is not convincing. but it is beautiful. and delicate like a silk butterfly. it is not very realistic but charm of each performance is necessary brick for a not really bad building. it is a kind of travel and fascination of viewer is secret satisfaction to know the truth at beginning. sure, Julia Roberts is not extraordinary but her work is correct. and this fact is important. like sign of a meeting between two fascinating actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The true horror is being forced to sit through this mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bults-356-93740
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to begin... How about the bland scenery? Bricks, fog, doors, fog, even the garden feels bland and lifeless. How about the so called "character study"? Well after watching this we now know that Mary is a ditz who makes Christine Daae look like Margarate Thatcher. We also know that she's (Spoiler!!! well... sort of) afraid of rats, and that her father was an absolute prick. Oh you wanted to know about Jekyll and Hyde's character? HA! You never learn anything you didn't already know about them other than their love of spouting exposition and "shocking" the audience with unexplained violence seemingly without any clear motive. In short, this movie will do its very best to "shock" and "scare" you but will ultimately only manage to disgust you. The only redeeming qualities are the impressive (but really very silly) transformation scene, one good jump scare, and laughing at Julia Roberts' "Irish" accent. Otherwise, this is an unrelentingly unpleasant movie that will leave you feeling empty. You will take NOTHING from this film, quite the contrary, it feels like it's taken something from you! Bottom line, don't watch this sick, poorly slapped together, bloody mess of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dr. Good and Mr.Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Mary Reilly, is the tale about good and evil. And how the two tore apart the soul of one man,driving him to madness.This man was a doctor by day and a killer by night.He was a healer of man loved by all who knew him.And at night he was someone that was feared by all that he meant a long the streets.He would have black outs and could not remember what he did at all.He killed many people, got away with it for a long time because; his other half would hide him in the darkness of his mind. Julia Roberts (aka Mary Reilly) played the part very well. I loved this movie because,I feel torn between my good and bad half.We all have times when we feel this way. But there are some people that do not know the difference between the two.The story Mary Reilly was Written by Valerie Martin.The other name for this dark tale is Dr.Jekyll and Mr.Hyde. By Robert Louis Stevenson. This is my mom's take on this tale of good vs evil, within ones self! mine is the two worked well together , in this dark thriller. John Malkovich , portrayed both characters equally well ! He really made me believe he had two totally different personalities. He was that convincing, I too loved this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody re-telling of Dr. Jeckyl story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Critics and audiences were bored with this remake of the Dr. Jeckyl tale when it first came out, but there is nonetheless a lot here to like. The viewpoint shift, allowing viewers to watch the familiar tale play out from the perspective of a serving woman in the Doctor's household, gives both a romantic edge to the picture and makes points about the place and role of women/servants in English society in Jeckyl's day. Roberts is very good as the lowest member of the household staff, trying to hold the Doctor himself and the household together while at the same time striving not to get above her station. And the grim, nearly black-and-white, dread-filled landscape of the picture is great to look at and memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An undiscovered gem which Julia shines in.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jimmy Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I initially came across this film when I found out it was at one stage planned to be a Winona Ryder/Tim Burton vehicle, and I have to sat I was so impressed by it that it is now one of my favorite films. With a bit of research I got the idea that this was a bad stage in Julias career, but I have to say I have never seen her better than she is in this. Her performance is just astounding, she has thus innocence and vulnerability that I never thought I'd see coming from her, she embodies the character extremely well, so well that it would have been a crime to see anyone else in the role. John Malkovich ramps up the creepy factor in this movie, his performance is also just stellar, he is truly terrifying in the scenes where he is Jekyll. Another thing I like is that this is such a great retelling of the Jekyll/ Hyde story, it's the best one I've ever seen, I think one big advantage it has is that its told from an onlookers perspective and not from an unknown or first person perspective. The cinematography is wonderful, the constant shade of grey and the overlying layer of fog both help to create the dark and moody atmosphere. I think it's definitely a movie fans of the story would enjoy and also people who aren't so familiar with it. Top notch Gothic horror that deserves to be seen....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The woman who loved Dr.Jekyll
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** Somewhat altered version of the Robert Louis Stevenson classic "Doctor Jekyll and Mister Hyde" with the sweet kindly and understanding Doctor Jekyll, John Malkovich, having a love interest who's a housemaid Mary Reilly, Julia Roberts, at his London home where her conducts his secrets experiments. Mary had a hard life with her being abused both psychically and mentally by her drunken father Mr. Reilly, Michael Gambon, that she in fact feels that's her lot in life and can do nothing about it. It's working at Dr.Henry Jekyll place that for the first time in her life Mary finds kindness and understanding for her many problems that includes the scars that her father gave her, like having rats chew at her, while she was a child. The fact that Dr.Jekyll takes such an interest in Mary has her boss the manager of the Jekyll house Mr. Poole, George Cole, get a bit jealous at her for his master, Dr.Jekyll, spending far more time with Mary then with him. Mary for her part is a bit perplexed of Dr.Jekyll in his going in and out of his both house and laboratory all hours of the night as if he's hiding something that he doesn't want anyone to find out about! It's one day when Dr.Jekyll sends Mary on a errand to a cat-house in the red light district in the seedy part of London that she realizes that the good doctor is up to no good. Not that he's a customer of the place but that his special assistant at his laboratory someone named Edward Hyde has made a mess of the place,by brutalizing the hookers, every time he goes there. Mary is told by the angry cat-house Madam Mrs. Farraday, Glenn Close, that Eddie or Mr. Hyde has gotten out of hand and she can't keep covering up for him anymore. Dr.Jekyll in trying to smooth things out by giving her payoff money, so she doesn't report Eddie to the police, also asks Mrs. Farraday, through Mary, to drop in and see him at his laboratory to talk things over! As it turns out Mrs. Farraday is met at the house not by Dr. Jekyll but Mister Hyde who ends up doing her in by making her at least a head shorter! ***SPOILERS*** AS we and Mary Reilly soon find out that he mysterious Edward Hyde is really Doctor Jekyll in the flesh. The doc had been having splitting headaches of late and developed this medication for them. As things turned out the medication did stop the headaches but it turned the genteel and civil Dr.Jekyll into the murderous and sex crazed Edward or Mister Hyde! Edward Hyde for his part took a shine to Mary and unlike his other-self Doctor Jekyll he had no trouble in him not controlling himself in his feeling for her. It's when Edward Hyde attacks and kills one of the late Madam Farrady's John's or customers at her cat or whorehouse the member of British Parliament and good friend of Dr.Jekyll Sir.Danvers Carew, Claran Hinds, that the cops or London Bobbies are called in to check things out! It's discovered that the murder weapon that Hyde killed Carew with, by bashing his skull in, was Doctor Jekyll's silver plated walking stick! ***MAJOR SPOILERS*** Doctor Jekyll now knowing that his life is doomed in that his other-self, by Mister Hyde manipulating his headache medication, has completely taken over his body and asks Mary to do what he doesn't have the guts to to in her doing him in and putting an end to this mesaghas,insanity in Yiddish, once in for all. Mary in what has to be an act of eternal love does what the doctor told her to do but in that she leaves herself open in her being in the wrong place at the wrong time, at the scene of the Sir. Danvers murder, to take the rap for the crime committed by the now departed Dr.Jekyll/Mr. Hyde and having to pay for It very possibly with her life!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I shudder to think what would have followed if this misfire had been a box office smash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film tells the story of the chambermaid who worked for Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde. Thankfully, this turgid mess bombed at the box office so we were spared sequels about Dracula's chauffeur, Frankenstein's tax attorney and the Wolfman's proctologist. Mary Reilly (Julia Roberts) works as a maid for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich) in 19th century London. I kid you not when I state that this movie essentially follows Mary around while she does her household chores and every so often we get a scene that peeks in on the classic tale of Jekyll and Hyde. If you don't know what that story's about, go down to the damn library and check out the book or watch one of the 37,000,000,000 other versions of the tale that have been committed to film. Basically, this thing is a Cliff's Notes version of Jekyll and Hyde, crossed with a documentary on the brutal drudgery of 19th century working class Britons, mixed with a Lifetime movie about a woman overcoming her memories of fatherly abuse. The heart of Mary Reilly is supposed to be about the attraction Mary feels for both Jekyll and Hyde and the affection they feel in return. A big problem is that it's hard to believe any man being lovestruck by this pale-faced woman with Conan O'Brien eyebrows. Julia Roberts is deliberately stripped of most of the beauty artifice that props up her appearance in other films and the audience is undeniably confronted with the fact that Roberts is not that pretty. She has very distinct features that need to be accommodated on screen and that doesn't happen here. Another defining negative about this film is very poor acting jobs by three big stars. Roberts intermittently adopts an Irish accent that rivals Kevin Costner's dialect in Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves for its "now you hear it, now you don't" quality. John Malkovich does worse than sleepwalk through his double role, even giving Edward Hyde an extremely pronounced limp early in the film which completely disappears later on. Either Malkovich and director Stephen Frears both forgot about the limp or Malkovich just got tired of doing it and Frears couldn't make him. Glenn Close is almost as bad as the owner of a London brothel. Her entire performance consists of giving her character an Elvis lip curl. The bottom line is that Mary Reilly is a movie about an uninteresting woman who stands still while an amazing story happens around her. The idea of telling a famous tale from the perspective of a minor character isn't a bad one. A movie about the London cop trying to track down and capture Edward Hyde sounds good to me. The trick is the minor character actually has to do something important in the story. Mary Reilly simply hovers and watches like the boring person on a reality show. Unless you're dying to view YET ANOTHER crappy adaptation of Jekyll and Hyde, skip this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawed period thriller is worth watching for the two lead performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An pretty but shy, depressed and lonely housemaid by the name of Mary Reilly (Oscar-Winner:Julia Roberts) works for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich). When Dr. Jekyll is working on a experiment, he tells his staff (George Cole, Michael Sheen, Kathy Staff and Bronagh Gallagher) and Mary that he will have an assistant working with him. But the stuff never fully sees him and remains an mystery. But when Mary gets closer to Dr. Jekyll talking about her awful childhood to him, begin abused by her drunken mean-spirited father (Michael Gambon). Mary finds herself slowly falling in love with Dr. Jekyll but soon discovers that Dr. Jekyll has an dark side and his mysterious assistant might be related to him. Directed by Stephen Frears (The Grifters, Hero, The Hours) made an very flawed but intriguing period suspense thriller with good performances by Roberts and Malkovich. The bleak setting is nicely done by production designer:Staurt Craig (The Harry Potter Series, Chaplin, The Secret Garden) and Glenn Close has fun in her minor role as a madam. Although there was trouble during production, because Roberts and Malkovich didn't get along. The film was also over budgeted and problems with Christopher Hampton's (Atonement, The Secret Agent, Total Eclipse) script. "Mary Reilly" ended up being re-shot in the end, despite it was an reunion from the Cast and Crew of "Dangerous Liaisions" for director:Frears, screenwriter:Hampton, actors:Malkovich & Close, producer:Norma Heyman, composer:George Fenton, cinematographer:Philippe Rousselot, production designer:Craig and casting director:Juliet Taylor. "Mary Reilly" does have an minor cult following, some might complain that Roberts was mis-cast but i thought she did well with his performance (Which she smiled only once in the film). One of the highlights is towards the end with Dr. Jekyll's character. Although watching the movie, it does look like at times, the movie had an troubled production. It's very flawed at times but it's Malkovich's fascinating performance keeps it together. Despite all the movie faults, it is still worth a look. Based on a novel by Valerie Martin.(*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What do I like about this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like the fact that the film is told from Mary Reilly's point of view. Not only hers, but everyone else's too, like the naive servants, the furious Mrs. Faraday (the brothel mistress). Mary Reilly - the character - also has a disturbing, traumatizing background story and at some point Mr. Hyde gives a pretty heavy psychological spin on it. It's never elaborated on or seems ignored even, but this suits the tone of the film. Insinuating things often hits harder than explaining them. Through some of the characters, some of the possible little script flaws (or plot holes) get solved. For instance, doesn't anybody notice that Dr. Jekyll and his assistant Mr. Hyde look very much alike? Only Hyde looks younger. Sure people notice this, but one of the servants goes about assuming that Mr. Hyde might very well be a product of Jekyll's student days. As a bright student, Jekyll was popular with the ladies. And since Jekyll never got married, if he would have had a son... in those days it was even a sin to merely speak about or suggest a thing like this. I like John Malkovich's performance a lot and it's clear that him & Stephen Frears both understood very well what they wanted to achieve here. The good doc Jekyll (whom is looked upon in high regards by his servants) is far from kosher to the bone himself (we get hints at how he conducts his research and we know he's a regular client at Mrs. Faraday's house of pleasure). While on the other hand, Mr. Hyde as the savage beast, has his scarce moments of weakness for Mary Reilly. See what I'm getting at? And when looking at it from Mary's side, she unwillingly brings out the worst in the best, and the best in the worst, so to speak. Frears & Malkovich and screenwriter Christopher Hampton added shades of gray to a classic, one too many times told story that is basically just about black & white. The film got me really interested in reading the source novel it was based on. To see how it compares the film. What else is there to like? Enough, I think. Phillipe Rousselot's wonderful cinematography. A captivating musical score by George Stenton. As much as it's a character-driven story, it does feature a handful moments of the grotesque. Glenn Close gets decapitated. Dr. Jekyll is seen on the street repeatedly kicking a little girl in the stomach. An engrossing scene that shows how slaughtered meat for consumption is being traded in the streets, followed by an analogy towards the trade of human organs for the sake of science. Not sure whom all were responsible for these sequences -- I understand that Frears, for example, never intended the film to end like it did, with that climactic transformation sequence. But said sequences are a graphic reminder of the fact that we are watching a horrific story. At any rate, I didn't think they hurt the film. They injected it with the necessary dosage of brutality. The set design is marvelous and Dr. Jekyll's laboratory - or at least the way of getting there - is cleverly structured (as it helps crafting the suspense of a certain scene in a brilliant manner). The 19th century London setting works convincing, but we don't get to see much of it. The blocking & framing makes sure we usually only see one part of a street at a time. And to add to this claustrophobic & dark notion this film has, most scenes take place on indoors sets. But also these sets are put to great use. To Mary Reilly, the doctor's mansion starts off as a safe haven, a place offering a good job and a possible better future. But it doesn't take long for this house to get infested with the evil of Mr. Hyde's presence at night. So much even, that it starts to haunt her dreams. This shift in tone happens gradually, with a slow but impeccable pace. Truth be told, to me Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde always seemed a very simplistic story to tell. At least in the classic version as it got famous. It's good source material, yes, but Frears & Hampton managed to squeeze a much more interesting film out of it. Which probably could have even been a lot better if the producing studio at the time wasn't so concerned about how it would do at the box office. Voil&agrave;, that's it for what I like about this film. Notice that I didn't mention Julia Roberts' performance. It's very down-toned, as it should be. She is there not to be noticed, her character demands it and so does the story. And while she does have a lot of screen time, she doesn't do much, so there's just not much to say about her acting. But you can always 'see' the wheels of her character's thoughts grinding, as she is the only one who's trying to fathom what's going on. From all the servants, she's the only one that knows how to read. Dr. Jekyll discovers this very early on, when he spots her reading a book in his library. This, of course, titillates the good doc's mind. And that's the point in the film, as soon as it comes, where you instantly realize this is going to take a turn for the worse. In that moment, there's a harmless thing between them that will inevitably unleash unspeakable horrors. And this 'harmless thing' even is personified throughout the whole film. It goes by the name of Mary Reilly. A very interesting adaptation. And a good film, full stop.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Next up, The Time Machine told from the perspective of the traveller's postman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here's the tale of a scientist who descends into madness when a potion he creates splits his personality in two, told from the point of view of... his maid. What a strange choice. The movie is less interested in Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde than the woman who brings him his tea. Well, okay. Amongst the film's other misjudged elements are Julia Roberts' absolutely appalling Irish accent ('Ah, ye banged yer heed') and approximately nine hours worth of her looking sullen and hearing mysterious goings on. It's a boring film, drab and dreary. Glenn Close turns in a truly bizarre performance as a madam and John Malkovich is well cast as the-- I was about to say as the title character, herp derp  but they can't liven this thing up when the most interesting parts of the story are on the outskirts of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    correct work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    recreation of Victorian atmosphere. version of old story. inspired cast. ivory skin of central character. and John Malkovich. a film like a visit in museum. each piece on perfect place, each step as key for a treasure. strange flavor, cold touch. and air of love story. maybe, it is not convincing. but it is beautiful. and delicate like a silk butterfly. it is not very realistic but charm of each performance is necessary brick for a not really bad building. it is a kind of travel and fascination of viewer is secret satisfaction to know the truth at beginning. sure, Julia Roberts is not extraordinary but her work is correct. and this fact is important. like sign of a meeting between two fascinating actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The true horror is being forced to sit through this mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bults-356-93740
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to begin... How about the bland scenery? Bricks, fog, doors, fog, even the garden feels bland and lifeless. How about the so called "character study"? Well after watching this we now know that Mary is a ditz who makes Christine Daae look like Margarate Thatcher. We also know that she's (Spoiler!!! well... sort of) afraid of rats, and that her father was an absolute prick. Oh you wanted to know about Jekyll and Hyde's character? HA! You never learn anything you didn't already know about them other than their love of spouting exposition and "shocking" the audience with unexplained violence seemingly without any clear motive. In short, this movie will do its very best to "shock" and "scare" you but will ultimately only manage to disgust you. The only redeeming qualities are the impressive (but really very silly) transformation scene, one good jump scare, and laughing at Julia Roberts' "Irish" accent. Otherwise, this is an unrelentingly unpleasant movie that will leave you feeling empty. You will take NOTHING from this film, quite the contrary, it feels like it's taken something from you! Bottom line, don't watch this sick, poorly slapped together, bloody mess of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dr. Good and Mr.Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Mary Reilly, is the tale about good and evil. And how the two tore apart the soul of one man,driving him to madness.This man was a doctor by day and a killer by night.He was a healer of man loved by all who knew him.And at night he was someone that was feared by all that he meant a long the streets.He would have black outs and could not remember what he did at all.He killed many people, got away with it for a long time because; his other half would hide him in the darkness of his mind. Julia Roberts (aka Mary Reilly) played the part very well. I loved this movie because,I feel torn between my good and bad half.We all have times when we feel this way. But there are some people that do not know the difference between the two.The story Mary Reilly was Written by Valerie Martin.The other name for this dark tale is Dr.Jekyll and Mr.Hyde. By Robert Louis Stevenson. This is my mom's take on this tale of good vs evil, within ones self! mine is the two worked well together , in this dark thriller. John Malkovich , portrayed both characters equally well ! He really made me believe he had two totally different personalities. He was that convincing, I too loved this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody re-telling of Dr. Jeckyl story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Critics and audiences were bored with this remake of the Dr. Jeckyl tale when it first came out, but there is nonetheless a lot here to like. The viewpoint shift, allowing viewers to watch the familiar tale play out from the perspective of a serving woman in the Doctor's household, gives both a romantic edge to the picture and makes points about the place and role of women/servants in English society in Jeckyl's day. Roberts is very good as the lowest member of the household staff, trying to hold the Doctor himself and the household together while at the same time striving not to get above her station. And the grim, nearly black-and-white, dread-filled landscape of the picture is great to look at and memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An undiscovered gem which Julia shines in.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jimmy Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I initially came across this film when I found out it was at one stage planned to be a Winona Ryder/Tim Burton vehicle, and I have to sat I was so impressed by it that it is now one of my favorite films. With a bit of research I got the idea that this was a bad stage in Julias career, but I have to say I have never seen her better than she is in this. Her performance is just astounding, she has thus innocence and vulnerability that I never thought I'd see coming from her, she embodies the character extremely well, so well that it would have been a crime to see anyone else in the role. John Malkovich ramps up the creepy factor in this movie, his performance is also just stellar, he is truly terrifying in the scenes where he is Jekyll. Another thing I like is that this is such a great retelling of the Jekyll/ Hyde story, it's the best one I've ever seen, I think one big advantage it has is that its told from an onlookers perspective and not from an unknown or first person perspective. The cinematography is wonderful, the constant shade of grey and the overlying layer of fog both help to create the dark and moody atmosphere. I think it's definitely a movie fans of the story would enjoy and also people who aren't so familiar with it. Top notch Gothic horror that deserves to be seen....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The woman who loved Dr.Jekyll
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** Somewhat altered version of the Robert Louis Stevenson classic "Doctor Jekyll and Mister Hyde" with the sweet kindly and understanding Doctor Jekyll, John Malkovich, having a love interest who's a housemaid Mary Reilly, Julia Roberts, at his London home where her conducts his secrets experiments. Mary had a hard life with her being abused both psychically and mentally by her drunken father Mr. Reilly, Michael Gambon, that she in fact feels that's her lot in life and can do nothing about it. It's working at Dr.Henry Jekyll place that for the first time in her life Mary finds kindness and understanding for her many problems that includes the scars that her father gave her, like having rats chew at her, while she was a child. The fact that Dr.Jekyll takes such an interest in Mary has her boss the manager of the Jekyll house Mr. Poole, George Cole, get a bit jealous at her for his master, Dr.Jekyll, spending far more time with Mary then with him. Mary for her part is a bit perplexed of Dr.Jekyll in his going in and out of his both house and laboratory all hours of the night as if he's hiding something that he doesn't want anyone to find out about! It's one day when Dr.Jekyll sends Mary on a errand to a cat-house in the red light district in the seedy part of London that she realizes that the good doctor is up to no good. Not that he's a customer of the place but that his special assistant at his laboratory someone named Edward Hyde has made a mess of the place,by brutalizing the hookers, every time he goes there. Mary is told by the angry cat-house Madam Mrs. Farraday, Glenn Close, that Eddie or Mr. Hyde has gotten out of hand and she can't keep covering up for him anymore. Dr.Jekyll in trying to smooth things out by giving her payoff money, so she doesn't report Eddie to the police, also asks Mrs. Farraday, through Mary, to drop in and see him at his laboratory to talk things over! As it turns out Mrs. Farraday is met at the house not by Dr. Jekyll but Mister Hyde who ends up doing her in by making her at least a head shorter! ***SPOILERS*** AS we and Mary Reilly soon find out that he mysterious Edward Hyde is really Doctor Jekyll in the flesh. The doc had been having splitting headaches of late and developed this medication for them. As things turned out the medication did stop the headaches but it turned the genteel and civil Dr.Jekyll into the murderous and sex crazed Edward or Mister Hyde! Edward Hyde for his part took a shine to Mary and unlike his other-self Doctor Jekyll he had no trouble in him not controlling himself in his feeling for her. It's when Edward Hyde attacks and kills one of the late Madam Farrady's John's or customers at her cat or whorehouse the member of British Parliament and good friend of Dr.Jekyll Sir.Danvers Carew, Claran Hinds, that the cops or London Bobbies are called in to check things out! It's discovered that the murder weapon that Hyde killed Carew with, by bashing his skull in, was Doctor Jekyll's silver plated walking stick! ***MAJOR SPOILERS*** Doctor Jekyll now knowing that his life is doomed in that his other-self, by Mister Hyde manipulating his headache medication, has completely taken over his body and asks Mary to do what he doesn't have the guts to to in her doing him in and putting an end to this mesaghas,insanity in Yiddish, once in for all. Mary in what has to be an act of eternal love does what the doctor told her to do but in that she leaves herself open in her being in the wrong place at the wrong time, at the scene of the Sir. Danvers murder, to take the rap for the crime committed by the now departed Dr.Jekyll/Mr. Hyde and having to pay for It very possibly with her life!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I shudder to think what would have followed if this misfire had been a box office smash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film tells the story of the chambermaid who worked for Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde. Thankfully, this turgid mess bombed at the box office so we were spared sequels about Dracula's chauffeur, Frankenstein's tax attorney and the Wolfman's proctologist. Mary Reilly (Julia Roberts) works as a maid for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich) in 19th century London. I kid you not when I state that this movie essentially follows Mary around while she does her household chores and every so often we get a scene that peeks in on the classic tale of Jekyll and Hyde. If you don't know what that story's about, go down to the damn library and check out the book or watch one of the 37,000,000,000 other versions of the tale that have been committed to film. Basically, this thing is a Cliff's Notes version of Jekyll and Hyde, crossed with a documentary on the brutal drudgery of 19th century working class Britons, mixed with a Lifetime movie about a woman overcoming her memories of fatherly abuse. The heart of Mary Reilly is supposed to be about the attraction Mary feels for both Jekyll and Hyde and the affection they feel in return. A big problem is that it's hard to believe any man being lovestruck by this pale-faced woman with Conan O'Brien eyebrows. Julia Roberts is deliberately stripped of most of the beauty artifice that props up her appearance in other films and the audience is undeniably confronted with the fact that Roberts is not that pretty. She has very distinct features that need to be accommodated on screen and that doesn't happen here. Another defining negative about this film is very poor acting jobs by three big stars. Roberts intermittently adopts an Irish accent that rivals Kevin Costner's dialect in Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves for its "now you hear it, now you don't" quality. John Malkovich does worse than sleepwalk through his double role, even giving Edward Hyde an extremely pronounced limp early in the film which completely disappears later on. Either Malkovich and director Stephen Frears both forgot about the limp or Malkovich just got tired of doing it and Frears couldn't make him. Glenn Close is almost as bad as the owner of a London brothel. Her entire performance consists of giving her character an Elvis lip curl. The bottom line is that Mary Reilly is a movie about an uninteresting woman who stands still while an amazing story happens around her. The idea of telling a famous tale from the perspective of a minor character isn't a bad one. A movie about the London cop trying to track down and capture Edward Hyde sounds good to me. The trick is the minor character actually has to do something important in the story. Mary Reilly simply hovers and watches like the boring person on a reality show. Unless you're dying to view YET ANOTHER crappy adaptation of Jekyll and Hyde, skip this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawed period thriller is worth watching for the two lead performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An pretty but shy, depressed and lonely housemaid by the name of Mary Reilly (Oscar-Winner:Julia Roberts) works for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich). When Dr. Jekyll is working on a experiment, he tells his staff (George Cole, Michael Sheen, Kathy Staff and Bronagh Gallagher) and Mary that he will have an assistant working with him. But the stuff never fully sees him and remains an mystery. But when Mary gets closer to Dr. Jekyll talking about her awful childhood to him, begin abused by her drunken mean-spirited father (Michael Gambon). Mary finds herself slowly falling in love with Dr. Jekyll but soon discovers that Dr. Jekyll has an dark side and his mysterious assistant might be related to him. Directed by Stephen Frears (The Grifters, Hero, The Hours) made an very flawed but intriguing period suspense thriller with good performances by Roberts and Malkovich. The bleak setting is nicely done by production designer:Staurt Craig (The Harry Potter Series, Chaplin, The Secret Garden) and Glenn Close has fun in her minor role as a madam. Although there was trouble during production, because Roberts and Malkovich didn't get along. The film was also over budgeted and problems with Christopher Hampton's (Atonement, The Secret Agent, Total Eclipse) script. "Mary Reilly" ended up being re-shot in the end, despite it was an reunion from the Cast and Crew of "Dangerous Liaisions" for director:Frears, screenwriter:Hampton, actors:Malkovich & Close, producer:Norma Heyman, composer:George Fenton, cinematographer:Philippe Rousselot, production designer:Craig and casting director:Juliet Taylor. "Mary Reilly" does have an minor cult following, some might complain that Roberts was mis-cast but i thought she did well with his performance (Which she smiled only once in the film). One of the highlights is towards the end with Dr. Jekyll's character. Although watching the movie, it does look like at times, the movie had an troubled production. It's very flawed at times but it's Malkovich's fascinating performance keeps it together. Despite all the movie faults, it is still worth a look. Based on a novel by Valerie Martin.(*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What do I like about this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like the fact that the film is told from Mary Reilly's point of view. Not only hers, but everyone else's too, like the naive servants, the furious Mrs. Faraday (the brothel mistress). Mary Reilly - the character - also has a disturbing, traumatizing background story and at some point Mr. Hyde gives a pretty heavy psychological spin on it. It's never elaborated on or seems ignored even, but this suits the tone of the film. Insinuating things often hits harder than explaining them. Through some of the characters, some of the possible little script flaws (or plot holes) get solved. For instance, doesn't anybody notice that Dr. Jekyll and his assistant Mr. Hyde look very much alike? Only Hyde looks younger. Sure people notice this, but one of the servants goes about assuming that Mr. Hyde might very well be a product of Jekyll's student days. As a bright student, Jekyll was popular with the ladies. And since Jekyll never got married, if he would have had a son... in those days it was even a sin to merely speak about or suggest a thing like this. I like John Malkovich's performance a lot and it's clear that him & Stephen Frears both understood very well what they wanted to achieve here. The good doc Jekyll (whom is looked upon in high regards by his servants) is far from kosher to the bone himself (we get hints at how he conducts his research and we know he's a regular client at Mrs. Faraday's house of pleasure). While on the other hand, Mr. Hyde as the savage beast, has his scarce moments of weakness for Mary Reilly. See what I'm getting at? And when looking at it from Mary's side, she unwillingly brings out the worst in the best, and the best in the worst, so to speak. Frears & Malkovich and screenwriter Christopher Hampton added shades of gray to a classic, one too many times told story that is basically just about black & white. The film got me really interested in reading the source novel it was based on. To see how it compares the film. What else is there to like? Enough, I think. Phillipe Rousselot's wonderful cinematography. A captivating musical score by George Stenton. As much as it's a character-driven story, it does feature a handful moments of the grotesque. Glenn Close gets decapitated. Dr. Jekyll is seen on the street repeatedly kicking a little girl in the stomach. An engrossing scene that shows how slaughtered meat for consumption is being traded in the streets, followed by an analogy towards the trade of human organs for the sake of science. Not sure whom all were responsible for these sequences -- I understand that Frears, for example, never intended the film to end like it did, with that climactic transformation sequence. But said sequences are a graphic reminder of the fact that we are watching a horrific story. At any rate, I didn't think they hurt the film. They injected it with the necessary dosage of brutality. The set design is marvelous and Dr. Jekyll's laboratory - or at least the way of getting there - is cleverly structured (as it helps crafting the suspense of a certain scene in a brilliant manner). The 19th century London setting works convincing, but we don't get to see much of it. The blocking & framing makes sure we usually only see one part of a street at a time. And to add to this claustrophobic & dark notion this film has, most scenes take place on indoors sets. But also these sets are put to great use. To Mary Reilly, the doctor's mansion starts off as a safe haven, a place offering a good job and a possible better future. But it doesn't take long for this house to get infested with the evil of Mr. Hyde's presence at night. So much even, that it starts to haunt her dreams. This shift in tone happens gradually, with a slow but impeccable pace. Truth be told, to me Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde always seemed a very simplistic story to tell. At least in the classic version as it got famous. It's good source material, yes, but Frears & Hampton managed to squeeze a much more interesting film out of it. Which probably could have even been a lot better if the producing studio at the time wasn't so concerned about how it would do at the box office. Voil&agrave;, that's it for what I like about this film. Notice that I didn't mention Julia Roberts' performance. It's very down-toned, as it should be. She is there not to be noticed, her character demands it and so does the story. And while she does have a lot of screen time, she doesn't do much, so there's just not much to say about her acting. But you can always 'see' the wheels of her character's thoughts grinding, as she is the only one who's trying to fathom what's going on. From all the servants, she's the only one that knows how to read. Dr. Jekyll discovers this very early on, when he spots her reading a book in his library. This, of course, titillates the good doc's mind. And that's the point in the film, as soon as it comes, where you instantly realize this is going to take a turn for the worse. In that moment, there's a harmless thing between them that will inevitably unleash unspeakable horrors. And this 'harmless thing' even is personified throughout the whole film. It goes by the name of Mary Reilly. A very interesting adaptation. And a good film, full stop.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Next up, The Time Machine told from the perspective of the traveller's postman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here's the tale of a scientist who descends into madness when a potion he creates splits his personality in two, told from the point of view of... his maid. What a strange choice. The movie is less interested in Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde than the woman who brings him his tea. Well, okay. Amongst the film's other misjudged elements are Julia Roberts' absolutely appalling Irish accent ('Ah, ye banged yer heed') and approximately nine hours worth of her looking sullen and hearing mysterious goings on. It's a boring film, drab and dreary. Glenn Close turns in a truly bizarre performance as a madam and John Malkovich is well cast as the-- I was about to say as the title character, herp derp  but they can't liven this thing up when the most interesting parts of the story are on the outskirts of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    correct work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    recreation of Victorian atmosphere. version of old story. inspired cast. ivory skin of central character. and John Malkovich. a film like a visit in museum. each piece on perfect place, each step as key for a treasure. strange flavor, cold touch. and air of love story. maybe, it is not convincing. but it is beautiful. and delicate like a silk butterfly. it is not very realistic but charm of each performance is necessary brick for a not really bad building. it is a kind of travel and fascination of viewer is secret satisfaction to know the truth at beginning. sure, Julia Roberts is not extraordinary but her work is correct. and this fact is important. like sign of a meeting between two fascinating actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The true horror is being forced to sit through this mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bults-356-93740
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to begin... How about the bland scenery? Bricks, fog, doors, fog, even the garden feels bland and lifeless. How about the so called "character study"? Well after watching this we now know that Mary is a ditz who makes Christine Daae look like Margarate Thatcher. We also know that she's (Spoiler!!! well... sort of) afraid of rats, and that her father was an absolute prick. Oh you wanted to know about Jekyll and Hyde's character? HA! You never learn anything you didn't already know about them other than their love of spouting exposition and "shocking" the audience with unexplained violence seemingly without any clear motive. In short, this movie will do its very best to "shock" and "scare" you but will ultimately only manage to disgust you. The only redeeming qualities are the impressive (but really very silly) transformation scene, one good jump scare, and laughing at Julia Roberts' "Irish" accent. Otherwise, this is an unrelentingly unpleasant movie that will leave you feeling empty. You will take NOTHING from this film, quite the contrary, it feels like it's taken something from you! Bottom line, don't watch this sick, poorly slapped together, bloody mess of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dr. Good and Mr.Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Mary Reilly, is the tale about good and evil. And how the two tore apart the soul of one man,driving him to madness.This man was a doctor by day and a killer by night.He was a healer of man loved by all who knew him.And at night he was someone that was feared by all that he meant a long the streets.He would have black outs and could not remember what he did at all.He killed many people, got away with it for a long time because; his other half would hide him in the darkness of his mind. Julia Roberts (aka Mary Reilly) played the part very well. I loved this movie because,I feel torn between my good and bad half.We all have times when we feel this way. But there are some people that do not know the difference between the two.The story Mary Reilly was Written by Valerie Martin.The other name for this dark tale is Dr.Jekyll and Mr.Hyde. By Robert Louis Stevenson. This is my mom's take on this tale of good vs evil, within ones self! mine is the two worked well together , in this dark thriller. John Malkovich , portrayed both characters equally well ! He really made me believe he had two totally different personalities. He was that convincing, I too loved this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody re-telling of Dr. Jeckyl story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Critics and audiences were bored with this remake of the Dr. Jeckyl tale when it first came out, but there is nonetheless a lot here to like. The viewpoint shift, allowing viewers to watch the familiar tale play out from the perspective of a serving woman in the Doctor's household, gives both a romantic edge to the picture and makes points about the place and role of women/servants in English society in Jeckyl's day. Roberts is very good as the lowest member of the household staff, trying to hold the Doctor himself and the household together while at the same time striving not to get above her station. And the grim, nearly black-and-white, dread-filled landscape of the picture is great to look at and memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An undiscovered gem which Julia shines in.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jimmy Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I initially came across this film when I found out it was at one stage planned to be a Winona Ryder/Tim Burton vehicle, and I have to sat I was so impressed by it that it is now one of my favorite films. With a bit of research I got the idea that this was a bad stage in Julias career, but I have to say I have never seen her better than she is in this. Her performance is just astounding, she has thus innocence and vulnerability that I never thought I'd see coming from her, she embodies the character extremely well, so well that it would have been a crime to see anyone else in the role. John Malkovich ramps up the creepy factor in this movie, his performance is also just stellar, he is truly terrifying in the scenes where he is Jekyll. Another thing I like is that this is such a great retelling of the Jekyll/ Hyde story, it's the best one I've ever seen, I think one big advantage it has is that its told from an onlookers perspective and not from an unknown or first person perspective. The cinematography is wonderful, the constant shade of grey and the overlying layer of fog both help to create the dark and moody atmosphere. I think it's definitely a movie fans of the story would enjoy and also people who aren't so familiar with it. Top notch Gothic horror that deserves to be seen....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The woman who loved Dr.Jekyll
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** Somewhat altered version of the Robert Louis Stevenson classic "Doctor Jekyll and Mister Hyde" with the sweet kindly and understanding Doctor Jekyll, John Malkovich, having a love interest who's a housemaid Mary Reilly, Julia Roberts, at his London home where her conducts his secrets experiments. Mary had a hard life with her being abused both psychically and mentally by her drunken father Mr. Reilly, Michael Gambon, that she in fact feels that's her lot in life and can do nothing about it. It's working at Dr.Henry Jekyll place that for the first time in her life Mary finds kindness and understanding for her many problems that includes the scars that her father gave her, like having rats chew at her, while she was a child. The fact that Dr.Jekyll takes such an interest in Mary has her boss the manager of the Jekyll house Mr. Poole, George Cole, get a bit jealous at her for his master, Dr.Jekyll, spending far more time with Mary then with him. Mary for her part is a bit perplexed of Dr.Jekyll in his going in and out of his both house and laboratory all hours of the night as if he's hiding something that he doesn't want anyone to find out about! It's one day when Dr.Jekyll sends Mary on a errand to a cat-house in the red light district in the seedy part of London that she realizes that the good doctor is up to no good. Not that he's a customer of the place but that his special assistant at his laboratory someone named Edward Hyde has made a mess of the place,by brutalizing the hookers, every time he goes there. Mary is told by the angry cat-house Madam Mrs. Farraday, Glenn Close, that Eddie or Mr. Hyde has gotten out of hand and she can't keep covering up for him anymore. Dr.Jekyll in trying to smooth things out by giving her payoff money, so she doesn't report Eddie to the police, also asks Mrs. Farraday, through Mary, to drop in and see him at his laboratory to talk things over! As it turns out Mrs. Farraday is met at the house not by Dr. Jekyll but Mister Hyde who ends up doing her in by making her at least a head shorter! ***SPOILERS*** AS we and Mary Reilly soon find out that he mysterious Edward Hyde is really Doctor Jekyll in the flesh. The doc had been having splitting headaches of late and developed this medication for them. As things turned out the medication did stop the headaches but it turned the genteel and civil Dr.Jekyll into the murderous and sex crazed Edward or Mister Hyde! Edward Hyde for his part took a shine to Mary and unlike his other-self Doctor Jekyll he had no trouble in him not controlling himself in his feeling for her. It's when Edward Hyde attacks and kills one of the late Madam Farrady's John's or customers at her cat or whorehouse the member of British Parliament and good friend of Dr.Jekyll Sir.Danvers Carew, Claran Hinds, that the cops or London Bobbies are called in to check things out! It's discovered that the murder weapon that Hyde killed Carew with, by bashing his skull in, was Doctor Jekyll's silver plated walking stick! ***MAJOR SPOILERS*** Doctor Jekyll now knowing that his life is doomed in that his other-self, by Mister Hyde manipulating his headache medication, has completely taken over his body and asks Mary to do what he doesn't have the guts to to in her doing him in and putting an end to this mesaghas,insanity in Yiddish, once in for all. Mary in what has to be an act of eternal love does what the doctor told her to do but in that she leaves herself open in her being in the wrong place at the wrong time, at the scene of the Sir. Danvers murder, to take the rap for the crime committed by the now departed Dr.Jekyll/Mr. Hyde and having to pay for It very possibly with her life!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I shudder to think what would have followed if this misfire had been a box office smash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film tells the story of the chambermaid who worked for Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde. Thankfully, this turgid mess bombed at the box office so we were spared sequels about Dracula's chauffeur, Frankenstein's tax attorney and the Wolfman's proctologist. Mary Reilly (Julia Roberts) works as a maid for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich) in 19th century London. I kid you not when I state that this movie essentially follows Mary around while she does her household chores and every so often we get a scene that peeks in on the classic tale of Jekyll and Hyde. If you don't know what that story's about, go down to the damn library and check out the book or watch one of the 37,000,000,000 other versions of the tale that have been committed to film. Basically, this thing is a Cliff's Notes version of Jekyll and Hyde, crossed with a documentary on the brutal drudgery of 19th century working class Britons, mixed with a Lifetime movie about a woman overcoming her memories of fatherly abuse. The heart of Mary Reilly is supposed to be about the attraction Mary feels for both Jekyll and Hyde and the affection they feel in return. A big problem is that it's hard to believe any man being lovestruck by this pale-faced woman with Conan O'Brien eyebrows. Julia Roberts is deliberately stripped of most of the beauty artifice that props up her appearance in other films and the audience is undeniably confronted with the fact that Roberts is not that pretty. She has very distinct features that need to be accommodated on screen and that doesn't happen here. Another defining negative about this film is very poor acting jobs by three big stars. Roberts intermittently adopts an Irish accent that rivals Kevin Costner's dialect in Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves for its "now you hear it, now you don't" quality. John Malkovich does worse than sleepwalk through his double role, even giving Edward Hyde an extremely pronounced limp early in the film which completely disappears later on. Either Malkovich and director Stephen Frears both forgot about the limp or Malkovich just got tired of doing it and Frears couldn't make him. Glenn Close is almost as bad as the owner of a London brothel. Her entire performance consists of giving her character an Elvis lip curl. The bottom line is that Mary Reilly is a movie about an uninteresting woman who stands still while an amazing story happens around her. The idea of telling a famous tale from the perspective of a minor character isn't a bad one. A movie about the London cop trying to track down and capture Edward Hyde sounds good to me. The trick is the minor character actually has to do something important in the story. Mary Reilly simply hovers and watches like the boring person on a reality show. Unless you're dying to view YET ANOTHER crappy adaptation of Jekyll and Hyde, skip this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawed period thriller is worth watching for the two lead performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An pretty but shy, depressed and lonely housemaid by the name of Mary Reilly (Oscar-Winner:Julia Roberts) works for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich). When Dr. Jekyll is working on a experiment, he tells his staff (George Cole, Michael Sheen, Kathy Staff and Bronagh Gallagher) and Mary that he will have an assistant working with him. But the stuff never fully sees him and remains an mystery. But when Mary gets closer to Dr. Jekyll talking about her awful childhood to him, begin abused by her drunken mean-spirited father (Michael Gambon). Mary finds herself slowly falling in love with Dr. Jekyll but soon discovers that Dr. Jekyll has an dark side and his mysterious assistant might be related to him. Directed by Stephen Frears (The Grifters, Hero, The Hours) made an very flawed but intriguing period suspense thriller with good performances by Roberts and Malkovich. The bleak setting is nicely done by production designer:Staurt Craig (The Harry Potter Series, Chaplin, The Secret Garden) and Glenn Close has fun in her minor role as a madam. Although there was trouble during production, because Roberts and Malkovich didn't get along. The film was also over budgeted and problems with Christopher Hampton's (Atonement, The Secret Agent, Total Eclipse) script. "Mary Reilly" ended up being re-shot in the end, despite it was an reunion from the Cast and Crew of "Dangerous Liaisions" for director:Frears, screenwriter:Hampton, actors:Malkovich & Close, producer:Norma Heyman, composer:George Fenton, cinematographer:Philippe Rousselot, production designer:Craig and casting director:Juliet Taylor. "Mary Reilly" does have an minor cult following, some might complain that Roberts was mis-cast but i thought she did well with his performance (Which she smiled only once in the film). One of the highlights is towards the end with Dr. Jekyll's character. Although watching the movie, it does look like at times, the movie had an troubled production. It's very flawed at times but it's Malkovich's fascinating performance keeps it together. Despite all the movie faults, it is still worth a look. Based on a novel by Valerie Martin.(*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What do I like about this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like the fact that the film is told from Mary Reilly's point of view. Not only hers, but everyone else's too, like the naive servants, the furious Mrs. Faraday (the brothel mistress). Mary Reilly - the character - also has a disturbing, traumatizing background story and at some point Mr. Hyde gives a pretty heavy psychological spin on it. It's never elaborated on or seems ignored even, but this suits the tone of the film. Insinuating things often hits harder than explaining them. Through some of the characters, some of the possible little script flaws (or plot holes) get solved. For instance, doesn't anybody notice that Dr. Jekyll and his assistant Mr. Hyde look very much alike? Only Hyde looks younger. Sure people notice this, but one of the servants goes about assuming that Mr. Hyde might very well be a product of Jekyll's student days. As a bright student, Jekyll was popular with the ladies. And since Jekyll never got married, if he would have had a son... in those days it was even a sin to merely speak about or suggest a thing like this. I like John Malkovich's performance a lot and it's clear that him & Stephen Frears both understood very well what they wanted to achieve here. The good doc Jekyll (whom is looked upon in high regards by his servants) is far from kosher to the bone himself (we get hints at how he conducts his research and we know he's a regular client at Mrs. Faraday's house of pleasure). While on the other hand, Mr. Hyde as the savage beast, has his scarce moments of weakness for Mary Reilly. See what I'm getting at? And when looking at it from Mary's side, she unwillingly brings out the worst in the best, and the best in the worst, so to speak. Frears & Malkovich and screenwriter Christopher Hampton added shades of gray to a classic, one too many times told story that is basically just about black & white. The film got me really interested in reading the source novel it was based on. To see how it compares the film. What else is there to like? Enough, I think. Phillipe Rousselot's wonderful cinematography. A captivating musical score by George Stenton. As much as it's a character-driven story, it does feature a handful moments of the grotesque. Glenn Close gets decapitated. Dr. Jekyll is seen on the street repeatedly kicking a little girl in the stomach. An engrossing scene that shows how slaughtered meat for consumption is being traded in the streets, followed by an analogy towards the trade of human organs for the sake of science. Not sure whom all were responsible for these sequences -- I understand that Frears, for example, never intended the film to end like it did, with that climactic transformation sequence. But said sequences are a graphic reminder of the fact that we are watching a horrific story. At any rate, I didn't think they hurt the film. They injected it with the necessary dosage of brutality. The set design is marvelous and Dr. Jekyll's laboratory - or at least the way of getting there - is cleverly structured (as it helps crafting the suspense of a certain scene in a brilliant manner). The 19th century London setting works convincing, but we don't get to see much of it. The blocking & framing makes sure we usually only see one part of a street at a time. And to add to this claustrophobic & dark notion this film has, most scenes take place on indoors sets. But also these sets are put to great use. To Mary Reilly, the doctor's mansion starts off as a safe haven, a place offering a good job and a possible better future. But it doesn't take long for this house to get infested with the evil of Mr. Hyde's presence at night. So much even, that it starts to haunt her dreams. This shift in tone happens gradually, with a slow but impeccable pace. Truth be told, to me Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde always seemed a very simplistic story to tell. At least in the classic version as it got famous. It's good source material, yes, but Frears & Hampton managed to squeeze a much more interesting film out of it. Which probably could have even been a lot better if the producing studio at the time wasn't so concerned about how it would do at the box office. Voil&agrave;, that's it for what I like about this film. Notice that I didn't mention Julia Roberts' performance. It's very down-toned, as it should be. She is there not to be noticed, her character demands it and so does the story. And while she does have a lot of screen time, she doesn't do much, so there's just not much to say about her acting. But you can always 'see' the wheels of her character's thoughts grinding, as she is the only one who's trying to fathom what's going on. From all the servants, she's the only one that knows how to read. Dr. Jekyll discovers this very early on, when he spots her reading a book in his library. This, of course, titillates the good doc's mind. And that's the point in the film, as soon as it comes, where you instantly realize this is going to take a turn for the worse. In that moment, there's a harmless thing between them that will inevitably unleash unspeakable horrors. And this 'harmless thing' even is personified throughout the whole film. It goes by the name of Mary Reilly. A very interesting adaptation. And a good film, full stop.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Next up, The Time Machine told from the perspective of the traveller's postman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here's the tale of a scientist who descends into madness when a potion he creates splits his personality in two, told from the point of view of... his maid. What a strange choice. The movie is less interested in Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde than the woman who brings him his tea. Well, okay. Amongst the film's other misjudged elements are Julia Roberts' absolutely appalling Irish accent ('Ah, ye banged yer heed') and approximately nine hours worth of her looking sullen and hearing mysterious goings on. It's a boring film, drab and dreary. Glenn Close turns in a truly bizarre performance as a madam and John Malkovich is well cast as the-- I was about to say as the title character, herp derp  but they can't liven this thing up when the most interesting parts of the story are on the outskirts of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    correct work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    recreation of Victorian atmosphere. version of old story. inspired cast. ivory skin of central character. and John Malkovich. a film like a visit in museum. each piece on perfect place, each step as key for a treasure. strange flavor, cold touch. and air of love story. maybe, it is not convincing. but it is beautiful. and delicate like a silk butterfly. it is not very realistic but charm of each performance is necessary brick for a not really bad building. it is a kind of travel and fascination of viewer is secret satisfaction to know the truth at beginning. sure, Julia Roberts is not extraordinary but her work is correct. and this fact is important. like sign of a meeting between two fascinating actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The true horror is being forced to sit through this mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bults-356-93740
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to begin... How about the bland scenery? Bricks, fog, doors, fog, even the garden feels bland and lifeless. How about the so called "character study"? Well after watching this we now know that Mary is a ditz who makes Christine Daae look like Margarate Thatcher. We also know that she's (Spoiler!!! well... sort of) afraid of rats, and that her father was an absolute prick. Oh you wanted to know about Jekyll and Hyde's character? HA! You never learn anything you didn't already know about them other than their love of spouting exposition and "shocking" the audience with unexplained violence seemingly without any clear motive. In short, this movie will do its very best to "shock" and "scare" you but will ultimately only manage to disgust you. The only redeeming qualities are the impressive (but really very silly) transformation scene, one good jump scare, and laughing at Julia Roberts' "Irish" accent. Otherwise, this is an unrelentingly unpleasant movie that will leave you feeling empty. You will take NOTHING from this film, quite the contrary, it feels like it's taken something from you! Bottom line, don't watch this sick, poorly slapped together, bloody mess of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dr. Good and Mr.Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Mary Reilly, is the tale about good and evil. And how the two tore apart the soul of one man,driving him to madness.This man was a doctor by day and a killer by night.He was a healer of man loved by all who knew him.And at night he was someone that was feared by all that he meant a long the streets.He would have black outs and could not remember what he did at all.He killed many people, got away with it for a long time because; his other half would hide him in the darkness of his mind. Julia Roberts (aka Mary Reilly) played the part very well. I loved this movie because,I feel torn between my good and bad half.We all have times when we feel this way. But there are some people that do not know the difference between the two.The story Mary Reilly was Written by Valerie Martin.The other name for this dark tale is Dr.Jekyll and Mr.Hyde. By Robert Louis Stevenson. This is my mom's take on this tale of good vs evil, within ones self! mine is the two worked well together , in this dark thriller. John Malkovich , portrayed both characters equally well ! He really made me believe he had two totally different personalities. He was that convincing, I too loved this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody re-telling of Dr. Jeckyl story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Critics and audiences were bored with this remake of the Dr. Jeckyl tale when it first came out, but there is nonetheless a lot here to like. The viewpoint shift, allowing viewers to watch the familiar tale play out from the perspective of a serving woman in the Doctor's household, gives both a romantic edge to the picture and makes points about the place and role of women/servants in English society in Jeckyl's day. Roberts is very good as the lowest member of the household staff, trying to hold the Doctor himself and the household together while at the same time striving not to get above her station. And the grim, nearly black-and-white, dread-filled landscape of the picture is great to look at and memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An undiscovered gem which Julia shines in.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jimmy Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I initially came across this film when I found out it was at one stage planned to be a Winona Ryder/Tim Burton vehicle, and I have to sat I was so impressed by it that it is now one of my favorite films. With a bit of research I got the idea that this was a bad stage in Julias career, but I have to say I have never seen her better than she is in this. Her performance is just astounding, she has thus innocence and vulnerability that I never thought I'd see coming from her, she embodies the character extremely well, so well that it would have been a crime to see anyone else in the role. John Malkovich ramps up the creepy factor in this movie, his performance is also just stellar, he is truly terrifying in the scenes where he is Jekyll. Another thing I like is that this is such a great retelling of the Jekyll/ Hyde story, it's the best one I've ever seen, I think one big advantage it has is that its told from an onlookers perspective and not from an unknown or first person perspective. The cinematography is wonderful, the constant shade of grey and the overlying layer of fog both help to create the dark and moody atmosphere. I think it's definitely a movie fans of the story would enjoy and also people who aren't so familiar with it. Top notch Gothic horror that deserves to be seen....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The woman who loved Dr.Jekyll
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** Somewhat altered version of the Robert Louis Stevenson classic "Doctor Jekyll and Mister Hyde" with the sweet kindly and understanding Doctor Jekyll, John Malkovich, having a love interest who's a housemaid Mary Reilly, Julia Roberts, at his London home where her conducts his secrets experiments. Mary had a hard life with her being abused both psychically and mentally by her drunken father Mr. Reilly, Michael Gambon, that she in fact feels that's her lot in life and can do nothing about it. It's working at Dr.Henry Jekyll place that for the first time in her life Mary finds kindness and understanding for her many problems that includes the scars that her father gave her, like having rats chew at her, while she was a child. The fact that Dr.Jekyll takes such an interest in Mary has her boss the manager of the Jekyll house Mr. Poole, George Cole, get a bit jealous at her for his master, Dr.Jekyll, spending far more time with Mary then with him. Mary for her part is a bit perplexed of Dr.Jekyll in his going in and out of his both house and laboratory all hours of the night as if he's hiding something that he doesn't want anyone to find out about! It's one day when Dr.Jekyll sends Mary on a errand to a cat-house in the red light district in the seedy part of London that she realizes that the good doctor is up to no good. Not that he's a customer of the place but that his special assistant at his laboratory someone named Edward Hyde has made a mess of the place,by brutalizing the hookers, every time he goes there. Mary is told by the angry cat-house Madam Mrs. Farraday, Glenn Close, that Eddie or Mr. Hyde has gotten out of hand and she can't keep covering up for him anymore. Dr.Jekyll in trying to smooth things out by giving her payoff money, so she doesn't report Eddie to the police, also asks Mrs. Farraday, through Mary, to drop in and see him at his laboratory to talk things over! As it turns out Mrs. Farraday is met at the house not by Dr. Jekyll but Mister Hyde who ends up doing her in by making her at least a head shorter! ***SPOILERS*** AS we and Mary Reilly soon find out that he mysterious Edward Hyde is really Doctor Jekyll in the flesh. The doc had been having splitting headaches of late and developed this medication for them. As things turned out the medication did stop the headaches but it turned the genteel and civil Dr.Jekyll into the murderous and sex crazed Edward or Mister Hyde! Edward Hyde for his part took a shine to Mary and unlike his other-self Doctor Jekyll he had no trouble in him not controlling himself in his feeling for her. It's when Edward Hyde attacks and kills one of the late Madam Farrady's John's or customers at her cat or whorehouse the member of British Parliament and good friend of Dr.Jekyll Sir.Danvers Carew, Claran Hinds, that the cops or London Bobbies are called in to check things out! It's discovered that the murder weapon that Hyde killed Carew with, by bashing his skull in, was Doctor Jekyll's silver plated walking stick! ***MAJOR SPOILERS*** Doctor Jekyll now knowing that his life is doomed in that his other-self, by Mister Hyde manipulating his headache medication, has completely taken over his body and asks Mary to do what he doesn't have the guts to to in her doing him in and putting an end to this mesaghas,insanity in Yiddish, once in for all. Mary in what has to be an act of eternal love does what the doctor told her to do but in that she leaves herself open in her being in the wrong place at the wrong time, at the scene of the Sir. Danvers murder, to take the rap for the crime committed by the now departed Dr.Jekyll/Mr. Hyde and having to pay for It very possibly with her life!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I shudder to think what would have followed if this misfire had been a box office smash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film tells the story of the chambermaid who worked for Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde. Thankfully, this turgid mess bombed at the box office so we were spared sequels about Dracula's chauffeur, Frankenstein's tax attorney and the Wolfman's proctologist. Mary Reilly (Julia Roberts) works as a maid for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich) in 19th century London. I kid you not when I state that this movie essentially follows Mary around while she does her household chores and every so often we get a scene that peeks in on the classic tale of Jekyll and Hyde. If you don't know what that story's about, go down to the damn library and check out the book or watch one of the 37,000,000,000 other versions of the tale that have been committed to film. Basically, this thing is a Cliff's Notes version of Jekyll and Hyde, crossed with a documentary on the brutal drudgery of 19th century working class Britons, mixed with a Lifetime movie about a woman overcoming her memories of fatherly abuse. The heart of Mary Reilly is supposed to be about the attraction Mary feels for both Jekyll and Hyde and the affection they feel in return. A big problem is that it's hard to believe any man being lovestruck by this pale-faced woman with Conan O'Brien eyebrows. Julia Roberts is deliberately stripped of most of the beauty artifice that props up her appearance in other films and the audience is undeniably confronted with the fact that Roberts is not that pretty. She has very distinct features that need to be accommodated on screen and that doesn't happen here. Another defining negative about this film is very poor acting jobs by three big stars. Roberts intermittently adopts an Irish accent that rivals Kevin Costner's dialect in Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves for its "now you hear it, now you don't" quality. John Malkovich does worse than sleepwalk through his double role, even giving Edward Hyde an extremely pronounced limp early in the film which completely disappears later on. Either Malkovich and director Stephen Frears both forgot about the limp or Malkovich just got tired of doing it and Frears couldn't make him. Glenn Close is almost as bad as the owner of a London brothel. Her entire performance consists of giving her character an Elvis lip curl. The bottom line is that Mary Reilly is a movie about an uninteresting woman who stands still while an amazing story happens around her. The idea of telling a famous tale from the perspective of a minor character isn't a bad one. A movie about the London cop trying to track down and capture Edward Hyde sounds good to me. The trick is the minor character actually has to do something important in the story. Mary Reilly simply hovers and watches like the boring person on a reality show. Unless you're dying to view YET ANOTHER crappy adaptation of Jekyll and Hyde, skip this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawed period thriller is worth watching for the two lead performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An pretty but shy, depressed and lonely housemaid by the name of Mary Reilly (Oscar-Winner:Julia Roberts) works for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich). When Dr. Jekyll is working on a experiment, he tells his staff (George Cole, Michael Sheen, Kathy Staff and Bronagh Gallagher) and Mary that he will have an assistant working with him. But the stuff never fully sees him and remains an mystery. But when Mary gets closer to Dr. Jekyll talking about her awful childhood to him, begin abused by her drunken mean-spirited father (Michael Gambon). Mary finds herself slowly falling in love with Dr. Jekyll but soon discovers that Dr. Jekyll has an dark side and his mysterious assistant might be related to him. Directed by Stephen Frears (The Grifters, Hero, The Hours) made an very flawed but intriguing period suspense thriller with good performances by Roberts and Malkovich. The bleak setting is nicely done by production designer:Staurt Craig (The Harry Potter Series, Chaplin, The Secret Garden) and Glenn Close has fun in her minor role as a madam. Although there was trouble during production, because Roberts and Malkovich didn't get along. The film was also over budgeted and problems with Christopher Hampton's (Atonement, The Secret Agent, Total Eclipse) script. "Mary Reilly" ended up being re-shot in the end, despite it was an reunion from the Cast and Crew of "Dangerous Liaisions" for director:Frears, screenwriter:Hampton, actors:Malkovich & Close, producer:Norma Heyman, composer:George Fenton, cinematographer:Philippe Rousselot, production designer:Craig and casting director:Juliet Taylor. "Mary Reilly" does have an minor cult following, some might complain that Roberts was mis-cast but i thought she did well with his performance (Which she smiled only once in the film). One of the highlights is towards the end with Dr. Jekyll's character. Although watching the movie, it does look like at times, the movie had an troubled production. It's very flawed at times but it's Malkovich's fascinating performance keeps it together. Despite all the movie faults, it is still worth a look. Based on a novel by Valerie Martin.(*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What do I like about this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like the fact that the film is told from Mary Reilly's point of view. Not only hers, but everyone else's too, like the naive servants, the furious Mrs. Faraday (the brothel mistress). Mary Reilly - the character - also has a disturbing, traumatizing background story and at some point Mr. Hyde gives a pretty heavy psychological spin on it. It's never elaborated on or seems ignored even, but this suits the tone of the film. Insinuating things often hits harder than explaining them. Through some of the characters, some of the possible little script flaws (or plot holes) get solved. For instance, doesn't anybody notice that Dr. Jekyll and his assistant Mr. Hyde look very much alike? Only Hyde looks younger. Sure people notice this, but one of the servants goes about assuming that Mr. Hyde might very well be a product of Jekyll's student days. As a bright student, Jekyll was popular with the ladies. And since Jekyll never got married, if he would have had a son... in those days it was even a sin to merely speak about or suggest a thing like this. I like John Malkovich's performance a lot and it's clear that him & Stephen Frears both understood very well what they wanted to achieve here. The good doc Jekyll (whom is looked upon in high regards by his servants) is far from kosher to the bone himself (we get hints at how he conducts his research and we know he's a regular client at Mrs. Faraday's house of pleasure). While on the other hand, Mr. Hyde as the savage beast, has his scarce moments of weakness for Mary Reilly. See what I'm getting at? And when looking at it from Mary's side, she unwillingly brings out the worst in the best, and the best in the worst, so to speak. Frears & Malkovich and screenwriter Christopher Hampton added shades of gray to a classic, one too many times told story that is basically just about black & white. The film got me really interested in reading the source novel it was based on. To see how it compares the film. What else is there to like? Enough, I think. Phillipe Rousselot's wonderful cinematography. A captivating musical score by George Stenton. As much as it's a character-driven story, it does feature a handful moments of the grotesque. Glenn Close gets decapitated. Dr. Jekyll is seen on the street repeatedly kicking a little girl in the stomach. An engrossing scene that shows how slaughtered meat for consumption is being traded in the streets, followed by an analogy towards the trade of human organs for the sake of science. Not sure whom all were responsible for these sequences -- I understand that Frears, for example, never intended the film to end like it did, with that climactic transformation sequence. But said sequences are a graphic reminder of the fact that we are watching a horrific story. At any rate, I didn't think they hurt the film. They injected it with the necessary dosage of brutality. The set design is marvelous and Dr. Jekyll's laboratory - or at least the way of getting there - is cleverly structured (as it helps crafting the suspense of a certain scene in a brilliant manner). The 19th century London setting works convincing, but we don't get to see much of it. The blocking & framing makes sure we usually only see one part of a street at a time. And to add to this claustrophobic & dark notion this film has, most scenes take place on indoors sets. But also these sets are put to great use. To Mary Reilly, the doctor's mansion starts off as a safe haven, a place offering a good job and a possible better future. But it doesn't take long for this house to get infested with the evil of Mr. Hyde's presence at night. So much even, that it starts to haunt her dreams. This shift in tone happens gradually, with a slow but impeccable pace. Truth be told, to me Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde always seemed a very simplistic story to tell. At least in the classic version as it got famous. It's good source material, yes, but Frears & Hampton managed to squeeze a much more interesting film out of it. Which probably could have even been a lot better if the producing studio at the time wasn't so concerned about how it would do at the box office. Voil&agrave;, that's it for what I like about this film. Notice that I didn't mention Julia Roberts' performance. It's very down-toned, as it should be. She is there not to be noticed, her character demands it and so does the story. And while she does have a lot of screen time, she doesn't do much, so there's just not much to say about her acting. But you can always 'see' the wheels of her character's thoughts grinding, as she is the only one who's trying to fathom what's going on. From all the servants, she's the only one that knows how to read. Dr. Jekyll discovers this very early on, when he spots her reading a book in his library. This, of course, titillates the good doc's mind. And that's the point in the film, as soon as it comes, where you instantly realize this is going to take a turn for the worse. In that moment, there's a harmless thing between them that will inevitably unleash unspeakable horrors. And this 'harmless thing' even is personified throughout the whole film. It goes by the name of Mary Reilly. A very interesting adaptation. And a good film, full stop.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Next up, The Time Machine told from the perspective of the traveller's postman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here's the tale of a scientist who descends into madness when a potion he creates splits his personality in two, told from the point of view of... his maid. What a strange choice. The movie is less interested in Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde than the woman who brings him his tea. Well, okay. Amongst the film's other misjudged elements are Julia Roberts' absolutely appalling Irish accent ('Ah, ye banged yer heed') and approximately nine hours worth of her looking sullen and hearing mysterious goings on. It's a boring film, drab and dreary. Glenn Close turns in a truly bizarre performance as a madam and John Malkovich is well cast as the-- I was about to say as the title character, herp derp  but they can't liven this thing up when the most interesting parts of the story are on the outskirts of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    correct work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    recreation of Victorian atmosphere. version of old story. inspired cast. ivory skin of central character. and John Malkovich. a film like a visit in museum. each piece on perfect place, each step as key for a treasure. strange flavor, cold touch. and air of love story. maybe, it is not convincing. but it is beautiful. and delicate like a silk butterfly. it is not very realistic but charm of each performance is necessary brick for a not really bad building. it is a kind of travel and fascination of viewer is secret satisfaction to know the truth at beginning. sure, Julia Roberts is not extraordinary but her work is correct. and this fact is important. like sign of a meeting between two fascinating actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The true horror is being forced to sit through this mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bults-356-93740
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to begin... How about the bland scenery? Bricks, fog, doors, fog, even the garden feels bland and lifeless. How about the so called "character study"? Well after watching this we now know that Mary is a ditz who makes Christine Daae look like Margarate Thatcher. We also know that she's (Spoiler!!! well... sort of) afraid of rats, and that her father was an absolute prick. Oh you wanted to know about Jekyll and Hyde's character? HA! You never learn anything you didn't already know about them other than their love of spouting exposition and "shocking" the audience with unexplained violence seemingly without any clear motive. In short, this movie will do its very best to "shock" and "scare" you but will ultimately only manage to disgust you. The only redeeming qualities are the impressive (but really very silly) transformation scene, one good jump scare, and laughing at Julia Roberts' "Irish" accent. Otherwise, this is an unrelentingly unpleasant movie that will leave you feeling empty. You will take NOTHING from this film, quite the contrary, it feels like it's taken something from you! Bottom line, don't watch this sick, poorly slapped together, bloody mess of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dr. Good and Mr.Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Mary Reilly, is the tale about good and evil. And how the two tore apart the soul of one man,driving him to madness.This man was a doctor by day and a killer by night.He was a healer of man loved by all who knew him.And at night he was someone that was feared by all that he meant a long the streets.He would have black outs and could not remember what he did at all.He killed many people, got away with it for a long time because; his other half would hide him in the darkness of his mind. Julia Roberts (aka Mary Reilly) played the part very well. I loved this movie because,I feel torn between my good and bad half.We all have times when we feel this way. But there are some people that do not know the difference between the two.The story Mary Reilly was Written by Valerie Martin.The other name for this dark tale is Dr.Jekyll and Mr.Hyde. By Robert Louis Stevenson. This is my mom's take on this tale of good vs evil, within ones self! mine is the two worked well together , in this dark thriller. John Malkovich , portrayed both characters equally well ! He really made me believe he had two totally different personalities. He was that convincing, I too loved this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody re-telling of Dr. Jeckyl story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Critics and audiences were bored with this remake of the Dr. Jeckyl tale when it first came out, but there is nonetheless a lot here to like. The viewpoint shift, allowing viewers to watch the familiar tale play out from the perspective of a serving woman in the Doctor's household, gives both a romantic edge to the picture and makes points about the place and role of women/servants in English society in Jeckyl's day. Roberts is very good as the lowest member of the household staff, trying to hold the Doctor himself and the household together while at the same time striving not to get above her station. And the grim, nearly black-and-white, dread-filled landscape of the picture is great to look at and memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An undiscovered gem which Julia shines in.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jimmy Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I initially came across this film when I found out it was at one stage planned to be a Winona Ryder/Tim Burton vehicle, and I have to sat I was so impressed by it that it is now one of my favorite films. With a bit of research I got the idea that this was a bad stage in Julias career, but I have to say I have never seen her better than she is in this. Her performance is just astounding, she has thus innocence and vulnerability that I never thought I'd see coming from her, she embodies the character extremely well, so well that it would have been a crime to see anyone else in the role. John Malkovich ramps up the creepy factor in this movie, his performance is also just stellar, he is truly terrifying in the scenes where he is Jekyll. Another thing I like is that this is such a great retelling of the Jekyll/ Hyde story, it's the best one I've ever seen, I think one big advantage it has is that its told from an onlookers perspective and not from an unknown or first person perspective. The cinematography is wonderful, the constant shade of grey and the overlying layer of fog both help to create the dark and moody atmosphere. I think it's definitely a movie fans of the story would enjoy and also people who aren't so familiar with it. Top notch Gothic horror that deserves to be seen....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The woman who loved Dr.Jekyll
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** Somewhat altered version of the Robert Louis Stevenson classic "Doctor Jekyll and Mister Hyde" with the sweet kindly and understanding Doctor Jekyll, John Malkovich, having a love interest who's a housemaid Mary Reilly, Julia Roberts, at his London home where her conducts his secrets experiments. Mary had a hard life with her being abused both psychically and mentally by her drunken father Mr. Reilly, Michael Gambon, that she in fact feels that's her lot in life and can do nothing about it. It's working at Dr.Henry Jekyll place that for the first time in her life Mary finds kindness and understanding for her many problems that includes the scars that her father gave her, like having rats chew at her, while she was a child. The fact that Dr.Jekyll takes such an interest in Mary has her boss the manager of the Jekyll house Mr. Poole, George Cole, get a bit jealous at her for his master, Dr.Jekyll, spending far more time with Mary then with him. Mary for her part is a bit perplexed of Dr.Jekyll in his going in and out of his both house and laboratory all hours of the night as if he's hiding something that he doesn't want anyone to find out about! It's one day when Dr.Jekyll sends Mary on a errand to a cat-house in the red light district in the seedy part of London that she realizes that the good doctor is up to no good. Not that he's a customer of the place but that his special assistant at his laboratory someone named Edward Hyde has made a mess of the place,by brutalizing the hookers, every time he goes there. Mary is told by the angry cat-house Madam Mrs. Farraday, Glenn Close, that Eddie or Mr. Hyde has gotten out of hand and she can't keep covering up for him anymore. Dr.Jekyll in trying to smooth things out by giving her payoff money, so she doesn't report Eddie to the police, also asks Mrs. Farraday, through Mary, to drop in and see him at his laboratory to talk things over! As it turns out Mrs. Farraday is met at the house not by Dr. Jekyll but Mister Hyde who ends up doing her in by making her at least a head shorter! ***SPOILERS*** AS we and Mary Reilly soon find out that he mysterious Edward Hyde is really Doctor Jekyll in the flesh. The doc had been having splitting headaches of late and developed this medication for them. As things turned out the medication did stop the headaches but it turned the genteel and civil Dr.Jekyll into the murderous and sex crazed Edward or Mister Hyde! Edward Hyde for his part took a shine to Mary and unlike his other-self Doctor Jekyll he had no trouble in him not controlling himself in his feeling for her. It's when Edward Hyde attacks and kills one of the late Madam Farrady's John's or customers at her cat or whorehouse the member of British Parliament and good friend of Dr.Jekyll Sir.Danvers Carew, Claran Hinds, that the cops or London Bobbies are called in to check things out! It's discovered that the murder weapon that Hyde killed Carew with, by bashing his skull in, was Doctor Jekyll's silver plated walking stick! ***MAJOR SPOILERS*** Doctor Jekyll now knowing that his life is doomed in that his other-self, by Mister Hyde manipulating his headache medication, has completely taken over his body and asks Mary to do what he doesn't have the guts to to in her doing him in and putting an end to this mesaghas,insanity in Yiddish, once in for all. Mary in what has to be an act of eternal love does what the doctor told her to do but in that she leaves herself open in her being in the wrong place at the wrong time, at the scene of the Sir. Danvers murder, to take the rap for the crime committed by the now departed Dr.Jekyll/Mr. Hyde and having to pay for It very possibly with her life!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I shudder to think what would have followed if this misfire had been a box office smash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film tells the story of the chambermaid who worked for Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde. Thankfully, this turgid mess bombed at the box office so we were spared sequels about Dracula's chauffeur, Frankenstein's tax attorney and the Wolfman's proctologist. Mary Reilly (Julia Roberts) works as a maid for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich) in 19th century London. I kid you not when I state that this movie essentially follows Mary around while she does her household chores and every so often we get a scene that peeks in on the classic tale of Jekyll and Hyde. If you don't know what that story's about, go down to the damn library and check out the book or watch one of the 37,000,000,000 other versions of the tale that have been committed to film. Basically, this thing is a Cliff's Notes version of Jekyll and Hyde, crossed with a documentary on the brutal drudgery of 19th century working class Britons, mixed with a Lifetime movie about a woman overcoming her memories of fatherly abuse. The heart of Mary Reilly is supposed to be about the attraction Mary feels for both Jekyll and Hyde and the affection they feel in return. A big problem is that it's hard to believe any man being lovestruck by this pale-faced woman with Conan O'Brien eyebrows. Julia Roberts is deliberately stripped of most of the beauty artifice that props up her appearance in other films and the audience is undeniably confronted with the fact that Roberts is not that pretty. She has very distinct features that need to be accommodated on screen and that doesn't happen here. Another defining negative about this film is very poor acting jobs by three big stars. Roberts intermittently adopts an Irish accent that rivals Kevin Costner's dialect in Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves for its "now you hear it, now you don't" quality. John Malkovich does worse than sleepwalk through his double role, even giving Edward Hyde an extremely pronounced limp early in the film which completely disappears later on. Either Malkovich and director Stephen Frears both forgot about the limp or Malkovich just got tired of doing it and Frears couldn't make him. Glenn Close is almost as bad as the owner of a London brothel. Her entire performance consists of giving her character an Elvis lip curl. The bottom line is that Mary Reilly is a movie about an uninteresting woman who stands still while an amazing story happens around her. The idea of telling a famous tale from the perspective of a minor character isn't a bad one. A movie about the London cop trying to track down and capture Edward Hyde sounds good to me. The trick is the minor character actually has to do something important in the story. Mary Reilly simply hovers and watches like the boring person on a reality show. Unless you're dying to view YET ANOTHER crappy adaptation of Jekyll and Hyde, skip this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawed period thriller is worth watching for the two lead performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An pretty but shy, depressed and lonely housemaid by the name of Mary Reilly (Oscar-Winner:Julia Roberts) works for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich). When Dr. Jekyll is working on a experiment, he tells his staff (George Cole, Michael Sheen, Kathy Staff and Bronagh Gallagher) and Mary that he will have an assistant working with him. But the stuff never fully sees him and remains an mystery. But when Mary gets closer to Dr. Jekyll talking about her awful childhood to him, begin abused by her drunken mean-spirited father (Michael Gambon). Mary finds herself slowly falling in love with Dr. Jekyll but soon discovers that Dr. Jekyll has an dark side and his mysterious assistant might be related to him. Directed by Stephen Frears (The Grifters, Hero, The Hours) made an very flawed but intriguing period suspense thriller with good performances by Roberts and Malkovich. The bleak setting is nicely done by production designer:Staurt Craig (The Harry Potter Series, Chaplin, The Secret Garden) and Glenn Close has fun in her minor role as a madam. Although there was trouble during production, because Roberts and Malkovich didn't get along. The film was also over budgeted and problems with Christopher Hampton's (Atonement, The Secret Agent, Total Eclipse) script. "Mary Reilly" ended up being re-shot in the end, despite it was an reunion from the Cast and Crew of "Dangerous Liaisions" for director:Frears, screenwriter:Hampton, actors:Malkovich & Close, producer:Norma Heyman, composer:George Fenton, cinematographer:Philippe Rousselot, production designer:Craig and casting director:Juliet Taylor. "Mary Reilly" does have an minor cult following, some might complain that Roberts was mis-cast but i thought she did well with his performance (Which she smiled only once in the film). One of the highlights is towards the end with Dr. Jekyll's character. Although watching the movie, it does look like at times, the movie had an troubled production. It's very flawed at times but it's Malkovich's fascinating performance keeps it together. Despite all the movie faults, it is still worth a look. Based on a novel by Valerie Martin.(*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What do I like about this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like the fact that the film is told from Mary Reilly's point of view. Not only hers, but everyone else's too, like the naive servants, the furious Mrs. Faraday (the brothel mistress). Mary Reilly - the character - also has a disturbing, traumatizing background story and at some point Mr. Hyde gives a pretty heavy psychological spin on it. It's never elaborated on or seems ignored even, but this suits the tone of the film. Insinuating things often hits harder than explaining them. Through some of the characters, some of the possible little script flaws (or plot holes) get solved. For instance, doesn't anybody notice that Dr. Jekyll and his assistant Mr. Hyde look very much alike? Only Hyde looks younger. Sure people notice this, but one of the servants goes about assuming that Mr. Hyde might very well be a product of Jekyll's student days. As a bright student, Jekyll was popular with the ladies. And since Jekyll never got married, if he would have had a son... in those days it was even a sin to merely speak about or suggest a thing like this. I like John Malkovich's performance a lot and it's clear that him & Stephen Frears both understood very well what they wanted to achieve here. The good doc Jekyll (whom is looked upon in high regards by his servants) is far from kosher to the bone himself (we get hints at how he conducts his research and we know he's a regular client at Mrs. Faraday's house of pleasure). While on the other hand, Mr. Hyde as the savage beast, has his scarce moments of weakness for Mary Reilly. See what I'm getting at? And when looking at it from Mary's side, she unwillingly brings out the worst in the best, and the best in the worst, so to speak. Frears & Malkovich and screenwriter Christopher Hampton added shades of gray to a classic, one too many times told story that is basically just about black & white. The film got me really interested in reading the source novel it was based on. To see how it compares the film. What else is there to like? Enough, I think. Phillipe Rousselot's wonderful cinematography. A captivating musical score by George Stenton. As much as it's a character-driven story, it does feature a handful moments of the grotesque. Glenn Close gets decapitated. Dr. Jekyll is seen on the street repeatedly kicking a little girl in the stomach. An engrossing scene that shows how slaughtered meat for consumption is being traded in the streets, followed by an analogy towards the trade of human organs for the sake of science. Not sure whom all were responsible for these sequences -- I understand that Frears, for example, never intended the film to end like it did, with that climactic transformation sequence. But said sequences are a graphic reminder of the fact that we are watching a horrific story. At any rate, I didn't think they hurt the film. They injected it with the necessary dosage of brutality. The set design is marvelous and Dr. Jekyll's laboratory - or at least the way of getting there - is cleverly structured (as it helps crafting the suspense of a certain scene in a brilliant manner). The 19th century London setting works convincing, but we don't get to see much of it. The blocking & framing makes sure we usually only see one part of a street at a time. And to add to this claustrophobic & dark notion this film has, most scenes take place on indoors sets. But also these sets are put to great use. To Mary Reilly, the doctor's mansion starts off as a safe haven, a place offering a good job and a possible better future. But it doesn't take long for this house to get infested with the evil of Mr. Hyde's presence at night. So much even, that it starts to haunt her dreams. This shift in tone happens gradually, with a slow but impeccable pace. Truth be told, to me Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde always seemed a very simplistic story to tell. At least in the classic version as it got famous. It's good source material, yes, but Frears & Hampton managed to squeeze a much more interesting film out of it. Which probably could have even been a lot better if the producing studio at the time wasn't so concerned about how it would do at the box office. Voil&agrave;, that's it for what I like about this film. Notice that I didn't mention Julia Roberts' performance. It's very down-toned, as it should be. She is there not to be noticed, her character demands it and so does the story. And while she does have a lot of screen time, she doesn't do much, so there's just not much to say about her acting. But you can always 'see' the wheels of her character's thoughts grinding, as she is the only one who's trying to fathom what's going on. From all the servants, she's the only one that knows how to read. Dr. Jekyll discovers this very early on, when he spots her reading a book in his library. This, of course, titillates the good doc's mind. And that's the point in the film, as soon as it comes, where you instantly realize this is going to take a turn for the worse. In that moment, there's a harmless thing between them that will inevitably unleash unspeakable horrors. And this 'harmless thing' even is personified throughout the whole film. It goes by the name of Mary Reilly. A very interesting adaptation. And a good film, full stop.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Next up, The Time Machine told from the perspective of the traveller's postman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here's the tale of a scientist who descends into madness when a potion he creates splits his personality in two, told from the point of view of... his maid. What a strange choice. The movie is less interested in Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde than the woman who brings him his tea. Well, okay. Amongst the film's other misjudged elements are Julia Roberts' absolutely appalling Irish accent ('Ah, ye banged yer heed') and approximately nine hours worth of her looking sullen and hearing mysterious goings on. It's a boring film, drab and dreary. Glenn Close turns in a truly bizarre performance as a madam and John Malkovich is well cast as the-- I was about to say as the title character, herp derp  but they can't liven this thing up when the most interesting parts of the story are on the outskirts of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    correct work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    recreation of Victorian atmosphere. version of old story. inspired cast. ivory skin of central character. and John Malkovich. a film like a visit in museum. each piece on perfect place, each step as key for a treasure. strange flavor, cold touch. and air of love story. maybe, it is not convincing. but it is beautiful. and delicate like a silk butterfly. it is not very realistic but charm of each performance is necessary brick for a not really bad building. it is a kind of travel and fascination of viewer is secret satisfaction to know the truth at beginning. sure, Julia Roberts is not extraordinary but her work is correct. and this fact is important. like sign of a meeting between two fascinating actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The true horror is being forced to sit through this mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bults-356-93740
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to begin... How about the bland scenery? Bricks, fog, doors, fog, even the garden feels bland and lifeless. How about the so called "character study"? Well after watching this we now know that Mary is a ditz who makes Christine Daae look like Margarate Thatcher. We also know that she's (Spoiler!!! well... sort of) afraid of rats, and that her father was an absolute prick. Oh you wanted to know about Jekyll and Hyde's character? HA! You never learn anything you didn't already know about them other than their love of spouting exposition and "shocking" the audience with unexplained violence seemingly without any clear motive. In short, this movie will do its very best to "shock" and "scare" you but will ultimately only manage to disgust you. The only redeeming qualities are the impressive (but really very silly) transformation scene, one good jump scare, and laughing at Julia Roberts' "Irish" accent. Otherwise, this is an unrelentingly unpleasant movie that will leave you feeling empty. You will take NOTHING from this film, quite the contrary, it feels like it's taken something from you! Bottom line, don't watch this sick, poorly slapped together, bloody mess of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dr. Good and Mr.Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Mary Reilly, is the tale about good and evil. And how the two tore apart the soul of one man,driving him to madness.This man was a doctor by day and a killer by night.He was a healer of man loved by all who knew him.And at night he was someone that was feared by all that he meant a long the streets.He would have black outs and could not remember what he did at all.He killed many people, got away with it for a long time because; his other half would hide him in the darkness of his mind. Julia Roberts (aka Mary Reilly) played the part very well. I loved this movie because,I feel torn between my good and bad half.We all have times when we feel this way. But there are some people that do not know the difference between the two.The story Mary Reilly was Written by Valerie Martin.The other name for this dark tale is Dr.Jekyll and Mr.Hyde. By Robert Louis Stevenson. This is my mom's take on this tale of good vs evil, within ones self! mine is the two worked well together , in this dark thriller. John Malkovich , portrayed both characters equally well ! He really made me believe he had two totally different personalities. He was that convincing, I too loved this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody re-telling of Dr. Jeckyl story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Critics and audiences were bored with this remake of the Dr. Jeckyl tale when it first came out, but there is nonetheless a lot here to like. The viewpoint shift, allowing viewers to watch the familiar tale play out from the perspective of a serving woman in the Doctor's household, gives both a romantic edge to the picture and makes points about the place and role of women/servants in English society in Jeckyl's day. Roberts is very good as the lowest member of the household staff, trying to hold the Doctor himself and the household together while at the same time striving not to get above her station. And the grim, nearly black-and-white, dread-filled landscape of the picture is great to look at and memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An undiscovered gem which Julia shines in.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jimmy Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I initially came across this film when I found out it was at one stage planned to be a Winona Ryder/Tim Burton vehicle, and I have to sat I was so impressed by it that it is now one of my favorite films. With a bit of research I got the idea that this was a bad stage in Julias career, but I have to say I have never seen her better than she is in this. Her performance is just astounding, she has thus innocence and vulnerability that I never thought I'd see coming from her, she embodies the character extremely well, so well that it would have been a crime to see anyone else in the role. John Malkovich ramps up the creepy factor in this movie, his performance is also just stellar, he is truly terrifying in the scenes where he is Jekyll. Another thing I like is that this is such a great retelling of the Jekyll/ Hyde story, it's the best one I've ever seen, I think one big advantage it has is that its told from an onlookers perspective and not from an unknown or first person perspective. The cinematography is wonderful, the constant shade of grey and the overlying layer of fog both help to create the dark and moody atmosphere. I think it's definitely a movie fans of the story would enjoy and also people who aren't so familiar with it. Top notch Gothic horror that deserves to be seen....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The woman who loved Dr.Jekyll
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** Somewhat altered version of the Robert Louis Stevenson classic "Doctor Jekyll and Mister Hyde" with the sweet kindly and understanding Doctor Jekyll, John Malkovich, having a love interest who's a housemaid Mary Reilly, Julia Roberts, at his London home where her conducts his secrets experiments. Mary had a hard life with her being abused both psychically and mentally by her drunken father Mr. Reilly, Michael Gambon, that she in fact feels that's her lot in life and can do nothing about it. It's working at Dr.Henry Jekyll place that for the first time in her life Mary finds kindness and understanding for her many problems that includes the scars that her father gave her, like having rats chew at her, while she was a child. The fact that Dr.Jekyll takes such an interest in Mary has her boss the manager of the Jekyll house Mr. Poole, George Cole, get a bit jealous at her for his master, Dr.Jekyll, spending far more time with Mary then with him. Mary for her part is a bit perplexed of Dr.Jekyll in his going in and out of his both house and laboratory all hours of the night as if he's hiding something that he doesn't want anyone to find out about! It's one day when Dr.Jekyll sends Mary on a errand to a cat-house in the red light district in the seedy part of London that she realizes that the good doctor is up to no good. Not that he's a customer of the place but that his special assistant at his laboratory someone named Edward Hyde has made a mess of the place,by brutalizing the hookers, every time he goes there. Mary is told by the angry cat-house Madam Mrs. Farraday, Glenn Close, that Eddie or Mr. Hyde has gotten out of hand and she can't keep covering up for him anymore. Dr.Jekyll in trying to smooth things out by giving her payoff money, so she doesn't report Eddie to the police, also asks Mrs. Farraday, through Mary, to drop in and see him at his laboratory to talk things over! As it turns out Mrs. Farraday is met at the house not by Dr. Jekyll but Mister Hyde who ends up doing her in by making her at least a head shorter! ***SPOILERS*** AS we and Mary Reilly soon find out that he mysterious Edward Hyde is really Doctor Jekyll in the flesh. The doc had been having splitting headaches of late and developed this medication for them. As things turned out the medication did stop the headaches but it turned the genteel and civil Dr.Jekyll into the murderous and sex crazed Edward or Mister Hyde! Edward Hyde for his part took a shine to Mary and unlike his other-self Doctor Jekyll he had no trouble in him not controlling himself in his feeling for her. It's when Edward Hyde attacks and kills one of the late Madam Farrady's John's or customers at her cat or whorehouse the member of British Parliament and good friend of Dr.Jekyll Sir.Danvers Carew, Claran Hinds, that the cops or London Bobbies are called in to check things out! It's discovered that the murder weapon that Hyde killed Carew with, by bashing his skull in, was Doctor Jekyll's silver plated walking stick! ***MAJOR SPOILERS*** Doctor Jekyll now knowing that his life is doomed in that his other-self, by Mister Hyde manipulating his headache medication, has completely taken over his body and asks Mary to do what he doesn't have the guts to to in her doing him in and putting an end to this mesaghas,insanity in Yiddish, once in for all. Mary in what has to be an act of eternal love does what the doctor told her to do but in that she leaves herself open in her being in the wrong place at the wrong time, at the scene of the Sir. Danvers murder, to take the rap for the crime committed by the now departed Dr.Jekyll/Mr. Hyde and having to pay for It very possibly with her life!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I shudder to think what would have followed if this misfire had been a box office smash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film tells the story of the chambermaid who worked for Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde. Thankfully, this turgid mess bombed at the box office so we were spared sequels about Dracula's chauffeur, Frankenstein's tax attorney and the Wolfman's proctologist. Mary Reilly (Julia Roberts) works as a maid for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich) in 19th century London. I kid you not when I state that this movie essentially follows Mary around while she does her household chores and every so often we get a scene that peeks in on the classic tale of Jekyll and Hyde. If you don't know what that story's about, go down to the damn library and check out the book or watch one of the 37,000,000,000 other versions of the tale that have been committed to film. Basically, this thing is a Cliff's Notes version of Jekyll and Hyde, crossed with a documentary on the brutal drudgery of 19th century working class Britons, mixed with a Lifetime movie about a woman overcoming her memories of fatherly abuse. The heart of Mary Reilly is supposed to be about the attraction Mary feels for both Jekyll and Hyde and the affection they feel in return. A big problem is that it's hard to believe any man being lovestruck by this pale-faced woman with Conan O'Brien eyebrows. Julia Roberts is deliberately stripped of most of the beauty artifice that props up her appearance in other films and the audience is undeniably confronted with the fact that Roberts is not that pretty. She has very distinct features that need to be accommodated on screen and that doesn't happen here. Another defining negative about this film is very poor acting jobs by three big stars. Roberts intermittently adopts an Irish accent that rivals Kevin Costner's dialect in Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves for its "now you hear it, now you don't" quality. John Malkovich does worse than sleepwalk through his double role, even giving Edward Hyde an extremely pronounced limp early in the film which completely disappears later on. Either Malkovich and director Stephen Frears both forgot about the limp or Malkovich just got tired of doing it and Frears couldn't make him. Glenn Close is almost as bad as the owner of a London brothel. Her entire performance consists of giving her character an Elvis lip curl. The bottom line is that Mary Reilly is a movie about an uninteresting woman who stands still while an amazing story happens around her. The idea of telling a famous tale from the perspective of a minor character isn't a bad one. A movie about the London cop trying to track down and capture Edward Hyde sounds good to me. The trick is the minor character actually has to do something important in the story. Mary Reilly simply hovers and watches like the boring person on a reality show. Unless you're dying to view YET ANOTHER crappy adaptation of Jekyll and Hyde, skip this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawed period thriller is worth watching for the two lead performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An pretty but shy, depressed and lonely housemaid by the name of Mary Reilly (Oscar-Winner:Julia Roberts) works for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich). When Dr. Jekyll is working on a experiment, he tells his staff (George Cole, Michael Sheen, Kathy Staff and Bronagh Gallagher) and Mary that he will have an assistant working with him. But the stuff never fully sees him and remains an mystery. But when Mary gets closer to Dr. Jekyll talking about her awful childhood to him, begin abused by her drunken mean-spirited father (Michael Gambon). Mary finds herself slowly falling in love with Dr. Jekyll but soon discovers that Dr. Jekyll has an dark side and his mysterious assistant might be related to him. Directed by Stephen Frears (The Grifters, Hero, The Hours) made an very flawed but intriguing period suspense thriller with good performances by Roberts and Malkovich. The bleak setting is nicely done by production designer:Staurt Craig (The Harry Potter Series, Chaplin, The Secret Garden) and Glenn Close has fun in her minor role as a madam. Although there was trouble during production, because Roberts and Malkovich didn't get along. The film was also over budgeted and problems with Christopher Hampton's (Atonement, The Secret Agent, Total Eclipse) script. "Mary Reilly" ended up being re-shot in the end, despite it was an reunion from the Cast and Crew of "Dangerous Liaisions" for director:Frears, screenwriter:Hampton, actors:Malkovich & Close, producer:Norma Heyman, composer:George Fenton, cinematographer:Philippe Rousselot, production designer:Craig and casting director:Juliet Taylor. "Mary Reilly" does have an minor cult following, some might complain that Roberts was mis-cast but i thought she did well with his performance (Which she smiled only once in the film). One of the highlights is towards the end with Dr. Jekyll's character. Although watching the movie, it does look like at times, the movie had an troubled production. It's very flawed at times but it's Malkovich's fascinating performance keeps it together. Despite all the movie faults, it is still worth a look. Based on a novel by Valerie Martin.(*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What do I like about this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like the fact that the film is told from Mary Reilly's point of view. Not only hers, but everyone else's too, like the naive servants, the furious Mrs. Faraday (the brothel mistress). Mary Reilly - the character - also has a disturbing, traumatizing background story and at some point Mr. Hyde gives a pretty heavy psychological spin on it. It's never elaborated on or seems ignored even, but this suits the tone of the film. Insinuating things often hits harder than explaining them. Through some of the characters, some of the possible little script flaws (or plot holes) get solved. For instance, doesn't anybody notice that Dr. Jekyll and his assistant Mr. Hyde look very much alike? Only Hyde looks younger. Sure people notice this, but one of the servants goes about assuming that Mr. Hyde might very well be a product of Jekyll's student days. As a bright student, Jekyll was popular with the ladies. And since Jekyll never got married, if he would have had a son... in those days it was even a sin to merely speak about or suggest a thing like this. I like John Malkovich's performance a lot and it's clear that him & Stephen Frears both understood very well what they wanted to achieve here. The good doc Jekyll (whom is looked upon in high regards by his servants) is far from kosher to the bone himself (we get hints at how he conducts his research and we know he's a regular client at Mrs. Faraday's house of pleasure). While on the other hand, Mr. Hyde as the savage beast, has his scarce moments of weakness for Mary Reilly. See what I'm getting at? And when looking at it from Mary's side, she unwillingly brings out the worst in the best, and the best in the worst, so to speak. Frears & Malkovich and screenwriter Christopher Hampton added shades of gray to a classic, one too many times told story that is basically just about black & white. The film got me really interested in reading the source novel it was based on. To see how it compares the film. What else is there to like? Enough, I think. Phillipe Rousselot's wonderful cinematography. A captivating musical score by George Stenton. As much as it's a character-driven story, it does feature a handful moments of the grotesque. Glenn Close gets decapitated. Dr. Jekyll is seen on the street repeatedly kicking a little girl in the stomach. An engrossing scene that shows how slaughtered meat for consumption is being traded in the streets, followed by an analogy towards the trade of human organs for the sake of science. Not sure whom all were responsible for these sequences -- I understand that Frears, for example, never intended the film to end like it did, with that climactic transformation sequence. But said sequences are a graphic reminder of the fact that we are watching a horrific story. At any rate, I didn't think they hurt the film. They injected it with the necessary dosage of brutality. The set design is marvelous and Dr. Jekyll's laboratory - or at least the way of getting there - is cleverly structured (as it helps crafting the suspense of a certain scene in a brilliant manner). The 19th century London setting works convincing, but we don't get to see much of it. The blocking & framing makes sure we usually only see one part of a street at a time. And to add to this claustrophobic & dark notion this film has, most scenes take place on indoors sets. But also these sets are put to great use. To Mary Reilly, the doctor's mansion starts off as a safe haven, a place offering a good job and a possible better future. But it doesn't take long for this house to get infested with the evil of Mr. Hyde's presence at night. So much even, that it starts to haunt her dreams. This shift in tone happens gradually, with a slow but impeccable pace. Truth be told, to me Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde always seemed a very simplistic story to tell. At least in the classic version as it got famous. It's good source material, yes, but Frears & Hampton managed to squeeze a much more interesting film out of it. Which probably could have even been a lot better if the producing studio at the time wasn't so concerned about how it would do at the box office. Voil&agrave;, that's it for what I like about this film. Notice that I didn't mention Julia Roberts' performance. It's very down-toned, as it should be. She is there not to be noticed, her character demands it and so does the story. And while she does have a lot of screen time, she doesn't do much, so there's just not much to say about her acting. But you can always 'see' the wheels of her character's thoughts grinding, as she is the only one who's trying to fathom what's going on. From all the servants, she's the only one that knows how to read. Dr. Jekyll discovers this very early on, when he spots her reading a book in his library. This, of course, titillates the good doc's mind. And that's the point in the film, as soon as it comes, where you instantly realize this is going to take a turn for the worse. In that moment, there's a harmless thing between them that will inevitably unleash unspeakable horrors. And this 'harmless thing' even is personified throughout the whole film. It goes by the name of Mary Reilly. A very interesting adaptation. And a good film, full stop.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Next up, The Time Machine told from the perspective of the traveller's postman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here's the tale of a scientist who descends into madness when a potion he creates splits his personality in two, told from the point of view of... his maid. What a strange choice. The movie is less interested in Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde than the woman who brings him his tea. Well, okay. Amongst the film's other misjudged elements are Julia Roberts' absolutely appalling Irish accent ('Ah, ye banged yer heed') and approximately nine hours worth of her looking sullen and hearing mysterious goings on. It's a boring film, drab and dreary. Glenn Close turns in a truly bizarre performance as a madam and John Malkovich is well cast as the-- I was about to say as the title character, herp derp  but they can't liven this thing up when the most interesting parts of the story are on the outskirts of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    correct work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    recreation of Victorian atmosphere. version of old story. inspired cast. ivory skin of central character. and John Malkovich. a film like a visit in museum. each piece on perfect place, each step as key for a treasure. strange flavor, cold touch. and air of love story. maybe, it is not convincing. but it is beautiful. and delicate like a silk butterfly. it is not very realistic but charm of each performance is necessary brick for a not really bad building. it is a kind of travel and fascination of viewer is secret satisfaction to know the truth at beginning. sure, Julia Roberts is not extraordinary but her work is correct. and this fact is important. like sign of a meeting between two fascinating actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The true horror is being forced to sit through this mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bults-356-93740
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to begin... How about the bland scenery? Bricks, fog, doors, fog, even the garden feels bland and lifeless. How about the so called "character study"? Well after watching this we now know that Mary is a ditz who makes Christine Daae look like Margarate Thatcher. We also know that she's (Spoiler!!! well... sort of) afraid of rats, and that her father was an absolute prick. Oh you wanted to know about Jekyll and Hyde's character? HA! You never learn anything you didn't already know about them other than their love of spouting exposition and "shocking" the audience with unexplained violence seemingly without any clear motive. In short, this movie will do its very best to "shock" and "scare" you but will ultimately only manage to disgust you. The only redeeming qualities are the impressive (but really very silly) transformation scene, one good jump scare, and laughing at Julia Roberts' "Irish" accent. Otherwise, this is an unrelentingly unpleasant movie that will leave you feeling empty. You will take NOTHING from this film, quite the contrary, it feels like it's taken something from you! Bottom line, don't watch this sick, poorly slapped together, bloody mess of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dr. Good and Mr.Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Mary Reilly, is the tale about good and evil. And how the two tore apart the soul of one man,driving him to madness.This man was a doctor by day and a killer by night.He was a healer of man loved by all who knew him.And at night he was someone that was feared by all that he meant a long the streets.He would have black outs and could not remember what he did at all.He killed many people, got away with it for a long time because; his other half would hide him in the darkness of his mind. Julia Roberts (aka Mary Reilly) played the part very well. I loved this movie because,I feel torn between my good and bad half.We all have times when we feel this way. But there are some people that do not know the difference between the two.The story Mary Reilly was Written by Valerie Martin.The other name for this dark tale is Dr.Jekyll and Mr.Hyde. By Robert Louis Stevenson. This is my mom's take on this tale of good vs evil, within ones self! mine is the two worked well together , in this dark thriller. John Malkovich , portrayed both characters equally well ! He really made me believe he had two totally different personalities. He was that convincing, I too loved this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody re-telling of Dr. Jeckyl story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Critics and audiences were bored with this remake of the Dr. Jeckyl tale when it first came out, but there is nonetheless a lot here to like. The viewpoint shift, allowing viewers to watch the familiar tale play out from the perspective of a serving woman in the Doctor's household, gives both a romantic edge to the picture and makes points about the place and role of women/servants in English society in Jeckyl's day. Roberts is very good as the lowest member of the household staff, trying to hold the Doctor himself and the household together while at the same time striving not to get above her station. And the grim, nearly black-and-white, dread-filled landscape of the picture is great to look at and memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An undiscovered gem which Julia shines in.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jimmy Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I initially came across this film when I found out it was at one stage planned to be a Winona Ryder/Tim Burton vehicle, and I have to sat I was so impressed by it that it is now one of my favorite films. With a bit of research I got the idea that this was a bad stage in Julias career, but I have to say I have never seen her better than she is in this. Her performance is just astounding, she has thus innocence and vulnerability that I never thought I'd see coming from her, she embodies the character extremely well, so well that it would have been a crime to see anyone else in the role. John Malkovich ramps up the creepy factor in this movie, his performance is also just stellar, he is truly terrifying in the scenes where he is Jekyll. Another thing I like is that this is such a great retelling of the Jekyll/ Hyde story, it's the best one I've ever seen, I think one big advantage it has is that its told from an onlookers perspective and not from an unknown or first person perspective. The cinematography is wonderful, the constant shade of grey and the overlying layer of fog both help to create the dark and moody atmosphere. I think it's definitely a movie fans of the story would enjoy and also people who aren't so familiar with it. Top notch Gothic horror that deserves to be seen....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The woman who loved Dr.Jekyll
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** Somewhat altered version of the Robert Louis Stevenson classic "Doctor Jekyll and Mister Hyde" with the sweet kindly and understanding Doctor Jekyll, John Malkovich, having a love interest who's a housemaid Mary Reilly, Julia Roberts, at his London home where her conducts his secrets experiments. Mary had a hard life with her being abused both psychically and mentally by her drunken father Mr. Reilly, Michael Gambon, that she in fact feels that's her lot in life and can do nothing about it. It's working at Dr.Henry Jekyll place that for the first time in her life Mary finds kindness and understanding for her many problems that includes the scars that her father gave her, like having rats chew at her, while she was a child. The fact that Dr.Jekyll takes such an interest in Mary has her boss the manager of the Jekyll house Mr. Poole, George Cole, get a bit jealous at her for his master, Dr.Jekyll, spending far more time with Mary then with him. Mary for her part is a bit perplexed of Dr.Jekyll in his going in and out of his both house and laboratory all hours of the night as if he's hiding something that he doesn't want anyone to find out about! It's one day when Dr.Jekyll sends Mary on a errand to a cat-house in the red light district in the seedy part of London that she realizes that the good doctor is up to no good. Not that he's a customer of the place but that his special assistant at his laboratory someone named Edward Hyde has made a mess of the place,by brutalizing the hookers, every time he goes there. Mary is told by the angry cat-house Madam Mrs. Farraday, Glenn Close, that Eddie or Mr. Hyde has gotten out of hand and she can't keep covering up for him anymore. Dr.Jekyll in trying to smooth things out by giving her payoff money, so she doesn't report Eddie to the police, also asks Mrs. Farraday, through Mary, to drop in and see him at his laboratory to talk things over! As it turns out Mrs. Farraday is met at the house not by Dr. Jekyll but Mister Hyde who ends up doing her in by making her at least a head shorter! ***SPOILERS*** AS we and Mary Reilly soon find out that he mysterious Edward Hyde is really Doctor Jekyll in the flesh. The doc had been having splitting headaches of late and developed this medication for them. As things turned out the medication did stop the headaches but it turned the genteel and civil Dr.Jekyll into the murderous and sex crazed Edward or Mister Hyde! Edward Hyde for his part took a shine to Mary and unlike his other-self Doctor Jekyll he had no trouble in him not controlling himself in his feeling for her. It's when Edward Hyde attacks and kills one of the late Madam Farrady's John's or customers at her cat or whorehouse the member of British Parliament and good friend of Dr.Jekyll Sir.Danvers Carew, Claran Hinds, that the cops or London Bobbies are called in to check things out! It's discovered that the murder weapon that Hyde killed Carew with, by bashing his skull in, was Doctor Jekyll's silver plated walking stick! ***MAJOR SPOILERS*** Doctor Jekyll now knowing that his life is doomed in that his other-self, by Mister Hyde manipulating his headache medication, has completely taken over his body and asks Mary to do what he doesn't have the guts to to in her doing him in and putting an end to this mesaghas,insanity in Yiddish, once in for all. Mary in what has to be an act of eternal love does what the doctor told her to do but in that she leaves herself open in her being in the wrong place at the wrong time, at the scene of the Sir. Danvers murder, to take the rap for the crime committed by the now departed Dr.Jekyll/Mr. Hyde and having to pay for It very possibly with her life!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I shudder to think what would have followed if this misfire had been a box office smash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film tells the story of the chambermaid who worked for Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde. Thankfully, this turgid mess bombed at the box office so we were spared sequels about Dracula's chauffeur, Frankenstein's tax attorney and the Wolfman's proctologist. Mary Reilly (Julia Roberts) works as a maid for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich) in 19th century London. I kid you not when I state that this movie essentially follows Mary around while she does her household chores and every so often we get a scene that peeks in on the classic tale of Jekyll and Hyde. If you don't know what that story's about, go down to the damn library and check out the book or watch one of the 37,000,000,000 other versions of the tale that have been committed to film. Basically, this thing is a Cliff's Notes version of Jekyll and Hyde, crossed with a documentary on the brutal drudgery of 19th century working class Britons, mixed with a Lifetime movie about a woman overcoming her memories of fatherly abuse. The heart of Mary Reilly is supposed to be about the attraction Mary feels for both Jekyll and Hyde and the affection they feel in return. A big problem is that it's hard to believe any man being lovestruck by this pale-faced woman with Conan O'Brien eyebrows. Julia Roberts is deliberately stripped of most of the beauty artifice that props up her appearance in other films and the audience is undeniably confronted with the fact that Roberts is not that pretty. She has very distinct features that need to be accommodated on screen and that doesn't happen here. Another defining negative about this film is very poor acting jobs by three big stars. Roberts intermittently adopts an Irish accent that rivals Kevin Costner's dialect in Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves for its "now you hear it, now you don't" quality. John Malkovich does worse than sleepwalk through his double role, even giving Edward Hyde an extremely pronounced limp early in the film which completely disappears later on. Either Malkovich and director Stephen Frears both forgot about the limp or Malkovich just got tired of doing it and Frears couldn't make him. Glenn Close is almost as bad as the owner of a London brothel. Her entire performance consists of giving her character an Elvis lip curl. The bottom line is that Mary Reilly is a movie about an uninteresting woman who stands still while an amazing story happens around her. The idea of telling a famous tale from the perspective of a minor character isn't a bad one. A movie about the London cop trying to track down and capture Edward Hyde sounds good to me. The trick is the minor character actually has to do something important in the story. Mary Reilly simply hovers and watches like the boring person on a reality show. Unless you're dying to view YET ANOTHER crappy adaptation of Jekyll and Hyde, skip this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawed period thriller is worth watching for the two lead performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An pretty but shy, depressed and lonely housemaid by the name of Mary Reilly (Oscar-Winner:Julia Roberts) works for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich). When Dr. Jekyll is working on a experiment, he tells his staff (George Cole, Michael Sheen, Kathy Staff and Bronagh Gallagher) and Mary that he will have an assistant working with him. But the stuff never fully sees him and remains an mystery. But when Mary gets closer to Dr. Jekyll talking about her awful childhood to him, begin abused by her drunken mean-spirited father (Michael Gambon). Mary finds herself slowly falling in love with Dr. Jekyll but soon discovers that Dr. Jekyll has an dark side and his mysterious assistant might be related to him. Directed by Stephen Frears (The Grifters, Hero, The Hours) made an very flawed but intriguing period suspense thriller with good performances by Roberts and Malkovich. The bleak setting is nicely done by production designer:Staurt Craig (The Harry Potter Series, Chaplin, The Secret Garden) and Glenn Close has fun in her minor role as a madam. Although there was trouble during production, because Roberts and Malkovich didn't get along. The film was also over budgeted and problems with Christopher Hampton's (Atonement, The Secret Agent, Total Eclipse) script. "Mary Reilly" ended up being re-shot in the end, despite it was an reunion from the Cast and Crew of "Dangerous Liaisions" for director:Frears, screenwriter:Hampton, actors:Malkovich & Close, producer:Norma Heyman, composer:George Fenton, cinematographer:Philippe Rousselot, production designer:Craig and casting director:Juliet Taylor. "Mary Reilly" does have an minor cult following, some might complain that Roberts was mis-cast but i thought she did well with his performance (Which she smiled only once in the film). One of the highlights is towards the end with Dr. Jekyll's character. Although watching the movie, it does look like at times, the movie had an troubled production. It's very flawed at times but it's Malkovich's fascinating performance keeps it together. Despite all the movie faults, it is still worth a look. Based on a novel by Valerie Martin.(*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What do I like about this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like the fact that the film is told from Mary Reilly's point of view. Not only hers, but everyone else's too, like the naive servants, the furious Mrs. Faraday (the brothel mistress). Mary Reilly - the character - also has a disturbing, traumatizing background story and at some point Mr. Hyde gives a pretty heavy psychological spin on it. It's never elaborated on or seems ignored even, but this suits the tone of the film. Insinuating things often hits harder than explaining them. Through some of the characters, some of the possible little script flaws (or plot holes) get solved. For instance, doesn't anybody notice that Dr. Jekyll and his assistant Mr. Hyde look very much alike? Only Hyde looks younger. Sure people notice this, but one of the servants goes about assuming that Mr. Hyde might very well be a product of Jekyll's student days. As a bright student, Jekyll was popular with the ladies. And since Jekyll never got married, if he would have had a son... in those days it was even a sin to merely speak about or suggest a thing like this. I like John Malkovich's performance a lot and it's clear that him & Stephen Frears both understood very well what they wanted to achieve here. The good doc Jekyll (whom is looked upon in high regards by his servants) is far from kosher to the bone himself (we get hints at how he conducts his research and we know he's a regular client at Mrs. Faraday's house of pleasure). While on the other hand, Mr. Hyde as the savage beast, has his scarce moments of weakness for Mary Reilly. See what I'm getting at? And when looking at it from Mary's side, she unwillingly brings out the worst in the best, and the best in the worst, so to speak. Frears & Malkovich and screenwriter Christopher Hampton added shades of gray to a classic, one too many times told story that is basically just about black & white. The film got me really interested in reading the source novel it was based on. To see how it compares the film. What else is there to like? Enough, I think. Phillipe Rousselot's wonderful cinematography. A captivating musical score by George Stenton. As much as it's a character-driven story, it does feature a handful moments of the grotesque. Glenn Close gets decapitated. Dr. Jekyll is seen on the street repeatedly kicking a little girl in the stomach. An engrossing scene that shows how slaughtered meat for consumption is being traded in the streets, followed by an analogy towards the trade of human organs for the sake of science. Not sure whom all were responsible for these sequences -- I understand that Frears, for example, never intended the film to end like it did, with that climactic transformation sequence. But said sequences are a graphic reminder of the fact that we are watching a horrific story. At any rate, I didn't think they hurt the film. They injected it with the necessary dosage of brutality. The set design is marvelous and Dr. Jekyll's laboratory - or at least the way of getting there - is cleverly structured (as it helps crafting the suspense of a certain scene in a brilliant manner). The 19th century London setting works convincing, but we don't get to see much of it. The blocking & framing makes sure we usually only see one part of a street at a time. And to add to this claustrophobic & dark notion this film has, most scenes take place on indoors sets. But also these sets are put to great use. To Mary Reilly, the doctor's mansion starts off as a safe haven, a place offering a good job and a possible better future. But it doesn't take long for this house to get infested with the evil of Mr. Hyde's presence at night. So much even, that it starts to haunt her dreams. This shift in tone happens gradually, with a slow but impeccable pace. Truth be told, to me Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde always seemed a very simplistic story to tell. At least in the classic version as it got famous. It's good source material, yes, but Frears & Hampton managed to squeeze a much more interesting film out of it. Which probably could have even been a lot better if the producing studio at the time wasn't so concerned about how it would do at the box office. Voil&agrave;, that's it for what I like about this film. Notice that I didn't mention Julia Roberts' performance. It's very down-toned, as it should be. She is there not to be noticed, her character demands it and so does the story. And while she does have a lot of screen time, she doesn't do much, so there's just not much to say about her acting. But you can always 'see' the wheels of her character's thoughts grinding, as she is the only one who's trying to fathom what's going on. From all the servants, she's the only one that knows how to read. Dr. Jekyll discovers this very early on, when he spots her reading a book in his library. This, of course, titillates the good doc's mind. And that's the point in the film, as soon as it comes, where you instantly realize this is going to take a turn for the worse. In that moment, there's a harmless thing between them that will inevitably unleash unspeakable horrors. And this 'harmless thing' even is personified throughout the whole film. It goes by the name of Mary Reilly. A very interesting adaptation. And a good film, full stop.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Next up, The Time Machine told from the perspective of the traveller's postman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here's the tale of a scientist who descends into madness when a potion he creates splits his personality in two, told from the point of view of... his maid. What a strange choice. The movie is less interested in Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde than the woman who brings him his tea. Well, okay. Amongst the film's other misjudged elements are Julia Roberts' absolutely appalling Irish accent ('Ah, ye banged yer heed') and approximately nine hours worth of her looking sullen and hearing mysterious goings on. It's a boring film, drab and dreary. Glenn Close turns in a truly bizarre performance as a madam and John Malkovich is well cast as the-- I was about to say as the title character, herp derp  but they can't liven this thing up when the most interesting parts of the story are on the outskirts of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    correct work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    recreation of Victorian atmosphere. version of old story. inspired cast. ivory skin of central character. and John Malkovich. a film like a visit in museum. each piece on perfect place, each step as key for a treasure. strange flavor, cold touch. and air of love story. maybe, it is not convincing. but it is beautiful. and delicate like a silk butterfly. it is not very realistic but charm of each performance is necessary brick for a not really bad building. it is a kind of travel and fascination of viewer is secret satisfaction to know the truth at beginning. sure, Julia Roberts is not extraordinary but her work is correct. and this fact is important. like sign of a meeting between two fascinating actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The true horror is being forced to sit through this mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bults-356-93740
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to begin... How about the bland scenery? Bricks, fog, doors, fog, even the garden feels bland and lifeless. How about the so called "character study"? Well after watching this we now know that Mary is a ditz who makes Christine Daae look like Margarate Thatcher. We also know that she's (Spoiler!!! well... sort of) afraid of rats, and that her father was an absolute prick. Oh you wanted to know about Jekyll and Hyde's character? HA! You never learn anything you didn't already know about them other than their love of spouting exposition and "shocking" the audience with unexplained violence seemingly without any clear motive. In short, this movie will do its very best to "shock" and "scare" you but will ultimately only manage to disgust you. The only redeeming qualities are the impressive (but really very silly) transformation scene, one good jump scare, and laughing at Julia Roberts' "Irish" accent. Otherwise, this is an unrelentingly unpleasant movie that will leave you feeling empty. You will take NOTHING from this film, quite the contrary, it feels like it's taken something from you! Bottom line, don't watch this sick, poorly slapped together, bloody mess of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dr. Good and Mr.Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Mary Reilly, is the tale about good and evil. And how the two tore apart the soul of one man,driving him to madness.This man was a doctor by day and a killer by night.He was a healer of man loved by all who knew him.And at night he was someone that was feared by all that he meant a long the streets.He would have black outs and could not remember what he did at all.He killed many people, got away with it for a long time because; his other half would hide him in the darkness of his mind. Julia Roberts (aka Mary Reilly) played the part very well. I loved this movie because,I feel torn between my good and bad half.We all have times when we feel this way. But there are some people that do not know the difference between the two.The story Mary Reilly was Written by Valerie Martin.The other name for this dark tale is Dr.Jekyll and Mr.Hyde. By Robert Louis Stevenson. This is my mom's take on this tale of good vs evil, within ones self! mine is the two worked well together , in this dark thriller. John Malkovich , portrayed both characters equally well ! He really made me believe he had two totally different personalities. He was that convincing, I too loved this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody re-telling of Dr. Jeckyl story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Critics and audiences were bored with this remake of the Dr. Jeckyl tale when it first came out, but there is nonetheless a lot here to like. The viewpoint shift, allowing viewers to watch the familiar tale play out from the perspective of a serving woman in the Doctor's household, gives both a romantic edge to the picture and makes points about the place and role of women/servants in English society in Jeckyl's day. Roberts is very good as the lowest member of the household staff, trying to hold the Doctor himself and the household together while at the same time striving not to get above her station. And the grim, nearly black-and-white, dread-filled landscape of the picture is great to look at and memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An undiscovered gem which Julia shines in.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jimmy Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I initially came across this film when I found out it was at one stage planned to be a Winona Ryder/Tim Burton vehicle, and I have to sat I was so impressed by it that it is now one of my favorite films. With a bit of research I got the idea that this was a bad stage in Julias career, but I have to say I have never seen her better than she is in this. Her performance is just astounding, she has thus innocence and vulnerability that I never thought I'd see coming from her, she embodies the character extremely well, so well that it would have been a crime to see anyone else in the role. John Malkovich ramps up the creepy factor in this movie, his performance is also just stellar, he is truly terrifying in the scenes where he is Jekyll. Another thing I like is that this is such a great retelling of the Jekyll/ Hyde story, it's the best one I've ever seen, I think one big advantage it has is that its told from an onlookers perspective and not from an unknown or first person perspective. The cinematography is wonderful, the constant shade of grey and the overlying layer of fog both help to create the dark and moody atmosphere. I think it's definitely a movie fans of the story would enjoy and also people who aren't so familiar with it. Top notch Gothic horror that deserves to be seen....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The woman who loved Dr.Jekyll
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** Somewhat altered version of the Robert Louis Stevenson classic "Doctor Jekyll and Mister Hyde" with the sweet kindly and understanding Doctor Jekyll, John Malkovich, having a love interest who's a housemaid Mary Reilly, Julia Roberts, at his London home where her conducts his secrets experiments. Mary had a hard life with her being abused both psychically and mentally by her drunken father Mr. Reilly, Michael Gambon, that she in fact feels that's her lot in life and can do nothing about it. It's working at Dr.Henry Jekyll place that for the first time in her life Mary finds kindness and understanding for her many problems that includes the scars that her father gave her, like having rats chew at her, while she was a child. The fact that Dr.Jekyll takes such an interest in Mary has her boss the manager of the Jekyll house Mr. Poole, George Cole, get a bit jealous at her for his master, Dr.Jekyll, spending far more time with Mary then with him. Mary for her part is a bit perplexed of Dr.Jekyll in his going in and out of his both house and laboratory all hours of the night as if he's hiding something that he doesn't want anyone to find out about! It's one day when Dr.Jekyll sends Mary on a errand to a cat-house in the red light district in the seedy part of London that she realizes that the good doctor is up to no good. Not that he's a customer of the place but that his special assistant at his laboratory someone named Edward Hyde has made a mess of the place,by brutalizing the hookers, every time he goes there. Mary is told by the angry cat-house Madam Mrs. Farraday, Glenn Close, that Eddie or Mr. Hyde has gotten out of hand and she can't keep covering up for him anymore. Dr.Jekyll in trying to smooth things out by giving her payoff money, so she doesn't report Eddie to the police, also asks Mrs. Farraday, through Mary, to drop in and see him at his laboratory to talk things over! As it turns out Mrs. Farraday is met at the house not by Dr. Jekyll but Mister Hyde who ends up doing her in by making her at least a head shorter! ***SPOILERS*** AS we and Mary Reilly soon find out that he mysterious Edward Hyde is really Doctor Jekyll in the flesh. The doc had been having splitting headaches of late and developed this medication for them. As things turned out the medication did stop the headaches but it turned the genteel and civil Dr.Jekyll into the murderous and sex crazed Edward or Mister Hyde! Edward Hyde for his part took a shine to Mary and unlike his other-self Doctor Jekyll he had no trouble in him not controlling himself in his feeling for her. It's when Edward Hyde attacks and kills one of the late Madam Farrady's John's or customers at her cat or whorehouse the member of British Parliament and good friend of Dr.Jekyll Sir.Danvers Carew, Claran Hinds, that the cops or London Bobbies are called in to check things out! It's discovered that the murder weapon that Hyde killed Carew with, by bashing his skull in, was Doctor Jekyll's silver plated walking stick! ***MAJOR SPOILERS*** Doctor Jekyll now knowing that his life is doomed in that his other-self, by Mister Hyde manipulating his headache medication, has completely taken over his body and asks Mary to do what he doesn't have the guts to to in her doing him in and putting an end to this mesaghas,insanity in Yiddish, once in for all. Mary in what has to be an act of eternal love does what the doctor told her to do but in that she leaves herself open in her being in the wrong place at the wrong time, at the scene of the Sir. Danvers murder, to take the rap for the crime committed by the now departed Dr.Jekyll/Mr. Hyde and having to pay for It very possibly with her life!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I shudder to think what would have followed if this misfire had been a box office smash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film tells the story of the chambermaid who worked for Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde. Thankfully, this turgid mess bombed at the box office so we were spared sequels about Dracula's chauffeur, Frankenstein's tax attorney and the Wolfman's proctologist. Mary Reilly (Julia Roberts) works as a maid for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich) in 19th century London. I kid you not when I state that this movie essentially follows Mary around while she does her household chores and every so often we get a scene that peeks in on the classic tale of Jekyll and Hyde. If you don't know what that story's about, go down to the damn library and check out the book or watch one of the 37,000,000,000 other versions of the tale that have been committed to film. Basically, this thing is a Cliff's Notes version of Jekyll and Hyde, crossed with a documentary on the brutal drudgery of 19th century working class Britons, mixed with a Lifetime movie about a woman overcoming her memories of fatherly abuse. The heart of Mary Reilly is supposed to be about the attraction Mary feels for both Jekyll and Hyde and the affection they feel in return. A big problem is that it's hard to believe any man being lovestruck by this pale-faced woman with Conan O'Brien eyebrows. Julia Roberts is deliberately stripped of most of the beauty artifice that props up her appearance in other films and the audience is undeniably confronted with the fact that Roberts is not that pretty. She has very distinct features that need to be accommodated on screen and that doesn't happen here. Another defining negative about this film is very poor acting jobs by three big stars. Roberts intermittently adopts an Irish accent that rivals Kevin Costner's dialect in Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves for its "now you hear it, now you don't" quality. John Malkovich does worse than sleepwalk through his double role, even giving Edward Hyde an extremely pronounced limp early in the film which completely disappears later on. Either Malkovich and director Stephen Frears both forgot about the limp or Malkovich just got tired of doing it and Frears couldn't make him. Glenn Close is almost as bad as the owner of a London brothel. Her entire performance consists of giving her character an Elvis lip curl. The bottom line is that Mary Reilly is a movie about an uninteresting woman who stands still while an amazing story happens around her. The idea of telling a famous tale from the perspective of a minor character isn't a bad one. A movie about the London cop trying to track down and capture Edward Hyde sounds good to me. The trick is the minor character actually has to do something important in the story. Mary Reilly simply hovers and watches like the boring person on a reality show. Unless you're dying to view YET ANOTHER crappy adaptation of Jekyll and Hyde, skip this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawed period thriller is worth watching for the two lead performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An pretty but shy, depressed and lonely housemaid by the name of Mary Reilly (Oscar-Winner:Julia Roberts) works for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich). When Dr. Jekyll is working on a experiment, he tells his staff (George Cole, Michael Sheen, Kathy Staff and Bronagh Gallagher) and Mary that he will have an assistant working with him. But the stuff never fully sees him and remains an mystery. But when Mary gets closer to Dr. Jekyll talking about her awful childhood to him, begin abused by her drunken mean-spirited father (Michael Gambon). Mary finds herself slowly falling in love with Dr. Jekyll but soon discovers that Dr. Jekyll has an dark side and his mysterious assistant might be related to him. Directed by Stephen Frears (The Grifters, Hero, The Hours) made an very flawed but intriguing period suspense thriller with good performances by Roberts and Malkovich. The bleak setting is nicely done by production designer:Staurt Craig (The Harry Potter Series, Chaplin, The Secret Garden) and Glenn Close has fun in her minor role as a madam. Although there was trouble during production, because Roberts and Malkovich didn't get along. The film was also over budgeted and problems with Christopher Hampton's (Atonement, The Secret Agent, Total Eclipse) script. "Mary Reilly" ended up being re-shot in the end, despite it was an reunion from the Cast and Crew of "Dangerous Liaisions" for director:Frears, screenwriter:Hampton, actors:Malkovich & Close, producer:Norma Heyman, composer:George Fenton, cinematographer:Philippe Rousselot, production designer:Craig and casting director:Juliet Taylor. "Mary Reilly" does have an minor cult following, some might complain that Roberts was mis-cast but i thought she did well with his performance (Which she smiled only once in the film). One of the highlights is towards the end with Dr. Jekyll's character. Although watching the movie, it does look like at times, the movie had an troubled production. It's very flawed at times but it's Malkovich's fascinating performance keeps it together. Despite all the movie faults, it is still worth a look. Based on a novel by Valerie Martin.(*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What do I like about this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like the fact that the film is told from Mary Reilly's point of view. Not only hers, but everyone else's too, like the naive servants, the furious Mrs. Faraday (the brothel mistress). Mary Reilly - the character - also has a disturbing, traumatizing background story and at some point Mr. Hyde gives a pretty heavy psychological spin on it. It's never elaborated on or seems ignored even, but this suits the tone of the film. Insinuating things often hits harder than explaining them. Through some of the characters, some of the possible little script flaws (or plot holes) get solved. For instance, doesn't anybody notice that Dr. Jekyll and his assistant Mr. Hyde look very much alike? Only Hyde looks younger. Sure people notice this, but one of the servants goes about assuming that Mr. Hyde might very well be a product of Jekyll's student days. As a bright student, Jekyll was popular with the ladies. And since Jekyll never got married, if he would have had a son... in those days it was even a sin to merely speak about or suggest a thing like this. I like John Malkovich's performance a lot and it's clear that him & Stephen Frears both understood very well what they wanted to achieve here. The good doc Jekyll (whom is looked upon in high regards by his servants) is far from kosher to the bone himself (we get hints at how he conducts his research and we know he's a regular client at Mrs. Faraday's house of pleasure). While on the other hand, Mr. Hyde as the savage beast, has his scarce moments of weakness for Mary Reilly. See what I'm getting at? And when looking at it from Mary's side, she unwillingly brings out the worst in the best, and the best in the worst, so to speak. Frears & Malkovich and screenwriter Christopher Hampton added shades of gray to a classic, one too many times told story that is basically just about black & white. The film got me really interested in reading the source novel it was based on. To see how it compares the film. What else is there to like? Enough, I think. Phillipe Rousselot's wonderful cinematography. A captivating musical score by George Stenton. As much as it's a character-driven story, it does feature a handful moments of the grotesque. Glenn Close gets decapitated. Dr. Jekyll is seen on the street repeatedly kicking a little girl in the stomach. An engrossing scene that shows how slaughtered meat for consumption is being traded in the streets, followed by an analogy towards the trade of human organs for the sake of science. Not sure whom all were responsible for these sequences -- I understand that Frears, for example, never intended the film to end like it did, with that climactic transformation sequence. But said sequences are a graphic reminder of the fact that we are watching a horrific story. At any rate, I didn't think they hurt the film. They injected it with the necessary dosage of brutality. The set design is marvelous and Dr. Jekyll's laboratory - or at least the way of getting there - is cleverly structured (as it helps crafting the suspense of a certain scene in a brilliant manner). The 19th century London setting works convincing, but we don't get to see much of it. The blocking & framing makes sure we usually only see one part of a street at a time. And to add to this claustrophobic & dark notion this film has, most scenes take place on indoors sets. But also these sets are put to great use. To Mary Reilly, the doctor's mansion starts off as a safe haven, a place offering a good job and a possible better future. But it doesn't take long for this house to get infested with the evil of Mr. Hyde's presence at night. So much even, that it starts to haunt her dreams. This shift in tone happens gradually, with a slow but impeccable pace. Truth be told, to me Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde always seemed a very simplistic story to tell. At least in the classic version as it got famous. It's good source material, yes, but Frears & Hampton managed to squeeze a much more interesting film out of it. Which probably could have even been a lot better if the producing studio at the time wasn't so concerned about how it would do at the box office. Voil&agrave;, that's it for what I like about this film. Notice that I didn't mention Julia Roberts' performance. It's very down-toned, as it should be. She is there not to be noticed, her character demands it and so does the story. And while she does have a lot of screen time, she doesn't do much, so there's just not much to say about her acting. But you can always 'see' the wheels of her character's thoughts grinding, as she is the only one who's trying to fathom what's going on. From all the servants, she's the only one that knows how to read. Dr. Jekyll discovers this very early on, when he spots her reading a book in his library. This, of course, titillates the good doc's mind. And that's the point in the film, as soon as it comes, where you instantly realize this is going to take a turn for the worse. In that moment, there's a harmless thing between them that will inevitably unleash unspeakable horrors. And this 'harmless thing' even is personified throughout the whole film. It goes by the name of Mary Reilly. A very interesting adaptation. And a good film, full stop.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Next up, The Time Machine told from the perspective of the traveller's postman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here's the tale of a scientist who descends into madness when a potion he creates splits his personality in two, told from the point of view of... his maid. What a strange choice. The movie is less interested in Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde than the woman who brings him his tea. Well, okay. Amongst the film's other misjudged elements are Julia Roberts' absolutely appalling Irish accent ('Ah, ye banged yer heed') and approximately nine hours worth of her looking sullen and hearing mysterious goings on. It's a boring film, drab and dreary. Glenn Close turns in a truly bizarre performance as a madam and John Malkovich is well cast as the-- I was about to say as the title character, herp derp  but they can't liven this thing up when the most interesting parts of the story are on the outskirts of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    correct work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    recreation of Victorian atmosphere. version of old story. inspired cast. ivory skin of central character. and John Malkovich. a film like a visit in museum. each piece on perfect place, each step as key for a treasure. strange flavor, cold touch. and air of love story. maybe, it is not convincing. but it is beautiful. and delicate like a silk butterfly. it is not very realistic but charm of each performance is necessary brick for a not really bad building. it is a kind of travel and fascination of viewer is secret satisfaction to know the truth at beginning. sure, Julia Roberts is not extraordinary but her work is correct. and this fact is important. like sign of a meeting between two fascinating actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The true horror is being forced to sit through this mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bults-356-93740
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to begin... How about the bland scenery? Bricks, fog, doors, fog, even the garden feels bland and lifeless. How about the so called "character study"? Well after watching this we now know that Mary is a ditz who makes Christine Daae look like Margarate Thatcher. We also know that she's (Spoiler!!! well... sort of) afraid of rats, and that her father was an absolute prick. Oh you wanted to know about Jekyll and Hyde's character? HA! You never learn anything you didn't already know about them other than their love of spouting exposition and "shocking" the audience with unexplained violence seemingly without any clear motive. In short, this movie will do its very best to "shock" and "scare" you but will ultimately only manage to disgust you. The only redeeming qualities are the impressive (but really very silly) transformation scene, one good jump scare, and laughing at Julia Roberts' "Irish" accent. Otherwise, this is an unrelentingly unpleasant movie that will leave you feeling empty. You will take NOTHING from this film, quite the contrary, it feels like it's taken something from you! Bottom line, don't watch this sick, poorly slapped together, bloody mess of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dr. Good and Mr.Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Mary Reilly, is the tale about good and evil. And how the two tore apart the soul of one man,driving him to madness.This man was a doctor by day and a killer by night.He was a healer of man loved by all who knew him.And at night he was someone that was feared by all that he meant a long the streets.He would have black outs and could not remember what he did at all.He killed many people, got away with it for a long time because; his other half would hide him in the darkness of his mind. Julia Roberts (aka Mary Reilly) played the part very well. I loved this movie because,I feel torn between my good and bad half.We all have times when we feel this way. But there are some people that do not know the difference between the two.The story Mary Reilly was Written by Valerie Martin.The other name for this dark tale is Dr.Jekyll and Mr.Hyde. By Robert Louis Stevenson. This is my mom's take on this tale of good vs evil, within ones self! mine is the two worked well together , in this dark thriller. John Malkovich , portrayed both characters equally well ! He really made me believe he had two totally different personalities. He was that convincing, I too loved this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody re-telling of Dr. Jeckyl story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Critics and audiences were bored with this remake of the Dr. Jeckyl tale when it first came out, but there is nonetheless a lot here to like. The viewpoint shift, allowing viewers to watch the familiar tale play out from the perspective of a serving woman in the Doctor's household, gives both a romantic edge to the picture and makes points about the place and role of women/servants in English society in Jeckyl's day. Roberts is very good as the lowest member of the household staff, trying to hold the Doctor himself and the household together while at the same time striving not to get above her station. And the grim, nearly black-and-white, dread-filled landscape of the picture is great to look at and memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An undiscovered gem which Julia shines in.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jimmy Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I initially came across this film when I found out it was at one stage planned to be a Winona Ryder/Tim Burton vehicle, and I have to sat I was so impressed by it that it is now one of my favorite films. With a bit of research I got the idea that this was a bad stage in Julias career, but I have to say I have never seen her better than she is in this. Her performance is just astounding, she has thus innocence and vulnerability that I never thought I'd see coming from her, she embodies the character extremely well, so well that it would have been a crime to see anyone else in the role. John Malkovich ramps up the creepy factor in this movie, his performance is also just stellar, he is truly terrifying in the scenes where he is Jekyll. Another thing I like is that this is such a great retelling of the Jekyll/ Hyde story, it's the best one I've ever seen, I think one big advantage it has is that its told from an onlookers perspective and not from an unknown or first person perspective. The cinematography is wonderful, the constant shade of grey and the overlying layer of fog both help to create the dark and moody atmosphere. I think it's definitely a movie fans of the story would enjoy and also people who aren't so familiar with it. Top notch Gothic horror that deserves to be seen....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The woman who loved Dr.Jekyll
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** Somewhat altered version of the Robert Louis Stevenson classic "Doctor Jekyll and Mister Hyde" with the sweet kindly and understanding Doctor Jekyll, John Malkovich, having a love interest who's a housemaid Mary Reilly, Julia Roberts, at his London home where her conducts his secrets experiments. Mary had a hard life with her being abused both psychically and mentally by her drunken father Mr. Reilly, Michael Gambon, that she in fact feels that's her lot in life and can do nothing about it. It's working at Dr.Henry Jekyll place that for the first time in her life Mary finds kindness and understanding for her many problems that includes the scars that her father gave her, like having rats chew at her, while she was a child. The fact that Dr.Jekyll takes such an interest in Mary has her boss the manager of the Jekyll house Mr. Poole, George Cole, get a bit jealous at her for his master, Dr.Jekyll, spending far more time with Mary then with him. Mary for her part is a bit perplexed of Dr.Jekyll in his going in and out of his both house and laboratory all hours of the night as if he's hiding something that he doesn't want anyone to find out about! It's one day when Dr.Jekyll sends Mary on a errand to a cat-house in the red light district in the seedy part of London that she realizes that the good doctor is up to no good. Not that he's a customer of the place but that his special assistant at his laboratory someone named Edward Hyde has made a mess of the place,by brutalizing the hookers, every time he goes there. Mary is told by the angry cat-house Madam Mrs. Farraday, Glenn Close, that Eddie or Mr. Hyde has gotten out of hand and she can't keep covering up for him anymore. Dr.Jekyll in trying to smooth things out by giving her payoff money, so she doesn't report Eddie to the police, also asks Mrs. Farraday, through Mary, to drop in and see him at his laboratory to talk things over! As it turns out Mrs. Farraday is met at the house not by Dr. Jekyll but Mister Hyde who ends up doing her in by making her at least a head shorter! ***SPOILERS*** AS we and Mary Reilly soon find out that he mysterious Edward Hyde is really Doctor Jekyll in the flesh. The doc had been having splitting headaches of late and developed this medication for them. As things turned out the medication did stop the headaches but it turned the genteel and civil Dr.Jekyll into the murderous and sex crazed Edward or Mister Hyde! Edward Hyde for his part took a shine to Mary and unlike his other-self Doctor Jekyll he had no trouble in him not controlling himself in his feeling for her. It's when Edward Hyde attacks and kills one of the late Madam Farrady's John's or customers at her cat or whorehouse the member of British Parliament and good friend of Dr.Jekyll Sir.Danvers Carew, Claran Hinds, that the cops or London Bobbies are called in to check things out! It's discovered that the murder weapon that Hyde killed Carew with, by bashing his skull in, was Doctor Jekyll's silver plated walking stick! ***MAJOR SPOILERS*** Doctor Jekyll now knowing that his life is doomed in that his other-self, by Mister Hyde manipulating his headache medication, has completely taken over his body and asks Mary to do what he doesn't have the guts to to in her doing him in and putting an end to this mesaghas,insanity in Yiddish, once in for all. Mary in what has to be an act of eternal love does what the doctor told her to do but in that she leaves herself open in her being in the wrong place at the wrong time, at the scene of the Sir. Danvers murder, to take the rap for the crime committed by the now departed Dr.Jekyll/Mr. Hyde and having to pay for It very possibly with her life!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I shudder to think what would have followed if this misfire had been a box office smash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film tells the story of the chambermaid who worked for Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde. Thankfully, this turgid mess bombed at the box office so we were spared sequels about Dracula's chauffeur, Frankenstein's tax attorney and the Wolfman's proctologist. Mary Reilly (Julia Roberts) works as a maid for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich) in 19th century London. I kid you not when I state that this movie essentially follows Mary around while she does her household chores and every so often we get a scene that peeks in on the classic tale of Jekyll and Hyde. If you don't know what that story's about, go down to the damn library and check out the book or watch one of the 37,000,000,000 other versions of the tale that have been committed to film. Basically, this thing is a Cliff's Notes version of Jekyll and Hyde, crossed with a documentary on the brutal drudgery of 19th century working class Britons, mixed with a Lifetime movie about a woman overcoming her memories of fatherly abuse. The heart of Mary Reilly is supposed to be about the attraction Mary feels for both Jekyll and Hyde and the affection they feel in return. A big problem is that it's hard to believe any man being lovestruck by this pale-faced woman with Conan O'Brien eyebrows. Julia Roberts is deliberately stripped of most of the beauty artifice that props up her appearance in other films and the audience is undeniably confronted with the fact that Roberts is not that pretty. She has very distinct features that need to be accommodated on screen and that doesn't happen here. Another defining negative about this film is very poor acting jobs by three big stars. Roberts intermittently adopts an Irish accent that rivals Kevin Costner's dialect in Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves for its "now you hear it, now you don't" quality. John Malkovich does worse than sleepwalk through his double role, even giving Edward Hyde an extremely pronounced limp early in the film which completely disappears later on. Either Malkovich and director Stephen Frears both forgot about the limp or Malkovich just got tired of doing it and Frears couldn't make him. Glenn Close is almost as bad as the owner of a London brothel. Her entire performance consists of giving her character an Elvis lip curl. The bottom line is that Mary Reilly is a movie about an uninteresting woman who stands still while an amazing story happens around her. The idea of telling a famous tale from the perspective of a minor character isn't a bad one. A movie about the London cop trying to track down and capture Edward Hyde sounds good to me. The trick is the minor character actually has to do something important in the story. Mary Reilly simply hovers and watches like the boring person on a reality show. Unless you're dying to view YET ANOTHER crappy adaptation of Jekyll and Hyde, skip this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawed period thriller is worth watching for the two lead performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An pretty but shy, depressed and lonely housemaid by the name of Mary Reilly (Oscar-Winner:Julia Roberts) works for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich). When Dr. Jekyll is working on a experiment, he tells his staff (George Cole, Michael Sheen, Kathy Staff and Bronagh Gallagher) and Mary that he will have an assistant working with him. But the stuff never fully sees him and remains an mystery. But when Mary gets closer to Dr. Jekyll talking about her awful childhood to him, begin abused by her drunken mean-spirited father (Michael Gambon). Mary finds herself slowly falling in love with Dr. Jekyll but soon discovers that Dr. Jekyll has an dark side and his mysterious assistant might be related to him. Directed by Stephen Frears (The Grifters, Hero, The Hours) made an very flawed but intriguing period suspense thriller with good performances by Roberts and Malkovich. The bleak setting is nicely done by production designer:Staurt Craig (The Harry Potter Series, Chaplin, The Secret Garden) and Glenn Close has fun in her minor role as a madam. Although there was trouble during production, because Roberts and Malkovich didn't get along. The film was also over budgeted and problems with Christopher Hampton's (Atonement, The Secret Agent, Total Eclipse) script. "Mary Reilly" ended up being re-shot in the end, despite it was an reunion from the Cast and Crew of "Dangerous Liaisions" for director:Frears, screenwriter:Hampton, actors:Malkovich & Close, producer:Norma Heyman, composer:George Fenton, cinematographer:Philippe Rousselot, production designer:Craig and casting director:Juliet Taylor. "Mary Reilly" does have an minor cult following, some might complain that Roberts was mis-cast but i thought she did well with his performance (Which she smiled only once in the film). One of the highlights is towards the end with Dr. Jekyll's character. Although watching the movie, it does look like at times, the movie had an troubled production. It's very flawed at times but it's Malkovich's fascinating performance keeps it together. Despite all the movie faults, it is still worth a look. Based on a novel by Valerie Martin.(*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What do I like about this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like the fact that the film is told from Mary Reilly's point of view. Not only hers, but everyone else's too, like the naive servants, the furious Mrs. Faraday (the brothel mistress). Mary Reilly - the character - also has a disturbing, traumatizing background story and at some point Mr. Hyde gives a pretty heavy psychological spin on it. It's never elaborated on or seems ignored even, but this suits the tone of the film. Insinuating things often hits harder than explaining them. Through some of the characters, some of the possible little script flaws (or plot holes) get solved. For instance, doesn't anybody notice that Dr. Jekyll and his assistant Mr. Hyde look very much alike? Only Hyde looks younger. Sure people notice this, but one of the servants goes about assuming that Mr. Hyde might very well be a product of Jekyll's student days. As a bright student, Jekyll was popular with the ladies. And since Jekyll never got married, if he would have had a son... in those days it was even a sin to merely speak about or suggest a thing like this. I like John Malkovich's performance a lot and it's clear that him & Stephen Frears both understood very well what they wanted to achieve here. The good doc Jekyll (whom is looked upon in high regards by his servants) is far from kosher to the bone himself (we get hints at how he conducts his research and we know he's a regular client at Mrs. Faraday's house of pleasure). While on the other hand, Mr. Hyde as the savage beast, has his scarce moments of weakness for Mary Reilly. See what I'm getting at? And when looking at it from Mary's side, she unwillingly brings out the worst in the best, and the best in the worst, so to speak. Frears & Malkovich and screenwriter Christopher Hampton added shades of gray to a classic, one too many times told story that is basically just about black & white. The film got me really interested in reading the source novel it was based on. To see how it compares the film. What else is there to like? Enough, I think. Phillipe Rousselot's wonderful cinematography. A captivating musical score by George Stenton. As much as it's a character-driven story, it does feature a handful moments of the grotesque. Glenn Close gets decapitated. Dr. Jekyll is seen on the street repeatedly kicking a little girl in the stomach. An engrossing scene that shows how slaughtered meat for consumption is being traded in the streets, followed by an analogy towards the trade of human organs for the sake of science. Not sure whom all were responsible for these sequences -- I understand that Frears, for example, never intended the film to end like it did, with that climactic transformation sequence. But said sequences are a graphic reminder of the fact that we are watching a horrific story. At any rate, I didn't think they hurt the film. They injected it with the necessary dosage of brutality. The set design is marvelous and Dr. Jekyll's laboratory - or at least the way of getting there - is cleverly structured (as it helps crafting the suspense of a certain scene in a brilliant manner). The 19th century London setting works convincing, but we don't get to see much of it. The blocking & framing makes sure we usually only see one part of a street at a time. And to add to this claustrophobic & dark notion this film has, most scenes take place on indoors sets. But also these sets are put to great use. To Mary Reilly, the doctor's mansion starts off as a safe haven, a place offering a good job and a possible better future. But it doesn't take long for this house to get infested with the evil of Mr. Hyde's presence at night. So much even, that it starts to haunt her dreams. This shift in tone happens gradually, with a slow but impeccable pace. Truth be told, to me Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde always seemed a very simplistic story to tell. At least in the classic version as it got famous. It's good source material, yes, but Frears & Hampton managed to squeeze a much more interesting film out of it. Which probably could have even been a lot better if the producing studio at the time wasn't so concerned about how it would do at the box office. Voil&agrave;, that's it for what I like about this film. Notice that I didn't mention Julia Roberts' performance. It's very down-toned, as it should be. She is there not to be noticed, her character demands it and so does the story. And while she does have a lot of screen time, she doesn't do much, so there's just not much to say about her acting. But you can always 'see' the wheels of her character's thoughts grinding, as she is the only one who's trying to fathom what's going on. From all the servants, she's the only one that knows how to read. Dr. Jekyll discovers this very early on, when he spots her reading a book in his library. This, of course, titillates the good doc's mind. And that's the point in the film, as soon as it comes, where you instantly realize this is going to take a turn for the worse. In that moment, there's a harmless thing between them that will inevitably unleash unspeakable horrors. And this 'harmless thing' even is personified throughout the whole film. It goes by the name of Mary Reilly. A very interesting adaptation. And a good film, full stop.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Next up, The Time Machine told from the perspective of the traveller's postman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here's the tale of a scientist who descends into madness when a potion he creates splits his personality in two, told from the point of view of... his maid. What a strange choice. The movie is less interested in Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde than the woman who brings him his tea. Well, okay. Amongst the film's other misjudged elements are Julia Roberts' absolutely appalling Irish accent ('Ah, ye banged yer heed') and approximately nine hours worth of her looking sullen and hearing mysterious goings on. It's a boring film, drab and dreary. Glenn Close turns in a truly bizarre performance as a madam and John Malkovich is well cast as the-- I was about to say as the title character, herp derp  but they can't liven this thing up when the most interesting parts of the story are on the outskirts of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    correct work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    recreation of Victorian atmosphere. version of old story. inspired cast. ivory skin of central character. and John Malkovich. a film like a visit in museum. each piece on perfect place, each step as key for a treasure. strange flavor, cold touch. and air of love story. maybe, it is not convincing. but it is beautiful. and delicate like a silk butterfly. it is not very realistic but charm of each performance is necessary brick for a not really bad building. it is a kind of travel and fascination of viewer is secret satisfaction to know the truth at beginning. sure, Julia Roberts is not extraordinary but her work is correct. and this fact is important. like sign of a meeting between two fascinating actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The true horror is being forced to sit through this mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bults-356-93740
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to begin... How about the bland scenery? Bricks, fog, doors, fog, even the garden feels bland and lifeless. How about the so called "character study"? Well after watching this we now know that Mary is a ditz who makes Christine Daae look like Margarate Thatcher. We also know that she's (Spoiler!!! well... sort of) afraid of rats, and that her father was an absolute prick. Oh you wanted to know about Jekyll and Hyde's character? HA! You never learn anything you didn't already know about them other than their love of spouting exposition and "shocking" the audience with unexplained violence seemingly without any clear motive. In short, this movie will do its very best to "shock" and "scare" you but will ultimately only manage to disgust you. The only redeeming qualities are the impressive (but really very silly) transformation scene, one good jump scare, and laughing at Julia Roberts' "Irish" accent. Otherwise, this is an unrelentingly unpleasant movie that will leave you feeling empty. You will take NOTHING from this film, quite the contrary, it feels like it's taken something from you! Bottom line, don't watch this sick, poorly slapped together, bloody mess of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dr. Good and Mr.Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie Mary Reilly, is the tale about good and evil. And how the two tore apart the soul of one man,driving him to madness.This man was a doctor by day and a killer by night.He was a healer of man loved by all who knew him.And at night he was someone that was feared by all that he meant a long the streets.He would have black outs and could not remember what he did at all.He killed many people, got away with it for a long time because; his other half would hide him in the darkness of his mind. Julia Roberts (aka Mary Reilly) played the part very well. I loved this movie because,I feel torn between my good and bad half.We all have times when we feel this way. But there are some people that do not know the difference between the two.The story Mary Reilly was Written by Valerie Martin.The other name for this dark tale is Dr.Jekyll and Mr.Hyde. By Robert Louis Stevenson. This is my mom's take on this tale of good vs evil, within ones self! mine is the two worked well together , in this dark thriller. John Malkovich , portrayed both characters equally well ! He really made me believe he had two totally different personalities. He was that convincing, I too loved this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody re-telling of Dr. Jeckyl story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Critics and audiences were bored with this remake of the Dr. Jeckyl tale when it first came out, but there is nonetheless a lot here to like. The viewpoint shift, allowing viewers to watch the familiar tale play out from the perspective of a serving woman in the Doctor's household, gives both a romantic edge to the picture and makes points about the place and role of women/servants in English society in Jeckyl's day. Roberts is very good as the lowest member of the household staff, trying to hold the Doctor himself and the household together while at the same time striving not to get above her station. And the grim, nearly black-and-white, dread-filled landscape of the picture is great to look at and memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An undiscovered gem which Julia shines in.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jimmy Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I initially came across this film when I found out it was at one stage planned to be a Winona Ryder/Tim Burton vehicle, and I have to sat I was so impressed by it that it is now one of my favorite films. With a bit of research I got the idea that this was a bad stage in Julias career, but I have to say I have never seen her better than she is in this. Her performance is just astounding, she has thus innocence and vulnerability that I never thought I'd see coming from her, she embodies the character extremely well, so well that it would have been a crime to see anyone else in the role. John Malkovich ramps up the creepy factor in this movie, his performance is also just stellar, he is truly terrifying in the scenes where he is Jekyll. Another thing I like is that this is such a great retelling of the Jekyll/ Hyde story, it's the best one I've ever seen, I think one big advantage it has is that its told from an onlookers perspective and not from an unknown or first person perspective. The cinematography is wonderful, the constant shade of grey and the overlying layer of fog both help to create the dark and moody atmosphere. I think it's definitely a movie fans of the story would enjoy and also people who aren't so familiar with it. Top notch Gothic horror that deserves to be seen....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The woman who loved Dr.Jekyll
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ****SPOILERS**** Somewhat altered version of the Robert Louis Stevenson classic "Doctor Jekyll and Mister Hyde" with the sweet kindly and understanding Doctor Jekyll, John Malkovich, having a love interest who's a housemaid Mary Reilly, Julia Roberts, at his London home where her conducts his secrets experiments. Mary had a hard life with her being abused both psychically and mentally by her drunken father Mr. Reilly, Michael Gambon, that she in fact feels that's her lot in life and can do nothing about it. It's working at Dr.Henry Jekyll place that for the first time in her life Mary finds kindness and understanding for her many problems that includes the scars that her father gave her, like having rats chew at her, while she was a child. The fact that Dr.Jekyll takes such an interest in Mary has her boss the manager of the Jekyll house Mr. Poole, George Cole, get a bit jealous at her for his master, Dr.Jekyll, spending far more time with Mary then with him. Mary for her part is a bit perplexed of Dr.Jekyll in his going in and out of his both house and laboratory all hours of the night as if he's hiding something that he doesn't want anyone to find out about! It's one day when Dr.Jekyll sends Mary on a errand to a cat-house in the red light district in the seedy part of London that she realizes that the good doctor is up to no good. Not that he's a customer of the place but that his special assistant at his laboratory someone named Edward Hyde has made a mess of the place,by brutalizing the hookers, every time he goes there. Mary is told by the angry cat-house Madam Mrs. Farraday, Glenn Close, that Eddie or Mr. Hyde has gotten out of hand and she can't keep covering up for him anymore. Dr.Jekyll in trying to smooth things out by giving her payoff money, so she doesn't report Eddie to the police, also asks Mrs. Farraday, through Mary, to drop in and see him at his laboratory to talk things over! As it turns out Mrs. Farraday is met at the house not by Dr. Jekyll but Mister Hyde who ends up doing her in by making her at least a head shorter! ***SPOILERS*** AS we and Mary Reilly soon find out that he mysterious Edward Hyde is really Doctor Jekyll in the flesh. The doc had been having splitting headaches of late and developed this medication for them. As things turned out the medication did stop the headaches but it turned the genteel and civil Dr.Jekyll into the murderous and sex crazed Edward or Mister Hyde! Edward Hyde for his part took a shine to Mary and unlike his other-self Doctor Jekyll he had no trouble in him not controlling himself in his feeling for her. It's when Edward Hyde attacks and kills one of the late Madam Farrady's John's or customers at her cat or whorehouse the member of British Parliament and good friend of Dr.Jekyll Sir.Danvers Carew, Claran Hinds, that the cops or London Bobbies are called in to check things out! It's discovered that the murder weapon that Hyde killed Carew with, by bashing his skull in, was Doctor Jekyll's silver plated walking stick! ***MAJOR SPOILERS*** Doctor Jekyll now knowing that his life is doomed in that his other-self, by Mister Hyde manipulating his headache medication, has completely taken over his body and asks Mary to do what he doesn't have the guts to to in her doing him in and putting an end to this mesaghas,insanity in Yiddish, once in for all. Mary in what has to be an act of eternal love does what the doctor told her to do but in that she leaves herself open in her being in the wrong place at the wrong time, at the scene of the Sir. Danvers murder, to take the rap for the crime committed by the now departed Dr.Jekyll/Mr. Hyde and having to pay for It very possibly with her life!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I shudder to think what would have followed if this misfire had been a box office smash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film tells the story of the chambermaid who worked for Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde. Thankfully, this turgid mess bombed at the box office so we were spared sequels about Dracula's chauffeur, Frankenstein's tax attorney and the Wolfman's proctologist. Mary Reilly (Julia Roberts) works as a maid for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich) in 19th century London. I kid you not when I state that this movie essentially follows Mary around while she does her household chores and every so often we get a scene that peeks in on the classic tale of Jekyll and Hyde. If you don't know what that story's about, go down to the damn library and check out the book or watch one of the 37,000,000,000 other versions of the tale that have been committed to film. Basically, this thing is a Cliff's Notes version of Jekyll and Hyde, crossed with a documentary on the brutal drudgery of 19th century working class Britons, mixed with a Lifetime movie about a woman overcoming her memories of fatherly abuse. The heart of Mary Reilly is supposed to be about the attraction Mary feels for both Jekyll and Hyde and the affection they feel in return. A big problem is that it's hard to believe any man being lovestruck by this pale-faced woman with Conan O'Brien eyebrows. Julia Roberts is deliberately stripped of most of the beauty artifice that props up her appearance in other films and the audience is undeniably confronted with the fact that Roberts is not that pretty. She has very distinct features that need to be accommodated on screen and that doesn't happen here. Another defining negative about this film is very poor acting jobs by three big stars. Roberts intermittently adopts an Irish accent that rivals Kevin Costner's dialect in Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves for its "now you hear it, now you don't" quality. John Malkovich does worse than sleepwalk through his double role, even giving Edward Hyde an extremely pronounced limp early in the film which completely disappears later on. Either Malkovich and director Stephen Frears both forgot about the limp or Malkovich just got tired of doing it and Frears couldn't make him. Glenn Close is almost as bad as the owner of a London brothel. Her entire performance consists of giving her character an Elvis lip curl. The bottom line is that Mary Reilly is a movie about an uninteresting woman who stands still while an amazing story happens around her. The idea of telling a famous tale from the perspective of a minor character isn't a bad one. A movie about the London cop trying to track down and capture Edward Hyde sounds good to me. The trick is the minor character actually has to do something important in the story. Mary Reilly simply hovers and watches like the boring person on a reality show. Unless you're dying to view YET ANOTHER crappy adaptation of Jekyll and Hyde, skip this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawed period thriller is worth watching for the two lead performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An pretty but shy, depressed and lonely housemaid by the name of Mary Reilly (Oscar-Winner:Julia Roberts) works for Dr. Henry Jekyll (John Malkovich). When Dr. Jekyll is working on a experiment, he tells his staff (George Cole, Michael Sheen, Kathy Staff and Bronagh Gallagher) and Mary that he will have an assistant working with him. But the stuff never fully sees him and remains an mystery. But when Mary gets closer to Dr. Jekyll talking about her awful childhood to him, begin abused by her drunken mean-spirited father (Michael Gambon). Mary finds herself slowly falling in love with Dr. Jekyll but soon discovers that Dr. Jekyll has an dark side and his mysterious assistant might be related to him. Directed by Stephen Frears (The Grifters, Hero, The Hours) made an very flawed but intriguing period suspense thriller with good performances by Roberts and Malkovich. The bleak setting is nicely done by production designer:Staurt Craig (The Harry Potter Series, Chaplin, The Secret Garden) and Glenn Close has fun in her minor role as a madam. Although there was trouble during production, because Roberts and Malkovich didn't get along. The film was also over budgeted and problems with Christopher Hampton's (Atonement, The Secret Agent, Total Eclipse) script. "Mary Reilly" ended up being re-shot in the end, despite it was an reunion from the Cast and Crew of "Dangerous Liaisions" for director:Frears, screenwriter:Hampton, actors:Malkovich & Close, producer:Norma Heyman, composer:George Fenton, cinematographer:Philippe Rousselot, production designer:Craig and casting director:Juliet Taylor. "Mary Reilly" does have an minor cult following, some might complain that Roberts was mis-cast but i thought she did well with his performance (Which she smiled only once in the film). One of the highlights is towards the end with Dr. Jekyll's character. Although watching the movie, it does look like at times, the movie had an troubled production. It's very flawed at times but it's Malkovich's fascinating performance keeps it together. Despite all the movie faults, it is still worth a look. Based on a novel by Valerie Martin.(*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What do I like about this film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like the fact that the film is told from Mary Reilly's point of view. Not only hers, but everyone else's too, like the naive servants, the furious Mrs. Faraday (the brothel mistress). Mary Reilly - the character - also has a disturbing, traumatizing background story and at some point Mr. Hyde gives a pretty heavy psychological spin on it. It's never elaborated on or seems ignored even, but this suits the tone of the film. Insinuating things often hits harder than explaining them. Through some of the characters, some of the possible little script flaws (or plot holes) get solved. For instance, doesn't anybody notice that Dr. Jekyll and his assistant Mr. Hyde look very much alike? Only Hyde looks younger. Sure people notice this, but one of the servants goes about assuming that Mr. Hyde might very well be a product of Jekyll's student days. As a bright student, Jekyll was popular with the ladies. And since Jekyll never got married, if he would have had a son... in those days it was even a sin to merely speak about or suggest a thing like this. I like John Malkovich's performance a lot and it's clear that him & Stephen Frears both understood very well what they wanted to achieve here. The good doc Jekyll (whom is looked upon in high regards by his servants) is far from kosher to the bone himself (we get hints at how he conducts his research and we know he's a regular client at Mrs. Faraday's house of pleasure). While on the other hand, Mr. Hyde as the savage beast, has his scarce moments of weakness for Mary Reilly. See what I'm getting at? And when looking at it from Mary's side, she unwillingly brings out the worst in the best, and the best in the worst, so to speak. Frears & Malkovich and screenwriter Christopher Hampton added shades of gray to a classic, one too many times told story that is basically just about black & white. The film got me really interested in reading the source novel it was based on. To see how it compares the film. What else is there to like? Enough, I think. Phillipe Rousselot's wonderful cinematography. A captivating musical score by George Stenton. As much as it's a character-driven story, it does feature a handful moments of the grotesque. Glenn Close gets decapitated. Dr. Jekyll is seen on the street repeatedly kicking a little girl in the stomach. An engrossing scene that shows how slaughtered meat for consumption is being traded in the streets, followed by an analogy towards the trade of human organs for the sake of science. Not sure whom all were responsible for these sequences -- I understand that Frears, for example, never intended the film to end like it did, with that climactic transformation sequence. But said sequences are a graphic reminder of the fact that we are watching a horrific story. At any rate, I didn't think they hurt the film. They injected it with the necessary dosage of brutality. The set design is marvelous and Dr. Jekyll's laboratory - or at least the way of getting there - is cleverly structured (as it helps crafting the suspense of a certain scene in a brilliant manner). The 19th century London setting works convincing, but we don't get to see much of it. The blocking & framing makes sure we usually only see one part of a street at a time. And to add to this claustrophobic & dark notion this film has, most scenes take place on indoors sets. But also these sets are put to great use. To Mary Reilly, the doctor's mansion starts off as a safe haven, a place offering a good job and a possible better future. But it doesn't take long for this house to get infested with the evil of Mr. Hyde's presence at night. So much even, that it starts to haunt her dreams. This shift in tone happens gradually, with a slow but impeccable pace. Truth be told, to me Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde always seemed a very simplistic story to tell. At least in the classic version as it got famous. It's good source material, yes, but Frears & Hampton managed to squeeze a much more interesting film out of it. Which probably could have even been a lot better if the producing studio at the time wasn't so concerned about how it would do at the box office. Voil&agrave;, that's it for what I like about this film. Notice that I didn't mention Julia Roberts' performance. It's very down-toned, as it should be. She is there not to be noticed, her character demands it and so does the story. And while she does have a lot of screen time, she doesn't do much, so there's just not much to say about her acting. But you can always 'see' the wheels of her character's thoughts grinding, as she is the only one who's trying to fathom what's going on. From all the servants, she's the only one that knows how to read. Dr. Jekyll discovers this very early on, when he spots her reading a book in his library. This, of course, titillates the good doc's mind. And that's the point in the film, as soon as it comes, where you instantly realize this is going to take a turn for the worse. In that moment, there's a harmless thing between them that will inevitably unleash unspeakable horrors. And this 'harmless thing' even is personified throughout the whole film. It goes by the name of Mary Reilly. A very interesting adaptation. And a good film, full stop.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
