<filme>
 <id>
  377
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110006
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Turma da Pesada
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Plump kids are lured into joining a posh fat camp with the promise of quick weight loss and good times, only to find that the facility is a woodland hellhole run by a psycho ex-fitness instructor.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  11-year-old Gerald "Gerry" Garner lives in Long Island, New York, and he's overweight. Gerry's parents Maury and Mrs. Garner decide to send Gerry to Camp Hope, a camp for overweight boys. The camp is owned by kindly Harvey Bushkin and his equally kind wife Alice Bushkin. When the Bushkins file for bankruptcy the camp has to be sold, it is bought by a wacko named Tony Perkis. Tony plans to force the campers to lose as much weight as they can, and he also intends to document the marathon shedding of weight and use it for an infomercial for his slenderizing program. In the eyes of the campers, Tony has made Camp Hope a living hell. As Gerry and counselor Pat Finley lead the efforts to overthrow Tony, the campers prepare for the Apache Relay against arch rival Camp MVP. The Apache Relay is a kind of race in which Camp Hope has never defeated Camp MVP before.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   overweight
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fat camp
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   boy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bankruptcy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   exercise
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Steven Brill
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Judd Apatow
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Steven Brill
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Tom McGowan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Aaron Schwartz
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ben Stiller
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulse the monkey......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerry Garner lives is overweight. His parents decide to send him to Camp Hope, a camp for overweight boys. The camp is owned by kindly Harvey Bushkin and his equally kind wife Alice Bushkin. When the Bushkins file for bankruptcy the camp has to be sold, it is bought by Tony Perkis. Tony plans to force the campers to lose as much weight as they can, and he also intends to document the marathon shedding of weight and use it for an infomercial for his slenderising program. In the eyes of the campers, Tony has made Camp Hope a living hell. As Gerry and counsellor Pat Finley lead the efforts to overthrow Tony, the campers prepare for the Apache Relay against arch rival Camp MVP. The Apache Relay is a race in which Camp Hope has never defeated Camp MVP before. Although there is nothing new going on here, its your typical rush release Disney film that is like most of the junk he cast eat, fun while it lasts but leaves you feeling a little empty after a short while. The token children are there, as are the fat jokes, and of course the instructor who is a little too hard on the kids and has an accent which cannot be connected to any country and thus no upsetting anyone. Stiller plays Goodman before Dodgeball, and if you've seen a Ben Stiller movie, you pretty much know what to expect, he's funny, but predictable. So all in all, its a fun movie, but you will have a pressing sense of d&eacute;j&agrave; Vu, as this has been done so many times before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No Rolling in the Aisles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overweight high school student Aaron Schwartz (as Gerald "Gerry" Garner) thinks summer camp might be fun, but doesn't want to attend when he learns "Camp Hope" caters to portly adolescents. His parents make young Schwartz go anyway, hoping the experience will make him thinner. Initially, Schwartz finds it a fun place where fat kids smuggle in tons of candy. But quickly, the owners go bankrupt and oily fitness guru Ben Stiller (as Tony Perkis) takes over management. He immediately makes the boys camp a living hell... Flatulence, a four-letter-word, and Ben Stiller are used for laughs in this Disney production. There are ample overweight people in the cast, with whom weighty audience members can identity. The students are portrayed as fairly active, although it doesn't seem to benefit their health. Actual weight loss is not celebrated by these "Heavy Weights". The comedy team Stiller and Meara have a cameo as the camp's original owners; perhaps not coincidently, they are Ben Stiller's parents. Ben shows off nice hair and has a lot of exercise scenes. **** Heavy Weights (2/17/95) Steven Brill ~ Aaron Schwartz, Ben Stiller, Tom McGowan, Shaun Weiss
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly Stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShawnL2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was simply one of the worst movies I've ever seen. It was recommended by a now-former friend. The plot was clearly slapped together by three zombies from "The Walking Dead" (or a C- list Damon/Affleck non-sexual couple) and made about as much sense as Ron Paul ; the "we can do anything even though we're fat" message was ham-handed at best, and as blunt as Sarah Palin on a particularly stupid day; the dialog was wooden -- which make sense because so were the actors. I literally couldn't see the forest for the trees. Its the sort of movie that makes you pray for a forest fire, or for Jason Voorhees to show up and put a stop to this nonsense. That's the only ending that could have improved this movie: mass slaughter, starting with the writers. I'm stunned at how bad it is, in all honesty. I can't imagine how it got made. I really can't. The voice-over narration of the kid's letter home to grandma was filled with lines like, "Together, we can do anything!" and "We all love ourselves now" -- yet they feel that way after doing absolutely nothing to earn that confidence except promise to lead healthier lives after a night of binging. I laughed only because I can't believe that someone read the script and said yes. Avoid this movie. It's not an enjoyable mess, just a mess; on a brighter note, it is an epic triumph for writers and producers lacking talent, grace, and apparently basic intelligence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unassuming "family movie" that provides plenty of laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stratsz28
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Heavyweights" is a mid-90's Disney film about a fat camp taken over by the villainous fatboy-turned-success Tony Perkis. While the premise is not so novel, the execution is great and keeps you pretty entertained throughout. Some of the humor is dated, very 90's-specific. However, there is plenty of timeless, cross-generational humor, and Ben Stiller is absolutely at the top of his game. He would reprise this role many times again in his career: the guy with low self-esteem who becomes an overcompensating jerk. Tom McGowan, who plays a Camp Hope lifer, also plays a solid role and draws many laughs. Sure, it's another Disney story about underdog kids who end up conquering the odds... or something like that. But Stiller and McGowan are great, and the kids do a pretty admirable too. It's not a must-see movie, but you also won't feel like you wasted your time for having watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy precursor for the next decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being a child of the '90s, somehow I missed "Heavyweights" entirely. Considering the similarities it shares with "The Mighty Ducks" movies such as actors Kenan Thompson and Shaun Weiss, I'm almost embarrassed. Regardless, there's still plenty to appreciate about "Heavyweights" 15 years later in spite of its silliness -- and it's more than just a joke about the ineptitude of the Buffalo Bills. For one, it was written and directed by Judd Apatow, who has a majority hold on the comedies of the last decade and for two, it marks one of Ben Stiller's first prominent roles as fitness wack-job Tony Perkis, who takes over a once-adored fat camp and harasses the kids. Good thing "Heavyweights" was made then or it may never have surfaced, seeing as the age of political correctness and weight sensitivity has befallen us. The film is not cruel at all in its depiction of overweight campers, so parents surfing around for slightly older kid films and coming across this one shouldn't be concerned about that factor, but there's no doubt that such a concept would be hard to get off the ground, especially at Disney, in the 21st Century. Co-written by Apatow and Steven Brill, writer of "The Mighty Ducks" films, it was as if the two conspired to plant a seed for a type of humor that kids my age at the time would come to identify as their own as they entered the PG-13 and R-rated age. Tony Perkis, for example, is the spitting character image of Stiller's White Goodman from "Dodgeball" and yet to me he is just as amusing doing his patented whispery intimidating voice now despite my countless repeated viewings of "Dodgeball." There's also a classic overnight camp comedy sense of humor in "Heavyweights" like the kids getting beat in sports by their rival camp, an awkward dance mixer with a normal girls camp and when the kids unload the candy stashes they've snuck in camp into secret compartments -- as well as the run-of-the-mill fart jokes. Characters such as Tony's hysterical right-hand European man Lars, however, were way ahead of their time. "Heavyweights" is pretty immature and excludes girls (because fat girls would be too taboo for the '90s). Its typical camp movie plot as well as its "overthrow-the-bad-guy" story arch - - which ruled the '90s -- come off as stale. But ignore those distractions and "Heavyweights" is a funny, quotable movie with some classic scenes, which is all a kid (or someone trying to go back and grab some nostalgia) really wants. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite movie of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavyweights is a 1995 comedy released by Walt Disney Pictures and directed by Steven Brill, the creator of the also hilarious Mighty Ducks movie (which is another favorite of mine). It is about overweight kids who are sent to a camp run by a fitness fanatic named Tony Pekis (Ben Stiller from "Meet the Parents") who is out to make their summer a nightmare. I first saw this movie when it came on Disney Channel about 3 or 4 years ago and since then I have bought and watched this movie over 12 times and I plan to see it many, many more times because this movie is absolutely hilarious and I think it is a Classic movie. From the very beginning to the end credits where the Camp Hope song is sung (which will have you laughing even more) and where Perkis becomes a door-to-door salesman (which is also hilarious) Heavyweights is (if you have a sense of humor) a great movie which I love to quote. One of my many favorite quotes is when Josh, (Goldberg from The Mighty Ducks films) says to Perkis "I know whose candy it is, okay. The candy belongs to seymour butts." Then Perkis replies, confused "Seymour butts?" "Seymour butts?" "Who's seymour butts, huh who's seymour butts?" then Josh says "Nobodys seen more butts than you Uncle Tony!" If you haven't seen this movie yet, the next time you are in a video store, consider renting this one. You shouldn't and I hope you won't be disappointed. You will laugh harder than you probably ever have at a PG film. Rating: Over the scale! (if you've seen the movie you get my joke).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josiah Astle (rabbitfighter9)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -I watched this movie countless times and is the funniest movie on planet earth. I know it looks crappy, but I'm telling you Ben Stiller is amazing and you will love all the fat kids. I have seen a lot of amazing movies and award winners but still for some reason i can watch heavy weights day after day or sometimes twice a day and it is always funny. -It has the best soundtrack too, Disney hit a gold mine with this movie because its not lame funny or stupid mighty ducks funny. I can quote pretty much the whole movie, it is full of the funniest quotes. -Anyways all i can say is, watch this movie and you will know what I'm talking about. This is a perfect movie. -I love this movie more then anything on the top 250 list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, but if kids over 9 watch Meatballs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pufflump2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a very entertaining movie for my kids who had never seen Meatballs, that great late 70s flick with Bill Murry, his first I believe. I was only 9 when that came out and had not seen it in about 10 years when I saw Heavyweights, but almost immediately the comparisions come flowing -- you can't help but see them. Same movie as Meatballs, but worse. My (5 yr) son thought it was funny at times. But "Meatballs" is ripped off throughout. Ultimately Meatballs is the far better movie. Many scenes taken straight from Meatballs. Go cart scene is same as Rudy the Rabbit race at end. They chant the counselor name like they chanted "Spaz" in Meatballs. Stiller is great. And this movie is a good view. But, Meatballs holds up much better now that this movie is 15 years old.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing but BIG, FAT, love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunbare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavy Weights is not a politically correct movie. I first saw this movie as a child on the Disney channel and thought it was hilarious. ****SPOILERS******** The movie is basically about fat boys in a fat camp and their crazy summer with psycho fitness slut Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller). Jerry is the leading fat boy. The film starts with him at his last day of school ready to enjoy a lazy summer. After he misses his bus and is almost attacked by a dog he comes home to find his parents are sending him to Fat Camp. Jerry is not pleased and screams at his Dr. Phil looking father "Your fatter than I am, you go to camp!" Jerry ultimately is forced to camp where he meets lovely fellow big boys, and realizes camp might not be so bad. They have go carts, "the Blob" and best of all no one picks on you because everyone is the fat kid. He makes many friends right away including a young Keenan Thompson. The movie really pokes fun of the mockery of fat children. 1. The fat camps beloved owners (played by Ben Stillers real parents) have gone bankrupt and now new ownership has emerged in the form of former fat kid turned exercise Nazi Tony Perkis. This movie is where I first heard about Ben Stiller. He is great as the cruel Tony. He loves to embarrass his poor campers. At one point he cancels their lunch and simply tells them over the intercom "lunch has been canceled due to lack of hustle...Deal with it."CRUEL. 2. The dance. This is another of Tony's sick twisted jokes and is hilarious. The boys have a dance with the girls camp and of course these girls are repulsed by the boys. 3. Lars. This guy looks like one of the Gestapo. He is a counselor who has a thing for the camp nurse Julie. He is evil and perhaps his character is a mockery of a German Nazi. Lars is foreign and has an accent and marches around the camp with his Aryan looks blowing his whistle like a deranged fat hating Nazi. 4. The baseball game. This is just downright unfair. The camp plays baseball against camp MVP, camp MVP is a SPORTS camp....Guess who won the game? 5. Food stealing. There cannot be a movie about fat camp without the stealing of food. Sounds funny and it is...after all no matter how many "glandular" or "hormonal" problems a person of generous girth has, ultimately the majority just ate and a lot...The boys go crazy when they learn the slop they have to eat and resort to desperate measures. 6. Revenge. The boys are abused and downright sick of it. Their ultimate kidnapping of demonic Tony is hilarious. The scene at parents night when the parents see what their child is really going through is very funny! 6. The Apache Relay. The finale. This is where the camp again competes with camp MVP in order to win the Apache Relay.The apache relay is a serious of various obstacles that camp MVP always win..... The ending is really great. This movie certainly makes incredible fun of fat people, and not just fat people, but boys going through puberty. I found it hilarious than and still find it hilarious now. It may not appeal to anyone who does not like this sort of politically incorrect comedy, but for those who enjoy Ben Stiller or an occasional chubby joke may find this movie not only funny, but endearing. I would watch this with my brother and sister and we would laugh our heads off, but we were always rooting for the fat kids. Tony Perkis was the devil and we found the "capture" of him clever. Loved this movie.....may not be something for obese sensitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What I like about Ben Stiller's movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meganrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I've seen this movie a lot of times and I like it because it's an inspiring movie to a lot of people. It makes kids think that they can be overweight if they're comfortable with it. If kids are comfortable with being over weight it shouldn't matter to other people. I also like this movie because Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller) shakes things up with the fact that he has a problem with kids being overweight. He probably had a problem as a child being fat. He most likely thinks that because he was fat at one point in time that he can connect with these kids. But he is lowering their self-esteem with the things that he says. You don't see that from Ben Stiller in most movies that Ben Stiller stars in. He's more of the guy that gets beat and his self-esteem gets lowered. For example, in the movie, Dodgeball; An Underdog Story he thinks he's the best person in the beginning, but then he gets best and he starts gaining weight again. I couldn't help but notice the fact that Ben Stiller stars in a lot of movies about weight or stuff about health. I was wondering if he was overweight as a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulse the monkey......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerry Garner lives is overweight. His parents decide to send him to Camp Hope, a camp for overweight boys. The camp is owned by kindly Harvey Bushkin and his equally kind wife Alice Bushkin. When the Bushkins file for bankruptcy the camp has to be sold, it is bought by Tony Perkis. Tony plans to force the campers to lose as much weight as they can, and he also intends to document the marathon shedding of weight and use it for an infomercial for his slenderising program. In the eyes of the campers, Tony has made Camp Hope a living hell. As Gerry and counsellor Pat Finley lead the efforts to overthrow Tony, the campers prepare for the Apache Relay against arch rival Camp MVP. The Apache Relay is a race in which Camp Hope has never defeated Camp MVP before. Although there is nothing new going on here, its your typical rush release Disney film that is like most of the junk he cast eat, fun while it lasts but leaves you feeling a little empty after a short while. The token children are there, as are the fat jokes, and of course the instructor who is a little too hard on the kids and has an accent which cannot be connected to any country and thus no upsetting anyone. Stiller plays Goodman before Dodgeball, and if you've seen a Ben Stiller movie, you pretty much know what to expect, he's funny, but predictable. So all in all, its a fun movie, but you will have a pressing sense of d&eacute;j&agrave; Vu, as this has been done so many times before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No Rolling in the Aisles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overweight high school student Aaron Schwartz (as Gerald "Gerry" Garner) thinks summer camp might be fun, but doesn't want to attend when he learns "Camp Hope" caters to portly adolescents. His parents make young Schwartz go anyway, hoping the experience will make him thinner. Initially, Schwartz finds it a fun place where fat kids smuggle in tons of candy. But quickly, the owners go bankrupt and oily fitness guru Ben Stiller (as Tony Perkis) takes over management. He immediately makes the boys camp a living hell... Flatulence, a four-letter-word, and Ben Stiller are used for laughs in this Disney production. There are ample overweight people in the cast, with whom weighty audience members can identity. The students are portrayed as fairly active, although it doesn't seem to benefit their health. Actual weight loss is not celebrated by these "Heavy Weights". The comedy team Stiller and Meara have a cameo as the camp's original owners; perhaps not coincidently, they are Ben Stiller's parents. Ben shows off nice hair and has a lot of exercise scenes. **** Heavy Weights (2/17/95) Steven Brill ~ Aaron Schwartz, Ben Stiller, Tom McGowan, Shaun Weiss
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly Stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShawnL2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was simply one of the worst movies I've ever seen. It was recommended by a now-former friend. The plot was clearly slapped together by three zombies from "The Walking Dead" (or a C- list Damon/Affleck non-sexual couple) and made about as much sense as Ron Paul ; the "we can do anything even though we're fat" message was ham-handed at best, and as blunt as Sarah Palin on a particularly stupid day; the dialog was wooden -- which make sense because so were the actors. I literally couldn't see the forest for the trees. Its the sort of movie that makes you pray for a forest fire, or for Jason Voorhees to show up and put a stop to this nonsense. That's the only ending that could have improved this movie: mass slaughter, starting with the writers. I'm stunned at how bad it is, in all honesty. I can't imagine how it got made. I really can't. The voice-over narration of the kid's letter home to grandma was filled with lines like, "Together, we can do anything!" and "We all love ourselves now" -- yet they feel that way after doing absolutely nothing to earn that confidence except promise to lead healthier lives after a night of binging. I laughed only because I can't believe that someone read the script and said yes. Avoid this movie. It's not an enjoyable mess, just a mess; on a brighter note, it is an epic triumph for writers and producers lacking talent, grace, and apparently basic intelligence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unassuming "family movie" that provides plenty of laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stratsz28
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Heavyweights" is a mid-90's Disney film about a fat camp taken over by the villainous fatboy-turned-success Tony Perkis. While the premise is not so novel, the execution is great and keeps you pretty entertained throughout. Some of the humor is dated, very 90's-specific. However, there is plenty of timeless, cross-generational humor, and Ben Stiller is absolutely at the top of his game. He would reprise this role many times again in his career: the guy with low self-esteem who becomes an overcompensating jerk. Tom McGowan, who plays a Camp Hope lifer, also plays a solid role and draws many laughs. Sure, it's another Disney story about underdog kids who end up conquering the odds... or something like that. But Stiller and McGowan are great, and the kids do a pretty admirable too. It's not a must-see movie, but you also won't feel like you wasted your time for having watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy precursor for the next decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being a child of the '90s, somehow I missed "Heavyweights" entirely. Considering the similarities it shares with "The Mighty Ducks" movies such as actors Kenan Thompson and Shaun Weiss, I'm almost embarrassed. Regardless, there's still plenty to appreciate about "Heavyweights" 15 years later in spite of its silliness -- and it's more than just a joke about the ineptitude of the Buffalo Bills. For one, it was written and directed by Judd Apatow, who has a majority hold on the comedies of the last decade and for two, it marks one of Ben Stiller's first prominent roles as fitness wack-job Tony Perkis, who takes over a once-adored fat camp and harasses the kids. Good thing "Heavyweights" was made then or it may never have surfaced, seeing as the age of political correctness and weight sensitivity has befallen us. The film is not cruel at all in its depiction of overweight campers, so parents surfing around for slightly older kid films and coming across this one shouldn't be concerned about that factor, but there's no doubt that such a concept would be hard to get off the ground, especially at Disney, in the 21st Century. Co-written by Apatow and Steven Brill, writer of "The Mighty Ducks" films, it was as if the two conspired to plant a seed for a type of humor that kids my age at the time would come to identify as their own as they entered the PG-13 and R-rated age. Tony Perkis, for example, is the spitting character image of Stiller's White Goodman from "Dodgeball" and yet to me he is just as amusing doing his patented whispery intimidating voice now despite my countless repeated viewings of "Dodgeball." There's also a classic overnight camp comedy sense of humor in "Heavyweights" like the kids getting beat in sports by their rival camp, an awkward dance mixer with a normal girls camp and when the kids unload the candy stashes they've snuck in camp into secret compartments -- as well as the run-of-the-mill fart jokes. Characters such as Tony's hysterical right-hand European man Lars, however, were way ahead of their time. "Heavyweights" is pretty immature and excludes girls (because fat girls would be too taboo for the '90s). Its typical camp movie plot as well as its "overthrow-the-bad-guy" story arch - - which ruled the '90s -- come off as stale. But ignore those distractions and "Heavyweights" is a funny, quotable movie with some classic scenes, which is all a kid (or someone trying to go back and grab some nostalgia) really wants. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite movie of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavyweights is a 1995 comedy released by Walt Disney Pictures and directed by Steven Brill, the creator of the also hilarious Mighty Ducks movie (which is another favorite of mine). It is about overweight kids who are sent to a camp run by a fitness fanatic named Tony Pekis (Ben Stiller from "Meet the Parents") who is out to make their summer a nightmare. I first saw this movie when it came on Disney Channel about 3 or 4 years ago and since then I have bought and watched this movie over 12 times and I plan to see it many, many more times because this movie is absolutely hilarious and I think it is a Classic movie. From the very beginning to the end credits where the Camp Hope song is sung (which will have you laughing even more) and where Perkis becomes a door-to-door salesman (which is also hilarious) Heavyweights is (if you have a sense of humor) a great movie which I love to quote. One of my many favorite quotes is when Josh, (Goldberg from The Mighty Ducks films) says to Perkis "I know whose candy it is, okay. The candy belongs to seymour butts." Then Perkis replies, confused "Seymour butts?" "Seymour butts?" "Who's seymour butts, huh who's seymour butts?" then Josh says "Nobodys seen more butts than you Uncle Tony!" If you haven't seen this movie yet, the next time you are in a video store, consider renting this one. You shouldn't and I hope you won't be disappointed. You will laugh harder than you probably ever have at a PG film. Rating: Over the scale! (if you've seen the movie you get my joke).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josiah Astle (rabbitfighter9)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -I watched this movie countless times and is the funniest movie on planet earth. I know it looks crappy, but I'm telling you Ben Stiller is amazing and you will love all the fat kids. I have seen a lot of amazing movies and award winners but still for some reason i can watch heavy weights day after day or sometimes twice a day and it is always funny. -It has the best soundtrack too, Disney hit a gold mine with this movie because its not lame funny or stupid mighty ducks funny. I can quote pretty much the whole movie, it is full of the funniest quotes. -Anyways all i can say is, watch this movie and you will know what I'm talking about. This is a perfect movie. -I love this movie more then anything on the top 250 list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, but if kids over 9 watch Meatballs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pufflump2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a very entertaining movie for my kids who had never seen Meatballs, that great late 70s flick with Bill Murry, his first I believe. I was only 9 when that came out and had not seen it in about 10 years when I saw Heavyweights, but almost immediately the comparisions come flowing -- you can't help but see them. Same movie as Meatballs, but worse. My (5 yr) son thought it was funny at times. But "Meatballs" is ripped off throughout. Ultimately Meatballs is the far better movie. Many scenes taken straight from Meatballs. Go cart scene is same as Rudy the Rabbit race at end. They chant the counselor name like they chanted "Spaz" in Meatballs. Stiller is great. And this movie is a good view. But, Meatballs holds up much better now that this movie is 15 years old.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing but BIG, FAT, love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunbare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavy Weights is not a politically correct movie. I first saw this movie as a child on the Disney channel and thought it was hilarious. ****SPOILERS******** The movie is basically about fat boys in a fat camp and their crazy summer with psycho fitness slut Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller). Jerry is the leading fat boy. The film starts with him at his last day of school ready to enjoy a lazy summer. After he misses his bus and is almost attacked by a dog he comes home to find his parents are sending him to Fat Camp. Jerry is not pleased and screams at his Dr. Phil looking father "Your fatter than I am, you go to camp!" Jerry ultimately is forced to camp where he meets lovely fellow big boys, and realizes camp might not be so bad. They have go carts, "the Blob" and best of all no one picks on you because everyone is the fat kid. He makes many friends right away including a young Keenan Thompson. The movie really pokes fun of the mockery of fat children. 1. The fat camps beloved owners (played by Ben Stillers real parents) have gone bankrupt and now new ownership has emerged in the form of former fat kid turned exercise Nazi Tony Perkis. This movie is where I first heard about Ben Stiller. He is great as the cruel Tony. He loves to embarrass his poor campers. At one point he cancels their lunch and simply tells them over the intercom "lunch has been canceled due to lack of hustle...Deal with it."CRUEL. 2. The dance. This is another of Tony's sick twisted jokes and is hilarious. The boys have a dance with the girls camp and of course these girls are repulsed by the boys. 3. Lars. This guy looks like one of the Gestapo. He is a counselor who has a thing for the camp nurse Julie. He is evil and perhaps his character is a mockery of a German Nazi. Lars is foreign and has an accent and marches around the camp with his Aryan looks blowing his whistle like a deranged fat hating Nazi. 4. The baseball game. This is just downright unfair. The camp plays baseball against camp MVP, camp MVP is a SPORTS camp....Guess who won the game? 5. Food stealing. There cannot be a movie about fat camp without the stealing of food. Sounds funny and it is...after all no matter how many "glandular" or "hormonal" problems a person of generous girth has, ultimately the majority just ate and a lot...The boys go crazy when they learn the slop they have to eat and resort to desperate measures. 6. Revenge. The boys are abused and downright sick of it. Their ultimate kidnapping of demonic Tony is hilarious. The scene at parents night when the parents see what their child is really going through is very funny! 6. The Apache Relay. The finale. This is where the camp again competes with camp MVP in order to win the Apache Relay.The apache relay is a serious of various obstacles that camp MVP always win..... The ending is really great. This movie certainly makes incredible fun of fat people, and not just fat people, but boys going through puberty. I found it hilarious than and still find it hilarious now. It may not appeal to anyone who does not like this sort of politically incorrect comedy, but for those who enjoy Ben Stiller or an occasional chubby joke may find this movie not only funny, but endearing. I would watch this with my brother and sister and we would laugh our heads off, but we were always rooting for the fat kids. Tony Perkis was the devil and we found the "capture" of him clever. Loved this movie.....may not be something for obese sensitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What I like about Ben Stiller's movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meganrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I've seen this movie a lot of times and I like it because it's an inspiring movie to a lot of people. It makes kids think that they can be overweight if they're comfortable with it. If kids are comfortable with being over weight it shouldn't matter to other people. I also like this movie because Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller) shakes things up with the fact that he has a problem with kids being overweight. He probably had a problem as a child being fat. He most likely thinks that because he was fat at one point in time that he can connect with these kids. But he is lowering their self-esteem with the things that he says. You don't see that from Ben Stiller in most movies that Ben Stiller stars in. He's more of the guy that gets beat and his self-esteem gets lowered. For example, in the movie, Dodgeball; An Underdog Story he thinks he's the best person in the beginning, but then he gets best and he starts gaining weight again. I couldn't help but notice the fact that Ben Stiller stars in a lot of movies about weight or stuff about health. I was wondering if he was overweight as a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulse the monkey......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerry Garner lives is overweight. His parents decide to send him to Camp Hope, a camp for overweight boys. The camp is owned by kindly Harvey Bushkin and his equally kind wife Alice Bushkin. When the Bushkins file for bankruptcy the camp has to be sold, it is bought by Tony Perkis. Tony plans to force the campers to lose as much weight as they can, and he also intends to document the marathon shedding of weight and use it for an infomercial for his slenderising program. In the eyes of the campers, Tony has made Camp Hope a living hell. As Gerry and counsellor Pat Finley lead the efforts to overthrow Tony, the campers prepare for the Apache Relay against arch rival Camp MVP. The Apache Relay is a race in which Camp Hope has never defeated Camp MVP before. Although there is nothing new going on here, its your typical rush release Disney film that is like most of the junk he cast eat, fun while it lasts but leaves you feeling a little empty after a short while. The token children are there, as are the fat jokes, and of course the instructor who is a little too hard on the kids and has an accent which cannot be connected to any country and thus no upsetting anyone. Stiller plays Goodman before Dodgeball, and if you've seen a Ben Stiller movie, you pretty much know what to expect, he's funny, but predictable. So all in all, its a fun movie, but you will have a pressing sense of d&eacute;j&agrave; Vu, as this has been done so many times before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No Rolling in the Aisles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overweight high school student Aaron Schwartz (as Gerald "Gerry" Garner) thinks summer camp might be fun, but doesn't want to attend when he learns "Camp Hope" caters to portly adolescents. His parents make young Schwartz go anyway, hoping the experience will make him thinner. Initially, Schwartz finds it a fun place where fat kids smuggle in tons of candy. But quickly, the owners go bankrupt and oily fitness guru Ben Stiller (as Tony Perkis) takes over management. He immediately makes the boys camp a living hell... Flatulence, a four-letter-word, and Ben Stiller are used for laughs in this Disney production. There are ample overweight people in the cast, with whom weighty audience members can identity. The students are portrayed as fairly active, although it doesn't seem to benefit their health. Actual weight loss is not celebrated by these "Heavy Weights". The comedy team Stiller and Meara have a cameo as the camp's original owners; perhaps not coincidently, they are Ben Stiller's parents. Ben shows off nice hair and has a lot of exercise scenes. **** Heavy Weights (2/17/95) Steven Brill ~ Aaron Schwartz, Ben Stiller, Tom McGowan, Shaun Weiss
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly Stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShawnL2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was simply one of the worst movies I've ever seen. It was recommended by a now-former friend. The plot was clearly slapped together by three zombies from "The Walking Dead" (or a C- list Damon/Affleck non-sexual couple) and made about as much sense as Ron Paul ; the "we can do anything even though we're fat" message was ham-handed at best, and as blunt as Sarah Palin on a particularly stupid day; the dialog was wooden -- which make sense because so were the actors. I literally couldn't see the forest for the trees. Its the sort of movie that makes you pray for a forest fire, or for Jason Voorhees to show up and put a stop to this nonsense. That's the only ending that could have improved this movie: mass slaughter, starting with the writers. I'm stunned at how bad it is, in all honesty. I can't imagine how it got made. I really can't. The voice-over narration of the kid's letter home to grandma was filled with lines like, "Together, we can do anything!" and "We all love ourselves now" -- yet they feel that way after doing absolutely nothing to earn that confidence except promise to lead healthier lives after a night of binging. I laughed only because I can't believe that someone read the script and said yes. Avoid this movie. It's not an enjoyable mess, just a mess; on a brighter note, it is an epic triumph for writers and producers lacking talent, grace, and apparently basic intelligence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unassuming "family movie" that provides plenty of laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stratsz28
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Heavyweights" is a mid-90's Disney film about a fat camp taken over by the villainous fatboy-turned-success Tony Perkis. While the premise is not so novel, the execution is great and keeps you pretty entertained throughout. Some of the humor is dated, very 90's-specific. However, there is plenty of timeless, cross-generational humor, and Ben Stiller is absolutely at the top of his game. He would reprise this role many times again in his career: the guy with low self-esteem who becomes an overcompensating jerk. Tom McGowan, who plays a Camp Hope lifer, also plays a solid role and draws many laughs. Sure, it's another Disney story about underdog kids who end up conquering the odds... or something like that. But Stiller and McGowan are great, and the kids do a pretty admirable too. It's not a must-see movie, but you also won't feel like you wasted your time for having watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy precursor for the next decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being a child of the '90s, somehow I missed "Heavyweights" entirely. Considering the similarities it shares with "The Mighty Ducks" movies such as actors Kenan Thompson and Shaun Weiss, I'm almost embarrassed. Regardless, there's still plenty to appreciate about "Heavyweights" 15 years later in spite of its silliness -- and it's more than just a joke about the ineptitude of the Buffalo Bills. For one, it was written and directed by Judd Apatow, who has a majority hold on the comedies of the last decade and for two, it marks one of Ben Stiller's first prominent roles as fitness wack-job Tony Perkis, who takes over a once-adored fat camp and harasses the kids. Good thing "Heavyweights" was made then or it may never have surfaced, seeing as the age of political correctness and weight sensitivity has befallen us. The film is not cruel at all in its depiction of overweight campers, so parents surfing around for slightly older kid films and coming across this one shouldn't be concerned about that factor, but there's no doubt that such a concept would be hard to get off the ground, especially at Disney, in the 21st Century. Co-written by Apatow and Steven Brill, writer of "The Mighty Ducks" films, it was as if the two conspired to plant a seed for a type of humor that kids my age at the time would come to identify as their own as they entered the PG-13 and R-rated age. Tony Perkis, for example, is the spitting character image of Stiller's White Goodman from "Dodgeball" and yet to me he is just as amusing doing his patented whispery intimidating voice now despite my countless repeated viewings of "Dodgeball." There's also a classic overnight camp comedy sense of humor in "Heavyweights" like the kids getting beat in sports by their rival camp, an awkward dance mixer with a normal girls camp and when the kids unload the candy stashes they've snuck in camp into secret compartments -- as well as the run-of-the-mill fart jokes. Characters such as Tony's hysterical right-hand European man Lars, however, were way ahead of their time. "Heavyweights" is pretty immature and excludes girls (because fat girls would be too taboo for the '90s). Its typical camp movie plot as well as its "overthrow-the-bad-guy" story arch - - which ruled the '90s -- come off as stale. But ignore those distractions and "Heavyweights" is a funny, quotable movie with some classic scenes, which is all a kid (or someone trying to go back and grab some nostalgia) really wants. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite movie of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavyweights is a 1995 comedy released by Walt Disney Pictures and directed by Steven Brill, the creator of the also hilarious Mighty Ducks movie (which is another favorite of mine). It is about overweight kids who are sent to a camp run by a fitness fanatic named Tony Pekis (Ben Stiller from "Meet the Parents") who is out to make their summer a nightmare. I first saw this movie when it came on Disney Channel about 3 or 4 years ago and since then I have bought and watched this movie over 12 times and I plan to see it many, many more times because this movie is absolutely hilarious and I think it is a Classic movie. From the very beginning to the end credits where the Camp Hope song is sung (which will have you laughing even more) and where Perkis becomes a door-to-door salesman (which is also hilarious) Heavyweights is (if you have a sense of humor) a great movie which I love to quote. One of my many favorite quotes is when Josh, (Goldberg from The Mighty Ducks films) says to Perkis "I know whose candy it is, okay. The candy belongs to seymour butts." Then Perkis replies, confused "Seymour butts?" "Seymour butts?" "Who's seymour butts, huh who's seymour butts?" then Josh says "Nobodys seen more butts than you Uncle Tony!" If you haven't seen this movie yet, the next time you are in a video store, consider renting this one. You shouldn't and I hope you won't be disappointed. You will laugh harder than you probably ever have at a PG film. Rating: Over the scale! (if you've seen the movie you get my joke).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josiah Astle (rabbitfighter9)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -I watched this movie countless times and is the funniest movie on planet earth. I know it looks crappy, but I'm telling you Ben Stiller is amazing and you will love all the fat kids. I have seen a lot of amazing movies and award winners but still for some reason i can watch heavy weights day after day or sometimes twice a day and it is always funny. -It has the best soundtrack too, Disney hit a gold mine with this movie because its not lame funny or stupid mighty ducks funny. I can quote pretty much the whole movie, it is full of the funniest quotes. -Anyways all i can say is, watch this movie and you will know what I'm talking about. This is a perfect movie. -I love this movie more then anything on the top 250 list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, but if kids over 9 watch Meatballs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pufflump2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a very entertaining movie for my kids who had never seen Meatballs, that great late 70s flick with Bill Murry, his first I believe. I was only 9 when that came out and had not seen it in about 10 years when I saw Heavyweights, but almost immediately the comparisions come flowing -- you can't help but see them. Same movie as Meatballs, but worse. My (5 yr) son thought it was funny at times. But "Meatballs" is ripped off throughout. Ultimately Meatballs is the far better movie. Many scenes taken straight from Meatballs. Go cart scene is same as Rudy the Rabbit race at end. They chant the counselor name like they chanted "Spaz" in Meatballs. Stiller is great. And this movie is a good view. But, Meatballs holds up much better now that this movie is 15 years old.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing but BIG, FAT, love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunbare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavy Weights is not a politically correct movie. I first saw this movie as a child on the Disney channel and thought it was hilarious. ****SPOILERS******** The movie is basically about fat boys in a fat camp and their crazy summer with psycho fitness slut Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller). Jerry is the leading fat boy. The film starts with him at his last day of school ready to enjoy a lazy summer. After he misses his bus and is almost attacked by a dog he comes home to find his parents are sending him to Fat Camp. Jerry is not pleased and screams at his Dr. Phil looking father "Your fatter than I am, you go to camp!" Jerry ultimately is forced to camp where he meets lovely fellow big boys, and realizes camp might not be so bad. They have go carts, "the Blob" and best of all no one picks on you because everyone is the fat kid. He makes many friends right away including a young Keenan Thompson. The movie really pokes fun of the mockery of fat children. 1. The fat camps beloved owners (played by Ben Stillers real parents) have gone bankrupt and now new ownership has emerged in the form of former fat kid turned exercise Nazi Tony Perkis. This movie is where I first heard about Ben Stiller. He is great as the cruel Tony. He loves to embarrass his poor campers. At one point he cancels their lunch and simply tells them over the intercom "lunch has been canceled due to lack of hustle...Deal with it."CRUEL. 2. The dance. This is another of Tony's sick twisted jokes and is hilarious. The boys have a dance with the girls camp and of course these girls are repulsed by the boys. 3. Lars. This guy looks like one of the Gestapo. He is a counselor who has a thing for the camp nurse Julie. He is evil and perhaps his character is a mockery of a German Nazi. Lars is foreign and has an accent and marches around the camp with his Aryan looks blowing his whistle like a deranged fat hating Nazi. 4. The baseball game. This is just downright unfair. The camp plays baseball against camp MVP, camp MVP is a SPORTS camp....Guess who won the game? 5. Food stealing. There cannot be a movie about fat camp without the stealing of food. Sounds funny and it is...after all no matter how many "glandular" or "hormonal" problems a person of generous girth has, ultimately the majority just ate and a lot...The boys go crazy when they learn the slop they have to eat and resort to desperate measures. 6. Revenge. The boys are abused and downright sick of it. Their ultimate kidnapping of demonic Tony is hilarious. The scene at parents night when the parents see what their child is really going through is very funny! 6. The Apache Relay. The finale. This is where the camp again competes with camp MVP in order to win the Apache Relay.The apache relay is a serious of various obstacles that camp MVP always win..... The ending is really great. This movie certainly makes incredible fun of fat people, and not just fat people, but boys going through puberty. I found it hilarious than and still find it hilarious now. It may not appeal to anyone who does not like this sort of politically incorrect comedy, but for those who enjoy Ben Stiller or an occasional chubby joke may find this movie not only funny, but endearing. I would watch this with my brother and sister and we would laugh our heads off, but we were always rooting for the fat kids. Tony Perkis was the devil and we found the "capture" of him clever. Loved this movie.....may not be something for obese sensitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What I like about Ben Stiller's movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meganrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I've seen this movie a lot of times and I like it because it's an inspiring movie to a lot of people. It makes kids think that they can be overweight if they're comfortable with it. If kids are comfortable with being over weight it shouldn't matter to other people. I also like this movie because Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller) shakes things up with the fact that he has a problem with kids being overweight. He probably had a problem as a child being fat. He most likely thinks that because he was fat at one point in time that he can connect with these kids. But he is lowering their self-esteem with the things that he says. You don't see that from Ben Stiller in most movies that Ben Stiller stars in. He's more of the guy that gets beat and his self-esteem gets lowered. For example, in the movie, Dodgeball; An Underdog Story he thinks he's the best person in the beginning, but then he gets best and he starts gaining weight again. I couldn't help but notice the fact that Ben Stiller stars in a lot of movies about weight or stuff about health. I was wondering if he was overweight as a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulse the monkey......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerry Garner lives is overweight. His parents decide to send him to Camp Hope, a camp for overweight boys. The camp is owned by kindly Harvey Bushkin and his equally kind wife Alice Bushkin. When the Bushkins file for bankruptcy the camp has to be sold, it is bought by Tony Perkis. Tony plans to force the campers to lose as much weight as they can, and he also intends to document the marathon shedding of weight and use it for an infomercial for his slenderising program. In the eyes of the campers, Tony has made Camp Hope a living hell. As Gerry and counsellor Pat Finley lead the efforts to overthrow Tony, the campers prepare for the Apache Relay against arch rival Camp MVP. The Apache Relay is a race in which Camp Hope has never defeated Camp MVP before. Although there is nothing new going on here, its your typical rush release Disney film that is like most of the junk he cast eat, fun while it lasts but leaves you feeling a little empty after a short while. The token children are there, as are the fat jokes, and of course the instructor who is a little too hard on the kids and has an accent which cannot be connected to any country and thus no upsetting anyone. Stiller plays Goodman before Dodgeball, and if you've seen a Ben Stiller movie, you pretty much know what to expect, he's funny, but predictable. So all in all, its a fun movie, but you will have a pressing sense of d&eacute;j&agrave; Vu, as this has been done so many times before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No Rolling in the Aisles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overweight high school student Aaron Schwartz (as Gerald "Gerry" Garner) thinks summer camp might be fun, but doesn't want to attend when he learns "Camp Hope" caters to portly adolescents. His parents make young Schwartz go anyway, hoping the experience will make him thinner. Initially, Schwartz finds it a fun place where fat kids smuggle in tons of candy. But quickly, the owners go bankrupt and oily fitness guru Ben Stiller (as Tony Perkis) takes over management. He immediately makes the boys camp a living hell... Flatulence, a four-letter-word, and Ben Stiller are used for laughs in this Disney production. There are ample overweight people in the cast, with whom weighty audience members can identity. The students are portrayed as fairly active, although it doesn't seem to benefit their health. Actual weight loss is not celebrated by these "Heavy Weights". The comedy team Stiller and Meara have a cameo as the camp's original owners; perhaps not coincidently, they are Ben Stiller's parents. Ben shows off nice hair and has a lot of exercise scenes. **** Heavy Weights (2/17/95) Steven Brill ~ Aaron Schwartz, Ben Stiller, Tom McGowan, Shaun Weiss
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly Stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShawnL2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was simply one of the worst movies I've ever seen. It was recommended by a now-former friend. The plot was clearly slapped together by three zombies from "The Walking Dead" (or a C- list Damon/Affleck non-sexual couple) and made about as much sense as Ron Paul ; the "we can do anything even though we're fat" message was ham-handed at best, and as blunt as Sarah Palin on a particularly stupid day; the dialog was wooden -- which make sense because so were the actors. I literally couldn't see the forest for the trees. Its the sort of movie that makes you pray for a forest fire, or for Jason Voorhees to show up and put a stop to this nonsense. That's the only ending that could have improved this movie: mass slaughter, starting with the writers. I'm stunned at how bad it is, in all honesty. I can't imagine how it got made. I really can't. The voice-over narration of the kid's letter home to grandma was filled with lines like, "Together, we can do anything!" and "We all love ourselves now" -- yet they feel that way after doing absolutely nothing to earn that confidence except promise to lead healthier lives after a night of binging. I laughed only because I can't believe that someone read the script and said yes. Avoid this movie. It's not an enjoyable mess, just a mess; on a brighter note, it is an epic triumph for writers and producers lacking talent, grace, and apparently basic intelligence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unassuming "family movie" that provides plenty of laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stratsz28
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Heavyweights" is a mid-90's Disney film about a fat camp taken over by the villainous fatboy-turned-success Tony Perkis. While the premise is not so novel, the execution is great and keeps you pretty entertained throughout. Some of the humor is dated, very 90's-specific. However, there is plenty of timeless, cross-generational humor, and Ben Stiller is absolutely at the top of his game. He would reprise this role many times again in his career: the guy with low self-esteem who becomes an overcompensating jerk. Tom McGowan, who plays a Camp Hope lifer, also plays a solid role and draws many laughs. Sure, it's another Disney story about underdog kids who end up conquering the odds... or something like that. But Stiller and McGowan are great, and the kids do a pretty admirable too. It's not a must-see movie, but you also won't feel like you wasted your time for having watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy precursor for the next decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being a child of the '90s, somehow I missed "Heavyweights" entirely. Considering the similarities it shares with "The Mighty Ducks" movies such as actors Kenan Thompson and Shaun Weiss, I'm almost embarrassed. Regardless, there's still plenty to appreciate about "Heavyweights" 15 years later in spite of its silliness -- and it's more than just a joke about the ineptitude of the Buffalo Bills. For one, it was written and directed by Judd Apatow, who has a majority hold on the comedies of the last decade and for two, it marks one of Ben Stiller's first prominent roles as fitness wack-job Tony Perkis, who takes over a once-adored fat camp and harasses the kids. Good thing "Heavyweights" was made then or it may never have surfaced, seeing as the age of political correctness and weight sensitivity has befallen us. The film is not cruel at all in its depiction of overweight campers, so parents surfing around for slightly older kid films and coming across this one shouldn't be concerned about that factor, but there's no doubt that such a concept would be hard to get off the ground, especially at Disney, in the 21st Century. Co-written by Apatow and Steven Brill, writer of "The Mighty Ducks" films, it was as if the two conspired to plant a seed for a type of humor that kids my age at the time would come to identify as their own as they entered the PG-13 and R-rated age. Tony Perkis, for example, is the spitting character image of Stiller's White Goodman from "Dodgeball" and yet to me he is just as amusing doing his patented whispery intimidating voice now despite my countless repeated viewings of "Dodgeball." There's also a classic overnight camp comedy sense of humor in "Heavyweights" like the kids getting beat in sports by their rival camp, an awkward dance mixer with a normal girls camp and when the kids unload the candy stashes they've snuck in camp into secret compartments -- as well as the run-of-the-mill fart jokes. Characters such as Tony's hysterical right-hand European man Lars, however, were way ahead of their time. "Heavyweights" is pretty immature and excludes girls (because fat girls would be too taboo for the '90s). Its typical camp movie plot as well as its "overthrow-the-bad-guy" story arch - - which ruled the '90s -- come off as stale. But ignore those distractions and "Heavyweights" is a funny, quotable movie with some classic scenes, which is all a kid (or someone trying to go back and grab some nostalgia) really wants. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite movie of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavyweights is a 1995 comedy released by Walt Disney Pictures and directed by Steven Brill, the creator of the also hilarious Mighty Ducks movie (which is another favorite of mine). It is about overweight kids who are sent to a camp run by a fitness fanatic named Tony Pekis (Ben Stiller from "Meet the Parents") who is out to make their summer a nightmare. I first saw this movie when it came on Disney Channel about 3 or 4 years ago and since then I have bought and watched this movie over 12 times and I plan to see it many, many more times because this movie is absolutely hilarious and I think it is a Classic movie. From the very beginning to the end credits where the Camp Hope song is sung (which will have you laughing even more) and where Perkis becomes a door-to-door salesman (which is also hilarious) Heavyweights is (if you have a sense of humor) a great movie which I love to quote. One of my many favorite quotes is when Josh, (Goldberg from The Mighty Ducks films) says to Perkis "I know whose candy it is, okay. The candy belongs to seymour butts." Then Perkis replies, confused "Seymour butts?" "Seymour butts?" "Who's seymour butts, huh who's seymour butts?" then Josh says "Nobodys seen more butts than you Uncle Tony!" If you haven't seen this movie yet, the next time you are in a video store, consider renting this one. You shouldn't and I hope you won't be disappointed. You will laugh harder than you probably ever have at a PG film. Rating: Over the scale! (if you've seen the movie you get my joke).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josiah Astle (rabbitfighter9)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -I watched this movie countless times and is the funniest movie on planet earth. I know it looks crappy, but I'm telling you Ben Stiller is amazing and you will love all the fat kids. I have seen a lot of amazing movies and award winners but still for some reason i can watch heavy weights day after day or sometimes twice a day and it is always funny. -It has the best soundtrack too, Disney hit a gold mine with this movie because its not lame funny or stupid mighty ducks funny. I can quote pretty much the whole movie, it is full of the funniest quotes. -Anyways all i can say is, watch this movie and you will know what I'm talking about. This is a perfect movie. -I love this movie more then anything on the top 250 list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, but if kids over 9 watch Meatballs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pufflump2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a very entertaining movie for my kids who had never seen Meatballs, that great late 70s flick with Bill Murry, his first I believe. I was only 9 when that came out and had not seen it in about 10 years when I saw Heavyweights, but almost immediately the comparisions come flowing -- you can't help but see them. Same movie as Meatballs, but worse. My (5 yr) son thought it was funny at times. But "Meatballs" is ripped off throughout. Ultimately Meatballs is the far better movie. Many scenes taken straight from Meatballs. Go cart scene is same as Rudy the Rabbit race at end. They chant the counselor name like they chanted "Spaz" in Meatballs. Stiller is great. And this movie is a good view. But, Meatballs holds up much better now that this movie is 15 years old.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing but BIG, FAT, love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunbare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavy Weights is not a politically correct movie. I first saw this movie as a child on the Disney channel and thought it was hilarious. ****SPOILERS******** The movie is basically about fat boys in a fat camp and their crazy summer with psycho fitness slut Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller). Jerry is the leading fat boy. The film starts with him at his last day of school ready to enjoy a lazy summer. After he misses his bus and is almost attacked by a dog he comes home to find his parents are sending him to Fat Camp. Jerry is not pleased and screams at his Dr. Phil looking father "Your fatter than I am, you go to camp!" Jerry ultimately is forced to camp where he meets lovely fellow big boys, and realizes camp might not be so bad. They have go carts, "the Blob" and best of all no one picks on you because everyone is the fat kid. He makes many friends right away including a young Keenan Thompson. The movie really pokes fun of the mockery of fat children. 1. The fat camps beloved owners (played by Ben Stillers real parents) have gone bankrupt and now new ownership has emerged in the form of former fat kid turned exercise Nazi Tony Perkis. This movie is where I first heard about Ben Stiller. He is great as the cruel Tony. He loves to embarrass his poor campers. At one point he cancels their lunch and simply tells them over the intercom "lunch has been canceled due to lack of hustle...Deal with it."CRUEL. 2. The dance. This is another of Tony's sick twisted jokes and is hilarious. The boys have a dance with the girls camp and of course these girls are repulsed by the boys. 3. Lars. This guy looks like one of the Gestapo. He is a counselor who has a thing for the camp nurse Julie. He is evil and perhaps his character is a mockery of a German Nazi. Lars is foreign and has an accent and marches around the camp with his Aryan looks blowing his whistle like a deranged fat hating Nazi. 4. The baseball game. This is just downright unfair. The camp plays baseball against camp MVP, camp MVP is a SPORTS camp....Guess who won the game? 5. Food stealing. There cannot be a movie about fat camp without the stealing of food. Sounds funny and it is...after all no matter how many "glandular" or "hormonal" problems a person of generous girth has, ultimately the majority just ate and a lot...The boys go crazy when they learn the slop they have to eat and resort to desperate measures. 6. Revenge. The boys are abused and downright sick of it. Their ultimate kidnapping of demonic Tony is hilarious. The scene at parents night when the parents see what their child is really going through is very funny! 6. The Apache Relay. The finale. This is where the camp again competes with camp MVP in order to win the Apache Relay.The apache relay is a serious of various obstacles that camp MVP always win..... The ending is really great. This movie certainly makes incredible fun of fat people, and not just fat people, but boys going through puberty. I found it hilarious than and still find it hilarious now. It may not appeal to anyone who does not like this sort of politically incorrect comedy, but for those who enjoy Ben Stiller or an occasional chubby joke may find this movie not only funny, but endearing. I would watch this with my brother and sister and we would laugh our heads off, but we were always rooting for the fat kids. Tony Perkis was the devil and we found the "capture" of him clever. Loved this movie.....may not be something for obese sensitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What I like about Ben Stiller's movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meganrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I've seen this movie a lot of times and I like it because it's an inspiring movie to a lot of people. It makes kids think that they can be overweight if they're comfortable with it. If kids are comfortable with being over weight it shouldn't matter to other people. I also like this movie because Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller) shakes things up with the fact that he has a problem with kids being overweight. He probably had a problem as a child being fat. He most likely thinks that because he was fat at one point in time that he can connect with these kids. But he is lowering their self-esteem with the things that he says. You don't see that from Ben Stiller in most movies that Ben Stiller stars in. He's more of the guy that gets beat and his self-esteem gets lowered. For example, in the movie, Dodgeball; An Underdog Story he thinks he's the best person in the beginning, but then he gets best and he starts gaining weight again. I couldn't help but notice the fact that Ben Stiller stars in a lot of movies about weight or stuff about health. I was wondering if he was overweight as a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulse the monkey......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerry Garner lives is overweight. His parents decide to send him to Camp Hope, a camp for overweight boys. The camp is owned by kindly Harvey Bushkin and his equally kind wife Alice Bushkin. When the Bushkins file for bankruptcy the camp has to be sold, it is bought by Tony Perkis. Tony plans to force the campers to lose as much weight as they can, and he also intends to document the marathon shedding of weight and use it for an infomercial for his slenderising program. In the eyes of the campers, Tony has made Camp Hope a living hell. As Gerry and counsellor Pat Finley lead the efforts to overthrow Tony, the campers prepare for the Apache Relay against arch rival Camp MVP. The Apache Relay is a race in which Camp Hope has never defeated Camp MVP before. Although there is nothing new going on here, its your typical rush release Disney film that is like most of the junk he cast eat, fun while it lasts but leaves you feeling a little empty after a short while. The token children are there, as are the fat jokes, and of course the instructor who is a little too hard on the kids and has an accent which cannot be connected to any country and thus no upsetting anyone. Stiller plays Goodman before Dodgeball, and if you've seen a Ben Stiller movie, you pretty much know what to expect, he's funny, but predictable. So all in all, its a fun movie, but you will have a pressing sense of d&eacute;j&agrave; Vu, as this has been done so many times before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No Rolling in the Aisles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overweight high school student Aaron Schwartz (as Gerald "Gerry" Garner) thinks summer camp might be fun, but doesn't want to attend when he learns "Camp Hope" caters to portly adolescents. His parents make young Schwartz go anyway, hoping the experience will make him thinner. Initially, Schwartz finds it a fun place where fat kids smuggle in tons of candy. But quickly, the owners go bankrupt and oily fitness guru Ben Stiller (as Tony Perkis) takes over management. He immediately makes the boys camp a living hell... Flatulence, a four-letter-word, and Ben Stiller are used for laughs in this Disney production. There are ample overweight people in the cast, with whom weighty audience members can identity. The students are portrayed as fairly active, although it doesn't seem to benefit their health. Actual weight loss is not celebrated by these "Heavy Weights". The comedy team Stiller and Meara have a cameo as the camp's original owners; perhaps not coincidently, they are Ben Stiller's parents. Ben shows off nice hair and has a lot of exercise scenes. **** Heavy Weights (2/17/95) Steven Brill ~ Aaron Schwartz, Ben Stiller, Tom McGowan, Shaun Weiss
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly Stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShawnL2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was simply one of the worst movies I've ever seen. It was recommended by a now-former friend. The plot was clearly slapped together by three zombies from "The Walking Dead" (or a C- list Damon/Affleck non-sexual couple) and made about as much sense as Ron Paul ; the "we can do anything even though we're fat" message was ham-handed at best, and as blunt as Sarah Palin on a particularly stupid day; the dialog was wooden -- which make sense because so were the actors. I literally couldn't see the forest for the trees. Its the sort of movie that makes you pray for a forest fire, or for Jason Voorhees to show up and put a stop to this nonsense. That's the only ending that could have improved this movie: mass slaughter, starting with the writers. I'm stunned at how bad it is, in all honesty. I can't imagine how it got made. I really can't. The voice-over narration of the kid's letter home to grandma was filled with lines like, "Together, we can do anything!" and "We all love ourselves now" -- yet they feel that way after doing absolutely nothing to earn that confidence except promise to lead healthier lives after a night of binging. I laughed only because I can't believe that someone read the script and said yes. Avoid this movie. It's not an enjoyable mess, just a mess; on a brighter note, it is an epic triumph for writers and producers lacking talent, grace, and apparently basic intelligence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unassuming "family movie" that provides plenty of laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stratsz28
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Heavyweights" is a mid-90's Disney film about a fat camp taken over by the villainous fatboy-turned-success Tony Perkis. While the premise is not so novel, the execution is great and keeps you pretty entertained throughout. Some of the humor is dated, very 90's-specific. However, there is plenty of timeless, cross-generational humor, and Ben Stiller is absolutely at the top of his game. He would reprise this role many times again in his career: the guy with low self-esteem who becomes an overcompensating jerk. Tom McGowan, who plays a Camp Hope lifer, also plays a solid role and draws many laughs. Sure, it's another Disney story about underdog kids who end up conquering the odds... or something like that. But Stiller and McGowan are great, and the kids do a pretty admirable too. It's not a must-see movie, but you also won't feel like you wasted your time for having watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy precursor for the next decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being a child of the '90s, somehow I missed "Heavyweights" entirely. Considering the similarities it shares with "The Mighty Ducks" movies such as actors Kenan Thompson and Shaun Weiss, I'm almost embarrassed. Regardless, there's still plenty to appreciate about "Heavyweights" 15 years later in spite of its silliness -- and it's more than just a joke about the ineptitude of the Buffalo Bills. For one, it was written and directed by Judd Apatow, who has a majority hold on the comedies of the last decade and for two, it marks one of Ben Stiller's first prominent roles as fitness wack-job Tony Perkis, who takes over a once-adored fat camp and harasses the kids. Good thing "Heavyweights" was made then or it may never have surfaced, seeing as the age of political correctness and weight sensitivity has befallen us. The film is not cruel at all in its depiction of overweight campers, so parents surfing around for slightly older kid films and coming across this one shouldn't be concerned about that factor, but there's no doubt that such a concept would be hard to get off the ground, especially at Disney, in the 21st Century. Co-written by Apatow and Steven Brill, writer of "The Mighty Ducks" films, it was as if the two conspired to plant a seed for a type of humor that kids my age at the time would come to identify as their own as they entered the PG-13 and R-rated age. Tony Perkis, for example, is the spitting character image of Stiller's White Goodman from "Dodgeball" and yet to me he is just as amusing doing his patented whispery intimidating voice now despite my countless repeated viewings of "Dodgeball." There's also a classic overnight camp comedy sense of humor in "Heavyweights" like the kids getting beat in sports by their rival camp, an awkward dance mixer with a normal girls camp and when the kids unload the candy stashes they've snuck in camp into secret compartments -- as well as the run-of-the-mill fart jokes. Characters such as Tony's hysterical right-hand European man Lars, however, were way ahead of their time. "Heavyweights" is pretty immature and excludes girls (because fat girls would be too taboo for the '90s). Its typical camp movie plot as well as its "overthrow-the-bad-guy" story arch - - which ruled the '90s -- come off as stale. But ignore those distractions and "Heavyweights" is a funny, quotable movie with some classic scenes, which is all a kid (or someone trying to go back and grab some nostalgia) really wants. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite movie of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavyweights is a 1995 comedy released by Walt Disney Pictures and directed by Steven Brill, the creator of the also hilarious Mighty Ducks movie (which is another favorite of mine). It is about overweight kids who are sent to a camp run by a fitness fanatic named Tony Pekis (Ben Stiller from "Meet the Parents") who is out to make their summer a nightmare. I first saw this movie when it came on Disney Channel about 3 or 4 years ago and since then I have bought and watched this movie over 12 times and I plan to see it many, many more times because this movie is absolutely hilarious and I think it is a Classic movie. From the very beginning to the end credits where the Camp Hope song is sung (which will have you laughing even more) and where Perkis becomes a door-to-door salesman (which is also hilarious) Heavyweights is (if you have a sense of humor) a great movie which I love to quote. One of my many favorite quotes is when Josh, (Goldberg from The Mighty Ducks films) says to Perkis "I know whose candy it is, okay. The candy belongs to seymour butts." Then Perkis replies, confused "Seymour butts?" "Seymour butts?" "Who's seymour butts, huh who's seymour butts?" then Josh says "Nobodys seen more butts than you Uncle Tony!" If you haven't seen this movie yet, the next time you are in a video store, consider renting this one. You shouldn't and I hope you won't be disappointed. You will laugh harder than you probably ever have at a PG film. Rating: Over the scale! (if you've seen the movie you get my joke).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josiah Astle (rabbitfighter9)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -I watched this movie countless times and is the funniest movie on planet earth. I know it looks crappy, but I'm telling you Ben Stiller is amazing and you will love all the fat kids. I have seen a lot of amazing movies and award winners but still for some reason i can watch heavy weights day after day or sometimes twice a day and it is always funny. -It has the best soundtrack too, Disney hit a gold mine with this movie because its not lame funny or stupid mighty ducks funny. I can quote pretty much the whole movie, it is full of the funniest quotes. -Anyways all i can say is, watch this movie and you will know what I'm talking about. This is a perfect movie. -I love this movie more then anything on the top 250 list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, but if kids over 9 watch Meatballs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pufflump2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a very entertaining movie for my kids who had never seen Meatballs, that great late 70s flick with Bill Murry, his first I believe. I was only 9 when that came out and had not seen it in about 10 years when I saw Heavyweights, but almost immediately the comparisions come flowing -- you can't help but see them. Same movie as Meatballs, but worse. My (5 yr) son thought it was funny at times. But "Meatballs" is ripped off throughout. Ultimately Meatballs is the far better movie. Many scenes taken straight from Meatballs. Go cart scene is same as Rudy the Rabbit race at end. They chant the counselor name like they chanted "Spaz" in Meatballs. Stiller is great. And this movie is a good view. But, Meatballs holds up much better now that this movie is 15 years old.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing but BIG, FAT, love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunbare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavy Weights is not a politically correct movie. I first saw this movie as a child on the Disney channel and thought it was hilarious. ****SPOILERS******** The movie is basically about fat boys in a fat camp and their crazy summer with psycho fitness slut Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller). Jerry is the leading fat boy. The film starts with him at his last day of school ready to enjoy a lazy summer. After he misses his bus and is almost attacked by a dog he comes home to find his parents are sending him to Fat Camp. Jerry is not pleased and screams at his Dr. Phil looking father "Your fatter than I am, you go to camp!" Jerry ultimately is forced to camp where he meets lovely fellow big boys, and realizes camp might not be so bad. They have go carts, "the Blob" and best of all no one picks on you because everyone is the fat kid. He makes many friends right away including a young Keenan Thompson. The movie really pokes fun of the mockery of fat children. 1. The fat camps beloved owners (played by Ben Stillers real parents) have gone bankrupt and now new ownership has emerged in the form of former fat kid turned exercise Nazi Tony Perkis. This movie is where I first heard about Ben Stiller. He is great as the cruel Tony. He loves to embarrass his poor campers. At one point he cancels their lunch and simply tells them over the intercom "lunch has been canceled due to lack of hustle...Deal with it."CRUEL. 2. The dance. This is another of Tony's sick twisted jokes and is hilarious. The boys have a dance with the girls camp and of course these girls are repulsed by the boys. 3. Lars. This guy looks like one of the Gestapo. He is a counselor who has a thing for the camp nurse Julie. He is evil and perhaps his character is a mockery of a German Nazi. Lars is foreign and has an accent and marches around the camp with his Aryan looks blowing his whistle like a deranged fat hating Nazi. 4. The baseball game. This is just downright unfair. The camp plays baseball against camp MVP, camp MVP is a SPORTS camp....Guess who won the game? 5. Food stealing. There cannot be a movie about fat camp without the stealing of food. Sounds funny and it is...after all no matter how many "glandular" or "hormonal" problems a person of generous girth has, ultimately the majority just ate and a lot...The boys go crazy when they learn the slop they have to eat and resort to desperate measures. 6. Revenge. The boys are abused and downright sick of it. Their ultimate kidnapping of demonic Tony is hilarious. The scene at parents night when the parents see what their child is really going through is very funny! 6. The Apache Relay. The finale. This is where the camp again competes with camp MVP in order to win the Apache Relay.The apache relay is a serious of various obstacles that camp MVP always win..... The ending is really great. This movie certainly makes incredible fun of fat people, and not just fat people, but boys going through puberty. I found it hilarious than and still find it hilarious now. It may not appeal to anyone who does not like this sort of politically incorrect comedy, but for those who enjoy Ben Stiller or an occasional chubby joke may find this movie not only funny, but endearing. I would watch this with my brother and sister and we would laugh our heads off, but we were always rooting for the fat kids. Tony Perkis was the devil and we found the "capture" of him clever. Loved this movie.....may not be something for obese sensitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What I like about Ben Stiller's movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meganrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I've seen this movie a lot of times and I like it because it's an inspiring movie to a lot of people. It makes kids think that they can be overweight if they're comfortable with it. If kids are comfortable with being over weight it shouldn't matter to other people. I also like this movie because Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller) shakes things up with the fact that he has a problem with kids being overweight. He probably had a problem as a child being fat. He most likely thinks that because he was fat at one point in time that he can connect with these kids. But he is lowering their self-esteem with the things that he says. You don't see that from Ben Stiller in most movies that Ben Stiller stars in. He's more of the guy that gets beat and his self-esteem gets lowered. For example, in the movie, Dodgeball; An Underdog Story he thinks he's the best person in the beginning, but then he gets best and he starts gaining weight again. I couldn't help but notice the fact that Ben Stiller stars in a lot of movies about weight or stuff about health. I was wondering if he was overweight as a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulse the monkey......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerry Garner lives is overweight. His parents decide to send him to Camp Hope, a camp for overweight boys. The camp is owned by kindly Harvey Bushkin and his equally kind wife Alice Bushkin. When the Bushkins file for bankruptcy the camp has to be sold, it is bought by Tony Perkis. Tony plans to force the campers to lose as much weight as they can, and he also intends to document the marathon shedding of weight and use it for an infomercial for his slenderising program. In the eyes of the campers, Tony has made Camp Hope a living hell. As Gerry and counsellor Pat Finley lead the efforts to overthrow Tony, the campers prepare for the Apache Relay against arch rival Camp MVP. The Apache Relay is a race in which Camp Hope has never defeated Camp MVP before. Although there is nothing new going on here, its your typical rush release Disney film that is like most of the junk he cast eat, fun while it lasts but leaves you feeling a little empty after a short while. The token children are there, as are the fat jokes, and of course the instructor who is a little too hard on the kids and has an accent which cannot be connected to any country and thus no upsetting anyone. Stiller plays Goodman before Dodgeball, and if you've seen a Ben Stiller movie, you pretty much know what to expect, he's funny, but predictable. So all in all, its a fun movie, but you will have a pressing sense of d&eacute;j&agrave; Vu, as this has been done so many times before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No Rolling in the Aisles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overweight high school student Aaron Schwartz (as Gerald "Gerry" Garner) thinks summer camp might be fun, but doesn't want to attend when he learns "Camp Hope" caters to portly adolescents. His parents make young Schwartz go anyway, hoping the experience will make him thinner. Initially, Schwartz finds it a fun place where fat kids smuggle in tons of candy. But quickly, the owners go bankrupt and oily fitness guru Ben Stiller (as Tony Perkis) takes over management. He immediately makes the boys camp a living hell... Flatulence, a four-letter-word, and Ben Stiller are used for laughs in this Disney production. There are ample overweight people in the cast, with whom weighty audience members can identity. The students are portrayed as fairly active, although it doesn't seem to benefit their health. Actual weight loss is not celebrated by these "Heavy Weights". The comedy team Stiller and Meara have a cameo as the camp's original owners; perhaps not coincidently, they are Ben Stiller's parents. Ben shows off nice hair and has a lot of exercise scenes. **** Heavy Weights (2/17/95) Steven Brill ~ Aaron Schwartz, Ben Stiller, Tom McGowan, Shaun Weiss
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly Stupid
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShawnL2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was simply one of the worst movies I've ever seen. It was recommended by a now-former friend. The plot was clearly slapped together by three zombies from "The Walking Dead" (or a C- list Damon/Affleck non-sexual couple) and made about as much sense as Ron Paul ; the "we can do anything even though we're fat" message was ham-handed at best, and as blunt as Sarah Palin on a particularly stupid day; the dialog was wooden -- which make sense because so were the actors. I literally couldn't see the forest for the trees. Its the sort of movie that makes you pray for a forest fire, or for Jason Voorhees to show up and put a stop to this nonsense. That's the only ending that could have improved this movie: mass slaughter, starting with the writers. I'm stunned at how bad it is, in all honesty. I can't imagine how it got made. I really can't. The voice-over narration of the kid's letter home to grandma was filled with lines like, "Together, we can do anything!" and "We all love ourselves now" -- yet they feel that way after doing absolutely nothing to earn that confidence except promise to lead healthier lives after a night of binging. I laughed only because I can't believe that someone read the script and said yes. Avoid this movie. It's not an enjoyable mess, just a mess; on a brighter note, it is an epic triumph for writers and producers lacking talent, grace, and apparently basic intelligence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unassuming "family movie" that provides plenty of laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stratsz28
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Heavyweights" is a mid-90's Disney film about a fat camp taken over by the villainous fatboy-turned-success Tony Perkis. While the premise is not so novel, the execution is great and keeps you pretty entertained throughout. Some of the humor is dated, very 90's-specific. However, there is plenty of timeless, cross-generational humor, and Ben Stiller is absolutely at the top of his game. He would reprise this role many times again in his career: the guy with low self-esteem who becomes an overcompensating jerk. Tom McGowan, who plays a Camp Hope lifer, also plays a solid role and draws many laughs. Sure, it's another Disney story about underdog kids who end up conquering the odds... or something like that. But Stiller and McGowan are great, and the kids do a pretty admirable too. It's not a must-see movie, but you also won't feel like you wasted your time for having watched it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy precursor for the next decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being a child of the '90s, somehow I missed "Heavyweights" entirely. Considering the similarities it shares with "The Mighty Ducks" movies such as actors Kenan Thompson and Shaun Weiss, I'm almost embarrassed. Regardless, there's still plenty to appreciate about "Heavyweights" 15 years later in spite of its silliness -- and it's more than just a joke about the ineptitude of the Buffalo Bills. For one, it was written and directed by Judd Apatow, who has a majority hold on the comedies of the last decade and for two, it marks one of Ben Stiller's first prominent roles as fitness wack-job Tony Perkis, who takes over a once-adored fat camp and harasses the kids. Good thing "Heavyweights" was made then or it may never have surfaced, seeing as the age of political correctness and weight sensitivity has befallen us. The film is not cruel at all in its depiction of overweight campers, so parents surfing around for slightly older kid films and coming across this one shouldn't be concerned about that factor, but there's no doubt that such a concept would be hard to get off the ground, especially at Disney, in the 21st Century. Co-written by Apatow and Steven Brill, writer of "The Mighty Ducks" films, it was as if the two conspired to plant a seed for a type of humor that kids my age at the time would come to identify as their own as they entered the PG-13 and R-rated age. Tony Perkis, for example, is the spitting character image of Stiller's White Goodman from "Dodgeball" and yet to me he is just as amusing doing his patented whispery intimidating voice now despite my countless repeated viewings of "Dodgeball." There's also a classic overnight camp comedy sense of humor in "Heavyweights" like the kids getting beat in sports by their rival camp, an awkward dance mixer with a normal girls camp and when the kids unload the candy stashes they've snuck in camp into secret compartments -- as well as the run-of-the-mill fart jokes. Characters such as Tony's hysterical right-hand European man Lars, however, were way ahead of their time. "Heavyweights" is pretty immature and excludes girls (because fat girls would be too taboo for the '90s). Its typical camp movie plot as well as its "overthrow-the-bad-guy" story arch - - which ruled the '90s -- come off as stale. But ignore those distractions and "Heavyweights" is a funny, quotable movie with some classic scenes, which is all a kid (or someone trying to go back and grab some nostalgia) really wants. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite movie of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavyweights is a 1995 comedy released by Walt Disney Pictures and directed by Steven Brill, the creator of the also hilarious Mighty Ducks movie (which is another favorite of mine). It is about overweight kids who are sent to a camp run by a fitness fanatic named Tony Pekis (Ben Stiller from "Meet the Parents") who is out to make their summer a nightmare. I first saw this movie when it came on Disney Channel about 3 or 4 years ago and since then I have bought and watched this movie over 12 times and I plan to see it many, many more times because this movie is absolutely hilarious and I think it is a Classic movie. From the very beginning to the end credits where the Camp Hope song is sung (which will have you laughing even more) and where Perkis becomes a door-to-door salesman (which is also hilarious) Heavyweights is (if you have a sense of humor) a great movie which I love to quote. One of my many favorite quotes is when Josh, (Goldberg from The Mighty Ducks films) says to Perkis "I know whose candy it is, okay. The candy belongs to seymour butts." Then Perkis replies, confused "Seymour butts?" "Seymour butts?" "Who's seymour butts, huh who's seymour butts?" then Josh says "Nobodys seen more butts than you Uncle Tony!" If you haven't seen this movie yet, the next time you are in a video store, consider renting this one. You shouldn't and I hope you won't be disappointed. You will laugh harder than you probably ever have at a PG film. Rating: Over the scale! (if you've seen the movie you get my joke).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josiah Astle (rabbitfighter9)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    -I watched this movie countless times and is the funniest movie on planet earth. I know it looks crappy, but I'm telling you Ben Stiller is amazing and you will love all the fat kids. I have seen a lot of amazing movies and award winners but still for some reason i can watch heavy weights day after day or sometimes twice a day and it is always funny. -It has the best soundtrack too, Disney hit a gold mine with this movie because its not lame funny or stupid mighty ducks funny. I can quote pretty much the whole movie, it is full of the funniest quotes. -Anyways all i can say is, watch this movie and you will know what I'm talking about. This is a perfect movie. -I love this movie more then anything on the top 250 list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK, but if kids over 9 watch Meatballs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pufflump2003
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a very entertaining movie for my kids who had never seen Meatballs, that great late 70s flick with Bill Murry, his first I believe. I was only 9 when that came out and had not seen it in about 10 years when I saw Heavyweights, but almost immediately the comparisions come flowing -- you can't help but see them. Same movie as Meatballs, but worse. My (5 yr) son thought it was funny at times. But "Meatballs" is ripped off throughout. Ultimately Meatballs is the far better movie. Many scenes taken straight from Meatballs. Go cart scene is same as Rudy the Rabbit race at end. They chant the counselor name like they chanted "Spaz" in Meatballs. Stiller is great. And this movie is a good view. But, Meatballs holds up much better now that this movie is 15 years old.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing but BIG, FAT, love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunbare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavy Weights is not a politically correct movie. I first saw this movie as a child on the Disney channel and thought it was hilarious. ****SPOILERS******** The movie is basically about fat boys in a fat camp and their crazy summer with psycho fitness slut Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller). Jerry is the leading fat boy. The film starts with him at his last day of school ready to enjoy a lazy summer. After he misses his bus and is almost attacked by a dog he comes home to find his parents are sending him to Fat Camp. Jerry is not pleased and screams at his Dr. Phil looking father "Your fatter than I am, you go to camp!" Jerry ultimately is forced to camp where he meets lovely fellow big boys, and realizes camp might not be so bad. They have go carts, "the Blob" and best of all no one picks on you because everyone is the fat kid. He makes many friends right away including a young Keenan Thompson. The movie really pokes fun of the mockery of fat children. 1. The fat camps beloved owners (played by Ben Stillers real parents) have gone bankrupt and now new ownership has emerged in the form of former fat kid turned exercise Nazi Tony Perkis. This movie is where I first heard about Ben Stiller. He is great as the cruel Tony. He loves to embarrass his poor campers. At one point he cancels their lunch and simply tells them over the intercom "lunch has been canceled due to lack of hustle...Deal with it."CRUEL. 2. The dance. This is another of Tony's sick twisted jokes and is hilarious. The boys have a dance with the girls camp and of course these girls are repulsed by the boys. 3. Lars. This guy looks like one of the Gestapo. He is a counselor who has a thing for the camp nurse Julie. He is evil and perhaps his character is a mockery of a German Nazi. Lars is foreign and has an accent and marches around the camp with his Aryan looks blowing his whistle like a deranged fat hating Nazi. 4. The baseball game. This is just downright unfair. The camp plays baseball against camp MVP, camp MVP is a SPORTS camp....Guess who won the game? 5. Food stealing. There cannot be a movie about fat camp without the stealing of food. Sounds funny and it is...after all no matter how many "glandular" or "hormonal" problems a person of generous girth has, ultimately the majority just ate and a lot...The boys go crazy when they learn the slop they have to eat and resort to desperate measures. 6. Revenge. The boys are abused and downright sick of it. Their ultimate kidnapping of demonic Tony is hilarious. The scene at parents night when the parents see what their child is really going through is very funny! 6. The Apache Relay. The finale. This is where the camp again competes with camp MVP in order to win the Apache Relay.The apache relay is a serious of various obstacles that camp MVP always win..... The ending is really great. This movie certainly makes incredible fun of fat people, and not just fat people, but boys going through puberty. I found it hilarious than and still find it hilarious now. It may not appeal to anyone who does not like this sort of politically incorrect comedy, but for those who enjoy Ben Stiller or an occasional chubby joke may find this movie not only funny, but endearing. I would watch this with my brother and sister and we would laugh our heads off, but we were always rooting for the fat kids. Tony Perkis was the devil and we found the "capture" of him clever. Loved this movie.....may not be something for obese sensitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What I like about Ben Stiller's movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    meganrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I've seen this movie a lot of times and I like it because it's an inspiring movie to a lot of people. It makes kids think that they can be overweight if they're comfortable with it. If kids are comfortable with being over weight it shouldn't matter to other people. I also like this movie because Tony Perkis (Ben Stiller) shakes things up with the fact that he has a problem with kids being overweight. He probably had a problem as a child being fat. He most likely thinks that because he was fat at one point in time that he can connect with these kids. But he is lowering their self-esteem with the things that he says. You don't see that from Ben Stiller in most movies that Ben Stiller stars in. He's more of the guy that gets beat and his self-esteem gets lowered. For example, in the movie, Dodgeball; An Underdog Story he thinks he's the best person in the beginning, but then he gets best and he starts gaining weight again. I couldn't help but notice the fact that Ben Stiller stars in a lot of movies about weight or stuff about health. I was wondering if he was overweight as a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
