<filme>
 <id>
  378
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110527
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Milagre na Rua 34
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A little girl discovers dreams do come true if you really believe. Six-year-old Susan has doubts about childhood's most enduring miracle - Santa Claus. Her mother told her the "secret" ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A little girl discovers dreams do come true if you really believe. Six-year-old Susan has doubts about childhood's most enduring miracle - Santa Claus. Her mother told her the "secret" about Santa a long time ago, so Susan doesn't expect to receive the most important gifts on her Christmas list. But after meeting a special department store Santa who's convinced he's the real thing, Susan is given the most precious gift of all - something to believe in.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   girl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   department store santa
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   santa claus
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   christmas
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   redheaded woman
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Les Mayfield
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Valentine Davies
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   George Seaton
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Richard Attenborough
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Elizabeth Perkins
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dylan McDermott
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    None of the fun the 1947 version had
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I believe a great film can be updated to fit more recent times, the 1994 remake of the 1947 classic Miracle on 34th Street is an example of how good intentions can go astray. I thought Richard Attenborough did a fine job in the lead role. The spirit of the film was truly much like the original version. Where they went wrong was getting too heavily into the serious plotsthe scenes between Mrs. Walker and the attorney were too long and too detailed, without being humorous at all. {Spoiler alert} One scene near the end was troubling to me. They appeared in a Catholic church after midnight Mass and the priest was happy to marry them even though they obviously had not agreed to get married beforehand. This isn't Las Vegas. Any normal minister on seeing that the couple had not really planned on getting married, but were just then considering it, would have wanted to wait until they were sure before performing a ceremony. What really hurt was that most of the scenes from the original that made it such a fun film were eliminated in the remake. The comical interaction between Kris and Susan as he tried to let her learn to pretend, and, most significantly, the great courtroom scene where all the huge bags of mail were carried in, convincing the judge that the postal service considers Kris to be Santa were not in the remake. In fact, the "big courtroom scene" had the judge all ready with his verdict, then, on seeing one familiar phrase on the back of a dollar bill, suddenly rendering a totally different verdict on a rather flimsy bit of logic. In the original, the judge's dilemma was saved by thousands of pieces of unexpected evidence. In the remake, the judge changed his mind over seeing something that he could easily have thought about on his ownthe concept of trusting someone or something you can't see is not unique to the phrase on the our money. I will agree that the 1994 Kris had more reason to strike his antagonist in the remakebut the scenes of him being tormented were not fun to watch. When he struck at the man, he swung his cane quite hardhard enough to have done some real damage, which is something I'd like to think a real St. Nicholas would simply not do. In the original, he was simply frustrated at the annoying Macy's employee and gave a light tap that clearly would not have seriously hurt anyone. Even the opening scene in the remake removed the humor of the original. I remember well how I was impressed the first time I saw the original, where Kris is walking down the street and happens to see reindeer and a Santa figure in a display window, and he knocks on the door and proceeds to instruct the man that he has the reindeer misarranged. The 1994 version simply has Kris standing at a stop light and when the man beside him says that the little boy next to him thinks Kris is Santa Claus, he leans over and whispers, "I am Santa Claus." Ho-ho-dull.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    for the presence of Richard Attenborough. or for charming performance of Robert Prosky. but not more. because it is difficult to do a good remake to a masterpiece. because the actualization of story is not really inspired. but, if you do not know the original, this is one of touching films. humor and Christmas spirit are perfect options for entertainment and for a evening with family.correct - the reference to Saint Nicholas is a good point -it has not magic of original. is it a sin ? not but the hope is always a virtue.. a love story, a girl and Santa in his entire splendor. same story about spirit of holiday, faith and miracle. a nice film, yes, it is a nice film. with few drops of deep beauty grace of extraordinary mister Attenborough
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad acting and writing make this a "must-miss" remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yerwan1
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dylan McDermott (Mr. Gailey), Richard Attenborough (Kris Kringle), and Mara Wilson (the girl) are fine, but Elizabeth Perkins is miserable as Mrs. Walker, the girl's mom. She mumbles her lines with no intensity or feeling. Also, in the original there were some dramatic twists that were interesting and advanced the plot; here, all the twists are planned ahead of time and telegraphed to the audience. I liked the Walker girl watching the parade out of Mr. Gailey's window -- all the floats were (in color!) right there. And, Dylan McDermott does his best to be an engaging boyfriend wannabe, and Richard Attenborough tries to be a charismatic Santa, but the movie really falls flat with poor writing, poor acting by Elizabeth Perkins, and probably poor pacing, staging, and dramatic narrative by the director. Take a pass on this faux remake and go back to the original with great actors like Edmund Gwenn, Maureen O'Hara, and Natalie Wood, and a narrative that was actually dramati, real, and interesting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I adore this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pegaroo2-235-917453
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watch it every year. I've read negative reviews of Mara Wilson's performance but I think she is charming and smart but not at all obnoxious or know-it-all as others have said. She is acting over maturely as she was raised by her no-nonsense and jaded mother. Her subtle winks and expressions are very apropos to her role and she interacts very well with Mr. Kringle. (Perhaps I like her because she looks like my daughter when she was little.) Regardless, I love the way this story is told and Mara makes it for me. Even though logically she was taught that Santa was not real, as a little girl she was still willing to believe. Take a little joy in believing! I hope you enjoy :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad Santa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed this modern-day remake of the old Christmas classic, but with some reservations. First of all, let me compliment Richard Attenborough's performance as the is-he-or-isn't-he modern-day Santa Claus, even if he plays it with an avowed English accent. He interacts sweetly with the children in the cast in particular and with a twinkle never far away from his eye, gets you rooting for him at the climactic trial scene by the end. He performs no "miracles" per se but still convinces you of his identity with his innocence, charm and sincerity. As for the rest of the cast, I'm not so sure. Elizabeth Perkins and Dylan McDermott as the yuppie couple bound to get together, lack warmth and seem just too perfect with their stylish clothes and coiffured hair. Worse, Mara Wilson as the little-miss-know-it-all 6-going-on 60 daughter of Perkins, really could just be a female Macauley Culkin, which was no doubt the aim but still isn't a good thing. There are some nice support turns though, especially Robert Prosky as the humane judge and JT Walsh as the persecuting counsel but they don't quite offset the main leads mentioned above. The seasonal shots of New York are a treat for the eye and with a pleasant Christmas-themed soundtrack too, this is enjoyable seasonal fare, well worth taking a break from gift-wrapping, to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really wanted to enjoy this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BatStarIndyFreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to be cautiously optimistic when it comes to remakes, and had a little more faith than usual in this one, as much as I like Richard Attenborough. What bothered me more than anything is that what I'm seeing in this film is "Santa with an ego." For all of Santa's selflessness, compassion, and belief in what he does, it goes against all those qualities to see him on the defensive in terms of any heckling in a department store where kids are waiting in line to sit on his lap, as well as being quickly drawn to strike the same guy who presented no real threat to him on the street other than continued heckling. What also bothered me was the lack of substance I saw in the resolution. In the original, Kris's lawyer found a legal loophole for the government to recognize him as the real Santa, while here an apparent parallel philosophy to the belief in Santa is enough for a judge to make his ruling of--I'm not sure what. There is indeed plenty of holiday warmth in this film, but no strong reasoning to what is at stake, on either side, in the plot. I've read enough reviews to see what reasons others have found that lead them to like the movie, and I have no problem if they keep watching it based on that. For me, it just simply did not have a strong foundation to make it a good movie, even without comparing it to the 1947 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do yourself a favor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shannon-228-780770
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watch the original again. I often but NOT ALWAYS like the originals a little better than the remakes. In this case I like it WAY better. One of my main problems is Mara Wilson. I can't put my finger on it but I didn't like her for the role of Susan. Other than that it just didn't have the presence the 1st film had. I'd have to re-watch it to give you more specifics and I don't intend to do that. If you haven't seen the other one I recommend you watch this one and then watch it. If you've already seen the 1947 version just walk away you will not care for this one. It might stand on it's own but it doesn't hold up in the shadow of such a classic work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One magic movies full of hope and faith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    naomi-macwhirter
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Faith is believing when common sense tells you not to! This movie has always inspired me to believe, and I have grown up watching it time and time again. If... you can't believe, if you can't accept anything on faith, then you're doomed for a life dominated by doubt. Kris Kringle tells us this, and the movie tells us this. It shows us that Kris Kringle, Santa Clause, Saint Nicholas.. is a symbol. A symbol of faith, and a symbol of hope. Christmas is not for children, or for those who are young. Christmas is for all, and if you believe Christmas Miracles can come true. Hope is the greatest of the gifts you'll receive. Christmas and Santa Clause gives us hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was probably a very brave decision to remake Miracle on 34th Street. The original 1947 movie is much loved and pretty near to a perfect Christmas film. This 1994 version is actually the third remake, but the only remake made for cinematic release. The story is more or less the same. A young girl named Susan doesn't believe in Santa Claus, but then she meets the new Santa at Cole's Department Store (the original film used Macy's, but Macy's didn't want to lend their name to this film, so the fictional store of Cole's was used instead), who insists that he is is the real Santa Claus. Susan starts to wonder whether Santa might in fact really exist There are a few changes in this version. In 1947 those who wanted to prosecute Kris Kringle only needed to prove that the man really believed he was Santa Claus, in order to prove him insane, and have him committed. In 1994, the fact that a man might believe he is Santa Claus would not be enough to have him committed  he is no danger to anyone else or to himself. To that end, the reason for Kris going on trial is changed slightly. There are also a couple of added villains who provide a tangent that was not in the first film. I would say that while this was not an unenjoyable film, it simply is nowhere near a patch on the original. Richard Attenborough is certainly great as Kris Kringle/Santa; I preferred Edmund Gwenn in the role, but Attenborough cannot be faulted. However, whereas the little girl Susan was so adorably portrayed by a young Natalie Wood in the original version, I found Mara Wilson somewhat irritating in the same role (and I do feel bad criticising a child actor in a Christmas film!). The real difference however is in the chemistry  or lack of  between Elizabeth Perkins as Dorey, Susan's mother, and Dylan McDermott as Bryan Bedford, Dorey's some-time boyfriend who defends Kris in court. There simply wasn't any spark between them; Bryan came off as bland, and Dorey verged on being unlikeable (unlike in the original film when the chemistry between Maureen O'Hara and John Payne really crackled). The story dragged a little bit more as well, and the added elements didn't really work. On a shallow note however, there was one thing going for this film  James Remar as a spy for a rival department store, was GORGEOUS! I very much enjoyed watching him on the screen! Overall I would say that my enjoyment of this film was slightly lessened by my enthusiasm for the original. If you watch the 1994 version first, you may really enjoy it; it just doesn't stand up well to comparison.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Miracle on 34th Street (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pretty darn awesome remake. It may bring some extra 90's cheese, mostly due to the needlessly dramatic music, and it may be overlong in places, but this certainly works. Attenborough is the only person I could imagine taking over this role. He comes across as a genuinely kind and considerate man, with nothing but kindness in his heart. Like the original, it keeps silent as to whether he is Santa or not. The court scene is particularly funny, with a few fist pumping moments. I'd still pick the original, but if you can't sit your whole family down in front of a black and white film, this certainly doesn't offend the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    None of the fun the 1947 version had
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I believe a great film can be updated to fit more recent times, the 1994 remake of the 1947 classic Miracle on 34th Street is an example of how good intentions can go astray. I thought Richard Attenborough did a fine job in the lead role. The spirit of the film was truly much like the original version. Where they went wrong was getting too heavily into the serious plotsthe scenes between Mrs. Walker and the attorney were too long and too detailed, without being humorous at all. {Spoiler alert} One scene near the end was troubling to me. They appeared in a Catholic church after midnight Mass and the priest was happy to marry them even though they obviously had not agreed to get married beforehand. This isn't Las Vegas. Any normal minister on seeing that the couple had not really planned on getting married, but were just then considering it, would have wanted to wait until they were sure before performing a ceremony. What really hurt was that most of the scenes from the original that made it such a fun film were eliminated in the remake. The comical interaction between Kris and Susan as he tried to let her learn to pretend, and, most significantly, the great courtroom scene where all the huge bags of mail were carried in, convincing the judge that the postal service considers Kris to be Santa were not in the remake. In fact, the "big courtroom scene" had the judge all ready with his verdict, then, on seeing one familiar phrase on the back of a dollar bill, suddenly rendering a totally different verdict on a rather flimsy bit of logic. In the original, the judge's dilemma was saved by thousands of pieces of unexpected evidence. In the remake, the judge changed his mind over seeing something that he could easily have thought about on his ownthe concept of trusting someone or something you can't see is not unique to the phrase on the our money. I will agree that the 1994 Kris had more reason to strike his antagonist in the remakebut the scenes of him being tormented were not fun to watch. When he struck at the man, he swung his cane quite hardhard enough to have done some real damage, which is something I'd like to think a real St. Nicholas would simply not do. In the original, he was simply frustrated at the annoying Macy's employee and gave a light tap that clearly would not have seriously hurt anyone. Even the opening scene in the remake removed the humor of the original. I remember well how I was impressed the first time I saw the original, where Kris is walking down the street and happens to see reindeer and a Santa figure in a display window, and he knocks on the door and proceeds to instruct the man that he has the reindeer misarranged. The 1994 version simply has Kris standing at a stop light and when the man beside him says that the little boy next to him thinks Kris is Santa Claus, he leans over and whispers, "I am Santa Claus." Ho-ho-dull.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    for the presence of Richard Attenborough. or for charming performance of Robert Prosky. but not more. because it is difficult to do a good remake to a masterpiece. because the actualization of story is not really inspired. but, if you do not know the original, this is one of touching films. humor and Christmas spirit are perfect options for entertainment and for a evening with family.correct - the reference to Saint Nicholas is a good point -it has not magic of original. is it a sin ? not but the hope is always a virtue.. a love story, a girl and Santa in his entire splendor. same story about spirit of holiday, faith and miracle. a nice film, yes, it is a nice film. with few drops of deep beauty grace of extraordinary mister Attenborough
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad acting and writing make this a "must-miss" remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yerwan1
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dylan McDermott (Mr. Gailey), Richard Attenborough (Kris Kringle), and Mara Wilson (the girl) are fine, but Elizabeth Perkins is miserable as Mrs. Walker, the girl's mom. She mumbles her lines with no intensity or feeling. Also, in the original there were some dramatic twists that were interesting and advanced the plot; here, all the twists are planned ahead of time and telegraphed to the audience. I liked the Walker girl watching the parade out of Mr. Gailey's window -- all the floats were (in color!) right there. And, Dylan McDermott does his best to be an engaging boyfriend wannabe, and Richard Attenborough tries to be a charismatic Santa, but the movie really falls flat with poor writing, poor acting by Elizabeth Perkins, and probably poor pacing, staging, and dramatic narrative by the director. Take a pass on this faux remake and go back to the original with great actors like Edmund Gwenn, Maureen O'Hara, and Natalie Wood, and a narrative that was actually dramati, real, and interesting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I adore this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pegaroo2-235-917453
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watch it every year. I've read negative reviews of Mara Wilson's performance but I think she is charming and smart but not at all obnoxious or know-it-all as others have said. She is acting over maturely as she was raised by her no-nonsense and jaded mother. Her subtle winks and expressions are very apropos to her role and she interacts very well with Mr. Kringle. (Perhaps I like her because she looks like my daughter when she was little.) Regardless, I love the way this story is told and Mara makes it for me. Even though logically she was taught that Santa was not real, as a little girl she was still willing to believe. Take a little joy in believing! I hope you enjoy :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad Santa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed this modern-day remake of the old Christmas classic, but with some reservations. First of all, let me compliment Richard Attenborough's performance as the is-he-or-isn't-he modern-day Santa Claus, even if he plays it with an avowed English accent. He interacts sweetly with the children in the cast in particular and with a twinkle never far away from his eye, gets you rooting for him at the climactic trial scene by the end. He performs no "miracles" per se but still convinces you of his identity with his innocence, charm and sincerity. As for the rest of the cast, I'm not so sure. Elizabeth Perkins and Dylan McDermott as the yuppie couple bound to get together, lack warmth and seem just too perfect with their stylish clothes and coiffured hair. Worse, Mara Wilson as the little-miss-know-it-all 6-going-on 60 daughter of Perkins, really could just be a female Macauley Culkin, which was no doubt the aim but still isn't a good thing. There are some nice support turns though, especially Robert Prosky as the humane judge and JT Walsh as the persecuting counsel but they don't quite offset the main leads mentioned above. The seasonal shots of New York are a treat for the eye and with a pleasant Christmas-themed soundtrack too, this is enjoyable seasonal fare, well worth taking a break from gift-wrapping, to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really wanted to enjoy this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BatStarIndyFreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to be cautiously optimistic when it comes to remakes, and had a little more faith than usual in this one, as much as I like Richard Attenborough. What bothered me more than anything is that what I'm seeing in this film is "Santa with an ego." For all of Santa's selflessness, compassion, and belief in what he does, it goes against all those qualities to see him on the defensive in terms of any heckling in a department store where kids are waiting in line to sit on his lap, as well as being quickly drawn to strike the same guy who presented no real threat to him on the street other than continued heckling. What also bothered me was the lack of substance I saw in the resolution. In the original, Kris's lawyer found a legal loophole for the government to recognize him as the real Santa, while here an apparent parallel philosophy to the belief in Santa is enough for a judge to make his ruling of--I'm not sure what. There is indeed plenty of holiday warmth in this film, but no strong reasoning to what is at stake, on either side, in the plot. I've read enough reviews to see what reasons others have found that lead them to like the movie, and I have no problem if they keep watching it based on that. For me, it just simply did not have a strong foundation to make it a good movie, even without comparing it to the 1947 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do yourself a favor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shannon-228-780770
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watch the original again. I often but NOT ALWAYS like the originals a little better than the remakes. In this case I like it WAY better. One of my main problems is Mara Wilson. I can't put my finger on it but I didn't like her for the role of Susan. Other than that it just didn't have the presence the 1st film had. I'd have to re-watch it to give you more specifics and I don't intend to do that. If you haven't seen the other one I recommend you watch this one and then watch it. If you've already seen the 1947 version just walk away you will not care for this one. It might stand on it's own but it doesn't hold up in the shadow of such a classic work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One magic movies full of hope and faith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    naomi-macwhirter
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Faith is believing when common sense tells you not to! This movie has always inspired me to believe, and I have grown up watching it time and time again. If... you can't believe, if you can't accept anything on faith, then you're doomed for a life dominated by doubt. Kris Kringle tells us this, and the movie tells us this. It shows us that Kris Kringle, Santa Clause, Saint Nicholas.. is a symbol. A symbol of faith, and a symbol of hope. Christmas is not for children, or for those who are young. Christmas is for all, and if you believe Christmas Miracles can come true. Hope is the greatest of the gifts you'll receive. Christmas and Santa Clause gives us hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was probably a very brave decision to remake Miracle on 34th Street. The original 1947 movie is much loved and pretty near to a perfect Christmas film. This 1994 version is actually the third remake, but the only remake made for cinematic release. The story is more or less the same. A young girl named Susan doesn't believe in Santa Claus, but then she meets the new Santa at Cole's Department Store (the original film used Macy's, but Macy's didn't want to lend their name to this film, so the fictional store of Cole's was used instead), who insists that he is is the real Santa Claus. Susan starts to wonder whether Santa might in fact really exist There are a few changes in this version. In 1947 those who wanted to prosecute Kris Kringle only needed to prove that the man really believed he was Santa Claus, in order to prove him insane, and have him committed. In 1994, the fact that a man might believe he is Santa Claus would not be enough to have him committed  he is no danger to anyone else or to himself. To that end, the reason for Kris going on trial is changed slightly. There are also a couple of added villains who provide a tangent that was not in the first film. I would say that while this was not an unenjoyable film, it simply is nowhere near a patch on the original. Richard Attenborough is certainly great as Kris Kringle/Santa; I preferred Edmund Gwenn in the role, but Attenborough cannot be faulted. However, whereas the little girl Susan was so adorably portrayed by a young Natalie Wood in the original version, I found Mara Wilson somewhat irritating in the same role (and I do feel bad criticising a child actor in a Christmas film!). The real difference however is in the chemistry  or lack of  between Elizabeth Perkins as Dorey, Susan's mother, and Dylan McDermott as Bryan Bedford, Dorey's some-time boyfriend who defends Kris in court. There simply wasn't any spark between them; Bryan came off as bland, and Dorey verged on being unlikeable (unlike in the original film when the chemistry between Maureen O'Hara and John Payne really crackled). The story dragged a little bit more as well, and the added elements didn't really work. On a shallow note however, there was one thing going for this film  James Remar as a spy for a rival department store, was GORGEOUS! I very much enjoyed watching him on the screen! Overall I would say that my enjoyment of this film was slightly lessened by my enthusiasm for the original. If you watch the 1994 version first, you may really enjoy it; it just doesn't stand up well to comparison.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Miracle on 34th Street (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pretty darn awesome remake. It may bring some extra 90's cheese, mostly due to the needlessly dramatic music, and it may be overlong in places, but this certainly works. Attenborough is the only person I could imagine taking over this role. He comes across as a genuinely kind and considerate man, with nothing but kindness in his heart. Like the original, it keeps silent as to whether he is Santa or not. The court scene is particularly funny, with a few fist pumping moments. I'd still pick the original, but if you can't sit your whole family down in front of a black and white film, this certainly doesn't offend the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    None of the fun the 1947 version had
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I believe a great film can be updated to fit more recent times, the 1994 remake of the 1947 classic Miracle on 34th Street is an example of how good intentions can go astray. I thought Richard Attenborough did a fine job in the lead role. The spirit of the film was truly much like the original version. Where they went wrong was getting too heavily into the serious plotsthe scenes between Mrs. Walker and the attorney were too long and too detailed, without being humorous at all. {Spoiler alert} One scene near the end was troubling to me. They appeared in a Catholic church after midnight Mass and the priest was happy to marry them even though they obviously had not agreed to get married beforehand. This isn't Las Vegas. Any normal minister on seeing that the couple had not really planned on getting married, but were just then considering it, would have wanted to wait until they were sure before performing a ceremony. What really hurt was that most of the scenes from the original that made it such a fun film were eliminated in the remake. The comical interaction between Kris and Susan as he tried to let her learn to pretend, and, most significantly, the great courtroom scene where all the huge bags of mail were carried in, convincing the judge that the postal service considers Kris to be Santa were not in the remake. In fact, the "big courtroom scene" had the judge all ready with his verdict, then, on seeing one familiar phrase on the back of a dollar bill, suddenly rendering a totally different verdict on a rather flimsy bit of logic. In the original, the judge's dilemma was saved by thousands of pieces of unexpected evidence. In the remake, the judge changed his mind over seeing something that he could easily have thought about on his ownthe concept of trusting someone or something you can't see is not unique to the phrase on the our money. I will agree that the 1994 Kris had more reason to strike his antagonist in the remakebut the scenes of him being tormented were not fun to watch. When he struck at the man, he swung his cane quite hardhard enough to have done some real damage, which is something I'd like to think a real St. Nicholas would simply not do. In the original, he was simply frustrated at the annoying Macy's employee and gave a light tap that clearly would not have seriously hurt anyone. Even the opening scene in the remake removed the humor of the original. I remember well how I was impressed the first time I saw the original, where Kris is walking down the street and happens to see reindeer and a Santa figure in a display window, and he knocks on the door and proceeds to instruct the man that he has the reindeer misarranged. The 1994 version simply has Kris standing at a stop light and when the man beside him says that the little boy next to him thinks Kris is Santa Claus, he leans over and whispers, "I am Santa Claus." Ho-ho-dull.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    for the presence of Richard Attenborough. or for charming performance of Robert Prosky. but not more. because it is difficult to do a good remake to a masterpiece. because the actualization of story is not really inspired. but, if you do not know the original, this is one of touching films. humor and Christmas spirit are perfect options for entertainment and for a evening with family.correct - the reference to Saint Nicholas is a good point -it has not magic of original. is it a sin ? not but the hope is always a virtue.. a love story, a girl and Santa in his entire splendor. same story about spirit of holiday, faith and miracle. a nice film, yes, it is a nice film. with few drops of deep beauty grace of extraordinary mister Attenborough
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad acting and writing make this a "must-miss" remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yerwan1
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dylan McDermott (Mr. Gailey), Richard Attenborough (Kris Kringle), and Mara Wilson (the girl) are fine, but Elizabeth Perkins is miserable as Mrs. Walker, the girl's mom. She mumbles her lines with no intensity or feeling. Also, in the original there were some dramatic twists that were interesting and advanced the plot; here, all the twists are planned ahead of time and telegraphed to the audience. I liked the Walker girl watching the parade out of Mr. Gailey's window -- all the floats were (in color!) right there. And, Dylan McDermott does his best to be an engaging boyfriend wannabe, and Richard Attenborough tries to be a charismatic Santa, but the movie really falls flat with poor writing, poor acting by Elizabeth Perkins, and probably poor pacing, staging, and dramatic narrative by the director. Take a pass on this faux remake and go back to the original with great actors like Edmund Gwenn, Maureen O'Hara, and Natalie Wood, and a narrative that was actually dramati, real, and interesting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I adore this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pegaroo2-235-917453
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watch it every year. I've read negative reviews of Mara Wilson's performance but I think she is charming and smart but not at all obnoxious or know-it-all as others have said. She is acting over maturely as she was raised by her no-nonsense and jaded mother. Her subtle winks and expressions are very apropos to her role and she interacts very well with Mr. Kringle. (Perhaps I like her because she looks like my daughter when she was little.) Regardless, I love the way this story is told and Mara makes it for me. Even though logically she was taught that Santa was not real, as a little girl she was still willing to believe. Take a little joy in believing! I hope you enjoy :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad Santa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed this modern-day remake of the old Christmas classic, but with some reservations. First of all, let me compliment Richard Attenborough's performance as the is-he-or-isn't-he modern-day Santa Claus, even if he plays it with an avowed English accent. He interacts sweetly with the children in the cast in particular and with a twinkle never far away from his eye, gets you rooting for him at the climactic trial scene by the end. He performs no "miracles" per se but still convinces you of his identity with his innocence, charm and sincerity. As for the rest of the cast, I'm not so sure. Elizabeth Perkins and Dylan McDermott as the yuppie couple bound to get together, lack warmth and seem just too perfect with their stylish clothes and coiffured hair. Worse, Mara Wilson as the little-miss-know-it-all 6-going-on 60 daughter of Perkins, really could just be a female Macauley Culkin, which was no doubt the aim but still isn't a good thing. There are some nice support turns though, especially Robert Prosky as the humane judge and JT Walsh as the persecuting counsel but they don't quite offset the main leads mentioned above. The seasonal shots of New York are a treat for the eye and with a pleasant Christmas-themed soundtrack too, this is enjoyable seasonal fare, well worth taking a break from gift-wrapping, to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really wanted to enjoy this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BatStarIndyFreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to be cautiously optimistic when it comes to remakes, and had a little more faith than usual in this one, as much as I like Richard Attenborough. What bothered me more than anything is that what I'm seeing in this film is "Santa with an ego." For all of Santa's selflessness, compassion, and belief in what he does, it goes against all those qualities to see him on the defensive in terms of any heckling in a department store where kids are waiting in line to sit on his lap, as well as being quickly drawn to strike the same guy who presented no real threat to him on the street other than continued heckling. What also bothered me was the lack of substance I saw in the resolution. In the original, Kris's lawyer found a legal loophole for the government to recognize him as the real Santa, while here an apparent parallel philosophy to the belief in Santa is enough for a judge to make his ruling of--I'm not sure what. There is indeed plenty of holiday warmth in this film, but no strong reasoning to what is at stake, on either side, in the plot. I've read enough reviews to see what reasons others have found that lead them to like the movie, and I have no problem if they keep watching it based on that. For me, it just simply did not have a strong foundation to make it a good movie, even without comparing it to the 1947 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do yourself a favor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shannon-228-780770
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watch the original again. I often but NOT ALWAYS like the originals a little better than the remakes. In this case I like it WAY better. One of my main problems is Mara Wilson. I can't put my finger on it but I didn't like her for the role of Susan. Other than that it just didn't have the presence the 1st film had. I'd have to re-watch it to give you more specifics and I don't intend to do that. If you haven't seen the other one I recommend you watch this one and then watch it. If you've already seen the 1947 version just walk away you will not care for this one. It might stand on it's own but it doesn't hold up in the shadow of such a classic work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One magic movies full of hope and faith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    naomi-macwhirter
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Faith is believing when common sense tells you not to! This movie has always inspired me to believe, and I have grown up watching it time and time again. If... you can't believe, if you can't accept anything on faith, then you're doomed for a life dominated by doubt. Kris Kringle tells us this, and the movie tells us this. It shows us that Kris Kringle, Santa Clause, Saint Nicholas.. is a symbol. A symbol of faith, and a symbol of hope. Christmas is not for children, or for those who are young. Christmas is for all, and if you believe Christmas Miracles can come true. Hope is the greatest of the gifts you'll receive. Christmas and Santa Clause gives us hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was probably a very brave decision to remake Miracle on 34th Street. The original 1947 movie is much loved and pretty near to a perfect Christmas film. This 1994 version is actually the third remake, but the only remake made for cinematic release. The story is more or less the same. A young girl named Susan doesn't believe in Santa Claus, but then she meets the new Santa at Cole's Department Store (the original film used Macy's, but Macy's didn't want to lend their name to this film, so the fictional store of Cole's was used instead), who insists that he is is the real Santa Claus. Susan starts to wonder whether Santa might in fact really exist There are a few changes in this version. In 1947 those who wanted to prosecute Kris Kringle only needed to prove that the man really believed he was Santa Claus, in order to prove him insane, and have him committed. In 1994, the fact that a man might believe he is Santa Claus would not be enough to have him committed  he is no danger to anyone else or to himself. To that end, the reason for Kris going on trial is changed slightly. There are also a couple of added villains who provide a tangent that was not in the first film. I would say that while this was not an unenjoyable film, it simply is nowhere near a patch on the original. Richard Attenborough is certainly great as Kris Kringle/Santa; I preferred Edmund Gwenn in the role, but Attenborough cannot be faulted. However, whereas the little girl Susan was so adorably portrayed by a young Natalie Wood in the original version, I found Mara Wilson somewhat irritating in the same role (and I do feel bad criticising a child actor in a Christmas film!). The real difference however is in the chemistry  or lack of  between Elizabeth Perkins as Dorey, Susan's mother, and Dylan McDermott as Bryan Bedford, Dorey's some-time boyfriend who defends Kris in court. There simply wasn't any spark between them; Bryan came off as bland, and Dorey verged on being unlikeable (unlike in the original film when the chemistry between Maureen O'Hara and John Payne really crackled). The story dragged a little bit more as well, and the added elements didn't really work. On a shallow note however, there was one thing going for this film  James Remar as a spy for a rival department store, was GORGEOUS! I very much enjoyed watching him on the screen! Overall I would say that my enjoyment of this film was slightly lessened by my enthusiasm for the original. If you watch the 1994 version first, you may really enjoy it; it just doesn't stand up well to comparison.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Miracle on 34th Street (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pretty darn awesome remake. It may bring some extra 90's cheese, mostly due to the needlessly dramatic music, and it may be overlong in places, but this certainly works. Attenborough is the only person I could imagine taking over this role. He comes across as a genuinely kind and considerate man, with nothing but kindness in his heart. Like the original, it keeps silent as to whether he is Santa or not. The court scene is particularly funny, with a few fist pumping moments. I'd still pick the original, but if you can't sit your whole family down in front of a black and white film, this certainly doesn't offend the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    None of the fun the 1947 version had
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I believe a great film can be updated to fit more recent times, the 1994 remake of the 1947 classic Miracle on 34th Street is an example of how good intentions can go astray. I thought Richard Attenborough did a fine job in the lead role. The spirit of the film was truly much like the original version. Where they went wrong was getting too heavily into the serious plotsthe scenes between Mrs. Walker and the attorney were too long and too detailed, without being humorous at all. {Spoiler alert} One scene near the end was troubling to me. They appeared in a Catholic church after midnight Mass and the priest was happy to marry them even though they obviously had not agreed to get married beforehand. This isn't Las Vegas. Any normal minister on seeing that the couple had not really planned on getting married, but were just then considering it, would have wanted to wait until they were sure before performing a ceremony. What really hurt was that most of the scenes from the original that made it such a fun film were eliminated in the remake. The comical interaction between Kris and Susan as he tried to let her learn to pretend, and, most significantly, the great courtroom scene where all the huge bags of mail were carried in, convincing the judge that the postal service considers Kris to be Santa were not in the remake. In fact, the "big courtroom scene" had the judge all ready with his verdict, then, on seeing one familiar phrase on the back of a dollar bill, suddenly rendering a totally different verdict on a rather flimsy bit of logic. In the original, the judge's dilemma was saved by thousands of pieces of unexpected evidence. In the remake, the judge changed his mind over seeing something that he could easily have thought about on his ownthe concept of trusting someone or something you can't see is not unique to the phrase on the our money. I will agree that the 1994 Kris had more reason to strike his antagonist in the remakebut the scenes of him being tormented were not fun to watch. When he struck at the man, he swung his cane quite hardhard enough to have done some real damage, which is something I'd like to think a real St. Nicholas would simply not do. In the original, he was simply frustrated at the annoying Macy's employee and gave a light tap that clearly would not have seriously hurt anyone. Even the opening scene in the remake removed the humor of the original. I remember well how I was impressed the first time I saw the original, where Kris is walking down the street and happens to see reindeer and a Santa figure in a display window, and he knocks on the door and proceeds to instruct the man that he has the reindeer misarranged. The 1994 version simply has Kris standing at a stop light and when the man beside him says that the little boy next to him thinks Kris is Santa Claus, he leans over and whispers, "I am Santa Claus." Ho-ho-dull.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    for the presence of Richard Attenborough. or for charming performance of Robert Prosky. but not more. because it is difficult to do a good remake to a masterpiece. because the actualization of story is not really inspired. but, if you do not know the original, this is one of touching films. humor and Christmas spirit are perfect options for entertainment and for a evening with family.correct - the reference to Saint Nicholas is a good point -it has not magic of original. is it a sin ? not but the hope is always a virtue.. a love story, a girl and Santa in his entire splendor. same story about spirit of holiday, faith and miracle. a nice film, yes, it is a nice film. with few drops of deep beauty grace of extraordinary mister Attenborough
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad acting and writing make this a "must-miss" remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yerwan1
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dylan McDermott (Mr. Gailey), Richard Attenborough (Kris Kringle), and Mara Wilson (the girl) are fine, but Elizabeth Perkins is miserable as Mrs. Walker, the girl's mom. She mumbles her lines with no intensity or feeling. Also, in the original there were some dramatic twists that were interesting and advanced the plot; here, all the twists are planned ahead of time and telegraphed to the audience. I liked the Walker girl watching the parade out of Mr. Gailey's window -- all the floats were (in color!) right there. And, Dylan McDermott does his best to be an engaging boyfriend wannabe, and Richard Attenborough tries to be a charismatic Santa, but the movie really falls flat with poor writing, poor acting by Elizabeth Perkins, and probably poor pacing, staging, and dramatic narrative by the director. Take a pass on this faux remake and go back to the original with great actors like Edmund Gwenn, Maureen O'Hara, and Natalie Wood, and a narrative that was actually dramati, real, and interesting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I adore this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pegaroo2-235-917453
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watch it every year. I've read negative reviews of Mara Wilson's performance but I think she is charming and smart but not at all obnoxious or know-it-all as others have said. She is acting over maturely as she was raised by her no-nonsense and jaded mother. Her subtle winks and expressions are very apropos to her role and she interacts very well with Mr. Kringle. (Perhaps I like her because she looks like my daughter when she was little.) Regardless, I love the way this story is told and Mara makes it for me. Even though logically she was taught that Santa was not real, as a little girl she was still willing to believe. Take a little joy in believing! I hope you enjoy :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad Santa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed this modern-day remake of the old Christmas classic, but with some reservations. First of all, let me compliment Richard Attenborough's performance as the is-he-or-isn't-he modern-day Santa Claus, even if he plays it with an avowed English accent. He interacts sweetly with the children in the cast in particular and with a twinkle never far away from his eye, gets you rooting for him at the climactic trial scene by the end. He performs no "miracles" per se but still convinces you of his identity with his innocence, charm and sincerity. As for the rest of the cast, I'm not so sure. Elizabeth Perkins and Dylan McDermott as the yuppie couple bound to get together, lack warmth and seem just too perfect with their stylish clothes and coiffured hair. Worse, Mara Wilson as the little-miss-know-it-all 6-going-on 60 daughter of Perkins, really could just be a female Macauley Culkin, which was no doubt the aim but still isn't a good thing. There are some nice support turns though, especially Robert Prosky as the humane judge and JT Walsh as the persecuting counsel but they don't quite offset the main leads mentioned above. The seasonal shots of New York are a treat for the eye and with a pleasant Christmas-themed soundtrack too, this is enjoyable seasonal fare, well worth taking a break from gift-wrapping, to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really wanted to enjoy this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BatStarIndyFreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to be cautiously optimistic when it comes to remakes, and had a little more faith than usual in this one, as much as I like Richard Attenborough. What bothered me more than anything is that what I'm seeing in this film is "Santa with an ego." For all of Santa's selflessness, compassion, and belief in what he does, it goes against all those qualities to see him on the defensive in terms of any heckling in a department store where kids are waiting in line to sit on his lap, as well as being quickly drawn to strike the same guy who presented no real threat to him on the street other than continued heckling. What also bothered me was the lack of substance I saw in the resolution. In the original, Kris's lawyer found a legal loophole for the government to recognize him as the real Santa, while here an apparent parallel philosophy to the belief in Santa is enough for a judge to make his ruling of--I'm not sure what. There is indeed plenty of holiday warmth in this film, but no strong reasoning to what is at stake, on either side, in the plot. I've read enough reviews to see what reasons others have found that lead them to like the movie, and I have no problem if they keep watching it based on that. For me, it just simply did not have a strong foundation to make it a good movie, even without comparing it to the 1947 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do yourself a favor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shannon-228-780770
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watch the original again. I often but NOT ALWAYS like the originals a little better than the remakes. In this case I like it WAY better. One of my main problems is Mara Wilson. I can't put my finger on it but I didn't like her for the role of Susan. Other than that it just didn't have the presence the 1st film had. I'd have to re-watch it to give you more specifics and I don't intend to do that. If you haven't seen the other one I recommend you watch this one and then watch it. If you've already seen the 1947 version just walk away you will not care for this one. It might stand on it's own but it doesn't hold up in the shadow of such a classic work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One magic movies full of hope and faith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    naomi-macwhirter
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Faith is believing when common sense tells you not to! This movie has always inspired me to believe, and I have grown up watching it time and time again. If... you can't believe, if you can't accept anything on faith, then you're doomed for a life dominated by doubt. Kris Kringle tells us this, and the movie tells us this. It shows us that Kris Kringle, Santa Clause, Saint Nicholas.. is a symbol. A symbol of faith, and a symbol of hope. Christmas is not for children, or for those who are young. Christmas is for all, and if you believe Christmas Miracles can come true. Hope is the greatest of the gifts you'll receive. Christmas and Santa Clause gives us hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was probably a very brave decision to remake Miracle on 34th Street. The original 1947 movie is much loved and pretty near to a perfect Christmas film. This 1994 version is actually the third remake, but the only remake made for cinematic release. The story is more or less the same. A young girl named Susan doesn't believe in Santa Claus, but then she meets the new Santa at Cole's Department Store (the original film used Macy's, but Macy's didn't want to lend their name to this film, so the fictional store of Cole's was used instead), who insists that he is is the real Santa Claus. Susan starts to wonder whether Santa might in fact really exist There are a few changes in this version. In 1947 those who wanted to prosecute Kris Kringle only needed to prove that the man really believed he was Santa Claus, in order to prove him insane, and have him committed. In 1994, the fact that a man might believe he is Santa Claus would not be enough to have him committed  he is no danger to anyone else or to himself. To that end, the reason for Kris going on trial is changed slightly. There are also a couple of added villains who provide a tangent that was not in the first film. I would say that while this was not an unenjoyable film, it simply is nowhere near a patch on the original. Richard Attenborough is certainly great as Kris Kringle/Santa; I preferred Edmund Gwenn in the role, but Attenborough cannot be faulted. However, whereas the little girl Susan was so adorably portrayed by a young Natalie Wood in the original version, I found Mara Wilson somewhat irritating in the same role (and I do feel bad criticising a child actor in a Christmas film!). The real difference however is in the chemistry  or lack of  between Elizabeth Perkins as Dorey, Susan's mother, and Dylan McDermott as Bryan Bedford, Dorey's some-time boyfriend who defends Kris in court. There simply wasn't any spark between them; Bryan came off as bland, and Dorey verged on being unlikeable (unlike in the original film when the chemistry between Maureen O'Hara and John Payne really crackled). The story dragged a little bit more as well, and the added elements didn't really work. On a shallow note however, there was one thing going for this film  James Remar as a spy for a rival department store, was GORGEOUS! I very much enjoyed watching him on the screen! Overall I would say that my enjoyment of this film was slightly lessened by my enthusiasm for the original. If you watch the 1994 version first, you may really enjoy it; it just doesn't stand up well to comparison.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Miracle on 34th Street (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pretty darn awesome remake. It may bring some extra 90's cheese, mostly due to the needlessly dramatic music, and it may be overlong in places, but this certainly works. Attenborough is the only person I could imagine taking over this role. He comes across as a genuinely kind and considerate man, with nothing but kindness in his heart. Like the original, it keeps silent as to whether he is Santa or not. The court scene is particularly funny, with a few fist pumping moments. I'd still pick the original, but if you can't sit your whole family down in front of a black and white film, this certainly doesn't offend the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    None of the fun the 1947 version had
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I believe a great film can be updated to fit more recent times, the 1994 remake of the 1947 classic Miracle on 34th Street is an example of how good intentions can go astray. I thought Richard Attenborough did a fine job in the lead role. The spirit of the film was truly much like the original version. Where they went wrong was getting too heavily into the serious plotsthe scenes between Mrs. Walker and the attorney were too long and too detailed, without being humorous at all. {Spoiler alert} One scene near the end was troubling to me. They appeared in a Catholic church after midnight Mass and the priest was happy to marry them even though they obviously had not agreed to get married beforehand. This isn't Las Vegas. Any normal minister on seeing that the couple had not really planned on getting married, but were just then considering it, would have wanted to wait until they were sure before performing a ceremony. What really hurt was that most of the scenes from the original that made it such a fun film were eliminated in the remake. The comical interaction between Kris and Susan as he tried to let her learn to pretend, and, most significantly, the great courtroom scene where all the huge bags of mail were carried in, convincing the judge that the postal service considers Kris to be Santa were not in the remake. In fact, the "big courtroom scene" had the judge all ready with his verdict, then, on seeing one familiar phrase on the back of a dollar bill, suddenly rendering a totally different verdict on a rather flimsy bit of logic. In the original, the judge's dilemma was saved by thousands of pieces of unexpected evidence. In the remake, the judge changed his mind over seeing something that he could easily have thought about on his ownthe concept of trusting someone or something you can't see is not unique to the phrase on the our money. I will agree that the 1994 Kris had more reason to strike his antagonist in the remakebut the scenes of him being tormented were not fun to watch. When he struck at the man, he swung his cane quite hardhard enough to have done some real damage, which is something I'd like to think a real St. Nicholas would simply not do. In the original, he was simply frustrated at the annoying Macy's employee and gave a light tap that clearly would not have seriously hurt anyone. Even the opening scene in the remake removed the humor of the original. I remember well how I was impressed the first time I saw the original, where Kris is walking down the street and happens to see reindeer and a Santa figure in a display window, and he knocks on the door and proceeds to instruct the man that he has the reindeer misarranged. The 1994 version simply has Kris standing at a stop light and when the man beside him says that the little boy next to him thinks Kris is Santa Claus, he leans over and whispers, "I am Santa Claus." Ho-ho-dull.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    for the presence of Richard Attenborough. or for charming performance of Robert Prosky. but not more. because it is difficult to do a good remake to a masterpiece. because the actualization of story is not really inspired. but, if you do not know the original, this is one of touching films. humor and Christmas spirit are perfect options for entertainment and for a evening with family.correct - the reference to Saint Nicholas is a good point -it has not magic of original. is it a sin ? not but the hope is always a virtue.. a love story, a girl and Santa in his entire splendor. same story about spirit of holiday, faith and miracle. a nice film, yes, it is a nice film. with few drops of deep beauty grace of extraordinary mister Attenborough
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad acting and writing make this a "must-miss" remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yerwan1
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dylan McDermott (Mr. Gailey), Richard Attenborough (Kris Kringle), and Mara Wilson (the girl) are fine, but Elizabeth Perkins is miserable as Mrs. Walker, the girl's mom. She mumbles her lines with no intensity or feeling. Also, in the original there were some dramatic twists that were interesting and advanced the plot; here, all the twists are planned ahead of time and telegraphed to the audience. I liked the Walker girl watching the parade out of Mr. Gailey's window -- all the floats were (in color!) right there. And, Dylan McDermott does his best to be an engaging boyfriend wannabe, and Richard Attenborough tries to be a charismatic Santa, but the movie really falls flat with poor writing, poor acting by Elizabeth Perkins, and probably poor pacing, staging, and dramatic narrative by the director. Take a pass on this faux remake and go back to the original with great actors like Edmund Gwenn, Maureen O'Hara, and Natalie Wood, and a narrative that was actually dramati, real, and interesting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I adore this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pegaroo2-235-917453
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watch it every year. I've read negative reviews of Mara Wilson's performance but I think she is charming and smart but not at all obnoxious or know-it-all as others have said. She is acting over maturely as she was raised by her no-nonsense and jaded mother. Her subtle winks and expressions are very apropos to her role and she interacts very well with Mr. Kringle. (Perhaps I like her because she looks like my daughter when she was little.) Regardless, I love the way this story is told and Mara makes it for me. Even though logically she was taught that Santa was not real, as a little girl she was still willing to believe. Take a little joy in believing! I hope you enjoy :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad Santa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed this modern-day remake of the old Christmas classic, but with some reservations. First of all, let me compliment Richard Attenborough's performance as the is-he-or-isn't-he modern-day Santa Claus, even if he plays it with an avowed English accent. He interacts sweetly with the children in the cast in particular and with a twinkle never far away from his eye, gets you rooting for him at the climactic trial scene by the end. He performs no "miracles" per se but still convinces you of his identity with his innocence, charm and sincerity. As for the rest of the cast, I'm not so sure. Elizabeth Perkins and Dylan McDermott as the yuppie couple bound to get together, lack warmth and seem just too perfect with their stylish clothes and coiffured hair. Worse, Mara Wilson as the little-miss-know-it-all 6-going-on 60 daughter of Perkins, really could just be a female Macauley Culkin, which was no doubt the aim but still isn't a good thing. There are some nice support turns though, especially Robert Prosky as the humane judge and JT Walsh as the persecuting counsel but they don't quite offset the main leads mentioned above. The seasonal shots of New York are a treat for the eye and with a pleasant Christmas-themed soundtrack too, this is enjoyable seasonal fare, well worth taking a break from gift-wrapping, to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really wanted to enjoy this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BatStarIndyFreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to be cautiously optimistic when it comes to remakes, and had a little more faith than usual in this one, as much as I like Richard Attenborough. What bothered me more than anything is that what I'm seeing in this film is "Santa with an ego." For all of Santa's selflessness, compassion, and belief in what he does, it goes against all those qualities to see him on the defensive in terms of any heckling in a department store where kids are waiting in line to sit on his lap, as well as being quickly drawn to strike the same guy who presented no real threat to him on the street other than continued heckling. What also bothered me was the lack of substance I saw in the resolution. In the original, Kris's lawyer found a legal loophole for the government to recognize him as the real Santa, while here an apparent parallel philosophy to the belief in Santa is enough for a judge to make his ruling of--I'm not sure what. There is indeed plenty of holiday warmth in this film, but no strong reasoning to what is at stake, on either side, in the plot. I've read enough reviews to see what reasons others have found that lead them to like the movie, and I have no problem if they keep watching it based on that. For me, it just simply did not have a strong foundation to make it a good movie, even without comparing it to the 1947 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do yourself a favor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shannon-228-780770
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watch the original again. I often but NOT ALWAYS like the originals a little better than the remakes. In this case I like it WAY better. One of my main problems is Mara Wilson. I can't put my finger on it but I didn't like her for the role of Susan. Other than that it just didn't have the presence the 1st film had. I'd have to re-watch it to give you more specifics and I don't intend to do that. If you haven't seen the other one I recommend you watch this one and then watch it. If you've already seen the 1947 version just walk away you will not care for this one. It might stand on it's own but it doesn't hold up in the shadow of such a classic work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One magic movies full of hope and faith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    naomi-macwhirter
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Faith is believing when common sense tells you not to! This movie has always inspired me to believe, and I have grown up watching it time and time again. If... you can't believe, if you can't accept anything on faith, then you're doomed for a life dominated by doubt. Kris Kringle tells us this, and the movie tells us this. It shows us that Kris Kringle, Santa Clause, Saint Nicholas.. is a symbol. A symbol of faith, and a symbol of hope. Christmas is not for children, or for those who are young. Christmas is for all, and if you believe Christmas Miracles can come true. Hope is the greatest of the gifts you'll receive. Christmas and Santa Clause gives us hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was probably a very brave decision to remake Miracle on 34th Street. The original 1947 movie is much loved and pretty near to a perfect Christmas film. This 1994 version is actually the third remake, but the only remake made for cinematic release. The story is more or less the same. A young girl named Susan doesn't believe in Santa Claus, but then she meets the new Santa at Cole's Department Store (the original film used Macy's, but Macy's didn't want to lend their name to this film, so the fictional store of Cole's was used instead), who insists that he is is the real Santa Claus. Susan starts to wonder whether Santa might in fact really exist There are a few changes in this version. In 1947 those who wanted to prosecute Kris Kringle only needed to prove that the man really believed he was Santa Claus, in order to prove him insane, and have him committed. In 1994, the fact that a man might believe he is Santa Claus would not be enough to have him committed  he is no danger to anyone else or to himself. To that end, the reason for Kris going on trial is changed slightly. There are also a couple of added villains who provide a tangent that was not in the first film. I would say that while this was not an unenjoyable film, it simply is nowhere near a patch on the original. Richard Attenborough is certainly great as Kris Kringle/Santa; I preferred Edmund Gwenn in the role, but Attenborough cannot be faulted. However, whereas the little girl Susan was so adorably portrayed by a young Natalie Wood in the original version, I found Mara Wilson somewhat irritating in the same role (and I do feel bad criticising a child actor in a Christmas film!). The real difference however is in the chemistry  or lack of  between Elizabeth Perkins as Dorey, Susan's mother, and Dylan McDermott as Bryan Bedford, Dorey's some-time boyfriend who defends Kris in court. There simply wasn't any spark between them; Bryan came off as bland, and Dorey verged on being unlikeable (unlike in the original film when the chemistry between Maureen O'Hara and John Payne really crackled). The story dragged a little bit more as well, and the added elements didn't really work. On a shallow note however, there was one thing going for this film  James Remar as a spy for a rival department store, was GORGEOUS! I very much enjoyed watching him on the screen! Overall I would say that my enjoyment of this film was slightly lessened by my enthusiasm for the original. If you watch the 1994 version first, you may really enjoy it; it just doesn't stand up well to comparison.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Miracle on 34th Street (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pretty darn awesome remake. It may bring some extra 90's cheese, mostly due to the needlessly dramatic music, and it may be overlong in places, but this certainly works. Attenborough is the only person I could imagine taking over this role. He comes across as a genuinely kind and considerate man, with nothing but kindness in his heart. Like the original, it keeps silent as to whether he is Santa or not. The court scene is particularly funny, with a few fist pumping moments. I'd still pick the original, but if you can't sit your whole family down in front of a black and white film, this certainly doesn't offend the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    None of the fun the 1947 version had
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I believe a great film can be updated to fit more recent times, the 1994 remake of the 1947 classic Miracle on 34th Street is an example of how good intentions can go astray. I thought Richard Attenborough did a fine job in the lead role. The spirit of the film was truly much like the original version. Where they went wrong was getting too heavily into the serious plotsthe scenes between Mrs. Walker and the attorney were too long and too detailed, without being humorous at all. {Spoiler alert} One scene near the end was troubling to me. They appeared in a Catholic church after midnight Mass and the priest was happy to marry them even though they obviously had not agreed to get married beforehand. This isn't Las Vegas. Any normal minister on seeing that the couple had not really planned on getting married, but were just then considering it, would have wanted to wait until they were sure before performing a ceremony. What really hurt was that most of the scenes from the original that made it such a fun film were eliminated in the remake. The comical interaction between Kris and Susan as he tried to let her learn to pretend, and, most significantly, the great courtroom scene where all the huge bags of mail were carried in, convincing the judge that the postal service considers Kris to be Santa were not in the remake. In fact, the "big courtroom scene" had the judge all ready with his verdict, then, on seeing one familiar phrase on the back of a dollar bill, suddenly rendering a totally different verdict on a rather flimsy bit of logic. In the original, the judge's dilemma was saved by thousands of pieces of unexpected evidence. In the remake, the judge changed his mind over seeing something that he could easily have thought about on his ownthe concept of trusting someone or something you can't see is not unique to the phrase on the our money. I will agree that the 1994 Kris had more reason to strike his antagonist in the remakebut the scenes of him being tormented were not fun to watch. When he struck at the man, he swung his cane quite hardhard enough to have done some real damage, which is something I'd like to think a real St. Nicholas would simply not do. In the original, he was simply frustrated at the annoying Macy's employee and gave a light tap that clearly would not have seriously hurt anyone. Even the opening scene in the remake removed the humor of the original. I remember well how I was impressed the first time I saw the original, where Kris is walking down the street and happens to see reindeer and a Santa figure in a display window, and he knocks on the door and proceeds to instruct the man that he has the reindeer misarranged. The 1994 version simply has Kris standing at a stop light and when the man beside him says that the little boy next to him thinks Kris is Santa Claus, he leans over and whispers, "I am Santa Claus." Ho-ho-dull.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    for the presence of Richard Attenborough. or for charming performance of Robert Prosky. but not more. because it is difficult to do a good remake to a masterpiece. because the actualization of story is not really inspired. but, if you do not know the original, this is one of touching films. humor and Christmas spirit are perfect options for entertainment and for a evening with family.correct - the reference to Saint Nicholas is a good point -it has not magic of original. is it a sin ? not but the hope is always a virtue.. a love story, a girl and Santa in his entire splendor. same story about spirit of holiday, faith and miracle. a nice film, yes, it is a nice film. with few drops of deep beauty grace of extraordinary mister Attenborough
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad acting and writing make this a "must-miss" remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yerwan1
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dylan McDermott (Mr. Gailey), Richard Attenborough (Kris Kringle), and Mara Wilson (the girl) are fine, but Elizabeth Perkins is miserable as Mrs. Walker, the girl's mom. She mumbles her lines with no intensity or feeling. Also, in the original there were some dramatic twists that were interesting and advanced the plot; here, all the twists are planned ahead of time and telegraphed to the audience. I liked the Walker girl watching the parade out of Mr. Gailey's window -- all the floats were (in color!) right there. And, Dylan McDermott does his best to be an engaging boyfriend wannabe, and Richard Attenborough tries to be a charismatic Santa, but the movie really falls flat with poor writing, poor acting by Elizabeth Perkins, and probably poor pacing, staging, and dramatic narrative by the director. Take a pass on this faux remake and go back to the original with great actors like Edmund Gwenn, Maureen O'Hara, and Natalie Wood, and a narrative that was actually dramati, real, and interesting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I adore this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pegaroo2-235-917453
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watch it every year. I've read negative reviews of Mara Wilson's performance but I think she is charming and smart but not at all obnoxious or know-it-all as others have said. She is acting over maturely as she was raised by her no-nonsense and jaded mother. Her subtle winks and expressions are very apropos to her role and she interacts very well with Mr. Kringle. (Perhaps I like her because she looks like my daughter when she was little.) Regardless, I love the way this story is told and Mara makes it for me. Even though logically she was taught that Santa was not real, as a little girl she was still willing to believe. Take a little joy in believing! I hope you enjoy :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad Santa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed this modern-day remake of the old Christmas classic, but with some reservations. First of all, let me compliment Richard Attenborough's performance as the is-he-or-isn't-he modern-day Santa Claus, even if he plays it with an avowed English accent. He interacts sweetly with the children in the cast in particular and with a twinkle never far away from his eye, gets you rooting for him at the climactic trial scene by the end. He performs no "miracles" per se but still convinces you of his identity with his innocence, charm and sincerity. As for the rest of the cast, I'm not so sure. Elizabeth Perkins and Dylan McDermott as the yuppie couple bound to get together, lack warmth and seem just too perfect with their stylish clothes and coiffured hair. Worse, Mara Wilson as the little-miss-know-it-all 6-going-on 60 daughter of Perkins, really could just be a female Macauley Culkin, which was no doubt the aim but still isn't a good thing. There are some nice support turns though, especially Robert Prosky as the humane judge and JT Walsh as the persecuting counsel but they don't quite offset the main leads mentioned above. The seasonal shots of New York are a treat for the eye and with a pleasant Christmas-themed soundtrack too, this is enjoyable seasonal fare, well worth taking a break from gift-wrapping, to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really wanted to enjoy this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BatStarIndyFreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to be cautiously optimistic when it comes to remakes, and had a little more faith than usual in this one, as much as I like Richard Attenborough. What bothered me more than anything is that what I'm seeing in this film is "Santa with an ego." For all of Santa's selflessness, compassion, and belief in what he does, it goes against all those qualities to see him on the defensive in terms of any heckling in a department store where kids are waiting in line to sit on his lap, as well as being quickly drawn to strike the same guy who presented no real threat to him on the street other than continued heckling. What also bothered me was the lack of substance I saw in the resolution. In the original, Kris's lawyer found a legal loophole for the government to recognize him as the real Santa, while here an apparent parallel philosophy to the belief in Santa is enough for a judge to make his ruling of--I'm not sure what. There is indeed plenty of holiday warmth in this film, but no strong reasoning to what is at stake, on either side, in the plot. I've read enough reviews to see what reasons others have found that lead them to like the movie, and I have no problem if they keep watching it based on that. For me, it just simply did not have a strong foundation to make it a good movie, even without comparing it to the 1947 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do yourself a favor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shannon-228-780770
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watch the original again. I often but NOT ALWAYS like the originals a little better than the remakes. In this case I like it WAY better. One of my main problems is Mara Wilson. I can't put my finger on it but I didn't like her for the role of Susan. Other than that it just didn't have the presence the 1st film had. I'd have to re-watch it to give you more specifics and I don't intend to do that. If you haven't seen the other one I recommend you watch this one and then watch it. If you've already seen the 1947 version just walk away you will not care for this one. It might stand on it's own but it doesn't hold up in the shadow of such a classic work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One magic movies full of hope and faith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    naomi-macwhirter
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Faith is believing when common sense tells you not to! This movie has always inspired me to believe, and I have grown up watching it time and time again. If... you can't believe, if you can't accept anything on faith, then you're doomed for a life dominated by doubt. Kris Kringle tells us this, and the movie tells us this. It shows us that Kris Kringle, Santa Clause, Saint Nicholas.. is a symbol. A symbol of faith, and a symbol of hope. Christmas is not for children, or for those who are young. Christmas is for all, and if you believe Christmas Miracles can come true. Hope is the greatest of the gifts you'll receive. Christmas and Santa Clause gives us hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was probably a very brave decision to remake Miracle on 34th Street. The original 1947 movie is much loved and pretty near to a perfect Christmas film. This 1994 version is actually the third remake, but the only remake made for cinematic release. The story is more or less the same. A young girl named Susan doesn't believe in Santa Claus, but then she meets the new Santa at Cole's Department Store (the original film used Macy's, but Macy's didn't want to lend their name to this film, so the fictional store of Cole's was used instead), who insists that he is is the real Santa Claus. Susan starts to wonder whether Santa might in fact really exist There are a few changes in this version. In 1947 those who wanted to prosecute Kris Kringle only needed to prove that the man really believed he was Santa Claus, in order to prove him insane, and have him committed. In 1994, the fact that a man might believe he is Santa Claus would not be enough to have him committed  he is no danger to anyone else or to himself. To that end, the reason for Kris going on trial is changed slightly. There are also a couple of added villains who provide a tangent that was not in the first film. I would say that while this was not an unenjoyable film, it simply is nowhere near a patch on the original. Richard Attenborough is certainly great as Kris Kringle/Santa; I preferred Edmund Gwenn in the role, but Attenborough cannot be faulted. However, whereas the little girl Susan was so adorably portrayed by a young Natalie Wood in the original version, I found Mara Wilson somewhat irritating in the same role (and I do feel bad criticising a child actor in a Christmas film!). The real difference however is in the chemistry  or lack of  between Elizabeth Perkins as Dorey, Susan's mother, and Dylan McDermott as Bryan Bedford, Dorey's some-time boyfriend who defends Kris in court. There simply wasn't any spark between them; Bryan came off as bland, and Dorey verged on being unlikeable (unlike in the original film when the chemistry between Maureen O'Hara and John Payne really crackled). The story dragged a little bit more as well, and the added elements didn't really work. On a shallow note however, there was one thing going for this film  James Remar as a spy for a rival department store, was GORGEOUS! I very much enjoyed watching him on the screen! Overall I would say that my enjoyment of this film was slightly lessened by my enthusiasm for the original. If you watch the 1994 version first, you may really enjoy it; it just doesn't stand up well to comparison.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Miracle on 34th Street (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pretty darn awesome remake. It may bring some extra 90's cheese, mostly due to the needlessly dramatic music, and it may be overlong in places, but this certainly works. Attenborough is the only person I could imagine taking over this role. He comes across as a genuinely kind and considerate man, with nothing but kindness in his heart. Like the original, it keeps silent as to whether he is Santa or not. The court scene is particularly funny, with a few fist pumping moments. I'd still pick the original, but if you can't sit your whole family down in front of a black and white film, this certainly doesn't offend the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    None of the fun the 1947 version had
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlushingCaps
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I believe a great film can be updated to fit more recent times, the 1994 remake of the 1947 classic Miracle on 34th Street is an example of how good intentions can go astray. I thought Richard Attenborough did a fine job in the lead role. The spirit of the film was truly much like the original version. Where they went wrong was getting too heavily into the serious plotsthe scenes between Mrs. Walker and the attorney were too long and too detailed, without being humorous at all. {Spoiler alert} One scene near the end was troubling to me. They appeared in a Catholic church after midnight Mass and the priest was happy to marry them even though they obviously had not agreed to get married beforehand. This isn't Las Vegas. Any normal minister on seeing that the couple had not really planned on getting married, but were just then considering it, would have wanted to wait until they were sure before performing a ceremony. What really hurt was that most of the scenes from the original that made it such a fun film were eliminated in the remake. The comical interaction between Kris and Susan as he tried to let her learn to pretend, and, most significantly, the great courtroom scene where all the huge bags of mail were carried in, convincing the judge that the postal service considers Kris to be Santa were not in the remake. In fact, the "big courtroom scene" had the judge all ready with his verdict, then, on seeing one familiar phrase on the back of a dollar bill, suddenly rendering a totally different verdict on a rather flimsy bit of logic. In the original, the judge's dilemma was saved by thousands of pieces of unexpected evidence. In the remake, the judge changed his mind over seeing something that he could easily have thought about on his ownthe concept of trusting someone or something you can't see is not unique to the phrase on the our money. I will agree that the 1994 Kris had more reason to strike his antagonist in the remakebut the scenes of him being tormented were not fun to watch. When he struck at the man, he swung his cane quite hardhard enough to have done some real damage, which is something I'd like to think a real St. Nicholas would simply not do. In the original, he was simply frustrated at the annoying Macy's employee and gave a light tap that clearly would not have seriously hurt anyone. Even the opening scene in the remake removed the humor of the original. I remember well how I was impressed the first time I saw the original, where Kris is walking down the street and happens to see reindeer and a Santa figure in a display window, and he knocks on the door and proceeds to instruct the man that he has the reindeer misarranged. The 1994 version simply has Kris standing at a stop light and when the man beside him says that the little boy next to him thinks Kris is Santa Claus, he leans over and whispers, "I am Santa Claus." Ho-ho-dull.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    for the presence of Richard Attenborough. or for charming performance of Robert Prosky. but not more. because it is difficult to do a good remake to a masterpiece. because the actualization of story is not really inspired. but, if you do not know the original, this is one of touching films. humor and Christmas spirit are perfect options for entertainment and for a evening with family.correct - the reference to Saint Nicholas is a good point -it has not magic of original. is it a sin ? not but the hope is always a virtue.. a love story, a girl and Santa in his entire splendor. same story about spirit of holiday, faith and miracle. a nice film, yes, it is a nice film. with few drops of deep beauty grace of extraordinary mister Attenborough
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad acting and writing make this a "must-miss" remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yerwan1
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dylan McDermott (Mr. Gailey), Richard Attenborough (Kris Kringle), and Mara Wilson (the girl) are fine, but Elizabeth Perkins is miserable as Mrs. Walker, the girl's mom. She mumbles her lines with no intensity or feeling. Also, in the original there were some dramatic twists that were interesting and advanced the plot; here, all the twists are planned ahead of time and telegraphed to the audience. I liked the Walker girl watching the parade out of Mr. Gailey's window -- all the floats were (in color!) right there. And, Dylan McDermott does his best to be an engaging boyfriend wannabe, and Richard Attenborough tries to be a charismatic Santa, but the movie really falls flat with poor writing, poor acting by Elizabeth Perkins, and probably poor pacing, staging, and dramatic narrative by the director. Take a pass on this faux remake and go back to the original with great actors like Edmund Gwenn, Maureen O'Hara, and Natalie Wood, and a narrative that was actually dramati, real, and interesting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I adore this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pegaroo2-235-917453
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watch it every year. I've read negative reviews of Mara Wilson's performance but I think she is charming and smart but not at all obnoxious or know-it-all as others have said. She is acting over maturely as she was raised by her no-nonsense and jaded mother. Her subtle winks and expressions are very apropos to her role and she interacts very well with Mr. Kringle. (Perhaps I like her because she looks like my daughter when she was little.) Regardless, I love the way this story is told and Mara makes it for me. Even though logically she was taught that Santa was not real, as a little girl she was still willing to believe. Take a little joy in believing! I hope you enjoy :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad Santa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed this modern-day remake of the old Christmas classic, but with some reservations. First of all, let me compliment Richard Attenborough's performance as the is-he-or-isn't-he modern-day Santa Claus, even if he plays it with an avowed English accent. He interacts sweetly with the children in the cast in particular and with a twinkle never far away from his eye, gets you rooting for him at the climactic trial scene by the end. He performs no "miracles" per se but still convinces you of his identity with his innocence, charm and sincerity. As for the rest of the cast, I'm not so sure. Elizabeth Perkins and Dylan McDermott as the yuppie couple bound to get together, lack warmth and seem just too perfect with their stylish clothes and coiffured hair. Worse, Mara Wilson as the little-miss-know-it-all 6-going-on 60 daughter of Perkins, really could just be a female Macauley Culkin, which was no doubt the aim but still isn't a good thing. There are some nice support turns though, especially Robert Prosky as the humane judge and JT Walsh as the persecuting counsel but they don't quite offset the main leads mentioned above. The seasonal shots of New York are a treat for the eye and with a pleasant Christmas-themed soundtrack too, this is enjoyable seasonal fare, well worth taking a break from gift-wrapping, to enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really wanted to enjoy this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BatStarIndyFreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to be cautiously optimistic when it comes to remakes, and had a little more faith than usual in this one, as much as I like Richard Attenborough. What bothered me more than anything is that what I'm seeing in this film is "Santa with an ego." For all of Santa's selflessness, compassion, and belief in what he does, it goes against all those qualities to see him on the defensive in terms of any heckling in a department store where kids are waiting in line to sit on his lap, as well as being quickly drawn to strike the same guy who presented no real threat to him on the street other than continued heckling. What also bothered me was the lack of substance I saw in the resolution. In the original, Kris's lawyer found a legal loophole for the government to recognize him as the real Santa, while here an apparent parallel philosophy to the belief in Santa is enough for a judge to make his ruling of--I'm not sure what. There is indeed plenty of holiday warmth in this film, but no strong reasoning to what is at stake, on either side, in the plot. I've read enough reviews to see what reasons others have found that lead them to like the movie, and I have no problem if they keep watching it based on that. For me, it just simply did not have a strong foundation to make it a good movie, even without comparing it to the 1947 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Do yourself a favor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shannon-228-780770
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watch the original again. I often but NOT ALWAYS like the originals a little better than the remakes. In this case I like it WAY better. One of my main problems is Mara Wilson. I can't put my finger on it but I didn't like her for the role of Susan. Other than that it just didn't have the presence the 1st film had. I'd have to re-watch it to give you more specifics and I don't intend to do that. If you haven't seen the other one I recommend you watch this one and then watch it. If you've already seen the 1947 version just walk away you will not care for this one. It might stand on it's own but it doesn't hold up in the shadow of such a classic work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One magic movies full of hope and faith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    naomi-macwhirter
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Faith is believing when common sense tells you not to! This movie has always inspired me to believe, and I have grown up watching it time and time again. If... you can't believe, if you can't accept anything on faith, then you're doomed for a life dominated by doubt. Kris Kringle tells us this, and the movie tells us this. It shows us that Kris Kringle, Santa Clause, Saint Nicholas.. is a symbol. A symbol of faith, and a symbol of hope. Christmas is not for children, or for those who are young. Christmas is for all, and if you believe Christmas Miracles can come true. Hope is the greatest of the gifts you'll receive. Christmas and Santa Clause gives us hope.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was probably a very brave decision to remake Miracle on 34th Street. The original 1947 movie is much loved and pretty near to a perfect Christmas film. This 1994 version is actually the third remake, but the only remake made for cinematic release. The story is more or less the same. A young girl named Susan doesn't believe in Santa Claus, but then she meets the new Santa at Cole's Department Store (the original film used Macy's, but Macy's didn't want to lend their name to this film, so the fictional store of Cole's was used instead), who insists that he is is the real Santa Claus. Susan starts to wonder whether Santa might in fact really exist There are a few changes in this version. In 1947 those who wanted to prosecute Kris Kringle only needed to prove that the man really believed he was Santa Claus, in order to prove him insane, and have him committed. In 1994, the fact that a man might believe he is Santa Claus would not be enough to have him committed  he is no danger to anyone else or to himself. To that end, the reason for Kris going on trial is changed slightly. There are also a couple of added villains who provide a tangent that was not in the first film. I would say that while this was not an unenjoyable film, it simply is nowhere near a patch on the original. Richard Attenborough is certainly great as Kris Kringle/Santa; I preferred Edmund Gwenn in the role, but Attenborough cannot be faulted. However, whereas the little girl Susan was so adorably portrayed by a young Natalie Wood in the original version, I found Mara Wilson somewhat irritating in the same role (and I do feel bad criticising a child actor in a Christmas film!). The real difference however is in the chemistry  or lack of  between Elizabeth Perkins as Dorey, Susan's mother, and Dylan McDermott as Bryan Bedford, Dorey's some-time boyfriend who defends Kris in court. There simply wasn't any spark between them; Bryan came off as bland, and Dorey verged on being unlikeable (unlike in the original film when the chemistry between Maureen O'Hara and John Payne really crackled). The story dragged a little bit more as well, and the added elements didn't really work. On a shallow note however, there was one thing going for this film  James Remar as a spy for a rival department store, was GORGEOUS! I very much enjoyed watching him on the screen! Overall I would say that my enjoyment of this film was slightly lessened by my enthusiasm for the original. If you watch the 1994 version first, you may really enjoy it; it just doesn't stand up well to comparison.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Miracle on 34th Street (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pretty darn awesome remake. It may bring some extra 90's cheese, mostly due to the needlessly dramatic music, and it may be overlong in places, but this certainly works. Attenborough is the only person I could imagine taking over this role. He comes across as a genuinely kind and considerate man, with nothing but kindness in his heart. Like the original, it keeps silent as to whether he is Santa or not. The court scene is particularly funny, with a few fist pumping moments. I'd still pick the original, but if you can't sit your whole family down in front of a black and white film, this certainly doesn't offend the original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
