<filme>
 <id>
  380
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111280
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Jornada nas Estrelas: Generations
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Captain Picard, with the help of supposedly dead Captain Kirk, must stop a madman willing to murder on a planetary scale in order to enter a space matrix.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In the late 23rd century, the gala maiden voyage of the third Starship Enterprise (NCC-1701-B) boasts such luminaries as Pavel Chekov, Montgomery Scott and the legendary Captain James T. Kirk as guests. But the maiden voyage turns to disaster as the unprepared ship is forced to rescue two transport ships from a mysterious energy ribbon. The Enterprise manages to save a handful of the ships' passengers and barely makes it out intact... but at the cost of Captain Kirk's life. Seventy-eight years later, Captain Jean-Luc Picard and the crew of the Enterprise-D find themselves at odds with the renegade scientist Tolian Soran... who is destroying entire star systems. Only one man can help Picard stop Soran's scheme... and he's been dead for seventy-eight years.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   rescue
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   23rd century
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   generation
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   seventh part
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   toaster
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   David Carson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Gene Roddenberry
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Rick Berman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Patrick Stewart
  </ator>
  <ator>
   William Shatner
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Malcolm McDowell
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cast is Strong But The Plot Wears Thin,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek: Generations is a good movie with a storyline that dosen't really go anywhere for a very long time but a very inspired cast like there always is in Star Trek.It definitely wasn't a fantastic start for the Next Generation crew,it being their first movie,but I don't think its as bad as most people make it out to be,I don't think its the worst Star Trek but its certainly not the best,these movies are sometimes outstanding (The Wrath of Khan) and other times awful (The Final Frontier),I would put this right in the middle.The plot was sometimes very frustrating because it just didn't know were it was going for such a long time,but the impressive cast made it bearable,I really enjoyed Malcolm McDowell as the villain,he always delivers very creepy performances and he fit perfectly into the Star Trek universe.I didn't really appreciate William Shatner's performance,it all felt very forced and I think this movie would have been better off just focusing on the Next Generation crew instead of bringing in members from the original series.Fans of Star Trek:The Next Generation will definitely be disappointed,but will still appreciate the casts strong performances. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) disappears on a mission,seven decades later,Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) encounters similar peril and only the two captains can save the Enterprise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some fun to be had but not as momentous as it needs to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The seventh film in the series passes the torch to the crew of 'The Next Generation' with mixed results. A strong story was required to celebrate the meeting of Captains Kirk and Picard, but the plot is frustratingly underdeveloped and trundles towards a fizzling finale. It's a shame, too, that Leonard Nimoy and DeForest Kelley declined to appear. But there is excitement and humour along the way, plenty of thoughtful dialogue, an excellent performance from Patrick Stewart, and William Shatner seems to be having fun in his farewell performance, practically winking at the camera at times. The 'Trek' films are so middling that this isn't really any worse than the previous six (it's better than some); all the same, it carries with it the feeling that such a key chapter in 'Trek' history should have had more meat on its bones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and Confusing but with a couple of redeeming qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjkelley333
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I shouldn't be reviewing this film. I haven't seen Star Trek: The Next Generation. A lot of what I say here may be said out of ignorance. Well, who cares, I'll review it anyway. The film starts out with the christening of another starship U. S. S. Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk is on board for the ride. The ship comes across an energy phenomenon, which damages their ship. Kirk goes down to the core (or whatever you call that part of a starship) and fixes their problem. However, the room he is in is taken away by the energy, and he is declared dead. 78 years later, the current crew of the Enterprise, headed by Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) is summoned by Star Fleet to check out a damaged space station. There they discover Soran (Malcolm McDowell, A Clockwork Orange), an engineer whose home planet had been destroyed by the energy field at the beginning of the film. Soran attacks some crew members, and then travels to a planet where that energy field is headed. Captain Picard then learns that the energy field is called the Nexus, a space matrix that brings to life your heart's desire. However, it destroys everything in its path, and Soran is willing to commit murder to get back in the Nexus. There are two things I really like about this movie. One is the Nexus. It really is an interesting idea. A phenomenon that brings your dream to life is a fascinating idea, and actually quite thought- provoking. The other part I enjoy is Malcolm McDowell's performance. McDowell feels evil, psychotic, and brilliant. But hey, it's not like he hasn't played a psychopath before. However, there are many things I don't enjoy. There are pointless subplots that for the most part go nowhere. The most prominent subplot involves Data (Brent Spiner), a robot who resembles a human. He has a chip installed in himself that causes human emotion. His emotions are discussed throughout the film, but it doesn't go anywhere and is distracting. This brings up another question- how did they put feelings on an electronic chip? Another subplot centers around Picard. Some family members of his have recently died in a fire. He is shown mourning them. Later, he is in the Nexus, and he sees them alive again. This subplot never goes anywhere. The trailer and the posters for this film give the impressions that Kirk plays a large role in this film. However, he disappears in the beginning and doesn't reappear until the final half hour. Picard finds him in the Nexus, at his old home. At first Kirk says that he won't return to Star Fleet, but for some reason suddenly changes his mind. Yet another flaw of this film is Soran's plan. He is willing to commit murder and destroy planets to get to the Nexus. But he knows where it's headed. Why couldn't he just fly to it? But my biggest problem is this- it's SO BORING. That's all I can say- it's so dull. I really didn't care what was going on. And this is coming from someone who liked Star Trek: The Motion Picture. This film had a good villain and some fascinating ideas, but the slowness and subplots really brought it down. C
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed bag of goods for Star Trek fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sedativchunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen "Star Trek Generations" (STG) hundreds of times being a huge Star Trek fan. Recently I've watched it again from beginning to end in HD. Having watched watched pretty much every episode of all the Star Trek TV shows and all of the movies (including the newest "Into Darkness"), I felt the need to write a new, updated review for my take on this film. For many years, I hated this film as most other Star Trek fans have over the years. There many bad things about this movie. From the storyline to minor things like random changing between the standard TNG uniforms, this movie had a "wild" things going on. However, with all the shortcomings of this movie, after recently re-watching this film I've had a change of heart about my attitude towards this film. The good sides of this movie: STG is still a good, quality Star Trek film. The camera work, set design, costumes, and the works were all done with superb quality. After having watched most of TNG over recently, I've come to appreciate the nice budget this film got. The CGI, for the most part, is great. The shots of the Enterprise D were fantastic and a huge step up from the TV show models, from the flying through space to the destruction of the ship. In HD, this movie really pops for being almost 20 years old already. Although some find Data's behavior over the top in this film, I found it hilarious and if you are truly a TNG fan you will enjoy Brent Spiner's performance. We even get to see Spot, Data's cat again! Lastly, although I'm not a fan of the story, the villain is great and the concept behind "the nexus" is intriguing. Now for the bad sides of this film: the rest of the storyline! Simply put, STG has too much going on at once. They tried to cram too many things into this movie, making it a loyal TNG film while honoring Captain Kirk's history. The main thing that hurts this film and made many fans including myself dislike it, was the death of Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk's character was forced into this film. I found it completely unnecessary to ever make Picard and Kirk ever meet face-to-face in the first place. And the way William Shatner's Captain Kirk was killed off; I have and always will find it insulting and just plain bad for such a legendary TV icon. Although the story was interesting, in the end, TNG could have had a great start on the big screen without the "passing of the torch" from Kirk to Picard. The way "The Undiscovered Country" left off was perfect. Kirk has his last voyage in Enterprise and that was it. Instead they forcibly brought him back in this film as an excuse to involve him with TNG's storyline. In conclusion "Star Trek Generations" is a decent Star Trek film. If you can get past the mixed timelines/story and enjoy the good sides of this film, it is still an enjoyable movie with some hidden surprises. With that being said, though, this movie at heart is a TNG film. If you're not a TNG fan, you're going to hate this film. I also don't thing this is a good Star Trek film for the general audience. Unless you're a Star Trek fan, you probably won't "get" this movie. Of the TNG franchise, I still thing the best of the bunch is "First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Davyd Teather
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star trek generations is one of the most underrated star trek films if not one of the most underrated films in general. The mix of the original star trek characters with the next generation cast was amazing. This film starts off with three of the original star trek characters, James t. Kirk, Scotty and Chekov boarding the enterprise b. Just after the ship leaves spacedock, they get a distress call from a couple of spacecrafts caught on an energy ribbon and the enterprise b is the only ship in range. However it is not ready with a medical crew, tractor beam or weapons. They they close to the energy ribbon or the nexus as it is also called and rescue as many people from the spacecraft that they can and then use the deflector to break free from the energy ribbon. After they break free scotty tries to contact kirk but gets no response. He, and to other crew members go to the deck the deck to find him but find a chunk of the ship is missing and they believe he is dead. Then it fast forwards 78 years into the future showing the next generation cast. They are up against a mad man who is obsessed about getting back to the nexus, a place where time has no meaning, by destroying stars in order to change its course so he can get back into it. It is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Should Have Ended It After The Last One
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek Generations *1/2 (out of 4) 113 mins/ PG Cast: Patrick Stewart, Jonathan Frakes, Brent Spiner, LeVar Burton, Michael Dorn, Gates McFadden, Marina Sirtis, William Shatner, James Doohan, Whoopi Goldberg, Walter Koenig, Malcolm McDowell, Alan Ruck Director: David Carson Plot: Captain Picard must team up with Captain Kirk to stop a crazy scientist from destroying a whole planetary system in order to enter a world of happiness. JJ's Verdict: Many believe that Star Trek V: The Final Frontier is the worst of the series. I however, believe that Star Trek Generations is the worst of the series. After the success of Star Trek VI, Paramount must have been wondering what to do with what has at that point, become a great franchise. Of course, bring in a new cast and start again with Star Trek. Now this would have been fine, had they decided that some people (actually quite a lot of people) had never seen The Next Generation TV series and so needed a nice and easy to understand introduction to the characters. However, they didn't bother to introduce us to any of the characters or their backgrounds, or their relationships with other characters, or even their names until about half way through (and still you're struggling to remember who is who). Further on in the film, they want you to feel emotional towards these characters, but you can't because, as the viewer, you have no connection with them. This new crew and ship, set in the 24th century, while not a bad bunch of characters, do not capture the magic of the original crew and considering they had been on a TV show for 7 years, their chemistry is extremely poor and lacklustre. Now to the actual plot.... Kirk is guest of honour on the maiden voyage of the Enterprise B. But when a mysterious energy ribbon forces the Enterprise to save the ship's passengers, it comes at a cost: the death of Captain Kirk. Meanwhile, eighty years into the future, Captain Picard of the Enterprise D is up against evil scientist Soran, who is destroying planets so that he can reach Nexus, a mind matrix of happiness. Needing help, Picard somehow finds Kirk in the Nexus and the two team up to defeat Soran. Although the film is marketed as a battle involving captains from past and future, Shatner's role in the film is nothing more than a glorified cameo and you end up wondering whether Picard actually needs Kirk. Their scenes, although fun and full of references that Trekkies will love, are extremely silly and unnecessarily boring and slow. Throughout the film, threatening situations appear out of nowhere and while the action pieces are well set-up they are confusingly executed. Many other things are confusing and unexplained like how Picard gets out of the Nexus and it never tells the viewer how much time travel actually happens in this film. The only positives in this horrendous film are the short appearances of James Doohan and Walter Koenig as their original crew characters and the performances of British actors Patrick Stewart and Malcolm McDowell as Picard and Soran. Stewart has such a commanding presence on screen and the way he deals with emotional stress with his ageing self is superior to Shatner's in past instalments. Malcolm McDowell, most famous for playing a psychopath in Stanley Kubrick's ultra violent A Clockwork Orange, is both freaky and frightening in a very good performance. With three screen icons in its cast, it seems ridiculous that Star Trek Generations could be anything but good. Of course, it doesn't work that way in the film industry and even actors as good as Shatner, Stewart and McDowell can't stop this series 7th instalment from being a downright failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ultimate Star Trek movie. Kirk and Piccard are the best st duo ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokuguys
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie mainly because Its Kirk and Picard the two best st captains who ever lived. therefore it is the best st movie of all time. I was surprised of how high the quality of this movie was. i'm sure allot of people think of it as two old geezers fooling around in a crappy license movie but this was quite the contrary. i almost lost track of time, i was so absorbed in how amazing the movie was. It just wasn't the fact that the two of them were together at last. The acting of Bret spinner was incredible as well. For those of you who haven't seen it yet you are in for a treat(i don't want to oversell but you are going to love this film!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rough around the edges but it does the job, I suppose - 68%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the original TV crew dispatched, it was time to hand over the baton to the next phase in the franchise - the Next Generation. As this was the version of Star Trek I grew up watching, I was eagerly anticipating their first big screen outing and at the time, I wasn't disappointed. But as is often the way, watching it again today reminded me of several faults I'd overlooked before. A weak plot and villain, dialogue that would make George Lucas cringe and some pretty shoddy direction undermines a film with surprisingly good performances and effects that do justice to Gene Roddenbury's original vision. On the maiden voyage of the new Enterprise B, the inexperienced crew are forced to rescue two ships breaking up in some weird space ribbon. One of those rescued is a man named Soran (Malcolm McDowell) who is desperate to return to his exploding vessel. However, the Enterprise herself is badly damaged and the guest of honour, the retired Captain Kirk (William Shatner), is sadly sucked out into space. Seventy-eight years later and the current Enterprise, helmed by Jean-Luc Picard (Patrick Stewart) and the rest of the Next Gen gang, encounters the same ribbon as they rescue Soran again from a Federation space station. But this is no ordinary energy ribbon (like, are there many others and what are they like then?) - the Nexus is a portal to another realm where time stands still and every whim is made real. In his desperation to return to the Nexus, Soran is prepared to commit murder on a galactic scale and Picard finds himself in need of another Starfleet captain in order to stop him... "Star Trek: Generations" has no lack of ambition in terms of story but execution is found wanting. Take the climatic battle between Picard and Soran on a rickety metal bridge that appear to be held in place with a couple of badly rusted nails - imagine a huge crystal chandelier held up by a safety pin and you get the idea. I know this is Trek and thus, eminently theatrical (much like Star Wars, of course) but Trek was always more about the characters spouting pseudo-scientific garbage than firing phasers and fisticuffs. To that end, we have Data (Brent Spiner) and his Emotion Chip overloading his positronic network or something which provides director David Carson with a handy sub-plot. But he gets it wrong - an android suddenly developing emotions could have provided us with moments of humour or "Blade Runner"-style philosophy but instead, we get Data going haywire for a bit and from that point on, he is reduced to comic sidekick. Not good. It's not a complete bust - the film looks OK although there isn't much to touch the zero gravity sequence from its predecessor "Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country" and the leads all perform well. Stewart and McDowell are actually a pretty good contrast - Picard's usually unflappable manner verses Soran's wide-eyed fanatic. The same cannot be said for the rest of the cast - perhaps with so much going on, they forgot to include any scenes of substance with Worf (Michael Dorn) or Doctor Crusher (Gates McFadden). Hell, even Guinan (Whoopi Goldberg) has more to do than those two. As a film, it's uneven - it's certainly entertaining in a not-really-sci-fi kinda way but fans expecting anything as dramatic as "Star Trek II: The Wrath Of Khan" would be advised to seek their thrills elsewhere. But then, there's that unwritten rule that odd-numbered Star Trek films are no match for even-numbered films and technically, this is Star Trek VII - for me, if you're wanting a better Next Gen film then you should check out "Star Trek: First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Commendably Thoughtful / Viciously Boring / Superfluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to agree with those who are of the opinion that the Original Series Star Trek crew did not need to appear in this film. They had already had their send off, and a very fine one at that, in The Undiscovered Country. There was no need for their presence to be stretched out into Generations. That applies to Kirk more than to anyone else, of course. But here, he gets to take his final bow, of sorts. It could have been done better. At the same time, it could be argued that the Next Generation crew did not need to be in this film, either. It doesn't really do much to meaningfully develop them beyond what had already been done in their seven seasons on television. The subsequent film, First Contact, probably should have served as the lone Next Generation big screen-adventure. In any event, Generations is not a horrible film, but in practice it is a bit of a drag to watch, like one of those books that are hard to read without falling asleep. Some will argue that it is superfluous, and most would probably agree that it is exceedingly slow and frankly boring in spite of its decent screenplay and somewhat fresh plot. Speaking of which, the overall story (beyond the obvious 'Kirk meets Piccard, passes baton' gimmick) looks fairly cool on paper. A ribbon of energy writhing through space, which happens to be a portal to a hallucinogenic other-dimension called the Nexus, where time has no meaning? All right. Malcolm McDowell's Dr. Soren, a member of a long-lived species who has been trying to get back into the Nexus for decades, who collaborates with rogue Klingons, and who is willing to destroy an entire populated planet in the service of his obsession? Sure. A sequence in which the USS Enterprise-D suffers a warp-core breach, forcing the crew to evacuate to the saucer section, which then crashes into the forests of the planet below? Why not  that sounds exciting. Nothing like blowing up the Enterprise to create a spectacle. As mentioned before, however, it all unfolds at an excessively leisurely pace that challenges the attention span of all but the most dedicated of viewers, and neither Enterprise crew (the 'B' crew at the beginning, featuring the old guys, or the 'D' Next Generation crew) really gets much out of it in terms of character development. I do however have to note Jacqueline Kim's brief but excellent performance as Ensign Demora Sulu, i.e. Hikaru Sulu's grown-up daughter. She looks like a terrific captain in the making as she holds the helm in the opening sequence, and frankly I would rather watch a film about her than what the rest of Generations turns out to be. Two specific things dog all of the Next Generation-era films, and they both rear their heads here. The first and arguably the most annoying is the overestimation of Data's fascination quotient. Every single one of the four Next Generation films feels compelled to put significant focus on his character, and with the exception of First Contact, it all feels gratuitous to me. Yes, his search for humanity is interesting. But not this interesting, and his adventures in humor here are more obnoxious than charming (or actually funny). Instead of fixating on Data, I wish that a more involved role would have been written for Dr. Crusher, who I feel to have been neglected more than any other major crew member. The other issue is the hard truth that the Next Generation's tone and aesthetic sensibilities, while well-suited for television, are simply not big-screen cinematic, particularly in comparison to the Original Series elements with which they share screen time in Generations. The uniforms especially could have benefited from a more sophisticated re-design. The common criticism that Next Generation films are more like glorified television episodes is not entirely unwarranted, although to be fair, Generations does have some very nice sequences. Is this the worst Star Trek film? Goodness, no. It might not even be the worst Next Generation-era film, when you consider the respective issues present in Insurrection and Nemesis. If being boring is a crime, then both Insurrection and The Motion Picture have no doubt shared a cell with Generations. Ultimately, this is a decent film, but probably only of much interest to Star Trek enthusiasts, and even then more as a curiosity than anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely poor dialogue, NOT redeemed in any way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To illustrate the horrible-ness of the film to the best, Star Trek: Generations is to the original crew films as to what Star Wars: The Phantom Menace is to the original Star Wars trilogy. Horrible! Whilst perhaps not as horrible as The Phantom Menace and the two horrid sequels that followed, Star Trek Generations gets plenty wrong for what is yet another perfect illustration of a horrible Star Trek film and perfectly justifies the statement that all Star Trek films with an odd number are poor, with the exception of The Search for Spock. Following the presumed death of Captain James T. Kirk, over 70 years later, The Enterprise has fallen into the hands of Captain Picard who deals with family strains whilst a new threat is under way. A surviver of an accident, that isn't carefully explained nor dealt with, has begun his attack on a star that when destroyed, will somehow give way to be able to visit the Nexus, which is a dream like world that presents the best and the happiest moments to anyone and everyone. The film suffers on almost every single aspect. The story is poor, but it goes even beyond this. It's not just a poor story and poor writing, but the story leaves no impact on us, as we have no idea who these new characters are. Much like how the original crew were first presented in Star Trek: The Motion Picture, the characters here are presented extremely ridiculously and annoyingly, the greatest of them being Data, who could have come off as an interesting android for the remainder of this franchise but is literally depicted as Jar Jar Binks. Now, it is clearly evident where George Lucas got his influence from. See, Spock was a fatherly figure and a wise man and was an interesting and likable character. Data is supposed to be a similar character but here is presented in the most horrid manner much like how we were apparently supposed to view Jar Jar as a Yoda type character. Such event is referred to as deliberately taking a sh*t on one's head! Data is annoying and is horrible jokes about an emotion chip and how he is suddenly able to understand jokes that were told years ago is not funny, its downright ridiculous. And not in a good way like in Monty Python and the Holy Grail. This character should've been presented far better and horrible writing is clearly evident here. Not only is Data poorly written, so is Picard who throughout the film deals with such family issues, having recently received the news that his family has died. Two things make this completely a forgettable and unnecessary sub plot to the film: This is the first time we even know who Picard is. There is obviously no reference in the original series due to the fact that this takes place over 70 years later. And secondly, the story about his family is hardly elaborated in anyway whatsoever and is instead, thrown in from the air and just left in a steady place. More poor writing is evident here. Each character is poorly written, to the fullest. The villain in the film, played by Malcolm McDowell, is yet again, another one of the many examples of poor writing in the film. His plan and his plot in the film is quickly summed up and almost never really referred to. Had he been written well, Soran could be a similar villain to Khan from the great 'Wrath of Khan'. Apparently in the film, Soran deals with personal issues of his own. MaybeThis character is hardly explained, due to horrible writing and has quite a silly and ridiculous plot. Whereas Star Trek 5 was ridiculous, it was not to this extent. The villain had a purpose that seemed more legit than here. Special effects are the same as all Star Trek films. Not great but decent enough for a pass. The acting is good, I would possibly say. Patrick Stewart as Picard is a great choice as is Malcolm McDowell as Soran but both are utterly wasted in this film. Returning is William Shatner, early on in the film as Captain James T. Kirk, in the best proportion of the film and returning late in the film in an extremely ridiculous concept. The best part of the film is the opening proportion as it cleverly resembles a good Star Trek film dealing with Kirk's desperation to get back into the captain's chair. Everything after this, is downhill ***SPOILERS*** The film suffers a lot in every way possible but here is when it is clearly evident that this is a truly horrible film. Our main character, James T Kirk, who has been loved by all is killed at the very end of the film in the most ridiculous and one of the most anticlimactic deaths to one of the great heroes. He dies and this scene shares no emotion like good Trek films do. When your main character, that you've loved so long, is killed and you laugh, that there is the perfect example of poor writing. ***END OF SPOILERS*** Star Trek: Generations, is in my opinion, the second worst film of the franchise, winning the silver medal with a gold going to the first Star Trek film. This film pretty much ensures that all odd numbered Star Trek films are terrible, with one small exception. Badly written, with a lame story and undeveloped characters, due to poor writing, Star Trek Generations is an utter failure. To imagine this movie, it is the Phantom Menace of Star Trek. To illustrate, prior to the making of the film, the director realized it was the 7th instalment and that it had to be horrible, and so asked for some horrible writing and extremely poor character development This film is a complete failure in every aspect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cast is Strong But The Plot Wears Thin,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek: Generations is a good movie with a storyline that dosen't really go anywhere for a very long time but a very inspired cast like there always is in Star Trek.It definitely wasn't a fantastic start for the Next Generation crew,it being their first movie,but I don't think its as bad as most people make it out to be,I don't think its the worst Star Trek but its certainly not the best,these movies are sometimes outstanding (The Wrath of Khan) and other times awful (The Final Frontier),I would put this right in the middle.The plot was sometimes very frustrating because it just didn't know were it was going for such a long time,but the impressive cast made it bearable,I really enjoyed Malcolm McDowell as the villain,he always delivers very creepy performances and he fit perfectly into the Star Trek universe.I didn't really appreciate William Shatner's performance,it all felt very forced and I think this movie would have been better off just focusing on the Next Generation crew instead of bringing in members from the original series.Fans of Star Trek:The Next Generation will definitely be disappointed,but will still appreciate the casts strong performances. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) disappears on a mission,seven decades later,Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) encounters similar peril and only the two captains can save the Enterprise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some fun to be had but not as momentous as it needs to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The seventh film in the series passes the torch to the crew of 'The Next Generation' with mixed results. A strong story was required to celebrate the meeting of Captains Kirk and Picard, but the plot is frustratingly underdeveloped and trundles towards a fizzling finale. It's a shame, too, that Leonard Nimoy and DeForest Kelley declined to appear. But there is excitement and humour along the way, plenty of thoughtful dialogue, an excellent performance from Patrick Stewart, and William Shatner seems to be having fun in his farewell performance, practically winking at the camera at times. The 'Trek' films are so middling that this isn't really any worse than the previous six (it's better than some); all the same, it carries with it the feeling that such a key chapter in 'Trek' history should have had more meat on its bones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and Confusing but with a couple of redeeming qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjkelley333
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I shouldn't be reviewing this film. I haven't seen Star Trek: The Next Generation. A lot of what I say here may be said out of ignorance. Well, who cares, I'll review it anyway. The film starts out with the christening of another starship U. S. S. Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk is on board for the ride. The ship comes across an energy phenomenon, which damages their ship. Kirk goes down to the core (or whatever you call that part of a starship) and fixes their problem. However, the room he is in is taken away by the energy, and he is declared dead. 78 years later, the current crew of the Enterprise, headed by Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) is summoned by Star Fleet to check out a damaged space station. There they discover Soran (Malcolm McDowell, A Clockwork Orange), an engineer whose home planet had been destroyed by the energy field at the beginning of the film. Soran attacks some crew members, and then travels to a planet where that energy field is headed. Captain Picard then learns that the energy field is called the Nexus, a space matrix that brings to life your heart's desire. However, it destroys everything in its path, and Soran is willing to commit murder to get back in the Nexus. There are two things I really like about this movie. One is the Nexus. It really is an interesting idea. A phenomenon that brings your dream to life is a fascinating idea, and actually quite thought- provoking. The other part I enjoy is Malcolm McDowell's performance. McDowell feels evil, psychotic, and brilliant. But hey, it's not like he hasn't played a psychopath before. However, there are many things I don't enjoy. There are pointless subplots that for the most part go nowhere. The most prominent subplot involves Data (Brent Spiner), a robot who resembles a human. He has a chip installed in himself that causes human emotion. His emotions are discussed throughout the film, but it doesn't go anywhere and is distracting. This brings up another question- how did they put feelings on an electronic chip? Another subplot centers around Picard. Some family members of his have recently died in a fire. He is shown mourning them. Later, he is in the Nexus, and he sees them alive again. This subplot never goes anywhere. The trailer and the posters for this film give the impressions that Kirk plays a large role in this film. However, he disappears in the beginning and doesn't reappear until the final half hour. Picard finds him in the Nexus, at his old home. At first Kirk says that he won't return to Star Fleet, but for some reason suddenly changes his mind. Yet another flaw of this film is Soran's plan. He is willing to commit murder and destroy planets to get to the Nexus. But he knows where it's headed. Why couldn't he just fly to it? But my biggest problem is this- it's SO BORING. That's all I can say- it's so dull. I really didn't care what was going on. And this is coming from someone who liked Star Trek: The Motion Picture. This film had a good villain and some fascinating ideas, but the slowness and subplots really brought it down. C
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed bag of goods for Star Trek fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sedativchunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen "Star Trek Generations" (STG) hundreds of times being a huge Star Trek fan. Recently I've watched it again from beginning to end in HD. Having watched watched pretty much every episode of all the Star Trek TV shows and all of the movies (including the newest "Into Darkness"), I felt the need to write a new, updated review for my take on this film. For many years, I hated this film as most other Star Trek fans have over the years. There many bad things about this movie. From the storyline to minor things like random changing between the standard TNG uniforms, this movie had a "wild" things going on. However, with all the shortcomings of this movie, after recently re-watching this film I've had a change of heart about my attitude towards this film. The good sides of this movie: STG is still a good, quality Star Trek film. The camera work, set design, costumes, and the works were all done with superb quality. After having watched most of TNG over recently, I've come to appreciate the nice budget this film got. The CGI, for the most part, is great. The shots of the Enterprise D were fantastic and a huge step up from the TV show models, from the flying through space to the destruction of the ship. In HD, this movie really pops for being almost 20 years old already. Although some find Data's behavior over the top in this film, I found it hilarious and if you are truly a TNG fan you will enjoy Brent Spiner's performance. We even get to see Spot, Data's cat again! Lastly, although I'm not a fan of the story, the villain is great and the concept behind "the nexus" is intriguing. Now for the bad sides of this film: the rest of the storyline! Simply put, STG has too much going on at once. They tried to cram too many things into this movie, making it a loyal TNG film while honoring Captain Kirk's history. The main thing that hurts this film and made many fans including myself dislike it, was the death of Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk's character was forced into this film. I found it completely unnecessary to ever make Picard and Kirk ever meet face-to-face in the first place. And the way William Shatner's Captain Kirk was killed off; I have and always will find it insulting and just plain bad for such a legendary TV icon. Although the story was interesting, in the end, TNG could have had a great start on the big screen without the "passing of the torch" from Kirk to Picard. The way "The Undiscovered Country" left off was perfect. Kirk has his last voyage in Enterprise and that was it. Instead they forcibly brought him back in this film as an excuse to involve him with TNG's storyline. In conclusion "Star Trek Generations" is a decent Star Trek film. If you can get past the mixed timelines/story and enjoy the good sides of this film, it is still an enjoyable movie with some hidden surprises. With that being said, though, this movie at heart is a TNG film. If you're not a TNG fan, you're going to hate this film. I also don't thing this is a good Star Trek film for the general audience. Unless you're a Star Trek fan, you probably won't "get" this movie. Of the TNG franchise, I still thing the best of the bunch is "First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Davyd Teather
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star trek generations is one of the most underrated star trek films if not one of the most underrated films in general. The mix of the original star trek characters with the next generation cast was amazing. This film starts off with three of the original star trek characters, James t. Kirk, Scotty and Chekov boarding the enterprise b. Just after the ship leaves spacedock, they get a distress call from a couple of spacecrafts caught on an energy ribbon and the enterprise b is the only ship in range. However it is not ready with a medical crew, tractor beam or weapons. They they close to the energy ribbon or the nexus as it is also called and rescue as many people from the spacecraft that they can and then use the deflector to break free from the energy ribbon. After they break free scotty tries to contact kirk but gets no response. He, and to other crew members go to the deck the deck to find him but find a chunk of the ship is missing and they believe he is dead. Then it fast forwards 78 years into the future showing the next generation cast. They are up against a mad man who is obsessed about getting back to the nexus, a place where time has no meaning, by destroying stars in order to change its course so he can get back into it. It is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Should Have Ended It After The Last One
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek Generations *1/2 (out of 4) 113 mins/ PG Cast: Patrick Stewart, Jonathan Frakes, Brent Spiner, LeVar Burton, Michael Dorn, Gates McFadden, Marina Sirtis, William Shatner, James Doohan, Whoopi Goldberg, Walter Koenig, Malcolm McDowell, Alan Ruck Director: David Carson Plot: Captain Picard must team up with Captain Kirk to stop a crazy scientist from destroying a whole planetary system in order to enter a world of happiness. JJ's Verdict: Many believe that Star Trek V: The Final Frontier is the worst of the series. I however, believe that Star Trek Generations is the worst of the series. After the success of Star Trek VI, Paramount must have been wondering what to do with what has at that point, become a great franchise. Of course, bring in a new cast and start again with Star Trek. Now this would have been fine, had they decided that some people (actually quite a lot of people) had never seen The Next Generation TV series and so needed a nice and easy to understand introduction to the characters. However, they didn't bother to introduce us to any of the characters or their backgrounds, or their relationships with other characters, or even their names until about half way through (and still you're struggling to remember who is who). Further on in the film, they want you to feel emotional towards these characters, but you can't because, as the viewer, you have no connection with them. This new crew and ship, set in the 24th century, while not a bad bunch of characters, do not capture the magic of the original crew and considering they had been on a TV show for 7 years, their chemistry is extremely poor and lacklustre. Now to the actual plot.... Kirk is guest of honour on the maiden voyage of the Enterprise B. But when a mysterious energy ribbon forces the Enterprise to save the ship's passengers, it comes at a cost: the death of Captain Kirk. Meanwhile, eighty years into the future, Captain Picard of the Enterprise D is up against evil scientist Soran, who is destroying planets so that he can reach Nexus, a mind matrix of happiness. Needing help, Picard somehow finds Kirk in the Nexus and the two team up to defeat Soran. Although the film is marketed as a battle involving captains from past and future, Shatner's role in the film is nothing more than a glorified cameo and you end up wondering whether Picard actually needs Kirk. Their scenes, although fun and full of references that Trekkies will love, are extremely silly and unnecessarily boring and slow. Throughout the film, threatening situations appear out of nowhere and while the action pieces are well set-up they are confusingly executed. Many other things are confusing and unexplained like how Picard gets out of the Nexus and it never tells the viewer how much time travel actually happens in this film. The only positives in this horrendous film are the short appearances of James Doohan and Walter Koenig as their original crew characters and the performances of British actors Patrick Stewart and Malcolm McDowell as Picard and Soran. Stewart has such a commanding presence on screen and the way he deals with emotional stress with his ageing self is superior to Shatner's in past instalments. Malcolm McDowell, most famous for playing a psychopath in Stanley Kubrick's ultra violent A Clockwork Orange, is both freaky and frightening in a very good performance. With three screen icons in its cast, it seems ridiculous that Star Trek Generations could be anything but good. Of course, it doesn't work that way in the film industry and even actors as good as Shatner, Stewart and McDowell can't stop this series 7th instalment from being a downright failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ultimate Star Trek movie. Kirk and Piccard are the best st duo ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokuguys
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie mainly because Its Kirk and Picard the two best st captains who ever lived. therefore it is the best st movie of all time. I was surprised of how high the quality of this movie was. i'm sure allot of people think of it as two old geezers fooling around in a crappy license movie but this was quite the contrary. i almost lost track of time, i was so absorbed in how amazing the movie was. It just wasn't the fact that the two of them were together at last. The acting of Bret spinner was incredible as well. For those of you who haven't seen it yet you are in for a treat(i don't want to oversell but you are going to love this film!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rough around the edges but it does the job, I suppose - 68%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the original TV crew dispatched, it was time to hand over the baton to the next phase in the franchise - the Next Generation. As this was the version of Star Trek I grew up watching, I was eagerly anticipating their first big screen outing and at the time, I wasn't disappointed. But as is often the way, watching it again today reminded me of several faults I'd overlooked before. A weak plot and villain, dialogue that would make George Lucas cringe and some pretty shoddy direction undermines a film with surprisingly good performances and effects that do justice to Gene Roddenbury's original vision. On the maiden voyage of the new Enterprise B, the inexperienced crew are forced to rescue two ships breaking up in some weird space ribbon. One of those rescued is a man named Soran (Malcolm McDowell) who is desperate to return to his exploding vessel. However, the Enterprise herself is badly damaged and the guest of honour, the retired Captain Kirk (William Shatner), is sadly sucked out into space. Seventy-eight years later and the current Enterprise, helmed by Jean-Luc Picard (Patrick Stewart) and the rest of the Next Gen gang, encounters the same ribbon as they rescue Soran again from a Federation space station. But this is no ordinary energy ribbon (like, are there many others and what are they like then?) - the Nexus is a portal to another realm where time stands still and every whim is made real. In his desperation to return to the Nexus, Soran is prepared to commit murder on a galactic scale and Picard finds himself in need of another Starfleet captain in order to stop him... "Star Trek: Generations" has no lack of ambition in terms of story but execution is found wanting. Take the climatic battle between Picard and Soran on a rickety metal bridge that appear to be held in place with a couple of badly rusted nails - imagine a huge crystal chandelier held up by a safety pin and you get the idea. I know this is Trek and thus, eminently theatrical (much like Star Wars, of course) but Trek was always more about the characters spouting pseudo-scientific garbage than firing phasers and fisticuffs. To that end, we have Data (Brent Spiner) and his Emotion Chip overloading his positronic network or something which provides director David Carson with a handy sub-plot. But he gets it wrong - an android suddenly developing emotions could have provided us with moments of humour or "Blade Runner"-style philosophy but instead, we get Data going haywire for a bit and from that point on, he is reduced to comic sidekick. Not good. It's not a complete bust - the film looks OK although there isn't much to touch the zero gravity sequence from its predecessor "Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country" and the leads all perform well. Stewart and McDowell are actually a pretty good contrast - Picard's usually unflappable manner verses Soran's wide-eyed fanatic. The same cannot be said for the rest of the cast - perhaps with so much going on, they forgot to include any scenes of substance with Worf (Michael Dorn) or Doctor Crusher (Gates McFadden). Hell, even Guinan (Whoopi Goldberg) has more to do than those two. As a film, it's uneven - it's certainly entertaining in a not-really-sci-fi kinda way but fans expecting anything as dramatic as "Star Trek II: The Wrath Of Khan" would be advised to seek their thrills elsewhere. But then, there's that unwritten rule that odd-numbered Star Trek films are no match for even-numbered films and technically, this is Star Trek VII - for me, if you're wanting a better Next Gen film then you should check out "Star Trek: First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Commendably Thoughtful / Viciously Boring / Superfluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to agree with those who are of the opinion that the Original Series Star Trek crew did not need to appear in this film. They had already had their send off, and a very fine one at that, in The Undiscovered Country. There was no need for their presence to be stretched out into Generations. That applies to Kirk more than to anyone else, of course. But here, he gets to take his final bow, of sorts. It could have been done better. At the same time, it could be argued that the Next Generation crew did not need to be in this film, either. It doesn't really do much to meaningfully develop them beyond what had already been done in their seven seasons on television. The subsequent film, First Contact, probably should have served as the lone Next Generation big screen-adventure. In any event, Generations is not a horrible film, but in practice it is a bit of a drag to watch, like one of those books that are hard to read without falling asleep. Some will argue that it is superfluous, and most would probably agree that it is exceedingly slow and frankly boring in spite of its decent screenplay and somewhat fresh plot. Speaking of which, the overall story (beyond the obvious 'Kirk meets Piccard, passes baton' gimmick) looks fairly cool on paper. A ribbon of energy writhing through space, which happens to be a portal to a hallucinogenic other-dimension called the Nexus, where time has no meaning? All right. Malcolm McDowell's Dr. Soren, a member of a long-lived species who has been trying to get back into the Nexus for decades, who collaborates with rogue Klingons, and who is willing to destroy an entire populated planet in the service of his obsession? Sure. A sequence in which the USS Enterprise-D suffers a warp-core breach, forcing the crew to evacuate to the saucer section, which then crashes into the forests of the planet below? Why not  that sounds exciting. Nothing like blowing up the Enterprise to create a spectacle. As mentioned before, however, it all unfolds at an excessively leisurely pace that challenges the attention span of all but the most dedicated of viewers, and neither Enterprise crew (the 'B' crew at the beginning, featuring the old guys, or the 'D' Next Generation crew) really gets much out of it in terms of character development. I do however have to note Jacqueline Kim's brief but excellent performance as Ensign Demora Sulu, i.e. Hikaru Sulu's grown-up daughter. She looks like a terrific captain in the making as she holds the helm in the opening sequence, and frankly I would rather watch a film about her than what the rest of Generations turns out to be. Two specific things dog all of the Next Generation-era films, and they both rear their heads here. The first and arguably the most annoying is the overestimation of Data's fascination quotient. Every single one of the four Next Generation films feels compelled to put significant focus on his character, and with the exception of First Contact, it all feels gratuitous to me. Yes, his search for humanity is interesting. But not this interesting, and his adventures in humor here are more obnoxious than charming (or actually funny). Instead of fixating on Data, I wish that a more involved role would have been written for Dr. Crusher, who I feel to have been neglected more than any other major crew member. The other issue is the hard truth that the Next Generation's tone and aesthetic sensibilities, while well-suited for television, are simply not big-screen cinematic, particularly in comparison to the Original Series elements with which they share screen time in Generations. The uniforms especially could have benefited from a more sophisticated re-design. The common criticism that Next Generation films are more like glorified television episodes is not entirely unwarranted, although to be fair, Generations does have some very nice sequences. Is this the worst Star Trek film? Goodness, no. It might not even be the worst Next Generation-era film, when you consider the respective issues present in Insurrection and Nemesis. If being boring is a crime, then both Insurrection and The Motion Picture have no doubt shared a cell with Generations. Ultimately, this is a decent film, but probably only of much interest to Star Trek enthusiasts, and even then more as a curiosity than anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely poor dialogue, NOT redeemed in any way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To illustrate the horrible-ness of the film to the best, Star Trek: Generations is to the original crew films as to what Star Wars: The Phantom Menace is to the original Star Wars trilogy. Horrible! Whilst perhaps not as horrible as The Phantom Menace and the two horrid sequels that followed, Star Trek Generations gets plenty wrong for what is yet another perfect illustration of a horrible Star Trek film and perfectly justifies the statement that all Star Trek films with an odd number are poor, with the exception of The Search for Spock. Following the presumed death of Captain James T. Kirk, over 70 years later, The Enterprise has fallen into the hands of Captain Picard who deals with family strains whilst a new threat is under way. A surviver of an accident, that isn't carefully explained nor dealt with, has begun his attack on a star that when destroyed, will somehow give way to be able to visit the Nexus, which is a dream like world that presents the best and the happiest moments to anyone and everyone. The film suffers on almost every single aspect. The story is poor, but it goes even beyond this. It's not just a poor story and poor writing, but the story leaves no impact on us, as we have no idea who these new characters are. Much like how the original crew were first presented in Star Trek: The Motion Picture, the characters here are presented extremely ridiculously and annoyingly, the greatest of them being Data, who could have come off as an interesting android for the remainder of this franchise but is literally depicted as Jar Jar Binks. Now, it is clearly evident where George Lucas got his influence from. See, Spock was a fatherly figure and a wise man and was an interesting and likable character. Data is supposed to be a similar character but here is presented in the most horrid manner much like how we were apparently supposed to view Jar Jar as a Yoda type character. Such event is referred to as deliberately taking a sh*t on one's head! Data is annoying and is horrible jokes about an emotion chip and how he is suddenly able to understand jokes that were told years ago is not funny, its downright ridiculous. And not in a good way like in Monty Python and the Holy Grail. This character should've been presented far better and horrible writing is clearly evident here. Not only is Data poorly written, so is Picard who throughout the film deals with such family issues, having recently received the news that his family has died. Two things make this completely a forgettable and unnecessary sub plot to the film: This is the first time we even know who Picard is. There is obviously no reference in the original series due to the fact that this takes place over 70 years later. And secondly, the story about his family is hardly elaborated in anyway whatsoever and is instead, thrown in from the air and just left in a steady place. More poor writing is evident here. Each character is poorly written, to the fullest. The villain in the film, played by Malcolm McDowell, is yet again, another one of the many examples of poor writing in the film. His plan and his plot in the film is quickly summed up and almost never really referred to. Had he been written well, Soran could be a similar villain to Khan from the great 'Wrath of Khan'. Apparently in the film, Soran deals with personal issues of his own. MaybeThis character is hardly explained, due to horrible writing and has quite a silly and ridiculous plot. Whereas Star Trek 5 was ridiculous, it was not to this extent. The villain had a purpose that seemed more legit than here. Special effects are the same as all Star Trek films. Not great but decent enough for a pass. The acting is good, I would possibly say. Patrick Stewart as Picard is a great choice as is Malcolm McDowell as Soran but both are utterly wasted in this film. Returning is William Shatner, early on in the film as Captain James T. Kirk, in the best proportion of the film and returning late in the film in an extremely ridiculous concept. The best part of the film is the opening proportion as it cleverly resembles a good Star Trek film dealing with Kirk's desperation to get back into the captain's chair. Everything after this, is downhill ***SPOILERS*** The film suffers a lot in every way possible but here is when it is clearly evident that this is a truly horrible film. Our main character, James T Kirk, who has been loved by all is killed at the very end of the film in the most ridiculous and one of the most anticlimactic deaths to one of the great heroes. He dies and this scene shares no emotion like good Trek films do. When your main character, that you've loved so long, is killed and you laugh, that there is the perfect example of poor writing. ***END OF SPOILERS*** Star Trek: Generations, is in my opinion, the second worst film of the franchise, winning the silver medal with a gold going to the first Star Trek film. This film pretty much ensures that all odd numbered Star Trek films are terrible, with one small exception. Badly written, with a lame story and undeveloped characters, due to poor writing, Star Trek Generations is an utter failure. To imagine this movie, it is the Phantom Menace of Star Trek. To illustrate, prior to the making of the film, the director realized it was the 7th instalment and that it had to be horrible, and so asked for some horrible writing and extremely poor character development This film is a complete failure in every aspect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cast is Strong But The Plot Wears Thin,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek: Generations is a good movie with a storyline that dosen't really go anywhere for a very long time but a very inspired cast like there always is in Star Trek.It definitely wasn't a fantastic start for the Next Generation crew,it being their first movie,but I don't think its as bad as most people make it out to be,I don't think its the worst Star Trek but its certainly not the best,these movies are sometimes outstanding (The Wrath of Khan) and other times awful (The Final Frontier),I would put this right in the middle.The plot was sometimes very frustrating because it just didn't know were it was going for such a long time,but the impressive cast made it bearable,I really enjoyed Malcolm McDowell as the villain,he always delivers very creepy performances and he fit perfectly into the Star Trek universe.I didn't really appreciate William Shatner's performance,it all felt very forced and I think this movie would have been better off just focusing on the Next Generation crew instead of bringing in members from the original series.Fans of Star Trek:The Next Generation will definitely be disappointed,but will still appreciate the casts strong performances. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) disappears on a mission,seven decades later,Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) encounters similar peril and only the two captains can save the Enterprise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some fun to be had but not as momentous as it needs to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The seventh film in the series passes the torch to the crew of 'The Next Generation' with mixed results. A strong story was required to celebrate the meeting of Captains Kirk and Picard, but the plot is frustratingly underdeveloped and trundles towards a fizzling finale. It's a shame, too, that Leonard Nimoy and DeForest Kelley declined to appear. But there is excitement and humour along the way, plenty of thoughtful dialogue, an excellent performance from Patrick Stewart, and William Shatner seems to be having fun in his farewell performance, practically winking at the camera at times. The 'Trek' films are so middling that this isn't really any worse than the previous six (it's better than some); all the same, it carries with it the feeling that such a key chapter in 'Trek' history should have had more meat on its bones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and Confusing but with a couple of redeeming qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjkelley333
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I shouldn't be reviewing this film. I haven't seen Star Trek: The Next Generation. A lot of what I say here may be said out of ignorance. Well, who cares, I'll review it anyway. The film starts out with the christening of another starship U. S. S. Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk is on board for the ride. The ship comes across an energy phenomenon, which damages their ship. Kirk goes down to the core (or whatever you call that part of a starship) and fixes their problem. However, the room he is in is taken away by the energy, and he is declared dead. 78 years later, the current crew of the Enterprise, headed by Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) is summoned by Star Fleet to check out a damaged space station. There they discover Soran (Malcolm McDowell, A Clockwork Orange), an engineer whose home planet had been destroyed by the energy field at the beginning of the film. Soran attacks some crew members, and then travels to a planet where that energy field is headed. Captain Picard then learns that the energy field is called the Nexus, a space matrix that brings to life your heart's desire. However, it destroys everything in its path, and Soran is willing to commit murder to get back in the Nexus. There are two things I really like about this movie. One is the Nexus. It really is an interesting idea. A phenomenon that brings your dream to life is a fascinating idea, and actually quite thought- provoking. The other part I enjoy is Malcolm McDowell's performance. McDowell feels evil, psychotic, and brilliant. But hey, it's not like he hasn't played a psychopath before. However, there are many things I don't enjoy. There are pointless subplots that for the most part go nowhere. The most prominent subplot involves Data (Brent Spiner), a robot who resembles a human. He has a chip installed in himself that causes human emotion. His emotions are discussed throughout the film, but it doesn't go anywhere and is distracting. This brings up another question- how did they put feelings on an electronic chip? Another subplot centers around Picard. Some family members of his have recently died in a fire. He is shown mourning them. Later, he is in the Nexus, and he sees them alive again. This subplot never goes anywhere. The trailer and the posters for this film give the impressions that Kirk plays a large role in this film. However, he disappears in the beginning and doesn't reappear until the final half hour. Picard finds him in the Nexus, at his old home. At first Kirk says that he won't return to Star Fleet, but for some reason suddenly changes his mind. Yet another flaw of this film is Soran's plan. He is willing to commit murder and destroy planets to get to the Nexus. But he knows where it's headed. Why couldn't he just fly to it? But my biggest problem is this- it's SO BORING. That's all I can say- it's so dull. I really didn't care what was going on. And this is coming from someone who liked Star Trek: The Motion Picture. This film had a good villain and some fascinating ideas, but the slowness and subplots really brought it down. C
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed bag of goods for Star Trek fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sedativchunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen "Star Trek Generations" (STG) hundreds of times being a huge Star Trek fan. Recently I've watched it again from beginning to end in HD. Having watched watched pretty much every episode of all the Star Trek TV shows and all of the movies (including the newest "Into Darkness"), I felt the need to write a new, updated review for my take on this film. For many years, I hated this film as most other Star Trek fans have over the years. There many bad things about this movie. From the storyline to minor things like random changing between the standard TNG uniforms, this movie had a "wild" things going on. However, with all the shortcomings of this movie, after recently re-watching this film I've had a change of heart about my attitude towards this film. The good sides of this movie: STG is still a good, quality Star Trek film. The camera work, set design, costumes, and the works were all done with superb quality. After having watched most of TNG over recently, I've come to appreciate the nice budget this film got. The CGI, for the most part, is great. The shots of the Enterprise D were fantastic and a huge step up from the TV show models, from the flying through space to the destruction of the ship. In HD, this movie really pops for being almost 20 years old already. Although some find Data's behavior over the top in this film, I found it hilarious and if you are truly a TNG fan you will enjoy Brent Spiner's performance. We even get to see Spot, Data's cat again! Lastly, although I'm not a fan of the story, the villain is great and the concept behind "the nexus" is intriguing. Now for the bad sides of this film: the rest of the storyline! Simply put, STG has too much going on at once. They tried to cram too many things into this movie, making it a loyal TNG film while honoring Captain Kirk's history. The main thing that hurts this film and made many fans including myself dislike it, was the death of Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk's character was forced into this film. I found it completely unnecessary to ever make Picard and Kirk ever meet face-to-face in the first place. And the way William Shatner's Captain Kirk was killed off; I have and always will find it insulting and just plain bad for such a legendary TV icon. Although the story was interesting, in the end, TNG could have had a great start on the big screen without the "passing of the torch" from Kirk to Picard. The way "The Undiscovered Country" left off was perfect. Kirk has his last voyage in Enterprise and that was it. Instead they forcibly brought him back in this film as an excuse to involve him with TNG's storyline. In conclusion "Star Trek Generations" is a decent Star Trek film. If you can get past the mixed timelines/story and enjoy the good sides of this film, it is still an enjoyable movie with some hidden surprises. With that being said, though, this movie at heart is a TNG film. If you're not a TNG fan, you're going to hate this film. I also don't thing this is a good Star Trek film for the general audience. Unless you're a Star Trek fan, you probably won't "get" this movie. Of the TNG franchise, I still thing the best of the bunch is "First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Davyd Teather
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star trek generations is one of the most underrated star trek films if not one of the most underrated films in general. The mix of the original star trek characters with the next generation cast was amazing. This film starts off with three of the original star trek characters, James t. Kirk, Scotty and Chekov boarding the enterprise b. Just after the ship leaves spacedock, they get a distress call from a couple of spacecrafts caught on an energy ribbon and the enterprise b is the only ship in range. However it is not ready with a medical crew, tractor beam or weapons. They they close to the energy ribbon or the nexus as it is also called and rescue as many people from the spacecraft that they can and then use the deflector to break free from the energy ribbon. After they break free scotty tries to contact kirk but gets no response. He, and to other crew members go to the deck the deck to find him but find a chunk of the ship is missing and they believe he is dead. Then it fast forwards 78 years into the future showing the next generation cast. They are up against a mad man who is obsessed about getting back to the nexus, a place where time has no meaning, by destroying stars in order to change its course so he can get back into it. It is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Should Have Ended It After The Last One
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek Generations *1/2 (out of 4) 113 mins/ PG Cast: Patrick Stewart, Jonathan Frakes, Brent Spiner, LeVar Burton, Michael Dorn, Gates McFadden, Marina Sirtis, William Shatner, James Doohan, Whoopi Goldberg, Walter Koenig, Malcolm McDowell, Alan Ruck Director: David Carson Plot: Captain Picard must team up with Captain Kirk to stop a crazy scientist from destroying a whole planetary system in order to enter a world of happiness. JJ's Verdict: Many believe that Star Trek V: The Final Frontier is the worst of the series. I however, believe that Star Trek Generations is the worst of the series. After the success of Star Trek VI, Paramount must have been wondering what to do with what has at that point, become a great franchise. Of course, bring in a new cast and start again with Star Trek. Now this would have been fine, had they decided that some people (actually quite a lot of people) had never seen The Next Generation TV series and so needed a nice and easy to understand introduction to the characters. However, they didn't bother to introduce us to any of the characters or their backgrounds, or their relationships with other characters, or even their names until about half way through (and still you're struggling to remember who is who). Further on in the film, they want you to feel emotional towards these characters, but you can't because, as the viewer, you have no connection with them. This new crew and ship, set in the 24th century, while not a bad bunch of characters, do not capture the magic of the original crew and considering they had been on a TV show for 7 years, their chemistry is extremely poor and lacklustre. Now to the actual plot.... Kirk is guest of honour on the maiden voyage of the Enterprise B. But when a mysterious energy ribbon forces the Enterprise to save the ship's passengers, it comes at a cost: the death of Captain Kirk. Meanwhile, eighty years into the future, Captain Picard of the Enterprise D is up against evil scientist Soran, who is destroying planets so that he can reach Nexus, a mind matrix of happiness. Needing help, Picard somehow finds Kirk in the Nexus and the two team up to defeat Soran. Although the film is marketed as a battle involving captains from past and future, Shatner's role in the film is nothing more than a glorified cameo and you end up wondering whether Picard actually needs Kirk. Their scenes, although fun and full of references that Trekkies will love, are extremely silly and unnecessarily boring and slow. Throughout the film, threatening situations appear out of nowhere and while the action pieces are well set-up they are confusingly executed. Many other things are confusing and unexplained like how Picard gets out of the Nexus and it never tells the viewer how much time travel actually happens in this film. The only positives in this horrendous film are the short appearances of James Doohan and Walter Koenig as their original crew characters and the performances of British actors Patrick Stewart and Malcolm McDowell as Picard and Soran. Stewart has such a commanding presence on screen and the way he deals with emotional stress with his ageing self is superior to Shatner's in past instalments. Malcolm McDowell, most famous for playing a psychopath in Stanley Kubrick's ultra violent A Clockwork Orange, is both freaky and frightening in a very good performance. With three screen icons in its cast, it seems ridiculous that Star Trek Generations could be anything but good. Of course, it doesn't work that way in the film industry and even actors as good as Shatner, Stewart and McDowell can't stop this series 7th instalment from being a downright failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ultimate Star Trek movie. Kirk and Piccard are the best st duo ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokuguys
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie mainly because Its Kirk and Picard the two best st captains who ever lived. therefore it is the best st movie of all time. I was surprised of how high the quality of this movie was. i'm sure allot of people think of it as two old geezers fooling around in a crappy license movie but this was quite the contrary. i almost lost track of time, i was so absorbed in how amazing the movie was. It just wasn't the fact that the two of them were together at last. The acting of Bret spinner was incredible as well. For those of you who haven't seen it yet you are in for a treat(i don't want to oversell but you are going to love this film!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rough around the edges but it does the job, I suppose - 68%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the original TV crew dispatched, it was time to hand over the baton to the next phase in the franchise - the Next Generation. As this was the version of Star Trek I grew up watching, I was eagerly anticipating their first big screen outing and at the time, I wasn't disappointed. But as is often the way, watching it again today reminded me of several faults I'd overlooked before. A weak plot and villain, dialogue that would make George Lucas cringe and some pretty shoddy direction undermines a film with surprisingly good performances and effects that do justice to Gene Roddenbury's original vision. On the maiden voyage of the new Enterprise B, the inexperienced crew are forced to rescue two ships breaking up in some weird space ribbon. One of those rescued is a man named Soran (Malcolm McDowell) who is desperate to return to his exploding vessel. However, the Enterprise herself is badly damaged and the guest of honour, the retired Captain Kirk (William Shatner), is sadly sucked out into space. Seventy-eight years later and the current Enterprise, helmed by Jean-Luc Picard (Patrick Stewart) and the rest of the Next Gen gang, encounters the same ribbon as they rescue Soran again from a Federation space station. But this is no ordinary energy ribbon (like, are there many others and what are they like then?) - the Nexus is a portal to another realm where time stands still and every whim is made real. In his desperation to return to the Nexus, Soran is prepared to commit murder on a galactic scale and Picard finds himself in need of another Starfleet captain in order to stop him... "Star Trek: Generations" has no lack of ambition in terms of story but execution is found wanting. Take the climatic battle between Picard and Soran on a rickety metal bridge that appear to be held in place with a couple of badly rusted nails - imagine a huge crystal chandelier held up by a safety pin and you get the idea. I know this is Trek and thus, eminently theatrical (much like Star Wars, of course) but Trek was always more about the characters spouting pseudo-scientific garbage than firing phasers and fisticuffs. To that end, we have Data (Brent Spiner) and his Emotion Chip overloading his positronic network or something which provides director David Carson with a handy sub-plot. But he gets it wrong - an android suddenly developing emotions could have provided us with moments of humour or "Blade Runner"-style philosophy but instead, we get Data going haywire for a bit and from that point on, he is reduced to comic sidekick. Not good. It's not a complete bust - the film looks OK although there isn't much to touch the zero gravity sequence from its predecessor "Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country" and the leads all perform well. Stewart and McDowell are actually a pretty good contrast - Picard's usually unflappable manner verses Soran's wide-eyed fanatic. The same cannot be said for the rest of the cast - perhaps with so much going on, they forgot to include any scenes of substance with Worf (Michael Dorn) or Doctor Crusher (Gates McFadden). Hell, even Guinan (Whoopi Goldberg) has more to do than those two. As a film, it's uneven - it's certainly entertaining in a not-really-sci-fi kinda way but fans expecting anything as dramatic as "Star Trek II: The Wrath Of Khan" would be advised to seek their thrills elsewhere. But then, there's that unwritten rule that odd-numbered Star Trek films are no match for even-numbered films and technically, this is Star Trek VII - for me, if you're wanting a better Next Gen film then you should check out "Star Trek: First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Commendably Thoughtful / Viciously Boring / Superfluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to agree with those who are of the opinion that the Original Series Star Trek crew did not need to appear in this film. They had already had their send off, and a very fine one at that, in The Undiscovered Country. There was no need for their presence to be stretched out into Generations. That applies to Kirk more than to anyone else, of course. But here, he gets to take his final bow, of sorts. It could have been done better. At the same time, it could be argued that the Next Generation crew did not need to be in this film, either. It doesn't really do much to meaningfully develop them beyond what had already been done in their seven seasons on television. The subsequent film, First Contact, probably should have served as the lone Next Generation big screen-adventure. In any event, Generations is not a horrible film, but in practice it is a bit of a drag to watch, like one of those books that are hard to read without falling asleep. Some will argue that it is superfluous, and most would probably agree that it is exceedingly slow and frankly boring in spite of its decent screenplay and somewhat fresh plot. Speaking of which, the overall story (beyond the obvious 'Kirk meets Piccard, passes baton' gimmick) looks fairly cool on paper. A ribbon of energy writhing through space, which happens to be a portal to a hallucinogenic other-dimension called the Nexus, where time has no meaning? All right. Malcolm McDowell's Dr. Soren, a member of a long-lived species who has been trying to get back into the Nexus for decades, who collaborates with rogue Klingons, and who is willing to destroy an entire populated planet in the service of his obsession? Sure. A sequence in which the USS Enterprise-D suffers a warp-core breach, forcing the crew to evacuate to the saucer section, which then crashes into the forests of the planet below? Why not  that sounds exciting. Nothing like blowing up the Enterprise to create a spectacle. As mentioned before, however, it all unfolds at an excessively leisurely pace that challenges the attention span of all but the most dedicated of viewers, and neither Enterprise crew (the 'B' crew at the beginning, featuring the old guys, or the 'D' Next Generation crew) really gets much out of it in terms of character development. I do however have to note Jacqueline Kim's brief but excellent performance as Ensign Demora Sulu, i.e. Hikaru Sulu's grown-up daughter. She looks like a terrific captain in the making as she holds the helm in the opening sequence, and frankly I would rather watch a film about her than what the rest of Generations turns out to be. Two specific things dog all of the Next Generation-era films, and they both rear their heads here. The first and arguably the most annoying is the overestimation of Data's fascination quotient. Every single one of the four Next Generation films feels compelled to put significant focus on his character, and with the exception of First Contact, it all feels gratuitous to me. Yes, his search for humanity is interesting. But not this interesting, and his adventures in humor here are more obnoxious than charming (or actually funny). Instead of fixating on Data, I wish that a more involved role would have been written for Dr. Crusher, who I feel to have been neglected more than any other major crew member. The other issue is the hard truth that the Next Generation's tone and aesthetic sensibilities, while well-suited for television, are simply not big-screen cinematic, particularly in comparison to the Original Series elements with which they share screen time in Generations. The uniforms especially could have benefited from a more sophisticated re-design. The common criticism that Next Generation films are more like glorified television episodes is not entirely unwarranted, although to be fair, Generations does have some very nice sequences. Is this the worst Star Trek film? Goodness, no. It might not even be the worst Next Generation-era film, when you consider the respective issues present in Insurrection and Nemesis. If being boring is a crime, then both Insurrection and The Motion Picture have no doubt shared a cell with Generations. Ultimately, this is a decent film, but probably only of much interest to Star Trek enthusiasts, and even then more as a curiosity than anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely poor dialogue, NOT redeemed in any way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To illustrate the horrible-ness of the film to the best, Star Trek: Generations is to the original crew films as to what Star Wars: The Phantom Menace is to the original Star Wars trilogy. Horrible! Whilst perhaps not as horrible as The Phantom Menace and the two horrid sequels that followed, Star Trek Generations gets plenty wrong for what is yet another perfect illustration of a horrible Star Trek film and perfectly justifies the statement that all Star Trek films with an odd number are poor, with the exception of The Search for Spock. Following the presumed death of Captain James T. Kirk, over 70 years later, The Enterprise has fallen into the hands of Captain Picard who deals with family strains whilst a new threat is under way. A surviver of an accident, that isn't carefully explained nor dealt with, has begun his attack on a star that when destroyed, will somehow give way to be able to visit the Nexus, which is a dream like world that presents the best and the happiest moments to anyone and everyone. The film suffers on almost every single aspect. The story is poor, but it goes even beyond this. It's not just a poor story and poor writing, but the story leaves no impact on us, as we have no idea who these new characters are. Much like how the original crew were first presented in Star Trek: The Motion Picture, the characters here are presented extremely ridiculously and annoyingly, the greatest of them being Data, who could have come off as an interesting android for the remainder of this franchise but is literally depicted as Jar Jar Binks. Now, it is clearly evident where George Lucas got his influence from. See, Spock was a fatherly figure and a wise man and was an interesting and likable character. Data is supposed to be a similar character but here is presented in the most horrid manner much like how we were apparently supposed to view Jar Jar as a Yoda type character. Such event is referred to as deliberately taking a sh*t on one's head! Data is annoying and is horrible jokes about an emotion chip and how he is suddenly able to understand jokes that were told years ago is not funny, its downright ridiculous. And not in a good way like in Monty Python and the Holy Grail. This character should've been presented far better and horrible writing is clearly evident here. Not only is Data poorly written, so is Picard who throughout the film deals with such family issues, having recently received the news that his family has died. Two things make this completely a forgettable and unnecessary sub plot to the film: This is the first time we even know who Picard is. There is obviously no reference in the original series due to the fact that this takes place over 70 years later. And secondly, the story about his family is hardly elaborated in anyway whatsoever and is instead, thrown in from the air and just left in a steady place. More poor writing is evident here. Each character is poorly written, to the fullest. The villain in the film, played by Malcolm McDowell, is yet again, another one of the many examples of poor writing in the film. His plan and his plot in the film is quickly summed up and almost never really referred to. Had he been written well, Soran could be a similar villain to Khan from the great 'Wrath of Khan'. Apparently in the film, Soran deals with personal issues of his own. MaybeThis character is hardly explained, due to horrible writing and has quite a silly and ridiculous plot. Whereas Star Trek 5 was ridiculous, it was not to this extent. The villain had a purpose that seemed more legit than here. Special effects are the same as all Star Trek films. Not great but decent enough for a pass. The acting is good, I would possibly say. Patrick Stewart as Picard is a great choice as is Malcolm McDowell as Soran but both are utterly wasted in this film. Returning is William Shatner, early on in the film as Captain James T. Kirk, in the best proportion of the film and returning late in the film in an extremely ridiculous concept. The best part of the film is the opening proportion as it cleverly resembles a good Star Trek film dealing with Kirk's desperation to get back into the captain's chair. Everything after this, is downhill ***SPOILERS*** The film suffers a lot in every way possible but here is when it is clearly evident that this is a truly horrible film. Our main character, James T Kirk, who has been loved by all is killed at the very end of the film in the most ridiculous and one of the most anticlimactic deaths to one of the great heroes. He dies and this scene shares no emotion like good Trek films do. When your main character, that you've loved so long, is killed and you laugh, that there is the perfect example of poor writing. ***END OF SPOILERS*** Star Trek: Generations, is in my opinion, the second worst film of the franchise, winning the silver medal with a gold going to the first Star Trek film. This film pretty much ensures that all odd numbered Star Trek films are terrible, with one small exception. Badly written, with a lame story and undeveloped characters, due to poor writing, Star Trek Generations is an utter failure. To imagine this movie, it is the Phantom Menace of Star Trek. To illustrate, prior to the making of the film, the director realized it was the 7th instalment and that it had to be horrible, and so asked for some horrible writing and extremely poor character development This film is a complete failure in every aspect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cast is Strong But The Plot Wears Thin,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek: Generations is a good movie with a storyline that dosen't really go anywhere for a very long time but a very inspired cast like there always is in Star Trek.It definitely wasn't a fantastic start for the Next Generation crew,it being their first movie,but I don't think its as bad as most people make it out to be,I don't think its the worst Star Trek but its certainly not the best,these movies are sometimes outstanding (The Wrath of Khan) and other times awful (The Final Frontier),I would put this right in the middle.The plot was sometimes very frustrating because it just didn't know were it was going for such a long time,but the impressive cast made it bearable,I really enjoyed Malcolm McDowell as the villain,he always delivers very creepy performances and he fit perfectly into the Star Trek universe.I didn't really appreciate William Shatner's performance,it all felt very forced and I think this movie would have been better off just focusing on the Next Generation crew instead of bringing in members from the original series.Fans of Star Trek:The Next Generation will definitely be disappointed,but will still appreciate the casts strong performances. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) disappears on a mission,seven decades later,Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) encounters similar peril and only the two captains can save the Enterprise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some fun to be had but not as momentous as it needs to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The seventh film in the series passes the torch to the crew of 'The Next Generation' with mixed results. A strong story was required to celebrate the meeting of Captains Kirk and Picard, but the plot is frustratingly underdeveloped and trundles towards a fizzling finale. It's a shame, too, that Leonard Nimoy and DeForest Kelley declined to appear. But there is excitement and humour along the way, plenty of thoughtful dialogue, an excellent performance from Patrick Stewart, and William Shatner seems to be having fun in his farewell performance, practically winking at the camera at times. The 'Trek' films are so middling that this isn't really any worse than the previous six (it's better than some); all the same, it carries with it the feeling that such a key chapter in 'Trek' history should have had more meat on its bones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and Confusing but with a couple of redeeming qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjkelley333
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I shouldn't be reviewing this film. I haven't seen Star Trek: The Next Generation. A lot of what I say here may be said out of ignorance. Well, who cares, I'll review it anyway. The film starts out with the christening of another starship U. S. S. Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk is on board for the ride. The ship comes across an energy phenomenon, which damages their ship. Kirk goes down to the core (or whatever you call that part of a starship) and fixes their problem. However, the room he is in is taken away by the energy, and he is declared dead. 78 years later, the current crew of the Enterprise, headed by Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) is summoned by Star Fleet to check out a damaged space station. There they discover Soran (Malcolm McDowell, A Clockwork Orange), an engineer whose home planet had been destroyed by the energy field at the beginning of the film. Soran attacks some crew members, and then travels to a planet where that energy field is headed. Captain Picard then learns that the energy field is called the Nexus, a space matrix that brings to life your heart's desire. However, it destroys everything in its path, and Soran is willing to commit murder to get back in the Nexus. There are two things I really like about this movie. One is the Nexus. It really is an interesting idea. A phenomenon that brings your dream to life is a fascinating idea, and actually quite thought- provoking. The other part I enjoy is Malcolm McDowell's performance. McDowell feels evil, psychotic, and brilliant. But hey, it's not like he hasn't played a psychopath before. However, there are many things I don't enjoy. There are pointless subplots that for the most part go nowhere. The most prominent subplot involves Data (Brent Spiner), a robot who resembles a human. He has a chip installed in himself that causes human emotion. His emotions are discussed throughout the film, but it doesn't go anywhere and is distracting. This brings up another question- how did they put feelings on an electronic chip? Another subplot centers around Picard. Some family members of his have recently died in a fire. He is shown mourning them. Later, he is in the Nexus, and he sees them alive again. This subplot never goes anywhere. The trailer and the posters for this film give the impressions that Kirk plays a large role in this film. However, he disappears in the beginning and doesn't reappear until the final half hour. Picard finds him in the Nexus, at his old home. At first Kirk says that he won't return to Star Fleet, but for some reason suddenly changes his mind. Yet another flaw of this film is Soran's plan. He is willing to commit murder and destroy planets to get to the Nexus. But he knows where it's headed. Why couldn't he just fly to it? But my biggest problem is this- it's SO BORING. That's all I can say- it's so dull. I really didn't care what was going on. And this is coming from someone who liked Star Trek: The Motion Picture. This film had a good villain and some fascinating ideas, but the slowness and subplots really brought it down. C
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed bag of goods for Star Trek fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sedativchunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen "Star Trek Generations" (STG) hundreds of times being a huge Star Trek fan. Recently I've watched it again from beginning to end in HD. Having watched watched pretty much every episode of all the Star Trek TV shows and all of the movies (including the newest "Into Darkness"), I felt the need to write a new, updated review for my take on this film. For many years, I hated this film as most other Star Trek fans have over the years. There many bad things about this movie. From the storyline to minor things like random changing between the standard TNG uniforms, this movie had a "wild" things going on. However, with all the shortcomings of this movie, after recently re-watching this film I've had a change of heart about my attitude towards this film. The good sides of this movie: STG is still a good, quality Star Trek film. The camera work, set design, costumes, and the works were all done with superb quality. After having watched most of TNG over recently, I've come to appreciate the nice budget this film got. The CGI, for the most part, is great. The shots of the Enterprise D were fantastic and a huge step up from the TV show models, from the flying through space to the destruction of the ship. In HD, this movie really pops for being almost 20 years old already. Although some find Data's behavior over the top in this film, I found it hilarious and if you are truly a TNG fan you will enjoy Brent Spiner's performance. We even get to see Spot, Data's cat again! Lastly, although I'm not a fan of the story, the villain is great and the concept behind "the nexus" is intriguing. Now for the bad sides of this film: the rest of the storyline! Simply put, STG has too much going on at once. They tried to cram too many things into this movie, making it a loyal TNG film while honoring Captain Kirk's history. The main thing that hurts this film and made many fans including myself dislike it, was the death of Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk's character was forced into this film. I found it completely unnecessary to ever make Picard and Kirk ever meet face-to-face in the first place. And the way William Shatner's Captain Kirk was killed off; I have and always will find it insulting and just plain bad for such a legendary TV icon. Although the story was interesting, in the end, TNG could have had a great start on the big screen without the "passing of the torch" from Kirk to Picard. The way "The Undiscovered Country" left off was perfect. Kirk has his last voyage in Enterprise and that was it. Instead they forcibly brought him back in this film as an excuse to involve him with TNG's storyline. In conclusion "Star Trek Generations" is a decent Star Trek film. If you can get past the mixed timelines/story and enjoy the good sides of this film, it is still an enjoyable movie with some hidden surprises. With that being said, though, this movie at heart is a TNG film. If you're not a TNG fan, you're going to hate this film. I also don't thing this is a good Star Trek film for the general audience. Unless you're a Star Trek fan, you probably won't "get" this movie. Of the TNG franchise, I still thing the best of the bunch is "First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Davyd Teather
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star trek generations is one of the most underrated star trek films if not one of the most underrated films in general. The mix of the original star trek characters with the next generation cast was amazing. This film starts off with three of the original star trek characters, James t. Kirk, Scotty and Chekov boarding the enterprise b. Just after the ship leaves spacedock, they get a distress call from a couple of spacecrafts caught on an energy ribbon and the enterprise b is the only ship in range. However it is not ready with a medical crew, tractor beam or weapons. They they close to the energy ribbon or the nexus as it is also called and rescue as many people from the spacecraft that they can and then use the deflector to break free from the energy ribbon. After they break free scotty tries to contact kirk but gets no response. He, and to other crew members go to the deck the deck to find him but find a chunk of the ship is missing and they believe he is dead. Then it fast forwards 78 years into the future showing the next generation cast. They are up against a mad man who is obsessed about getting back to the nexus, a place where time has no meaning, by destroying stars in order to change its course so he can get back into it. It is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Should Have Ended It After The Last One
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek Generations *1/2 (out of 4) 113 mins/ PG Cast: Patrick Stewart, Jonathan Frakes, Brent Spiner, LeVar Burton, Michael Dorn, Gates McFadden, Marina Sirtis, William Shatner, James Doohan, Whoopi Goldberg, Walter Koenig, Malcolm McDowell, Alan Ruck Director: David Carson Plot: Captain Picard must team up with Captain Kirk to stop a crazy scientist from destroying a whole planetary system in order to enter a world of happiness. JJ's Verdict: Many believe that Star Trek V: The Final Frontier is the worst of the series. I however, believe that Star Trek Generations is the worst of the series. After the success of Star Trek VI, Paramount must have been wondering what to do with what has at that point, become a great franchise. Of course, bring in a new cast and start again with Star Trek. Now this would have been fine, had they decided that some people (actually quite a lot of people) had never seen The Next Generation TV series and so needed a nice and easy to understand introduction to the characters. However, they didn't bother to introduce us to any of the characters or their backgrounds, or their relationships with other characters, or even their names until about half way through (and still you're struggling to remember who is who). Further on in the film, they want you to feel emotional towards these characters, but you can't because, as the viewer, you have no connection with them. This new crew and ship, set in the 24th century, while not a bad bunch of characters, do not capture the magic of the original crew and considering they had been on a TV show for 7 years, their chemistry is extremely poor and lacklustre. Now to the actual plot.... Kirk is guest of honour on the maiden voyage of the Enterprise B. But when a mysterious energy ribbon forces the Enterprise to save the ship's passengers, it comes at a cost: the death of Captain Kirk. Meanwhile, eighty years into the future, Captain Picard of the Enterprise D is up against evil scientist Soran, who is destroying planets so that he can reach Nexus, a mind matrix of happiness. Needing help, Picard somehow finds Kirk in the Nexus and the two team up to defeat Soran. Although the film is marketed as a battle involving captains from past and future, Shatner's role in the film is nothing more than a glorified cameo and you end up wondering whether Picard actually needs Kirk. Their scenes, although fun and full of references that Trekkies will love, are extremely silly and unnecessarily boring and slow. Throughout the film, threatening situations appear out of nowhere and while the action pieces are well set-up they are confusingly executed. Many other things are confusing and unexplained like how Picard gets out of the Nexus and it never tells the viewer how much time travel actually happens in this film. The only positives in this horrendous film are the short appearances of James Doohan and Walter Koenig as their original crew characters and the performances of British actors Patrick Stewart and Malcolm McDowell as Picard and Soran. Stewart has such a commanding presence on screen and the way he deals with emotional stress with his ageing self is superior to Shatner's in past instalments. Malcolm McDowell, most famous for playing a psychopath in Stanley Kubrick's ultra violent A Clockwork Orange, is both freaky and frightening in a very good performance. With three screen icons in its cast, it seems ridiculous that Star Trek Generations could be anything but good. Of course, it doesn't work that way in the film industry and even actors as good as Shatner, Stewart and McDowell can't stop this series 7th instalment from being a downright failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ultimate Star Trek movie. Kirk and Piccard are the best st duo ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokuguys
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie mainly because Its Kirk and Picard the two best st captains who ever lived. therefore it is the best st movie of all time. I was surprised of how high the quality of this movie was. i'm sure allot of people think of it as two old geezers fooling around in a crappy license movie but this was quite the contrary. i almost lost track of time, i was so absorbed in how amazing the movie was. It just wasn't the fact that the two of them were together at last. The acting of Bret spinner was incredible as well. For those of you who haven't seen it yet you are in for a treat(i don't want to oversell but you are going to love this film!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rough around the edges but it does the job, I suppose - 68%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the original TV crew dispatched, it was time to hand over the baton to the next phase in the franchise - the Next Generation. As this was the version of Star Trek I grew up watching, I was eagerly anticipating their first big screen outing and at the time, I wasn't disappointed. But as is often the way, watching it again today reminded me of several faults I'd overlooked before. A weak plot and villain, dialogue that would make George Lucas cringe and some pretty shoddy direction undermines a film with surprisingly good performances and effects that do justice to Gene Roddenbury's original vision. On the maiden voyage of the new Enterprise B, the inexperienced crew are forced to rescue two ships breaking up in some weird space ribbon. One of those rescued is a man named Soran (Malcolm McDowell) who is desperate to return to his exploding vessel. However, the Enterprise herself is badly damaged and the guest of honour, the retired Captain Kirk (William Shatner), is sadly sucked out into space. Seventy-eight years later and the current Enterprise, helmed by Jean-Luc Picard (Patrick Stewart) and the rest of the Next Gen gang, encounters the same ribbon as they rescue Soran again from a Federation space station. But this is no ordinary energy ribbon (like, are there many others and what are they like then?) - the Nexus is a portal to another realm where time stands still and every whim is made real. In his desperation to return to the Nexus, Soran is prepared to commit murder on a galactic scale and Picard finds himself in need of another Starfleet captain in order to stop him... "Star Trek: Generations" has no lack of ambition in terms of story but execution is found wanting. Take the climatic battle between Picard and Soran on a rickety metal bridge that appear to be held in place with a couple of badly rusted nails - imagine a huge crystal chandelier held up by a safety pin and you get the idea. I know this is Trek and thus, eminently theatrical (much like Star Wars, of course) but Trek was always more about the characters spouting pseudo-scientific garbage than firing phasers and fisticuffs. To that end, we have Data (Brent Spiner) and his Emotion Chip overloading his positronic network or something which provides director David Carson with a handy sub-plot. But he gets it wrong - an android suddenly developing emotions could have provided us with moments of humour or "Blade Runner"-style philosophy but instead, we get Data going haywire for a bit and from that point on, he is reduced to comic sidekick. Not good. It's not a complete bust - the film looks OK although there isn't much to touch the zero gravity sequence from its predecessor "Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country" and the leads all perform well. Stewart and McDowell are actually a pretty good contrast - Picard's usually unflappable manner verses Soran's wide-eyed fanatic. The same cannot be said for the rest of the cast - perhaps with so much going on, they forgot to include any scenes of substance with Worf (Michael Dorn) or Doctor Crusher (Gates McFadden). Hell, even Guinan (Whoopi Goldberg) has more to do than those two. As a film, it's uneven - it's certainly entertaining in a not-really-sci-fi kinda way but fans expecting anything as dramatic as "Star Trek II: The Wrath Of Khan" would be advised to seek their thrills elsewhere. But then, there's that unwritten rule that odd-numbered Star Trek films are no match for even-numbered films and technically, this is Star Trek VII - for me, if you're wanting a better Next Gen film then you should check out "Star Trek: First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Commendably Thoughtful / Viciously Boring / Superfluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to agree with those who are of the opinion that the Original Series Star Trek crew did not need to appear in this film. They had already had their send off, and a very fine one at that, in The Undiscovered Country. There was no need for their presence to be stretched out into Generations. That applies to Kirk more than to anyone else, of course. But here, he gets to take his final bow, of sorts. It could have been done better. At the same time, it could be argued that the Next Generation crew did not need to be in this film, either. It doesn't really do much to meaningfully develop them beyond what had already been done in their seven seasons on television. The subsequent film, First Contact, probably should have served as the lone Next Generation big screen-adventure. In any event, Generations is not a horrible film, but in practice it is a bit of a drag to watch, like one of those books that are hard to read without falling asleep. Some will argue that it is superfluous, and most would probably agree that it is exceedingly slow and frankly boring in spite of its decent screenplay and somewhat fresh plot. Speaking of which, the overall story (beyond the obvious 'Kirk meets Piccard, passes baton' gimmick) looks fairly cool on paper. A ribbon of energy writhing through space, which happens to be a portal to a hallucinogenic other-dimension called the Nexus, where time has no meaning? All right. Malcolm McDowell's Dr. Soren, a member of a long-lived species who has been trying to get back into the Nexus for decades, who collaborates with rogue Klingons, and who is willing to destroy an entire populated planet in the service of his obsession? Sure. A sequence in which the USS Enterprise-D suffers a warp-core breach, forcing the crew to evacuate to the saucer section, which then crashes into the forests of the planet below? Why not  that sounds exciting. Nothing like blowing up the Enterprise to create a spectacle. As mentioned before, however, it all unfolds at an excessively leisurely pace that challenges the attention span of all but the most dedicated of viewers, and neither Enterprise crew (the 'B' crew at the beginning, featuring the old guys, or the 'D' Next Generation crew) really gets much out of it in terms of character development. I do however have to note Jacqueline Kim's brief but excellent performance as Ensign Demora Sulu, i.e. Hikaru Sulu's grown-up daughter. She looks like a terrific captain in the making as she holds the helm in the opening sequence, and frankly I would rather watch a film about her than what the rest of Generations turns out to be. Two specific things dog all of the Next Generation-era films, and they both rear their heads here. The first and arguably the most annoying is the overestimation of Data's fascination quotient. Every single one of the four Next Generation films feels compelled to put significant focus on his character, and with the exception of First Contact, it all feels gratuitous to me. Yes, his search for humanity is interesting. But not this interesting, and his adventures in humor here are more obnoxious than charming (or actually funny). Instead of fixating on Data, I wish that a more involved role would have been written for Dr. Crusher, who I feel to have been neglected more than any other major crew member. The other issue is the hard truth that the Next Generation's tone and aesthetic sensibilities, while well-suited for television, are simply not big-screen cinematic, particularly in comparison to the Original Series elements with which they share screen time in Generations. The uniforms especially could have benefited from a more sophisticated re-design. The common criticism that Next Generation films are more like glorified television episodes is not entirely unwarranted, although to be fair, Generations does have some very nice sequences. Is this the worst Star Trek film? Goodness, no. It might not even be the worst Next Generation-era film, when you consider the respective issues present in Insurrection and Nemesis. If being boring is a crime, then both Insurrection and The Motion Picture have no doubt shared a cell with Generations. Ultimately, this is a decent film, but probably only of much interest to Star Trek enthusiasts, and even then more as a curiosity than anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely poor dialogue, NOT redeemed in any way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To illustrate the horrible-ness of the film to the best, Star Trek: Generations is to the original crew films as to what Star Wars: The Phantom Menace is to the original Star Wars trilogy. Horrible! Whilst perhaps not as horrible as The Phantom Menace and the two horrid sequels that followed, Star Trek Generations gets plenty wrong for what is yet another perfect illustration of a horrible Star Trek film and perfectly justifies the statement that all Star Trek films with an odd number are poor, with the exception of The Search for Spock. Following the presumed death of Captain James T. Kirk, over 70 years later, The Enterprise has fallen into the hands of Captain Picard who deals with family strains whilst a new threat is under way. A surviver of an accident, that isn't carefully explained nor dealt with, has begun his attack on a star that when destroyed, will somehow give way to be able to visit the Nexus, which is a dream like world that presents the best and the happiest moments to anyone and everyone. The film suffers on almost every single aspect. The story is poor, but it goes even beyond this. It's not just a poor story and poor writing, but the story leaves no impact on us, as we have no idea who these new characters are. Much like how the original crew were first presented in Star Trek: The Motion Picture, the characters here are presented extremely ridiculously and annoyingly, the greatest of them being Data, who could have come off as an interesting android for the remainder of this franchise but is literally depicted as Jar Jar Binks. Now, it is clearly evident where George Lucas got his influence from. See, Spock was a fatherly figure and a wise man and was an interesting and likable character. Data is supposed to be a similar character but here is presented in the most horrid manner much like how we were apparently supposed to view Jar Jar as a Yoda type character. Such event is referred to as deliberately taking a sh*t on one's head! Data is annoying and is horrible jokes about an emotion chip and how he is suddenly able to understand jokes that were told years ago is not funny, its downright ridiculous. And not in a good way like in Monty Python and the Holy Grail. This character should've been presented far better and horrible writing is clearly evident here. Not only is Data poorly written, so is Picard who throughout the film deals with such family issues, having recently received the news that his family has died. Two things make this completely a forgettable and unnecessary sub plot to the film: This is the first time we even know who Picard is. There is obviously no reference in the original series due to the fact that this takes place over 70 years later. And secondly, the story about his family is hardly elaborated in anyway whatsoever and is instead, thrown in from the air and just left in a steady place. More poor writing is evident here. Each character is poorly written, to the fullest. The villain in the film, played by Malcolm McDowell, is yet again, another one of the many examples of poor writing in the film. His plan and his plot in the film is quickly summed up and almost never really referred to. Had he been written well, Soran could be a similar villain to Khan from the great 'Wrath of Khan'. Apparently in the film, Soran deals with personal issues of his own. MaybeThis character is hardly explained, due to horrible writing and has quite a silly and ridiculous plot. Whereas Star Trek 5 was ridiculous, it was not to this extent. The villain had a purpose that seemed more legit than here. Special effects are the same as all Star Trek films. Not great but decent enough for a pass. The acting is good, I would possibly say. Patrick Stewart as Picard is a great choice as is Malcolm McDowell as Soran but both are utterly wasted in this film. Returning is William Shatner, early on in the film as Captain James T. Kirk, in the best proportion of the film and returning late in the film in an extremely ridiculous concept. The best part of the film is the opening proportion as it cleverly resembles a good Star Trek film dealing with Kirk's desperation to get back into the captain's chair. Everything after this, is downhill ***SPOILERS*** The film suffers a lot in every way possible but here is when it is clearly evident that this is a truly horrible film. Our main character, James T Kirk, who has been loved by all is killed at the very end of the film in the most ridiculous and one of the most anticlimactic deaths to one of the great heroes. He dies and this scene shares no emotion like good Trek films do. When your main character, that you've loved so long, is killed and you laugh, that there is the perfect example of poor writing. ***END OF SPOILERS*** Star Trek: Generations, is in my opinion, the second worst film of the franchise, winning the silver medal with a gold going to the first Star Trek film. This film pretty much ensures that all odd numbered Star Trek films are terrible, with one small exception. Badly written, with a lame story and undeveloped characters, due to poor writing, Star Trek Generations is an utter failure. To imagine this movie, it is the Phantom Menace of Star Trek. To illustrate, prior to the making of the film, the director realized it was the 7th instalment and that it had to be horrible, and so asked for some horrible writing and extremely poor character development This film is a complete failure in every aspect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cast is Strong But The Plot Wears Thin,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek: Generations is a good movie with a storyline that dosen't really go anywhere for a very long time but a very inspired cast like there always is in Star Trek.It definitely wasn't a fantastic start for the Next Generation crew,it being their first movie,but I don't think its as bad as most people make it out to be,I don't think its the worst Star Trek but its certainly not the best,these movies are sometimes outstanding (The Wrath of Khan) and other times awful (The Final Frontier),I would put this right in the middle.The plot was sometimes very frustrating because it just didn't know were it was going for such a long time,but the impressive cast made it bearable,I really enjoyed Malcolm McDowell as the villain,he always delivers very creepy performances and he fit perfectly into the Star Trek universe.I didn't really appreciate William Shatner's performance,it all felt very forced and I think this movie would have been better off just focusing on the Next Generation crew instead of bringing in members from the original series.Fans of Star Trek:The Next Generation will definitely be disappointed,but will still appreciate the casts strong performances. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) disappears on a mission,seven decades later,Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) encounters similar peril and only the two captains can save the Enterprise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some fun to be had but not as momentous as it needs to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The seventh film in the series passes the torch to the crew of 'The Next Generation' with mixed results. A strong story was required to celebrate the meeting of Captains Kirk and Picard, but the plot is frustratingly underdeveloped and trundles towards a fizzling finale. It's a shame, too, that Leonard Nimoy and DeForest Kelley declined to appear. But there is excitement and humour along the way, plenty of thoughtful dialogue, an excellent performance from Patrick Stewart, and William Shatner seems to be having fun in his farewell performance, practically winking at the camera at times. The 'Trek' films are so middling that this isn't really any worse than the previous six (it's better than some); all the same, it carries with it the feeling that such a key chapter in 'Trek' history should have had more meat on its bones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and Confusing but with a couple of redeeming qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjkelley333
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I shouldn't be reviewing this film. I haven't seen Star Trek: The Next Generation. A lot of what I say here may be said out of ignorance. Well, who cares, I'll review it anyway. The film starts out with the christening of another starship U. S. S. Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk is on board for the ride. The ship comes across an energy phenomenon, which damages their ship. Kirk goes down to the core (or whatever you call that part of a starship) and fixes their problem. However, the room he is in is taken away by the energy, and he is declared dead. 78 years later, the current crew of the Enterprise, headed by Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) is summoned by Star Fleet to check out a damaged space station. There they discover Soran (Malcolm McDowell, A Clockwork Orange), an engineer whose home planet had been destroyed by the energy field at the beginning of the film. Soran attacks some crew members, and then travels to a planet where that energy field is headed. Captain Picard then learns that the energy field is called the Nexus, a space matrix that brings to life your heart's desire. However, it destroys everything in its path, and Soran is willing to commit murder to get back in the Nexus. There are two things I really like about this movie. One is the Nexus. It really is an interesting idea. A phenomenon that brings your dream to life is a fascinating idea, and actually quite thought- provoking. The other part I enjoy is Malcolm McDowell's performance. McDowell feels evil, psychotic, and brilliant. But hey, it's not like he hasn't played a psychopath before. However, there are many things I don't enjoy. There are pointless subplots that for the most part go nowhere. The most prominent subplot involves Data (Brent Spiner), a robot who resembles a human. He has a chip installed in himself that causes human emotion. His emotions are discussed throughout the film, but it doesn't go anywhere and is distracting. This brings up another question- how did they put feelings on an electronic chip? Another subplot centers around Picard. Some family members of his have recently died in a fire. He is shown mourning them. Later, he is in the Nexus, and he sees them alive again. This subplot never goes anywhere. The trailer and the posters for this film give the impressions that Kirk plays a large role in this film. However, he disappears in the beginning and doesn't reappear until the final half hour. Picard finds him in the Nexus, at his old home. At first Kirk says that he won't return to Star Fleet, but for some reason suddenly changes his mind. Yet another flaw of this film is Soran's plan. He is willing to commit murder and destroy planets to get to the Nexus. But he knows where it's headed. Why couldn't he just fly to it? But my biggest problem is this- it's SO BORING. That's all I can say- it's so dull. I really didn't care what was going on. And this is coming from someone who liked Star Trek: The Motion Picture. This film had a good villain and some fascinating ideas, but the slowness and subplots really brought it down. C
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed bag of goods for Star Trek fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sedativchunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen "Star Trek Generations" (STG) hundreds of times being a huge Star Trek fan. Recently I've watched it again from beginning to end in HD. Having watched watched pretty much every episode of all the Star Trek TV shows and all of the movies (including the newest "Into Darkness"), I felt the need to write a new, updated review for my take on this film. For many years, I hated this film as most other Star Trek fans have over the years. There many bad things about this movie. From the storyline to minor things like random changing between the standard TNG uniforms, this movie had a "wild" things going on. However, with all the shortcomings of this movie, after recently re-watching this film I've had a change of heart about my attitude towards this film. The good sides of this movie: STG is still a good, quality Star Trek film. The camera work, set design, costumes, and the works were all done with superb quality. After having watched most of TNG over recently, I've come to appreciate the nice budget this film got. The CGI, for the most part, is great. The shots of the Enterprise D were fantastic and a huge step up from the TV show models, from the flying through space to the destruction of the ship. In HD, this movie really pops for being almost 20 years old already. Although some find Data's behavior over the top in this film, I found it hilarious and if you are truly a TNG fan you will enjoy Brent Spiner's performance. We even get to see Spot, Data's cat again! Lastly, although I'm not a fan of the story, the villain is great and the concept behind "the nexus" is intriguing. Now for the bad sides of this film: the rest of the storyline! Simply put, STG has too much going on at once. They tried to cram too many things into this movie, making it a loyal TNG film while honoring Captain Kirk's history. The main thing that hurts this film and made many fans including myself dislike it, was the death of Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk's character was forced into this film. I found it completely unnecessary to ever make Picard and Kirk ever meet face-to-face in the first place. And the way William Shatner's Captain Kirk was killed off; I have and always will find it insulting and just plain bad for such a legendary TV icon. Although the story was interesting, in the end, TNG could have had a great start on the big screen without the "passing of the torch" from Kirk to Picard. The way "The Undiscovered Country" left off was perfect. Kirk has his last voyage in Enterprise and that was it. Instead they forcibly brought him back in this film as an excuse to involve him with TNG's storyline. In conclusion "Star Trek Generations" is a decent Star Trek film. If you can get past the mixed timelines/story and enjoy the good sides of this film, it is still an enjoyable movie with some hidden surprises. With that being said, though, this movie at heart is a TNG film. If you're not a TNG fan, you're going to hate this film. I also don't thing this is a good Star Trek film for the general audience. Unless you're a Star Trek fan, you probably won't "get" this movie. Of the TNG franchise, I still thing the best of the bunch is "First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Davyd Teather
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star trek generations is one of the most underrated star trek films if not one of the most underrated films in general. The mix of the original star trek characters with the next generation cast was amazing. This film starts off with three of the original star trek characters, James t. Kirk, Scotty and Chekov boarding the enterprise b. Just after the ship leaves spacedock, they get a distress call from a couple of spacecrafts caught on an energy ribbon and the enterprise b is the only ship in range. However it is not ready with a medical crew, tractor beam or weapons. They they close to the energy ribbon or the nexus as it is also called and rescue as many people from the spacecraft that they can and then use the deflector to break free from the energy ribbon. After they break free scotty tries to contact kirk but gets no response. He, and to other crew members go to the deck the deck to find him but find a chunk of the ship is missing and they believe he is dead. Then it fast forwards 78 years into the future showing the next generation cast. They are up against a mad man who is obsessed about getting back to the nexus, a place where time has no meaning, by destroying stars in order to change its course so he can get back into it. It is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Should Have Ended It After The Last One
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek Generations *1/2 (out of 4) 113 mins/ PG Cast: Patrick Stewart, Jonathan Frakes, Brent Spiner, LeVar Burton, Michael Dorn, Gates McFadden, Marina Sirtis, William Shatner, James Doohan, Whoopi Goldberg, Walter Koenig, Malcolm McDowell, Alan Ruck Director: David Carson Plot: Captain Picard must team up with Captain Kirk to stop a crazy scientist from destroying a whole planetary system in order to enter a world of happiness. JJ's Verdict: Many believe that Star Trek V: The Final Frontier is the worst of the series. I however, believe that Star Trek Generations is the worst of the series. After the success of Star Trek VI, Paramount must have been wondering what to do with what has at that point, become a great franchise. Of course, bring in a new cast and start again with Star Trek. Now this would have been fine, had they decided that some people (actually quite a lot of people) had never seen The Next Generation TV series and so needed a nice and easy to understand introduction to the characters. However, they didn't bother to introduce us to any of the characters or their backgrounds, or their relationships with other characters, or even their names until about half way through (and still you're struggling to remember who is who). Further on in the film, they want you to feel emotional towards these characters, but you can't because, as the viewer, you have no connection with them. This new crew and ship, set in the 24th century, while not a bad bunch of characters, do not capture the magic of the original crew and considering they had been on a TV show for 7 years, their chemistry is extremely poor and lacklustre. Now to the actual plot.... Kirk is guest of honour on the maiden voyage of the Enterprise B. But when a mysterious energy ribbon forces the Enterprise to save the ship's passengers, it comes at a cost: the death of Captain Kirk. Meanwhile, eighty years into the future, Captain Picard of the Enterprise D is up against evil scientist Soran, who is destroying planets so that he can reach Nexus, a mind matrix of happiness. Needing help, Picard somehow finds Kirk in the Nexus and the two team up to defeat Soran. Although the film is marketed as a battle involving captains from past and future, Shatner's role in the film is nothing more than a glorified cameo and you end up wondering whether Picard actually needs Kirk. Their scenes, although fun and full of references that Trekkies will love, are extremely silly and unnecessarily boring and slow. Throughout the film, threatening situations appear out of nowhere and while the action pieces are well set-up they are confusingly executed. Many other things are confusing and unexplained like how Picard gets out of the Nexus and it never tells the viewer how much time travel actually happens in this film. The only positives in this horrendous film are the short appearances of James Doohan and Walter Koenig as their original crew characters and the performances of British actors Patrick Stewart and Malcolm McDowell as Picard and Soran. Stewart has such a commanding presence on screen and the way he deals with emotional stress with his ageing self is superior to Shatner's in past instalments. Malcolm McDowell, most famous for playing a psychopath in Stanley Kubrick's ultra violent A Clockwork Orange, is both freaky and frightening in a very good performance. With three screen icons in its cast, it seems ridiculous that Star Trek Generations could be anything but good. Of course, it doesn't work that way in the film industry and even actors as good as Shatner, Stewart and McDowell can't stop this series 7th instalment from being a downright failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ultimate Star Trek movie. Kirk and Piccard are the best st duo ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokuguys
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie mainly because Its Kirk and Picard the two best st captains who ever lived. therefore it is the best st movie of all time. I was surprised of how high the quality of this movie was. i'm sure allot of people think of it as two old geezers fooling around in a crappy license movie but this was quite the contrary. i almost lost track of time, i was so absorbed in how amazing the movie was. It just wasn't the fact that the two of them were together at last. The acting of Bret spinner was incredible as well. For those of you who haven't seen it yet you are in for a treat(i don't want to oversell but you are going to love this film!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rough around the edges but it does the job, I suppose - 68%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the original TV crew dispatched, it was time to hand over the baton to the next phase in the franchise - the Next Generation. As this was the version of Star Trek I grew up watching, I was eagerly anticipating their first big screen outing and at the time, I wasn't disappointed. But as is often the way, watching it again today reminded me of several faults I'd overlooked before. A weak plot and villain, dialogue that would make George Lucas cringe and some pretty shoddy direction undermines a film with surprisingly good performances and effects that do justice to Gene Roddenbury's original vision. On the maiden voyage of the new Enterprise B, the inexperienced crew are forced to rescue two ships breaking up in some weird space ribbon. One of those rescued is a man named Soran (Malcolm McDowell) who is desperate to return to his exploding vessel. However, the Enterprise herself is badly damaged and the guest of honour, the retired Captain Kirk (William Shatner), is sadly sucked out into space. Seventy-eight years later and the current Enterprise, helmed by Jean-Luc Picard (Patrick Stewart) and the rest of the Next Gen gang, encounters the same ribbon as they rescue Soran again from a Federation space station. But this is no ordinary energy ribbon (like, are there many others and what are they like then?) - the Nexus is a portal to another realm where time stands still and every whim is made real. In his desperation to return to the Nexus, Soran is prepared to commit murder on a galactic scale and Picard finds himself in need of another Starfleet captain in order to stop him... "Star Trek: Generations" has no lack of ambition in terms of story but execution is found wanting. Take the climatic battle between Picard and Soran on a rickety metal bridge that appear to be held in place with a couple of badly rusted nails - imagine a huge crystal chandelier held up by a safety pin and you get the idea. I know this is Trek and thus, eminently theatrical (much like Star Wars, of course) but Trek was always more about the characters spouting pseudo-scientific garbage than firing phasers and fisticuffs. To that end, we have Data (Brent Spiner) and his Emotion Chip overloading his positronic network or something which provides director David Carson with a handy sub-plot. But he gets it wrong - an android suddenly developing emotions could have provided us with moments of humour or "Blade Runner"-style philosophy but instead, we get Data going haywire for a bit and from that point on, he is reduced to comic sidekick. Not good. It's not a complete bust - the film looks OK although there isn't much to touch the zero gravity sequence from its predecessor "Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country" and the leads all perform well. Stewart and McDowell are actually a pretty good contrast - Picard's usually unflappable manner verses Soran's wide-eyed fanatic. The same cannot be said for the rest of the cast - perhaps with so much going on, they forgot to include any scenes of substance with Worf (Michael Dorn) or Doctor Crusher (Gates McFadden). Hell, even Guinan (Whoopi Goldberg) has more to do than those two. As a film, it's uneven - it's certainly entertaining in a not-really-sci-fi kinda way but fans expecting anything as dramatic as "Star Trek II: The Wrath Of Khan" would be advised to seek their thrills elsewhere. But then, there's that unwritten rule that odd-numbered Star Trek films are no match for even-numbered films and technically, this is Star Trek VII - for me, if you're wanting a better Next Gen film then you should check out "Star Trek: First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Commendably Thoughtful / Viciously Boring / Superfluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to agree with those who are of the opinion that the Original Series Star Trek crew did not need to appear in this film. They had already had their send off, and a very fine one at that, in The Undiscovered Country. There was no need for their presence to be stretched out into Generations. That applies to Kirk more than to anyone else, of course. But here, he gets to take his final bow, of sorts. It could have been done better. At the same time, it could be argued that the Next Generation crew did not need to be in this film, either. It doesn't really do much to meaningfully develop them beyond what had already been done in their seven seasons on television. The subsequent film, First Contact, probably should have served as the lone Next Generation big screen-adventure. In any event, Generations is not a horrible film, but in practice it is a bit of a drag to watch, like one of those books that are hard to read without falling asleep. Some will argue that it is superfluous, and most would probably agree that it is exceedingly slow and frankly boring in spite of its decent screenplay and somewhat fresh plot. Speaking of which, the overall story (beyond the obvious 'Kirk meets Piccard, passes baton' gimmick) looks fairly cool on paper. A ribbon of energy writhing through space, which happens to be a portal to a hallucinogenic other-dimension called the Nexus, where time has no meaning? All right. Malcolm McDowell's Dr. Soren, a member of a long-lived species who has been trying to get back into the Nexus for decades, who collaborates with rogue Klingons, and who is willing to destroy an entire populated planet in the service of his obsession? Sure. A sequence in which the USS Enterprise-D suffers a warp-core breach, forcing the crew to evacuate to the saucer section, which then crashes into the forests of the planet below? Why not  that sounds exciting. Nothing like blowing up the Enterprise to create a spectacle. As mentioned before, however, it all unfolds at an excessively leisurely pace that challenges the attention span of all but the most dedicated of viewers, and neither Enterprise crew (the 'B' crew at the beginning, featuring the old guys, or the 'D' Next Generation crew) really gets much out of it in terms of character development. I do however have to note Jacqueline Kim's brief but excellent performance as Ensign Demora Sulu, i.e. Hikaru Sulu's grown-up daughter. She looks like a terrific captain in the making as she holds the helm in the opening sequence, and frankly I would rather watch a film about her than what the rest of Generations turns out to be. Two specific things dog all of the Next Generation-era films, and they both rear their heads here. The first and arguably the most annoying is the overestimation of Data's fascination quotient. Every single one of the four Next Generation films feels compelled to put significant focus on his character, and with the exception of First Contact, it all feels gratuitous to me. Yes, his search for humanity is interesting. But not this interesting, and his adventures in humor here are more obnoxious than charming (or actually funny). Instead of fixating on Data, I wish that a more involved role would have been written for Dr. Crusher, who I feel to have been neglected more than any other major crew member. The other issue is the hard truth that the Next Generation's tone and aesthetic sensibilities, while well-suited for television, are simply not big-screen cinematic, particularly in comparison to the Original Series elements with which they share screen time in Generations. The uniforms especially could have benefited from a more sophisticated re-design. The common criticism that Next Generation films are more like glorified television episodes is not entirely unwarranted, although to be fair, Generations does have some very nice sequences. Is this the worst Star Trek film? Goodness, no. It might not even be the worst Next Generation-era film, when you consider the respective issues present in Insurrection and Nemesis. If being boring is a crime, then both Insurrection and The Motion Picture have no doubt shared a cell with Generations. Ultimately, this is a decent film, but probably only of much interest to Star Trek enthusiasts, and even then more as a curiosity than anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely poor dialogue, NOT redeemed in any way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To illustrate the horrible-ness of the film to the best, Star Trek: Generations is to the original crew films as to what Star Wars: The Phantom Menace is to the original Star Wars trilogy. Horrible! Whilst perhaps not as horrible as The Phantom Menace and the two horrid sequels that followed, Star Trek Generations gets plenty wrong for what is yet another perfect illustration of a horrible Star Trek film and perfectly justifies the statement that all Star Trek films with an odd number are poor, with the exception of The Search for Spock. Following the presumed death of Captain James T. Kirk, over 70 years later, The Enterprise has fallen into the hands of Captain Picard who deals with family strains whilst a new threat is under way. A surviver of an accident, that isn't carefully explained nor dealt with, has begun his attack on a star that when destroyed, will somehow give way to be able to visit the Nexus, which is a dream like world that presents the best and the happiest moments to anyone and everyone. The film suffers on almost every single aspect. The story is poor, but it goes even beyond this. It's not just a poor story and poor writing, but the story leaves no impact on us, as we have no idea who these new characters are. Much like how the original crew were first presented in Star Trek: The Motion Picture, the characters here are presented extremely ridiculously and annoyingly, the greatest of them being Data, who could have come off as an interesting android for the remainder of this franchise but is literally depicted as Jar Jar Binks. Now, it is clearly evident where George Lucas got his influence from. See, Spock was a fatherly figure and a wise man and was an interesting and likable character. Data is supposed to be a similar character but here is presented in the most horrid manner much like how we were apparently supposed to view Jar Jar as a Yoda type character. Such event is referred to as deliberately taking a sh*t on one's head! Data is annoying and is horrible jokes about an emotion chip and how he is suddenly able to understand jokes that were told years ago is not funny, its downright ridiculous. And not in a good way like in Monty Python and the Holy Grail. This character should've been presented far better and horrible writing is clearly evident here. Not only is Data poorly written, so is Picard who throughout the film deals with such family issues, having recently received the news that his family has died. Two things make this completely a forgettable and unnecessary sub plot to the film: This is the first time we even know who Picard is. There is obviously no reference in the original series due to the fact that this takes place over 70 years later. And secondly, the story about his family is hardly elaborated in anyway whatsoever and is instead, thrown in from the air and just left in a steady place. More poor writing is evident here. Each character is poorly written, to the fullest. The villain in the film, played by Malcolm McDowell, is yet again, another one of the many examples of poor writing in the film. His plan and his plot in the film is quickly summed up and almost never really referred to. Had he been written well, Soran could be a similar villain to Khan from the great 'Wrath of Khan'. Apparently in the film, Soran deals with personal issues of his own. MaybeThis character is hardly explained, due to horrible writing and has quite a silly and ridiculous plot. Whereas Star Trek 5 was ridiculous, it was not to this extent. The villain had a purpose that seemed more legit than here. Special effects are the same as all Star Trek films. Not great but decent enough for a pass. The acting is good, I would possibly say. Patrick Stewart as Picard is a great choice as is Malcolm McDowell as Soran but both are utterly wasted in this film. Returning is William Shatner, early on in the film as Captain James T. Kirk, in the best proportion of the film and returning late in the film in an extremely ridiculous concept. The best part of the film is the opening proportion as it cleverly resembles a good Star Trek film dealing with Kirk's desperation to get back into the captain's chair. Everything after this, is downhill ***SPOILERS*** The film suffers a lot in every way possible but here is when it is clearly evident that this is a truly horrible film. Our main character, James T Kirk, who has been loved by all is killed at the very end of the film in the most ridiculous and one of the most anticlimactic deaths to one of the great heroes. He dies and this scene shares no emotion like good Trek films do. When your main character, that you've loved so long, is killed and you laugh, that there is the perfect example of poor writing. ***END OF SPOILERS*** Star Trek: Generations, is in my opinion, the second worst film of the franchise, winning the silver medal with a gold going to the first Star Trek film. This film pretty much ensures that all odd numbered Star Trek films are terrible, with one small exception. Badly written, with a lame story and undeveloped characters, due to poor writing, Star Trek Generations is an utter failure. To imagine this movie, it is the Phantom Menace of Star Trek. To illustrate, prior to the making of the film, the director realized it was the 7th instalment and that it had to be horrible, and so asked for some horrible writing and extremely poor character development This film is a complete failure in every aspect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cast is Strong But The Plot Wears Thin,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek: Generations is a good movie with a storyline that dosen't really go anywhere for a very long time but a very inspired cast like there always is in Star Trek.It definitely wasn't a fantastic start for the Next Generation crew,it being their first movie,but I don't think its as bad as most people make it out to be,I don't think its the worst Star Trek but its certainly not the best,these movies are sometimes outstanding (The Wrath of Khan) and other times awful (The Final Frontier),I would put this right in the middle.The plot was sometimes very frustrating because it just didn't know were it was going for such a long time,but the impressive cast made it bearable,I really enjoyed Malcolm McDowell as the villain,he always delivers very creepy performances and he fit perfectly into the Star Trek universe.I didn't really appreciate William Shatner's performance,it all felt very forced and I think this movie would have been better off just focusing on the Next Generation crew instead of bringing in members from the original series.Fans of Star Trek:The Next Generation will definitely be disappointed,but will still appreciate the casts strong performances. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) disappears on a mission,seven decades later,Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) encounters similar peril and only the two captains can save the Enterprise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some fun to be had but not as momentous as it needs to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The seventh film in the series passes the torch to the crew of 'The Next Generation' with mixed results. A strong story was required to celebrate the meeting of Captains Kirk and Picard, but the plot is frustratingly underdeveloped and trundles towards a fizzling finale. It's a shame, too, that Leonard Nimoy and DeForest Kelley declined to appear. But there is excitement and humour along the way, plenty of thoughtful dialogue, an excellent performance from Patrick Stewart, and William Shatner seems to be having fun in his farewell performance, practically winking at the camera at times. The 'Trek' films are so middling that this isn't really any worse than the previous six (it's better than some); all the same, it carries with it the feeling that such a key chapter in 'Trek' history should have had more meat on its bones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and Confusing but with a couple of redeeming qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjkelley333
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I shouldn't be reviewing this film. I haven't seen Star Trek: The Next Generation. A lot of what I say here may be said out of ignorance. Well, who cares, I'll review it anyway. The film starts out with the christening of another starship U. S. S. Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk is on board for the ride. The ship comes across an energy phenomenon, which damages their ship. Kirk goes down to the core (or whatever you call that part of a starship) and fixes their problem. However, the room he is in is taken away by the energy, and he is declared dead. 78 years later, the current crew of the Enterprise, headed by Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) is summoned by Star Fleet to check out a damaged space station. There they discover Soran (Malcolm McDowell, A Clockwork Orange), an engineer whose home planet had been destroyed by the energy field at the beginning of the film. Soran attacks some crew members, and then travels to a planet where that energy field is headed. Captain Picard then learns that the energy field is called the Nexus, a space matrix that brings to life your heart's desire. However, it destroys everything in its path, and Soran is willing to commit murder to get back in the Nexus. There are two things I really like about this movie. One is the Nexus. It really is an interesting idea. A phenomenon that brings your dream to life is a fascinating idea, and actually quite thought- provoking. The other part I enjoy is Malcolm McDowell's performance. McDowell feels evil, psychotic, and brilliant. But hey, it's not like he hasn't played a psychopath before. However, there are many things I don't enjoy. There are pointless subplots that for the most part go nowhere. The most prominent subplot involves Data (Brent Spiner), a robot who resembles a human. He has a chip installed in himself that causes human emotion. His emotions are discussed throughout the film, but it doesn't go anywhere and is distracting. This brings up another question- how did they put feelings on an electronic chip? Another subplot centers around Picard. Some family members of his have recently died in a fire. He is shown mourning them. Later, he is in the Nexus, and he sees them alive again. This subplot never goes anywhere. The trailer and the posters for this film give the impressions that Kirk plays a large role in this film. However, he disappears in the beginning and doesn't reappear until the final half hour. Picard finds him in the Nexus, at his old home. At first Kirk says that he won't return to Star Fleet, but for some reason suddenly changes his mind. Yet another flaw of this film is Soran's plan. He is willing to commit murder and destroy planets to get to the Nexus. But he knows where it's headed. Why couldn't he just fly to it? But my biggest problem is this- it's SO BORING. That's all I can say- it's so dull. I really didn't care what was going on. And this is coming from someone who liked Star Trek: The Motion Picture. This film had a good villain and some fascinating ideas, but the slowness and subplots really brought it down. C
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed bag of goods for Star Trek fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sedativchunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen "Star Trek Generations" (STG) hundreds of times being a huge Star Trek fan. Recently I've watched it again from beginning to end in HD. Having watched watched pretty much every episode of all the Star Trek TV shows and all of the movies (including the newest "Into Darkness"), I felt the need to write a new, updated review for my take on this film. For many years, I hated this film as most other Star Trek fans have over the years. There many bad things about this movie. From the storyline to minor things like random changing between the standard TNG uniforms, this movie had a "wild" things going on. However, with all the shortcomings of this movie, after recently re-watching this film I've had a change of heart about my attitude towards this film. The good sides of this movie: STG is still a good, quality Star Trek film. The camera work, set design, costumes, and the works were all done with superb quality. After having watched most of TNG over recently, I've come to appreciate the nice budget this film got. The CGI, for the most part, is great. The shots of the Enterprise D were fantastic and a huge step up from the TV show models, from the flying through space to the destruction of the ship. In HD, this movie really pops for being almost 20 years old already. Although some find Data's behavior over the top in this film, I found it hilarious and if you are truly a TNG fan you will enjoy Brent Spiner's performance. We even get to see Spot, Data's cat again! Lastly, although I'm not a fan of the story, the villain is great and the concept behind "the nexus" is intriguing. Now for the bad sides of this film: the rest of the storyline! Simply put, STG has too much going on at once. They tried to cram too many things into this movie, making it a loyal TNG film while honoring Captain Kirk's history. The main thing that hurts this film and made many fans including myself dislike it, was the death of Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk's character was forced into this film. I found it completely unnecessary to ever make Picard and Kirk ever meet face-to-face in the first place. And the way William Shatner's Captain Kirk was killed off; I have and always will find it insulting and just plain bad for such a legendary TV icon. Although the story was interesting, in the end, TNG could have had a great start on the big screen without the "passing of the torch" from Kirk to Picard. The way "The Undiscovered Country" left off was perfect. Kirk has his last voyage in Enterprise and that was it. Instead they forcibly brought him back in this film as an excuse to involve him with TNG's storyline. In conclusion "Star Trek Generations" is a decent Star Trek film. If you can get past the mixed timelines/story and enjoy the good sides of this film, it is still an enjoyable movie with some hidden surprises. With that being said, though, this movie at heart is a TNG film. If you're not a TNG fan, you're going to hate this film. I also don't thing this is a good Star Trek film for the general audience. Unless you're a Star Trek fan, you probably won't "get" this movie. Of the TNG franchise, I still thing the best of the bunch is "First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Davyd Teather
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star trek generations is one of the most underrated star trek films if not one of the most underrated films in general. The mix of the original star trek characters with the next generation cast was amazing. This film starts off with three of the original star trek characters, James t. Kirk, Scotty and Chekov boarding the enterprise b. Just after the ship leaves spacedock, they get a distress call from a couple of spacecrafts caught on an energy ribbon and the enterprise b is the only ship in range. However it is not ready with a medical crew, tractor beam or weapons. They they close to the energy ribbon or the nexus as it is also called and rescue as many people from the spacecraft that they can and then use the deflector to break free from the energy ribbon. After they break free scotty tries to contact kirk but gets no response. He, and to other crew members go to the deck the deck to find him but find a chunk of the ship is missing and they believe he is dead. Then it fast forwards 78 years into the future showing the next generation cast. They are up against a mad man who is obsessed about getting back to the nexus, a place where time has no meaning, by destroying stars in order to change its course so he can get back into it. It is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Should Have Ended It After The Last One
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek Generations *1/2 (out of 4) 113 mins/ PG Cast: Patrick Stewart, Jonathan Frakes, Brent Spiner, LeVar Burton, Michael Dorn, Gates McFadden, Marina Sirtis, William Shatner, James Doohan, Whoopi Goldberg, Walter Koenig, Malcolm McDowell, Alan Ruck Director: David Carson Plot: Captain Picard must team up with Captain Kirk to stop a crazy scientist from destroying a whole planetary system in order to enter a world of happiness. JJ's Verdict: Many believe that Star Trek V: The Final Frontier is the worst of the series. I however, believe that Star Trek Generations is the worst of the series. After the success of Star Trek VI, Paramount must have been wondering what to do with what has at that point, become a great franchise. Of course, bring in a new cast and start again with Star Trek. Now this would have been fine, had they decided that some people (actually quite a lot of people) had never seen The Next Generation TV series and so needed a nice and easy to understand introduction to the characters. However, they didn't bother to introduce us to any of the characters or their backgrounds, or their relationships with other characters, or even their names until about half way through (and still you're struggling to remember who is who). Further on in the film, they want you to feel emotional towards these characters, but you can't because, as the viewer, you have no connection with them. This new crew and ship, set in the 24th century, while not a bad bunch of characters, do not capture the magic of the original crew and considering they had been on a TV show for 7 years, their chemistry is extremely poor and lacklustre. Now to the actual plot.... Kirk is guest of honour on the maiden voyage of the Enterprise B. But when a mysterious energy ribbon forces the Enterprise to save the ship's passengers, it comes at a cost: the death of Captain Kirk. Meanwhile, eighty years into the future, Captain Picard of the Enterprise D is up against evil scientist Soran, who is destroying planets so that he can reach Nexus, a mind matrix of happiness. Needing help, Picard somehow finds Kirk in the Nexus and the two team up to defeat Soran. Although the film is marketed as a battle involving captains from past and future, Shatner's role in the film is nothing more than a glorified cameo and you end up wondering whether Picard actually needs Kirk. Their scenes, although fun and full of references that Trekkies will love, are extremely silly and unnecessarily boring and slow. Throughout the film, threatening situations appear out of nowhere and while the action pieces are well set-up they are confusingly executed. Many other things are confusing and unexplained like how Picard gets out of the Nexus and it never tells the viewer how much time travel actually happens in this film. The only positives in this horrendous film are the short appearances of James Doohan and Walter Koenig as their original crew characters and the performances of British actors Patrick Stewart and Malcolm McDowell as Picard and Soran. Stewart has such a commanding presence on screen and the way he deals with emotional stress with his ageing self is superior to Shatner's in past instalments. Malcolm McDowell, most famous for playing a psychopath in Stanley Kubrick's ultra violent A Clockwork Orange, is both freaky and frightening in a very good performance. With three screen icons in its cast, it seems ridiculous that Star Trek Generations could be anything but good. Of course, it doesn't work that way in the film industry and even actors as good as Shatner, Stewart and McDowell can't stop this series 7th instalment from being a downright failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ultimate Star Trek movie. Kirk and Piccard are the best st duo ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokuguys
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie mainly because Its Kirk and Picard the two best st captains who ever lived. therefore it is the best st movie of all time. I was surprised of how high the quality of this movie was. i'm sure allot of people think of it as two old geezers fooling around in a crappy license movie but this was quite the contrary. i almost lost track of time, i was so absorbed in how amazing the movie was. It just wasn't the fact that the two of them were together at last. The acting of Bret spinner was incredible as well. For those of you who haven't seen it yet you are in for a treat(i don't want to oversell but you are going to love this film!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rough around the edges but it does the job, I suppose - 68%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the original TV crew dispatched, it was time to hand over the baton to the next phase in the franchise - the Next Generation. As this was the version of Star Trek I grew up watching, I was eagerly anticipating their first big screen outing and at the time, I wasn't disappointed. But as is often the way, watching it again today reminded me of several faults I'd overlooked before. A weak plot and villain, dialogue that would make George Lucas cringe and some pretty shoddy direction undermines a film with surprisingly good performances and effects that do justice to Gene Roddenbury's original vision. On the maiden voyage of the new Enterprise B, the inexperienced crew are forced to rescue two ships breaking up in some weird space ribbon. One of those rescued is a man named Soran (Malcolm McDowell) who is desperate to return to his exploding vessel. However, the Enterprise herself is badly damaged and the guest of honour, the retired Captain Kirk (William Shatner), is sadly sucked out into space. Seventy-eight years later and the current Enterprise, helmed by Jean-Luc Picard (Patrick Stewart) and the rest of the Next Gen gang, encounters the same ribbon as they rescue Soran again from a Federation space station. But this is no ordinary energy ribbon (like, are there many others and what are they like then?) - the Nexus is a portal to another realm where time stands still and every whim is made real. In his desperation to return to the Nexus, Soran is prepared to commit murder on a galactic scale and Picard finds himself in need of another Starfleet captain in order to stop him... "Star Trek: Generations" has no lack of ambition in terms of story but execution is found wanting. Take the climatic battle between Picard and Soran on a rickety metal bridge that appear to be held in place with a couple of badly rusted nails - imagine a huge crystal chandelier held up by a safety pin and you get the idea. I know this is Trek and thus, eminently theatrical (much like Star Wars, of course) but Trek was always more about the characters spouting pseudo-scientific garbage than firing phasers and fisticuffs. To that end, we have Data (Brent Spiner) and his Emotion Chip overloading his positronic network or something which provides director David Carson with a handy sub-plot. But he gets it wrong - an android suddenly developing emotions could have provided us with moments of humour or "Blade Runner"-style philosophy but instead, we get Data going haywire for a bit and from that point on, he is reduced to comic sidekick. Not good. It's not a complete bust - the film looks OK although there isn't much to touch the zero gravity sequence from its predecessor "Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country" and the leads all perform well. Stewart and McDowell are actually a pretty good contrast - Picard's usually unflappable manner verses Soran's wide-eyed fanatic. The same cannot be said for the rest of the cast - perhaps with so much going on, they forgot to include any scenes of substance with Worf (Michael Dorn) or Doctor Crusher (Gates McFadden). Hell, even Guinan (Whoopi Goldberg) has more to do than those two. As a film, it's uneven - it's certainly entertaining in a not-really-sci-fi kinda way but fans expecting anything as dramatic as "Star Trek II: The Wrath Of Khan" would be advised to seek their thrills elsewhere. But then, there's that unwritten rule that odd-numbered Star Trek films are no match for even-numbered films and technically, this is Star Trek VII - for me, if you're wanting a better Next Gen film then you should check out "Star Trek: First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Commendably Thoughtful / Viciously Boring / Superfluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to agree with those who are of the opinion that the Original Series Star Trek crew did not need to appear in this film. They had already had their send off, and a very fine one at that, in The Undiscovered Country. There was no need for their presence to be stretched out into Generations. That applies to Kirk more than to anyone else, of course. But here, he gets to take his final bow, of sorts. It could have been done better. At the same time, it could be argued that the Next Generation crew did not need to be in this film, either. It doesn't really do much to meaningfully develop them beyond what had already been done in their seven seasons on television. The subsequent film, First Contact, probably should have served as the lone Next Generation big screen-adventure. In any event, Generations is not a horrible film, but in practice it is a bit of a drag to watch, like one of those books that are hard to read without falling asleep. Some will argue that it is superfluous, and most would probably agree that it is exceedingly slow and frankly boring in spite of its decent screenplay and somewhat fresh plot. Speaking of which, the overall story (beyond the obvious 'Kirk meets Piccard, passes baton' gimmick) looks fairly cool on paper. A ribbon of energy writhing through space, which happens to be a portal to a hallucinogenic other-dimension called the Nexus, where time has no meaning? All right. Malcolm McDowell's Dr. Soren, a member of a long-lived species who has been trying to get back into the Nexus for decades, who collaborates with rogue Klingons, and who is willing to destroy an entire populated planet in the service of his obsession? Sure. A sequence in which the USS Enterprise-D suffers a warp-core breach, forcing the crew to evacuate to the saucer section, which then crashes into the forests of the planet below? Why not  that sounds exciting. Nothing like blowing up the Enterprise to create a spectacle. As mentioned before, however, it all unfolds at an excessively leisurely pace that challenges the attention span of all but the most dedicated of viewers, and neither Enterprise crew (the 'B' crew at the beginning, featuring the old guys, or the 'D' Next Generation crew) really gets much out of it in terms of character development. I do however have to note Jacqueline Kim's brief but excellent performance as Ensign Demora Sulu, i.e. Hikaru Sulu's grown-up daughter. She looks like a terrific captain in the making as she holds the helm in the opening sequence, and frankly I would rather watch a film about her than what the rest of Generations turns out to be. Two specific things dog all of the Next Generation-era films, and they both rear their heads here. The first and arguably the most annoying is the overestimation of Data's fascination quotient. Every single one of the four Next Generation films feels compelled to put significant focus on his character, and with the exception of First Contact, it all feels gratuitous to me. Yes, his search for humanity is interesting. But not this interesting, and his adventures in humor here are more obnoxious than charming (or actually funny). Instead of fixating on Data, I wish that a more involved role would have been written for Dr. Crusher, who I feel to have been neglected more than any other major crew member. The other issue is the hard truth that the Next Generation's tone and aesthetic sensibilities, while well-suited for television, are simply not big-screen cinematic, particularly in comparison to the Original Series elements with which they share screen time in Generations. The uniforms especially could have benefited from a more sophisticated re-design. The common criticism that Next Generation films are more like glorified television episodes is not entirely unwarranted, although to be fair, Generations does have some very nice sequences. Is this the worst Star Trek film? Goodness, no. It might not even be the worst Next Generation-era film, when you consider the respective issues present in Insurrection and Nemesis. If being boring is a crime, then both Insurrection and The Motion Picture have no doubt shared a cell with Generations. Ultimately, this is a decent film, but probably only of much interest to Star Trek enthusiasts, and even then more as a curiosity than anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely poor dialogue, NOT redeemed in any way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To illustrate the horrible-ness of the film to the best, Star Trek: Generations is to the original crew films as to what Star Wars: The Phantom Menace is to the original Star Wars trilogy. Horrible! Whilst perhaps not as horrible as The Phantom Menace and the two horrid sequels that followed, Star Trek Generations gets plenty wrong for what is yet another perfect illustration of a horrible Star Trek film and perfectly justifies the statement that all Star Trek films with an odd number are poor, with the exception of The Search for Spock. Following the presumed death of Captain James T. Kirk, over 70 years later, The Enterprise has fallen into the hands of Captain Picard who deals with family strains whilst a new threat is under way. A surviver of an accident, that isn't carefully explained nor dealt with, has begun his attack on a star that when destroyed, will somehow give way to be able to visit the Nexus, which is a dream like world that presents the best and the happiest moments to anyone and everyone. The film suffers on almost every single aspect. The story is poor, but it goes even beyond this. It's not just a poor story and poor writing, but the story leaves no impact on us, as we have no idea who these new characters are. Much like how the original crew were first presented in Star Trek: The Motion Picture, the characters here are presented extremely ridiculously and annoyingly, the greatest of them being Data, who could have come off as an interesting android for the remainder of this franchise but is literally depicted as Jar Jar Binks. Now, it is clearly evident where George Lucas got his influence from. See, Spock was a fatherly figure and a wise man and was an interesting and likable character. Data is supposed to be a similar character but here is presented in the most horrid manner much like how we were apparently supposed to view Jar Jar as a Yoda type character. Such event is referred to as deliberately taking a sh*t on one's head! Data is annoying and is horrible jokes about an emotion chip and how he is suddenly able to understand jokes that were told years ago is not funny, its downright ridiculous. And not in a good way like in Monty Python and the Holy Grail. This character should've been presented far better and horrible writing is clearly evident here. Not only is Data poorly written, so is Picard who throughout the film deals with such family issues, having recently received the news that his family has died. Two things make this completely a forgettable and unnecessary sub plot to the film: This is the first time we even know who Picard is. There is obviously no reference in the original series due to the fact that this takes place over 70 years later. And secondly, the story about his family is hardly elaborated in anyway whatsoever and is instead, thrown in from the air and just left in a steady place. More poor writing is evident here. Each character is poorly written, to the fullest. The villain in the film, played by Malcolm McDowell, is yet again, another one of the many examples of poor writing in the film. His plan and his plot in the film is quickly summed up and almost never really referred to. Had he been written well, Soran could be a similar villain to Khan from the great 'Wrath of Khan'. Apparently in the film, Soran deals with personal issues of his own. MaybeThis character is hardly explained, due to horrible writing and has quite a silly and ridiculous plot. Whereas Star Trek 5 was ridiculous, it was not to this extent. The villain had a purpose that seemed more legit than here. Special effects are the same as all Star Trek films. Not great but decent enough for a pass. The acting is good, I would possibly say. Patrick Stewart as Picard is a great choice as is Malcolm McDowell as Soran but both are utterly wasted in this film. Returning is William Shatner, early on in the film as Captain James T. Kirk, in the best proportion of the film and returning late in the film in an extremely ridiculous concept. The best part of the film is the opening proportion as it cleverly resembles a good Star Trek film dealing with Kirk's desperation to get back into the captain's chair. Everything after this, is downhill ***SPOILERS*** The film suffers a lot in every way possible but here is when it is clearly evident that this is a truly horrible film. Our main character, James T Kirk, who has been loved by all is killed at the very end of the film in the most ridiculous and one of the most anticlimactic deaths to one of the great heroes. He dies and this scene shares no emotion like good Trek films do. When your main character, that you've loved so long, is killed and you laugh, that there is the perfect example of poor writing. ***END OF SPOILERS*** Star Trek: Generations, is in my opinion, the second worst film of the franchise, winning the silver medal with a gold going to the first Star Trek film. This film pretty much ensures that all odd numbered Star Trek films are terrible, with one small exception. Badly written, with a lame story and undeveloped characters, due to poor writing, Star Trek Generations is an utter failure. To imagine this movie, it is the Phantom Menace of Star Trek. To illustrate, prior to the making of the film, the director realized it was the 7th instalment and that it had to be horrible, and so asked for some horrible writing and extremely poor character development This film is a complete failure in every aspect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cast is Strong But The Plot Wears Thin,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek: Generations is a good movie with a storyline that dosen't really go anywhere for a very long time but a very inspired cast like there always is in Star Trek.It definitely wasn't a fantastic start for the Next Generation crew,it being their first movie,but I don't think its as bad as most people make it out to be,I don't think its the worst Star Trek but its certainly not the best,these movies are sometimes outstanding (The Wrath of Khan) and other times awful (The Final Frontier),I would put this right in the middle.The plot was sometimes very frustrating because it just didn't know were it was going for such a long time,but the impressive cast made it bearable,I really enjoyed Malcolm McDowell as the villain,he always delivers very creepy performances and he fit perfectly into the Star Trek universe.I didn't really appreciate William Shatner's performance,it all felt very forced and I think this movie would have been better off just focusing on the Next Generation crew instead of bringing in members from the original series.Fans of Star Trek:The Next Generation will definitely be disappointed,but will still appreciate the casts strong performances. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) disappears on a mission,seven decades later,Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) encounters similar peril and only the two captains can save the Enterprise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some fun to be had but not as momentous as it needs to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The seventh film in the series passes the torch to the crew of 'The Next Generation' with mixed results. A strong story was required to celebrate the meeting of Captains Kirk and Picard, but the plot is frustratingly underdeveloped and trundles towards a fizzling finale. It's a shame, too, that Leonard Nimoy and DeForest Kelley declined to appear. But there is excitement and humour along the way, plenty of thoughtful dialogue, an excellent performance from Patrick Stewart, and William Shatner seems to be having fun in his farewell performance, practically winking at the camera at times. The 'Trek' films are so middling that this isn't really any worse than the previous six (it's better than some); all the same, it carries with it the feeling that such a key chapter in 'Trek' history should have had more meat on its bones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and Confusing but with a couple of redeeming qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjkelley333
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I shouldn't be reviewing this film. I haven't seen Star Trek: The Next Generation. A lot of what I say here may be said out of ignorance. Well, who cares, I'll review it anyway. The film starts out with the christening of another starship U. S. S. Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk is on board for the ride. The ship comes across an energy phenomenon, which damages their ship. Kirk goes down to the core (or whatever you call that part of a starship) and fixes their problem. However, the room he is in is taken away by the energy, and he is declared dead. 78 years later, the current crew of the Enterprise, headed by Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) is summoned by Star Fleet to check out a damaged space station. There they discover Soran (Malcolm McDowell, A Clockwork Orange), an engineer whose home planet had been destroyed by the energy field at the beginning of the film. Soran attacks some crew members, and then travels to a planet where that energy field is headed. Captain Picard then learns that the energy field is called the Nexus, a space matrix that brings to life your heart's desire. However, it destroys everything in its path, and Soran is willing to commit murder to get back in the Nexus. There are two things I really like about this movie. One is the Nexus. It really is an interesting idea. A phenomenon that brings your dream to life is a fascinating idea, and actually quite thought- provoking. The other part I enjoy is Malcolm McDowell's performance. McDowell feels evil, psychotic, and brilliant. But hey, it's not like he hasn't played a psychopath before. However, there are many things I don't enjoy. There are pointless subplots that for the most part go nowhere. The most prominent subplot involves Data (Brent Spiner), a robot who resembles a human. He has a chip installed in himself that causes human emotion. His emotions are discussed throughout the film, but it doesn't go anywhere and is distracting. This brings up another question- how did they put feelings on an electronic chip? Another subplot centers around Picard. Some family members of his have recently died in a fire. He is shown mourning them. Later, he is in the Nexus, and he sees them alive again. This subplot never goes anywhere. The trailer and the posters for this film give the impressions that Kirk plays a large role in this film. However, he disappears in the beginning and doesn't reappear until the final half hour. Picard finds him in the Nexus, at his old home. At first Kirk says that he won't return to Star Fleet, but for some reason suddenly changes his mind. Yet another flaw of this film is Soran's plan. He is willing to commit murder and destroy planets to get to the Nexus. But he knows where it's headed. Why couldn't he just fly to it? But my biggest problem is this- it's SO BORING. That's all I can say- it's so dull. I really didn't care what was going on. And this is coming from someone who liked Star Trek: The Motion Picture. This film had a good villain and some fascinating ideas, but the slowness and subplots really brought it down. C
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed bag of goods for Star Trek fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sedativchunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen "Star Trek Generations" (STG) hundreds of times being a huge Star Trek fan. Recently I've watched it again from beginning to end in HD. Having watched watched pretty much every episode of all the Star Trek TV shows and all of the movies (including the newest "Into Darkness"), I felt the need to write a new, updated review for my take on this film. For many years, I hated this film as most other Star Trek fans have over the years. There many bad things about this movie. From the storyline to minor things like random changing between the standard TNG uniforms, this movie had a "wild" things going on. However, with all the shortcomings of this movie, after recently re-watching this film I've had a change of heart about my attitude towards this film. The good sides of this movie: STG is still a good, quality Star Trek film. The camera work, set design, costumes, and the works were all done with superb quality. After having watched most of TNG over recently, I've come to appreciate the nice budget this film got. The CGI, for the most part, is great. The shots of the Enterprise D were fantastic and a huge step up from the TV show models, from the flying through space to the destruction of the ship. In HD, this movie really pops for being almost 20 years old already. Although some find Data's behavior over the top in this film, I found it hilarious and if you are truly a TNG fan you will enjoy Brent Spiner's performance. We even get to see Spot, Data's cat again! Lastly, although I'm not a fan of the story, the villain is great and the concept behind "the nexus" is intriguing. Now for the bad sides of this film: the rest of the storyline! Simply put, STG has too much going on at once. They tried to cram too many things into this movie, making it a loyal TNG film while honoring Captain Kirk's history. The main thing that hurts this film and made many fans including myself dislike it, was the death of Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk's character was forced into this film. I found it completely unnecessary to ever make Picard and Kirk ever meet face-to-face in the first place. And the way William Shatner's Captain Kirk was killed off; I have and always will find it insulting and just plain bad for such a legendary TV icon. Although the story was interesting, in the end, TNG could have had a great start on the big screen without the "passing of the torch" from Kirk to Picard. The way "The Undiscovered Country" left off was perfect. Kirk has his last voyage in Enterprise and that was it. Instead they forcibly brought him back in this film as an excuse to involve him with TNG's storyline. In conclusion "Star Trek Generations" is a decent Star Trek film. If you can get past the mixed timelines/story and enjoy the good sides of this film, it is still an enjoyable movie with some hidden surprises. With that being said, though, this movie at heart is a TNG film. If you're not a TNG fan, you're going to hate this film. I also don't thing this is a good Star Trek film for the general audience. Unless you're a Star Trek fan, you probably won't "get" this movie. Of the TNG franchise, I still thing the best of the bunch is "First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Davyd Teather
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star trek generations is one of the most underrated star trek films if not one of the most underrated films in general. The mix of the original star trek characters with the next generation cast was amazing. This film starts off with three of the original star trek characters, James t. Kirk, Scotty and Chekov boarding the enterprise b. Just after the ship leaves spacedock, they get a distress call from a couple of spacecrafts caught on an energy ribbon and the enterprise b is the only ship in range. However it is not ready with a medical crew, tractor beam or weapons. They they close to the energy ribbon or the nexus as it is also called and rescue as many people from the spacecraft that they can and then use the deflector to break free from the energy ribbon. After they break free scotty tries to contact kirk but gets no response. He, and to other crew members go to the deck the deck to find him but find a chunk of the ship is missing and they believe he is dead. Then it fast forwards 78 years into the future showing the next generation cast. They are up against a mad man who is obsessed about getting back to the nexus, a place where time has no meaning, by destroying stars in order to change its course so he can get back into it. It is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Should Have Ended It After The Last One
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek Generations *1/2 (out of 4) 113 mins/ PG Cast: Patrick Stewart, Jonathan Frakes, Brent Spiner, LeVar Burton, Michael Dorn, Gates McFadden, Marina Sirtis, William Shatner, James Doohan, Whoopi Goldberg, Walter Koenig, Malcolm McDowell, Alan Ruck Director: David Carson Plot: Captain Picard must team up with Captain Kirk to stop a crazy scientist from destroying a whole planetary system in order to enter a world of happiness. JJ's Verdict: Many believe that Star Trek V: The Final Frontier is the worst of the series. I however, believe that Star Trek Generations is the worst of the series. After the success of Star Trek VI, Paramount must have been wondering what to do with what has at that point, become a great franchise. Of course, bring in a new cast and start again with Star Trek. Now this would have been fine, had they decided that some people (actually quite a lot of people) had never seen The Next Generation TV series and so needed a nice and easy to understand introduction to the characters. However, they didn't bother to introduce us to any of the characters or their backgrounds, or their relationships with other characters, or even their names until about half way through (and still you're struggling to remember who is who). Further on in the film, they want you to feel emotional towards these characters, but you can't because, as the viewer, you have no connection with them. This new crew and ship, set in the 24th century, while not a bad bunch of characters, do not capture the magic of the original crew and considering they had been on a TV show for 7 years, their chemistry is extremely poor and lacklustre. Now to the actual plot.... Kirk is guest of honour on the maiden voyage of the Enterprise B. But when a mysterious energy ribbon forces the Enterprise to save the ship's passengers, it comes at a cost: the death of Captain Kirk. Meanwhile, eighty years into the future, Captain Picard of the Enterprise D is up against evil scientist Soran, who is destroying planets so that he can reach Nexus, a mind matrix of happiness. Needing help, Picard somehow finds Kirk in the Nexus and the two team up to defeat Soran. Although the film is marketed as a battle involving captains from past and future, Shatner's role in the film is nothing more than a glorified cameo and you end up wondering whether Picard actually needs Kirk. Their scenes, although fun and full of references that Trekkies will love, are extremely silly and unnecessarily boring and slow. Throughout the film, threatening situations appear out of nowhere and while the action pieces are well set-up they are confusingly executed. Many other things are confusing and unexplained like how Picard gets out of the Nexus and it never tells the viewer how much time travel actually happens in this film. The only positives in this horrendous film are the short appearances of James Doohan and Walter Koenig as their original crew characters and the performances of British actors Patrick Stewart and Malcolm McDowell as Picard and Soran. Stewart has such a commanding presence on screen and the way he deals with emotional stress with his ageing self is superior to Shatner's in past instalments. Malcolm McDowell, most famous for playing a psychopath in Stanley Kubrick's ultra violent A Clockwork Orange, is both freaky and frightening in a very good performance. With three screen icons in its cast, it seems ridiculous that Star Trek Generations could be anything but good. Of course, it doesn't work that way in the film industry and even actors as good as Shatner, Stewart and McDowell can't stop this series 7th instalment from being a downright failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ultimate Star Trek movie. Kirk and Piccard are the best st duo ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokuguys
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie mainly because Its Kirk and Picard the two best st captains who ever lived. therefore it is the best st movie of all time. I was surprised of how high the quality of this movie was. i'm sure allot of people think of it as two old geezers fooling around in a crappy license movie but this was quite the contrary. i almost lost track of time, i was so absorbed in how amazing the movie was. It just wasn't the fact that the two of them were together at last. The acting of Bret spinner was incredible as well. For those of you who haven't seen it yet you are in for a treat(i don't want to oversell but you are going to love this film!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rough around the edges but it does the job, I suppose - 68%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the original TV crew dispatched, it was time to hand over the baton to the next phase in the franchise - the Next Generation. As this was the version of Star Trek I grew up watching, I was eagerly anticipating their first big screen outing and at the time, I wasn't disappointed. But as is often the way, watching it again today reminded me of several faults I'd overlooked before. A weak plot and villain, dialogue that would make George Lucas cringe and some pretty shoddy direction undermines a film with surprisingly good performances and effects that do justice to Gene Roddenbury's original vision. On the maiden voyage of the new Enterprise B, the inexperienced crew are forced to rescue two ships breaking up in some weird space ribbon. One of those rescued is a man named Soran (Malcolm McDowell) who is desperate to return to his exploding vessel. However, the Enterprise herself is badly damaged and the guest of honour, the retired Captain Kirk (William Shatner), is sadly sucked out into space. Seventy-eight years later and the current Enterprise, helmed by Jean-Luc Picard (Patrick Stewart) and the rest of the Next Gen gang, encounters the same ribbon as they rescue Soran again from a Federation space station. But this is no ordinary energy ribbon (like, are there many others and what are they like then?) - the Nexus is a portal to another realm where time stands still and every whim is made real. In his desperation to return to the Nexus, Soran is prepared to commit murder on a galactic scale and Picard finds himself in need of another Starfleet captain in order to stop him... "Star Trek: Generations" has no lack of ambition in terms of story but execution is found wanting. Take the climatic battle between Picard and Soran on a rickety metal bridge that appear to be held in place with a couple of badly rusted nails - imagine a huge crystal chandelier held up by a safety pin and you get the idea. I know this is Trek and thus, eminently theatrical (much like Star Wars, of course) but Trek was always more about the characters spouting pseudo-scientific garbage than firing phasers and fisticuffs. To that end, we have Data (Brent Spiner) and his Emotion Chip overloading his positronic network or something which provides director David Carson with a handy sub-plot. But he gets it wrong - an android suddenly developing emotions could have provided us with moments of humour or "Blade Runner"-style philosophy but instead, we get Data going haywire for a bit and from that point on, he is reduced to comic sidekick. Not good. It's not a complete bust - the film looks OK although there isn't much to touch the zero gravity sequence from its predecessor "Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country" and the leads all perform well. Stewart and McDowell are actually a pretty good contrast - Picard's usually unflappable manner verses Soran's wide-eyed fanatic. The same cannot be said for the rest of the cast - perhaps with so much going on, they forgot to include any scenes of substance with Worf (Michael Dorn) or Doctor Crusher (Gates McFadden). Hell, even Guinan (Whoopi Goldberg) has more to do than those two. As a film, it's uneven - it's certainly entertaining in a not-really-sci-fi kinda way but fans expecting anything as dramatic as "Star Trek II: The Wrath Of Khan" would be advised to seek their thrills elsewhere. But then, there's that unwritten rule that odd-numbered Star Trek films are no match for even-numbered films and technically, this is Star Trek VII - for me, if you're wanting a better Next Gen film then you should check out "Star Trek: First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Commendably Thoughtful / Viciously Boring / Superfluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to agree with those who are of the opinion that the Original Series Star Trek crew did not need to appear in this film. They had already had their send off, and a very fine one at that, in The Undiscovered Country. There was no need for their presence to be stretched out into Generations. That applies to Kirk more than to anyone else, of course. But here, he gets to take his final bow, of sorts. It could have been done better. At the same time, it could be argued that the Next Generation crew did not need to be in this film, either. It doesn't really do much to meaningfully develop them beyond what had already been done in their seven seasons on television. The subsequent film, First Contact, probably should have served as the lone Next Generation big screen-adventure. In any event, Generations is not a horrible film, but in practice it is a bit of a drag to watch, like one of those books that are hard to read without falling asleep. Some will argue that it is superfluous, and most would probably agree that it is exceedingly slow and frankly boring in spite of its decent screenplay and somewhat fresh plot. Speaking of which, the overall story (beyond the obvious 'Kirk meets Piccard, passes baton' gimmick) looks fairly cool on paper. A ribbon of energy writhing through space, which happens to be a portal to a hallucinogenic other-dimension called the Nexus, where time has no meaning? All right. Malcolm McDowell's Dr. Soren, a member of a long-lived species who has been trying to get back into the Nexus for decades, who collaborates with rogue Klingons, and who is willing to destroy an entire populated planet in the service of his obsession? Sure. A sequence in which the USS Enterprise-D suffers a warp-core breach, forcing the crew to evacuate to the saucer section, which then crashes into the forests of the planet below? Why not  that sounds exciting. Nothing like blowing up the Enterprise to create a spectacle. As mentioned before, however, it all unfolds at an excessively leisurely pace that challenges the attention span of all but the most dedicated of viewers, and neither Enterprise crew (the 'B' crew at the beginning, featuring the old guys, or the 'D' Next Generation crew) really gets much out of it in terms of character development. I do however have to note Jacqueline Kim's brief but excellent performance as Ensign Demora Sulu, i.e. Hikaru Sulu's grown-up daughter. She looks like a terrific captain in the making as she holds the helm in the opening sequence, and frankly I would rather watch a film about her than what the rest of Generations turns out to be. Two specific things dog all of the Next Generation-era films, and they both rear their heads here. The first and arguably the most annoying is the overestimation of Data's fascination quotient. Every single one of the four Next Generation films feels compelled to put significant focus on his character, and with the exception of First Contact, it all feels gratuitous to me. Yes, his search for humanity is interesting. But not this interesting, and his adventures in humor here are more obnoxious than charming (or actually funny). Instead of fixating on Data, I wish that a more involved role would have been written for Dr. Crusher, who I feel to have been neglected more than any other major crew member. The other issue is the hard truth that the Next Generation's tone and aesthetic sensibilities, while well-suited for television, are simply not big-screen cinematic, particularly in comparison to the Original Series elements with which they share screen time in Generations. The uniforms especially could have benefited from a more sophisticated re-design. The common criticism that Next Generation films are more like glorified television episodes is not entirely unwarranted, although to be fair, Generations does have some very nice sequences. Is this the worst Star Trek film? Goodness, no. It might not even be the worst Next Generation-era film, when you consider the respective issues present in Insurrection and Nemesis. If being boring is a crime, then both Insurrection and The Motion Picture have no doubt shared a cell with Generations. Ultimately, this is a decent film, but probably only of much interest to Star Trek enthusiasts, and even then more as a curiosity than anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely poor dialogue, NOT redeemed in any way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To illustrate the horrible-ness of the film to the best, Star Trek: Generations is to the original crew films as to what Star Wars: The Phantom Menace is to the original Star Wars trilogy. Horrible! Whilst perhaps not as horrible as The Phantom Menace and the two horrid sequels that followed, Star Trek Generations gets plenty wrong for what is yet another perfect illustration of a horrible Star Trek film and perfectly justifies the statement that all Star Trek films with an odd number are poor, with the exception of The Search for Spock. Following the presumed death of Captain James T. Kirk, over 70 years later, The Enterprise has fallen into the hands of Captain Picard who deals with family strains whilst a new threat is under way. A surviver of an accident, that isn't carefully explained nor dealt with, has begun his attack on a star that when destroyed, will somehow give way to be able to visit the Nexus, which is a dream like world that presents the best and the happiest moments to anyone and everyone. The film suffers on almost every single aspect. The story is poor, but it goes even beyond this. It's not just a poor story and poor writing, but the story leaves no impact on us, as we have no idea who these new characters are. Much like how the original crew were first presented in Star Trek: The Motion Picture, the characters here are presented extremely ridiculously and annoyingly, the greatest of them being Data, who could have come off as an interesting android for the remainder of this franchise but is literally depicted as Jar Jar Binks. Now, it is clearly evident where George Lucas got his influence from. See, Spock was a fatherly figure and a wise man and was an interesting and likable character. Data is supposed to be a similar character but here is presented in the most horrid manner much like how we were apparently supposed to view Jar Jar as a Yoda type character. Such event is referred to as deliberately taking a sh*t on one's head! Data is annoying and is horrible jokes about an emotion chip and how he is suddenly able to understand jokes that were told years ago is not funny, its downright ridiculous. And not in a good way like in Monty Python and the Holy Grail. This character should've been presented far better and horrible writing is clearly evident here. Not only is Data poorly written, so is Picard who throughout the film deals with such family issues, having recently received the news that his family has died. Two things make this completely a forgettable and unnecessary sub plot to the film: This is the first time we even know who Picard is. There is obviously no reference in the original series due to the fact that this takes place over 70 years later. And secondly, the story about his family is hardly elaborated in anyway whatsoever and is instead, thrown in from the air and just left in a steady place. More poor writing is evident here. Each character is poorly written, to the fullest. The villain in the film, played by Malcolm McDowell, is yet again, another one of the many examples of poor writing in the film. His plan and his plot in the film is quickly summed up and almost never really referred to. Had he been written well, Soran could be a similar villain to Khan from the great 'Wrath of Khan'. Apparently in the film, Soran deals with personal issues of his own. MaybeThis character is hardly explained, due to horrible writing and has quite a silly and ridiculous plot. Whereas Star Trek 5 was ridiculous, it was not to this extent. The villain had a purpose that seemed more legit than here. Special effects are the same as all Star Trek films. Not great but decent enough for a pass. The acting is good, I would possibly say. Patrick Stewart as Picard is a great choice as is Malcolm McDowell as Soran but both are utterly wasted in this film. Returning is William Shatner, early on in the film as Captain James T. Kirk, in the best proportion of the film and returning late in the film in an extremely ridiculous concept. The best part of the film is the opening proportion as it cleverly resembles a good Star Trek film dealing with Kirk's desperation to get back into the captain's chair. Everything after this, is downhill ***SPOILERS*** The film suffers a lot in every way possible but here is when it is clearly evident that this is a truly horrible film. Our main character, James T Kirk, who has been loved by all is killed at the very end of the film in the most ridiculous and one of the most anticlimactic deaths to one of the great heroes. He dies and this scene shares no emotion like good Trek films do. When your main character, that you've loved so long, is killed and you laugh, that there is the perfect example of poor writing. ***END OF SPOILERS*** Star Trek: Generations, is in my opinion, the second worst film of the franchise, winning the silver medal with a gold going to the first Star Trek film. This film pretty much ensures that all odd numbered Star Trek films are terrible, with one small exception. Badly written, with a lame story and undeveloped characters, due to poor writing, Star Trek Generations is an utter failure. To imagine this movie, it is the Phantom Menace of Star Trek. To illustrate, prior to the making of the film, the director realized it was the 7th instalment and that it had to be horrible, and so asked for some horrible writing and extremely poor character development This film is a complete failure in every aspect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cast is Strong But The Plot Wears Thin,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek: Generations is a good movie with a storyline that dosen't really go anywhere for a very long time but a very inspired cast like there always is in Star Trek.It definitely wasn't a fantastic start for the Next Generation crew,it being their first movie,but I don't think its as bad as most people make it out to be,I don't think its the worst Star Trek but its certainly not the best,these movies are sometimes outstanding (The Wrath of Khan) and other times awful (The Final Frontier),I would put this right in the middle.The plot was sometimes very frustrating because it just didn't know were it was going for such a long time,but the impressive cast made it bearable,I really enjoyed Malcolm McDowell as the villain,he always delivers very creepy performances and he fit perfectly into the Star Trek universe.I didn't really appreciate William Shatner's performance,it all felt very forced and I think this movie would have been better off just focusing on the Next Generation crew instead of bringing in members from the original series.Fans of Star Trek:The Next Generation will definitely be disappointed,but will still appreciate the casts strong performances. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) disappears on a mission,seven decades later,Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) encounters similar peril and only the two captains can save the Enterprise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some fun to be had but not as momentous as it needs to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The seventh film in the series passes the torch to the crew of 'The Next Generation' with mixed results. A strong story was required to celebrate the meeting of Captains Kirk and Picard, but the plot is frustratingly underdeveloped and trundles towards a fizzling finale. It's a shame, too, that Leonard Nimoy and DeForest Kelley declined to appear. But there is excitement and humour along the way, plenty of thoughtful dialogue, an excellent performance from Patrick Stewart, and William Shatner seems to be having fun in his farewell performance, practically winking at the camera at times. The 'Trek' films are so middling that this isn't really any worse than the previous six (it's better than some); all the same, it carries with it the feeling that such a key chapter in 'Trek' history should have had more meat on its bones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and Confusing but with a couple of redeeming qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjkelley333
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I shouldn't be reviewing this film. I haven't seen Star Trek: The Next Generation. A lot of what I say here may be said out of ignorance. Well, who cares, I'll review it anyway. The film starts out with the christening of another starship U. S. S. Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk is on board for the ride. The ship comes across an energy phenomenon, which damages their ship. Kirk goes down to the core (or whatever you call that part of a starship) and fixes their problem. However, the room he is in is taken away by the energy, and he is declared dead. 78 years later, the current crew of the Enterprise, headed by Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) is summoned by Star Fleet to check out a damaged space station. There they discover Soran (Malcolm McDowell, A Clockwork Orange), an engineer whose home planet had been destroyed by the energy field at the beginning of the film. Soran attacks some crew members, and then travels to a planet where that energy field is headed. Captain Picard then learns that the energy field is called the Nexus, a space matrix that brings to life your heart's desire. However, it destroys everything in its path, and Soran is willing to commit murder to get back in the Nexus. There are two things I really like about this movie. One is the Nexus. It really is an interesting idea. A phenomenon that brings your dream to life is a fascinating idea, and actually quite thought- provoking. The other part I enjoy is Malcolm McDowell's performance. McDowell feels evil, psychotic, and brilliant. But hey, it's not like he hasn't played a psychopath before. However, there are many things I don't enjoy. There are pointless subplots that for the most part go nowhere. The most prominent subplot involves Data (Brent Spiner), a robot who resembles a human. He has a chip installed in himself that causes human emotion. His emotions are discussed throughout the film, but it doesn't go anywhere and is distracting. This brings up another question- how did they put feelings on an electronic chip? Another subplot centers around Picard. Some family members of his have recently died in a fire. He is shown mourning them. Later, he is in the Nexus, and he sees them alive again. This subplot never goes anywhere. The trailer and the posters for this film give the impressions that Kirk plays a large role in this film. However, he disappears in the beginning and doesn't reappear until the final half hour. Picard finds him in the Nexus, at his old home. At first Kirk says that he won't return to Star Fleet, but for some reason suddenly changes his mind. Yet another flaw of this film is Soran's plan. He is willing to commit murder and destroy planets to get to the Nexus. But he knows where it's headed. Why couldn't he just fly to it? But my biggest problem is this- it's SO BORING. That's all I can say- it's so dull. I really didn't care what was going on. And this is coming from someone who liked Star Trek: The Motion Picture. This film had a good villain and some fascinating ideas, but the slowness and subplots really brought it down. C
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed bag of goods for Star Trek fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sedativchunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen "Star Trek Generations" (STG) hundreds of times being a huge Star Trek fan. Recently I've watched it again from beginning to end in HD. Having watched watched pretty much every episode of all the Star Trek TV shows and all of the movies (including the newest "Into Darkness"), I felt the need to write a new, updated review for my take on this film. For many years, I hated this film as most other Star Trek fans have over the years. There many bad things about this movie. From the storyline to minor things like random changing between the standard TNG uniforms, this movie had a "wild" things going on. However, with all the shortcomings of this movie, after recently re-watching this film I've had a change of heart about my attitude towards this film. The good sides of this movie: STG is still a good, quality Star Trek film. The camera work, set design, costumes, and the works were all done with superb quality. After having watched most of TNG over recently, I've come to appreciate the nice budget this film got. The CGI, for the most part, is great. The shots of the Enterprise D were fantastic and a huge step up from the TV show models, from the flying through space to the destruction of the ship. In HD, this movie really pops for being almost 20 years old already. Although some find Data's behavior over the top in this film, I found it hilarious and if you are truly a TNG fan you will enjoy Brent Spiner's performance. We even get to see Spot, Data's cat again! Lastly, although I'm not a fan of the story, the villain is great and the concept behind "the nexus" is intriguing. Now for the bad sides of this film: the rest of the storyline! Simply put, STG has too much going on at once. They tried to cram too many things into this movie, making it a loyal TNG film while honoring Captain Kirk's history. The main thing that hurts this film and made many fans including myself dislike it, was the death of Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk's character was forced into this film. I found it completely unnecessary to ever make Picard and Kirk ever meet face-to-face in the first place. And the way William Shatner's Captain Kirk was killed off; I have and always will find it insulting and just plain bad for such a legendary TV icon. Although the story was interesting, in the end, TNG could have had a great start on the big screen without the "passing of the torch" from Kirk to Picard. The way "The Undiscovered Country" left off was perfect. Kirk has his last voyage in Enterprise and that was it. Instead they forcibly brought him back in this film as an excuse to involve him with TNG's storyline. In conclusion "Star Trek Generations" is a decent Star Trek film. If you can get past the mixed timelines/story and enjoy the good sides of this film, it is still an enjoyable movie with some hidden surprises. With that being said, though, this movie at heart is a TNG film. If you're not a TNG fan, you're going to hate this film. I also don't thing this is a good Star Trek film for the general audience. Unless you're a Star Trek fan, you probably won't "get" this movie. Of the TNG franchise, I still thing the best of the bunch is "First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Davyd Teather
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star trek generations is one of the most underrated star trek films if not one of the most underrated films in general. The mix of the original star trek characters with the next generation cast was amazing. This film starts off with three of the original star trek characters, James t. Kirk, Scotty and Chekov boarding the enterprise b. Just after the ship leaves spacedock, they get a distress call from a couple of spacecrafts caught on an energy ribbon and the enterprise b is the only ship in range. However it is not ready with a medical crew, tractor beam or weapons. They they close to the energy ribbon or the nexus as it is also called and rescue as many people from the spacecraft that they can and then use the deflector to break free from the energy ribbon. After they break free scotty tries to contact kirk but gets no response. He, and to other crew members go to the deck the deck to find him but find a chunk of the ship is missing and they believe he is dead. Then it fast forwards 78 years into the future showing the next generation cast. They are up against a mad man who is obsessed about getting back to the nexus, a place where time has no meaning, by destroying stars in order to change its course so he can get back into it. It is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Should Have Ended It After The Last One
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek Generations *1/2 (out of 4) 113 mins/ PG Cast: Patrick Stewart, Jonathan Frakes, Brent Spiner, LeVar Burton, Michael Dorn, Gates McFadden, Marina Sirtis, William Shatner, James Doohan, Whoopi Goldberg, Walter Koenig, Malcolm McDowell, Alan Ruck Director: David Carson Plot: Captain Picard must team up with Captain Kirk to stop a crazy scientist from destroying a whole planetary system in order to enter a world of happiness. JJ's Verdict: Many believe that Star Trek V: The Final Frontier is the worst of the series. I however, believe that Star Trek Generations is the worst of the series. After the success of Star Trek VI, Paramount must have been wondering what to do with what has at that point, become a great franchise. Of course, bring in a new cast and start again with Star Trek. Now this would have been fine, had they decided that some people (actually quite a lot of people) had never seen The Next Generation TV series and so needed a nice and easy to understand introduction to the characters. However, they didn't bother to introduce us to any of the characters or their backgrounds, or their relationships with other characters, or even their names until about half way through (and still you're struggling to remember who is who). Further on in the film, they want you to feel emotional towards these characters, but you can't because, as the viewer, you have no connection with them. This new crew and ship, set in the 24th century, while not a bad bunch of characters, do not capture the magic of the original crew and considering they had been on a TV show for 7 years, their chemistry is extremely poor and lacklustre. Now to the actual plot.... Kirk is guest of honour on the maiden voyage of the Enterprise B. But when a mysterious energy ribbon forces the Enterprise to save the ship's passengers, it comes at a cost: the death of Captain Kirk. Meanwhile, eighty years into the future, Captain Picard of the Enterprise D is up against evil scientist Soran, who is destroying planets so that he can reach Nexus, a mind matrix of happiness. Needing help, Picard somehow finds Kirk in the Nexus and the two team up to defeat Soran. Although the film is marketed as a battle involving captains from past and future, Shatner's role in the film is nothing more than a glorified cameo and you end up wondering whether Picard actually needs Kirk. Their scenes, although fun and full of references that Trekkies will love, are extremely silly and unnecessarily boring and slow. Throughout the film, threatening situations appear out of nowhere and while the action pieces are well set-up they are confusingly executed. Many other things are confusing and unexplained like how Picard gets out of the Nexus and it never tells the viewer how much time travel actually happens in this film. The only positives in this horrendous film are the short appearances of James Doohan and Walter Koenig as their original crew characters and the performances of British actors Patrick Stewart and Malcolm McDowell as Picard and Soran. Stewart has such a commanding presence on screen and the way he deals with emotional stress with his ageing self is superior to Shatner's in past instalments. Malcolm McDowell, most famous for playing a psychopath in Stanley Kubrick's ultra violent A Clockwork Orange, is both freaky and frightening in a very good performance. With three screen icons in its cast, it seems ridiculous that Star Trek Generations could be anything but good. Of course, it doesn't work that way in the film industry and even actors as good as Shatner, Stewart and McDowell can't stop this series 7th instalment from being a downright failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ultimate Star Trek movie. Kirk and Piccard are the best st duo ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokuguys
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie mainly because Its Kirk and Picard the two best st captains who ever lived. therefore it is the best st movie of all time. I was surprised of how high the quality of this movie was. i'm sure allot of people think of it as two old geezers fooling around in a crappy license movie but this was quite the contrary. i almost lost track of time, i was so absorbed in how amazing the movie was. It just wasn't the fact that the two of them were together at last. The acting of Bret spinner was incredible as well. For those of you who haven't seen it yet you are in for a treat(i don't want to oversell but you are going to love this film!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rough around the edges but it does the job, I suppose - 68%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the original TV crew dispatched, it was time to hand over the baton to the next phase in the franchise - the Next Generation. As this was the version of Star Trek I grew up watching, I was eagerly anticipating their first big screen outing and at the time, I wasn't disappointed. But as is often the way, watching it again today reminded me of several faults I'd overlooked before. A weak plot and villain, dialogue that would make George Lucas cringe and some pretty shoddy direction undermines a film with surprisingly good performances and effects that do justice to Gene Roddenbury's original vision. On the maiden voyage of the new Enterprise B, the inexperienced crew are forced to rescue two ships breaking up in some weird space ribbon. One of those rescued is a man named Soran (Malcolm McDowell) who is desperate to return to his exploding vessel. However, the Enterprise herself is badly damaged and the guest of honour, the retired Captain Kirk (William Shatner), is sadly sucked out into space. Seventy-eight years later and the current Enterprise, helmed by Jean-Luc Picard (Patrick Stewart) and the rest of the Next Gen gang, encounters the same ribbon as they rescue Soran again from a Federation space station. But this is no ordinary energy ribbon (like, are there many others and what are they like then?) - the Nexus is a portal to another realm where time stands still and every whim is made real. In his desperation to return to the Nexus, Soran is prepared to commit murder on a galactic scale and Picard finds himself in need of another Starfleet captain in order to stop him... "Star Trek: Generations" has no lack of ambition in terms of story but execution is found wanting. Take the climatic battle between Picard and Soran on a rickety metal bridge that appear to be held in place with a couple of badly rusted nails - imagine a huge crystal chandelier held up by a safety pin and you get the idea. I know this is Trek and thus, eminently theatrical (much like Star Wars, of course) but Trek was always more about the characters spouting pseudo-scientific garbage than firing phasers and fisticuffs. To that end, we have Data (Brent Spiner) and his Emotion Chip overloading his positronic network or something which provides director David Carson with a handy sub-plot. But he gets it wrong - an android suddenly developing emotions could have provided us with moments of humour or "Blade Runner"-style philosophy but instead, we get Data going haywire for a bit and from that point on, he is reduced to comic sidekick. Not good. It's not a complete bust - the film looks OK although there isn't much to touch the zero gravity sequence from its predecessor "Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country" and the leads all perform well. Stewart and McDowell are actually a pretty good contrast - Picard's usually unflappable manner verses Soran's wide-eyed fanatic. The same cannot be said for the rest of the cast - perhaps with so much going on, they forgot to include any scenes of substance with Worf (Michael Dorn) or Doctor Crusher (Gates McFadden). Hell, even Guinan (Whoopi Goldberg) has more to do than those two. As a film, it's uneven - it's certainly entertaining in a not-really-sci-fi kinda way but fans expecting anything as dramatic as "Star Trek II: The Wrath Of Khan" would be advised to seek their thrills elsewhere. But then, there's that unwritten rule that odd-numbered Star Trek films are no match for even-numbered films and technically, this is Star Trek VII - for me, if you're wanting a better Next Gen film then you should check out "Star Trek: First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Commendably Thoughtful / Viciously Boring / Superfluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to agree with those who are of the opinion that the Original Series Star Trek crew did not need to appear in this film. They had already had their send off, and a very fine one at that, in The Undiscovered Country. There was no need for their presence to be stretched out into Generations. That applies to Kirk more than to anyone else, of course. But here, he gets to take his final bow, of sorts. It could have been done better. At the same time, it could be argued that the Next Generation crew did not need to be in this film, either. It doesn't really do much to meaningfully develop them beyond what had already been done in their seven seasons on television. The subsequent film, First Contact, probably should have served as the lone Next Generation big screen-adventure. In any event, Generations is not a horrible film, but in practice it is a bit of a drag to watch, like one of those books that are hard to read without falling asleep. Some will argue that it is superfluous, and most would probably agree that it is exceedingly slow and frankly boring in spite of its decent screenplay and somewhat fresh plot. Speaking of which, the overall story (beyond the obvious 'Kirk meets Piccard, passes baton' gimmick) looks fairly cool on paper. A ribbon of energy writhing through space, which happens to be a portal to a hallucinogenic other-dimension called the Nexus, where time has no meaning? All right. Malcolm McDowell's Dr. Soren, a member of a long-lived species who has been trying to get back into the Nexus for decades, who collaborates with rogue Klingons, and who is willing to destroy an entire populated planet in the service of his obsession? Sure. A sequence in which the USS Enterprise-D suffers a warp-core breach, forcing the crew to evacuate to the saucer section, which then crashes into the forests of the planet below? Why not  that sounds exciting. Nothing like blowing up the Enterprise to create a spectacle. As mentioned before, however, it all unfolds at an excessively leisurely pace that challenges the attention span of all but the most dedicated of viewers, and neither Enterprise crew (the 'B' crew at the beginning, featuring the old guys, or the 'D' Next Generation crew) really gets much out of it in terms of character development. I do however have to note Jacqueline Kim's brief but excellent performance as Ensign Demora Sulu, i.e. Hikaru Sulu's grown-up daughter. She looks like a terrific captain in the making as she holds the helm in the opening sequence, and frankly I would rather watch a film about her than what the rest of Generations turns out to be. Two specific things dog all of the Next Generation-era films, and they both rear their heads here. The first and arguably the most annoying is the overestimation of Data's fascination quotient. Every single one of the four Next Generation films feels compelled to put significant focus on his character, and with the exception of First Contact, it all feels gratuitous to me. Yes, his search for humanity is interesting. But not this interesting, and his adventures in humor here are more obnoxious than charming (or actually funny). Instead of fixating on Data, I wish that a more involved role would have been written for Dr. Crusher, who I feel to have been neglected more than any other major crew member. The other issue is the hard truth that the Next Generation's tone and aesthetic sensibilities, while well-suited for television, are simply not big-screen cinematic, particularly in comparison to the Original Series elements with which they share screen time in Generations. The uniforms especially could have benefited from a more sophisticated re-design. The common criticism that Next Generation films are more like glorified television episodes is not entirely unwarranted, although to be fair, Generations does have some very nice sequences. Is this the worst Star Trek film? Goodness, no. It might not even be the worst Next Generation-era film, when you consider the respective issues present in Insurrection and Nemesis. If being boring is a crime, then both Insurrection and The Motion Picture have no doubt shared a cell with Generations. Ultimately, this is a decent film, but probably only of much interest to Star Trek enthusiasts, and even then more as a curiosity than anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely poor dialogue, NOT redeemed in any way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To illustrate the horrible-ness of the film to the best, Star Trek: Generations is to the original crew films as to what Star Wars: The Phantom Menace is to the original Star Wars trilogy. Horrible! Whilst perhaps not as horrible as The Phantom Menace and the two horrid sequels that followed, Star Trek Generations gets plenty wrong for what is yet another perfect illustration of a horrible Star Trek film and perfectly justifies the statement that all Star Trek films with an odd number are poor, with the exception of The Search for Spock. Following the presumed death of Captain James T. Kirk, over 70 years later, The Enterprise has fallen into the hands of Captain Picard who deals with family strains whilst a new threat is under way. A surviver of an accident, that isn't carefully explained nor dealt with, has begun his attack on a star that when destroyed, will somehow give way to be able to visit the Nexus, which is a dream like world that presents the best and the happiest moments to anyone and everyone. The film suffers on almost every single aspect. The story is poor, but it goes even beyond this. It's not just a poor story and poor writing, but the story leaves no impact on us, as we have no idea who these new characters are. Much like how the original crew were first presented in Star Trek: The Motion Picture, the characters here are presented extremely ridiculously and annoyingly, the greatest of them being Data, who could have come off as an interesting android for the remainder of this franchise but is literally depicted as Jar Jar Binks. Now, it is clearly evident where George Lucas got his influence from. See, Spock was a fatherly figure and a wise man and was an interesting and likable character. Data is supposed to be a similar character but here is presented in the most horrid manner much like how we were apparently supposed to view Jar Jar as a Yoda type character. Such event is referred to as deliberately taking a sh*t on one's head! Data is annoying and is horrible jokes about an emotion chip and how he is suddenly able to understand jokes that were told years ago is not funny, its downright ridiculous. And not in a good way like in Monty Python and the Holy Grail. This character should've been presented far better and horrible writing is clearly evident here. Not only is Data poorly written, so is Picard who throughout the film deals with such family issues, having recently received the news that his family has died. Two things make this completely a forgettable and unnecessary sub plot to the film: This is the first time we even know who Picard is. There is obviously no reference in the original series due to the fact that this takes place over 70 years later. And secondly, the story about his family is hardly elaborated in anyway whatsoever and is instead, thrown in from the air and just left in a steady place. More poor writing is evident here. Each character is poorly written, to the fullest. The villain in the film, played by Malcolm McDowell, is yet again, another one of the many examples of poor writing in the film. His plan and his plot in the film is quickly summed up and almost never really referred to. Had he been written well, Soran could be a similar villain to Khan from the great 'Wrath of Khan'. Apparently in the film, Soran deals with personal issues of his own. MaybeThis character is hardly explained, due to horrible writing and has quite a silly and ridiculous plot. Whereas Star Trek 5 was ridiculous, it was not to this extent. The villain had a purpose that seemed more legit than here. Special effects are the same as all Star Trek films. Not great but decent enough for a pass. The acting is good, I would possibly say. Patrick Stewart as Picard is a great choice as is Malcolm McDowell as Soran but both are utterly wasted in this film. Returning is William Shatner, early on in the film as Captain James T. Kirk, in the best proportion of the film and returning late in the film in an extremely ridiculous concept. The best part of the film is the opening proportion as it cleverly resembles a good Star Trek film dealing with Kirk's desperation to get back into the captain's chair. Everything after this, is downhill ***SPOILERS*** The film suffers a lot in every way possible but here is when it is clearly evident that this is a truly horrible film. Our main character, James T Kirk, who has been loved by all is killed at the very end of the film in the most ridiculous and one of the most anticlimactic deaths to one of the great heroes. He dies and this scene shares no emotion like good Trek films do. When your main character, that you've loved so long, is killed and you laugh, that there is the perfect example of poor writing. ***END OF SPOILERS*** Star Trek: Generations, is in my opinion, the second worst film of the franchise, winning the silver medal with a gold going to the first Star Trek film. This film pretty much ensures that all odd numbered Star Trek films are terrible, with one small exception. Badly written, with a lame story and undeveloped characters, due to poor writing, Star Trek Generations is an utter failure. To imagine this movie, it is the Phantom Menace of Star Trek. To illustrate, prior to the making of the film, the director realized it was the 7th instalment and that it had to be horrible, and so asked for some horrible writing and extremely poor character development This film is a complete failure in every aspect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cast is Strong But The Plot Wears Thin,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek: Generations is a good movie with a storyline that dosen't really go anywhere for a very long time but a very inspired cast like there always is in Star Trek.It definitely wasn't a fantastic start for the Next Generation crew,it being their first movie,but I don't think its as bad as most people make it out to be,I don't think its the worst Star Trek but its certainly not the best,these movies are sometimes outstanding (The Wrath of Khan) and other times awful (The Final Frontier),I would put this right in the middle.The plot was sometimes very frustrating because it just didn't know were it was going for such a long time,but the impressive cast made it bearable,I really enjoyed Malcolm McDowell as the villain,he always delivers very creepy performances and he fit perfectly into the Star Trek universe.I didn't really appreciate William Shatner's performance,it all felt very forced and I think this movie would have been better off just focusing on the Next Generation crew instead of bringing in members from the original series.Fans of Star Trek:The Next Generation will definitely be disappointed,but will still appreciate the casts strong performances. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) disappears on a mission,seven decades later,Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) encounters similar peril and only the two captains can save the Enterprise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some fun to be had but not as momentous as it needs to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The seventh film in the series passes the torch to the crew of 'The Next Generation' with mixed results. A strong story was required to celebrate the meeting of Captains Kirk and Picard, but the plot is frustratingly underdeveloped and trundles towards a fizzling finale. It's a shame, too, that Leonard Nimoy and DeForest Kelley declined to appear. But there is excitement and humour along the way, plenty of thoughtful dialogue, an excellent performance from Patrick Stewart, and William Shatner seems to be having fun in his farewell performance, practically winking at the camera at times. The 'Trek' films are so middling that this isn't really any worse than the previous six (it's better than some); all the same, it carries with it the feeling that such a key chapter in 'Trek' history should have had more meat on its bones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and Confusing but with a couple of redeeming qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjkelley333
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I shouldn't be reviewing this film. I haven't seen Star Trek: The Next Generation. A lot of what I say here may be said out of ignorance. Well, who cares, I'll review it anyway. The film starts out with the christening of another starship U. S. S. Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk is on board for the ride. The ship comes across an energy phenomenon, which damages their ship. Kirk goes down to the core (or whatever you call that part of a starship) and fixes their problem. However, the room he is in is taken away by the energy, and he is declared dead. 78 years later, the current crew of the Enterprise, headed by Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) is summoned by Star Fleet to check out a damaged space station. There they discover Soran (Malcolm McDowell, A Clockwork Orange), an engineer whose home planet had been destroyed by the energy field at the beginning of the film. Soran attacks some crew members, and then travels to a planet where that energy field is headed. Captain Picard then learns that the energy field is called the Nexus, a space matrix that brings to life your heart's desire. However, it destroys everything in its path, and Soran is willing to commit murder to get back in the Nexus. There are two things I really like about this movie. One is the Nexus. It really is an interesting idea. A phenomenon that brings your dream to life is a fascinating idea, and actually quite thought- provoking. The other part I enjoy is Malcolm McDowell's performance. McDowell feels evil, psychotic, and brilliant. But hey, it's not like he hasn't played a psychopath before. However, there are many things I don't enjoy. There are pointless subplots that for the most part go nowhere. The most prominent subplot involves Data (Brent Spiner), a robot who resembles a human. He has a chip installed in himself that causes human emotion. His emotions are discussed throughout the film, but it doesn't go anywhere and is distracting. This brings up another question- how did they put feelings on an electronic chip? Another subplot centers around Picard. Some family members of his have recently died in a fire. He is shown mourning them. Later, he is in the Nexus, and he sees them alive again. This subplot never goes anywhere. The trailer and the posters for this film give the impressions that Kirk plays a large role in this film. However, he disappears in the beginning and doesn't reappear until the final half hour. Picard finds him in the Nexus, at his old home. At first Kirk says that he won't return to Star Fleet, but for some reason suddenly changes his mind. Yet another flaw of this film is Soran's plan. He is willing to commit murder and destroy planets to get to the Nexus. But he knows where it's headed. Why couldn't he just fly to it? But my biggest problem is this- it's SO BORING. That's all I can say- it's so dull. I really didn't care what was going on. And this is coming from someone who liked Star Trek: The Motion Picture. This film had a good villain and some fascinating ideas, but the slowness and subplots really brought it down. C
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed bag of goods for Star Trek fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sedativchunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen "Star Trek Generations" (STG) hundreds of times being a huge Star Trek fan. Recently I've watched it again from beginning to end in HD. Having watched watched pretty much every episode of all the Star Trek TV shows and all of the movies (including the newest "Into Darkness"), I felt the need to write a new, updated review for my take on this film. For many years, I hated this film as most other Star Trek fans have over the years. There many bad things about this movie. From the storyline to minor things like random changing between the standard TNG uniforms, this movie had a "wild" things going on. However, with all the shortcomings of this movie, after recently re-watching this film I've had a change of heart about my attitude towards this film. The good sides of this movie: STG is still a good, quality Star Trek film. The camera work, set design, costumes, and the works were all done with superb quality. After having watched most of TNG over recently, I've come to appreciate the nice budget this film got. The CGI, for the most part, is great. The shots of the Enterprise D were fantastic and a huge step up from the TV show models, from the flying through space to the destruction of the ship. In HD, this movie really pops for being almost 20 years old already. Although some find Data's behavior over the top in this film, I found it hilarious and if you are truly a TNG fan you will enjoy Brent Spiner's performance. We even get to see Spot, Data's cat again! Lastly, although I'm not a fan of the story, the villain is great and the concept behind "the nexus" is intriguing. Now for the bad sides of this film: the rest of the storyline! Simply put, STG has too much going on at once. They tried to cram too many things into this movie, making it a loyal TNG film while honoring Captain Kirk's history. The main thing that hurts this film and made many fans including myself dislike it, was the death of Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk's character was forced into this film. I found it completely unnecessary to ever make Picard and Kirk ever meet face-to-face in the first place. And the way William Shatner's Captain Kirk was killed off; I have and always will find it insulting and just plain bad for such a legendary TV icon. Although the story was interesting, in the end, TNG could have had a great start on the big screen without the "passing of the torch" from Kirk to Picard. The way "The Undiscovered Country" left off was perfect. Kirk has his last voyage in Enterprise and that was it. Instead they forcibly brought him back in this film as an excuse to involve him with TNG's storyline. In conclusion "Star Trek Generations" is a decent Star Trek film. If you can get past the mixed timelines/story and enjoy the good sides of this film, it is still an enjoyable movie with some hidden surprises. With that being said, though, this movie at heart is a TNG film. If you're not a TNG fan, you're going to hate this film. I also don't thing this is a good Star Trek film for the general audience. Unless you're a Star Trek fan, you probably won't "get" this movie. Of the TNG franchise, I still thing the best of the bunch is "First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Davyd Teather
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star trek generations is one of the most underrated star trek films if not one of the most underrated films in general. The mix of the original star trek characters with the next generation cast was amazing. This film starts off with three of the original star trek characters, James t. Kirk, Scotty and Chekov boarding the enterprise b. Just after the ship leaves spacedock, they get a distress call from a couple of spacecrafts caught on an energy ribbon and the enterprise b is the only ship in range. However it is not ready with a medical crew, tractor beam or weapons. They they close to the energy ribbon or the nexus as it is also called and rescue as many people from the spacecraft that they can and then use the deflector to break free from the energy ribbon. After they break free scotty tries to contact kirk but gets no response. He, and to other crew members go to the deck the deck to find him but find a chunk of the ship is missing and they believe he is dead. Then it fast forwards 78 years into the future showing the next generation cast. They are up against a mad man who is obsessed about getting back to the nexus, a place where time has no meaning, by destroying stars in order to change its course so he can get back into it. It is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Should Have Ended It After The Last One
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek Generations *1/2 (out of 4) 113 mins/ PG Cast: Patrick Stewart, Jonathan Frakes, Brent Spiner, LeVar Burton, Michael Dorn, Gates McFadden, Marina Sirtis, William Shatner, James Doohan, Whoopi Goldberg, Walter Koenig, Malcolm McDowell, Alan Ruck Director: David Carson Plot: Captain Picard must team up with Captain Kirk to stop a crazy scientist from destroying a whole planetary system in order to enter a world of happiness. JJ's Verdict: Many believe that Star Trek V: The Final Frontier is the worst of the series. I however, believe that Star Trek Generations is the worst of the series. After the success of Star Trek VI, Paramount must have been wondering what to do with what has at that point, become a great franchise. Of course, bring in a new cast and start again with Star Trek. Now this would have been fine, had they decided that some people (actually quite a lot of people) had never seen The Next Generation TV series and so needed a nice and easy to understand introduction to the characters. However, they didn't bother to introduce us to any of the characters or their backgrounds, or their relationships with other characters, or even their names until about half way through (and still you're struggling to remember who is who). Further on in the film, they want you to feel emotional towards these characters, but you can't because, as the viewer, you have no connection with them. This new crew and ship, set in the 24th century, while not a bad bunch of characters, do not capture the magic of the original crew and considering they had been on a TV show for 7 years, their chemistry is extremely poor and lacklustre. Now to the actual plot.... Kirk is guest of honour on the maiden voyage of the Enterprise B. But when a mysterious energy ribbon forces the Enterprise to save the ship's passengers, it comes at a cost: the death of Captain Kirk. Meanwhile, eighty years into the future, Captain Picard of the Enterprise D is up against evil scientist Soran, who is destroying planets so that he can reach Nexus, a mind matrix of happiness. Needing help, Picard somehow finds Kirk in the Nexus and the two team up to defeat Soran. Although the film is marketed as a battle involving captains from past and future, Shatner's role in the film is nothing more than a glorified cameo and you end up wondering whether Picard actually needs Kirk. Their scenes, although fun and full of references that Trekkies will love, are extremely silly and unnecessarily boring and slow. Throughout the film, threatening situations appear out of nowhere and while the action pieces are well set-up they are confusingly executed. Many other things are confusing and unexplained like how Picard gets out of the Nexus and it never tells the viewer how much time travel actually happens in this film. The only positives in this horrendous film are the short appearances of James Doohan and Walter Koenig as their original crew characters and the performances of British actors Patrick Stewart and Malcolm McDowell as Picard and Soran. Stewart has such a commanding presence on screen and the way he deals with emotional stress with his ageing self is superior to Shatner's in past instalments. Malcolm McDowell, most famous for playing a psychopath in Stanley Kubrick's ultra violent A Clockwork Orange, is both freaky and frightening in a very good performance. With three screen icons in its cast, it seems ridiculous that Star Trek Generations could be anything but good. Of course, it doesn't work that way in the film industry and even actors as good as Shatner, Stewart and McDowell can't stop this series 7th instalment from being a downright failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ultimate Star Trek movie. Kirk and Piccard are the best st duo ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokuguys
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie mainly because Its Kirk and Picard the two best st captains who ever lived. therefore it is the best st movie of all time. I was surprised of how high the quality of this movie was. i'm sure allot of people think of it as two old geezers fooling around in a crappy license movie but this was quite the contrary. i almost lost track of time, i was so absorbed in how amazing the movie was. It just wasn't the fact that the two of them were together at last. The acting of Bret spinner was incredible as well. For those of you who haven't seen it yet you are in for a treat(i don't want to oversell but you are going to love this film!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rough around the edges but it does the job, I suppose - 68%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the original TV crew dispatched, it was time to hand over the baton to the next phase in the franchise - the Next Generation. As this was the version of Star Trek I grew up watching, I was eagerly anticipating their first big screen outing and at the time, I wasn't disappointed. But as is often the way, watching it again today reminded me of several faults I'd overlooked before. A weak plot and villain, dialogue that would make George Lucas cringe and some pretty shoddy direction undermines a film with surprisingly good performances and effects that do justice to Gene Roddenbury's original vision. On the maiden voyage of the new Enterprise B, the inexperienced crew are forced to rescue two ships breaking up in some weird space ribbon. One of those rescued is a man named Soran (Malcolm McDowell) who is desperate to return to his exploding vessel. However, the Enterprise herself is badly damaged and the guest of honour, the retired Captain Kirk (William Shatner), is sadly sucked out into space. Seventy-eight years later and the current Enterprise, helmed by Jean-Luc Picard (Patrick Stewart) and the rest of the Next Gen gang, encounters the same ribbon as they rescue Soran again from a Federation space station. But this is no ordinary energy ribbon (like, are there many others and what are they like then?) - the Nexus is a portal to another realm where time stands still and every whim is made real. In his desperation to return to the Nexus, Soran is prepared to commit murder on a galactic scale and Picard finds himself in need of another Starfleet captain in order to stop him... "Star Trek: Generations" has no lack of ambition in terms of story but execution is found wanting. Take the climatic battle between Picard and Soran on a rickety metal bridge that appear to be held in place with a couple of badly rusted nails - imagine a huge crystal chandelier held up by a safety pin and you get the idea. I know this is Trek and thus, eminently theatrical (much like Star Wars, of course) but Trek was always more about the characters spouting pseudo-scientific garbage than firing phasers and fisticuffs. To that end, we have Data (Brent Spiner) and his Emotion Chip overloading his positronic network or something which provides director David Carson with a handy sub-plot. But he gets it wrong - an android suddenly developing emotions could have provided us with moments of humour or "Blade Runner"-style philosophy but instead, we get Data going haywire for a bit and from that point on, he is reduced to comic sidekick. Not good. It's not a complete bust - the film looks OK although there isn't much to touch the zero gravity sequence from its predecessor "Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country" and the leads all perform well. Stewart and McDowell are actually a pretty good contrast - Picard's usually unflappable manner verses Soran's wide-eyed fanatic. The same cannot be said for the rest of the cast - perhaps with so much going on, they forgot to include any scenes of substance with Worf (Michael Dorn) or Doctor Crusher (Gates McFadden). Hell, even Guinan (Whoopi Goldberg) has more to do than those two. As a film, it's uneven - it's certainly entertaining in a not-really-sci-fi kinda way but fans expecting anything as dramatic as "Star Trek II: The Wrath Of Khan" would be advised to seek their thrills elsewhere. But then, there's that unwritten rule that odd-numbered Star Trek films are no match for even-numbered films and technically, this is Star Trek VII - for me, if you're wanting a better Next Gen film then you should check out "Star Trek: First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Commendably Thoughtful / Viciously Boring / Superfluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to agree with those who are of the opinion that the Original Series Star Trek crew did not need to appear in this film. They had already had their send off, and a very fine one at that, in The Undiscovered Country. There was no need for their presence to be stretched out into Generations. That applies to Kirk more than to anyone else, of course. But here, he gets to take his final bow, of sorts. It could have been done better. At the same time, it could be argued that the Next Generation crew did not need to be in this film, either. It doesn't really do much to meaningfully develop them beyond what had already been done in their seven seasons on television. The subsequent film, First Contact, probably should have served as the lone Next Generation big screen-adventure. In any event, Generations is not a horrible film, but in practice it is a bit of a drag to watch, like one of those books that are hard to read without falling asleep. Some will argue that it is superfluous, and most would probably agree that it is exceedingly slow and frankly boring in spite of its decent screenplay and somewhat fresh plot. Speaking of which, the overall story (beyond the obvious 'Kirk meets Piccard, passes baton' gimmick) looks fairly cool on paper. A ribbon of energy writhing through space, which happens to be a portal to a hallucinogenic other-dimension called the Nexus, where time has no meaning? All right. Malcolm McDowell's Dr. Soren, a member of a long-lived species who has been trying to get back into the Nexus for decades, who collaborates with rogue Klingons, and who is willing to destroy an entire populated planet in the service of his obsession? Sure. A sequence in which the USS Enterprise-D suffers a warp-core breach, forcing the crew to evacuate to the saucer section, which then crashes into the forests of the planet below? Why not  that sounds exciting. Nothing like blowing up the Enterprise to create a spectacle. As mentioned before, however, it all unfolds at an excessively leisurely pace that challenges the attention span of all but the most dedicated of viewers, and neither Enterprise crew (the 'B' crew at the beginning, featuring the old guys, or the 'D' Next Generation crew) really gets much out of it in terms of character development. I do however have to note Jacqueline Kim's brief but excellent performance as Ensign Demora Sulu, i.e. Hikaru Sulu's grown-up daughter. She looks like a terrific captain in the making as she holds the helm in the opening sequence, and frankly I would rather watch a film about her than what the rest of Generations turns out to be. Two specific things dog all of the Next Generation-era films, and they both rear their heads here. The first and arguably the most annoying is the overestimation of Data's fascination quotient. Every single one of the four Next Generation films feels compelled to put significant focus on his character, and with the exception of First Contact, it all feels gratuitous to me. Yes, his search for humanity is interesting. But not this interesting, and his adventures in humor here are more obnoxious than charming (or actually funny). Instead of fixating on Data, I wish that a more involved role would have been written for Dr. Crusher, who I feel to have been neglected more than any other major crew member. The other issue is the hard truth that the Next Generation's tone and aesthetic sensibilities, while well-suited for television, are simply not big-screen cinematic, particularly in comparison to the Original Series elements with which they share screen time in Generations. The uniforms especially could have benefited from a more sophisticated re-design. The common criticism that Next Generation films are more like glorified television episodes is not entirely unwarranted, although to be fair, Generations does have some very nice sequences. Is this the worst Star Trek film? Goodness, no. It might not even be the worst Next Generation-era film, when you consider the respective issues present in Insurrection and Nemesis. If being boring is a crime, then both Insurrection and The Motion Picture have no doubt shared a cell with Generations. Ultimately, this is a decent film, but probably only of much interest to Star Trek enthusiasts, and even then more as a curiosity than anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely poor dialogue, NOT redeemed in any way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To illustrate the horrible-ness of the film to the best, Star Trek: Generations is to the original crew films as to what Star Wars: The Phantom Menace is to the original Star Wars trilogy. Horrible! Whilst perhaps not as horrible as The Phantom Menace and the two horrid sequels that followed, Star Trek Generations gets plenty wrong for what is yet another perfect illustration of a horrible Star Trek film and perfectly justifies the statement that all Star Trek films with an odd number are poor, with the exception of The Search for Spock. Following the presumed death of Captain James T. Kirk, over 70 years later, The Enterprise has fallen into the hands of Captain Picard who deals with family strains whilst a new threat is under way. A surviver of an accident, that isn't carefully explained nor dealt with, has begun his attack on a star that when destroyed, will somehow give way to be able to visit the Nexus, which is a dream like world that presents the best and the happiest moments to anyone and everyone. The film suffers on almost every single aspect. The story is poor, but it goes even beyond this. It's not just a poor story and poor writing, but the story leaves no impact on us, as we have no idea who these new characters are. Much like how the original crew were first presented in Star Trek: The Motion Picture, the characters here are presented extremely ridiculously and annoyingly, the greatest of them being Data, who could have come off as an interesting android for the remainder of this franchise but is literally depicted as Jar Jar Binks. Now, it is clearly evident where George Lucas got his influence from. See, Spock was a fatherly figure and a wise man and was an interesting and likable character. Data is supposed to be a similar character but here is presented in the most horrid manner much like how we were apparently supposed to view Jar Jar as a Yoda type character. Such event is referred to as deliberately taking a sh*t on one's head! Data is annoying and is horrible jokes about an emotion chip and how he is suddenly able to understand jokes that were told years ago is not funny, its downright ridiculous. And not in a good way like in Monty Python and the Holy Grail. This character should've been presented far better and horrible writing is clearly evident here. Not only is Data poorly written, so is Picard who throughout the film deals with such family issues, having recently received the news that his family has died. Two things make this completely a forgettable and unnecessary sub plot to the film: This is the first time we even know who Picard is. There is obviously no reference in the original series due to the fact that this takes place over 70 years later. And secondly, the story about his family is hardly elaborated in anyway whatsoever and is instead, thrown in from the air and just left in a steady place. More poor writing is evident here. Each character is poorly written, to the fullest. The villain in the film, played by Malcolm McDowell, is yet again, another one of the many examples of poor writing in the film. His plan and his plot in the film is quickly summed up and almost never really referred to. Had he been written well, Soran could be a similar villain to Khan from the great 'Wrath of Khan'. Apparently in the film, Soran deals with personal issues of his own. MaybeThis character is hardly explained, due to horrible writing and has quite a silly and ridiculous plot. Whereas Star Trek 5 was ridiculous, it was not to this extent. The villain had a purpose that seemed more legit than here. Special effects are the same as all Star Trek films. Not great but decent enough for a pass. The acting is good, I would possibly say. Patrick Stewart as Picard is a great choice as is Malcolm McDowell as Soran but both are utterly wasted in this film. Returning is William Shatner, early on in the film as Captain James T. Kirk, in the best proportion of the film and returning late in the film in an extremely ridiculous concept. The best part of the film is the opening proportion as it cleverly resembles a good Star Trek film dealing with Kirk's desperation to get back into the captain's chair. Everything after this, is downhill ***SPOILERS*** The film suffers a lot in every way possible but here is when it is clearly evident that this is a truly horrible film. Our main character, James T Kirk, who has been loved by all is killed at the very end of the film in the most ridiculous and one of the most anticlimactic deaths to one of the great heroes. He dies and this scene shares no emotion like good Trek films do. When your main character, that you've loved so long, is killed and you laugh, that there is the perfect example of poor writing. ***END OF SPOILERS*** Star Trek: Generations, is in my opinion, the second worst film of the franchise, winning the silver medal with a gold going to the first Star Trek film. This film pretty much ensures that all odd numbered Star Trek films are terrible, with one small exception. Badly written, with a lame story and undeveloped characters, due to poor writing, Star Trek Generations is an utter failure. To imagine this movie, it is the Phantom Menace of Star Trek. To illustrate, prior to the making of the film, the director realized it was the 7th instalment and that it had to be horrible, and so asked for some horrible writing and extremely poor character development This film is a complete failure in every aspect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cast is Strong But The Plot Wears Thin,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek: Generations is a good movie with a storyline that dosen't really go anywhere for a very long time but a very inspired cast like there always is in Star Trek.It definitely wasn't a fantastic start for the Next Generation crew,it being their first movie,but I don't think its as bad as most people make it out to be,I don't think its the worst Star Trek but its certainly not the best,these movies are sometimes outstanding (The Wrath of Khan) and other times awful (The Final Frontier),I would put this right in the middle.The plot was sometimes very frustrating because it just didn't know were it was going for such a long time,but the impressive cast made it bearable,I really enjoyed Malcolm McDowell as the villain,he always delivers very creepy performances and he fit perfectly into the Star Trek universe.I didn't really appreciate William Shatner's performance,it all felt very forced and I think this movie would have been better off just focusing on the Next Generation crew instead of bringing in members from the original series.Fans of Star Trek:The Next Generation will definitely be disappointed,but will still appreciate the casts strong performances. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) disappears on a mission,seven decades later,Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) encounters similar peril and only the two captains can save the Enterprise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some fun to be had but not as momentous as it needs to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The seventh film in the series passes the torch to the crew of 'The Next Generation' with mixed results. A strong story was required to celebrate the meeting of Captains Kirk and Picard, but the plot is frustratingly underdeveloped and trundles towards a fizzling finale. It's a shame, too, that Leonard Nimoy and DeForest Kelley declined to appear. But there is excitement and humour along the way, plenty of thoughtful dialogue, an excellent performance from Patrick Stewart, and William Shatner seems to be having fun in his farewell performance, practically winking at the camera at times. The 'Trek' films are so middling that this isn't really any worse than the previous six (it's better than some); all the same, it carries with it the feeling that such a key chapter in 'Trek' history should have had more meat on its bones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boring and Confusing but with a couple of redeeming qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjkelley333
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I shouldn't be reviewing this film. I haven't seen Star Trek: The Next Generation. A lot of what I say here may be said out of ignorance. Well, who cares, I'll review it anyway. The film starts out with the christening of another starship U. S. S. Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk is on board for the ride. The ship comes across an energy phenomenon, which damages their ship. Kirk goes down to the core (or whatever you call that part of a starship) and fixes their problem. However, the room he is in is taken away by the energy, and he is declared dead. 78 years later, the current crew of the Enterprise, headed by Captain Picard (Patrick Stewart) is summoned by Star Fleet to check out a damaged space station. There they discover Soran (Malcolm McDowell, A Clockwork Orange), an engineer whose home planet had been destroyed by the energy field at the beginning of the film. Soran attacks some crew members, and then travels to a planet where that energy field is headed. Captain Picard then learns that the energy field is called the Nexus, a space matrix that brings to life your heart's desire. However, it destroys everything in its path, and Soran is willing to commit murder to get back in the Nexus. There are two things I really like about this movie. One is the Nexus. It really is an interesting idea. A phenomenon that brings your dream to life is a fascinating idea, and actually quite thought- provoking. The other part I enjoy is Malcolm McDowell's performance. McDowell feels evil, psychotic, and brilliant. But hey, it's not like he hasn't played a psychopath before. However, there are many things I don't enjoy. There are pointless subplots that for the most part go nowhere. The most prominent subplot involves Data (Brent Spiner), a robot who resembles a human. He has a chip installed in himself that causes human emotion. His emotions are discussed throughout the film, but it doesn't go anywhere and is distracting. This brings up another question- how did they put feelings on an electronic chip? Another subplot centers around Picard. Some family members of his have recently died in a fire. He is shown mourning them. Later, he is in the Nexus, and he sees them alive again. This subplot never goes anywhere. The trailer and the posters for this film give the impressions that Kirk plays a large role in this film. However, he disappears in the beginning and doesn't reappear until the final half hour. Picard finds him in the Nexus, at his old home. At first Kirk says that he won't return to Star Fleet, but for some reason suddenly changes his mind. Yet another flaw of this film is Soran's plan. He is willing to commit murder and destroy planets to get to the Nexus. But he knows where it's headed. Why couldn't he just fly to it? But my biggest problem is this- it's SO BORING. That's all I can say- it's so dull. I really didn't care what was going on. And this is coming from someone who liked Star Trek: The Motion Picture. This film had a good villain and some fascinating ideas, but the slowness and subplots really brought it down. C
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed bag of goods for Star Trek fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sedativchunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen "Star Trek Generations" (STG) hundreds of times being a huge Star Trek fan. Recently I've watched it again from beginning to end in HD. Having watched watched pretty much every episode of all the Star Trek TV shows and all of the movies (including the newest "Into Darkness"), I felt the need to write a new, updated review for my take on this film. For many years, I hated this film as most other Star Trek fans have over the years. There many bad things about this movie. From the storyline to minor things like random changing between the standard TNG uniforms, this movie had a "wild" things going on. However, with all the shortcomings of this movie, after recently re-watching this film I've had a change of heart about my attitude towards this film. The good sides of this movie: STG is still a good, quality Star Trek film. The camera work, set design, costumes, and the works were all done with superb quality. After having watched most of TNG over recently, I've come to appreciate the nice budget this film got. The CGI, for the most part, is great. The shots of the Enterprise D were fantastic and a huge step up from the TV show models, from the flying through space to the destruction of the ship. In HD, this movie really pops for being almost 20 years old already. Although some find Data's behavior over the top in this film, I found it hilarious and if you are truly a TNG fan you will enjoy Brent Spiner's performance. We even get to see Spot, Data's cat again! Lastly, although I'm not a fan of the story, the villain is great and the concept behind "the nexus" is intriguing. Now for the bad sides of this film: the rest of the storyline! Simply put, STG has too much going on at once. They tried to cram too many things into this movie, making it a loyal TNG film while honoring Captain Kirk's history. The main thing that hurts this film and made many fans including myself dislike it, was the death of Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk's character was forced into this film. I found it completely unnecessary to ever make Picard and Kirk ever meet face-to-face in the first place. And the way William Shatner's Captain Kirk was killed off; I have and always will find it insulting and just plain bad for such a legendary TV icon. Although the story was interesting, in the end, TNG could have had a great start on the big screen without the "passing of the torch" from Kirk to Picard. The way "The Undiscovered Country" left off was perfect. Kirk has his last voyage in Enterprise and that was it. Instead they forcibly brought him back in this film as an excuse to involve him with TNG's storyline. In conclusion "Star Trek Generations" is a decent Star Trek film. If you can get past the mixed timelines/story and enjoy the good sides of this film, it is still an enjoyable movie with some hidden surprises. With that being said, though, this movie at heart is a TNG film. If you're not a TNG fan, you're going to hate this film. I also don't thing this is a good Star Trek film for the general audience. Unless you're a Star Trek fan, you probably won't "get" this movie. Of the TNG franchise, I still thing the best of the bunch is "First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Davyd Teather
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star trek generations is one of the most underrated star trek films if not one of the most underrated films in general. The mix of the original star trek characters with the next generation cast was amazing. This film starts off with three of the original star trek characters, James t. Kirk, Scotty and Chekov boarding the enterprise b. Just after the ship leaves spacedock, they get a distress call from a couple of spacecrafts caught on an energy ribbon and the enterprise b is the only ship in range. However it is not ready with a medical crew, tractor beam or weapons. They they close to the energy ribbon or the nexus as it is also called and rescue as many people from the spacecraft that they can and then use the deflector to break free from the energy ribbon. After they break free scotty tries to contact kirk but gets no response. He, and to other crew members go to the deck the deck to find him but find a chunk of the ship is missing and they believe he is dead. Then it fast forwards 78 years into the future showing the next generation cast. They are up against a mad man who is obsessed about getting back to the nexus, a place where time has no meaning, by destroying stars in order to change its course so he can get back into it. It is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    They Should Have Ended It After The Last One
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek Generations *1/2 (out of 4) 113 mins/ PG Cast: Patrick Stewart, Jonathan Frakes, Brent Spiner, LeVar Burton, Michael Dorn, Gates McFadden, Marina Sirtis, William Shatner, James Doohan, Whoopi Goldberg, Walter Koenig, Malcolm McDowell, Alan Ruck Director: David Carson Plot: Captain Picard must team up with Captain Kirk to stop a crazy scientist from destroying a whole planetary system in order to enter a world of happiness. JJ's Verdict: Many believe that Star Trek V: The Final Frontier is the worst of the series. I however, believe that Star Trek Generations is the worst of the series. After the success of Star Trek VI, Paramount must have been wondering what to do with what has at that point, become a great franchise. Of course, bring in a new cast and start again with Star Trek. Now this would have been fine, had they decided that some people (actually quite a lot of people) had never seen The Next Generation TV series and so needed a nice and easy to understand introduction to the characters. However, they didn't bother to introduce us to any of the characters or their backgrounds, or their relationships with other characters, or even their names until about half way through (and still you're struggling to remember who is who). Further on in the film, they want you to feel emotional towards these characters, but you can't because, as the viewer, you have no connection with them. This new crew and ship, set in the 24th century, while not a bad bunch of characters, do not capture the magic of the original crew and considering they had been on a TV show for 7 years, their chemistry is extremely poor and lacklustre. Now to the actual plot.... Kirk is guest of honour on the maiden voyage of the Enterprise B. But when a mysterious energy ribbon forces the Enterprise to save the ship's passengers, it comes at a cost: the death of Captain Kirk. Meanwhile, eighty years into the future, Captain Picard of the Enterprise D is up against evil scientist Soran, who is destroying planets so that he can reach Nexus, a mind matrix of happiness. Needing help, Picard somehow finds Kirk in the Nexus and the two team up to defeat Soran. Although the film is marketed as a battle involving captains from past and future, Shatner's role in the film is nothing more than a glorified cameo and you end up wondering whether Picard actually needs Kirk. Their scenes, although fun and full of references that Trekkies will love, are extremely silly and unnecessarily boring and slow. Throughout the film, threatening situations appear out of nowhere and while the action pieces are well set-up they are confusingly executed. Many other things are confusing and unexplained like how Picard gets out of the Nexus and it never tells the viewer how much time travel actually happens in this film. The only positives in this horrendous film are the short appearances of James Doohan and Walter Koenig as their original crew characters and the performances of British actors Patrick Stewart and Malcolm McDowell as Picard and Soran. Stewart has such a commanding presence on screen and the way he deals with emotional stress with his ageing self is superior to Shatner's in past instalments. Malcolm McDowell, most famous for playing a psychopath in Stanley Kubrick's ultra violent A Clockwork Orange, is both freaky and frightening in a very good performance. With three screen icons in its cast, it seems ridiculous that Star Trek Generations could be anything but good. Of course, it doesn't work that way in the film industry and even actors as good as Shatner, Stewart and McDowell can't stop this series 7th instalment from being a downright failure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ultimate Star Trek movie. Kirk and Piccard are the best st duo ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gokuguys
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie mainly because Its Kirk and Picard the two best st captains who ever lived. therefore it is the best st movie of all time. I was surprised of how high the quality of this movie was. i'm sure allot of people think of it as two old geezers fooling around in a crappy license movie but this was quite the contrary. i almost lost track of time, i was so absorbed in how amazing the movie was. It just wasn't the fact that the two of them were together at last. The acting of Bret spinner was incredible as well. For those of you who haven't seen it yet you are in for a treat(i don't want to oversell but you are going to love this film!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rough around the edges but it does the job, I suppose - 68%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the original TV crew dispatched, it was time to hand over the baton to the next phase in the franchise - the Next Generation. As this was the version of Star Trek I grew up watching, I was eagerly anticipating their first big screen outing and at the time, I wasn't disappointed. But as is often the way, watching it again today reminded me of several faults I'd overlooked before. A weak plot and villain, dialogue that would make George Lucas cringe and some pretty shoddy direction undermines a film with surprisingly good performances and effects that do justice to Gene Roddenbury's original vision. On the maiden voyage of the new Enterprise B, the inexperienced crew are forced to rescue two ships breaking up in some weird space ribbon. One of those rescued is a man named Soran (Malcolm McDowell) who is desperate to return to his exploding vessel. However, the Enterprise herself is badly damaged and the guest of honour, the retired Captain Kirk (William Shatner), is sadly sucked out into space. Seventy-eight years later and the current Enterprise, helmed by Jean-Luc Picard (Patrick Stewart) and the rest of the Next Gen gang, encounters the same ribbon as they rescue Soran again from a Federation space station. But this is no ordinary energy ribbon (like, are there many others and what are they like then?) - the Nexus is a portal to another realm where time stands still and every whim is made real. In his desperation to return to the Nexus, Soran is prepared to commit murder on a galactic scale and Picard finds himself in need of another Starfleet captain in order to stop him... "Star Trek: Generations" has no lack of ambition in terms of story but execution is found wanting. Take the climatic battle between Picard and Soran on a rickety metal bridge that appear to be held in place with a couple of badly rusted nails - imagine a huge crystal chandelier held up by a safety pin and you get the idea. I know this is Trek and thus, eminently theatrical (much like Star Wars, of course) but Trek was always more about the characters spouting pseudo-scientific garbage than firing phasers and fisticuffs. To that end, we have Data (Brent Spiner) and his Emotion Chip overloading his positronic network or something which provides director David Carson with a handy sub-plot. But he gets it wrong - an android suddenly developing emotions could have provided us with moments of humour or "Blade Runner"-style philosophy but instead, we get Data going haywire for a bit and from that point on, he is reduced to comic sidekick. Not good. It's not a complete bust - the film looks OK although there isn't much to touch the zero gravity sequence from its predecessor "Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country" and the leads all perform well. Stewart and McDowell are actually a pretty good contrast - Picard's usually unflappable manner verses Soran's wide-eyed fanatic. The same cannot be said for the rest of the cast - perhaps with so much going on, they forgot to include any scenes of substance with Worf (Michael Dorn) or Doctor Crusher (Gates McFadden). Hell, even Guinan (Whoopi Goldberg) has more to do than those two. As a film, it's uneven - it's certainly entertaining in a not-really-sci-fi kinda way but fans expecting anything as dramatic as "Star Trek II: The Wrath Of Khan" would be advised to seek their thrills elsewhere. But then, there's that unwritten rule that odd-numbered Star Trek films are no match for even-numbered films and technically, this is Star Trek VII - for me, if you're wanting a better Next Gen film then you should check out "Star Trek: First Contact".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Commendably Thoughtful / Viciously Boring / Superfluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I tend to agree with those who are of the opinion that the Original Series Star Trek crew did not need to appear in this film. They had already had their send off, and a very fine one at that, in The Undiscovered Country. There was no need for their presence to be stretched out into Generations. That applies to Kirk more than to anyone else, of course. But here, he gets to take his final bow, of sorts. It could have been done better. At the same time, it could be argued that the Next Generation crew did not need to be in this film, either. It doesn't really do much to meaningfully develop them beyond what had already been done in their seven seasons on television. The subsequent film, First Contact, probably should have served as the lone Next Generation big screen-adventure. In any event, Generations is not a horrible film, but in practice it is a bit of a drag to watch, like one of those books that are hard to read without falling asleep. Some will argue that it is superfluous, and most would probably agree that it is exceedingly slow and frankly boring in spite of its decent screenplay and somewhat fresh plot. Speaking of which, the overall story (beyond the obvious 'Kirk meets Piccard, passes baton' gimmick) looks fairly cool on paper. A ribbon of energy writhing through space, which happens to be a portal to a hallucinogenic other-dimension called the Nexus, where time has no meaning? All right. Malcolm McDowell's Dr. Soren, a member of a long-lived species who has been trying to get back into the Nexus for decades, who collaborates with rogue Klingons, and who is willing to destroy an entire populated planet in the service of his obsession? Sure. A sequence in which the USS Enterprise-D suffers a warp-core breach, forcing the crew to evacuate to the saucer section, which then crashes into the forests of the planet below? Why not  that sounds exciting. Nothing like blowing up the Enterprise to create a spectacle. As mentioned before, however, it all unfolds at an excessively leisurely pace that challenges the attention span of all but the most dedicated of viewers, and neither Enterprise crew (the 'B' crew at the beginning, featuring the old guys, or the 'D' Next Generation crew) really gets much out of it in terms of character development. I do however have to note Jacqueline Kim's brief but excellent performance as Ensign Demora Sulu, i.e. Hikaru Sulu's grown-up daughter. She looks like a terrific captain in the making as she holds the helm in the opening sequence, and frankly I would rather watch a film about her than what the rest of Generations turns out to be. Two specific things dog all of the Next Generation-era films, and they both rear their heads here. The first and arguably the most annoying is the overestimation of Data's fascination quotient. Every single one of the four Next Generation films feels compelled to put significant focus on his character, and with the exception of First Contact, it all feels gratuitous to me. Yes, his search for humanity is interesting. But not this interesting, and his adventures in humor here are more obnoxious than charming (or actually funny). Instead of fixating on Data, I wish that a more involved role would have been written for Dr. Crusher, who I feel to have been neglected more than any other major crew member. The other issue is the hard truth that the Next Generation's tone and aesthetic sensibilities, while well-suited for television, are simply not big-screen cinematic, particularly in comparison to the Original Series elements with which they share screen time in Generations. The uniforms especially could have benefited from a more sophisticated re-design. The common criticism that Next Generation films are more like glorified television episodes is not entirely unwarranted, although to be fair, Generations does have some very nice sequences. Is this the worst Star Trek film? Goodness, no. It might not even be the worst Next Generation-era film, when you consider the respective issues present in Insurrection and Nemesis. If being boring is a crime, then both Insurrection and The Motion Picture have no doubt shared a cell with Generations. Ultimately, this is a decent film, but probably only of much interest to Star Trek enthusiasts, and even then more as a curiosity than anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely poor dialogue, NOT redeemed in any way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To illustrate the horrible-ness of the film to the best, Star Trek: Generations is to the original crew films as to what Star Wars: The Phantom Menace is to the original Star Wars trilogy. Horrible! Whilst perhaps not as horrible as The Phantom Menace and the two horrid sequels that followed, Star Trek Generations gets plenty wrong for what is yet another perfect illustration of a horrible Star Trek film and perfectly justifies the statement that all Star Trek films with an odd number are poor, with the exception of The Search for Spock. Following the presumed death of Captain James T. Kirk, over 70 years later, The Enterprise has fallen into the hands of Captain Picard who deals with family strains whilst a new threat is under way. A surviver of an accident, that isn't carefully explained nor dealt with, has begun his attack on a star that when destroyed, will somehow give way to be able to visit the Nexus, which is a dream like world that presents the best and the happiest moments to anyone and everyone. The film suffers on almost every single aspect. The story is poor, but it goes even beyond this. It's not just a poor story and poor writing, but the story leaves no impact on us, as we have no idea who these new characters are. Much like how the original crew were first presented in Star Trek: The Motion Picture, the characters here are presented extremely ridiculously and annoyingly, the greatest of them being Data, who could have come off as an interesting android for the remainder of this franchise but is literally depicted as Jar Jar Binks. Now, it is clearly evident where George Lucas got his influence from. See, Spock was a fatherly figure and a wise man and was an interesting and likable character. Data is supposed to be a similar character but here is presented in the most horrid manner much like how we were apparently supposed to view Jar Jar as a Yoda type character. Such event is referred to as deliberately taking a sh*t on one's head! Data is annoying and is horrible jokes about an emotion chip and how he is suddenly able to understand jokes that were told years ago is not funny, its downright ridiculous. And not in a good way like in Monty Python and the Holy Grail. This character should've been presented far better and horrible writing is clearly evident here. Not only is Data poorly written, so is Picard who throughout the film deals with such family issues, having recently received the news that his family has died. Two things make this completely a forgettable and unnecessary sub plot to the film: This is the first time we even know who Picard is. There is obviously no reference in the original series due to the fact that this takes place over 70 years later. And secondly, the story about his family is hardly elaborated in anyway whatsoever and is instead, thrown in from the air and just left in a steady place. More poor writing is evident here. Each character is poorly written, to the fullest. The villain in the film, played by Malcolm McDowell, is yet again, another one of the many examples of poor writing in the film. His plan and his plot in the film is quickly summed up and almost never really referred to. Had he been written well, Soran could be a similar villain to Khan from the great 'Wrath of Khan'. Apparently in the film, Soran deals with personal issues of his own. MaybeThis character is hardly explained, due to horrible writing and has quite a silly and ridiculous plot. Whereas Star Trek 5 was ridiculous, it was not to this extent. The villain had a purpose that seemed more legit than here. Special effects are the same as all Star Trek films. Not great but decent enough for a pass. The acting is good, I would possibly say. Patrick Stewart as Picard is a great choice as is Malcolm McDowell as Soran but both are utterly wasted in this film. Returning is William Shatner, early on in the film as Captain James T. Kirk, in the best proportion of the film and returning late in the film in an extremely ridiculous concept. The best part of the film is the opening proportion as it cleverly resembles a good Star Trek film dealing with Kirk's desperation to get back into the captain's chair. Everything after this, is downhill ***SPOILERS*** The film suffers a lot in every way possible but here is when it is clearly evident that this is a truly horrible film. Our main character, James T Kirk, who has been loved by all is killed at the very end of the film in the most ridiculous and one of the most anticlimactic deaths to one of the great heroes. He dies and this scene shares no emotion like good Trek films do. When your main character, that you've loved so long, is killed and you laugh, that there is the perfect example of poor writing. ***END OF SPOILERS*** Star Trek: Generations, is in my opinion, the second worst film of the franchise, winning the silver medal with a gold going to the first Star Trek film. This film pretty much ensures that all odd numbered Star Trek films are terrible, with one small exception. Badly written, with a lame story and undeveloped characters, due to poor writing, Star Trek Generations is an utter failure. To imagine this movie, it is the Phantom Menace of Star Trek. To illustrate, prior to the making of the film, the director realized it was the 7th instalment and that it had to be horrible, and so asked for some horrible writing and extremely poor character development This film is a complete failure in every aspect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
