<filme>
 <id>
  388
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109254
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Tira da Pesada 3
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Axel Foley, while investigating a car theft ring, comes across something much bigger than that: the same men who shot his boss are running a counterfeit money ring out of a theme park in Los Angeles.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Axle Foley, while investigating a car theft ring, comes across something much bigger than that: the same men who shot his boss are running a counterfeit money ring out of a theme park in Los Angeles.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   theme park
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   counterfeit
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   rescue
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   counterfeiting
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Landis
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Danilo Bach
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Daniel Petrie Jr.
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Eddie Murphy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jon Tenney
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Joey Travolta
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonder World, Wonder World. Where a disappointing sequel is the theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Axel Foley's boss gets shot in the middle of a car theft ring. Gunning for revenge, Axel finds out the same man that killed his boss is running an illegal operation with fake money out of an infamous theme park in L.A. Axel has Flint (Elizondo) and his longtime pal, Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) to help him. I love the first movie, and the sequel is highly entertaining. This one, however? It's the definition of disappointment. I'll start off with my biggest gripe about this movie. Why would you have this take place at an amusement park? Who in their right mind thought this was an amusing idea?! It does have some OK action sequences. It has a pretty decent rescue sequence involving a couple of children at the theme park, with a few really memorable stunts. I also didn't like how some of the characters were written. Judge Reinhold was hilarious in the first two movies, but his role seems pointless and contrived here. Taggart (Who is absent because he has retired in Phoenix, according to this movie) is replaced by Hector Elizondo (who is actually quite good) but I just didn't feel the magic anymore. The whole movie feels so artificial, that I had trouble enjoying myself. The finale is especially ludicrous with it's implausibility. It's very reminiscent of the one in Bird on A Wire with Mel Gibson & Goldie Hawn. Eddie Murphy runs out of tricks in this one. He's as watchable as ever, but the script lets him down. Stephen McHattie steals a few scenes he is in as the straight faced agent. John Saxon has a thankless role as an accomplice to the main villain, whilst Timothy Carhart makes for a very bland bad guy as Ellis De Wald. Final Thoughts: I didn't hate this movie, but I was sorely disappointed in it. I was unimpressed the first time I saw it years ago, and my opinion remains the same, after viewing it a second time. I'd only give it a look if nothing else is on. Stick with the first two movies 5.2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Back Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy and Judge Reinhold return again in this sequel, as Axel Foley follows the suspects of a car theft ring to(of course!) Beverly Hills, California, though also Los Angeles, where a counterfeiting ring seems to be operating within the confines of a famous amusement park. There are some stunts involving various rides, in this John Landis directed installment. Nothing new here, except it feels watered down and innocuous, perhaps in response to criticism that Part II was too cold hearted? Either way, this is a silly, lightweight trifle, with actors coasting along without much enthusiasm. Change of setting is different, but this amusement park satire idea was better handled in the first "Vacation" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only slightly better than part II
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zbigniew_Krycsiwiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once again, Detroit cop Murphy returns to BH, this time, after his captain is killed in a shootout in a Detroit chop-shop. Film is pointlessly titled, as it takes place in a fun park, not Beverly Hills (and its title doesn't even appear on-screen at the start, only during the end credits) Screenplay tried desperately hard to be funny, even going as far as bringing back Bronson Pinchot's character for another cameo, as an ex-gallery worker turned gun salesman(?) and recycling the original film's music score, to no avail. It comes off as being a carbon copy sequel in some scenes, while its climactic scenes look like merely an excuse to show us Universal Studios' rides and rollercoasters to climax its repetitive, and thin, plot. Film makes the same mistake part II did, with having one character (Walt Disney clone "Uncle Dave") shot and on his deathbed shortly before Murphy and Reinhold are shot as well, but minutes later, Dave has recovered fully while Murphy and Reinhold are still in casts and wheelchairs at the final scene. Don't get me started on the asinine Spider ride rescue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    cop 3
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well first of without John Ashton the film lacks a lot of laughs, it's seems whoever wrote and produced this didn't give Eddie Murphy near enough good one liners,, like the first two films,, plus the Detroit Police Chief character is gone,, so when they put in new characters,, plus a new villain , then decided to set the main action in an amusement park , i just was like hey wait a minute,, this movie lacked the laughs, and hard bite that the first two had. i really can 't think of that many good things to say about this particular movie,, i hear there is a bhc 4 coming out,, i hope it isn't like 3 at all or i won't even bother with it . there 's some action and some of it is funny not totally unwatchable if it stood alone but compared to 1st two,, i would say that you would have to be crazy to like this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of Murphy's downfall.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TopperHarley29
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wasn't as bad as some people make it out to be, but it still isn't very good. The first movie was the funniest out of all of them and the second one was OK and provided a few good laughs, but this is the weakest. My main problem is that it barely feels like a Beverly Hills Cop movie. It feels like it's a movie about Eddie Murphy hanging out at an amusement park. Some of the jokes are just mildly funny, but the one that stood out the most in my opinion was the counterfeit money with Axel Foley's face. So far this is the only John Landis movie I do not care for which is a shame since he is a good director. This isn't his worst movie, (So far it's The Haunted Mansion.) but it was the beginning of Eddie Murphy's downfall. He tried to redeem himself with Tower Heist, but some idiot made A Thousand Words and now he's back to square one again. I hope he starts acting in good movies again because I don't want him remembered by today's generation as the Daddy Daycare guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not Bad, But Not As Good As The First 2 Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy, Judge Reinhold, Hector Elizondo, Timothy Carhart, Theresa Randle, Alan Young, Gil Hill, Bronson Pinchot and John Saxon star in this 1994 action-comedy sequel. This installment begins in Detroit, Michigan where cop, Axel Foley (Murphy) is on a stakeout. Soon, his boss, Inspector Douglas Todd (Hill) is killed in the crossfire by crooked businessman, Ellis De Wald (Carhart). Axel is determined to avenge Todd and tracks De Wald to Beverly Hills, California where he runs an amusement park, Wonderworld. He also reunites with cop friend, Billy Rosewood (Reinhold) and meets his co-worker, Jon Flynt (Elizondo). Axel gets himself in some snags when he tries to confront De Wald and learns of his counterfeiting scheme. Randle plays Janice, a woman who works for De Wald and gets close with Axel, Young (Mister Ed) plays Wonderworld owner, Uncle Dave Thornton, Saxon (A Nightmare on Elm Street) plays De Wald's associate Orrin Sanderson and Pinchot (Perfect Strangers) appears briefly reprising his role as Serge. There's also cameos by directors, Joe Dante and George Lucas. This sequel isn't bad, but not as good as the first 2 films. I missed John Ashton as John Taggart and it seemed like Elizondo's character, Flynt was kind of a substitute. I'm glad Reinhold came back and like the way they play the late, Harold Faltermeyer's classic theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Stuart
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so disappointed with this film, I loved the original and not only that but the Director, John Landis, made my favourite ever film "An American Werewolf in London". It is un-cinematic, the actors are not engaged, the script is woeful and the pace pedestrian. Every one seemed to just show up for the pay cheque. It's not the worst film ever made but it's a real franchise killer and sticks out as real waste of pedigree considering what came before it and the people involved. O out of 10 for effort, every one concerned should be very, very ashamed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Uneven to Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beverly Hills Cop III (1994) ** (out of 4) Incredibly disappointing third entry in the series has Axel Foley (Eddie Murphy) running an operation on a car theft ring but soon he realizes it's much more than just this. After his boss is murdered he heads back out West to try and find the killers as well as uncover what's really going on. There's really no getting around the fact that this film is a major dud and it's really a shame considering what director John Landis and star Murphy had done together previously. I think it's easy to say this is a very big black spot on both of their careers. The majority of the blame has to go to the screenplay, which offers up a rather silly story full of silly situations, bad characters and some pretty lifeless comedy. It also doesn't help that Landis tries to put his stamp all over the picture, which not only takes it away from what the series was, it also adds some really boring and drawn out moments that should have been left on the cutting room floor. A perfect example happens right at the start when two of the bad guys are singing and dancing around for no real reason to the story. I'm really not sure what Landis was going for here but it's just downright silly. Even worse are some of the characters who are flat out boring including Judge Reinhold who just seems downright out of place. He's basically given nothing to do except stand around and make dumb faces as well as say some really bad dialogue. Even Murphy is pretty forgettable here. I'm not sure if he just wasn't into the film or perhaps he knew he didn't have much to work with. Hector Elizondo adds nothing in his role and the same is true for Timothy Carhart as the bad guy. The film is also incredibly uneven in its style and I'd say that there must have been some real creative control issues going on behind the scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap on a stick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandra DeLonghi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing has NOTHING in common with the original idea. It was more like a cheap-arse cash grab attempt but then falling $10 million short of break even. The problem is that they got it all wrong: Close to no humorous moments, no slapstick, no multiple layers of plot or parallelism, a half hour wasted on a pointless rescue-scene shot with CGI (even Eddie Murphy acted bored doing this), stupid time-wasters such as the "gramma oki doki pushed me" scene, wheeling out the "Serge" figure for five minutes of gay-talk. No suspense, a complete lack of care or passion. Bad writing and sad directing and last but not least fake-landscape-scenery that looked entirely shot in a studio, at a low budget. The music adaptation of Faltermeyer's theme score is inept. In the E/R movie review books this thing would have to be a fat turkey - at best. I was seriously, seriously (did I say SERIOUSLY) let down by this piece of &sect;hit. BO-RING.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the 3 films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it weren't for the amusement park story, this would probably be just another dull entry in the BHC series. Part II was a slight disappointment (at least when it came to anything other than action scenes), but this one is even better than the first movie and a big improvement over part 2. Unlike Part 2, the villains are mean enough (and seen more often), and Murphy doesn't do his comedy as much, which helps. My only quibble is Bronson Pinchot, who I think, didn't really need to be in the movie. His character is completely unnecessary. In fact, I think his appearance in the first movie was also unnecessary. His role is basically comic relief. That's what Murphy is for. It's as if Pinchot is playing a less funny version of Balki from "Perfect Strangers", only he doesn't Larry to annoy. ***1/2 out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonder World, Wonder World. Where a disappointing sequel is the theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Axel Foley's boss gets shot in the middle of a car theft ring. Gunning for revenge, Axel finds out the same man that killed his boss is running an illegal operation with fake money out of an infamous theme park in L.A. Axel has Flint (Elizondo) and his longtime pal, Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) to help him. I love the first movie, and the sequel is highly entertaining. This one, however? It's the definition of disappointment. I'll start off with my biggest gripe about this movie. Why would you have this take place at an amusement park? Who in their right mind thought this was an amusing idea?! It does have some OK action sequences. It has a pretty decent rescue sequence involving a couple of children at the theme park, with a few really memorable stunts. I also didn't like how some of the characters were written. Judge Reinhold was hilarious in the first two movies, but his role seems pointless and contrived here. Taggart (Who is absent because he has retired in Phoenix, according to this movie) is replaced by Hector Elizondo (who is actually quite good) but I just didn't feel the magic anymore. The whole movie feels so artificial, that I had trouble enjoying myself. The finale is especially ludicrous with it's implausibility. It's very reminiscent of the one in Bird on A Wire with Mel Gibson & Goldie Hawn. Eddie Murphy runs out of tricks in this one. He's as watchable as ever, but the script lets him down. Stephen McHattie steals a few scenes he is in as the straight faced agent. John Saxon has a thankless role as an accomplice to the main villain, whilst Timothy Carhart makes for a very bland bad guy as Ellis De Wald. Final Thoughts: I didn't hate this movie, but I was sorely disappointed in it. I was unimpressed the first time I saw it years ago, and my opinion remains the same, after viewing it a second time. I'd only give it a look if nothing else is on. Stick with the first two movies 5.2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Back Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy and Judge Reinhold return again in this sequel, as Axel Foley follows the suspects of a car theft ring to(of course!) Beverly Hills, California, though also Los Angeles, where a counterfeiting ring seems to be operating within the confines of a famous amusement park. There are some stunts involving various rides, in this John Landis directed installment. Nothing new here, except it feels watered down and innocuous, perhaps in response to criticism that Part II was too cold hearted? Either way, this is a silly, lightweight trifle, with actors coasting along without much enthusiasm. Change of setting is different, but this amusement park satire idea was better handled in the first "Vacation" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only slightly better than part II
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zbigniew_Krycsiwiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once again, Detroit cop Murphy returns to BH, this time, after his captain is killed in a shootout in a Detroit chop-shop. Film is pointlessly titled, as it takes place in a fun park, not Beverly Hills (and its title doesn't even appear on-screen at the start, only during the end credits) Screenplay tried desperately hard to be funny, even going as far as bringing back Bronson Pinchot's character for another cameo, as an ex-gallery worker turned gun salesman(?) and recycling the original film's music score, to no avail. It comes off as being a carbon copy sequel in some scenes, while its climactic scenes look like merely an excuse to show us Universal Studios' rides and rollercoasters to climax its repetitive, and thin, plot. Film makes the same mistake part II did, with having one character (Walt Disney clone "Uncle Dave") shot and on his deathbed shortly before Murphy and Reinhold are shot as well, but minutes later, Dave has recovered fully while Murphy and Reinhold are still in casts and wheelchairs at the final scene. Don't get me started on the asinine Spider ride rescue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    cop 3
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well first of without John Ashton the film lacks a lot of laughs, it's seems whoever wrote and produced this didn't give Eddie Murphy near enough good one liners,, like the first two films,, plus the Detroit Police Chief character is gone,, so when they put in new characters,, plus a new villain , then decided to set the main action in an amusement park , i just was like hey wait a minute,, this movie lacked the laughs, and hard bite that the first two had. i really can 't think of that many good things to say about this particular movie,, i hear there is a bhc 4 coming out,, i hope it isn't like 3 at all or i won't even bother with it . there 's some action and some of it is funny not totally unwatchable if it stood alone but compared to 1st two,, i would say that you would have to be crazy to like this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of Murphy's downfall.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TopperHarley29
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wasn't as bad as some people make it out to be, but it still isn't very good. The first movie was the funniest out of all of them and the second one was OK and provided a few good laughs, but this is the weakest. My main problem is that it barely feels like a Beverly Hills Cop movie. It feels like it's a movie about Eddie Murphy hanging out at an amusement park. Some of the jokes are just mildly funny, but the one that stood out the most in my opinion was the counterfeit money with Axel Foley's face. So far this is the only John Landis movie I do not care for which is a shame since he is a good director. This isn't his worst movie, (So far it's The Haunted Mansion.) but it was the beginning of Eddie Murphy's downfall. He tried to redeem himself with Tower Heist, but some idiot made A Thousand Words and now he's back to square one again. I hope he starts acting in good movies again because I don't want him remembered by today's generation as the Daddy Daycare guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not Bad, But Not As Good As The First 2 Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy, Judge Reinhold, Hector Elizondo, Timothy Carhart, Theresa Randle, Alan Young, Gil Hill, Bronson Pinchot and John Saxon star in this 1994 action-comedy sequel. This installment begins in Detroit, Michigan where cop, Axel Foley (Murphy) is on a stakeout. Soon, his boss, Inspector Douglas Todd (Hill) is killed in the crossfire by crooked businessman, Ellis De Wald (Carhart). Axel is determined to avenge Todd and tracks De Wald to Beverly Hills, California where he runs an amusement park, Wonderworld. He also reunites with cop friend, Billy Rosewood (Reinhold) and meets his co-worker, Jon Flynt (Elizondo). Axel gets himself in some snags when he tries to confront De Wald and learns of his counterfeiting scheme. Randle plays Janice, a woman who works for De Wald and gets close with Axel, Young (Mister Ed) plays Wonderworld owner, Uncle Dave Thornton, Saxon (A Nightmare on Elm Street) plays De Wald's associate Orrin Sanderson and Pinchot (Perfect Strangers) appears briefly reprising his role as Serge. There's also cameos by directors, Joe Dante and George Lucas. This sequel isn't bad, but not as good as the first 2 films. I missed John Ashton as John Taggart and it seemed like Elizondo's character, Flynt was kind of a substitute. I'm glad Reinhold came back and like the way they play the late, Harold Faltermeyer's classic theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Stuart
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so disappointed with this film, I loved the original and not only that but the Director, John Landis, made my favourite ever film "An American Werewolf in London". It is un-cinematic, the actors are not engaged, the script is woeful and the pace pedestrian. Every one seemed to just show up for the pay cheque. It's not the worst film ever made but it's a real franchise killer and sticks out as real waste of pedigree considering what came before it and the people involved. O out of 10 for effort, every one concerned should be very, very ashamed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Uneven to Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beverly Hills Cop III (1994) ** (out of 4) Incredibly disappointing third entry in the series has Axel Foley (Eddie Murphy) running an operation on a car theft ring but soon he realizes it's much more than just this. After his boss is murdered he heads back out West to try and find the killers as well as uncover what's really going on. There's really no getting around the fact that this film is a major dud and it's really a shame considering what director John Landis and star Murphy had done together previously. I think it's easy to say this is a very big black spot on both of their careers. The majority of the blame has to go to the screenplay, which offers up a rather silly story full of silly situations, bad characters and some pretty lifeless comedy. It also doesn't help that Landis tries to put his stamp all over the picture, which not only takes it away from what the series was, it also adds some really boring and drawn out moments that should have been left on the cutting room floor. A perfect example happens right at the start when two of the bad guys are singing and dancing around for no real reason to the story. I'm really not sure what Landis was going for here but it's just downright silly. Even worse are some of the characters who are flat out boring including Judge Reinhold who just seems downright out of place. He's basically given nothing to do except stand around and make dumb faces as well as say some really bad dialogue. Even Murphy is pretty forgettable here. I'm not sure if he just wasn't into the film or perhaps he knew he didn't have much to work with. Hector Elizondo adds nothing in his role and the same is true for Timothy Carhart as the bad guy. The film is also incredibly uneven in its style and I'd say that there must have been some real creative control issues going on behind the scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap on a stick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandra DeLonghi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing has NOTHING in common with the original idea. It was more like a cheap-arse cash grab attempt but then falling $10 million short of break even. The problem is that they got it all wrong: Close to no humorous moments, no slapstick, no multiple layers of plot or parallelism, a half hour wasted on a pointless rescue-scene shot with CGI (even Eddie Murphy acted bored doing this), stupid time-wasters such as the "gramma oki doki pushed me" scene, wheeling out the "Serge" figure for five minutes of gay-talk. No suspense, a complete lack of care or passion. Bad writing and sad directing and last but not least fake-landscape-scenery that looked entirely shot in a studio, at a low budget. The music adaptation of Faltermeyer's theme score is inept. In the E/R movie review books this thing would have to be a fat turkey - at best. I was seriously, seriously (did I say SERIOUSLY) let down by this piece of &sect;hit. BO-RING.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the 3 films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it weren't for the amusement park story, this would probably be just another dull entry in the BHC series. Part II was a slight disappointment (at least when it came to anything other than action scenes), but this one is even better than the first movie and a big improvement over part 2. Unlike Part 2, the villains are mean enough (and seen more often), and Murphy doesn't do his comedy as much, which helps. My only quibble is Bronson Pinchot, who I think, didn't really need to be in the movie. His character is completely unnecessary. In fact, I think his appearance in the first movie was also unnecessary. His role is basically comic relief. That's what Murphy is for. It's as if Pinchot is playing a less funny version of Balki from "Perfect Strangers", only he doesn't Larry to annoy. ***1/2 out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonder World, Wonder World. Where a disappointing sequel is the theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Axel Foley's boss gets shot in the middle of a car theft ring. Gunning for revenge, Axel finds out the same man that killed his boss is running an illegal operation with fake money out of an infamous theme park in L.A. Axel has Flint (Elizondo) and his longtime pal, Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) to help him. I love the first movie, and the sequel is highly entertaining. This one, however? It's the definition of disappointment. I'll start off with my biggest gripe about this movie. Why would you have this take place at an amusement park? Who in their right mind thought this was an amusing idea?! It does have some OK action sequences. It has a pretty decent rescue sequence involving a couple of children at the theme park, with a few really memorable stunts. I also didn't like how some of the characters were written. Judge Reinhold was hilarious in the first two movies, but his role seems pointless and contrived here. Taggart (Who is absent because he has retired in Phoenix, according to this movie) is replaced by Hector Elizondo (who is actually quite good) but I just didn't feel the magic anymore. The whole movie feels so artificial, that I had trouble enjoying myself. The finale is especially ludicrous with it's implausibility. It's very reminiscent of the one in Bird on A Wire with Mel Gibson & Goldie Hawn. Eddie Murphy runs out of tricks in this one. He's as watchable as ever, but the script lets him down. Stephen McHattie steals a few scenes he is in as the straight faced agent. John Saxon has a thankless role as an accomplice to the main villain, whilst Timothy Carhart makes for a very bland bad guy as Ellis De Wald. Final Thoughts: I didn't hate this movie, but I was sorely disappointed in it. I was unimpressed the first time I saw it years ago, and my opinion remains the same, after viewing it a second time. I'd only give it a look if nothing else is on. Stick with the first two movies 5.2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Back Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy and Judge Reinhold return again in this sequel, as Axel Foley follows the suspects of a car theft ring to(of course!) Beverly Hills, California, though also Los Angeles, where a counterfeiting ring seems to be operating within the confines of a famous amusement park. There are some stunts involving various rides, in this John Landis directed installment. Nothing new here, except it feels watered down and innocuous, perhaps in response to criticism that Part II was too cold hearted? Either way, this is a silly, lightweight trifle, with actors coasting along without much enthusiasm. Change of setting is different, but this amusement park satire idea was better handled in the first "Vacation" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only slightly better than part II
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zbigniew_Krycsiwiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once again, Detroit cop Murphy returns to BH, this time, after his captain is killed in a shootout in a Detroit chop-shop. Film is pointlessly titled, as it takes place in a fun park, not Beverly Hills (and its title doesn't even appear on-screen at the start, only during the end credits) Screenplay tried desperately hard to be funny, even going as far as bringing back Bronson Pinchot's character for another cameo, as an ex-gallery worker turned gun salesman(?) and recycling the original film's music score, to no avail. It comes off as being a carbon copy sequel in some scenes, while its climactic scenes look like merely an excuse to show us Universal Studios' rides and rollercoasters to climax its repetitive, and thin, plot. Film makes the same mistake part II did, with having one character (Walt Disney clone "Uncle Dave") shot and on his deathbed shortly before Murphy and Reinhold are shot as well, but minutes later, Dave has recovered fully while Murphy and Reinhold are still in casts and wheelchairs at the final scene. Don't get me started on the asinine Spider ride rescue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    cop 3
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well first of without John Ashton the film lacks a lot of laughs, it's seems whoever wrote and produced this didn't give Eddie Murphy near enough good one liners,, like the first two films,, plus the Detroit Police Chief character is gone,, so when they put in new characters,, plus a new villain , then decided to set the main action in an amusement park , i just was like hey wait a minute,, this movie lacked the laughs, and hard bite that the first two had. i really can 't think of that many good things to say about this particular movie,, i hear there is a bhc 4 coming out,, i hope it isn't like 3 at all or i won't even bother with it . there 's some action and some of it is funny not totally unwatchable if it stood alone but compared to 1st two,, i would say that you would have to be crazy to like this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of Murphy's downfall.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TopperHarley29
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wasn't as bad as some people make it out to be, but it still isn't very good. The first movie was the funniest out of all of them and the second one was OK and provided a few good laughs, but this is the weakest. My main problem is that it barely feels like a Beverly Hills Cop movie. It feels like it's a movie about Eddie Murphy hanging out at an amusement park. Some of the jokes are just mildly funny, but the one that stood out the most in my opinion was the counterfeit money with Axel Foley's face. So far this is the only John Landis movie I do not care for which is a shame since he is a good director. This isn't his worst movie, (So far it's The Haunted Mansion.) but it was the beginning of Eddie Murphy's downfall. He tried to redeem himself with Tower Heist, but some idiot made A Thousand Words and now he's back to square one again. I hope he starts acting in good movies again because I don't want him remembered by today's generation as the Daddy Daycare guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not Bad, But Not As Good As The First 2 Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy, Judge Reinhold, Hector Elizondo, Timothy Carhart, Theresa Randle, Alan Young, Gil Hill, Bronson Pinchot and John Saxon star in this 1994 action-comedy sequel. This installment begins in Detroit, Michigan where cop, Axel Foley (Murphy) is on a stakeout. Soon, his boss, Inspector Douglas Todd (Hill) is killed in the crossfire by crooked businessman, Ellis De Wald (Carhart). Axel is determined to avenge Todd and tracks De Wald to Beverly Hills, California where he runs an amusement park, Wonderworld. He also reunites with cop friend, Billy Rosewood (Reinhold) and meets his co-worker, Jon Flynt (Elizondo). Axel gets himself in some snags when he tries to confront De Wald and learns of his counterfeiting scheme. Randle plays Janice, a woman who works for De Wald and gets close with Axel, Young (Mister Ed) plays Wonderworld owner, Uncle Dave Thornton, Saxon (A Nightmare on Elm Street) plays De Wald's associate Orrin Sanderson and Pinchot (Perfect Strangers) appears briefly reprising his role as Serge. There's also cameos by directors, Joe Dante and George Lucas. This sequel isn't bad, but not as good as the first 2 films. I missed John Ashton as John Taggart and it seemed like Elizondo's character, Flynt was kind of a substitute. I'm glad Reinhold came back and like the way they play the late, Harold Faltermeyer's classic theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Stuart
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so disappointed with this film, I loved the original and not only that but the Director, John Landis, made my favourite ever film "An American Werewolf in London". It is un-cinematic, the actors are not engaged, the script is woeful and the pace pedestrian. Every one seemed to just show up for the pay cheque. It's not the worst film ever made but it's a real franchise killer and sticks out as real waste of pedigree considering what came before it and the people involved. O out of 10 for effort, every one concerned should be very, very ashamed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Uneven to Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beverly Hills Cop III (1994) ** (out of 4) Incredibly disappointing third entry in the series has Axel Foley (Eddie Murphy) running an operation on a car theft ring but soon he realizes it's much more than just this. After his boss is murdered he heads back out West to try and find the killers as well as uncover what's really going on. There's really no getting around the fact that this film is a major dud and it's really a shame considering what director John Landis and star Murphy had done together previously. I think it's easy to say this is a very big black spot on both of their careers. The majority of the blame has to go to the screenplay, which offers up a rather silly story full of silly situations, bad characters and some pretty lifeless comedy. It also doesn't help that Landis tries to put his stamp all over the picture, which not only takes it away from what the series was, it also adds some really boring and drawn out moments that should have been left on the cutting room floor. A perfect example happens right at the start when two of the bad guys are singing and dancing around for no real reason to the story. I'm really not sure what Landis was going for here but it's just downright silly. Even worse are some of the characters who are flat out boring including Judge Reinhold who just seems downright out of place. He's basically given nothing to do except stand around and make dumb faces as well as say some really bad dialogue. Even Murphy is pretty forgettable here. I'm not sure if he just wasn't into the film or perhaps he knew he didn't have much to work with. Hector Elizondo adds nothing in his role and the same is true for Timothy Carhart as the bad guy. The film is also incredibly uneven in its style and I'd say that there must have been some real creative control issues going on behind the scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap on a stick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandra DeLonghi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing has NOTHING in common with the original idea. It was more like a cheap-arse cash grab attempt but then falling $10 million short of break even. The problem is that they got it all wrong: Close to no humorous moments, no slapstick, no multiple layers of plot or parallelism, a half hour wasted on a pointless rescue-scene shot with CGI (even Eddie Murphy acted bored doing this), stupid time-wasters such as the "gramma oki doki pushed me" scene, wheeling out the "Serge" figure for five minutes of gay-talk. No suspense, a complete lack of care or passion. Bad writing and sad directing and last but not least fake-landscape-scenery that looked entirely shot in a studio, at a low budget. The music adaptation of Faltermeyer's theme score is inept. In the E/R movie review books this thing would have to be a fat turkey - at best. I was seriously, seriously (did I say SERIOUSLY) let down by this piece of &sect;hit. BO-RING.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the 3 films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it weren't for the amusement park story, this would probably be just another dull entry in the BHC series. Part II was a slight disappointment (at least when it came to anything other than action scenes), but this one is even better than the first movie and a big improvement over part 2. Unlike Part 2, the villains are mean enough (and seen more often), and Murphy doesn't do his comedy as much, which helps. My only quibble is Bronson Pinchot, who I think, didn't really need to be in the movie. His character is completely unnecessary. In fact, I think his appearance in the first movie was also unnecessary. His role is basically comic relief. That's what Murphy is for. It's as if Pinchot is playing a less funny version of Balki from "Perfect Strangers", only he doesn't Larry to annoy. ***1/2 out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonder World, Wonder World. Where a disappointing sequel is the theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Axel Foley's boss gets shot in the middle of a car theft ring. Gunning for revenge, Axel finds out the same man that killed his boss is running an illegal operation with fake money out of an infamous theme park in L.A. Axel has Flint (Elizondo) and his longtime pal, Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) to help him. I love the first movie, and the sequel is highly entertaining. This one, however? It's the definition of disappointment. I'll start off with my biggest gripe about this movie. Why would you have this take place at an amusement park? Who in their right mind thought this was an amusing idea?! It does have some OK action sequences. It has a pretty decent rescue sequence involving a couple of children at the theme park, with a few really memorable stunts. I also didn't like how some of the characters were written. Judge Reinhold was hilarious in the first two movies, but his role seems pointless and contrived here. Taggart (Who is absent because he has retired in Phoenix, according to this movie) is replaced by Hector Elizondo (who is actually quite good) but I just didn't feel the magic anymore. The whole movie feels so artificial, that I had trouble enjoying myself. The finale is especially ludicrous with it's implausibility. It's very reminiscent of the one in Bird on A Wire with Mel Gibson & Goldie Hawn. Eddie Murphy runs out of tricks in this one. He's as watchable as ever, but the script lets him down. Stephen McHattie steals a few scenes he is in as the straight faced agent. John Saxon has a thankless role as an accomplice to the main villain, whilst Timothy Carhart makes for a very bland bad guy as Ellis De Wald. Final Thoughts: I didn't hate this movie, but I was sorely disappointed in it. I was unimpressed the first time I saw it years ago, and my opinion remains the same, after viewing it a second time. I'd only give it a look if nothing else is on. Stick with the first two movies 5.2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Back Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy and Judge Reinhold return again in this sequel, as Axel Foley follows the suspects of a car theft ring to(of course!) Beverly Hills, California, though also Los Angeles, where a counterfeiting ring seems to be operating within the confines of a famous amusement park. There are some stunts involving various rides, in this John Landis directed installment. Nothing new here, except it feels watered down and innocuous, perhaps in response to criticism that Part II was too cold hearted? Either way, this is a silly, lightweight trifle, with actors coasting along without much enthusiasm. Change of setting is different, but this amusement park satire idea was better handled in the first "Vacation" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only slightly better than part II
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zbigniew_Krycsiwiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once again, Detroit cop Murphy returns to BH, this time, after his captain is killed in a shootout in a Detroit chop-shop. Film is pointlessly titled, as it takes place in a fun park, not Beverly Hills (and its title doesn't even appear on-screen at the start, only during the end credits) Screenplay tried desperately hard to be funny, even going as far as bringing back Bronson Pinchot's character for another cameo, as an ex-gallery worker turned gun salesman(?) and recycling the original film's music score, to no avail. It comes off as being a carbon copy sequel in some scenes, while its climactic scenes look like merely an excuse to show us Universal Studios' rides and rollercoasters to climax its repetitive, and thin, plot. Film makes the same mistake part II did, with having one character (Walt Disney clone "Uncle Dave") shot and on his deathbed shortly before Murphy and Reinhold are shot as well, but minutes later, Dave has recovered fully while Murphy and Reinhold are still in casts and wheelchairs at the final scene. Don't get me started on the asinine Spider ride rescue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    cop 3
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well first of without John Ashton the film lacks a lot of laughs, it's seems whoever wrote and produced this didn't give Eddie Murphy near enough good one liners,, like the first two films,, plus the Detroit Police Chief character is gone,, so when they put in new characters,, plus a new villain , then decided to set the main action in an amusement park , i just was like hey wait a minute,, this movie lacked the laughs, and hard bite that the first two had. i really can 't think of that many good things to say about this particular movie,, i hear there is a bhc 4 coming out,, i hope it isn't like 3 at all or i won't even bother with it . there 's some action and some of it is funny not totally unwatchable if it stood alone but compared to 1st two,, i would say that you would have to be crazy to like this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of Murphy's downfall.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TopperHarley29
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wasn't as bad as some people make it out to be, but it still isn't very good. The first movie was the funniest out of all of them and the second one was OK and provided a few good laughs, but this is the weakest. My main problem is that it barely feels like a Beverly Hills Cop movie. It feels like it's a movie about Eddie Murphy hanging out at an amusement park. Some of the jokes are just mildly funny, but the one that stood out the most in my opinion was the counterfeit money with Axel Foley's face. So far this is the only John Landis movie I do not care for which is a shame since he is a good director. This isn't his worst movie, (So far it's The Haunted Mansion.) but it was the beginning of Eddie Murphy's downfall. He tried to redeem himself with Tower Heist, but some idiot made A Thousand Words and now he's back to square one again. I hope he starts acting in good movies again because I don't want him remembered by today's generation as the Daddy Daycare guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not Bad, But Not As Good As The First 2 Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy, Judge Reinhold, Hector Elizondo, Timothy Carhart, Theresa Randle, Alan Young, Gil Hill, Bronson Pinchot and John Saxon star in this 1994 action-comedy sequel. This installment begins in Detroit, Michigan where cop, Axel Foley (Murphy) is on a stakeout. Soon, his boss, Inspector Douglas Todd (Hill) is killed in the crossfire by crooked businessman, Ellis De Wald (Carhart). Axel is determined to avenge Todd and tracks De Wald to Beverly Hills, California where he runs an amusement park, Wonderworld. He also reunites with cop friend, Billy Rosewood (Reinhold) and meets his co-worker, Jon Flynt (Elizondo). Axel gets himself in some snags when he tries to confront De Wald and learns of his counterfeiting scheme. Randle plays Janice, a woman who works for De Wald and gets close with Axel, Young (Mister Ed) plays Wonderworld owner, Uncle Dave Thornton, Saxon (A Nightmare on Elm Street) plays De Wald's associate Orrin Sanderson and Pinchot (Perfect Strangers) appears briefly reprising his role as Serge. There's also cameos by directors, Joe Dante and George Lucas. This sequel isn't bad, but not as good as the first 2 films. I missed John Ashton as John Taggart and it seemed like Elizondo's character, Flynt was kind of a substitute. I'm glad Reinhold came back and like the way they play the late, Harold Faltermeyer's classic theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Stuart
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so disappointed with this film, I loved the original and not only that but the Director, John Landis, made my favourite ever film "An American Werewolf in London". It is un-cinematic, the actors are not engaged, the script is woeful and the pace pedestrian. Every one seemed to just show up for the pay cheque. It's not the worst film ever made but it's a real franchise killer and sticks out as real waste of pedigree considering what came before it and the people involved. O out of 10 for effort, every one concerned should be very, very ashamed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Uneven to Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beverly Hills Cop III (1994) ** (out of 4) Incredibly disappointing third entry in the series has Axel Foley (Eddie Murphy) running an operation on a car theft ring but soon he realizes it's much more than just this. After his boss is murdered he heads back out West to try and find the killers as well as uncover what's really going on. There's really no getting around the fact that this film is a major dud and it's really a shame considering what director John Landis and star Murphy had done together previously. I think it's easy to say this is a very big black spot on both of their careers. The majority of the blame has to go to the screenplay, which offers up a rather silly story full of silly situations, bad characters and some pretty lifeless comedy. It also doesn't help that Landis tries to put his stamp all over the picture, which not only takes it away from what the series was, it also adds some really boring and drawn out moments that should have been left on the cutting room floor. A perfect example happens right at the start when two of the bad guys are singing and dancing around for no real reason to the story. I'm really not sure what Landis was going for here but it's just downright silly. Even worse are some of the characters who are flat out boring including Judge Reinhold who just seems downright out of place. He's basically given nothing to do except stand around and make dumb faces as well as say some really bad dialogue. Even Murphy is pretty forgettable here. I'm not sure if he just wasn't into the film or perhaps he knew he didn't have much to work with. Hector Elizondo adds nothing in his role and the same is true for Timothy Carhart as the bad guy. The film is also incredibly uneven in its style and I'd say that there must have been some real creative control issues going on behind the scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap on a stick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandra DeLonghi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing has NOTHING in common with the original idea. It was more like a cheap-arse cash grab attempt but then falling $10 million short of break even. The problem is that they got it all wrong: Close to no humorous moments, no slapstick, no multiple layers of plot or parallelism, a half hour wasted on a pointless rescue-scene shot with CGI (even Eddie Murphy acted bored doing this), stupid time-wasters such as the "gramma oki doki pushed me" scene, wheeling out the "Serge" figure for five minutes of gay-talk. No suspense, a complete lack of care or passion. Bad writing and sad directing and last but not least fake-landscape-scenery that looked entirely shot in a studio, at a low budget. The music adaptation of Faltermeyer's theme score is inept. In the E/R movie review books this thing would have to be a fat turkey - at best. I was seriously, seriously (did I say SERIOUSLY) let down by this piece of &sect;hit. BO-RING.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the 3 films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it weren't for the amusement park story, this would probably be just another dull entry in the BHC series. Part II was a slight disappointment (at least when it came to anything other than action scenes), but this one is even better than the first movie and a big improvement over part 2. Unlike Part 2, the villains are mean enough (and seen more often), and Murphy doesn't do his comedy as much, which helps. My only quibble is Bronson Pinchot, who I think, didn't really need to be in the movie. His character is completely unnecessary. In fact, I think his appearance in the first movie was also unnecessary. His role is basically comic relief. That's what Murphy is for. It's as if Pinchot is playing a less funny version of Balki from "Perfect Strangers", only he doesn't Larry to annoy. ***1/2 out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonder World, Wonder World. Where a disappointing sequel is the theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Axel Foley's boss gets shot in the middle of a car theft ring. Gunning for revenge, Axel finds out the same man that killed his boss is running an illegal operation with fake money out of an infamous theme park in L.A. Axel has Flint (Elizondo) and his longtime pal, Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) to help him. I love the first movie, and the sequel is highly entertaining. This one, however? It's the definition of disappointment. I'll start off with my biggest gripe about this movie. Why would you have this take place at an amusement park? Who in their right mind thought this was an amusing idea?! It does have some OK action sequences. It has a pretty decent rescue sequence involving a couple of children at the theme park, with a few really memorable stunts. I also didn't like how some of the characters were written. Judge Reinhold was hilarious in the first two movies, but his role seems pointless and contrived here. Taggart (Who is absent because he has retired in Phoenix, according to this movie) is replaced by Hector Elizondo (who is actually quite good) but I just didn't feel the magic anymore. The whole movie feels so artificial, that I had trouble enjoying myself. The finale is especially ludicrous with it's implausibility. It's very reminiscent of the one in Bird on A Wire with Mel Gibson & Goldie Hawn. Eddie Murphy runs out of tricks in this one. He's as watchable as ever, but the script lets him down. Stephen McHattie steals a few scenes he is in as the straight faced agent. John Saxon has a thankless role as an accomplice to the main villain, whilst Timothy Carhart makes for a very bland bad guy as Ellis De Wald. Final Thoughts: I didn't hate this movie, but I was sorely disappointed in it. I was unimpressed the first time I saw it years ago, and my opinion remains the same, after viewing it a second time. I'd only give it a look if nothing else is on. Stick with the first two movies 5.2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Back Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy and Judge Reinhold return again in this sequel, as Axel Foley follows the suspects of a car theft ring to(of course!) Beverly Hills, California, though also Los Angeles, where a counterfeiting ring seems to be operating within the confines of a famous amusement park. There are some stunts involving various rides, in this John Landis directed installment. Nothing new here, except it feels watered down and innocuous, perhaps in response to criticism that Part II was too cold hearted? Either way, this is a silly, lightweight trifle, with actors coasting along without much enthusiasm. Change of setting is different, but this amusement park satire idea was better handled in the first "Vacation" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only slightly better than part II
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zbigniew_Krycsiwiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once again, Detroit cop Murphy returns to BH, this time, after his captain is killed in a shootout in a Detroit chop-shop. Film is pointlessly titled, as it takes place in a fun park, not Beverly Hills (and its title doesn't even appear on-screen at the start, only during the end credits) Screenplay tried desperately hard to be funny, even going as far as bringing back Bronson Pinchot's character for another cameo, as an ex-gallery worker turned gun salesman(?) and recycling the original film's music score, to no avail. It comes off as being a carbon copy sequel in some scenes, while its climactic scenes look like merely an excuse to show us Universal Studios' rides and rollercoasters to climax its repetitive, and thin, plot. Film makes the same mistake part II did, with having one character (Walt Disney clone "Uncle Dave") shot and on his deathbed shortly before Murphy and Reinhold are shot as well, but minutes later, Dave has recovered fully while Murphy and Reinhold are still in casts and wheelchairs at the final scene. Don't get me started on the asinine Spider ride rescue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    cop 3
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well first of without John Ashton the film lacks a lot of laughs, it's seems whoever wrote and produced this didn't give Eddie Murphy near enough good one liners,, like the first two films,, plus the Detroit Police Chief character is gone,, so when they put in new characters,, plus a new villain , then decided to set the main action in an amusement park , i just was like hey wait a minute,, this movie lacked the laughs, and hard bite that the first two had. i really can 't think of that many good things to say about this particular movie,, i hear there is a bhc 4 coming out,, i hope it isn't like 3 at all or i won't even bother with it . there 's some action and some of it is funny not totally unwatchable if it stood alone but compared to 1st two,, i would say that you would have to be crazy to like this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of Murphy's downfall.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TopperHarley29
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wasn't as bad as some people make it out to be, but it still isn't very good. The first movie was the funniest out of all of them and the second one was OK and provided a few good laughs, but this is the weakest. My main problem is that it barely feels like a Beverly Hills Cop movie. It feels like it's a movie about Eddie Murphy hanging out at an amusement park. Some of the jokes are just mildly funny, but the one that stood out the most in my opinion was the counterfeit money with Axel Foley's face. So far this is the only John Landis movie I do not care for which is a shame since he is a good director. This isn't his worst movie, (So far it's The Haunted Mansion.) but it was the beginning of Eddie Murphy's downfall. He tried to redeem himself with Tower Heist, but some idiot made A Thousand Words and now he's back to square one again. I hope he starts acting in good movies again because I don't want him remembered by today's generation as the Daddy Daycare guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not Bad, But Not As Good As The First 2 Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy, Judge Reinhold, Hector Elizondo, Timothy Carhart, Theresa Randle, Alan Young, Gil Hill, Bronson Pinchot and John Saxon star in this 1994 action-comedy sequel. This installment begins in Detroit, Michigan where cop, Axel Foley (Murphy) is on a stakeout. Soon, his boss, Inspector Douglas Todd (Hill) is killed in the crossfire by crooked businessman, Ellis De Wald (Carhart). Axel is determined to avenge Todd and tracks De Wald to Beverly Hills, California where he runs an amusement park, Wonderworld. He also reunites with cop friend, Billy Rosewood (Reinhold) and meets his co-worker, Jon Flynt (Elizondo). Axel gets himself in some snags when he tries to confront De Wald and learns of his counterfeiting scheme. Randle plays Janice, a woman who works for De Wald and gets close with Axel, Young (Mister Ed) plays Wonderworld owner, Uncle Dave Thornton, Saxon (A Nightmare on Elm Street) plays De Wald's associate Orrin Sanderson and Pinchot (Perfect Strangers) appears briefly reprising his role as Serge. There's also cameos by directors, Joe Dante and George Lucas. This sequel isn't bad, but not as good as the first 2 films. I missed John Ashton as John Taggart and it seemed like Elizondo's character, Flynt was kind of a substitute. I'm glad Reinhold came back and like the way they play the late, Harold Faltermeyer's classic theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Stuart
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so disappointed with this film, I loved the original and not only that but the Director, John Landis, made my favourite ever film "An American Werewolf in London". It is un-cinematic, the actors are not engaged, the script is woeful and the pace pedestrian. Every one seemed to just show up for the pay cheque. It's not the worst film ever made but it's a real franchise killer and sticks out as real waste of pedigree considering what came before it and the people involved. O out of 10 for effort, every one concerned should be very, very ashamed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Uneven to Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beverly Hills Cop III (1994) ** (out of 4) Incredibly disappointing third entry in the series has Axel Foley (Eddie Murphy) running an operation on a car theft ring but soon he realizes it's much more than just this. After his boss is murdered he heads back out West to try and find the killers as well as uncover what's really going on. There's really no getting around the fact that this film is a major dud and it's really a shame considering what director John Landis and star Murphy had done together previously. I think it's easy to say this is a very big black spot on both of their careers. The majority of the blame has to go to the screenplay, which offers up a rather silly story full of silly situations, bad characters and some pretty lifeless comedy. It also doesn't help that Landis tries to put his stamp all over the picture, which not only takes it away from what the series was, it also adds some really boring and drawn out moments that should have been left on the cutting room floor. A perfect example happens right at the start when two of the bad guys are singing and dancing around for no real reason to the story. I'm really not sure what Landis was going for here but it's just downright silly. Even worse are some of the characters who are flat out boring including Judge Reinhold who just seems downright out of place. He's basically given nothing to do except stand around and make dumb faces as well as say some really bad dialogue. Even Murphy is pretty forgettable here. I'm not sure if he just wasn't into the film or perhaps he knew he didn't have much to work with. Hector Elizondo adds nothing in his role and the same is true for Timothy Carhart as the bad guy. The film is also incredibly uneven in its style and I'd say that there must have been some real creative control issues going on behind the scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap on a stick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandra DeLonghi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing has NOTHING in common with the original idea. It was more like a cheap-arse cash grab attempt but then falling $10 million short of break even. The problem is that they got it all wrong: Close to no humorous moments, no slapstick, no multiple layers of plot or parallelism, a half hour wasted on a pointless rescue-scene shot with CGI (even Eddie Murphy acted bored doing this), stupid time-wasters such as the "gramma oki doki pushed me" scene, wheeling out the "Serge" figure for five minutes of gay-talk. No suspense, a complete lack of care or passion. Bad writing and sad directing and last but not least fake-landscape-scenery that looked entirely shot in a studio, at a low budget. The music adaptation of Faltermeyer's theme score is inept. In the E/R movie review books this thing would have to be a fat turkey - at best. I was seriously, seriously (did I say SERIOUSLY) let down by this piece of &sect;hit. BO-RING.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the 3 films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it weren't for the amusement park story, this would probably be just another dull entry in the BHC series. Part II was a slight disappointment (at least when it came to anything other than action scenes), but this one is even better than the first movie and a big improvement over part 2. Unlike Part 2, the villains are mean enough (and seen more often), and Murphy doesn't do his comedy as much, which helps. My only quibble is Bronson Pinchot, who I think, didn't really need to be in the movie. His character is completely unnecessary. In fact, I think his appearance in the first movie was also unnecessary. His role is basically comic relief. That's what Murphy is for. It's as if Pinchot is playing a less funny version of Balki from "Perfect Strangers", only he doesn't Larry to annoy. ***1/2 out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonder World, Wonder World. Where a disappointing sequel is the theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Axel Foley's boss gets shot in the middle of a car theft ring. Gunning for revenge, Axel finds out the same man that killed his boss is running an illegal operation with fake money out of an infamous theme park in L.A. Axel has Flint (Elizondo) and his longtime pal, Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) to help him. I love the first movie, and the sequel is highly entertaining. This one, however? It's the definition of disappointment. I'll start off with my biggest gripe about this movie. Why would you have this take place at an amusement park? Who in their right mind thought this was an amusing idea?! It does have some OK action sequences. It has a pretty decent rescue sequence involving a couple of children at the theme park, with a few really memorable stunts. I also didn't like how some of the characters were written. Judge Reinhold was hilarious in the first two movies, but his role seems pointless and contrived here. Taggart (Who is absent because he has retired in Phoenix, according to this movie) is replaced by Hector Elizondo (who is actually quite good) but I just didn't feel the magic anymore. The whole movie feels so artificial, that I had trouble enjoying myself. The finale is especially ludicrous with it's implausibility. It's very reminiscent of the one in Bird on A Wire with Mel Gibson & Goldie Hawn. Eddie Murphy runs out of tricks in this one. He's as watchable as ever, but the script lets him down. Stephen McHattie steals a few scenes he is in as the straight faced agent. John Saxon has a thankless role as an accomplice to the main villain, whilst Timothy Carhart makes for a very bland bad guy as Ellis De Wald. Final Thoughts: I didn't hate this movie, but I was sorely disappointed in it. I was unimpressed the first time I saw it years ago, and my opinion remains the same, after viewing it a second time. I'd only give it a look if nothing else is on. Stick with the first two movies 5.2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Back Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy and Judge Reinhold return again in this sequel, as Axel Foley follows the suspects of a car theft ring to(of course!) Beverly Hills, California, though also Los Angeles, where a counterfeiting ring seems to be operating within the confines of a famous amusement park. There are some stunts involving various rides, in this John Landis directed installment. Nothing new here, except it feels watered down and innocuous, perhaps in response to criticism that Part II was too cold hearted? Either way, this is a silly, lightweight trifle, with actors coasting along without much enthusiasm. Change of setting is different, but this amusement park satire idea was better handled in the first "Vacation" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only slightly better than part II
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zbigniew_Krycsiwiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once again, Detroit cop Murphy returns to BH, this time, after his captain is killed in a shootout in a Detroit chop-shop. Film is pointlessly titled, as it takes place in a fun park, not Beverly Hills (and its title doesn't even appear on-screen at the start, only during the end credits) Screenplay tried desperately hard to be funny, even going as far as bringing back Bronson Pinchot's character for another cameo, as an ex-gallery worker turned gun salesman(?) and recycling the original film's music score, to no avail. It comes off as being a carbon copy sequel in some scenes, while its climactic scenes look like merely an excuse to show us Universal Studios' rides and rollercoasters to climax its repetitive, and thin, plot. Film makes the same mistake part II did, with having one character (Walt Disney clone "Uncle Dave") shot and on his deathbed shortly before Murphy and Reinhold are shot as well, but minutes later, Dave has recovered fully while Murphy and Reinhold are still in casts and wheelchairs at the final scene. Don't get me started on the asinine Spider ride rescue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    cop 3
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well first of without John Ashton the film lacks a lot of laughs, it's seems whoever wrote and produced this didn't give Eddie Murphy near enough good one liners,, like the first two films,, plus the Detroit Police Chief character is gone,, so when they put in new characters,, plus a new villain , then decided to set the main action in an amusement park , i just was like hey wait a minute,, this movie lacked the laughs, and hard bite that the first two had. i really can 't think of that many good things to say about this particular movie,, i hear there is a bhc 4 coming out,, i hope it isn't like 3 at all or i won't even bother with it . there 's some action and some of it is funny not totally unwatchable if it stood alone but compared to 1st two,, i would say that you would have to be crazy to like this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of Murphy's downfall.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TopperHarley29
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wasn't as bad as some people make it out to be, but it still isn't very good. The first movie was the funniest out of all of them and the second one was OK and provided a few good laughs, but this is the weakest. My main problem is that it barely feels like a Beverly Hills Cop movie. It feels like it's a movie about Eddie Murphy hanging out at an amusement park. Some of the jokes are just mildly funny, but the one that stood out the most in my opinion was the counterfeit money with Axel Foley's face. So far this is the only John Landis movie I do not care for which is a shame since he is a good director. This isn't his worst movie, (So far it's The Haunted Mansion.) but it was the beginning of Eddie Murphy's downfall. He tried to redeem himself with Tower Heist, but some idiot made A Thousand Words and now he's back to square one again. I hope he starts acting in good movies again because I don't want him remembered by today's generation as the Daddy Daycare guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not Bad, But Not As Good As The First 2 Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy, Judge Reinhold, Hector Elizondo, Timothy Carhart, Theresa Randle, Alan Young, Gil Hill, Bronson Pinchot and John Saxon star in this 1994 action-comedy sequel. This installment begins in Detroit, Michigan where cop, Axel Foley (Murphy) is on a stakeout. Soon, his boss, Inspector Douglas Todd (Hill) is killed in the crossfire by crooked businessman, Ellis De Wald (Carhart). Axel is determined to avenge Todd and tracks De Wald to Beverly Hills, California where he runs an amusement park, Wonderworld. He also reunites with cop friend, Billy Rosewood (Reinhold) and meets his co-worker, Jon Flynt (Elizondo). Axel gets himself in some snags when he tries to confront De Wald and learns of his counterfeiting scheme. Randle plays Janice, a woman who works for De Wald and gets close with Axel, Young (Mister Ed) plays Wonderworld owner, Uncle Dave Thornton, Saxon (A Nightmare on Elm Street) plays De Wald's associate Orrin Sanderson and Pinchot (Perfect Strangers) appears briefly reprising his role as Serge. There's also cameos by directors, Joe Dante and George Lucas. This sequel isn't bad, but not as good as the first 2 films. I missed John Ashton as John Taggart and it seemed like Elizondo's character, Flynt was kind of a substitute. I'm glad Reinhold came back and like the way they play the late, Harold Faltermeyer's classic theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Stuart
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so disappointed with this film, I loved the original and not only that but the Director, John Landis, made my favourite ever film "An American Werewolf in London". It is un-cinematic, the actors are not engaged, the script is woeful and the pace pedestrian. Every one seemed to just show up for the pay cheque. It's not the worst film ever made but it's a real franchise killer and sticks out as real waste of pedigree considering what came before it and the people involved. O out of 10 for effort, every one concerned should be very, very ashamed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Uneven to Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beverly Hills Cop III (1994) ** (out of 4) Incredibly disappointing third entry in the series has Axel Foley (Eddie Murphy) running an operation on a car theft ring but soon he realizes it's much more than just this. After his boss is murdered he heads back out West to try and find the killers as well as uncover what's really going on. There's really no getting around the fact that this film is a major dud and it's really a shame considering what director John Landis and star Murphy had done together previously. I think it's easy to say this is a very big black spot on both of their careers. The majority of the blame has to go to the screenplay, which offers up a rather silly story full of silly situations, bad characters and some pretty lifeless comedy. It also doesn't help that Landis tries to put his stamp all over the picture, which not only takes it away from what the series was, it also adds some really boring and drawn out moments that should have been left on the cutting room floor. A perfect example happens right at the start when two of the bad guys are singing and dancing around for no real reason to the story. I'm really not sure what Landis was going for here but it's just downright silly. Even worse are some of the characters who are flat out boring including Judge Reinhold who just seems downright out of place. He's basically given nothing to do except stand around and make dumb faces as well as say some really bad dialogue. Even Murphy is pretty forgettable here. I'm not sure if he just wasn't into the film or perhaps he knew he didn't have much to work with. Hector Elizondo adds nothing in his role and the same is true for Timothy Carhart as the bad guy. The film is also incredibly uneven in its style and I'd say that there must have been some real creative control issues going on behind the scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap on a stick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandra DeLonghi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing has NOTHING in common with the original idea. It was more like a cheap-arse cash grab attempt but then falling $10 million short of break even. The problem is that they got it all wrong: Close to no humorous moments, no slapstick, no multiple layers of plot or parallelism, a half hour wasted on a pointless rescue-scene shot with CGI (even Eddie Murphy acted bored doing this), stupid time-wasters such as the "gramma oki doki pushed me" scene, wheeling out the "Serge" figure for five minutes of gay-talk. No suspense, a complete lack of care or passion. Bad writing and sad directing and last but not least fake-landscape-scenery that looked entirely shot in a studio, at a low budget. The music adaptation of Faltermeyer's theme score is inept. In the E/R movie review books this thing would have to be a fat turkey - at best. I was seriously, seriously (did I say SERIOUSLY) let down by this piece of &sect;hit. BO-RING.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the 3 films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it weren't for the amusement park story, this would probably be just another dull entry in the BHC series. Part II was a slight disappointment (at least when it came to anything other than action scenes), but this one is even better than the first movie and a big improvement over part 2. Unlike Part 2, the villains are mean enough (and seen more often), and Murphy doesn't do his comedy as much, which helps. My only quibble is Bronson Pinchot, who I think, didn't really need to be in the movie. His character is completely unnecessary. In fact, I think his appearance in the first movie was also unnecessary. His role is basically comic relief. That's what Murphy is for. It's as if Pinchot is playing a less funny version of Balki from "Perfect Strangers", only he doesn't Larry to annoy. ***1/2 out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonder World, Wonder World. Where a disappointing sequel is the theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Axel Foley's boss gets shot in the middle of a car theft ring. Gunning for revenge, Axel finds out the same man that killed his boss is running an illegal operation with fake money out of an infamous theme park in L.A. Axel has Flint (Elizondo) and his longtime pal, Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) to help him. I love the first movie, and the sequel is highly entertaining. This one, however? It's the definition of disappointment. I'll start off with my biggest gripe about this movie. Why would you have this take place at an amusement park? Who in their right mind thought this was an amusing idea?! It does have some OK action sequences. It has a pretty decent rescue sequence involving a couple of children at the theme park, with a few really memorable stunts. I also didn't like how some of the characters were written. Judge Reinhold was hilarious in the first two movies, but his role seems pointless and contrived here. Taggart (Who is absent because he has retired in Phoenix, according to this movie) is replaced by Hector Elizondo (who is actually quite good) but I just didn't feel the magic anymore. The whole movie feels so artificial, that I had trouble enjoying myself. The finale is especially ludicrous with it's implausibility. It's very reminiscent of the one in Bird on A Wire with Mel Gibson & Goldie Hawn. Eddie Murphy runs out of tricks in this one. He's as watchable as ever, but the script lets him down. Stephen McHattie steals a few scenes he is in as the straight faced agent. John Saxon has a thankless role as an accomplice to the main villain, whilst Timothy Carhart makes for a very bland bad guy as Ellis De Wald. Final Thoughts: I didn't hate this movie, but I was sorely disappointed in it. I was unimpressed the first time I saw it years ago, and my opinion remains the same, after viewing it a second time. I'd only give it a look if nothing else is on. Stick with the first two movies 5.2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Back Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy and Judge Reinhold return again in this sequel, as Axel Foley follows the suspects of a car theft ring to(of course!) Beverly Hills, California, though also Los Angeles, where a counterfeiting ring seems to be operating within the confines of a famous amusement park. There are some stunts involving various rides, in this John Landis directed installment. Nothing new here, except it feels watered down and innocuous, perhaps in response to criticism that Part II was too cold hearted? Either way, this is a silly, lightweight trifle, with actors coasting along without much enthusiasm. Change of setting is different, but this amusement park satire idea was better handled in the first "Vacation" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only slightly better than part II
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zbigniew_Krycsiwiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once again, Detroit cop Murphy returns to BH, this time, after his captain is killed in a shootout in a Detroit chop-shop. Film is pointlessly titled, as it takes place in a fun park, not Beverly Hills (and its title doesn't even appear on-screen at the start, only during the end credits) Screenplay tried desperately hard to be funny, even going as far as bringing back Bronson Pinchot's character for another cameo, as an ex-gallery worker turned gun salesman(?) and recycling the original film's music score, to no avail. It comes off as being a carbon copy sequel in some scenes, while its climactic scenes look like merely an excuse to show us Universal Studios' rides and rollercoasters to climax its repetitive, and thin, plot. Film makes the same mistake part II did, with having one character (Walt Disney clone "Uncle Dave") shot and on his deathbed shortly before Murphy and Reinhold are shot as well, but minutes later, Dave has recovered fully while Murphy and Reinhold are still in casts and wheelchairs at the final scene. Don't get me started on the asinine Spider ride rescue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    cop 3
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well first of without John Ashton the film lacks a lot of laughs, it's seems whoever wrote and produced this didn't give Eddie Murphy near enough good one liners,, like the first two films,, plus the Detroit Police Chief character is gone,, so when they put in new characters,, plus a new villain , then decided to set the main action in an amusement park , i just was like hey wait a minute,, this movie lacked the laughs, and hard bite that the first two had. i really can 't think of that many good things to say about this particular movie,, i hear there is a bhc 4 coming out,, i hope it isn't like 3 at all or i won't even bother with it . there 's some action and some of it is funny not totally unwatchable if it stood alone but compared to 1st two,, i would say that you would have to be crazy to like this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of Murphy's downfall.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TopperHarley29
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wasn't as bad as some people make it out to be, but it still isn't very good. The first movie was the funniest out of all of them and the second one was OK and provided a few good laughs, but this is the weakest. My main problem is that it barely feels like a Beverly Hills Cop movie. It feels like it's a movie about Eddie Murphy hanging out at an amusement park. Some of the jokes are just mildly funny, but the one that stood out the most in my opinion was the counterfeit money with Axel Foley's face. So far this is the only John Landis movie I do not care for which is a shame since he is a good director. This isn't his worst movie, (So far it's The Haunted Mansion.) but it was the beginning of Eddie Murphy's downfall. He tried to redeem himself with Tower Heist, but some idiot made A Thousand Words and now he's back to square one again. I hope he starts acting in good movies again because I don't want him remembered by today's generation as the Daddy Daycare guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not Bad, But Not As Good As The First 2 Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy, Judge Reinhold, Hector Elizondo, Timothy Carhart, Theresa Randle, Alan Young, Gil Hill, Bronson Pinchot and John Saxon star in this 1994 action-comedy sequel. This installment begins in Detroit, Michigan where cop, Axel Foley (Murphy) is on a stakeout. Soon, his boss, Inspector Douglas Todd (Hill) is killed in the crossfire by crooked businessman, Ellis De Wald (Carhart). Axel is determined to avenge Todd and tracks De Wald to Beverly Hills, California where he runs an amusement park, Wonderworld. He also reunites with cop friend, Billy Rosewood (Reinhold) and meets his co-worker, Jon Flynt (Elizondo). Axel gets himself in some snags when he tries to confront De Wald and learns of his counterfeiting scheme. Randle plays Janice, a woman who works for De Wald and gets close with Axel, Young (Mister Ed) plays Wonderworld owner, Uncle Dave Thornton, Saxon (A Nightmare on Elm Street) plays De Wald's associate Orrin Sanderson and Pinchot (Perfect Strangers) appears briefly reprising his role as Serge. There's also cameos by directors, Joe Dante and George Lucas. This sequel isn't bad, but not as good as the first 2 films. I missed John Ashton as John Taggart and it seemed like Elizondo's character, Flynt was kind of a substitute. I'm glad Reinhold came back and like the way they play the late, Harold Faltermeyer's classic theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Stuart
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so disappointed with this film, I loved the original and not only that but the Director, John Landis, made my favourite ever film "An American Werewolf in London". It is un-cinematic, the actors are not engaged, the script is woeful and the pace pedestrian. Every one seemed to just show up for the pay cheque. It's not the worst film ever made but it's a real franchise killer and sticks out as real waste of pedigree considering what came before it and the people involved. O out of 10 for effort, every one concerned should be very, very ashamed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Uneven to Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beverly Hills Cop III (1994) ** (out of 4) Incredibly disappointing third entry in the series has Axel Foley (Eddie Murphy) running an operation on a car theft ring but soon he realizes it's much more than just this. After his boss is murdered he heads back out West to try and find the killers as well as uncover what's really going on. There's really no getting around the fact that this film is a major dud and it's really a shame considering what director John Landis and star Murphy had done together previously. I think it's easy to say this is a very big black spot on both of their careers. The majority of the blame has to go to the screenplay, which offers up a rather silly story full of silly situations, bad characters and some pretty lifeless comedy. It also doesn't help that Landis tries to put his stamp all over the picture, which not only takes it away from what the series was, it also adds some really boring and drawn out moments that should have been left on the cutting room floor. A perfect example happens right at the start when two of the bad guys are singing and dancing around for no real reason to the story. I'm really not sure what Landis was going for here but it's just downright silly. Even worse are some of the characters who are flat out boring including Judge Reinhold who just seems downright out of place. He's basically given nothing to do except stand around and make dumb faces as well as say some really bad dialogue. Even Murphy is pretty forgettable here. I'm not sure if he just wasn't into the film or perhaps he knew he didn't have much to work with. Hector Elizondo adds nothing in his role and the same is true for Timothy Carhart as the bad guy. The film is also incredibly uneven in its style and I'd say that there must have been some real creative control issues going on behind the scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap on a stick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandra DeLonghi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing has NOTHING in common with the original idea. It was more like a cheap-arse cash grab attempt but then falling $10 million short of break even. The problem is that they got it all wrong: Close to no humorous moments, no slapstick, no multiple layers of plot or parallelism, a half hour wasted on a pointless rescue-scene shot with CGI (even Eddie Murphy acted bored doing this), stupid time-wasters such as the "gramma oki doki pushed me" scene, wheeling out the "Serge" figure for five minutes of gay-talk. No suspense, a complete lack of care or passion. Bad writing and sad directing and last but not least fake-landscape-scenery that looked entirely shot in a studio, at a low budget. The music adaptation of Faltermeyer's theme score is inept. In the E/R movie review books this thing would have to be a fat turkey - at best. I was seriously, seriously (did I say SERIOUSLY) let down by this piece of &sect;hit. BO-RING.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the 3 films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it weren't for the amusement park story, this would probably be just another dull entry in the BHC series. Part II was a slight disappointment (at least when it came to anything other than action scenes), but this one is even better than the first movie and a big improvement over part 2. Unlike Part 2, the villains are mean enough (and seen more often), and Murphy doesn't do his comedy as much, which helps. My only quibble is Bronson Pinchot, who I think, didn't really need to be in the movie. His character is completely unnecessary. In fact, I think his appearance in the first movie was also unnecessary. His role is basically comic relief. That's what Murphy is for. It's as if Pinchot is playing a less funny version of Balki from "Perfect Strangers", only he doesn't Larry to annoy. ***1/2 out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonder World, Wonder World. Where a disappointing sequel is the theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Axel Foley's boss gets shot in the middle of a car theft ring. Gunning for revenge, Axel finds out the same man that killed his boss is running an illegal operation with fake money out of an infamous theme park in L.A. Axel has Flint (Elizondo) and his longtime pal, Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) to help him. I love the first movie, and the sequel is highly entertaining. This one, however? It's the definition of disappointment. I'll start off with my biggest gripe about this movie. Why would you have this take place at an amusement park? Who in their right mind thought this was an amusing idea?! It does have some OK action sequences. It has a pretty decent rescue sequence involving a couple of children at the theme park, with a few really memorable stunts. I also didn't like how some of the characters were written. Judge Reinhold was hilarious in the first two movies, but his role seems pointless and contrived here. Taggart (Who is absent because he has retired in Phoenix, according to this movie) is replaced by Hector Elizondo (who is actually quite good) but I just didn't feel the magic anymore. The whole movie feels so artificial, that I had trouble enjoying myself. The finale is especially ludicrous with it's implausibility. It's very reminiscent of the one in Bird on A Wire with Mel Gibson & Goldie Hawn. Eddie Murphy runs out of tricks in this one. He's as watchable as ever, but the script lets him down. Stephen McHattie steals a few scenes he is in as the straight faced agent. John Saxon has a thankless role as an accomplice to the main villain, whilst Timothy Carhart makes for a very bland bad guy as Ellis De Wald. Final Thoughts: I didn't hate this movie, but I was sorely disappointed in it. I was unimpressed the first time I saw it years ago, and my opinion remains the same, after viewing it a second time. I'd only give it a look if nothing else is on. Stick with the first two movies 5.2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Back Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy and Judge Reinhold return again in this sequel, as Axel Foley follows the suspects of a car theft ring to(of course!) Beverly Hills, California, though also Los Angeles, where a counterfeiting ring seems to be operating within the confines of a famous amusement park. There are some stunts involving various rides, in this John Landis directed installment. Nothing new here, except it feels watered down and innocuous, perhaps in response to criticism that Part II was too cold hearted? Either way, this is a silly, lightweight trifle, with actors coasting along without much enthusiasm. Change of setting is different, but this amusement park satire idea was better handled in the first "Vacation" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only slightly better than part II
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zbigniew_Krycsiwiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once again, Detroit cop Murphy returns to BH, this time, after his captain is killed in a shootout in a Detroit chop-shop. Film is pointlessly titled, as it takes place in a fun park, not Beverly Hills (and its title doesn't even appear on-screen at the start, only during the end credits) Screenplay tried desperately hard to be funny, even going as far as bringing back Bronson Pinchot's character for another cameo, as an ex-gallery worker turned gun salesman(?) and recycling the original film's music score, to no avail. It comes off as being a carbon copy sequel in some scenes, while its climactic scenes look like merely an excuse to show us Universal Studios' rides and rollercoasters to climax its repetitive, and thin, plot. Film makes the same mistake part II did, with having one character (Walt Disney clone "Uncle Dave") shot and on his deathbed shortly before Murphy and Reinhold are shot as well, but minutes later, Dave has recovered fully while Murphy and Reinhold are still in casts and wheelchairs at the final scene. Don't get me started on the asinine Spider ride rescue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    cop 3
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well first of without John Ashton the film lacks a lot of laughs, it's seems whoever wrote and produced this didn't give Eddie Murphy near enough good one liners,, like the first two films,, plus the Detroit Police Chief character is gone,, so when they put in new characters,, plus a new villain , then decided to set the main action in an amusement park , i just was like hey wait a minute,, this movie lacked the laughs, and hard bite that the first two had. i really can 't think of that many good things to say about this particular movie,, i hear there is a bhc 4 coming out,, i hope it isn't like 3 at all or i won't even bother with it . there 's some action and some of it is funny not totally unwatchable if it stood alone but compared to 1st two,, i would say that you would have to be crazy to like this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of Murphy's downfall.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TopperHarley29
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wasn't as bad as some people make it out to be, but it still isn't very good. The first movie was the funniest out of all of them and the second one was OK and provided a few good laughs, but this is the weakest. My main problem is that it barely feels like a Beverly Hills Cop movie. It feels like it's a movie about Eddie Murphy hanging out at an amusement park. Some of the jokes are just mildly funny, but the one that stood out the most in my opinion was the counterfeit money with Axel Foley's face. So far this is the only John Landis movie I do not care for which is a shame since he is a good director. This isn't his worst movie, (So far it's The Haunted Mansion.) but it was the beginning of Eddie Murphy's downfall. He tried to redeem himself with Tower Heist, but some idiot made A Thousand Words and now he's back to square one again. I hope he starts acting in good movies again because I don't want him remembered by today's generation as the Daddy Daycare guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not Bad, But Not As Good As The First 2 Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy, Judge Reinhold, Hector Elizondo, Timothy Carhart, Theresa Randle, Alan Young, Gil Hill, Bronson Pinchot and John Saxon star in this 1994 action-comedy sequel. This installment begins in Detroit, Michigan where cop, Axel Foley (Murphy) is on a stakeout. Soon, his boss, Inspector Douglas Todd (Hill) is killed in the crossfire by crooked businessman, Ellis De Wald (Carhart). Axel is determined to avenge Todd and tracks De Wald to Beverly Hills, California where he runs an amusement park, Wonderworld. He also reunites with cop friend, Billy Rosewood (Reinhold) and meets his co-worker, Jon Flynt (Elizondo). Axel gets himself in some snags when he tries to confront De Wald and learns of his counterfeiting scheme. Randle plays Janice, a woman who works for De Wald and gets close with Axel, Young (Mister Ed) plays Wonderworld owner, Uncle Dave Thornton, Saxon (A Nightmare on Elm Street) plays De Wald's associate Orrin Sanderson and Pinchot (Perfect Strangers) appears briefly reprising his role as Serge. There's also cameos by directors, Joe Dante and George Lucas. This sequel isn't bad, but not as good as the first 2 films. I missed John Ashton as John Taggart and it seemed like Elizondo's character, Flynt was kind of a substitute. I'm glad Reinhold came back and like the way they play the late, Harold Faltermeyer's classic theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Stuart
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so disappointed with this film, I loved the original and not only that but the Director, John Landis, made my favourite ever film "An American Werewolf in London". It is un-cinematic, the actors are not engaged, the script is woeful and the pace pedestrian. Every one seemed to just show up for the pay cheque. It's not the worst film ever made but it's a real franchise killer and sticks out as real waste of pedigree considering what came before it and the people involved. O out of 10 for effort, every one concerned should be very, very ashamed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Uneven to Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beverly Hills Cop III (1994) ** (out of 4) Incredibly disappointing third entry in the series has Axel Foley (Eddie Murphy) running an operation on a car theft ring but soon he realizes it's much more than just this. After his boss is murdered he heads back out West to try and find the killers as well as uncover what's really going on. There's really no getting around the fact that this film is a major dud and it's really a shame considering what director John Landis and star Murphy had done together previously. I think it's easy to say this is a very big black spot on both of their careers. The majority of the blame has to go to the screenplay, which offers up a rather silly story full of silly situations, bad characters and some pretty lifeless comedy. It also doesn't help that Landis tries to put his stamp all over the picture, which not only takes it away from what the series was, it also adds some really boring and drawn out moments that should have been left on the cutting room floor. A perfect example happens right at the start when two of the bad guys are singing and dancing around for no real reason to the story. I'm really not sure what Landis was going for here but it's just downright silly. Even worse are some of the characters who are flat out boring including Judge Reinhold who just seems downright out of place. He's basically given nothing to do except stand around and make dumb faces as well as say some really bad dialogue. Even Murphy is pretty forgettable here. I'm not sure if he just wasn't into the film or perhaps he knew he didn't have much to work with. Hector Elizondo adds nothing in his role and the same is true for Timothy Carhart as the bad guy. The film is also incredibly uneven in its style and I'd say that there must have been some real creative control issues going on behind the scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap on a stick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandra DeLonghi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing has NOTHING in common with the original idea. It was more like a cheap-arse cash grab attempt but then falling $10 million short of break even. The problem is that they got it all wrong: Close to no humorous moments, no slapstick, no multiple layers of plot or parallelism, a half hour wasted on a pointless rescue-scene shot with CGI (even Eddie Murphy acted bored doing this), stupid time-wasters such as the "gramma oki doki pushed me" scene, wheeling out the "Serge" figure for five minutes of gay-talk. No suspense, a complete lack of care or passion. Bad writing and sad directing and last but not least fake-landscape-scenery that looked entirely shot in a studio, at a low budget. The music adaptation of Faltermeyer's theme score is inept. In the E/R movie review books this thing would have to be a fat turkey - at best. I was seriously, seriously (did I say SERIOUSLY) let down by this piece of &sect;hit. BO-RING.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the 3 films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it weren't for the amusement park story, this would probably be just another dull entry in the BHC series. Part II was a slight disappointment (at least when it came to anything other than action scenes), but this one is even better than the first movie and a big improvement over part 2. Unlike Part 2, the villains are mean enough (and seen more often), and Murphy doesn't do his comedy as much, which helps. My only quibble is Bronson Pinchot, who I think, didn't really need to be in the movie. His character is completely unnecessary. In fact, I think his appearance in the first movie was also unnecessary. His role is basically comic relief. That's what Murphy is for. It's as if Pinchot is playing a less funny version of Balki from "Perfect Strangers", only he doesn't Larry to annoy. ***1/2 out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonder World, Wonder World. Where a disappointing sequel is the theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Axel Foley's boss gets shot in the middle of a car theft ring. Gunning for revenge, Axel finds out the same man that killed his boss is running an illegal operation with fake money out of an infamous theme park in L.A. Axel has Flint (Elizondo) and his longtime pal, Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) to help him. I love the first movie, and the sequel is highly entertaining. This one, however? It's the definition of disappointment. I'll start off with my biggest gripe about this movie. Why would you have this take place at an amusement park? Who in their right mind thought this was an amusing idea?! It does have some OK action sequences. It has a pretty decent rescue sequence involving a couple of children at the theme park, with a few really memorable stunts. I also didn't like how some of the characters were written. Judge Reinhold was hilarious in the first two movies, but his role seems pointless and contrived here. Taggart (Who is absent because he has retired in Phoenix, according to this movie) is replaced by Hector Elizondo (who is actually quite good) but I just didn't feel the magic anymore. The whole movie feels so artificial, that I had trouble enjoying myself. The finale is especially ludicrous with it's implausibility. It's very reminiscent of the one in Bird on A Wire with Mel Gibson & Goldie Hawn. Eddie Murphy runs out of tricks in this one. He's as watchable as ever, but the script lets him down. Stephen McHattie steals a few scenes he is in as the straight faced agent. John Saxon has a thankless role as an accomplice to the main villain, whilst Timothy Carhart makes for a very bland bad guy as Ellis De Wald. Final Thoughts: I didn't hate this movie, but I was sorely disappointed in it. I was unimpressed the first time I saw it years ago, and my opinion remains the same, after viewing it a second time. I'd only give it a look if nothing else is on. Stick with the first two movies 5.2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Back Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy and Judge Reinhold return again in this sequel, as Axel Foley follows the suspects of a car theft ring to(of course!) Beverly Hills, California, though also Los Angeles, where a counterfeiting ring seems to be operating within the confines of a famous amusement park. There are some stunts involving various rides, in this John Landis directed installment. Nothing new here, except it feels watered down and innocuous, perhaps in response to criticism that Part II was too cold hearted? Either way, this is a silly, lightweight trifle, with actors coasting along without much enthusiasm. Change of setting is different, but this amusement park satire idea was better handled in the first "Vacation" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only slightly better than part II
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zbigniew_Krycsiwiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once again, Detroit cop Murphy returns to BH, this time, after his captain is killed in a shootout in a Detroit chop-shop. Film is pointlessly titled, as it takes place in a fun park, not Beverly Hills (and its title doesn't even appear on-screen at the start, only during the end credits) Screenplay tried desperately hard to be funny, even going as far as bringing back Bronson Pinchot's character for another cameo, as an ex-gallery worker turned gun salesman(?) and recycling the original film's music score, to no avail. It comes off as being a carbon copy sequel in some scenes, while its climactic scenes look like merely an excuse to show us Universal Studios' rides and rollercoasters to climax its repetitive, and thin, plot. Film makes the same mistake part II did, with having one character (Walt Disney clone "Uncle Dave") shot and on his deathbed shortly before Murphy and Reinhold are shot as well, but minutes later, Dave has recovered fully while Murphy and Reinhold are still in casts and wheelchairs at the final scene. Don't get me started on the asinine Spider ride rescue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    cop 3
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well first of without John Ashton the film lacks a lot of laughs, it's seems whoever wrote and produced this didn't give Eddie Murphy near enough good one liners,, like the first two films,, plus the Detroit Police Chief character is gone,, so when they put in new characters,, plus a new villain , then decided to set the main action in an amusement park , i just was like hey wait a minute,, this movie lacked the laughs, and hard bite that the first two had. i really can 't think of that many good things to say about this particular movie,, i hear there is a bhc 4 coming out,, i hope it isn't like 3 at all or i won't even bother with it . there 's some action and some of it is funny not totally unwatchable if it stood alone but compared to 1st two,, i would say that you would have to be crazy to like this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of Murphy's downfall.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TopperHarley29
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wasn't as bad as some people make it out to be, but it still isn't very good. The first movie was the funniest out of all of them and the second one was OK and provided a few good laughs, but this is the weakest. My main problem is that it barely feels like a Beverly Hills Cop movie. It feels like it's a movie about Eddie Murphy hanging out at an amusement park. Some of the jokes are just mildly funny, but the one that stood out the most in my opinion was the counterfeit money with Axel Foley's face. So far this is the only John Landis movie I do not care for which is a shame since he is a good director. This isn't his worst movie, (So far it's The Haunted Mansion.) but it was the beginning of Eddie Murphy's downfall. He tried to redeem himself with Tower Heist, but some idiot made A Thousand Words and now he's back to square one again. I hope he starts acting in good movies again because I don't want him remembered by today's generation as the Daddy Daycare guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not Bad, But Not As Good As The First 2 Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy, Judge Reinhold, Hector Elizondo, Timothy Carhart, Theresa Randle, Alan Young, Gil Hill, Bronson Pinchot and John Saxon star in this 1994 action-comedy sequel. This installment begins in Detroit, Michigan where cop, Axel Foley (Murphy) is on a stakeout. Soon, his boss, Inspector Douglas Todd (Hill) is killed in the crossfire by crooked businessman, Ellis De Wald (Carhart). Axel is determined to avenge Todd and tracks De Wald to Beverly Hills, California where he runs an amusement park, Wonderworld. He also reunites with cop friend, Billy Rosewood (Reinhold) and meets his co-worker, Jon Flynt (Elizondo). Axel gets himself in some snags when he tries to confront De Wald and learns of his counterfeiting scheme. Randle plays Janice, a woman who works for De Wald and gets close with Axel, Young (Mister Ed) plays Wonderworld owner, Uncle Dave Thornton, Saxon (A Nightmare on Elm Street) plays De Wald's associate Orrin Sanderson and Pinchot (Perfect Strangers) appears briefly reprising his role as Serge. There's also cameos by directors, Joe Dante and George Lucas. This sequel isn't bad, but not as good as the first 2 films. I missed John Ashton as John Taggart and it seemed like Elizondo's character, Flynt was kind of a substitute. I'm glad Reinhold came back and like the way they play the late, Harold Faltermeyer's classic theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Stuart
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so disappointed with this film, I loved the original and not only that but the Director, John Landis, made my favourite ever film "An American Werewolf in London". It is un-cinematic, the actors are not engaged, the script is woeful and the pace pedestrian. Every one seemed to just show up for the pay cheque. It's not the worst film ever made but it's a real franchise killer and sticks out as real waste of pedigree considering what came before it and the people involved. O out of 10 for effort, every one concerned should be very, very ashamed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Uneven to Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beverly Hills Cop III (1994) ** (out of 4) Incredibly disappointing third entry in the series has Axel Foley (Eddie Murphy) running an operation on a car theft ring but soon he realizes it's much more than just this. After his boss is murdered he heads back out West to try and find the killers as well as uncover what's really going on. There's really no getting around the fact that this film is a major dud and it's really a shame considering what director John Landis and star Murphy had done together previously. I think it's easy to say this is a very big black spot on both of their careers. The majority of the blame has to go to the screenplay, which offers up a rather silly story full of silly situations, bad characters and some pretty lifeless comedy. It also doesn't help that Landis tries to put his stamp all over the picture, which not only takes it away from what the series was, it also adds some really boring and drawn out moments that should have been left on the cutting room floor. A perfect example happens right at the start when two of the bad guys are singing and dancing around for no real reason to the story. I'm really not sure what Landis was going for here but it's just downright silly. Even worse are some of the characters who are flat out boring including Judge Reinhold who just seems downright out of place. He's basically given nothing to do except stand around and make dumb faces as well as say some really bad dialogue. Even Murphy is pretty forgettable here. I'm not sure if he just wasn't into the film or perhaps he knew he didn't have much to work with. Hector Elizondo adds nothing in his role and the same is true for Timothy Carhart as the bad guy. The film is also incredibly uneven in its style and I'd say that there must have been some real creative control issues going on behind the scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap on a stick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandra DeLonghi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing has NOTHING in common with the original idea. It was more like a cheap-arse cash grab attempt but then falling $10 million short of break even. The problem is that they got it all wrong: Close to no humorous moments, no slapstick, no multiple layers of plot or parallelism, a half hour wasted on a pointless rescue-scene shot with CGI (even Eddie Murphy acted bored doing this), stupid time-wasters such as the "gramma oki doki pushed me" scene, wheeling out the "Serge" figure for five minutes of gay-talk. No suspense, a complete lack of care or passion. Bad writing and sad directing and last but not least fake-landscape-scenery that looked entirely shot in a studio, at a low budget. The music adaptation of Faltermeyer's theme score is inept. In the E/R movie review books this thing would have to be a fat turkey - at best. I was seriously, seriously (did I say SERIOUSLY) let down by this piece of &sect;hit. BO-RING.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the 3 films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it weren't for the amusement park story, this would probably be just another dull entry in the BHC series. Part II was a slight disappointment (at least when it came to anything other than action scenes), but this one is even better than the first movie and a big improvement over part 2. Unlike Part 2, the villains are mean enough (and seen more often), and Murphy doesn't do his comedy as much, which helps. My only quibble is Bronson Pinchot, who I think, didn't really need to be in the movie. His character is completely unnecessary. In fact, I think his appearance in the first movie was also unnecessary. His role is basically comic relief. That's what Murphy is for. It's as if Pinchot is playing a less funny version of Balki from "Perfect Strangers", only he doesn't Larry to annoy. ***1/2 out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonder World, Wonder World. Where a disappointing sequel is the theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Axel Foley's boss gets shot in the middle of a car theft ring. Gunning for revenge, Axel finds out the same man that killed his boss is running an illegal operation with fake money out of an infamous theme park in L.A. Axel has Flint (Elizondo) and his longtime pal, Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) to help him. I love the first movie, and the sequel is highly entertaining. This one, however? It's the definition of disappointment. I'll start off with my biggest gripe about this movie. Why would you have this take place at an amusement park? Who in their right mind thought this was an amusing idea?! It does have some OK action sequences. It has a pretty decent rescue sequence involving a couple of children at the theme park, with a few really memorable stunts. I also didn't like how some of the characters were written. Judge Reinhold was hilarious in the first two movies, but his role seems pointless and contrived here. Taggart (Who is absent because he has retired in Phoenix, according to this movie) is replaced by Hector Elizondo (who is actually quite good) but I just didn't feel the magic anymore. The whole movie feels so artificial, that I had trouble enjoying myself. The finale is especially ludicrous with it's implausibility. It's very reminiscent of the one in Bird on A Wire with Mel Gibson & Goldie Hawn. Eddie Murphy runs out of tricks in this one. He's as watchable as ever, but the script lets him down. Stephen McHattie steals a few scenes he is in as the straight faced agent. John Saxon has a thankless role as an accomplice to the main villain, whilst Timothy Carhart makes for a very bland bad guy as Ellis De Wald. Final Thoughts: I didn't hate this movie, but I was sorely disappointed in it. I was unimpressed the first time I saw it years ago, and my opinion remains the same, after viewing it a second time. I'd only give it a look if nothing else is on. Stick with the first two movies 5.2/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Back Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy and Judge Reinhold return again in this sequel, as Axel Foley follows the suspects of a car theft ring to(of course!) Beverly Hills, California, though also Los Angeles, where a counterfeiting ring seems to be operating within the confines of a famous amusement park. There are some stunts involving various rides, in this John Landis directed installment. Nothing new here, except it feels watered down and innocuous, perhaps in response to criticism that Part II was too cold hearted? Either way, this is a silly, lightweight trifle, with actors coasting along without much enthusiasm. Change of setting is different, but this amusement park satire idea was better handled in the first "Vacation" film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only slightly better than part II
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zbigniew_Krycsiwiki
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Once again, Detroit cop Murphy returns to BH, this time, after his captain is killed in a shootout in a Detroit chop-shop. Film is pointlessly titled, as it takes place in a fun park, not Beverly Hills (and its title doesn't even appear on-screen at the start, only during the end credits) Screenplay tried desperately hard to be funny, even going as far as bringing back Bronson Pinchot's character for another cameo, as an ex-gallery worker turned gun salesman(?) and recycling the original film's music score, to no avail. It comes off as being a carbon copy sequel in some scenes, while its climactic scenes look like merely an excuse to show us Universal Studios' rides and rollercoasters to climax its repetitive, and thin, plot. Film makes the same mistake part II did, with having one character (Walt Disney clone "Uncle Dave") shot and on his deathbed shortly before Murphy and Reinhold are shot as well, but minutes later, Dave has recovered fully while Murphy and Reinhold are still in casts and wheelchairs at the final scene. Don't get me started on the asinine Spider ride rescue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    cop 3
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    well first of without John Ashton the film lacks a lot of laughs, it's seems whoever wrote and produced this didn't give Eddie Murphy near enough good one liners,, like the first two films,, plus the Detroit Police Chief character is gone,, so when they put in new characters,, plus a new villain , then decided to set the main action in an amusement park , i just was like hey wait a minute,, this movie lacked the laughs, and hard bite that the first two had. i really can 't think of that many good things to say about this particular movie,, i hear there is a bhc 4 coming out,, i hope it isn't like 3 at all or i won't even bother with it . there 's some action and some of it is funny not totally unwatchable if it stood alone but compared to 1st two,, i would say that you would have to be crazy to like this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of Murphy's downfall.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TopperHarley29
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wasn't as bad as some people make it out to be, but it still isn't very good. The first movie was the funniest out of all of them and the second one was OK and provided a few good laughs, but this is the weakest. My main problem is that it barely feels like a Beverly Hills Cop movie. It feels like it's a movie about Eddie Murphy hanging out at an amusement park. Some of the jokes are just mildly funny, but the one that stood out the most in my opinion was the counterfeit money with Axel Foley's face. So far this is the only John Landis movie I do not care for which is a shame since he is a good director. This isn't his worst movie, (So far it's The Haunted Mansion.) but it was the beginning of Eddie Murphy's downfall. He tried to redeem himself with Tower Heist, but some idiot made A Thousand Words and now he's back to square one again. I hope he starts acting in good movies again because I don't want him remembered by today's generation as the Daddy Daycare guy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Not Bad, But Not As Good As The First 2 Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie Murphy, Judge Reinhold, Hector Elizondo, Timothy Carhart, Theresa Randle, Alan Young, Gil Hill, Bronson Pinchot and John Saxon star in this 1994 action-comedy sequel. This installment begins in Detroit, Michigan where cop, Axel Foley (Murphy) is on a stakeout. Soon, his boss, Inspector Douglas Todd (Hill) is killed in the crossfire by crooked businessman, Ellis De Wald (Carhart). Axel is determined to avenge Todd and tracks De Wald to Beverly Hills, California where he runs an amusement park, Wonderworld. He also reunites with cop friend, Billy Rosewood (Reinhold) and meets his co-worker, Jon Flynt (Elizondo). Axel gets himself in some snags when he tries to confront De Wald and learns of his counterfeiting scheme. Randle plays Janice, a woman who works for De Wald and gets close with Axel, Young (Mister Ed) plays Wonderworld owner, Uncle Dave Thornton, Saxon (A Nightmare on Elm Street) plays De Wald's associate Orrin Sanderson and Pinchot (Perfect Strangers) appears briefly reprising his role as Serge. There's also cameos by directors, Joe Dante and George Lucas. This sequel isn't bad, but not as good as the first 2 films. I missed John Ashton as John Taggart and it seemed like Elizondo's character, Flynt was kind of a substitute. I'm glad Reinhold came back and like the way they play the late, Harold Faltermeyer's classic theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Stuart
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so disappointed with this film, I loved the original and not only that but the Director, John Landis, made my favourite ever film "An American Werewolf in London". It is un-cinematic, the actors are not engaged, the script is woeful and the pace pedestrian. Every one seemed to just show up for the pay cheque. It's not the worst film ever made but it's a real franchise killer and sticks out as real waste of pedigree considering what came before it and the people involved. O out of 10 for effort, every one concerned should be very, very ashamed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Uneven to Work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beverly Hills Cop III (1994) ** (out of 4) Incredibly disappointing third entry in the series has Axel Foley (Eddie Murphy) running an operation on a car theft ring but soon he realizes it's much more than just this. After his boss is murdered he heads back out West to try and find the killers as well as uncover what's really going on. There's really no getting around the fact that this film is a major dud and it's really a shame considering what director John Landis and star Murphy had done together previously. I think it's easy to say this is a very big black spot on both of their careers. The majority of the blame has to go to the screenplay, which offers up a rather silly story full of silly situations, bad characters and some pretty lifeless comedy. It also doesn't help that Landis tries to put his stamp all over the picture, which not only takes it away from what the series was, it also adds some really boring and drawn out moments that should have been left on the cutting room floor. A perfect example happens right at the start when two of the bad guys are singing and dancing around for no real reason to the story. I'm really not sure what Landis was going for here but it's just downright silly. Even worse are some of the characters who are flat out boring including Judge Reinhold who just seems downright out of place. He's basically given nothing to do except stand around and make dumb faces as well as say some really bad dialogue. Even Murphy is pretty forgettable here. I'm not sure if he just wasn't into the film or perhaps he knew he didn't have much to work with. Hector Elizondo adds nothing in his role and the same is true for Timothy Carhart as the bad guy. The film is also incredibly uneven in its style and I'd say that there must have been some real creative control issues going on behind the scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crap on a stick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandra DeLonghi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thing has NOTHING in common with the original idea. It was more like a cheap-arse cash grab attempt but then falling $10 million short of break even. The problem is that they got it all wrong: Close to no humorous moments, no slapstick, no multiple layers of plot or parallelism, a half hour wasted on a pointless rescue-scene shot with CGI (even Eddie Murphy acted bored doing this), stupid time-wasters such as the "gramma oki doki pushed me" scene, wheeling out the "Serge" figure for five minutes of gay-talk. No suspense, a complete lack of care or passion. Bad writing and sad directing and last but not least fake-landscape-scenery that looked entirely shot in a studio, at a low budget. The music adaptation of Faltermeyer's theme score is inept. In the E/R movie review books this thing would have to be a fat turkey - at best. I was seriously, seriously (did I say SERIOUSLY) let down by this piece of &sect;hit. BO-RING.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the 3 films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it weren't for the amusement park story, this would probably be just another dull entry in the BHC series. Part II was a slight disappointment (at least when it came to anything other than action scenes), but this one is even better than the first movie and a big improvement over part 2. Unlike Part 2, the villains are mean enough (and seen more often), and Murphy doesn't do his comedy as much, which helps. My only quibble is Bronson Pinchot, who I think, didn't really need to be in the movie. His character is completely unnecessary. In fact, I think his appearance in the first movie was also unnecessary. His role is basically comic relief. That's what Murphy is for. It's as if Pinchot is playing a less funny version of Balki from "Perfect Strangers", only he doesn't Larry to annoy. ***1/2 out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
