<filme>
 <id>
  391
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107362
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O &Uacute;ltimo Grande Her&oacute;i
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young movie fan gets thrown into the movie world of his favourite action film character.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Young Danny Madigan is a big fan of Jack Slater, a larger-than-life action hero played by Arnold Schwarzenegger. When his best friend, Nick the projectionist, gives him a magic ticket to the new Jack Slater film, Danny is transported into Slater's world, where the good guys always win. One of Slater's enemies, Benedict the hitman, gets hold of the ticket and ends up in Danny's world, where he realises that if he can kill Schwarzenegger, Slater will be no more. Slater and Danny must travel back and stop him.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   ticket
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hero
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   magic
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   projectionist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   action hero
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John McTiernan
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Zak Penn
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Adam Leff
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Arnold Schwarzenegger
  </ator>
  <ator>
   F. Murray Abraham
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Art Carney
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was right the first time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Last Action Hero back in 1993; I didn't like it. Twenty years later and I begin to wonder whether my opinion was a knee-jerk reaction to seeing Schwarzenegger in something a little different to his usual fare, and that perhaps I would appreciate the film more second time round. Well, I just watched it again and, if anything, I disliked it even more than the first time. The basic (high) conceptaction movie fan Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) enters the fictional world of his movie hero Jack Slater (Arnie)is actually pretty clever, allowing for lots of ingenious meta-moments, but the way in which it is all realised is diabolical: the screenplay is full of misjudged humour (what is it with that dumb animated cat?), child star Austin O'Brien puts in a thoroughly annoying performance, and the exaggerated action scenes within Slater's movie-verse are completely devoid of excitement. There are also quite a few jokes that have dated extremely badly, especially the 'star' cameos from people that are no longer as famous as they used to be. The saddest thing about the whole film is that, given the great talent involved (Arnie, screenwriter Shane Black, director John McTiernan) it really should have been much, much better. Studio intervention may have been the reason it turned out so bad, but knowing that doesn't make the film any more enjoyable to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupidity stops where its own awareness starts ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that principle applies for both people and movies. And this is why parody generally provides the cleverest films, mocking the archetypes over-exploited by lazy directors with a subtle, and so engaging, wink to the audience. And "Last Action Hero" parodies the action-flick, featuring its most iconic ambassador, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the lone-ranger bad-ass cigar-smoking titular hero of a never-ending franchise: Jack Slater. As if he was plenty aware that "Die Hard" put a deathblow on the credibility of such super-heroic figures popularized by "Commando" and "Predator", John McTiernan becomes the iconoclast of his own creations -a demonstration of smart sense of humor a few directors ever achieved. The opening "Jack Slater" film even concludes with a reference to the genre-defining "Die Hard", using the same score to contribute to the whole 'inside joke' effect, completed when Jack Slater becomes a movie-within-a-movie character, from the perspective of Danny, his number one fan, played by Austin O'Brien. Basically, Danny is to "Last Action Hero" what Cecilia (Mia Farrow) was to "The Purple Rose of Cairo": a movie lover whose only means to transcend routine's banality was a constant ecstatic stare toward the silver screen. And being a kid of the early 90's, I could only respond to his hypnotic fascination. Action films are indeed the best pop-culture fillers, crystallizing the most common denominators of fun and entertainment and generating codes and formula that are part of cinema's timeless and universal heritage, no matter how overused they are: the never-dying hero, the yelling superior, the revenge plot, the villainous monologue, the sexy daughter, the comic-relief sidekick, the sophisticated boss' right hand who becomes the real villain and a lame catchphrase. They're all there in "Last Action Hero" less because they're obligatory but for the necessity to turn them into derision, by confronting them to reality. Still, there has to be some fantasy in this reality: Danny is given by the projectionist Nick (Art Carney) a magic ticket that belonged to the Great Houdini. And while he watches the fourth opus of Jack Slater's adventures during a private screening, the ticket glows, sticks of dynamite are thrown from the screen and land near his feet. Danny starts to take the notion of 'danger' less cynically before the explosion immediately projects him into his hero's universe. The film's greatest moments come from Danny's desperate attempts to convince Slater that they live in a movie where phone numbers start with "555", video-store workers are sexy and profanity is prohibited. Hell, in this parallel universe, his own rival Stallone played the Terminator roles (which made me wonder who then played Rocky or Rambo). The film recycles every clich&eacute; in such an over-the-top way it's hilarious: the car rams into an ice cream truck and explodes, a henchman gets an ice cone on the neck, many gags feel like these 'McBain' segments from "The Simpsons", thus never fail. The film also features one hilarious modernization of "Hamlet" and two delightful movie references. One of Slater's friends is played by F. Murray Abraham, naturally, Danny warns him that it's the same guy who killed Mozart in "Amadeus": the film that got 8 Oscars. For a kid, he has the knowledge of an IMDb user, which says a lot about "Last Action Hero" exhilarating effect as pure geek escapism, reinforced by the obscure intrusion of Death from "The Seventh Seal", a joke I didn't even get when I saw the film as a teenager. Now, there are two facts regarding "Last Action Hero": the film flopped, and it didn't deserve to, not when box-office laws are governed by rules that allow "Cliffhanger" to be the 7th highest grossing film anyway. Therefore, I can only qualify its bombing as 'accidental', the same accident that made "Sorcerer" flop in 1977. The parallel is all the more eloquent because "Last Action Hero" suffered from an ill-fated opening coinciding with the big event of 1993: the release of Steven Spielberg's "Jurassik park" ("Sorcerer" had it worse with "Star Wars") and perhaps misleading title, trailer and word-of-mouth that branded the film in the total opposite way it expected to: a dumb action film, 'another one'. I don't blame the viewers who thought a bunch of reptilian carnivores would be a fresher spectacle, I, was misled too, the first time I saw the TV announcement. But being a box-office flop is one thing, but when I started to examine the disastrous reception from those who actually saw the film- I was stunned. Seriously, what's with all these Razzies' nominations? Worst actor? Arnold had to play his usual role. Worst screenplay? Check the review's title. Worst new star? That's the worst thing about vocation-discouraging Razzies: the kid was supposed to be annoying and he played that part quite well. Worst song? It's a cheesy action-flick, did they expect Barbra Streisand? "Last Action Hero" is not beyond criticism though especially in the last act, when they 'get' in the real world. It's true that the film could have pushed its self-reflexive concept to more thought-provoking levels, that the emotional involvement lacked when the action was conditioned by predictable plot devices and needed to be compensated in the 'real world'. It's also true that confronting Slater to Arnold (like in Woody Allen's film) or having Danny talking to him, could have induced more interesting situations, but the reception would make anyone believe the film is like "Stop or my Mom Will Shoot!". Talk about unfortunate misunderstanding, not that I believe it truly deserves this 8, but it makes up for the undeserved negativity it inspired. McTiernan would finally make the highest-grossing film of 1995: "Die Hard 3 With a Vengeance" which feels like his personal vengeance. The film is as corny and over-the-top as "Last Action Hero" but I guess the average audience wasn't ready for that level of subtlety, so he probably thought : "Hell, give them the movie they deserve and give me a break".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun cheeky spoof movie that has gained a cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best things about Last Action Hero is that the more you read about it, you realize the smarter it is. There are so many little nods and cheeky references to the action genre and to Hollywood that you can't possibly catch them all the first time around. It appears, on the surface, to be this huge action film but really the entire film is poking fun at the genre. And who better to bring on board to do that but the King of eighties action Arnold Schwarzenegger. There is so much right about this film. The scenes with Arnold playing himself and the interaction between him and "Jack Slater" are just awesome. The cameos and the world they create inside the movie is just so much fun to watch. The problem is that the film is almost too much of a joke. Fans of Schwarzenegger and action films might find their genre being made a total fool of a bit much to handle. And also one of the leading roles is really not good but more on that in a minute. It is definitely a PG-13 movie and while there is nothing wrong with that, it feels like it struggles to purposely try to stay PG and it has trouble doing that. I love Arnold Schwarzenegger, he has just always been one of my Hollywood icons. This is such an odd role for him because he is making fun of himself and what he does best. However, it works well and he is actually fun as Slater. He is especially fun in the brief scenes where is "playing" or "over-playing" himself. The banter between him and real life wife/ex-wife Maria Shriver is just awesome. Austin O'Brien is the young actor portraying Schwarzenegger's partner and his fan as well. O'Brien is unfortunately the character I mentioned previously that really holds back this film. He is simply unnatural and gives a strained and poor performance. It just is very underwhelming. The chemistry between him and Schwarzenegger is nearly awful and that would be the key point to this movie. Charles Dance is very good as the evil villain Benedict. He is over the top but looks menacing and certainly is the perfect personification of an action movie villain. Tom Noonan is also good as the twisted Ripper villain who is also an amped up spoof of a slasher villain. Everyone else in the film are basically cameos but there are some really good ones worth mentioning. F. Murray Abraham, Art Carney, Frank McRae, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and even Ian McKellan are just a few of the faces you will recognize and they give good solid campy performances. If there was any director they should have gotten to direct this film it would be John McTiernan. Die Hard, Predator, The Hunt For Red October, Die Hard 3, Medicine Man...and more. Every action film he has done has at least been decent so he was the perfect choice to do this film and poke fun at the genre. The action scenes are well done and yet overdone at the same time (which granted is the point.) Last Action Hero is fun and exciting but is held back by making fun of itself almost too much. Still, it is a modern day cult classic and more and more people are calling it under-rated and when you look at some of the hidden Easter eggs in the film, it becomes even more fascinating and fun. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice parody of an action movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colm-hearne365
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I noticed that this movie got some pretty bad reception from critics and didn't do that well in the box office but that was because it was released at the same time as Jurassic Park. And I think the reason why people didn't like was because they took it too seriously. The thing is this movie is a parody of action movies like Blazing Saddles is a parody of westerns or Spaceballs was a parody of sci-fi movies. But even I can admit this movie gets pretty cheesy and over the top at times but parodies are like that. And even the kid, Danny was pretty annoying at times. But I think its a fun movie to watch, especially if you're an action fan and Arnold Schwarzenegger has always been my favourite action star. And I like the idea of the clash between fantasy and reality and it's also funny and exciting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated, but not flawless, gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero has got a lot of bad mouthing over the years, but it seems a lot of critics were just jumping on the bandwagon, afraid to say something positive. It is difficult to see why no-one would like it at all. While a tad heavy-handed, the constant riffing on typical macho action flicks is spot-on, always amusing, and yet at the same time the film delivers saw awe-inspiring, sometimes deliberately implausible action set-pieces. Arnie sends himself up fine, while Austin O'Brien often says out loud what most often think watching these kinds of films. Charles Dance makes a menacing villain, and provides some dark amusement of his own - I JUST SHOT SOMEBODY, I DID IT ON PURPOSE. Where the film begins to falter is when the fictional characters, plus Danny, enter the real world. Until this point, it had been going along at a roaring clip, constantly amusing. Perhaps it was necessary to show a dose of reality to those brought up on mindless action flicks, but it starts becoming a little more serious and darker in tone, more sentimental, and consequently less fun. That doesn't make it bad though, and it does provide some food for thought, with Arnie-in-character ranting about how he's fed up of shooting people in films, and blowing things up. Not a masterpiece perhaps, but deserves to be ranked high on Arnie's filmography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Last Action Hero' is Pure Fun! A highly entertaining escapist fare, that works from start to end. 'Last Action Hero' Synopsis: A young movie fan gets thrown into the movie world of his favorite action film character. 'Last Action Hero' is innovative & fun. The pace is perfect & the action-sequences are top-notch. Shane Black, David Arnott & William Goldman's Screenplay is child-like, but works wonderfully. John McTiernan's Direction is efficient. Cinematography is stylish. Art Design is perfect. Performance-Wise: Arnold Schwarzenegger plays to the gallery. He enacts the hero with his usual ease. Austin O'Brien is extremely likable, as he's energetic all through. Robert Prosky is restrained. Charles Dance is excellent. Anthony Quinn is effective. On the whole, 'Last Action Hero' is some great vintage entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This hero stuff has its limits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero is directed by John McTiernan and written by Shane Black and David Arnott. It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, F. Murray Abraham, Charles Dance, Tom Noonan, Austin O'Brien, Art Carney, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and Bridgette Wilson. Music is by Micahel Kamen and cinematography by Dean Semler. Film within a film action parody that sees young Danny Madigan (O'Brien) magically transported into the parallel universe of an action film featuring his fictional hero, Jack Slater (Schwarzenegger). A financial failure and beaten relentlessly by the critics upon release (even McTiernan would condemn it down the line), Last Action Hero is viewed some what in better terms these days. Whilst the arguments that it was ahead of its time, misunderstood and released at the wrong time due to competition with Jurassic Park (the last one was Arnie himself, bless him) are weak and really not worth considering, it's a decent and "intelligent" film that could have been very good if cut by at least half an hour. Running at over two hours in length, the film's central concept of parodying action movies, with Arnold broadly laughing at himself, runs out of steam, the joke just becomes a millstone around its neck. You can see the drop in quality of the action in the last third as well, purely because so much is thrown at the audience, it gets tiresome for the director, which is such a shame given that it's McTiernan at the helm, the man who in Predator and Die Hard gave the 80s its two best American action movies. As it is, and I was helped enormously in my viewing of this because I watched it back to back with Hard Target, much of the parody and cineaste jokes strike a humorous chord. While the roll call of actors lining up to be in on the joke is impressive and often laugh out loud funny. Yet amongst all the satire and tongue in cheek wink winks, there is also some depth to the dizzying narrative that is worth appraising, particularly when the picture pitches up the real life of an actor to that of the character he plays, with one sequence as Arnie faces up to Arnie particularly brilliant. Better than you may have heard it is, but still a film that's difficult to recommend with confidence. Some self-examining depth and smart in- movie jokes ensure it's no dud, but entering the last third it becomes tiresome and routine and that leaves a disappointment that's hard to shake. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it as a kid in '93, and I've grown to appreciate it as an adult.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reading some of the lurid behind-the-scenes details on "Last Action Hero" (do a search, it's scintillating!), one would walk into this thing expecting an &uuml;ber-expensive disaster. And it was, at least financially. But time has been kind to this movie, and it's actually - for most of its runtime - a pretty kickass genre sendup. The idea behind "Last Action Hero" is satirically brilliant: to deconstruct the big Hollywood action movie. You know, your "Lethal Weapon"s, your "Die Hard"s and your Schwarzenegger "sh-t blows up real good!" movies. And when the movie focuses on that aspect, it's a fun romp. You see enough '80s action movies, the tropes and clich&eacute;s become commonplace. They're all here: - huge explosions send the hero flying (ultimately unscathed) while everyone around him winds up dead - change of scenery from location to studio backlot within a scene - there are no unattractive women - police headquarters is unbelievably posh - the Lieutenant speaks only in vein-popping screams - gunshots send bad guys flying - an inordinate number of explosions And it's that novelty of the genre satire that really makes this movie, for me. Which means the film's first 90 minutes are very entertaining. It's when the villain escapes the movie and our focus centers on the real world that "Last Action Hero" loses me. The film's first half is front-loaded with all of the good stuff. All of the good jokes and sight gags are there. I have no interest in what goes on in the real world. The real magic is in the artificial one. But there's strength in the casting. Arnold is able and surprisingly good at offering himself up for parody. And in a role that's sure to be annoying on paper, Austin O'Brien is actually kinda endearing as the kid sidekick. I really liked him here. And Charles Dance as Benedict . . . he's a terrific bad guy. In this type of movie, especially; great comedic timing, and just a pleasure to watch. He steals every one of his scenes. His lines are the funniest. "Last Action Hero" would definitely merit a higher rating if I didn't feel the need to turn it off with 45 minutes left to go. But when I think of this movie, it's that great first half that sticks in my brain. It should've performed better 20 years ago. The lousy reputation is (for the most part) undeserved, and it's a clear example of the kind of curious oddity that can result after many bad decisions made during the filmmaking process. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better the older you get
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dame Shumma
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grandiose, like Schwarzenegger takes the mickey out here himself, knows his last name wrong constantly and eventually called Arnold Braunschweiger. There are ongoing links to other movies, where, like in Die Hard. Danny makes Jack's attention to look up after a car accident even if the bad guy except death. In Die Hard, it was finally so that the blonde is hanged, and at the end is still alive. Grandiose, something is a feast for action lovers. The final rise to the film premiere of "Jack Slater IV" in New York. Schwarzenegger plays himself here, and is approached by his wife to make lasting advertising for Planet Hollywood. John Belushi announces Jack Slater movies so he does not like, and Van Damme, yes, even the Belgian martial arts goes to the premiere. Just plain funny. Slater is run by Danny corrected. Whenever he "I'll be back," says Danny knew beforehand that he will say that it is, after all, his trademark. Even the testing center for movies, the MPAA will not be left out. Danny writes a word, probably "fuck" on a piece of paper. Slater read it will not. Danny Comment: "You can not read it, because this movie is PG-13" Just wonderful. Who wants to keep checking back for once really look over a very successful action movie parody must. However, you should really have already seen some in the sector to understand everything. In order to find every hidden joke I have seen the movie a few times anyway. Well, anyway, the story is incidental and not the hammer. But is sufficient. I admit: Movie Review: 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A curious oddity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When young Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) is given a magic movie ticket by friendly cinema owner Nick (Robert Prosky) at an advance screening of new action movie Jack Slater IV, he is magically transported into the movie and into the car of supercop Jack Slater (Arnold Schwarzenegger). Danny starts to inform Slater about who the bad guys are after seeing them on screen, and the two are paired up as a mismatched investigative duo by Slater's screaming boss. Glass-eyed bad guy Mr. Benedict (Charles Dance) manages to get his hands on the magic ticket, and escapes into the real world, where he finds things are much easier for the bad guys. Slater must leave his action movie clich&eacute; of a world where he is nigh on invincible behind, and enter one where things are slightly more difficult. Last Action Hero had one of the most expensive and turbulent page-to- screen stories in recent cinema history. Originally written as a self- mocking action movie that embraced the clich&eacute;s of the genre, that was also a proper action movie in its own right. After an unexpected bidding war, the young scribes Zak Penn and Adam Leff were shocked to find that Arnold Schwarzenegger had taken a personal interest in it (the original hero name was Arno Slater). This was to be the turning point. Arnie saw the potential for a franchise as a kid's film and immediately wanted to tone down the violence, so Penn and Leff were fired, and genre legend Shane Black was hired to spruce up the script. Things changed yet again when director John McTiernan was brought in, and, due to the success of his previous films, was given full control. A few script re-writes, firings, and storm-outs later, the film was shot and ready to hit the market. A toy franchise and a ridiculously expensive and calamitous advertising campaign (they paid half a million dollars to have the film's name on a NASA rocket, only to have the launched delayed till long after the film's release) were put into motion, and the film's release date was announced for the week after Jurassic Park's. Last Action Hero had disastrous test screenings, but the release date was not changed, and naturally, Jurassic Park stormed the box-office and merchandising range, and Last Action Hero was revealed to be an over-ambitious, confused dud of a movie. However, the legend is rather cruel on Schwarzenegger's biggest flop, as although it is a gigantic mess, it has plenty of interesting ideas than are unfortunately spewed out onto the film in ungraceful belches. The biggest problem is that it doesn't know what kind of film it is. At its heart, its a kid's film, complete with annoying mop-haired child, a kindly old man, magic tickets and, um, a cartoon cat. Yet on its surface, its a rather uninspired action film that is actually rather violent and, once in the real world, is quite grim. The film never seems to know whether it wants to homage, spoof or simply in-joke. The movie world it creates is itself confused - while it has some funny touches such as the police line pairing together various mismatched partners - it also has women walking around in sexy, futuristic costumes, and the aforementioned cartoon cat called Whiskers (voiced by Danny DeVito). Seriously, whose idea was that? I've never seen a cartoon cat in a live- action action movie! However, the sheer mess that is the complete film does prove Last Action Hero to be a curious little oddity. There have been much finer examples of action-movie send-ups, namely in Shane Black's own excellent Kiss Kiss Bang Bang (2005), so perhaps the producers weren't ready back in 1993 to take on such an ambitious project. Arnie is pleasantly game for sending himself up, and Charles Dance chews the screen with his gloriously hammy British bad guy. But Last Action Hero will ultimately always be a reminder of how the Hollywood system to suck up an interesting maverick project, f**k it over a few times, and bundle it over the finishing line with such unbelievable inefficiency. I did love it as a kid, however. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was right the first time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Last Action Hero back in 1993; I didn't like it. Twenty years later and I begin to wonder whether my opinion was a knee-jerk reaction to seeing Schwarzenegger in something a little different to his usual fare, and that perhaps I would appreciate the film more second time round. Well, I just watched it again and, if anything, I disliked it even more than the first time. The basic (high) conceptaction movie fan Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) enters the fictional world of his movie hero Jack Slater (Arnie)is actually pretty clever, allowing for lots of ingenious meta-moments, but the way in which it is all realised is diabolical: the screenplay is full of misjudged humour (what is it with that dumb animated cat?), child star Austin O'Brien puts in a thoroughly annoying performance, and the exaggerated action scenes within Slater's movie-verse are completely devoid of excitement. There are also quite a few jokes that have dated extremely badly, especially the 'star' cameos from people that are no longer as famous as they used to be. The saddest thing about the whole film is that, given the great talent involved (Arnie, screenwriter Shane Black, director John McTiernan) it really should have been much, much better. Studio intervention may have been the reason it turned out so bad, but knowing that doesn't make the film any more enjoyable to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupidity stops where its own awareness starts ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that principle applies for both people and movies. And this is why parody generally provides the cleverest films, mocking the archetypes over-exploited by lazy directors with a subtle, and so engaging, wink to the audience. And "Last Action Hero" parodies the action-flick, featuring its most iconic ambassador, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the lone-ranger bad-ass cigar-smoking titular hero of a never-ending franchise: Jack Slater. As if he was plenty aware that "Die Hard" put a deathblow on the credibility of such super-heroic figures popularized by "Commando" and "Predator", John McTiernan becomes the iconoclast of his own creations -a demonstration of smart sense of humor a few directors ever achieved. The opening "Jack Slater" film even concludes with a reference to the genre-defining "Die Hard", using the same score to contribute to the whole 'inside joke' effect, completed when Jack Slater becomes a movie-within-a-movie character, from the perspective of Danny, his number one fan, played by Austin O'Brien. Basically, Danny is to "Last Action Hero" what Cecilia (Mia Farrow) was to "The Purple Rose of Cairo": a movie lover whose only means to transcend routine's banality was a constant ecstatic stare toward the silver screen. And being a kid of the early 90's, I could only respond to his hypnotic fascination. Action films are indeed the best pop-culture fillers, crystallizing the most common denominators of fun and entertainment and generating codes and formula that are part of cinema's timeless and universal heritage, no matter how overused they are: the never-dying hero, the yelling superior, the revenge plot, the villainous monologue, the sexy daughter, the comic-relief sidekick, the sophisticated boss' right hand who becomes the real villain and a lame catchphrase. They're all there in "Last Action Hero" less because they're obligatory but for the necessity to turn them into derision, by confronting them to reality. Still, there has to be some fantasy in this reality: Danny is given by the projectionist Nick (Art Carney) a magic ticket that belonged to the Great Houdini. And while he watches the fourth opus of Jack Slater's adventures during a private screening, the ticket glows, sticks of dynamite are thrown from the screen and land near his feet. Danny starts to take the notion of 'danger' less cynically before the explosion immediately projects him into his hero's universe. The film's greatest moments come from Danny's desperate attempts to convince Slater that they live in a movie where phone numbers start with "555", video-store workers are sexy and profanity is prohibited. Hell, in this parallel universe, his own rival Stallone played the Terminator roles (which made me wonder who then played Rocky or Rambo). The film recycles every clich&eacute; in such an over-the-top way it's hilarious: the car rams into an ice cream truck and explodes, a henchman gets an ice cone on the neck, many gags feel like these 'McBain' segments from "The Simpsons", thus never fail. The film also features one hilarious modernization of "Hamlet" and two delightful movie references. One of Slater's friends is played by F. Murray Abraham, naturally, Danny warns him that it's the same guy who killed Mozart in "Amadeus": the film that got 8 Oscars. For a kid, he has the knowledge of an IMDb user, which says a lot about "Last Action Hero" exhilarating effect as pure geek escapism, reinforced by the obscure intrusion of Death from "The Seventh Seal", a joke I didn't even get when I saw the film as a teenager. Now, there are two facts regarding "Last Action Hero": the film flopped, and it didn't deserve to, not when box-office laws are governed by rules that allow "Cliffhanger" to be the 7th highest grossing film anyway. Therefore, I can only qualify its bombing as 'accidental', the same accident that made "Sorcerer" flop in 1977. The parallel is all the more eloquent because "Last Action Hero" suffered from an ill-fated opening coinciding with the big event of 1993: the release of Steven Spielberg's "Jurassik park" ("Sorcerer" had it worse with "Star Wars") and perhaps misleading title, trailer and word-of-mouth that branded the film in the total opposite way it expected to: a dumb action film, 'another one'. I don't blame the viewers who thought a bunch of reptilian carnivores would be a fresher spectacle, I, was misled too, the first time I saw the TV announcement. But being a box-office flop is one thing, but when I started to examine the disastrous reception from those who actually saw the film- I was stunned. Seriously, what's with all these Razzies' nominations? Worst actor? Arnold had to play his usual role. Worst screenplay? Check the review's title. Worst new star? That's the worst thing about vocation-discouraging Razzies: the kid was supposed to be annoying and he played that part quite well. Worst song? It's a cheesy action-flick, did they expect Barbra Streisand? "Last Action Hero" is not beyond criticism though especially in the last act, when they 'get' in the real world. It's true that the film could have pushed its self-reflexive concept to more thought-provoking levels, that the emotional involvement lacked when the action was conditioned by predictable plot devices and needed to be compensated in the 'real world'. It's also true that confronting Slater to Arnold (like in Woody Allen's film) or having Danny talking to him, could have induced more interesting situations, but the reception would make anyone believe the film is like "Stop or my Mom Will Shoot!". Talk about unfortunate misunderstanding, not that I believe it truly deserves this 8, but it makes up for the undeserved negativity it inspired. McTiernan would finally make the highest-grossing film of 1995: "Die Hard 3 With a Vengeance" which feels like his personal vengeance. The film is as corny and over-the-top as "Last Action Hero" but I guess the average audience wasn't ready for that level of subtlety, so he probably thought : "Hell, give them the movie they deserve and give me a break".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun cheeky spoof movie that has gained a cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best things about Last Action Hero is that the more you read about it, you realize the smarter it is. There are so many little nods and cheeky references to the action genre and to Hollywood that you can't possibly catch them all the first time around. It appears, on the surface, to be this huge action film but really the entire film is poking fun at the genre. And who better to bring on board to do that but the King of eighties action Arnold Schwarzenegger. There is so much right about this film. The scenes with Arnold playing himself and the interaction between him and "Jack Slater" are just awesome. The cameos and the world they create inside the movie is just so much fun to watch. The problem is that the film is almost too much of a joke. Fans of Schwarzenegger and action films might find their genre being made a total fool of a bit much to handle. And also one of the leading roles is really not good but more on that in a minute. It is definitely a PG-13 movie and while there is nothing wrong with that, it feels like it struggles to purposely try to stay PG and it has trouble doing that. I love Arnold Schwarzenegger, he has just always been one of my Hollywood icons. This is such an odd role for him because he is making fun of himself and what he does best. However, it works well and he is actually fun as Slater. He is especially fun in the brief scenes where is "playing" or "over-playing" himself. The banter between him and real life wife/ex-wife Maria Shriver is just awesome. Austin O'Brien is the young actor portraying Schwarzenegger's partner and his fan as well. O'Brien is unfortunately the character I mentioned previously that really holds back this film. He is simply unnatural and gives a strained and poor performance. It just is very underwhelming. The chemistry between him and Schwarzenegger is nearly awful and that would be the key point to this movie. Charles Dance is very good as the evil villain Benedict. He is over the top but looks menacing and certainly is the perfect personification of an action movie villain. Tom Noonan is also good as the twisted Ripper villain who is also an amped up spoof of a slasher villain. Everyone else in the film are basically cameos but there are some really good ones worth mentioning. F. Murray Abraham, Art Carney, Frank McRae, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and even Ian McKellan are just a few of the faces you will recognize and they give good solid campy performances. If there was any director they should have gotten to direct this film it would be John McTiernan. Die Hard, Predator, The Hunt For Red October, Die Hard 3, Medicine Man...and more. Every action film he has done has at least been decent so he was the perfect choice to do this film and poke fun at the genre. The action scenes are well done and yet overdone at the same time (which granted is the point.) Last Action Hero is fun and exciting but is held back by making fun of itself almost too much. Still, it is a modern day cult classic and more and more people are calling it under-rated and when you look at some of the hidden Easter eggs in the film, it becomes even more fascinating and fun. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice parody of an action movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colm-hearne365
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I noticed that this movie got some pretty bad reception from critics and didn't do that well in the box office but that was because it was released at the same time as Jurassic Park. And I think the reason why people didn't like was because they took it too seriously. The thing is this movie is a parody of action movies like Blazing Saddles is a parody of westerns or Spaceballs was a parody of sci-fi movies. But even I can admit this movie gets pretty cheesy and over the top at times but parodies are like that. And even the kid, Danny was pretty annoying at times. But I think its a fun movie to watch, especially if you're an action fan and Arnold Schwarzenegger has always been my favourite action star. And I like the idea of the clash between fantasy and reality and it's also funny and exciting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated, but not flawless, gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero has got a lot of bad mouthing over the years, but it seems a lot of critics were just jumping on the bandwagon, afraid to say something positive. It is difficult to see why no-one would like it at all. While a tad heavy-handed, the constant riffing on typical macho action flicks is spot-on, always amusing, and yet at the same time the film delivers saw awe-inspiring, sometimes deliberately implausible action set-pieces. Arnie sends himself up fine, while Austin O'Brien often says out loud what most often think watching these kinds of films. Charles Dance makes a menacing villain, and provides some dark amusement of his own - I JUST SHOT SOMEBODY, I DID IT ON PURPOSE. Where the film begins to falter is when the fictional characters, plus Danny, enter the real world. Until this point, it had been going along at a roaring clip, constantly amusing. Perhaps it was necessary to show a dose of reality to those brought up on mindless action flicks, but it starts becoming a little more serious and darker in tone, more sentimental, and consequently less fun. That doesn't make it bad though, and it does provide some food for thought, with Arnie-in-character ranting about how he's fed up of shooting people in films, and blowing things up. Not a masterpiece perhaps, but deserves to be ranked high on Arnie's filmography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Last Action Hero' is Pure Fun! A highly entertaining escapist fare, that works from start to end. 'Last Action Hero' Synopsis: A young movie fan gets thrown into the movie world of his favorite action film character. 'Last Action Hero' is innovative & fun. The pace is perfect & the action-sequences are top-notch. Shane Black, David Arnott & William Goldman's Screenplay is child-like, but works wonderfully. John McTiernan's Direction is efficient. Cinematography is stylish. Art Design is perfect. Performance-Wise: Arnold Schwarzenegger plays to the gallery. He enacts the hero with his usual ease. Austin O'Brien is extremely likable, as he's energetic all through. Robert Prosky is restrained. Charles Dance is excellent. Anthony Quinn is effective. On the whole, 'Last Action Hero' is some great vintage entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This hero stuff has its limits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero is directed by John McTiernan and written by Shane Black and David Arnott. It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, F. Murray Abraham, Charles Dance, Tom Noonan, Austin O'Brien, Art Carney, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and Bridgette Wilson. Music is by Micahel Kamen and cinematography by Dean Semler. Film within a film action parody that sees young Danny Madigan (O'Brien) magically transported into the parallel universe of an action film featuring his fictional hero, Jack Slater (Schwarzenegger). A financial failure and beaten relentlessly by the critics upon release (even McTiernan would condemn it down the line), Last Action Hero is viewed some what in better terms these days. Whilst the arguments that it was ahead of its time, misunderstood and released at the wrong time due to competition with Jurassic Park (the last one was Arnie himself, bless him) are weak and really not worth considering, it's a decent and "intelligent" film that could have been very good if cut by at least half an hour. Running at over two hours in length, the film's central concept of parodying action movies, with Arnold broadly laughing at himself, runs out of steam, the joke just becomes a millstone around its neck. You can see the drop in quality of the action in the last third as well, purely because so much is thrown at the audience, it gets tiresome for the director, which is such a shame given that it's McTiernan at the helm, the man who in Predator and Die Hard gave the 80s its two best American action movies. As it is, and I was helped enormously in my viewing of this because I watched it back to back with Hard Target, much of the parody and cineaste jokes strike a humorous chord. While the roll call of actors lining up to be in on the joke is impressive and often laugh out loud funny. Yet amongst all the satire and tongue in cheek wink winks, there is also some depth to the dizzying narrative that is worth appraising, particularly when the picture pitches up the real life of an actor to that of the character he plays, with one sequence as Arnie faces up to Arnie particularly brilliant. Better than you may have heard it is, but still a film that's difficult to recommend with confidence. Some self-examining depth and smart in- movie jokes ensure it's no dud, but entering the last third it becomes tiresome and routine and that leaves a disappointment that's hard to shake. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it as a kid in '93, and I've grown to appreciate it as an adult.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reading some of the lurid behind-the-scenes details on "Last Action Hero" (do a search, it's scintillating!), one would walk into this thing expecting an &uuml;ber-expensive disaster. And it was, at least financially. But time has been kind to this movie, and it's actually - for most of its runtime - a pretty kickass genre sendup. The idea behind "Last Action Hero" is satirically brilliant: to deconstruct the big Hollywood action movie. You know, your "Lethal Weapon"s, your "Die Hard"s and your Schwarzenegger "sh-t blows up real good!" movies. And when the movie focuses on that aspect, it's a fun romp. You see enough '80s action movies, the tropes and clich&eacute;s become commonplace. They're all here: - huge explosions send the hero flying (ultimately unscathed) while everyone around him winds up dead - change of scenery from location to studio backlot within a scene - there are no unattractive women - police headquarters is unbelievably posh - the Lieutenant speaks only in vein-popping screams - gunshots send bad guys flying - an inordinate number of explosions And it's that novelty of the genre satire that really makes this movie, for me. Which means the film's first 90 minutes are very entertaining. It's when the villain escapes the movie and our focus centers on the real world that "Last Action Hero" loses me. The film's first half is front-loaded with all of the good stuff. All of the good jokes and sight gags are there. I have no interest in what goes on in the real world. The real magic is in the artificial one. But there's strength in the casting. Arnold is able and surprisingly good at offering himself up for parody. And in a role that's sure to be annoying on paper, Austin O'Brien is actually kinda endearing as the kid sidekick. I really liked him here. And Charles Dance as Benedict . . . he's a terrific bad guy. In this type of movie, especially; great comedic timing, and just a pleasure to watch. He steals every one of his scenes. His lines are the funniest. "Last Action Hero" would definitely merit a higher rating if I didn't feel the need to turn it off with 45 minutes left to go. But when I think of this movie, it's that great first half that sticks in my brain. It should've performed better 20 years ago. The lousy reputation is (for the most part) undeserved, and it's a clear example of the kind of curious oddity that can result after many bad decisions made during the filmmaking process. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better the older you get
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dame Shumma
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grandiose, like Schwarzenegger takes the mickey out here himself, knows his last name wrong constantly and eventually called Arnold Braunschweiger. There are ongoing links to other movies, where, like in Die Hard. Danny makes Jack's attention to look up after a car accident even if the bad guy except death. In Die Hard, it was finally so that the blonde is hanged, and at the end is still alive. Grandiose, something is a feast for action lovers. The final rise to the film premiere of "Jack Slater IV" in New York. Schwarzenegger plays himself here, and is approached by his wife to make lasting advertising for Planet Hollywood. John Belushi announces Jack Slater movies so he does not like, and Van Damme, yes, even the Belgian martial arts goes to the premiere. Just plain funny. Slater is run by Danny corrected. Whenever he "I'll be back," says Danny knew beforehand that he will say that it is, after all, his trademark. Even the testing center for movies, the MPAA will not be left out. Danny writes a word, probably "fuck" on a piece of paper. Slater read it will not. Danny Comment: "You can not read it, because this movie is PG-13" Just wonderful. Who wants to keep checking back for once really look over a very successful action movie parody must. However, you should really have already seen some in the sector to understand everything. In order to find every hidden joke I have seen the movie a few times anyway. Well, anyway, the story is incidental and not the hammer. But is sufficient. I admit: Movie Review: 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A curious oddity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When young Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) is given a magic movie ticket by friendly cinema owner Nick (Robert Prosky) at an advance screening of new action movie Jack Slater IV, he is magically transported into the movie and into the car of supercop Jack Slater (Arnold Schwarzenegger). Danny starts to inform Slater about who the bad guys are after seeing them on screen, and the two are paired up as a mismatched investigative duo by Slater's screaming boss. Glass-eyed bad guy Mr. Benedict (Charles Dance) manages to get his hands on the magic ticket, and escapes into the real world, where he finds things are much easier for the bad guys. Slater must leave his action movie clich&eacute; of a world where he is nigh on invincible behind, and enter one where things are slightly more difficult. Last Action Hero had one of the most expensive and turbulent page-to- screen stories in recent cinema history. Originally written as a self- mocking action movie that embraced the clich&eacute;s of the genre, that was also a proper action movie in its own right. After an unexpected bidding war, the young scribes Zak Penn and Adam Leff were shocked to find that Arnold Schwarzenegger had taken a personal interest in it (the original hero name was Arno Slater). This was to be the turning point. Arnie saw the potential for a franchise as a kid's film and immediately wanted to tone down the violence, so Penn and Leff were fired, and genre legend Shane Black was hired to spruce up the script. Things changed yet again when director John McTiernan was brought in, and, due to the success of his previous films, was given full control. A few script re-writes, firings, and storm-outs later, the film was shot and ready to hit the market. A toy franchise and a ridiculously expensive and calamitous advertising campaign (they paid half a million dollars to have the film's name on a NASA rocket, only to have the launched delayed till long after the film's release) were put into motion, and the film's release date was announced for the week after Jurassic Park's. Last Action Hero had disastrous test screenings, but the release date was not changed, and naturally, Jurassic Park stormed the box-office and merchandising range, and Last Action Hero was revealed to be an over-ambitious, confused dud of a movie. However, the legend is rather cruel on Schwarzenegger's biggest flop, as although it is a gigantic mess, it has plenty of interesting ideas than are unfortunately spewed out onto the film in ungraceful belches. The biggest problem is that it doesn't know what kind of film it is. At its heart, its a kid's film, complete with annoying mop-haired child, a kindly old man, magic tickets and, um, a cartoon cat. Yet on its surface, its a rather uninspired action film that is actually rather violent and, once in the real world, is quite grim. The film never seems to know whether it wants to homage, spoof or simply in-joke. The movie world it creates is itself confused - while it has some funny touches such as the police line pairing together various mismatched partners - it also has women walking around in sexy, futuristic costumes, and the aforementioned cartoon cat called Whiskers (voiced by Danny DeVito). Seriously, whose idea was that? I've never seen a cartoon cat in a live- action action movie! However, the sheer mess that is the complete film does prove Last Action Hero to be a curious little oddity. There have been much finer examples of action-movie send-ups, namely in Shane Black's own excellent Kiss Kiss Bang Bang (2005), so perhaps the producers weren't ready back in 1993 to take on such an ambitious project. Arnie is pleasantly game for sending himself up, and Charles Dance chews the screen with his gloriously hammy British bad guy. But Last Action Hero will ultimately always be a reminder of how the Hollywood system to suck up an interesting maverick project, f**k it over a few times, and bundle it over the finishing line with such unbelievable inefficiency. I did love it as a kid, however. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was right the first time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Last Action Hero back in 1993; I didn't like it. Twenty years later and I begin to wonder whether my opinion was a knee-jerk reaction to seeing Schwarzenegger in something a little different to his usual fare, and that perhaps I would appreciate the film more second time round. Well, I just watched it again and, if anything, I disliked it even more than the first time. The basic (high) conceptaction movie fan Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) enters the fictional world of his movie hero Jack Slater (Arnie)is actually pretty clever, allowing for lots of ingenious meta-moments, but the way in which it is all realised is diabolical: the screenplay is full of misjudged humour (what is it with that dumb animated cat?), child star Austin O'Brien puts in a thoroughly annoying performance, and the exaggerated action scenes within Slater's movie-verse are completely devoid of excitement. There are also quite a few jokes that have dated extremely badly, especially the 'star' cameos from people that are no longer as famous as they used to be. The saddest thing about the whole film is that, given the great talent involved (Arnie, screenwriter Shane Black, director John McTiernan) it really should have been much, much better. Studio intervention may have been the reason it turned out so bad, but knowing that doesn't make the film any more enjoyable to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupidity stops where its own awareness starts ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that principle applies for both people and movies. And this is why parody generally provides the cleverest films, mocking the archetypes over-exploited by lazy directors with a subtle, and so engaging, wink to the audience. And "Last Action Hero" parodies the action-flick, featuring its most iconic ambassador, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the lone-ranger bad-ass cigar-smoking titular hero of a never-ending franchise: Jack Slater. As if he was plenty aware that "Die Hard" put a deathblow on the credibility of such super-heroic figures popularized by "Commando" and "Predator", John McTiernan becomes the iconoclast of his own creations -a demonstration of smart sense of humor a few directors ever achieved. The opening "Jack Slater" film even concludes with a reference to the genre-defining "Die Hard", using the same score to contribute to the whole 'inside joke' effect, completed when Jack Slater becomes a movie-within-a-movie character, from the perspective of Danny, his number one fan, played by Austin O'Brien. Basically, Danny is to "Last Action Hero" what Cecilia (Mia Farrow) was to "The Purple Rose of Cairo": a movie lover whose only means to transcend routine's banality was a constant ecstatic stare toward the silver screen. And being a kid of the early 90's, I could only respond to his hypnotic fascination. Action films are indeed the best pop-culture fillers, crystallizing the most common denominators of fun and entertainment and generating codes and formula that are part of cinema's timeless and universal heritage, no matter how overused they are: the never-dying hero, the yelling superior, the revenge plot, the villainous monologue, the sexy daughter, the comic-relief sidekick, the sophisticated boss' right hand who becomes the real villain and a lame catchphrase. They're all there in "Last Action Hero" less because they're obligatory but for the necessity to turn them into derision, by confronting them to reality. Still, there has to be some fantasy in this reality: Danny is given by the projectionist Nick (Art Carney) a magic ticket that belonged to the Great Houdini. And while he watches the fourth opus of Jack Slater's adventures during a private screening, the ticket glows, sticks of dynamite are thrown from the screen and land near his feet. Danny starts to take the notion of 'danger' less cynically before the explosion immediately projects him into his hero's universe. The film's greatest moments come from Danny's desperate attempts to convince Slater that they live in a movie where phone numbers start with "555", video-store workers are sexy and profanity is prohibited. Hell, in this parallel universe, his own rival Stallone played the Terminator roles (which made me wonder who then played Rocky or Rambo). The film recycles every clich&eacute; in such an over-the-top way it's hilarious: the car rams into an ice cream truck and explodes, a henchman gets an ice cone on the neck, many gags feel like these 'McBain' segments from "The Simpsons", thus never fail. The film also features one hilarious modernization of "Hamlet" and two delightful movie references. One of Slater's friends is played by F. Murray Abraham, naturally, Danny warns him that it's the same guy who killed Mozart in "Amadeus": the film that got 8 Oscars. For a kid, he has the knowledge of an IMDb user, which says a lot about "Last Action Hero" exhilarating effect as pure geek escapism, reinforced by the obscure intrusion of Death from "The Seventh Seal", a joke I didn't even get when I saw the film as a teenager. Now, there are two facts regarding "Last Action Hero": the film flopped, and it didn't deserve to, not when box-office laws are governed by rules that allow "Cliffhanger" to be the 7th highest grossing film anyway. Therefore, I can only qualify its bombing as 'accidental', the same accident that made "Sorcerer" flop in 1977. The parallel is all the more eloquent because "Last Action Hero" suffered from an ill-fated opening coinciding with the big event of 1993: the release of Steven Spielberg's "Jurassik park" ("Sorcerer" had it worse with "Star Wars") and perhaps misleading title, trailer and word-of-mouth that branded the film in the total opposite way it expected to: a dumb action film, 'another one'. I don't blame the viewers who thought a bunch of reptilian carnivores would be a fresher spectacle, I, was misled too, the first time I saw the TV announcement. But being a box-office flop is one thing, but when I started to examine the disastrous reception from those who actually saw the film- I was stunned. Seriously, what's with all these Razzies' nominations? Worst actor? Arnold had to play his usual role. Worst screenplay? Check the review's title. Worst new star? That's the worst thing about vocation-discouraging Razzies: the kid was supposed to be annoying and he played that part quite well. Worst song? It's a cheesy action-flick, did they expect Barbra Streisand? "Last Action Hero" is not beyond criticism though especially in the last act, when they 'get' in the real world. It's true that the film could have pushed its self-reflexive concept to more thought-provoking levels, that the emotional involvement lacked when the action was conditioned by predictable plot devices and needed to be compensated in the 'real world'. It's also true that confronting Slater to Arnold (like in Woody Allen's film) or having Danny talking to him, could have induced more interesting situations, but the reception would make anyone believe the film is like "Stop or my Mom Will Shoot!". Talk about unfortunate misunderstanding, not that I believe it truly deserves this 8, but it makes up for the undeserved negativity it inspired. McTiernan would finally make the highest-grossing film of 1995: "Die Hard 3 With a Vengeance" which feels like his personal vengeance. The film is as corny and over-the-top as "Last Action Hero" but I guess the average audience wasn't ready for that level of subtlety, so he probably thought : "Hell, give them the movie they deserve and give me a break".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun cheeky spoof movie that has gained a cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best things about Last Action Hero is that the more you read about it, you realize the smarter it is. There are so many little nods and cheeky references to the action genre and to Hollywood that you can't possibly catch them all the first time around. It appears, on the surface, to be this huge action film but really the entire film is poking fun at the genre. And who better to bring on board to do that but the King of eighties action Arnold Schwarzenegger. There is so much right about this film. The scenes with Arnold playing himself and the interaction between him and "Jack Slater" are just awesome. The cameos and the world they create inside the movie is just so much fun to watch. The problem is that the film is almost too much of a joke. Fans of Schwarzenegger and action films might find their genre being made a total fool of a bit much to handle. And also one of the leading roles is really not good but more on that in a minute. It is definitely a PG-13 movie and while there is nothing wrong with that, it feels like it struggles to purposely try to stay PG and it has trouble doing that. I love Arnold Schwarzenegger, he has just always been one of my Hollywood icons. This is such an odd role for him because he is making fun of himself and what he does best. However, it works well and he is actually fun as Slater. He is especially fun in the brief scenes where is "playing" or "over-playing" himself. The banter between him and real life wife/ex-wife Maria Shriver is just awesome. Austin O'Brien is the young actor portraying Schwarzenegger's partner and his fan as well. O'Brien is unfortunately the character I mentioned previously that really holds back this film. He is simply unnatural and gives a strained and poor performance. It just is very underwhelming. The chemistry between him and Schwarzenegger is nearly awful and that would be the key point to this movie. Charles Dance is very good as the evil villain Benedict. He is over the top but looks menacing and certainly is the perfect personification of an action movie villain. Tom Noonan is also good as the twisted Ripper villain who is also an amped up spoof of a slasher villain. Everyone else in the film are basically cameos but there are some really good ones worth mentioning. F. Murray Abraham, Art Carney, Frank McRae, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and even Ian McKellan are just a few of the faces you will recognize and they give good solid campy performances. If there was any director they should have gotten to direct this film it would be John McTiernan. Die Hard, Predator, The Hunt For Red October, Die Hard 3, Medicine Man...and more. Every action film he has done has at least been decent so he was the perfect choice to do this film and poke fun at the genre. The action scenes are well done and yet overdone at the same time (which granted is the point.) Last Action Hero is fun and exciting but is held back by making fun of itself almost too much. Still, it is a modern day cult classic and more and more people are calling it under-rated and when you look at some of the hidden Easter eggs in the film, it becomes even more fascinating and fun. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice parody of an action movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colm-hearne365
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I noticed that this movie got some pretty bad reception from critics and didn't do that well in the box office but that was because it was released at the same time as Jurassic Park. And I think the reason why people didn't like was because they took it too seriously. The thing is this movie is a parody of action movies like Blazing Saddles is a parody of westerns or Spaceballs was a parody of sci-fi movies. But even I can admit this movie gets pretty cheesy and over the top at times but parodies are like that. And even the kid, Danny was pretty annoying at times. But I think its a fun movie to watch, especially if you're an action fan and Arnold Schwarzenegger has always been my favourite action star. And I like the idea of the clash between fantasy and reality and it's also funny and exciting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated, but not flawless, gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero has got a lot of bad mouthing over the years, but it seems a lot of critics were just jumping on the bandwagon, afraid to say something positive. It is difficult to see why no-one would like it at all. While a tad heavy-handed, the constant riffing on typical macho action flicks is spot-on, always amusing, and yet at the same time the film delivers saw awe-inspiring, sometimes deliberately implausible action set-pieces. Arnie sends himself up fine, while Austin O'Brien often says out loud what most often think watching these kinds of films. Charles Dance makes a menacing villain, and provides some dark amusement of his own - I JUST SHOT SOMEBODY, I DID IT ON PURPOSE. Where the film begins to falter is when the fictional characters, plus Danny, enter the real world. Until this point, it had been going along at a roaring clip, constantly amusing. Perhaps it was necessary to show a dose of reality to those brought up on mindless action flicks, but it starts becoming a little more serious and darker in tone, more sentimental, and consequently less fun. That doesn't make it bad though, and it does provide some food for thought, with Arnie-in-character ranting about how he's fed up of shooting people in films, and blowing things up. Not a masterpiece perhaps, but deserves to be ranked high on Arnie's filmography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Last Action Hero' is Pure Fun! A highly entertaining escapist fare, that works from start to end. 'Last Action Hero' Synopsis: A young movie fan gets thrown into the movie world of his favorite action film character. 'Last Action Hero' is innovative & fun. The pace is perfect & the action-sequences are top-notch. Shane Black, David Arnott & William Goldman's Screenplay is child-like, but works wonderfully. John McTiernan's Direction is efficient. Cinematography is stylish. Art Design is perfect. Performance-Wise: Arnold Schwarzenegger plays to the gallery. He enacts the hero with his usual ease. Austin O'Brien is extremely likable, as he's energetic all through. Robert Prosky is restrained. Charles Dance is excellent. Anthony Quinn is effective. On the whole, 'Last Action Hero' is some great vintage entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This hero stuff has its limits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero is directed by John McTiernan and written by Shane Black and David Arnott. It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, F. Murray Abraham, Charles Dance, Tom Noonan, Austin O'Brien, Art Carney, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and Bridgette Wilson. Music is by Micahel Kamen and cinematography by Dean Semler. Film within a film action parody that sees young Danny Madigan (O'Brien) magically transported into the parallel universe of an action film featuring his fictional hero, Jack Slater (Schwarzenegger). A financial failure and beaten relentlessly by the critics upon release (even McTiernan would condemn it down the line), Last Action Hero is viewed some what in better terms these days. Whilst the arguments that it was ahead of its time, misunderstood and released at the wrong time due to competition with Jurassic Park (the last one was Arnie himself, bless him) are weak and really not worth considering, it's a decent and "intelligent" film that could have been very good if cut by at least half an hour. Running at over two hours in length, the film's central concept of parodying action movies, with Arnold broadly laughing at himself, runs out of steam, the joke just becomes a millstone around its neck. You can see the drop in quality of the action in the last third as well, purely because so much is thrown at the audience, it gets tiresome for the director, which is such a shame given that it's McTiernan at the helm, the man who in Predator and Die Hard gave the 80s its two best American action movies. As it is, and I was helped enormously in my viewing of this because I watched it back to back with Hard Target, much of the parody and cineaste jokes strike a humorous chord. While the roll call of actors lining up to be in on the joke is impressive and often laugh out loud funny. Yet amongst all the satire and tongue in cheek wink winks, there is also some depth to the dizzying narrative that is worth appraising, particularly when the picture pitches up the real life of an actor to that of the character he plays, with one sequence as Arnie faces up to Arnie particularly brilliant. Better than you may have heard it is, but still a film that's difficult to recommend with confidence. Some self-examining depth and smart in- movie jokes ensure it's no dud, but entering the last third it becomes tiresome and routine and that leaves a disappointment that's hard to shake. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it as a kid in '93, and I've grown to appreciate it as an adult.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reading some of the lurid behind-the-scenes details on "Last Action Hero" (do a search, it's scintillating!), one would walk into this thing expecting an &uuml;ber-expensive disaster. And it was, at least financially. But time has been kind to this movie, and it's actually - for most of its runtime - a pretty kickass genre sendup. The idea behind "Last Action Hero" is satirically brilliant: to deconstruct the big Hollywood action movie. You know, your "Lethal Weapon"s, your "Die Hard"s and your Schwarzenegger "sh-t blows up real good!" movies. And when the movie focuses on that aspect, it's a fun romp. You see enough '80s action movies, the tropes and clich&eacute;s become commonplace. They're all here: - huge explosions send the hero flying (ultimately unscathed) while everyone around him winds up dead - change of scenery from location to studio backlot within a scene - there are no unattractive women - police headquarters is unbelievably posh - the Lieutenant speaks only in vein-popping screams - gunshots send bad guys flying - an inordinate number of explosions And it's that novelty of the genre satire that really makes this movie, for me. Which means the film's first 90 minutes are very entertaining. It's when the villain escapes the movie and our focus centers on the real world that "Last Action Hero" loses me. The film's first half is front-loaded with all of the good stuff. All of the good jokes and sight gags are there. I have no interest in what goes on in the real world. The real magic is in the artificial one. But there's strength in the casting. Arnold is able and surprisingly good at offering himself up for parody. And in a role that's sure to be annoying on paper, Austin O'Brien is actually kinda endearing as the kid sidekick. I really liked him here. And Charles Dance as Benedict . . . he's a terrific bad guy. In this type of movie, especially; great comedic timing, and just a pleasure to watch. He steals every one of his scenes. His lines are the funniest. "Last Action Hero" would definitely merit a higher rating if I didn't feel the need to turn it off with 45 minutes left to go. But when I think of this movie, it's that great first half that sticks in my brain. It should've performed better 20 years ago. The lousy reputation is (for the most part) undeserved, and it's a clear example of the kind of curious oddity that can result after many bad decisions made during the filmmaking process. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better the older you get
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dame Shumma
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grandiose, like Schwarzenegger takes the mickey out here himself, knows his last name wrong constantly and eventually called Arnold Braunschweiger. There are ongoing links to other movies, where, like in Die Hard. Danny makes Jack's attention to look up after a car accident even if the bad guy except death. In Die Hard, it was finally so that the blonde is hanged, and at the end is still alive. Grandiose, something is a feast for action lovers. The final rise to the film premiere of "Jack Slater IV" in New York. Schwarzenegger plays himself here, and is approached by his wife to make lasting advertising for Planet Hollywood. John Belushi announces Jack Slater movies so he does not like, and Van Damme, yes, even the Belgian martial arts goes to the premiere. Just plain funny. Slater is run by Danny corrected. Whenever he "I'll be back," says Danny knew beforehand that he will say that it is, after all, his trademark. Even the testing center for movies, the MPAA will not be left out. Danny writes a word, probably "fuck" on a piece of paper. Slater read it will not. Danny Comment: "You can not read it, because this movie is PG-13" Just wonderful. Who wants to keep checking back for once really look over a very successful action movie parody must. However, you should really have already seen some in the sector to understand everything. In order to find every hidden joke I have seen the movie a few times anyway. Well, anyway, the story is incidental and not the hammer. But is sufficient. I admit: Movie Review: 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A curious oddity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When young Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) is given a magic movie ticket by friendly cinema owner Nick (Robert Prosky) at an advance screening of new action movie Jack Slater IV, he is magically transported into the movie and into the car of supercop Jack Slater (Arnold Schwarzenegger). Danny starts to inform Slater about who the bad guys are after seeing them on screen, and the two are paired up as a mismatched investigative duo by Slater's screaming boss. Glass-eyed bad guy Mr. Benedict (Charles Dance) manages to get his hands on the magic ticket, and escapes into the real world, where he finds things are much easier for the bad guys. Slater must leave his action movie clich&eacute; of a world where he is nigh on invincible behind, and enter one where things are slightly more difficult. Last Action Hero had one of the most expensive and turbulent page-to- screen stories in recent cinema history. Originally written as a self- mocking action movie that embraced the clich&eacute;s of the genre, that was also a proper action movie in its own right. After an unexpected bidding war, the young scribes Zak Penn and Adam Leff were shocked to find that Arnold Schwarzenegger had taken a personal interest in it (the original hero name was Arno Slater). This was to be the turning point. Arnie saw the potential for a franchise as a kid's film and immediately wanted to tone down the violence, so Penn and Leff were fired, and genre legend Shane Black was hired to spruce up the script. Things changed yet again when director John McTiernan was brought in, and, due to the success of his previous films, was given full control. A few script re-writes, firings, and storm-outs later, the film was shot and ready to hit the market. A toy franchise and a ridiculously expensive and calamitous advertising campaign (they paid half a million dollars to have the film's name on a NASA rocket, only to have the launched delayed till long after the film's release) were put into motion, and the film's release date was announced for the week after Jurassic Park's. Last Action Hero had disastrous test screenings, but the release date was not changed, and naturally, Jurassic Park stormed the box-office and merchandising range, and Last Action Hero was revealed to be an over-ambitious, confused dud of a movie. However, the legend is rather cruel on Schwarzenegger's biggest flop, as although it is a gigantic mess, it has plenty of interesting ideas than are unfortunately spewed out onto the film in ungraceful belches. The biggest problem is that it doesn't know what kind of film it is. At its heart, its a kid's film, complete with annoying mop-haired child, a kindly old man, magic tickets and, um, a cartoon cat. Yet on its surface, its a rather uninspired action film that is actually rather violent and, once in the real world, is quite grim. The film never seems to know whether it wants to homage, spoof or simply in-joke. The movie world it creates is itself confused - while it has some funny touches such as the police line pairing together various mismatched partners - it also has women walking around in sexy, futuristic costumes, and the aforementioned cartoon cat called Whiskers (voiced by Danny DeVito). Seriously, whose idea was that? I've never seen a cartoon cat in a live- action action movie! However, the sheer mess that is the complete film does prove Last Action Hero to be a curious little oddity. There have been much finer examples of action-movie send-ups, namely in Shane Black's own excellent Kiss Kiss Bang Bang (2005), so perhaps the producers weren't ready back in 1993 to take on such an ambitious project. Arnie is pleasantly game for sending himself up, and Charles Dance chews the screen with his gloriously hammy British bad guy. But Last Action Hero will ultimately always be a reminder of how the Hollywood system to suck up an interesting maverick project, f**k it over a few times, and bundle it over the finishing line with such unbelievable inefficiency. I did love it as a kid, however. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was right the first time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Last Action Hero back in 1993; I didn't like it. Twenty years later and I begin to wonder whether my opinion was a knee-jerk reaction to seeing Schwarzenegger in something a little different to his usual fare, and that perhaps I would appreciate the film more second time round. Well, I just watched it again and, if anything, I disliked it even more than the first time. The basic (high) conceptaction movie fan Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) enters the fictional world of his movie hero Jack Slater (Arnie)is actually pretty clever, allowing for lots of ingenious meta-moments, but the way in which it is all realised is diabolical: the screenplay is full of misjudged humour (what is it with that dumb animated cat?), child star Austin O'Brien puts in a thoroughly annoying performance, and the exaggerated action scenes within Slater's movie-verse are completely devoid of excitement. There are also quite a few jokes that have dated extremely badly, especially the 'star' cameos from people that are no longer as famous as they used to be. The saddest thing about the whole film is that, given the great talent involved (Arnie, screenwriter Shane Black, director John McTiernan) it really should have been much, much better. Studio intervention may have been the reason it turned out so bad, but knowing that doesn't make the film any more enjoyable to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupidity stops where its own awareness starts ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that principle applies for both people and movies. And this is why parody generally provides the cleverest films, mocking the archetypes over-exploited by lazy directors with a subtle, and so engaging, wink to the audience. And "Last Action Hero" parodies the action-flick, featuring its most iconic ambassador, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the lone-ranger bad-ass cigar-smoking titular hero of a never-ending franchise: Jack Slater. As if he was plenty aware that "Die Hard" put a deathblow on the credibility of such super-heroic figures popularized by "Commando" and "Predator", John McTiernan becomes the iconoclast of his own creations -a demonstration of smart sense of humor a few directors ever achieved. The opening "Jack Slater" film even concludes with a reference to the genre-defining "Die Hard", using the same score to contribute to the whole 'inside joke' effect, completed when Jack Slater becomes a movie-within-a-movie character, from the perspective of Danny, his number one fan, played by Austin O'Brien. Basically, Danny is to "Last Action Hero" what Cecilia (Mia Farrow) was to "The Purple Rose of Cairo": a movie lover whose only means to transcend routine's banality was a constant ecstatic stare toward the silver screen. And being a kid of the early 90's, I could only respond to his hypnotic fascination. Action films are indeed the best pop-culture fillers, crystallizing the most common denominators of fun and entertainment and generating codes and formula that are part of cinema's timeless and universal heritage, no matter how overused they are: the never-dying hero, the yelling superior, the revenge plot, the villainous monologue, the sexy daughter, the comic-relief sidekick, the sophisticated boss' right hand who becomes the real villain and a lame catchphrase. They're all there in "Last Action Hero" less because they're obligatory but for the necessity to turn them into derision, by confronting them to reality. Still, there has to be some fantasy in this reality: Danny is given by the projectionist Nick (Art Carney) a magic ticket that belonged to the Great Houdini. And while he watches the fourth opus of Jack Slater's adventures during a private screening, the ticket glows, sticks of dynamite are thrown from the screen and land near his feet. Danny starts to take the notion of 'danger' less cynically before the explosion immediately projects him into his hero's universe. The film's greatest moments come from Danny's desperate attempts to convince Slater that they live in a movie where phone numbers start with "555", video-store workers are sexy and profanity is prohibited. Hell, in this parallel universe, his own rival Stallone played the Terminator roles (which made me wonder who then played Rocky or Rambo). The film recycles every clich&eacute; in such an over-the-top way it's hilarious: the car rams into an ice cream truck and explodes, a henchman gets an ice cone on the neck, many gags feel like these 'McBain' segments from "The Simpsons", thus never fail. The film also features one hilarious modernization of "Hamlet" and two delightful movie references. One of Slater's friends is played by F. Murray Abraham, naturally, Danny warns him that it's the same guy who killed Mozart in "Amadeus": the film that got 8 Oscars. For a kid, he has the knowledge of an IMDb user, which says a lot about "Last Action Hero" exhilarating effect as pure geek escapism, reinforced by the obscure intrusion of Death from "The Seventh Seal", a joke I didn't even get when I saw the film as a teenager. Now, there are two facts regarding "Last Action Hero": the film flopped, and it didn't deserve to, not when box-office laws are governed by rules that allow "Cliffhanger" to be the 7th highest grossing film anyway. Therefore, I can only qualify its bombing as 'accidental', the same accident that made "Sorcerer" flop in 1977. The parallel is all the more eloquent because "Last Action Hero" suffered from an ill-fated opening coinciding with the big event of 1993: the release of Steven Spielberg's "Jurassik park" ("Sorcerer" had it worse with "Star Wars") and perhaps misleading title, trailer and word-of-mouth that branded the film in the total opposite way it expected to: a dumb action film, 'another one'. I don't blame the viewers who thought a bunch of reptilian carnivores would be a fresher spectacle, I, was misled too, the first time I saw the TV announcement. But being a box-office flop is one thing, but when I started to examine the disastrous reception from those who actually saw the film- I was stunned. Seriously, what's with all these Razzies' nominations? Worst actor? Arnold had to play his usual role. Worst screenplay? Check the review's title. Worst new star? That's the worst thing about vocation-discouraging Razzies: the kid was supposed to be annoying and he played that part quite well. Worst song? It's a cheesy action-flick, did they expect Barbra Streisand? "Last Action Hero" is not beyond criticism though especially in the last act, when they 'get' in the real world. It's true that the film could have pushed its self-reflexive concept to more thought-provoking levels, that the emotional involvement lacked when the action was conditioned by predictable plot devices and needed to be compensated in the 'real world'. It's also true that confronting Slater to Arnold (like in Woody Allen's film) or having Danny talking to him, could have induced more interesting situations, but the reception would make anyone believe the film is like "Stop or my Mom Will Shoot!". Talk about unfortunate misunderstanding, not that I believe it truly deserves this 8, but it makes up for the undeserved negativity it inspired. McTiernan would finally make the highest-grossing film of 1995: "Die Hard 3 With a Vengeance" which feels like his personal vengeance. The film is as corny and over-the-top as "Last Action Hero" but I guess the average audience wasn't ready for that level of subtlety, so he probably thought : "Hell, give them the movie they deserve and give me a break".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun cheeky spoof movie that has gained a cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best things about Last Action Hero is that the more you read about it, you realize the smarter it is. There are so many little nods and cheeky references to the action genre and to Hollywood that you can't possibly catch them all the first time around. It appears, on the surface, to be this huge action film but really the entire film is poking fun at the genre. And who better to bring on board to do that but the King of eighties action Arnold Schwarzenegger. There is so much right about this film. The scenes with Arnold playing himself and the interaction between him and "Jack Slater" are just awesome. The cameos and the world they create inside the movie is just so much fun to watch. The problem is that the film is almost too much of a joke. Fans of Schwarzenegger and action films might find their genre being made a total fool of a bit much to handle. And also one of the leading roles is really not good but more on that in a minute. It is definitely a PG-13 movie and while there is nothing wrong with that, it feels like it struggles to purposely try to stay PG and it has trouble doing that. I love Arnold Schwarzenegger, he has just always been one of my Hollywood icons. This is such an odd role for him because he is making fun of himself and what he does best. However, it works well and he is actually fun as Slater. He is especially fun in the brief scenes where is "playing" or "over-playing" himself. The banter between him and real life wife/ex-wife Maria Shriver is just awesome. Austin O'Brien is the young actor portraying Schwarzenegger's partner and his fan as well. O'Brien is unfortunately the character I mentioned previously that really holds back this film. He is simply unnatural and gives a strained and poor performance. It just is very underwhelming. The chemistry between him and Schwarzenegger is nearly awful and that would be the key point to this movie. Charles Dance is very good as the evil villain Benedict. He is over the top but looks menacing and certainly is the perfect personification of an action movie villain. Tom Noonan is also good as the twisted Ripper villain who is also an amped up spoof of a slasher villain. Everyone else in the film are basically cameos but there are some really good ones worth mentioning. F. Murray Abraham, Art Carney, Frank McRae, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and even Ian McKellan are just a few of the faces you will recognize and they give good solid campy performances. If there was any director they should have gotten to direct this film it would be John McTiernan. Die Hard, Predator, The Hunt For Red October, Die Hard 3, Medicine Man...and more. Every action film he has done has at least been decent so he was the perfect choice to do this film and poke fun at the genre. The action scenes are well done and yet overdone at the same time (which granted is the point.) Last Action Hero is fun and exciting but is held back by making fun of itself almost too much. Still, it is a modern day cult classic and more and more people are calling it under-rated and when you look at some of the hidden Easter eggs in the film, it becomes even more fascinating and fun. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice parody of an action movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colm-hearne365
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I noticed that this movie got some pretty bad reception from critics and didn't do that well in the box office but that was because it was released at the same time as Jurassic Park. And I think the reason why people didn't like was because they took it too seriously. The thing is this movie is a parody of action movies like Blazing Saddles is a parody of westerns or Spaceballs was a parody of sci-fi movies. But even I can admit this movie gets pretty cheesy and over the top at times but parodies are like that. And even the kid, Danny was pretty annoying at times. But I think its a fun movie to watch, especially if you're an action fan and Arnold Schwarzenegger has always been my favourite action star. And I like the idea of the clash between fantasy and reality and it's also funny and exciting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated, but not flawless, gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero has got a lot of bad mouthing over the years, but it seems a lot of critics were just jumping on the bandwagon, afraid to say something positive. It is difficult to see why no-one would like it at all. While a tad heavy-handed, the constant riffing on typical macho action flicks is spot-on, always amusing, and yet at the same time the film delivers saw awe-inspiring, sometimes deliberately implausible action set-pieces. Arnie sends himself up fine, while Austin O'Brien often says out loud what most often think watching these kinds of films. Charles Dance makes a menacing villain, and provides some dark amusement of his own - I JUST SHOT SOMEBODY, I DID IT ON PURPOSE. Where the film begins to falter is when the fictional characters, plus Danny, enter the real world. Until this point, it had been going along at a roaring clip, constantly amusing. Perhaps it was necessary to show a dose of reality to those brought up on mindless action flicks, but it starts becoming a little more serious and darker in tone, more sentimental, and consequently less fun. That doesn't make it bad though, and it does provide some food for thought, with Arnie-in-character ranting about how he's fed up of shooting people in films, and blowing things up. Not a masterpiece perhaps, but deserves to be ranked high on Arnie's filmography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Last Action Hero' is Pure Fun! A highly entertaining escapist fare, that works from start to end. 'Last Action Hero' Synopsis: A young movie fan gets thrown into the movie world of his favorite action film character. 'Last Action Hero' is innovative & fun. The pace is perfect & the action-sequences are top-notch. Shane Black, David Arnott & William Goldman's Screenplay is child-like, but works wonderfully. John McTiernan's Direction is efficient. Cinematography is stylish. Art Design is perfect. Performance-Wise: Arnold Schwarzenegger plays to the gallery. He enacts the hero with his usual ease. Austin O'Brien is extremely likable, as he's energetic all through. Robert Prosky is restrained. Charles Dance is excellent. Anthony Quinn is effective. On the whole, 'Last Action Hero' is some great vintage entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This hero stuff has its limits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero is directed by John McTiernan and written by Shane Black and David Arnott. It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, F. Murray Abraham, Charles Dance, Tom Noonan, Austin O'Brien, Art Carney, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and Bridgette Wilson. Music is by Micahel Kamen and cinematography by Dean Semler. Film within a film action parody that sees young Danny Madigan (O'Brien) magically transported into the parallel universe of an action film featuring his fictional hero, Jack Slater (Schwarzenegger). A financial failure and beaten relentlessly by the critics upon release (even McTiernan would condemn it down the line), Last Action Hero is viewed some what in better terms these days. Whilst the arguments that it was ahead of its time, misunderstood and released at the wrong time due to competition with Jurassic Park (the last one was Arnie himself, bless him) are weak and really not worth considering, it's a decent and "intelligent" film that could have been very good if cut by at least half an hour. Running at over two hours in length, the film's central concept of parodying action movies, with Arnold broadly laughing at himself, runs out of steam, the joke just becomes a millstone around its neck. You can see the drop in quality of the action in the last third as well, purely because so much is thrown at the audience, it gets tiresome for the director, which is such a shame given that it's McTiernan at the helm, the man who in Predator and Die Hard gave the 80s its two best American action movies. As it is, and I was helped enormously in my viewing of this because I watched it back to back with Hard Target, much of the parody and cineaste jokes strike a humorous chord. While the roll call of actors lining up to be in on the joke is impressive and often laugh out loud funny. Yet amongst all the satire and tongue in cheek wink winks, there is also some depth to the dizzying narrative that is worth appraising, particularly when the picture pitches up the real life of an actor to that of the character he plays, with one sequence as Arnie faces up to Arnie particularly brilliant. Better than you may have heard it is, but still a film that's difficult to recommend with confidence. Some self-examining depth and smart in- movie jokes ensure it's no dud, but entering the last third it becomes tiresome and routine and that leaves a disappointment that's hard to shake. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it as a kid in '93, and I've grown to appreciate it as an adult.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reading some of the lurid behind-the-scenes details on "Last Action Hero" (do a search, it's scintillating!), one would walk into this thing expecting an &uuml;ber-expensive disaster. And it was, at least financially. But time has been kind to this movie, and it's actually - for most of its runtime - a pretty kickass genre sendup. The idea behind "Last Action Hero" is satirically brilliant: to deconstruct the big Hollywood action movie. You know, your "Lethal Weapon"s, your "Die Hard"s and your Schwarzenegger "sh-t blows up real good!" movies. And when the movie focuses on that aspect, it's a fun romp. You see enough '80s action movies, the tropes and clich&eacute;s become commonplace. They're all here: - huge explosions send the hero flying (ultimately unscathed) while everyone around him winds up dead - change of scenery from location to studio backlot within a scene - there are no unattractive women - police headquarters is unbelievably posh - the Lieutenant speaks only in vein-popping screams - gunshots send bad guys flying - an inordinate number of explosions And it's that novelty of the genre satire that really makes this movie, for me. Which means the film's first 90 minutes are very entertaining. It's when the villain escapes the movie and our focus centers on the real world that "Last Action Hero" loses me. The film's first half is front-loaded with all of the good stuff. All of the good jokes and sight gags are there. I have no interest in what goes on in the real world. The real magic is in the artificial one. But there's strength in the casting. Arnold is able and surprisingly good at offering himself up for parody. And in a role that's sure to be annoying on paper, Austin O'Brien is actually kinda endearing as the kid sidekick. I really liked him here. And Charles Dance as Benedict . . . he's a terrific bad guy. In this type of movie, especially; great comedic timing, and just a pleasure to watch. He steals every one of his scenes. His lines are the funniest. "Last Action Hero" would definitely merit a higher rating if I didn't feel the need to turn it off with 45 minutes left to go. But when I think of this movie, it's that great first half that sticks in my brain. It should've performed better 20 years ago. The lousy reputation is (for the most part) undeserved, and it's a clear example of the kind of curious oddity that can result after many bad decisions made during the filmmaking process. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better the older you get
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dame Shumma
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grandiose, like Schwarzenegger takes the mickey out here himself, knows his last name wrong constantly and eventually called Arnold Braunschweiger. There are ongoing links to other movies, where, like in Die Hard. Danny makes Jack's attention to look up after a car accident even if the bad guy except death. In Die Hard, it was finally so that the blonde is hanged, and at the end is still alive. Grandiose, something is a feast for action lovers. The final rise to the film premiere of "Jack Slater IV" in New York. Schwarzenegger plays himself here, and is approached by his wife to make lasting advertising for Planet Hollywood. John Belushi announces Jack Slater movies so he does not like, and Van Damme, yes, even the Belgian martial arts goes to the premiere. Just plain funny. Slater is run by Danny corrected. Whenever he "I'll be back," says Danny knew beforehand that he will say that it is, after all, his trademark. Even the testing center for movies, the MPAA will not be left out. Danny writes a word, probably "fuck" on a piece of paper. Slater read it will not. Danny Comment: "You can not read it, because this movie is PG-13" Just wonderful. Who wants to keep checking back for once really look over a very successful action movie parody must. However, you should really have already seen some in the sector to understand everything. In order to find every hidden joke I have seen the movie a few times anyway. Well, anyway, the story is incidental and not the hammer. But is sufficient. I admit: Movie Review: 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A curious oddity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When young Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) is given a magic movie ticket by friendly cinema owner Nick (Robert Prosky) at an advance screening of new action movie Jack Slater IV, he is magically transported into the movie and into the car of supercop Jack Slater (Arnold Schwarzenegger). Danny starts to inform Slater about who the bad guys are after seeing them on screen, and the two are paired up as a mismatched investigative duo by Slater's screaming boss. Glass-eyed bad guy Mr. Benedict (Charles Dance) manages to get his hands on the magic ticket, and escapes into the real world, where he finds things are much easier for the bad guys. Slater must leave his action movie clich&eacute; of a world where he is nigh on invincible behind, and enter one where things are slightly more difficult. Last Action Hero had one of the most expensive and turbulent page-to- screen stories in recent cinema history. Originally written as a self- mocking action movie that embraced the clich&eacute;s of the genre, that was also a proper action movie in its own right. After an unexpected bidding war, the young scribes Zak Penn and Adam Leff were shocked to find that Arnold Schwarzenegger had taken a personal interest in it (the original hero name was Arno Slater). This was to be the turning point. Arnie saw the potential for a franchise as a kid's film and immediately wanted to tone down the violence, so Penn and Leff were fired, and genre legend Shane Black was hired to spruce up the script. Things changed yet again when director John McTiernan was brought in, and, due to the success of his previous films, was given full control. A few script re-writes, firings, and storm-outs later, the film was shot and ready to hit the market. A toy franchise and a ridiculously expensive and calamitous advertising campaign (they paid half a million dollars to have the film's name on a NASA rocket, only to have the launched delayed till long after the film's release) were put into motion, and the film's release date was announced for the week after Jurassic Park's. Last Action Hero had disastrous test screenings, but the release date was not changed, and naturally, Jurassic Park stormed the box-office and merchandising range, and Last Action Hero was revealed to be an over-ambitious, confused dud of a movie. However, the legend is rather cruel on Schwarzenegger's biggest flop, as although it is a gigantic mess, it has plenty of interesting ideas than are unfortunately spewed out onto the film in ungraceful belches. The biggest problem is that it doesn't know what kind of film it is. At its heart, its a kid's film, complete with annoying mop-haired child, a kindly old man, magic tickets and, um, a cartoon cat. Yet on its surface, its a rather uninspired action film that is actually rather violent and, once in the real world, is quite grim. The film never seems to know whether it wants to homage, spoof or simply in-joke. The movie world it creates is itself confused - while it has some funny touches such as the police line pairing together various mismatched partners - it also has women walking around in sexy, futuristic costumes, and the aforementioned cartoon cat called Whiskers (voiced by Danny DeVito). Seriously, whose idea was that? I've never seen a cartoon cat in a live- action action movie! However, the sheer mess that is the complete film does prove Last Action Hero to be a curious little oddity. There have been much finer examples of action-movie send-ups, namely in Shane Black's own excellent Kiss Kiss Bang Bang (2005), so perhaps the producers weren't ready back in 1993 to take on such an ambitious project. Arnie is pleasantly game for sending himself up, and Charles Dance chews the screen with his gloriously hammy British bad guy. But Last Action Hero will ultimately always be a reminder of how the Hollywood system to suck up an interesting maverick project, f**k it over a few times, and bundle it over the finishing line with such unbelievable inefficiency. I did love it as a kid, however. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was right the first time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Last Action Hero back in 1993; I didn't like it. Twenty years later and I begin to wonder whether my opinion was a knee-jerk reaction to seeing Schwarzenegger in something a little different to his usual fare, and that perhaps I would appreciate the film more second time round. Well, I just watched it again and, if anything, I disliked it even more than the first time. The basic (high) conceptaction movie fan Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) enters the fictional world of his movie hero Jack Slater (Arnie)is actually pretty clever, allowing for lots of ingenious meta-moments, but the way in which it is all realised is diabolical: the screenplay is full of misjudged humour (what is it with that dumb animated cat?), child star Austin O'Brien puts in a thoroughly annoying performance, and the exaggerated action scenes within Slater's movie-verse are completely devoid of excitement. There are also quite a few jokes that have dated extremely badly, especially the 'star' cameos from people that are no longer as famous as they used to be. The saddest thing about the whole film is that, given the great talent involved (Arnie, screenwriter Shane Black, director John McTiernan) it really should have been much, much better. Studio intervention may have been the reason it turned out so bad, but knowing that doesn't make the film any more enjoyable to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupidity stops where its own awareness starts ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that principle applies for both people and movies. And this is why parody generally provides the cleverest films, mocking the archetypes over-exploited by lazy directors with a subtle, and so engaging, wink to the audience. And "Last Action Hero" parodies the action-flick, featuring its most iconic ambassador, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the lone-ranger bad-ass cigar-smoking titular hero of a never-ending franchise: Jack Slater. As if he was plenty aware that "Die Hard" put a deathblow on the credibility of such super-heroic figures popularized by "Commando" and "Predator", John McTiernan becomes the iconoclast of his own creations -a demonstration of smart sense of humor a few directors ever achieved. The opening "Jack Slater" film even concludes with a reference to the genre-defining "Die Hard", using the same score to contribute to the whole 'inside joke' effect, completed when Jack Slater becomes a movie-within-a-movie character, from the perspective of Danny, his number one fan, played by Austin O'Brien. Basically, Danny is to "Last Action Hero" what Cecilia (Mia Farrow) was to "The Purple Rose of Cairo": a movie lover whose only means to transcend routine's banality was a constant ecstatic stare toward the silver screen. And being a kid of the early 90's, I could only respond to his hypnotic fascination. Action films are indeed the best pop-culture fillers, crystallizing the most common denominators of fun and entertainment and generating codes and formula that are part of cinema's timeless and universal heritage, no matter how overused they are: the never-dying hero, the yelling superior, the revenge plot, the villainous monologue, the sexy daughter, the comic-relief sidekick, the sophisticated boss' right hand who becomes the real villain and a lame catchphrase. They're all there in "Last Action Hero" less because they're obligatory but for the necessity to turn them into derision, by confronting them to reality. Still, there has to be some fantasy in this reality: Danny is given by the projectionist Nick (Art Carney) a magic ticket that belonged to the Great Houdini. And while he watches the fourth opus of Jack Slater's adventures during a private screening, the ticket glows, sticks of dynamite are thrown from the screen and land near his feet. Danny starts to take the notion of 'danger' less cynically before the explosion immediately projects him into his hero's universe. The film's greatest moments come from Danny's desperate attempts to convince Slater that they live in a movie where phone numbers start with "555", video-store workers are sexy and profanity is prohibited. Hell, in this parallel universe, his own rival Stallone played the Terminator roles (which made me wonder who then played Rocky or Rambo). The film recycles every clich&eacute; in such an over-the-top way it's hilarious: the car rams into an ice cream truck and explodes, a henchman gets an ice cone on the neck, many gags feel like these 'McBain' segments from "The Simpsons", thus never fail. The film also features one hilarious modernization of "Hamlet" and two delightful movie references. One of Slater's friends is played by F. Murray Abraham, naturally, Danny warns him that it's the same guy who killed Mozart in "Amadeus": the film that got 8 Oscars. For a kid, he has the knowledge of an IMDb user, which says a lot about "Last Action Hero" exhilarating effect as pure geek escapism, reinforced by the obscure intrusion of Death from "The Seventh Seal", a joke I didn't even get when I saw the film as a teenager. Now, there are two facts regarding "Last Action Hero": the film flopped, and it didn't deserve to, not when box-office laws are governed by rules that allow "Cliffhanger" to be the 7th highest grossing film anyway. Therefore, I can only qualify its bombing as 'accidental', the same accident that made "Sorcerer" flop in 1977. The parallel is all the more eloquent because "Last Action Hero" suffered from an ill-fated opening coinciding with the big event of 1993: the release of Steven Spielberg's "Jurassik park" ("Sorcerer" had it worse with "Star Wars") and perhaps misleading title, trailer and word-of-mouth that branded the film in the total opposite way it expected to: a dumb action film, 'another one'. I don't blame the viewers who thought a bunch of reptilian carnivores would be a fresher spectacle, I, was misled too, the first time I saw the TV announcement. But being a box-office flop is one thing, but when I started to examine the disastrous reception from those who actually saw the film- I was stunned. Seriously, what's with all these Razzies' nominations? Worst actor? Arnold had to play his usual role. Worst screenplay? Check the review's title. Worst new star? That's the worst thing about vocation-discouraging Razzies: the kid was supposed to be annoying and he played that part quite well. Worst song? It's a cheesy action-flick, did they expect Barbra Streisand? "Last Action Hero" is not beyond criticism though especially in the last act, when they 'get' in the real world. It's true that the film could have pushed its self-reflexive concept to more thought-provoking levels, that the emotional involvement lacked when the action was conditioned by predictable plot devices and needed to be compensated in the 'real world'. It's also true that confronting Slater to Arnold (like in Woody Allen's film) or having Danny talking to him, could have induced more interesting situations, but the reception would make anyone believe the film is like "Stop or my Mom Will Shoot!". Talk about unfortunate misunderstanding, not that I believe it truly deserves this 8, but it makes up for the undeserved negativity it inspired. McTiernan would finally make the highest-grossing film of 1995: "Die Hard 3 With a Vengeance" which feels like his personal vengeance. The film is as corny and over-the-top as "Last Action Hero" but I guess the average audience wasn't ready for that level of subtlety, so he probably thought : "Hell, give them the movie they deserve and give me a break".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun cheeky spoof movie that has gained a cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best things about Last Action Hero is that the more you read about it, you realize the smarter it is. There are so many little nods and cheeky references to the action genre and to Hollywood that you can't possibly catch them all the first time around. It appears, on the surface, to be this huge action film but really the entire film is poking fun at the genre. And who better to bring on board to do that but the King of eighties action Arnold Schwarzenegger. There is so much right about this film. The scenes with Arnold playing himself and the interaction between him and "Jack Slater" are just awesome. The cameos and the world they create inside the movie is just so much fun to watch. The problem is that the film is almost too much of a joke. Fans of Schwarzenegger and action films might find their genre being made a total fool of a bit much to handle. And also one of the leading roles is really not good but more on that in a minute. It is definitely a PG-13 movie and while there is nothing wrong with that, it feels like it struggles to purposely try to stay PG and it has trouble doing that. I love Arnold Schwarzenegger, he has just always been one of my Hollywood icons. This is such an odd role for him because he is making fun of himself and what he does best. However, it works well and he is actually fun as Slater. He is especially fun in the brief scenes where is "playing" or "over-playing" himself. The banter between him and real life wife/ex-wife Maria Shriver is just awesome. Austin O'Brien is the young actor portraying Schwarzenegger's partner and his fan as well. O'Brien is unfortunately the character I mentioned previously that really holds back this film. He is simply unnatural and gives a strained and poor performance. It just is very underwhelming. The chemistry between him and Schwarzenegger is nearly awful and that would be the key point to this movie. Charles Dance is very good as the evil villain Benedict. He is over the top but looks menacing and certainly is the perfect personification of an action movie villain. Tom Noonan is also good as the twisted Ripper villain who is also an amped up spoof of a slasher villain. Everyone else in the film are basically cameos but there are some really good ones worth mentioning. F. Murray Abraham, Art Carney, Frank McRae, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and even Ian McKellan are just a few of the faces you will recognize and they give good solid campy performances. If there was any director they should have gotten to direct this film it would be John McTiernan. Die Hard, Predator, The Hunt For Red October, Die Hard 3, Medicine Man...and more. Every action film he has done has at least been decent so he was the perfect choice to do this film and poke fun at the genre. The action scenes are well done and yet overdone at the same time (which granted is the point.) Last Action Hero is fun and exciting but is held back by making fun of itself almost too much. Still, it is a modern day cult classic and more and more people are calling it under-rated and when you look at some of the hidden Easter eggs in the film, it becomes even more fascinating and fun. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice parody of an action movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colm-hearne365
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I noticed that this movie got some pretty bad reception from critics and didn't do that well in the box office but that was because it was released at the same time as Jurassic Park. And I think the reason why people didn't like was because they took it too seriously. The thing is this movie is a parody of action movies like Blazing Saddles is a parody of westerns or Spaceballs was a parody of sci-fi movies. But even I can admit this movie gets pretty cheesy and over the top at times but parodies are like that. And even the kid, Danny was pretty annoying at times. But I think its a fun movie to watch, especially if you're an action fan and Arnold Schwarzenegger has always been my favourite action star. And I like the idea of the clash between fantasy and reality and it's also funny and exciting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated, but not flawless, gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero has got a lot of bad mouthing over the years, but it seems a lot of critics were just jumping on the bandwagon, afraid to say something positive. It is difficult to see why no-one would like it at all. While a tad heavy-handed, the constant riffing on typical macho action flicks is spot-on, always amusing, and yet at the same time the film delivers saw awe-inspiring, sometimes deliberately implausible action set-pieces. Arnie sends himself up fine, while Austin O'Brien often says out loud what most often think watching these kinds of films. Charles Dance makes a menacing villain, and provides some dark amusement of his own - I JUST SHOT SOMEBODY, I DID IT ON PURPOSE. Where the film begins to falter is when the fictional characters, plus Danny, enter the real world. Until this point, it had been going along at a roaring clip, constantly amusing. Perhaps it was necessary to show a dose of reality to those brought up on mindless action flicks, but it starts becoming a little more serious and darker in tone, more sentimental, and consequently less fun. That doesn't make it bad though, and it does provide some food for thought, with Arnie-in-character ranting about how he's fed up of shooting people in films, and blowing things up. Not a masterpiece perhaps, but deserves to be ranked high on Arnie's filmography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Last Action Hero' is Pure Fun! A highly entertaining escapist fare, that works from start to end. 'Last Action Hero' Synopsis: A young movie fan gets thrown into the movie world of his favorite action film character. 'Last Action Hero' is innovative & fun. The pace is perfect & the action-sequences are top-notch. Shane Black, David Arnott & William Goldman's Screenplay is child-like, but works wonderfully. John McTiernan's Direction is efficient. Cinematography is stylish. Art Design is perfect. Performance-Wise: Arnold Schwarzenegger plays to the gallery. He enacts the hero with his usual ease. Austin O'Brien is extremely likable, as he's energetic all through. Robert Prosky is restrained. Charles Dance is excellent. Anthony Quinn is effective. On the whole, 'Last Action Hero' is some great vintage entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This hero stuff has its limits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero is directed by John McTiernan and written by Shane Black and David Arnott. It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, F. Murray Abraham, Charles Dance, Tom Noonan, Austin O'Brien, Art Carney, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and Bridgette Wilson. Music is by Micahel Kamen and cinematography by Dean Semler. Film within a film action parody that sees young Danny Madigan (O'Brien) magically transported into the parallel universe of an action film featuring his fictional hero, Jack Slater (Schwarzenegger). A financial failure and beaten relentlessly by the critics upon release (even McTiernan would condemn it down the line), Last Action Hero is viewed some what in better terms these days. Whilst the arguments that it was ahead of its time, misunderstood and released at the wrong time due to competition with Jurassic Park (the last one was Arnie himself, bless him) are weak and really not worth considering, it's a decent and "intelligent" film that could have been very good if cut by at least half an hour. Running at over two hours in length, the film's central concept of parodying action movies, with Arnold broadly laughing at himself, runs out of steam, the joke just becomes a millstone around its neck. You can see the drop in quality of the action in the last third as well, purely because so much is thrown at the audience, it gets tiresome for the director, which is such a shame given that it's McTiernan at the helm, the man who in Predator and Die Hard gave the 80s its two best American action movies. As it is, and I was helped enormously in my viewing of this because I watched it back to back with Hard Target, much of the parody and cineaste jokes strike a humorous chord. While the roll call of actors lining up to be in on the joke is impressive and often laugh out loud funny. Yet amongst all the satire and tongue in cheek wink winks, there is also some depth to the dizzying narrative that is worth appraising, particularly when the picture pitches up the real life of an actor to that of the character he plays, with one sequence as Arnie faces up to Arnie particularly brilliant. Better than you may have heard it is, but still a film that's difficult to recommend with confidence. Some self-examining depth and smart in- movie jokes ensure it's no dud, but entering the last third it becomes tiresome and routine and that leaves a disappointment that's hard to shake. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it as a kid in '93, and I've grown to appreciate it as an adult.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reading some of the lurid behind-the-scenes details on "Last Action Hero" (do a search, it's scintillating!), one would walk into this thing expecting an &uuml;ber-expensive disaster. And it was, at least financially. But time has been kind to this movie, and it's actually - for most of its runtime - a pretty kickass genre sendup. The idea behind "Last Action Hero" is satirically brilliant: to deconstruct the big Hollywood action movie. You know, your "Lethal Weapon"s, your "Die Hard"s and your Schwarzenegger "sh-t blows up real good!" movies. And when the movie focuses on that aspect, it's a fun romp. You see enough '80s action movies, the tropes and clich&eacute;s become commonplace. They're all here: - huge explosions send the hero flying (ultimately unscathed) while everyone around him winds up dead - change of scenery from location to studio backlot within a scene - there are no unattractive women - police headquarters is unbelievably posh - the Lieutenant speaks only in vein-popping screams - gunshots send bad guys flying - an inordinate number of explosions And it's that novelty of the genre satire that really makes this movie, for me. Which means the film's first 90 minutes are very entertaining. It's when the villain escapes the movie and our focus centers on the real world that "Last Action Hero" loses me. The film's first half is front-loaded with all of the good stuff. All of the good jokes and sight gags are there. I have no interest in what goes on in the real world. The real magic is in the artificial one. But there's strength in the casting. Arnold is able and surprisingly good at offering himself up for parody. And in a role that's sure to be annoying on paper, Austin O'Brien is actually kinda endearing as the kid sidekick. I really liked him here. And Charles Dance as Benedict . . . he's a terrific bad guy. In this type of movie, especially; great comedic timing, and just a pleasure to watch. He steals every one of his scenes. His lines are the funniest. "Last Action Hero" would definitely merit a higher rating if I didn't feel the need to turn it off with 45 minutes left to go. But when I think of this movie, it's that great first half that sticks in my brain. It should've performed better 20 years ago. The lousy reputation is (for the most part) undeserved, and it's a clear example of the kind of curious oddity that can result after many bad decisions made during the filmmaking process. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better the older you get
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dame Shumma
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grandiose, like Schwarzenegger takes the mickey out here himself, knows his last name wrong constantly and eventually called Arnold Braunschweiger. There are ongoing links to other movies, where, like in Die Hard. Danny makes Jack's attention to look up after a car accident even if the bad guy except death. In Die Hard, it was finally so that the blonde is hanged, and at the end is still alive. Grandiose, something is a feast for action lovers. The final rise to the film premiere of "Jack Slater IV" in New York. Schwarzenegger plays himself here, and is approached by his wife to make lasting advertising for Planet Hollywood. John Belushi announces Jack Slater movies so he does not like, and Van Damme, yes, even the Belgian martial arts goes to the premiere. Just plain funny. Slater is run by Danny corrected. Whenever he "I'll be back," says Danny knew beforehand that he will say that it is, after all, his trademark. Even the testing center for movies, the MPAA will not be left out. Danny writes a word, probably "fuck" on a piece of paper. Slater read it will not. Danny Comment: "You can not read it, because this movie is PG-13" Just wonderful. Who wants to keep checking back for once really look over a very successful action movie parody must. However, you should really have already seen some in the sector to understand everything. In order to find every hidden joke I have seen the movie a few times anyway. Well, anyway, the story is incidental and not the hammer. But is sufficient. I admit: Movie Review: 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A curious oddity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When young Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) is given a magic movie ticket by friendly cinema owner Nick (Robert Prosky) at an advance screening of new action movie Jack Slater IV, he is magically transported into the movie and into the car of supercop Jack Slater (Arnold Schwarzenegger). Danny starts to inform Slater about who the bad guys are after seeing them on screen, and the two are paired up as a mismatched investigative duo by Slater's screaming boss. Glass-eyed bad guy Mr. Benedict (Charles Dance) manages to get his hands on the magic ticket, and escapes into the real world, where he finds things are much easier for the bad guys. Slater must leave his action movie clich&eacute; of a world where he is nigh on invincible behind, and enter one where things are slightly more difficult. Last Action Hero had one of the most expensive and turbulent page-to- screen stories in recent cinema history. Originally written as a self- mocking action movie that embraced the clich&eacute;s of the genre, that was also a proper action movie in its own right. After an unexpected bidding war, the young scribes Zak Penn and Adam Leff were shocked to find that Arnold Schwarzenegger had taken a personal interest in it (the original hero name was Arno Slater). This was to be the turning point. Arnie saw the potential for a franchise as a kid's film and immediately wanted to tone down the violence, so Penn and Leff were fired, and genre legend Shane Black was hired to spruce up the script. Things changed yet again when director John McTiernan was brought in, and, due to the success of his previous films, was given full control. A few script re-writes, firings, and storm-outs later, the film was shot and ready to hit the market. A toy franchise and a ridiculously expensive and calamitous advertising campaign (they paid half a million dollars to have the film's name on a NASA rocket, only to have the launched delayed till long after the film's release) were put into motion, and the film's release date was announced for the week after Jurassic Park's. Last Action Hero had disastrous test screenings, but the release date was not changed, and naturally, Jurassic Park stormed the box-office and merchandising range, and Last Action Hero was revealed to be an over-ambitious, confused dud of a movie. However, the legend is rather cruel on Schwarzenegger's biggest flop, as although it is a gigantic mess, it has plenty of interesting ideas than are unfortunately spewed out onto the film in ungraceful belches. The biggest problem is that it doesn't know what kind of film it is. At its heart, its a kid's film, complete with annoying mop-haired child, a kindly old man, magic tickets and, um, a cartoon cat. Yet on its surface, its a rather uninspired action film that is actually rather violent and, once in the real world, is quite grim. The film never seems to know whether it wants to homage, spoof or simply in-joke. The movie world it creates is itself confused - while it has some funny touches such as the police line pairing together various mismatched partners - it also has women walking around in sexy, futuristic costumes, and the aforementioned cartoon cat called Whiskers (voiced by Danny DeVito). Seriously, whose idea was that? I've never seen a cartoon cat in a live- action action movie! However, the sheer mess that is the complete film does prove Last Action Hero to be a curious little oddity. There have been much finer examples of action-movie send-ups, namely in Shane Black's own excellent Kiss Kiss Bang Bang (2005), so perhaps the producers weren't ready back in 1993 to take on such an ambitious project. Arnie is pleasantly game for sending himself up, and Charles Dance chews the screen with his gloriously hammy British bad guy. But Last Action Hero will ultimately always be a reminder of how the Hollywood system to suck up an interesting maverick project, f**k it over a few times, and bundle it over the finishing line with such unbelievable inefficiency. I did love it as a kid, however. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was right the first time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Last Action Hero back in 1993; I didn't like it. Twenty years later and I begin to wonder whether my opinion was a knee-jerk reaction to seeing Schwarzenegger in something a little different to his usual fare, and that perhaps I would appreciate the film more second time round. Well, I just watched it again and, if anything, I disliked it even more than the first time. The basic (high) conceptaction movie fan Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) enters the fictional world of his movie hero Jack Slater (Arnie)is actually pretty clever, allowing for lots of ingenious meta-moments, but the way in which it is all realised is diabolical: the screenplay is full of misjudged humour (what is it with that dumb animated cat?), child star Austin O'Brien puts in a thoroughly annoying performance, and the exaggerated action scenes within Slater's movie-verse are completely devoid of excitement. There are also quite a few jokes that have dated extremely badly, especially the 'star' cameos from people that are no longer as famous as they used to be. The saddest thing about the whole film is that, given the great talent involved (Arnie, screenwriter Shane Black, director John McTiernan) it really should have been much, much better. Studio intervention may have been the reason it turned out so bad, but knowing that doesn't make the film any more enjoyable to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupidity stops where its own awareness starts ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that principle applies for both people and movies. And this is why parody generally provides the cleverest films, mocking the archetypes over-exploited by lazy directors with a subtle, and so engaging, wink to the audience. And "Last Action Hero" parodies the action-flick, featuring its most iconic ambassador, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the lone-ranger bad-ass cigar-smoking titular hero of a never-ending franchise: Jack Slater. As if he was plenty aware that "Die Hard" put a deathblow on the credibility of such super-heroic figures popularized by "Commando" and "Predator", John McTiernan becomes the iconoclast of his own creations -a demonstration of smart sense of humor a few directors ever achieved. The opening "Jack Slater" film even concludes with a reference to the genre-defining "Die Hard", using the same score to contribute to the whole 'inside joke' effect, completed when Jack Slater becomes a movie-within-a-movie character, from the perspective of Danny, his number one fan, played by Austin O'Brien. Basically, Danny is to "Last Action Hero" what Cecilia (Mia Farrow) was to "The Purple Rose of Cairo": a movie lover whose only means to transcend routine's banality was a constant ecstatic stare toward the silver screen. And being a kid of the early 90's, I could only respond to his hypnotic fascination. Action films are indeed the best pop-culture fillers, crystallizing the most common denominators of fun and entertainment and generating codes and formula that are part of cinema's timeless and universal heritage, no matter how overused they are: the never-dying hero, the yelling superior, the revenge plot, the villainous monologue, the sexy daughter, the comic-relief sidekick, the sophisticated boss' right hand who becomes the real villain and a lame catchphrase. They're all there in "Last Action Hero" less because they're obligatory but for the necessity to turn them into derision, by confronting them to reality. Still, there has to be some fantasy in this reality: Danny is given by the projectionist Nick (Art Carney) a magic ticket that belonged to the Great Houdini. And while he watches the fourth opus of Jack Slater's adventures during a private screening, the ticket glows, sticks of dynamite are thrown from the screen and land near his feet. Danny starts to take the notion of 'danger' less cynically before the explosion immediately projects him into his hero's universe. The film's greatest moments come from Danny's desperate attempts to convince Slater that they live in a movie where phone numbers start with "555", video-store workers are sexy and profanity is prohibited. Hell, in this parallel universe, his own rival Stallone played the Terminator roles (which made me wonder who then played Rocky or Rambo). The film recycles every clich&eacute; in such an over-the-top way it's hilarious: the car rams into an ice cream truck and explodes, a henchman gets an ice cone on the neck, many gags feel like these 'McBain' segments from "The Simpsons", thus never fail. The film also features one hilarious modernization of "Hamlet" and two delightful movie references. One of Slater's friends is played by F. Murray Abraham, naturally, Danny warns him that it's the same guy who killed Mozart in "Amadeus": the film that got 8 Oscars. For a kid, he has the knowledge of an IMDb user, which says a lot about "Last Action Hero" exhilarating effect as pure geek escapism, reinforced by the obscure intrusion of Death from "The Seventh Seal", a joke I didn't even get when I saw the film as a teenager. Now, there are two facts regarding "Last Action Hero": the film flopped, and it didn't deserve to, not when box-office laws are governed by rules that allow "Cliffhanger" to be the 7th highest grossing film anyway. Therefore, I can only qualify its bombing as 'accidental', the same accident that made "Sorcerer" flop in 1977. The parallel is all the more eloquent because "Last Action Hero" suffered from an ill-fated opening coinciding with the big event of 1993: the release of Steven Spielberg's "Jurassik park" ("Sorcerer" had it worse with "Star Wars") and perhaps misleading title, trailer and word-of-mouth that branded the film in the total opposite way it expected to: a dumb action film, 'another one'. I don't blame the viewers who thought a bunch of reptilian carnivores would be a fresher spectacle, I, was misled too, the first time I saw the TV announcement. But being a box-office flop is one thing, but when I started to examine the disastrous reception from those who actually saw the film- I was stunned. Seriously, what's with all these Razzies' nominations? Worst actor? Arnold had to play his usual role. Worst screenplay? Check the review's title. Worst new star? That's the worst thing about vocation-discouraging Razzies: the kid was supposed to be annoying and he played that part quite well. Worst song? It's a cheesy action-flick, did they expect Barbra Streisand? "Last Action Hero" is not beyond criticism though especially in the last act, when they 'get' in the real world. It's true that the film could have pushed its self-reflexive concept to more thought-provoking levels, that the emotional involvement lacked when the action was conditioned by predictable plot devices and needed to be compensated in the 'real world'. It's also true that confronting Slater to Arnold (like in Woody Allen's film) or having Danny talking to him, could have induced more interesting situations, but the reception would make anyone believe the film is like "Stop or my Mom Will Shoot!". Talk about unfortunate misunderstanding, not that I believe it truly deserves this 8, but it makes up for the undeserved negativity it inspired. McTiernan would finally make the highest-grossing film of 1995: "Die Hard 3 With a Vengeance" which feels like his personal vengeance. The film is as corny and over-the-top as "Last Action Hero" but I guess the average audience wasn't ready for that level of subtlety, so he probably thought : "Hell, give them the movie they deserve and give me a break".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun cheeky spoof movie that has gained a cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best things about Last Action Hero is that the more you read about it, you realize the smarter it is. There are so many little nods and cheeky references to the action genre and to Hollywood that you can't possibly catch them all the first time around. It appears, on the surface, to be this huge action film but really the entire film is poking fun at the genre. And who better to bring on board to do that but the King of eighties action Arnold Schwarzenegger. There is so much right about this film. The scenes with Arnold playing himself and the interaction between him and "Jack Slater" are just awesome. The cameos and the world they create inside the movie is just so much fun to watch. The problem is that the film is almost too much of a joke. Fans of Schwarzenegger and action films might find their genre being made a total fool of a bit much to handle. And also one of the leading roles is really not good but more on that in a minute. It is definitely a PG-13 movie and while there is nothing wrong with that, it feels like it struggles to purposely try to stay PG and it has trouble doing that. I love Arnold Schwarzenegger, he has just always been one of my Hollywood icons. This is such an odd role for him because he is making fun of himself and what he does best. However, it works well and he is actually fun as Slater. He is especially fun in the brief scenes where is "playing" or "over-playing" himself. The banter between him and real life wife/ex-wife Maria Shriver is just awesome. Austin O'Brien is the young actor portraying Schwarzenegger's partner and his fan as well. O'Brien is unfortunately the character I mentioned previously that really holds back this film. He is simply unnatural and gives a strained and poor performance. It just is very underwhelming. The chemistry between him and Schwarzenegger is nearly awful and that would be the key point to this movie. Charles Dance is very good as the evil villain Benedict. He is over the top but looks menacing and certainly is the perfect personification of an action movie villain. Tom Noonan is also good as the twisted Ripper villain who is also an amped up spoof of a slasher villain. Everyone else in the film are basically cameos but there are some really good ones worth mentioning. F. Murray Abraham, Art Carney, Frank McRae, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and even Ian McKellan are just a few of the faces you will recognize and they give good solid campy performances. If there was any director they should have gotten to direct this film it would be John McTiernan. Die Hard, Predator, The Hunt For Red October, Die Hard 3, Medicine Man...and more. Every action film he has done has at least been decent so he was the perfect choice to do this film and poke fun at the genre. The action scenes are well done and yet overdone at the same time (which granted is the point.) Last Action Hero is fun and exciting but is held back by making fun of itself almost too much. Still, it is a modern day cult classic and more and more people are calling it under-rated and when you look at some of the hidden Easter eggs in the film, it becomes even more fascinating and fun. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice parody of an action movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colm-hearne365
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I noticed that this movie got some pretty bad reception from critics and didn't do that well in the box office but that was because it was released at the same time as Jurassic Park. And I think the reason why people didn't like was because they took it too seriously. The thing is this movie is a parody of action movies like Blazing Saddles is a parody of westerns or Spaceballs was a parody of sci-fi movies. But even I can admit this movie gets pretty cheesy and over the top at times but parodies are like that. And even the kid, Danny was pretty annoying at times. But I think its a fun movie to watch, especially if you're an action fan and Arnold Schwarzenegger has always been my favourite action star. And I like the idea of the clash between fantasy and reality and it's also funny and exciting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated, but not flawless, gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero has got a lot of bad mouthing over the years, but it seems a lot of critics were just jumping on the bandwagon, afraid to say something positive. It is difficult to see why no-one would like it at all. While a tad heavy-handed, the constant riffing on typical macho action flicks is spot-on, always amusing, and yet at the same time the film delivers saw awe-inspiring, sometimes deliberately implausible action set-pieces. Arnie sends himself up fine, while Austin O'Brien often says out loud what most often think watching these kinds of films. Charles Dance makes a menacing villain, and provides some dark amusement of his own - I JUST SHOT SOMEBODY, I DID IT ON PURPOSE. Where the film begins to falter is when the fictional characters, plus Danny, enter the real world. Until this point, it had been going along at a roaring clip, constantly amusing. Perhaps it was necessary to show a dose of reality to those brought up on mindless action flicks, but it starts becoming a little more serious and darker in tone, more sentimental, and consequently less fun. That doesn't make it bad though, and it does provide some food for thought, with Arnie-in-character ranting about how he's fed up of shooting people in films, and blowing things up. Not a masterpiece perhaps, but deserves to be ranked high on Arnie's filmography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Last Action Hero' is Pure Fun! A highly entertaining escapist fare, that works from start to end. 'Last Action Hero' Synopsis: A young movie fan gets thrown into the movie world of his favorite action film character. 'Last Action Hero' is innovative & fun. The pace is perfect & the action-sequences are top-notch. Shane Black, David Arnott & William Goldman's Screenplay is child-like, but works wonderfully. John McTiernan's Direction is efficient. Cinematography is stylish. Art Design is perfect. Performance-Wise: Arnold Schwarzenegger plays to the gallery. He enacts the hero with his usual ease. Austin O'Brien is extremely likable, as he's energetic all through. Robert Prosky is restrained. Charles Dance is excellent. Anthony Quinn is effective. On the whole, 'Last Action Hero' is some great vintage entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This hero stuff has its limits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero is directed by John McTiernan and written by Shane Black and David Arnott. It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, F. Murray Abraham, Charles Dance, Tom Noonan, Austin O'Brien, Art Carney, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and Bridgette Wilson. Music is by Micahel Kamen and cinematography by Dean Semler. Film within a film action parody that sees young Danny Madigan (O'Brien) magically transported into the parallel universe of an action film featuring his fictional hero, Jack Slater (Schwarzenegger). A financial failure and beaten relentlessly by the critics upon release (even McTiernan would condemn it down the line), Last Action Hero is viewed some what in better terms these days. Whilst the arguments that it was ahead of its time, misunderstood and released at the wrong time due to competition with Jurassic Park (the last one was Arnie himself, bless him) are weak and really not worth considering, it's a decent and "intelligent" film that could have been very good if cut by at least half an hour. Running at over two hours in length, the film's central concept of parodying action movies, with Arnold broadly laughing at himself, runs out of steam, the joke just becomes a millstone around its neck. You can see the drop in quality of the action in the last third as well, purely because so much is thrown at the audience, it gets tiresome for the director, which is such a shame given that it's McTiernan at the helm, the man who in Predator and Die Hard gave the 80s its two best American action movies. As it is, and I was helped enormously in my viewing of this because I watched it back to back with Hard Target, much of the parody and cineaste jokes strike a humorous chord. While the roll call of actors lining up to be in on the joke is impressive and often laugh out loud funny. Yet amongst all the satire and tongue in cheek wink winks, there is also some depth to the dizzying narrative that is worth appraising, particularly when the picture pitches up the real life of an actor to that of the character he plays, with one sequence as Arnie faces up to Arnie particularly brilliant. Better than you may have heard it is, but still a film that's difficult to recommend with confidence. Some self-examining depth and smart in- movie jokes ensure it's no dud, but entering the last third it becomes tiresome and routine and that leaves a disappointment that's hard to shake. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it as a kid in '93, and I've grown to appreciate it as an adult.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reading some of the lurid behind-the-scenes details on "Last Action Hero" (do a search, it's scintillating!), one would walk into this thing expecting an &uuml;ber-expensive disaster. And it was, at least financially. But time has been kind to this movie, and it's actually - for most of its runtime - a pretty kickass genre sendup. The idea behind "Last Action Hero" is satirically brilliant: to deconstruct the big Hollywood action movie. You know, your "Lethal Weapon"s, your "Die Hard"s and your Schwarzenegger "sh-t blows up real good!" movies. And when the movie focuses on that aspect, it's a fun romp. You see enough '80s action movies, the tropes and clich&eacute;s become commonplace. They're all here: - huge explosions send the hero flying (ultimately unscathed) while everyone around him winds up dead - change of scenery from location to studio backlot within a scene - there are no unattractive women - police headquarters is unbelievably posh - the Lieutenant speaks only in vein-popping screams - gunshots send bad guys flying - an inordinate number of explosions And it's that novelty of the genre satire that really makes this movie, for me. Which means the film's first 90 minutes are very entertaining. It's when the villain escapes the movie and our focus centers on the real world that "Last Action Hero" loses me. The film's first half is front-loaded with all of the good stuff. All of the good jokes and sight gags are there. I have no interest in what goes on in the real world. The real magic is in the artificial one. But there's strength in the casting. Arnold is able and surprisingly good at offering himself up for parody. And in a role that's sure to be annoying on paper, Austin O'Brien is actually kinda endearing as the kid sidekick. I really liked him here. And Charles Dance as Benedict . . . he's a terrific bad guy. In this type of movie, especially; great comedic timing, and just a pleasure to watch. He steals every one of his scenes. His lines are the funniest. "Last Action Hero" would definitely merit a higher rating if I didn't feel the need to turn it off with 45 minutes left to go. But when I think of this movie, it's that great first half that sticks in my brain. It should've performed better 20 years ago. The lousy reputation is (for the most part) undeserved, and it's a clear example of the kind of curious oddity that can result after many bad decisions made during the filmmaking process. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better the older you get
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dame Shumma
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grandiose, like Schwarzenegger takes the mickey out here himself, knows his last name wrong constantly and eventually called Arnold Braunschweiger. There are ongoing links to other movies, where, like in Die Hard. Danny makes Jack's attention to look up after a car accident even if the bad guy except death. In Die Hard, it was finally so that the blonde is hanged, and at the end is still alive. Grandiose, something is a feast for action lovers. The final rise to the film premiere of "Jack Slater IV" in New York. Schwarzenegger plays himself here, and is approached by his wife to make lasting advertising for Planet Hollywood. John Belushi announces Jack Slater movies so he does not like, and Van Damme, yes, even the Belgian martial arts goes to the premiere. Just plain funny. Slater is run by Danny corrected. Whenever he "I'll be back," says Danny knew beforehand that he will say that it is, after all, his trademark. Even the testing center for movies, the MPAA will not be left out. Danny writes a word, probably "fuck" on a piece of paper. Slater read it will not. Danny Comment: "You can not read it, because this movie is PG-13" Just wonderful. Who wants to keep checking back for once really look over a very successful action movie parody must. However, you should really have already seen some in the sector to understand everything. In order to find every hidden joke I have seen the movie a few times anyway. Well, anyway, the story is incidental and not the hammer. But is sufficient. I admit: Movie Review: 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A curious oddity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When young Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) is given a magic movie ticket by friendly cinema owner Nick (Robert Prosky) at an advance screening of new action movie Jack Slater IV, he is magically transported into the movie and into the car of supercop Jack Slater (Arnold Schwarzenegger). Danny starts to inform Slater about who the bad guys are after seeing them on screen, and the two are paired up as a mismatched investigative duo by Slater's screaming boss. Glass-eyed bad guy Mr. Benedict (Charles Dance) manages to get his hands on the magic ticket, and escapes into the real world, where he finds things are much easier for the bad guys. Slater must leave his action movie clich&eacute; of a world where he is nigh on invincible behind, and enter one where things are slightly more difficult. Last Action Hero had one of the most expensive and turbulent page-to- screen stories in recent cinema history. Originally written as a self- mocking action movie that embraced the clich&eacute;s of the genre, that was also a proper action movie in its own right. After an unexpected bidding war, the young scribes Zak Penn and Adam Leff were shocked to find that Arnold Schwarzenegger had taken a personal interest in it (the original hero name was Arno Slater). This was to be the turning point. Arnie saw the potential for a franchise as a kid's film and immediately wanted to tone down the violence, so Penn and Leff were fired, and genre legend Shane Black was hired to spruce up the script. Things changed yet again when director John McTiernan was brought in, and, due to the success of his previous films, was given full control. A few script re-writes, firings, and storm-outs later, the film was shot and ready to hit the market. A toy franchise and a ridiculously expensive and calamitous advertising campaign (they paid half a million dollars to have the film's name on a NASA rocket, only to have the launched delayed till long after the film's release) were put into motion, and the film's release date was announced for the week after Jurassic Park's. Last Action Hero had disastrous test screenings, but the release date was not changed, and naturally, Jurassic Park stormed the box-office and merchandising range, and Last Action Hero was revealed to be an over-ambitious, confused dud of a movie. However, the legend is rather cruel on Schwarzenegger's biggest flop, as although it is a gigantic mess, it has plenty of interesting ideas than are unfortunately spewed out onto the film in ungraceful belches. The biggest problem is that it doesn't know what kind of film it is. At its heart, its a kid's film, complete with annoying mop-haired child, a kindly old man, magic tickets and, um, a cartoon cat. Yet on its surface, its a rather uninspired action film that is actually rather violent and, once in the real world, is quite grim. The film never seems to know whether it wants to homage, spoof or simply in-joke. The movie world it creates is itself confused - while it has some funny touches such as the police line pairing together various mismatched partners - it also has women walking around in sexy, futuristic costumes, and the aforementioned cartoon cat called Whiskers (voiced by Danny DeVito). Seriously, whose idea was that? I've never seen a cartoon cat in a live- action action movie! However, the sheer mess that is the complete film does prove Last Action Hero to be a curious little oddity. There have been much finer examples of action-movie send-ups, namely in Shane Black's own excellent Kiss Kiss Bang Bang (2005), so perhaps the producers weren't ready back in 1993 to take on such an ambitious project. Arnie is pleasantly game for sending himself up, and Charles Dance chews the screen with his gloriously hammy British bad guy. But Last Action Hero will ultimately always be a reminder of how the Hollywood system to suck up an interesting maverick project, f**k it over a few times, and bundle it over the finishing line with such unbelievable inefficiency. I did love it as a kid, however. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was right the first time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Last Action Hero back in 1993; I didn't like it. Twenty years later and I begin to wonder whether my opinion was a knee-jerk reaction to seeing Schwarzenegger in something a little different to his usual fare, and that perhaps I would appreciate the film more second time round. Well, I just watched it again and, if anything, I disliked it even more than the first time. The basic (high) conceptaction movie fan Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) enters the fictional world of his movie hero Jack Slater (Arnie)is actually pretty clever, allowing for lots of ingenious meta-moments, but the way in which it is all realised is diabolical: the screenplay is full of misjudged humour (what is it with that dumb animated cat?), child star Austin O'Brien puts in a thoroughly annoying performance, and the exaggerated action scenes within Slater's movie-verse are completely devoid of excitement. There are also quite a few jokes that have dated extremely badly, especially the 'star' cameos from people that are no longer as famous as they used to be. The saddest thing about the whole film is that, given the great talent involved (Arnie, screenwriter Shane Black, director John McTiernan) it really should have been much, much better. Studio intervention may have been the reason it turned out so bad, but knowing that doesn't make the film any more enjoyable to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupidity stops where its own awareness starts ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that principle applies for both people and movies. And this is why parody generally provides the cleverest films, mocking the archetypes over-exploited by lazy directors with a subtle, and so engaging, wink to the audience. And "Last Action Hero" parodies the action-flick, featuring its most iconic ambassador, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the lone-ranger bad-ass cigar-smoking titular hero of a never-ending franchise: Jack Slater. As if he was plenty aware that "Die Hard" put a deathblow on the credibility of such super-heroic figures popularized by "Commando" and "Predator", John McTiernan becomes the iconoclast of his own creations -a demonstration of smart sense of humor a few directors ever achieved. The opening "Jack Slater" film even concludes with a reference to the genre-defining "Die Hard", using the same score to contribute to the whole 'inside joke' effect, completed when Jack Slater becomes a movie-within-a-movie character, from the perspective of Danny, his number one fan, played by Austin O'Brien. Basically, Danny is to "Last Action Hero" what Cecilia (Mia Farrow) was to "The Purple Rose of Cairo": a movie lover whose only means to transcend routine's banality was a constant ecstatic stare toward the silver screen. And being a kid of the early 90's, I could only respond to his hypnotic fascination. Action films are indeed the best pop-culture fillers, crystallizing the most common denominators of fun and entertainment and generating codes and formula that are part of cinema's timeless and universal heritage, no matter how overused they are: the never-dying hero, the yelling superior, the revenge plot, the villainous monologue, the sexy daughter, the comic-relief sidekick, the sophisticated boss' right hand who becomes the real villain and a lame catchphrase. They're all there in "Last Action Hero" less because they're obligatory but for the necessity to turn them into derision, by confronting them to reality. Still, there has to be some fantasy in this reality: Danny is given by the projectionist Nick (Art Carney) a magic ticket that belonged to the Great Houdini. And while he watches the fourth opus of Jack Slater's adventures during a private screening, the ticket glows, sticks of dynamite are thrown from the screen and land near his feet. Danny starts to take the notion of 'danger' less cynically before the explosion immediately projects him into his hero's universe. The film's greatest moments come from Danny's desperate attempts to convince Slater that they live in a movie where phone numbers start with "555", video-store workers are sexy and profanity is prohibited. Hell, in this parallel universe, his own rival Stallone played the Terminator roles (which made me wonder who then played Rocky or Rambo). The film recycles every clich&eacute; in such an over-the-top way it's hilarious: the car rams into an ice cream truck and explodes, a henchman gets an ice cone on the neck, many gags feel like these 'McBain' segments from "The Simpsons", thus never fail. The film also features one hilarious modernization of "Hamlet" and two delightful movie references. One of Slater's friends is played by F. Murray Abraham, naturally, Danny warns him that it's the same guy who killed Mozart in "Amadeus": the film that got 8 Oscars. For a kid, he has the knowledge of an IMDb user, which says a lot about "Last Action Hero" exhilarating effect as pure geek escapism, reinforced by the obscure intrusion of Death from "The Seventh Seal", a joke I didn't even get when I saw the film as a teenager. Now, there are two facts regarding "Last Action Hero": the film flopped, and it didn't deserve to, not when box-office laws are governed by rules that allow "Cliffhanger" to be the 7th highest grossing film anyway. Therefore, I can only qualify its bombing as 'accidental', the same accident that made "Sorcerer" flop in 1977. The parallel is all the more eloquent because "Last Action Hero" suffered from an ill-fated opening coinciding with the big event of 1993: the release of Steven Spielberg's "Jurassik park" ("Sorcerer" had it worse with "Star Wars") and perhaps misleading title, trailer and word-of-mouth that branded the film in the total opposite way it expected to: a dumb action film, 'another one'. I don't blame the viewers who thought a bunch of reptilian carnivores would be a fresher spectacle, I, was misled too, the first time I saw the TV announcement. But being a box-office flop is one thing, but when I started to examine the disastrous reception from those who actually saw the film- I was stunned. Seriously, what's with all these Razzies' nominations? Worst actor? Arnold had to play his usual role. Worst screenplay? Check the review's title. Worst new star? That's the worst thing about vocation-discouraging Razzies: the kid was supposed to be annoying and he played that part quite well. Worst song? It's a cheesy action-flick, did they expect Barbra Streisand? "Last Action Hero" is not beyond criticism though especially in the last act, when they 'get' in the real world. It's true that the film could have pushed its self-reflexive concept to more thought-provoking levels, that the emotional involvement lacked when the action was conditioned by predictable plot devices and needed to be compensated in the 'real world'. It's also true that confronting Slater to Arnold (like in Woody Allen's film) or having Danny talking to him, could have induced more interesting situations, but the reception would make anyone believe the film is like "Stop or my Mom Will Shoot!". Talk about unfortunate misunderstanding, not that I believe it truly deserves this 8, but it makes up for the undeserved negativity it inspired. McTiernan would finally make the highest-grossing film of 1995: "Die Hard 3 With a Vengeance" which feels like his personal vengeance. The film is as corny and over-the-top as "Last Action Hero" but I guess the average audience wasn't ready for that level of subtlety, so he probably thought : "Hell, give them the movie they deserve and give me a break".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun cheeky spoof movie that has gained a cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best things about Last Action Hero is that the more you read about it, you realize the smarter it is. There are so many little nods and cheeky references to the action genre and to Hollywood that you can't possibly catch them all the first time around. It appears, on the surface, to be this huge action film but really the entire film is poking fun at the genre. And who better to bring on board to do that but the King of eighties action Arnold Schwarzenegger. There is so much right about this film. The scenes with Arnold playing himself and the interaction between him and "Jack Slater" are just awesome. The cameos and the world they create inside the movie is just so much fun to watch. The problem is that the film is almost too much of a joke. Fans of Schwarzenegger and action films might find their genre being made a total fool of a bit much to handle. And also one of the leading roles is really not good but more on that in a minute. It is definitely a PG-13 movie and while there is nothing wrong with that, it feels like it struggles to purposely try to stay PG and it has trouble doing that. I love Arnold Schwarzenegger, he has just always been one of my Hollywood icons. This is such an odd role for him because he is making fun of himself and what he does best. However, it works well and he is actually fun as Slater. He is especially fun in the brief scenes where is "playing" or "over-playing" himself. The banter between him and real life wife/ex-wife Maria Shriver is just awesome. Austin O'Brien is the young actor portraying Schwarzenegger's partner and his fan as well. O'Brien is unfortunately the character I mentioned previously that really holds back this film. He is simply unnatural and gives a strained and poor performance. It just is very underwhelming. The chemistry between him and Schwarzenegger is nearly awful and that would be the key point to this movie. Charles Dance is very good as the evil villain Benedict. He is over the top but looks menacing and certainly is the perfect personification of an action movie villain. Tom Noonan is also good as the twisted Ripper villain who is also an amped up spoof of a slasher villain. Everyone else in the film are basically cameos but there are some really good ones worth mentioning. F. Murray Abraham, Art Carney, Frank McRae, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and even Ian McKellan are just a few of the faces you will recognize and they give good solid campy performances. If there was any director they should have gotten to direct this film it would be John McTiernan. Die Hard, Predator, The Hunt For Red October, Die Hard 3, Medicine Man...and more. Every action film he has done has at least been decent so he was the perfect choice to do this film and poke fun at the genre. The action scenes are well done and yet overdone at the same time (which granted is the point.) Last Action Hero is fun and exciting but is held back by making fun of itself almost too much. Still, it is a modern day cult classic and more and more people are calling it under-rated and when you look at some of the hidden Easter eggs in the film, it becomes even more fascinating and fun. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice parody of an action movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colm-hearne365
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I noticed that this movie got some pretty bad reception from critics and didn't do that well in the box office but that was because it was released at the same time as Jurassic Park. And I think the reason why people didn't like was because they took it too seriously. The thing is this movie is a parody of action movies like Blazing Saddles is a parody of westerns or Spaceballs was a parody of sci-fi movies. But even I can admit this movie gets pretty cheesy and over the top at times but parodies are like that. And even the kid, Danny was pretty annoying at times. But I think its a fun movie to watch, especially if you're an action fan and Arnold Schwarzenegger has always been my favourite action star. And I like the idea of the clash between fantasy and reality and it's also funny and exciting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated, but not flawless, gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero has got a lot of bad mouthing over the years, but it seems a lot of critics were just jumping on the bandwagon, afraid to say something positive. It is difficult to see why no-one would like it at all. While a tad heavy-handed, the constant riffing on typical macho action flicks is spot-on, always amusing, and yet at the same time the film delivers saw awe-inspiring, sometimes deliberately implausible action set-pieces. Arnie sends himself up fine, while Austin O'Brien often says out loud what most often think watching these kinds of films. Charles Dance makes a menacing villain, and provides some dark amusement of his own - I JUST SHOT SOMEBODY, I DID IT ON PURPOSE. Where the film begins to falter is when the fictional characters, plus Danny, enter the real world. Until this point, it had been going along at a roaring clip, constantly amusing. Perhaps it was necessary to show a dose of reality to those brought up on mindless action flicks, but it starts becoming a little more serious and darker in tone, more sentimental, and consequently less fun. That doesn't make it bad though, and it does provide some food for thought, with Arnie-in-character ranting about how he's fed up of shooting people in films, and blowing things up. Not a masterpiece perhaps, but deserves to be ranked high on Arnie's filmography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Last Action Hero' is Pure Fun! A highly entertaining escapist fare, that works from start to end. 'Last Action Hero' Synopsis: A young movie fan gets thrown into the movie world of his favorite action film character. 'Last Action Hero' is innovative & fun. The pace is perfect & the action-sequences are top-notch. Shane Black, David Arnott & William Goldman's Screenplay is child-like, but works wonderfully. John McTiernan's Direction is efficient. Cinematography is stylish. Art Design is perfect. Performance-Wise: Arnold Schwarzenegger plays to the gallery. He enacts the hero with his usual ease. Austin O'Brien is extremely likable, as he's energetic all through. Robert Prosky is restrained. Charles Dance is excellent. Anthony Quinn is effective. On the whole, 'Last Action Hero' is some great vintage entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This hero stuff has its limits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero is directed by John McTiernan and written by Shane Black and David Arnott. It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, F. Murray Abraham, Charles Dance, Tom Noonan, Austin O'Brien, Art Carney, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and Bridgette Wilson. Music is by Micahel Kamen and cinematography by Dean Semler. Film within a film action parody that sees young Danny Madigan (O'Brien) magically transported into the parallel universe of an action film featuring his fictional hero, Jack Slater (Schwarzenegger). A financial failure and beaten relentlessly by the critics upon release (even McTiernan would condemn it down the line), Last Action Hero is viewed some what in better terms these days. Whilst the arguments that it was ahead of its time, misunderstood and released at the wrong time due to competition with Jurassic Park (the last one was Arnie himself, bless him) are weak and really not worth considering, it's a decent and "intelligent" film that could have been very good if cut by at least half an hour. Running at over two hours in length, the film's central concept of parodying action movies, with Arnold broadly laughing at himself, runs out of steam, the joke just becomes a millstone around its neck. You can see the drop in quality of the action in the last third as well, purely because so much is thrown at the audience, it gets tiresome for the director, which is such a shame given that it's McTiernan at the helm, the man who in Predator and Die Hard gave the 80s its two best American action movies. As it is, and I was helped enormously in my viewing of this because I watched it back to back with Hard Target, much of the parody and cineaste jokes strike a humorous chord. While the roll call of actors lining up to be in on the joke is impressive and often laugh out loud funny. Yet amongst all the satire and tongue in cheek wink winks, there is also some depth to the dizzying narrative that is worth appraising, particularly when the picture pitches up the real life of an actor to that of the character he plays, with one sequence as Arnie faces up to Arnie particularly brilliant. Better than you may have heard it is, but still a film that's difficult to recommend with confidence. Some self-examining depth and smart in- movie jokes ensure it's no dud, but entering the last third it becomes tiresome and routine and that leaves a disappointment that's hard to shake. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it as a kid in '93, and I've grown to appreciate it as an adult.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reading some of the lurid behind-the-scenes details on "Last Action Hero" (do a search, it's scintillating!), one would walk into this thing expecting an &uuml;ber-expensive disaster. And it was, at least financially. But time has been kind to this movie, and it's actually - for most of its runtime - a pretty kickass genre sendup. The idea behind "Last Action Hero" is satirically brilliant: to deconstruct the big Hollywood action movie. You know, your "Lethal Weapon"s, your "Die Hard"s and your Schwarzenegger "sh-t blows up real good!" movies. And when the movie focuses on that aspect, it's a fun romp. You see enough '80s action movies, the tropes and clich&eacute;s become commonplace. They're all here: - huge explosions send the hero flying (ultimately unscathed) while everyone around him winds up dead - change of scenery from location to studio backlot within a scene - there are no unattractive women - police headquarters is unbelievably posh - the Lieutenant speaks only in vein-popping screams - gunshots send bad guys flying - an inordinate number of explosions And it's that novelty of the genre satire that really makes this movie, for me. Which means the film's first 90 minutes are very entertaining. It's when the villain escapes the movie and our focus centers on the real world that "Last Action Hero" loses me. The film's first half is front-loaded with all of the good stuff. All of the good jokes and sight gags are there. I have no interest in what goes on in the real world. The real magic is in the artificial one. But there's strength in the casting. Arnold is able and surprisingly good at offering himself up for parody. And in a role that's sure to be annoying on paper, Austin O'Brien is actually kinda endearing as the kid sidekick. I really liked him here. And Charles Dance as Benedict . . . he's a terrific bad guy. In this type of movie, especially; great comedic timing, and just a pleasure to watch. He steals every one of his scenes. His lines are the funniest. "Last Action Hero" would definitely merit a higher rating if I didn't feel the need to turn it off with 45 minutes left to go. But when I think of this movie, it's that great first half that sticks in my brain. It should've performed better 20 years ago. The lousy reputation is (for the most part) undeserved, and it's a clear example of the kind of curious oddity that can result after many bad decisions made during the filmmaking process. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better the older you get
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dame Shumma
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grandiose, like Schwarzenegger takes the mickey out here himself, knows his last name wrong constantly and eventually called Arnold Braunschweiger. There are ongoing links to other movies, where, like in Die Hard. Danny makes Jack's attention to look up after a car accident even if the bad guy except death. In Die Hard, it was finally so that the blonde is hanged, and at the end is still alive. Grandiose, something is a feast for action lovers. The final rise to the film premiere of "Jack Slater IV" in New York. Schwarzenegger plays himself here, and is approached by his wife to make lasting advertising for Planet Hollywood. John Belushi announces Jack Slater movies so he does not like, and Van Damme, yes, even the Belgian martial arts goes to the premiere. Just plain funny. Slater is run by Danny corrected. Whenever he "I'll be back," says Danny knew beforehand that he will say that it is, after all, his trademark. Even the testing center for movies, the MPAA will not be left out. Danny writes a word, probably "fuck" on a piece of paper. Slater read it will not. Danny Comment: "You can not read it, because this movie is PG-13" Just wonderful. Who wants to keep checking back for once really look over a very successful action movie parody must. However, you should really have already seen some in the sector to understand everything. In order to find every hidden joke I have seen the movie a few times anyway. Well, anyway, the story is incidental and not the hammer. But is sufficient. I admit: Movie Review: 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A curious oddity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When young Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) is given a magic movie ticket by friendly cinema owner Nick (Robert Prosky) at an advance screening of new action movie Jack Slater IV, he is magically transported into the movie and into the car of supercop Jack Slater (Arnold Schwarzenegger). Danny starts to inform Slater about who the bad guys are after seeing them on screen, and the two are paired up as a mismatched investigative duo by Slater's screaming boss. Glass-eyed bad guy Mr. Benedict (Charles Dance) manages to get his hands on the magic ticket, and escapes into the real world, where he finds things are much easier for the bad guys. Slater must leave his action movie clich&eacute; of a world where he is nigh on invincible behind, and enter one where things are slightly more difficult. Last Action Hero had one of the most expensive and turbulent page-to- screen stories in recent cinema history. Originally written as a self- mocking action movie that embraced the clich&eacute;s of the genre, that was also a proper action movie in its own right. After an unexpected bidding war, the young scribes Zak Penn and Adam Leff were shocked to find that Arnold Schwarzenegger had taken a personal interest in it (the original hero name was Arno Slater). This was to be the turning point. Arnie saw the potential for a franchise as a kid's film and immediately wanted to tone down the violence, so Penn and Leff were fired, and genre legend Shane Black was hired to spruce up the script. Things changed yet again when director John McTiernan was brought in, and, due to the success of his previous films, was given full control. A few script re-writes, firings, and storm-outs later, the film was shot and ready to hit the market. A toy franchise and a ridiculously expensive and calamitous advertising campaign (they paid half a million dollars to have the film's name on a NASA rocket, only to have the launched delayed till long after the film's release) were put into motion, and the film's release date was announced for the week after Jurassic Park's. Last Action Hero had disastrous test screenings, but the release date was not changed, and naturally, Jurassic Park stormed the box-office and merchandising range, and Last Action Hero was revealed to be an over-ambitious, confused dud of a movie. However, the legend is rather cruel on Schwarzenegger's biggest flop, as although it is a gigantic mess, it has plenty of interesting ideas than are unfortunately spewed out onto the film in ungraceful belches. The biggest problem is that it doesn't know what kind of film it is. At its heart, its a kid's film, complete with annoying mop-haired child, a kindly old man, magic tickets and, um, a cartoon cat. Yet on its surface, its a rather uninspired action film that is actually rather violent and, once in the real world, is quite grim. The film never seems to know whether it wants to homage, spoof or simply in-joke. The movie world it creates is itself confused - while it has some funny touches such as the police line pairing together various mismatched partners - it also has women walking around in sexy, futuristic costumes, and the aforementioned cartoon cat called Whiskers (voiced by Danny DeVito). Seriously, whose idea was that? I've never seen a cartoon cat in a live- action action movie! However, the sheer mess that is the complete film does prove Last Action Hero to be a curious little oddity. There have been much finer examples of action-movie send-ups, namely in Shane Black's own excellent Kiss Kiss Bang Bang (2005), so perhaps the producers weren't ready back in 1993 to take on such an ambitious project. Arnie is pleasantly game for sending himself up, and Charles Dance chews the screen with his gloriously hammy British bad guy. But Last Action Hero will ultimately always be a reminder of how the Hollywood system to suck up an interesting maverick project, f**k it over a few times, and bundle it over the finishing line with such unbelievable inefficiency. I did love it as a kid, however. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was right the first time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Last Action Hero back in 1993; I didn't like it. Twenty years later and I begin to wonder whether my opinion was a knee-jerk reaction to seeing Schwarzenegger in something a little different to his usual fare, and that perhaps I would appreciate the film more second time round. Well, I just watched it again and, if anything, I disliked it even more than the first time. The basic (high) conceptaction movie fan Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) enters the fictional world of his movie hero Jack Slater (Arnie)is actually pretty clever, allowing for lots of ingenious meta-moments, but the way in which it is all realised is diabolical: the screenplay is full of misjudged humour (what is it with that dumb animated cat?), child star Austin O'Brien puts in a thoroughly annoying performance, and the exaggerated action scenes within Slater's movie-verse are completely devoid of excitement. There are also quite a few jokes that have dated extremely badly, especially the 'star' cameos from people that are no longer as famous as they used to be. The saddest thing about the whole film is that, given the great talent involved (Arnie, screenwriter Shane Black, director John McTiernan) it really should have been much, much better. Studio intervention may have been the reason it turned out so bad, but knowing that doesn't make the film any more enjoyable to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupidity stops where its own awareness starts ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that principle applies for both people and movies. And this is why parody generally provides the cleverest films, mocking the archetypes over-exploited by lazy directors with a subtle, and so engaging, wink to the audience. And "Last Action Hero" parodies the action-flick, featuring its most iconic ambassador, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the lone-ranger bad-ass cigar-smoking titular hero of a never-ending franchise: Jack Slater. As if he was plenty aware that "Die Hard" put a deathblow on the credibility of such super-heroic figures popularized by "Commando" and "Predator", John McTiernan becomes the iconoclast of his own creations -a demonstration of smart sense of humor a few directors ever achieved. The opening "Jack Slater" film even concludes with a reference to the genre-defining "Die Hard", using the same score to contribute to the whole 'inside joke' effect, completed when Jack Slater becomes a movie-within-a-movie character, from the perspective of Danny, his number one fan, played by Austin O'Brien. Basically, Danny is to "Last Action Hero" what Cecilia (Mia Farrow) was to "The Purple Rose of Cairo": a movie lover whose only means to transcend routine's banality was a constant ecstatic stare toward the silver screen. And being a kid of the early 90's, I could only respond to his hypnotic fascination. Action films are indeed the best pop-culture fillers, crystallizing the most common denominators of fun and entertainment and generating codes and formula that are part of cinema's timeless and universal heritage, no matter how overused they are: the never-dying hero, the yelling superior, the revenge plot, the villainous monologue, the sexy daughter, the comic-relief sidekick, the sophisticated boss' right hand who becomes the real villain and a lame catchphrase. They're all there in "Last Action Hero" less because they're obligatory but for the necessity to turn them into derision, by confronting them to reality. Still, there has to be some fantasy in this reality: Danny is given by the projectionist Nick (Art Carney) a magic ticket that belonged to the Great Houdini. And while he watches the fourth opus of Jack Slater's adventures during a private screening, the ticket glows, sticks of dynamite are thrown from the screen and land near his feet. Danny starts to take the notion of 'danger' less cynically before the explosion immediately projects him into his hero's universe. The film's greatest moments come from Danny's desperate attempts to convince Slater that they live in a movie where phone numbers start with "555", video-store workers are sexy and profanity is prohibited. Hell, in this parallel universe, his own rival Stallone played the Terminator roles (which made me wonder who then played Rocky or Rambo). The film recycles every clich&eacute; in such an over-the-top way it's hilarious: the car rams into an ice cream truck and explodes, a henchman gets an ice cone on the neck, many gags feel like these 'McBain' segments from "The Simpsons", thus never fail. The film also features one hilarious modernization of "Hamlet" and two delightful movie references. One of Slater's friends is played by F. Murray Abraham, naturally, Danny warns him that it's the same guy who killed Mozart in "Amadeus": the film that got 8 Oscars. For a kid, he has the knowledge of an IMDb user, which says a lot about "Last Action Hero" exhilarating effect as pure geek escapism, reinforced by the obscure intrusion of Death from "The Seventh Seal", a joke I didn't even get when I saw the film as a teenager. Now, there are two facts regarding "Last Action Hero": the film flopped, and it didn't deserve to, not when box-office laws are governed by rules that allow "Cliffhanger" to be the 7th highest grossing film anyway. Therefore, I can only qualify its bombing as 'accidental', the same accident that made "Sorcerer" flop in 1977. The parallel is all the more eloquent because "Last Action Hero" suffered from an ill-fated opening coinciding with the big event of 1993: the release of Steven Spielberg's "Jurassik park" ("Sorcerer" had it worse with "Star Wars") and perhaps misleading title, trailer and word-of-mouth that branded the film in the total opposite way it expected to: a dumb action film, 'another one'. I don't blame the viewers who thought a bunch of reptilian carnivores would be a fresher spectacle, I, was misled too, the first time I saw the TV announcement. But being a box-office flop is one thing, but when I started to examine the disastrous reception from those who actually saw the film- I was stunned. Seriously, what's with all these Razzies' nominations? Worst actor? Arnold had to play his usual role. Worst screenplay? Check the review's title. Worst new star? That's the worst thing about vocation-discouraging Razzies: the kid was supposed to be annoying and he played that part quite well. Worst song? It's a cheesy action-flick, did they expect Barbra Streisand? "Last Action Hero" is not beyond criticism though especially in the last act, when they 'get' in the real world. It's true that the film could have pushed its self-reflexive concept to more thought-provoking levels, that the emotional involvement lacked when the action was conditioned by predictable plot devices and needed to be compensated in the 'real world'. It's also true that confronting Slater to Arnold (like in Woody Allen's film) or having Danny talking to him, could have induced more interesting situations, but the reception would make anyone believe the film is like "Stop or my Mom Will Shoot!". Talk about unfortunate misunderstanding, not that I believe it truly deserves this 8, but it makes up for the undeserved negativity it inspired. McTiernan would finally make the highest-grossing film of 1995: "Die Hard 3 With a Vengeance" which feels like his personal vengeance. The film is as corny and over-the-top as "Last Action Hero" but I guess the average audience wasn't ready for that level of subtlety, so he probably thought : "Hell, give them the movie they deserve and give me a break".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun cheeky spoof movie that has gained a cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best things about Last Action Hero is that the more you read about it, you realize the smarter it is. There are so many little nods and cheeky references to the action genre and to Hollywood that you can't possibly catch them all the first time around. It appears, on the surface, to be this huge action film but really the entire film is poking fun at the genre. And who better to bring on board to do that but the King of eighties action Arnold Schwarzenegger. There is so much right about this film. The scenes with Arnold playing himself and the interaction between him and "Jack Slater" are just awesome. The cameos and the world they create inside the movie is just so much fun to watch. The problem is that the film is almost too much of a joke. Fans of Schwarzenegger and action films might find their genre being made a total fool of a bit much to handle. And also one of the leading roles is really not good but more on that in a minute. It is definitely a PG-13 movie and while there is nothing wrong with that, it feels like it struggles to purposely try to stay PG and it has trouble doing that. I love Arnold Schwarzenegger, he has just always been one of my Hollywood icons. This is such an odd role for him because he is making fun of himself and what he does best. However, it works well and he is actually fun as Slater. He is especially fun in the brief scenes where is "playing" or "over-playing" himself. The banter between him and real life wife/ex-wife Maria Shriver is just awesome. Austin O'Brien is the young actor portraying Schwarzenegger's partner and his fan as well. O'Brien is unfortunately the character I mentioned previously that really holds back this film. He is simply unnatural and gives a strained and poor performance. It just is very underwhelming. The chemistry between him and Schwarzenegger is nearly awful and that would be the key point to this movie. Charles Dance is very good as the evil villain Benedict. He is over the top but looks menacing and certainly is the perfect personification of an action movie villain. Tom Noonan is also good as the twisted Ripper villain who is also an amped up spoof of a slasher villain. Everyone else in the film are basically cameos but there are some really good ones worth mentioning. F. Murray Abraham, Art Carney, Frank McRae, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and even Ian McKellan are just a few of the faces you will recognize and they give good solid campy performances. If there was any director they should have gotten to direct this film it would be John McTiernan. Die Hard, Predator, The Hunt For Red October, Die Hard 3, Medicine Man...and more. Every action film he has done has at least been decent so he was the perfect choice to do this film and poke fun at the genre. The action scenes are well done and yet overdone at the same time (which granted is the point.) Last Action Hero is fun and exciting but is held back by making fun of itself almost too much. Still, it is a modern day cult classic and more and more people are calling it under-rated and when you look at some of the hidden Easter eggs in the film, it becomes even more fascinating and fun. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice parody of an action movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colm-hearne365
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I noticed that this movie got some pretty bad reception from critics and didn't do that well in the box office but that was because it was released at the same time as Jurassic Park. And I think the reason why people didn't like was because they took it too seriously. The thing is this movie is a parody of action movies like Blazing Saddles is a parody of westerns or Spaceballs was a parody of sci-fi movies. But even I can admit this movie gets pretty cheesy and over the top at times but parodies are like that. And even the kid, Danny was pretty annoying at times. But I think its a fun movie to watch, especially if you're an action fan and Arnold Schwarzenegger has always been my favourite action star. And I like the idea of the clash between fantasy and reality and it's also funny and exciting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated, but not flawless, gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero has got a lot of bad mouthing over the years, but it seems a lot of critics were just jumping on the bandwagon, afraid to say something positive. It is difficult to see why no-one would like it at all. While a tad heavy-handed, the constant riffing on typical macho action flicks is spot-on, always amusing, and yet at the same time the film delivers saw awe-inspiring, sometimes deliberately implausible action set-pieces. Arnie sends himself up fine, while Austin O'Brien often says out loud what most often think watching these kinds of films. Charles Dance makes a menacing villain, and provides some dark amusement of his own - I JUST SHOT SOMEBODY, I DID IT ON PURPOSE. Where the film begins to falter is when the fictional characters, plus Danny, enter the real world. Until this point, it had been going along at a roaring clip, constantly amusing. Perhaps it was necessary to show a dose of reality to those brought up on mindless action flicks, but it starts becoming a little more serious and darker in tone, more sentimental, and consequently less fun. That doesn't make it bad though, and it does provide some food for thought, with Arnie-in-character ranting about how he's fed up of shooting people in films, and blowing things up. Not a masterpiece perhaps, but deserves to be ranked high on Arnie's filmography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Last Action Hero' is Pure Fun! A highly entertaining escapist fare, that works from start to end. 'Last Action Hero' Synopsis: A young movie fan gets thrown into the movie world of his favorite action film character. 'Last Action Hero' is innovative & fun. The pace is perfect & the action-sequences are top-notch. Shane Black, David Arnott & William Goldman's Screenplay is child-like, but works wonderfully. John McTiernan's Direction is efficient. Cinematography is stylish. Art Design is perfect. Performance-Wise: Arnold Schwarzenegger plays to the gallery. He enacts the hero with his usual ease. Austin O'Brien is extremely likable, as he's energetic all through. Robert Prosky is restrained. Charles Dance is excellent. Anthony Quinn is effective. On the whole, 'Last Action Hero' is some great vintage entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This hero stuff has its limits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero is directed by John McTiernan and written by Shane Black and David Arnott. It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, F. Murray Abraham, Charles Dance, Tom Noonan, Austin O'Brien, Art Carney, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and Bridgette Wilson. Music is by Micahel Kamen and cinematography by Dean Semler. Film within a film action parody that sees young Danny Madigan (O'Brien) magically transported into the parallel universe of an action film featuring his fictional hero, Jack Slater (Schwarzenegger). A financial failure and beaten relentlessly by the critics upon release (even McTiernan would condemn it down the line), Last Action Hero is viewed some what in better terms these days. Whilst the arguments that it was ahead of its time, misunderstood and released at the wrong time due to competition with Jurassic Park (the last one was Arnie himself, bless him) are weak and really not worth considering, it's a decent and "intelligent" film that could have been very good if cut by at least half an hour. Running at over two hours in length, the film's central concept of parodying action movies, with Arnold broadly laughing at himself, runs out of steam, the joke just becomes a millstone around its neck. You can see the drop in quality of the action in the last third as well, purely because so much is thrown at the audience, it gets tiresome for the director, which is such a shame given that it's McTiernan at the helm, the man who in Predator and Die Hard gave the 80s its two best American action movies. As it is, and I was helped enormously in my viewing of this because I watched it back to back with Hard Target, much of the parody and cineaste jokes strike a humorous chord. While the roll call of actors lining up to be in on the joke is impressive and often laugh out loud funny. Yet amongst all the satire and tongue in cheek wink winks, there is also some depth to the dizzying narrative that is worth appraising, particularly when the picture pitches up the real life of an actor to that of the character he plays, with one sequence as Arnie faces up to Arnie particularly brilliant. Better than you may have heard it is, but still a film that's difficult to recommend with confidence. Some self-examining depth and smart in- movie jokes ensure it's no dud, but entering the last third it becomes tiresome and routine and that leaves a disappointment that's hard to shake. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it as a kid in '93, and I've grown to appreciate it as an adult.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reading some of the lurid behind-the-scenes details on "Last Action Hero" (do a search, it's scintillating!), one would walk into this thing expecting an &uuml;ber-expensive disaster. And it was, at least financially. But time has been kind to this movie, and it's actually - for most of its runtime - a pretty kickass genre sendup. The idea behind "Last Action Hero" is satirically brilliant: to deconstruct the big Hollywood action movie. You know, your "Lethal Weapon"s, your "Die Hard"s and your Schwarzenegger "sh-t blows up real good!" movies. And when the movie focuses on that aspect, it's a fun romp. You see enough '80s action movies, the tropes and clich&eacute;s become commonplace. They're all here: - huge explosions send the hero flying (ultimately unscathed) while everyone around him winds up dead - change of scenery from location to studio backlot within a scene - there are no unattractive women - police headquarters is unbelievably posh - the Lieutenant speaks only in vein-popping screams - gunshots send bad guys flying - an inordinate number of explosions And it's that novelty of the genre satire that really makes this movie, for me. Which means the film's first 90 minutes are very entertaining. It's when the villain escapes the movie and our focus centers on the real world that "Last Action Hero" loses me. The film's first half is front-loaded with all of the good stuff. All of the good jokes and sight gags are there. I have no interest in what goes on in the real world. The real magic is in the artificial one. But there's strength in the casting. Arnold is able and surprisingly good at offering himself up for parody. And in a role that's sure to be annoying on paper, Austin O'Brien is actually kinda endearing as the kid sidekick. I really liked him here. And Charles Dance as Benedict . . . he's a terrific bad guy. In this type of movie, especially; great comedic timing, and just a pleasure to watch. He steals every one of his scenes. His lines are the funniest. "Last Action Hero" would definitely merit a higher rating if I didn't feel the need to turn it off with 45 minutes left to go. But when I think of this movie, it's that great first half that sticks in my brain. It should've performed better 20 years ago. The lousy reputation is (for the most part) undeserved, and it's a clear example of the kind of curious oddity that can result after many bad decisions made during the filmmaking process. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better the older you get
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dame Shumma
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grandiose, like Schwarzenegger takes the mickey out here himself, knows his last name wrong constantly and eventually called Arnold Braunschweiger. There are ongoing links to other movies, where, like in Die Hard. Danny makes Jack's attention to look up after a car accident even if the bad guy except death. In Die Hard, it was finally so that the blonde is hanged, and at the end is still alive. Grandiose, something is a feast for action lovers. The final rise to the film premiere of "Jack Slater IV" in New York. Schwarzenegger plays himself here, and is approached by his wife to make lasting advertising for Planet Hollywood. John Belushi announces Jack Slater movies so he does not like, and Van Damme, yes, even the Belgian martial arts goes to the premiere. Just plain funny. Slater is run by Danny corrected. Whenever he "I'll be back," says Danny knew beforehand that he will say that it is, after all, his trademark. Even the testing center for movies, the MPAA will not be left out. Danny writes a word, probably "fuck" on a piece of paper. Slater read it will not. Danny Comment: "You can not read it, because this movie is PG-13" Just wonderful. Who wants to keep checking back for once really look over a very successful action movie parody must. However, you should really have already seen some in the sector to understand everything. In order to find every hidden joke I have seen the movie a few times anyway. Well, anyway, the story is incidental and not the hammer. But is sufficient. I admit: Movie Review: 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A curious oddity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When young Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) is given a magic movie ticket by friendly cinema owner Nick (Robert Prosky) at an advance screening of new action movie Jack Slater IV, he is magically transported into the movie and into the car of supercop Jack Slater (Arnold Schwarzenegger). Danny starts to inform Slater about who the bad guys are after seeing them on screen, and the two are paired up as a mismatched investigative duo by Slater's screaming boss. Glass-eyed bad guy Mr. Benedict (Charles Dance) manages to get his hands on the magic ticket, and escapes into the real world, where he finds things are much easier for the bad guys. Slater must leave his action movie clich&eacute; of a world where he is nigh on invincible behind, and enter one where things are slightly more difficult. Last Action Hero had one of the most expensive and turbulent page-to- screen stories in recent cinema history. Originally written as a self- mocking action movie that embraced the clich&eacute;s of the genre, that was also a proper action movie in its own right. After an unexpected bidding war, the young scribes Zak Penn and Adam Leff were shocked to find that Arnold Schwarzenegger had taken a personal interest in it (the original hero name was Arno Slater). This was to be the turning point. Arnie saw the potential for a franchise as a kid's film and immediately wanted to tone down the violence, so Penn and Leff were fired, and genre legend Shane Black was hired to spruce up the script. Things changed yet again when director John McTiernan was brought in, and, due to the success of his previous films, was given full control. A few script re-writes, firings, and storm-outs later, the film was shot and ready to hit the market. A toy franchise and a ridiculously expensive and calamitous advertising campaign (they paid half a million dollars to have the film's name on a NASA rocket, only to have the launched delayed till long after the film's release) were put into motion, and the film's release date was announced for the week after Jurassic Park's. Last Action Hero had disastrous test screenings, but the release date was not changed, and naturally, Jurassic Park stormed the box-office and merchandising range, and Last Action Hero was revealed to be an over-ambitious, confused dud of a movie. However, the legend is rather cruel on Schwarzenegger's biggest flop, as although it is a gigantic mess, it has plenty of interesting ideas than are unfortunately spewed out onto the film in ungraceful belches. The biggest problem is that it doesn't know what kind of film it is. At its heart, its a kid's film, complete with annoying mop-haired child, a kindly old man, magic tickets and, um, a cartoon cat. Yet on its surface, its a rather uninspired action film that is actually rather violent and, once in the real world, is quite grim. The film never seems to know whether it wants to homage, spoof or simply in-joke. The movie world it creates is itself confused - while it has some funny touches such as the police line pairing together various mismatched partners - it also has women walking around in sexy, futuristic costumes, and the aforementioned cartoon cat called Whiskers (voiced by Danny DeVito). Seriously, whose idea was that? I've never seen a cartoon cat in a live- action action movie! However, the sheer mess that is the complete film does prove Last Action Hero to be a curious little oddity. There have been much finer examples of action-movie send-ups, namely in Shane Black's own excellent Kiss Kiss Bang Bang (2005), so perhaps the producers weren't ready back in 1993 to take on such an ambitious project. Arnie is pleasantly game for sending himself up, and Charles Dance chews the screen with his gloriously hammy British bad guy. But Last Action Hero will ultimately always be a reminder of how the Hollywood system to suck up an interesting maverick project, f**k it over a few times, and bundle it over the finishing line with such unbelievable inefficiency. I did love it as a kid, however. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was right the first time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Last Action Hero back in 1993; I didn't like it. Twenty years later and I begin to wonder whether my opinion was a knee-jerk reaction to seeing Schwarzenegger in something a little different to his usual fare, and that perhaps I would appreciate the film more second time round. Well, I just watched it again and, if anything, I disliked it even more than the first time. The basic (high) conceptaction movie fan Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) enters the fictional world of his movie hero Jack Slater (Arnie)is actually pretty clever, allowing for lots of ingenious meta-moments, but the way in which it is all realised is diabolical: the screenplay is full of misjudged humour (what is it with that dumb animated cat?), child star Austin O'Brien puts in a thoroughly annoying performance, and the exaggerated action scenes within Slater's movie-verse are completely devoid of excitement. There are also quite a few jokes that have dated extremely badly, especially the 'star' cameos from people that are no longer as famous as they used to be. The saddest thing about the whole film is that, given the great talent involved (Arnie, screenwriter Shane Black, director John McTiernan) it really should have been much, much better. Studio intervention may have been the reason it turned out so bad, but knowing that doesn't make the film any more enjoyable to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupidity stops where its own awareness starts ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that principle applies for both people and movies. And this is why parody generally provides the cleverest films, mocking the archetypes over-exploited by lazy directors with a subtle, and so engaging, wink to the audience. And "Last Action Hero" parodies the action-flick, featuring its most iconic ambassador, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the lone-ranger bad-ass cigar-smoking titular hero of a never-ending franchise: Jack Slater. As if he was plenty aware that "Die Hard" put a deathblow on the credibility of such super-heroic figures popularized by "Commando" and "Predator", John McTiernan becomes the iconoclast of his own creations -a demonstration of smart sense of humor a few directors ever achieved. The opening "Jack Slater" film even concludes with a reference to the genre-defining "Die Hard", using the same score to contribute to the whole 'inside joke' effect, completed when Jack Slater becomes a movie-within-a-movie character, from the perspective of Danny, his number one fan, played by Austin O'Brien. Basically, Danny is to "Last Action Hero" what Cecilia (Mia Farrow) was to "The Purple Rose of Cairo": a movie lover whose only means to transcend routine's banality was a constant ecstatic stare toward the silver screen. And being a kid of the early 90's, I could only respond to his hypnotic fascination. Action films are indeed the best pop-culture fillers, crystallizing the most common denominators of fun and entertainment and generating codes and formula that are part of cinema's timeless and universal heritage, no matter how overused they are: the never-dying hero, the yelling superior, the revenge plot, the villainous monologue, the sexy daughter, the comic-relief sidekick, the sophisticated boss' right hand who becomes the real villain and a lame catchphrase. They're all there in "Last Action Hero" less because they're obligatory but for the necessity to turn them into derision, by confronting them to reality. Still, there has to be some fantasy in this reality: Danny is given by the projectionist Nick (Art Carney) a magic ticket that belonged to the Great Houdini. And while he watches the fourth opus of Jack Slater's adventures during a private screening, the ticket glows, sticks of dynamite are thrown from the screen and land near his feet. Danny starts to take the notion of 'danger' less cynically before the explosion immediately projects him into his hero's universe. The film's greatest moments come from Danny's desperate attempts to convince Slater that they live in a movie where phone numbers start with "555", video-store workers are sexy and profanity is prohibited. Hell, in this parallel universe, his own rival Stallone played the Terminator roles (which made me wonder who then played Rocky or Rambo). The film recycles every clich&eacute; in such an over-the-top way it's hilarious: the car rams into an ice cream truck and explodes, a henchman gets an ice cone on the neck, many gags feel like these 'McBain' segments from "The Simpsons", thus never fail. The film also features one hilarious modernization of "Hamlet" and two delightful movie references. One of Slater's friends is played by F. Murray Abraham, naturally, Danny warns him that it's the same guy who killed Mozart in "Amadeus": the film that got 8 Oscars. For a kid, he has the knowledge of an IMDb user, which says a lot about "Last Action Hero" exhilarating effect as pure geek escapism, reinforced by the obscure intrusion of Death from "The Seventh Seal", a joke I didn't even get when I saw the film as a teenager. Now, there are two facts regarding "Last Action Hero": the film flopped, and it didn't deserve to, not when box-office laws are governed by rules that allow "Cliffhanger" to be the 7th highest grossing film anyway. Therefore, I can only qualify its bombing as 'accidental', the same accident that made "Sorcerer" flop in 1977. The parallel is all the more eloquent because "Last Action Hero" suffered from an ill-fated opening coinciding with the big event of 1993: the release of Steven Spielberg's "Jurassik park" ("Sorcerer" had it worse with "Star Wars") and perhaps misleading title, trailer and word-of-mouth that branded the film in the total opposite way it expected to: a dumb action film, 'another one'. I don't blame the viewers who thought a bunch of reptilian carnivores would be a fresher spectacle, I, was misled too, the first time I saw the TV announcement. But being a box-office flop is one thing, but when I started to examine the disastrous reception from those who actually saw the film- I was stunned. Seriously, what's with all these Razzies' nominations? Worst actor? Arnold had to play his usual role. Worst screenplay? Check the review's title. Worst new star? That's the worst thing about vocation-discouraging Razzies: the kid was supposed to be annoying and he played that part quite well. Worst song? It's a cheesy action-flick, did they expect Barbra Streisand? "Last Action Hero" is not beyond criticism though especially in the last act, when they 'get' in the real world. It's true that the film could have pushed its self-reflexive concept to more thought-provoking levels, that the emotional involvement lacked when the action was conditioned by predictable plot devices and needed to be compensated in the 'real world'. It's also true that confronting Slater to Arnold (like in Woody Allen's film) or having Danny talking to him, could have induced more interesting situations, but the reception would make anyone believe the film is like "Stop or my Mom Will Shoot!". Talk about unfortunate misunderstanding, not that I believe it truly deserves this 8, but it makes up for the undeserved negativity it inspired. McTiernan would finally make the highest-grossing film of 1995: "Die Hard 3 With a Vengeance" which feels like his personal vengeance. The film is as corny and over-the-top as "Last Action Hero" but I guess the average audience wasn't ready for that level of subtlety, so he probably thought : "Hell, give them the movie they deserve and give me a break".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun cheeky spoof movie that has gained a cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best things about Last Action Hero is that the more you read about it, you realize the smarter it is. There are so many little nods and cheeky references to the action genre and to Hollywood that you can't possibly catch them all the first time around. It appears, on the surface, to be this huge action film but really the entire film is poking fun at the genre. And who better to bring on board to do that but the King of eighties action Arnold Schwarzenegger. There is so much right about this film. The scenes with Arnold playing himself and the interaction between him and "Jack Slater" are just awesome. The cameos and the world they create inside the movie is just so much fun to watch. The problem is that the film is almost too much of a joke. Fans of Schwarzenegger and action films might find their genre being made a total fool of a bit much to handle. And also one of the leading roles is really not good but more on that in a minute. It is definitely a PG-13 movie and while there is nothing wrong with that, it feels like it struggles to purposely try to stay PG and it has trouble doing that. I love Arnold Schwarzenegger, he has just always been one of my Hollywood icons. This is such an odd role for him because he is making fun of himself and what he does best. However, it works well and he is actually fun as Slater. He is especially fun in the brief scenes where is "playing" or "over-playing" himself. The banter between him and real life wife/ex-wife Maria Shriver is just awesome. Austin O'Brien is the young actor portraying Schwarzenegger's partner and his fan as well. O'Brien is unfortunately the character I mentioned previously that really holds back this film. He is simply unnatural and gives a strained and poor performance. It just is very underwhelming. The chemistry between him and Schwarzenegger is nearly awful and that would be the key point to this movie. Charles Dance is very good as the evil villain Benedict. He is over the top but looks menacing and certainly is the perfect personification of an action movie villain. Tom Noonan is also good as the twisted Ripper villain who is also an amped up spoof of a slasher villain. Everyone else in the film are basically cameos but there are some really good ones worth mentioning. F. Murray Abraham, Art Carney, Frank McRae, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and even Ian McKellan are just a few of the faces you will recognize and they give good solid campy performances. If there was any director they should have gotten to direct this film it would be John McTiernan. Die Hard, Predator, The Hunt For Red October, Die Hard 3, Medicine Man...and more. Every action film he has done has at least been decent so he was the perfect choice to do this film and poke fun at the genre. The action scenes are well done and yet overdone at the same time (which granted is the point.) Last Action Hero is fun and exciting but is held back by making fun of itself almost too much. Still, it is a modern day cult classic and more and more people are calling it under-rated and when you look at some of the hidden Easter eggs in the film, it becomes even more fascinating and fun. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice parody of an action movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colm-hearne365
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I noticed that this movie got some pretty bad reception from critics and didn't do that well in the box office but that was because it was released at the same time as Jurassic Park. And I think the reason why people didn't like was because they took it too seriously. The thing is this movie is a parody of action movies like Blazing Saddles is a parody of westerns or Spaceballs was a parody of sci-fi movies. But even I can admit this movie gets pretty cheesy and over the top at times but parodies are like that. And even the kid, Danny was pretty annoying at times. But I think its a fun movie to watch, especially if you're an action fan and Arnold Schwarzenegger has always been my favourite action star. And I like the idea of the clash between fantasy and reality and it's also funny and exciting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated, but not flawless, gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero has got a lot of bad mouthing over the years, but it seems a lot of critics were just jumping on the bandwagon, afraid to say something positive. It is difficult to see why no-one would like it at all. While a tad heavy-handed, the constant riffing on typical macho action flicks is spot-on, always amusing, and yet at the same time the film delivers saw awe-inspiring, sometimes deliberately implausible action set-pieces. Arnie sends himself up fine, while Austin O'Brien often says out loud what most often think watching these kinds of films. Charles Dance makes a menacing villain, and provides some dark amusement of his own - I JUST SHOT SOMEBODY, I DID IT ON PURPOSE. Where the film begins to falter is when the fictional characters, plus Danny, enter the real world. Until this point, it had been going along at a roaring clip, constantly amusing. Perhaps it was necessary to show a dose of reality to those brought up on mindless action flicks, but it starts becoming a little more serious and darker in tone, more sentimental, and consequently less fun. That doesn't make it bad though, and it does provide some food for thought, with Arnie-in-character ranting about how he's fed up of shooting people in films, and blowing things up. Not a masterpiece perhaps, but deserves to be ranked high on Arnie's filmography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Last Action Hero' is Pure Fun! A highly entertaining escapist fare, that works from start to end. 'Last Action Hero' Synopsis: A young movie fan gets thrown into the movie world of his favorite action film character. 'Last Action Hero' is innovative & fun. The pace is perfect & the action-sequences are top-notch. Shane Black, David Arnott & William Goldman's Screenplay is child-like, but works wonderfully. John McTiernan's Direction is efficient. Cinematography is stylish. Art Design is perfect. Performance-Wise: Arnold Schwarzenegger plays to the gallery. He enacts the hero with his usual ease. Austin O'Brien is extremely likable, as he's energetic all through. Robert Prosky is restrained. Charles Dance is excellent. Anthony Quinn is effective. On the whole, 'Last Action Hero' is some great vintage entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This hero stuff has its limits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero is directed by John McTiernan and written by Shane Black and David Arnott. It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, F. Murray Abraham, Charles Dance, Tom Noonan, Austin O'Brien, Art Carney, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and Bridgette Wilson. Music is by Micahel Kamen and cinematography by Dean Semler. Film within a film action parody that sees young Danny Madigan (O'Brien) magically transported into the parallel universe of an action film featuring his fictional hero, Jack Slater (Schwarzenegger). A financial failure and beaten relentlessly by the critics upon release (even McTiernan would condemn it down the line), Last Action Hero is viewed some what in better terms these days. Whilst the arguments that it was ahead of its time, misunderstood and released at the wrong time due to competition with Jurassic Park (the last one was Arnie himself, bless him) are weak and really not worth considering, it's a decent and "intelligent" film that could have been very good if cut by at least half an hour. Running at over two hours in length, the film's central concept of parodying action movies, with Arnold broadly laughing at himself, runs out of steam, the joke just becomes a millstone around its neck. You can see the drop in quality of the action in the last third as well, purely because so much is thrown at the audience, it gets tiresome for the director, which is such a shame given that it's McTiernan at the helm, the man who in Predator and Die Hard gave the 80s its two best American action movies. As it is, and I was helped enormously in my viewing of this because I watched it back to back with Hard Target, much of the parody and cineaste jokes strike a humorous chord. While the roll call of actors lining up to be in on the joke is impressive and often laugh out loud funny. Yet amongst all the satire and tongue in cheek wink winks, there is also some depth to the dizzying narrative that is worth appraising, particularly when the picture pitches up the real life of an actor to that of the character he plays, with one sequence as Arnie faces up to Arnie particularly brilliant. Better than you may have heard it is, but still a film that's difficult to recommend with confidence. Some self-examining depth and smart in- movie jokes ensure it's no dud, but entering the last third it becomes tiresome and routine and that leaves a disappointment that's hard to shake. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it as a kid in '93, and I've grown to appreciate it as an adult.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reading some of the lurid behind-the-scenes details on "Last Action Hero" (do a search, it's scintillating!), one would walk into this thing expecting an &uuml;ber-expensive disaster. And it was, at least financially. But time has been kind to this movie, and it's actually - for most of its runtime - a pretty kickass genre sendup. The idea behind "Last Action Hero" is satirically brilliant: to deconstruct the big Hollywood action movie. You know, your "Lethal Weapon"s, your "Die Hard"s and your Schwarzenegger "sh-t blows up real good!" movies. And when the movie focuses on that aspect, it's a fun romp. You see enough '80s action movies, the tropes and clich&eacute;s become commonplace. They're all here: - huge explosions send the hero flying (ultimately unscathed) while everyone around him winds up dead - change of scenery from location to studio backlot within a scene - there are no unattractive women - police headquarters is unbelievably posh - the Lieutenant speaks only in vein-popping screams - gunshots send bad guys flying - an inordinate number of explosions And it's that novelty of the genre satire that really makes this movie, for me. Which means the film's first 90 minutes are very entertaining. It's when the villain escapes the movie and our focus centers on the real world that "Last Action Hero" loses me. The film's first half is front-loaded with all of the good stuff. All of the good jokes and sight gags are there. I have no interest in what goes on in the real world. The real magic is in the artificial one. But there's strength in the casting. Arnold is able and surprisingly good at offering himself up for parody. And in a role that's sure to be annoying on paper, Austin O'Brien is actually kinda endearing as the kid sidekick. I really liked him here. And Charles Dance as Benedict . . . he's a terrific bad guy. In this type of movie, especially; great comedic timing, and just a pleasure to watch. He steals every one of his scenes. His lines are the funniest. "Last Action Hero" would definitely merit a higher rating if I didn't feel the need to turn it off with 45 minutes left to go. But when I think of this movie, it's that great first half that sticks in my brain. It should've performed better 20 years ago. The lousy reputation is (for the most part) undeserved, and it's a clear example of the kind of curious oddity that can result after many bad decisions made during the filmmaking process. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better the older you get
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dame Shumma
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grandiose, like Schwarzenegger takes the mickey out here himself, knows his last name wrong constantly and eventually called Arnold Braunschweiger. There are ongoing links to other movies, where, like in Die Hard. Danny makes Jack's attention to look up after a car accident even if the bad guy except death. In Die Hard, it was finally so that the blonde is hanged, and at the end is still alive. Grandiose, something is a feast for action lovers. The final rise to the film premiere of "Jack Slater IV" in New York. Schwarzenegger plays himself here, and is approached by his wife to make lasting advertising for Planet Hollywood. John Belushi announces Jack Slater movies so he does not like, and Van Damme, yes, even the Belgian martial arts goes to the premiere. Just plain funny. Slater is run by Danny corrected. Whenever he "I'll be back," says Danny knew beforehand that he will say that it is, after all, his trademark. Even the testing center for movies, the MPAA will not be left out. Danny writes a word, probably "fuck" on a piece of paper. Slater read it will not. Danny Comment: "You can not read it, because this movie is PG-13" Just wonderful. Who wants to keep checking back for once really look over a very successful action movie parody must. However, you should really have already seen some in the sector to understand everything. In order to find every hidden joke I have seen the movie a few times anyway. Well, anyway, the story is incidental and not the hammer. But is sufficient. I admit: Movie Review: 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A curious oddity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When young Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) is given a magic movie ticket by friendly cinema owner Nick (Robert Prosky) at an advance screening of new action movie Jack Slater IV, he is magically transported into the movie and into the car of supercop Jack Slater (Arnold Schwarzenegger). Danny starts to inform Slater about who the bad guys are after seeing them on screen, and the two are paired up as a mismatched investigative duo by Slater's screaming boss. Glass-eyed bad guy Mr. Benedict (Charles Dance) manages to get his hands on the magic ticket, and escapes into the real world, where he finds things are much easier for the bad guys. Slater must leave his action movie clich&eacute; of a world where he is nigh on invincible behind, and enter one where things are slightly more difficult. Last Action Hero had one of the most expensive and turbulent page-to- screen stories in recent cinema history. Originally written as a self- mocking action movie that embraced the clich&eacute;s of the genre, that was also a proper action movie in its own right. After an unexpected bidding war, the young scribes Zak Penn and Adam Leff were shocked to find that Arnold Schwarzenegger had taken a personal interest in it (the original hero name was Arno Slater). This was to be the turning point. Arnie saw the potential for a franchise as a kid's film and immediately wanted to tone down the violence, so Penn and Leff were fired, and genre legend Shane Black was hired to spruce up the script. Things changed yet again when director John McTiernan was brought in, and, due to the success of his previous films, was given full control. A few script re-writes, firings, and storm-outs later, the film was shot and ready to hit the market. A toy franchise and a ridiculously expensive and calamitous advertising campaign (they paid half a million dollars to have the film's name on a NASA rocket, only to have the launched delayed till long after the film's release) were put into motion, and the film's release date was announced for the week after Jurassic Park's. Last Action Hero had disastrous test screenings, but the release date was not changed, and naturally, Jurassic Park stormed the box-office and merchandising range, and Last Action Hero was revealed to be an over-ambitious, confused dud of a movie. However, the legend is rather cruel on Schwarzenegger's biggest flop, as although it is a gigantic mess, it has plenty of interesting ideas than are unfortunately spewed out onto the film in ungraceful belches. The biggest problem is that it doesn't know what kind of film it is. At its heart, its a kid's film, complete with annoying mop-haired child, a kindly old man, magic tickets and, um, a cartoon cat. Yet on its surface, its a rather uninspired action film that is actually rather violent and, once in the real world, is quite grim. The film never seems to know whether it wants to homage, spoof or simply in-joke. The movie world it creates is itself confused - while it has some funny touches such as the police line pairing together various mismatched partners - it also has women walking around in sexy, futuristic costumes, and the aforementioned cartoon cat called Whiskers (voiced by Danny DeVito). Seriously, whose idea was that? I've never seen a cartoon cat in a live- action action movie! However, the sheer mess that is the complete film does prove Last Action Hero to be a curious little oddity. There have been much finer examples of action-movie send-ups, namely in Shane Black's own excellent Kiss Kiss Bang Bang (2005), so perhaps the producers weren't ready back in 1993 to take on such an ambitious project. Arnie is pleasantly game for sending himself up, and Charles Dance chews the screen with his gloriously hammy British bad guy. But Last Action Hero will ultimately always be a reminder of how the Hollywood system to suck up an interesting maverick project, f**k it over a few times, and bundle it over the finishing line with such unbelievable inefficiency. I did love it as a kid, however. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I was right the first time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Last Action Hero back in 1993; I didn't like it. Twenty years later and I begin to wonder whether my opinion was a knee-jerk reaction to seeing Schwarzenegger in something a little different to his usual fare, and that perhaps I would appreciate the film more second time round. Well, I just watched it again and, if anything, I disliked it even more than the first time. The basic (high) conceptaction movie fan Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) enters the fictional world of his movie hero Jack Slater (Arnie)is actually pretty clever, allowing for lots of ingenious meta-moments, but the way in which it is all realised is diabolical: the screenplay is full of misjudged humour (what is it with that dumb animated cat?), child star Austin O'Brien puts in a thoroughly annoying performance, and the exaggerated action scenes within Slater's movie-verse are completely devoid of excitement. There are also quite a few jokes that have dated extremely badly, especially the 'star' cameos from people that are no longer as famous as they used to be. The saddest thing about the whole film is that, given the great talent involved (Arnie, screenwriter Shane Black, director John McTiernan) it really should have been much, much better. Studio intervention may have been the reason it turned out so bad, but knowing that doesn't make the film any more enjoyable to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupidity stops where its own awareness starts ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that principle applies for both people and movies. And this is why parody generally provides the cleverest films, mocking the archetypes over-exploited by lazy directors with a subtle, and so engaging, wink to the audience. And "Last Action Hero" parodies the action-flick, featuring its most iconic ambassador, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the lone-ranger bad-ass cigar-smoking titular hero of a never-ending franchise: Jack Slater. As if he was plenty aware that "Die Hard" put a deathblow on the credibility of such super-heroic figures popularized by "Commando" and "Predator", John McTiernan becomes the iconoclast of his own creations -a demonstration of smart sense of humor a few directors ever achieved. The opening "Jack Slater" film even concludes with a reference to the genre-defining "Die Hard", using the same score to contribute to the whole 'inside joke' effect, completed when Jack Slater becomes a movie-within-a-movie character, from the perspective of Danny, his number one fan, played by Austin O'Brien. Basically, Danny is to "Last Action Hero" what Cecilia (Mia Farrow) was to "The Purple Rose of Cairo": a movie lover whose only means to transcend routine's banality was a constant ecstatic stare toward the silver screen. And being a kid of the early 90's, I could only respond to his hypnotic fascination. Action films are indeed the best pop-culture fillers, crystallizing the most common denominators of fun and entertainment and generating codes and formula that are part of cinema's timeless and universal heritage, no matter how overused they are: the never-dying hero, the yelling superior, the revenge plot, the villainous monologue, the sexy daughter, the comic-relief sidekick, the sophisticated boss' right hand who becomes the real villain and a lame catchphrase. They're all there in "Last Action Hero" less because they're obligatory but for the necessity to turn them into derision, by confronting them to reality. Still, there has to be some fantasy in this reality: Danny is given by the projectionist Nick (Art Carney) a magic ticket that belonged to the Great Houdini. And while he watches the fourth opus of Jack Slater's adventures during a private screening, the ticket glows, sticks of dynamite are thrown from the screen and land near his feet. Danny starts to take the notion of 'danger' less cynically before the explosion immediately projects him into his hero's universe. The film's greatest moments come from Danny's desperate attempts to convince Slater that they live in a movie where phone numbers start with "555", video-store workers are sexy and profanity is prohibited. Hell, in this parallel universe, his own rival Stallone played the Terminator roles (which made me wonder who then played Rocky or Rambo). The film recycles every clich&eacute; in such an over-the-top way it's hilarious: the car rams into an ice cream truck and explodes, a henchman gets an ice cone on the neck, many gags feel like these 'McBain' segments from "The Simpsons", thus never fail. The film also features one hilarious modernization of "Hamlet" and two delightful movie references. One of Slater's friends is played by F. Murray Abraham, naturally, Danny warns him that it's the same guy who killed Mozart in "Amadeus": the film that got 8 Oscars. For a kid, he has the knowledge of an IMDb user, which says a lot about "Last Action Hero" exhilarating effect as pure geek escapism, reinforced by the obscure intrusion of Death from "The Seventh Seal", a joke I didn't even get when I saw the film as a teenager. Now, there are two facts regarding "Last Action Hero": the film flopped, and it didn't deserve to, not when box-office laws are governed by rules that allow "Cliffhanger" to be the 7th highest grossing film anyway. Therefore, I can only qualify its bombing as 'accidental', the same accident that made "Sorcerer" flop in 1977. The parallel is all the more eloquent because "Last Action Hero" suffered from an ill-fated opening coinciding with the big event of 1993: the release of Steven Spielberg's "Jurassik park" ("Sorcerer" had it worse with "Star Wars") and perhaps misleading title, trailer and word-of-mouth that branded the film in the total opposite way it expected to: a dumb action film, 'another one'. I don't blame the viewers who thought a bunch of reptilian carnivores would be a fresher spectacle, I, was misled too, the first time I saw the TV announcement. But being a box-office flop is one thing, but when I started to examine the disastrous reception from those who actually saw the film- I was stunned. Seriously, what's with all these Razzies' nominations? Worst actor? Arnold had to play his usual role. Worst screenplay? Check the review's title. Worst new star? That's the worst thing about vocation-discouraging Razzies: the kid was supposed to be annoying and he played that part quite well. Worst song? It's a cheesy action-flick, did they expect Barbra Streisand? "Last Action Hero" is not beyond criticism though especially in the last act, when they 'get' in the real world. It's true that the film could have pushed its self-reflexive concept to more thought-provoking levels, that the emotional involvement lacked when the action was conditioned by predictable plot devices and needed to be compensated in the 'real world'. It's also true that confronting Slater to Arnold (like in Woody Allen's film) or having Danny talking to him, could have induced more interesting situations, but the reception would make anyone believe the film is like "Stop or my Mom Will Shoot!". Talk about unfortunate misunderstanding, not that I believe it truly deserves this 8, but it makes up for the undeserved negativity it inspired. McTiernan would finally make the highest-grossing film of 1995: "Die Hard 3 With a Vengeance" which feels like his personal vengeance. The film is as corny and over-the-top as "Last Action Hero" but I guess the average audience wasn't ready for that level of subtlety, so he probably thought : "Hell, give them the movie they deserve and give me a break".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun cheeky spoof movie that has gained a cult status
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best things about Last Action Hero is that the more you read about it, you realize the smarter it is. There are so many little nods and cheeky references to the action genre and to Hollywood that you can't possibly catch them all the first time around. It appears, on the surface, to be this huge action film but really the entire film is poking fun at the genre. And who better to bring on board to do that but the King of eighties action Arnold Schwarzenegger. There is so much right about this film. The scenes with Arnold playing himself and the interaction between him and "Jack Slater" are just awesome. The cameos and the world they create inside the movie is just so much fun to watch. The problem is that the film is almost too much of a joke. Fans of Schwarzenegger and action films might find their genre being made a total fool of a bit much to handle. And also one of the leading roles is really not good but more on that in a minute. It is definitely a PG-13 movie and while there is nothing wrong with that, it feels like it struggles to purposely try to stay PG and it has trouble doing that. I love Arnold Schwarzenegger, he has just always been one of my Hollywood icons. This is such an odd role for him because he is making fun of himself and what he does best. However, it works well and he is actually fun as Slater. He is especially fun in the brief scenes where is "playing" or "over-playing" himself. The banter between him and real life wife/ex-wife Maria Shriver is just awesome. Austin O'Brien is the young actor portraying Schwarzenegger's partner and his fan as well. O'Brien is unfortunately the character I mentioned previously that really holds back this film. He is simply unnatural and gives a strained and poor performance. It just is very underwhelming. The chemistry between him and Schwarzenegger is nearly awful and that would be the key point to this movie. Charles Dance is very good as the evil villain Benedict. He is over the top but looks menacing and certainly is the perfect personification of an action movie villain. Tom Noonan is also good as the twisted Ripper villain who is also an amped up spoof of a slasher villain. Everyone else in the film are basically cameos but there are some really good ones worth mentioning. F. Murray Abraham, Art Carney, Frank McRae, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and even Ian McKellan are just a few of the faces you will recognize and they give good solid campy performances. If there was any director they should have gotten to direct this film it would be John McTiernan. Die Hard, Predator, The Hunt For Red October, Die Hard 3, Medicine Man...and more. Every action film he has done has at least been decent so he was the perfect choice to do this film and poke fun at the genre. The action scenes are well done and yet overdone at the same time (which granted is the point.) Last Action Hero is fun and exciting but is held back by making fun of itself almost too much. Still, it is a modern day cult classic and more and more people are calling it under-rated and when you look at some of the hidden Easter eggs in the film, it becomes even more fascinating and fun. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice parody of an action movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colm-hearne365
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I noticed that this movie got some pretty bad reception from critics and didn't do that well in the box office but that was because it was released at the same time as Jurassic Park. And I think the reason why people didn't like was because they took it too seriously. The thing is this movie is a parody of action movies like Blazing Saddles is a parody of westerns or Spaceballs was a parody of sci-fi movies. But even I can admit this movie gets pretty cheesy and over the top at times but parodies are like that. And even the kid, Danny was pretty annoying at times. But I think its a fun movie to watch, especially if you're an action fan and Arnold Schwarzenegger has always been my favourite action star. And I like the idea of the clash between fantasy and reality and it's also funny and exciting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Under-rated, but not flawless, gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero has got a lot of bad mouthing over the years, but it seems a lot of critics were just jumping on the bandwagon, afraid to say something positive. It is difficult to see why no-one would like it at all. While a tad heavy-handed, the constant riffing on typical macho action flicks is spot-on, always amusing, and yet at the same time the film delivers saw awe-inspiring, sometimes deliberately implausible action set-pieces. Arnie sends himself up fine, while Austin O'Brien often says out loud what most often think watching these kinds of films. Charles Dance makes a menacing villain, and provides some dark amusement of his own - I JUST SHOT SOMEBODY, I DID IT ON PURPOSE. Where the film begins to falter is when the fictional characters, plus Danny, enter the real world. Until this point, it had been going along at a roaring clip, constantly amusing. Perhaps it was necessary to show a dose of reality to those brought up on mindless action flicks, but it starts becoming a little more serious and darker in tone, more sentimental, and consequently less fun. That doesn't make it bad though, and it does provide some food for thought, with Arnie-in-character ranting about how he's fed up of shooting people in films, and blowing things up. Not a masterpiece perhaps, but deserves to be ranked high on Arnie's filmography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure Fun!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Last Action Hero' is Pure Fun! A highly entertaining escapist fare, that works from start to end. 'Last Action Hero' Synopsis: A young movie fan gets thrown into the movie world of his favorite action film character. 'Last Action Hero' is innovative & fun. The pace is perfect & the action-sequences are top-notch. Shane Black, David Arnott & William Goldman's Screenplay is child-like, but works wonderfully. John McTiernan's Direction is efficient. Cinematography is stylish. Art Design is perfect. Performance-Wise: Arnold Schwarzenegger plays to the gallery. He enacts the hero with his usual ease. Austin O'Brien is extremely likable, as he's energetic all through. Robert Prosky is restrained. Charles Dance is excellent. Anthony Quinn is effective. On the whole, 'Last Action Hero' is some great vintage entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This hero stuff has its limits.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Last Action Hero is directed by John McTiernan and written by Shane Black and David Arnott. It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, F. Murray Abraham, Charles Dance, Tom Noonan, Austin O'Brien, Art Carney, Robert Prosky, Anthony Quinn and Bridgette Wilson. Music is by Micahel Kamen and cinematography by Dean Semler. Film within a film action parody that sees young Danny Madigan (O'Brien) magically transported into the parallel universe of an action film featuring his fictional hero, Jack Slater (Schwarzenegger). A financial failure and beaten relentlessly by the critics upon release (even McTiernan would condemn it down the line), Last Action Hero is viewed some what in better terms these days. Whilst the arguments that it was ahead of its time, misunderstood and released at the wrong time due to competition with Jurassic Park (the last one was Arnie himself, bless him) are weak and really not worth considering, it's a decent and "intelligent" film that could have been very good if cut by at least half an hour. Running at over two hours in length, the film's central concept of parodying action movies, with Arnold broadly laughing at himself, runs out of steam, the joke just becomes a millstone around its neck. You can see the drop in quality of the action in the last third as well, purely because so much is thrown at the audience, it gets tiresome for the director, which is such a shame given that it's McTiernan at the helm, the man who in Predator and Die Hard gave the 80s its two best American action movies. As it is, and I was helped enormously in my viewing of this because I watched it back to back with Hard Target, much of the parody and cineaste jokes strike a humorous chord. While the roll call of actors lining up to be in on the joke is impressive and often laugh out loud funny. Yet amongst all the satire and tongue in cheek wink winks, there is also some depth to the dizzying narrative that is worth appraising, particularly when the picture pitches up the real life of an actor to that of the character he plays, with one sequence as Arnie faces up to Arnie particularly brilliant. Better than you may have heard it is, but still a film that's difficult to recommend with confidence. Some self-examining depth and smart in- movie jokes ensure it's no dud, but entering the last third it becomes tiresome and routine and that leaves a disappointment that's hard to shake. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked it as a kid in '93, and I've grown to appreciate it as an adult.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reading some of the lurid behind-the-scenes details on "Last Action Hero" (do a search, it's scintillating!), one would walk into this thing expecting an &uuml;ber-expensive disaster. And it was, at least financially. But time has been kind to this movie, and it's actually - for most of its runtime - a pretty kickass genre sendup. The idea behind "Last Action Hero" is satirically brilliant: to deconstruct the big Hollywood action movie. You know, your "Lethal Weapon"s, your "Die Hard"s and your Schwarzenegger "sh-t blows up real good!" movies. And when the movie focuses on that aspect, it's a fun romp. You see enough '80s action movies, the tropes and clich&eacute;s become commonplace. They're all here: - huge explosions send the hero flying (ultimately unscathed) while everyone around him winds up dead - change of scenery from location to studio backlot within a scene - there are no unattractive women - police headquarters is unbelievably posh - the Lieutenant speaks only in vein-popping screams - gunshots send bad guys flying - an inordinate number of explosions And it's that novelty of the genre satire that really makes this movie, for me. Which means the film's first 90 minutes are very entertaining. It's when the villain escapes the movie and our focus centers on the real world that "Last Action Hero" loses me. The film's first half is front-loaded with all of the good stuff. All of the good jokes and sight gags are there. I have no interest in what goes on in the real world. The real magic is in the artificial one. But there's strength in the casting. Arnold is able and surprisingly good at offering himself up for parody. And in a role that's sure to be annoying on paper, Austin O'Brien is actually kinda endearing as the kid sidekick. I really liked him here. And Charles Dance as Benedict . . . he's a terrific bad guy. In this type of movie, especially; great comedic timing, and just a pleasure to watch. He steals every one of his scenes. His lines are the funniest. "Last Action Hero" would definitely merit a higher rating if I didn't feel the need to turn it off with 45 minutes left to go. But when I think of this movie, it's that great first half that sticks in my brain. It should've performed better 20 years ago. The lousy reputation is (for the most part) undeserved, and it's a clear example of the kind of curious oddity that can result after many bad decisions made during the filmmaking process. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better the older you get
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dame Shumma
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grandiose, like Schwarzenegger takes the mickey out here himself, knows his last name wrong constantly and eventually called Arnold Braunschweiger. There are ongoing links to other movies, where, like in Die Hard. Danny makes Jack's attention to look up after a car accident even if the bad guy except death. In Die Hard, it was finally so that the blonde is hanged, and at the end is still alive. Grandiose, something is a feast for action lovers. The final rise to the film premiere of "Jack Slater IV" in New York. Schwarzenegger plays himself here, and is approached by his wife to make lasting advertising for Planet Hollywood. John Belushi announces Jack Slater movies so he does not like, and Van Damme, yes, even the Belgian martial arts goes to the premiere. Just plain funny. Slater is run by Danny corrected. Whenever he "I'll be back," says Danny knew beforehand that he will say that it is, after all, his trademark. Even the testing center for movies, the MPAA will not be left out. Danny writes a word, probably "fuck" on a piece of paper. Slater read it will not. Danny Comment: "You can not read it, because this movie is PG-13" Just wonderful. Who wants to keep checking back for once really look over a very successful action movie parody must. However, you should really have already seen some in the sector to understand everything. In order to find every hidden joke I have seen the movie a few times anyway. Well, anyway, the story is incidental and not the hammer. But is sufficient. I admit: Movie Review: 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A curious oddity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When young Danny Madigan (Austin O'Brien) is given a magic movie ticket by friendly cinema owner Nick (Robert Prosky) at an advance screening of new action movie Jack Slater IV, he is magically transported into the movie and into the car of supercop Jack Slater (Arnold Schwarzenegger). Danny starts to inform Slater about who the bad guys are after seeing them on screen, and the two are paired up as a mismatched investigative duo by Slater's screaming boss. Glass-eyed bad guy Mr. Benedict (Charles Dance) manages to get his hands on the magic ticket, and escapes into the real world, where he finds things are much easier for the bad guys. Slater must leave his action movie clich&eacute; of a world where he is nigh on invincible behind, and enter one where things are slightly more difficult. Last Action Hero had one of the most expensive and turbulent page-to- screen stories in recent cinema history. Originally written as a self- mocking action movie that embraced the clich&eacute;s of the genre, that was also a proper action movie in its own right. After an unexpected bidding war, the young scribes Zak Penn and Adam Leff were shocked to find that Arnold Schwarzenegger had taken a personal interest in it (the original hero name was Arno Slater). This was to be the turning point. Arnie saw the potential for a franchise as a kid's film and immediately wanted to tone down the violence, so Penn and Leff were fired, and genre legend Shane Black was hired to spruce up the script. Things changed yet again when director John McTiernan was brought in, and, due to the success of his previous films, was given full control. A few script re-writes, firings, and storm-outs later, the film was shot and ready to hit the market. A toy franchise and a ridiculously expensive and calamitous advertising campaign (they paid half a million dollars to have the film's name on a NASA rocket, only to have the launched delayed till long after the film's release) were put into motion, and the film's release date was announced for the week after Jurassic Park's. Last Action Hero had disastrous test screenings, but the release date was not changed, and naturally, Jurassic Park stormed the box-office and merchandising range, and Last Action Hero was revealed to be an over-ambitious, confused dud of a movie. However, the legend is rather cruel on Schwarzenegger's biggest flop, as although it is a gigantic mess, it has plenty of interesting ideas than are unfortunately spewed out onto the film in ungraceful belches. The biggest problem is that it doesn't know what kind of film it is. At its heart, its a kid's film, complete with annoying mop-haired child, a kindly old man, magic tickets and, um, a cartoon cat. Yet on its surface, its a rather uninspired action film that is actually rather violent and, once in the real world, is quite grim. The film never seems to know whether it wants to homage, spoof or simply in-joke. The movie world it creates is itself confused - while it has some funny touches such as the police line pairing together various mismatched partners - it also has women walking around in sexy, futuristic costumes, and the aforementioned cartoon cat called Whiskers (voiced by Danny DeVito). Seriously, whose idea was that? I've never seen a cartoon cat in a live- action action movie! However, the sheer mess that is the complete film does prove Last Action Hero to be a curious little oddity. There have been much finer examples of action-movie send-ups, namely in Shane Black's own excellent Kiss Kiss Bang Bang (2005), so perhaps the producers weren't ready back in 1993 to take on such an ambitious project. Arnie is pleasantly game for sending himself up, and Charles Dance chews the screen with his gloriously hammy British bad guy. But Last Action Hero will ultimately always be a reminder of how the Hollywood system to suck up an interesting maverick project, f**k it over a few times, and bundle it over the finishing line with such unbelievable inefficiency. I did love it as a kid, however. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
