<filme>
 <id>
  397
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0108238
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Zona de Perigo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Coming from a police family, Tom Hardy ends up fighting his uncle after the murder of his father. Tom believes the killer is another cop, and goes on the record with his allegations. Demoted then to river duty, the killer taunts Tom.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A serial killer is back in Pittsburgh to torment the former homicide detective who was on his trail years before. Tom Hardy, who has been relegated to water-way duty, along with new partner Jo Christman, navigate the three rivers looking for clues and discovering bodies. This time the victims are women Tom knows, he must find the killer to prove his innocence.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   river
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   serial killer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   chase
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   river rescue
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Rowdy Herrington
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Rowdy Herrington
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Marty Kaplan
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Bruce Willis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sarah Jessica Parker
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dennis Farina
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG this has to be the most horrible movie in history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glennataylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would rather watch reruns of the Smother's brothers. This movie is beyond pathetic. SJP is hideous, i wouldn't sleep with her for $5000. I actually met Demi and her mother during the filming of this movie, I served her lunch. They were both beautiful and delightful. If this (SJP) bitch could be more annoying and ugly it would be difficult, I would rather sleep with Oprah. Hideous, ugly, nasty, no-talent Pig.Behind that is the bad, really bad acting of the rest of the 'cast". No plot, bad acting, predictable scenes, it's like Woody Allen decided to make another bad movie that wasn't "supposed" to be funny. It is so contrived and horrid it's ridiculous, I want to vomit when i SEE HER. If I could break her face with a hammer I would be the happiest man on Earth. She can't act, she is ugly, she is pathetic. F>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>> I hate her guts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder and revenge on the waters, in a high octane thriller that strikes back
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like John Q, Striking Distance is another film, that leaves me in an enigma, of how panned it was. This is just as good as a lot of other Willis actioners. Most of Willis's films I like, and this is no exception. It's really a very well plotted revenge thriller, with a great car chase, I might add, which left this flick playing over a couple of months in Adelaide. I like the family angle to it. Willis like his father, (John Mahoney, before Frasier, and years after Code Of Silence, which he made a brief appearance in) is a Pittsburgh cop. So is his Uncle (Dennis Farina) and his two other sons, one of them who's on trial for battery, where Willis gone up against him, telling the court the real version, much to the bitter dislike of his fellow officers. Like Willis's character, Tom Hardy, (catchy) says "Look where telling the truth's got me". Sadly at the end of the chase, things went awry, where Mahoney is executed. There's a bigger picture to this story, and I'm not gonna spoil it for ya. Soon after, Farina's bad cop son, where things are not looking to good for him, threatens to jump off the bridge saying "Cops don't go to prison. I'm not going". Well, bad cops do. Well, he jumps. His body's never recovered. Cut to a couple of years later, disgraced cop, Willis, now drowning his sorrows in alcohol, and making the best of his stinking situation, now works as a river cop. Everything's just dandy. He lives on a houseboat, has a cat, even gets a surprise visit later from Farina's other out of control, boozing son, now ex cop, (Tom Sizemore, quite impressive here) who like the other cops, initially had it in for Hardy too. Things are looking up when he's partnered with Jo, new to the job. But now things are about to become a living hell, where for Hardy, his haunted past returns, though he's always been haunted, since those tragic events years prior. A score of dead young women, start surfacing on the river waters, all of who have been sexually involved with Willis. He's convinced this is the work of the same killer, responsible for his father's execution. So here's a great thriller ride for you. Too, as an added treat, we have an unrelated action scene on a houseboat, where some hijackers have taken it over, so it's good ol Bruce to the rescue. Too near the end, in it's horrifying revelation, where the killer comes into light, we really learn about family and loyalty, where again to finish the killer off, a cattle crod is used, that instantly had me remembering that scene in The Last Boy Scout. And like the end of Cobra, Willis gets to punch out the loud mouthed cop. See, this film has everything, including a bit of romance and a nice after ending. For Willis fans, specially. Check out the classic opening with the remote control car, cool like the rest of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance-Strike **** for this Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We could literally call this excellent thriller ALL IN THE FAMILY as it deals with a family of police caught up in a series of serial killings that eventually takes the life of the father of Bruce Willis. Scorned by police when he turns his own cousin in on an unrelated police matter, and his persistence that the man found guilty of the crime is innocent and that the real killer is none other than a police officer. The plot twists are great and there is plenty of action. Bruce Willis has the perfect part for himself and he is aided by Sarah Jessica Palmer, who has another assigned agenda on her part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full of holes, clich&eacute;s, emoting, but a decent car chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    plex
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see Bruce Willis develop his 2-dimensional acting "chops" in this, one of his earliest action flicks. He basically has 3 emotions: the overly subdued "I'm to cool to care" tone, the aloof/smug tone, and the yelling tone. The facial contortions he exhibits when he shoots a gun is so ham and often repeated throughout his career. ( Don't get me wrong, some of his films, if not his work, I am very fond of). You either love Sarah J, Parker or not. But it strikes me odd that she has been in SO many love scenes and starred in the Sex & The City shows and movies, yet she obviously takes herself too serious as their must be a no-nip clause in all of her contracts. I guess whats good enough for serious actresses like Helen Mirren, Susan Sarandon, Kate Winslet, and Julianne Moore isn't good enough for her. The film: This is a 19 year old movie, so I am going to assume the plot has been well covered here. But I couldn't get passed a couple of things: Great opening car chase scene, highly frenetic, however father and son are having a completely sedate personal conversation. Its one thing to be in control of your emotions, its another being inhuman. So they get in this rolling car crash, its the middle of the day and apparently they all just sat there for hours and hours because its dark when the other cops ( some involved in the pursuit) arrive at the scene. Second big thing, you have our villain, a cop. He's on the bridge for the longest time. All of his relatives are cops, his dad is a cop. There's is the omnipotent river patrol, who our protagonist joins later in the film. Yet, when the villain jumps in, the river patrol cant immediately find him? After all, all of the other dead bodies are found, and apparently the river is pretty clean ( of course not) because we see night-time underwater sequences. Wouldn't they want his body recovered? They certainly had the resources. Minor things: Why was the guy who dumped a throw-rug so anxious to risk life&limb and his car ( which explodes) over it? Was this our villain? Never explained. The worst things for me had to be Sarah's mushy court-room testimony, and Brion James ( who I like in other films) who is so over-the-top angry about everything its just plain humorous, or his diatribe in the end when he eats crow and ego strokes Bruce. Really cheesy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Land shark.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hardy is a fifth-generation cop. When his father dies during the chase of a serial killer, Hardy further complicates matters by implicating his partner and cousin Jimmy in a police brutality case. Two years after Jimmy is believed to have committed suicide, women from Hardy's past start to turn up dead, and his father's alleged killer is found. Believing that the alleged killer is a patsy, Hardy conducts his own illegal investigation into his father's own death, and the women's deaths as well. Hardy and the killer ultimately lock horns in a showdown that ties all the loose ends on both case. It's pretty formulaic stuff for Willis, during the time I like to refer to as his 'chubby era'. He had a pretty bad run of films between 93 to 95, and was finally broke by DHWAV in the summer of 95. It's fun stuff though while it lasts, Cop turns alcoholic, argues a lot with Farina and James, and the killer turns up at the end, but isn't surprising as his name is pretty high up on the credits at the beginning. Parker is fine, but if her character was cut out of the story, it wouldn't damage the narrative. If your a Willis fine, it's a good movie with no surprises.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard the title and who starred in somewhere, I am pretty sure it was from seeing the DVD cover, I guess I watched it just to see some reasonable action fun with the two lead stars I knew. Basically Det. Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) comes from a generation of cops, and he is devastated when his father Vince (John Mahoney) dies during the chase of a serial killer, and after he gets himself in an argument with his partner and cousin Det. Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli). Two years later Tom is working as part of the river rescue police, but is pulled back into action with new partner Jo Christman (Sarah Jessica Parker) when possibly the same killer, nicknamed the Polish Hill strangler, is on the loose again. The victims seem to be women that Tom knew, making him a prime suspect, and no-one apart from maybe Jo believes it is the same killer from the past, and he will have to find the right clues to prove his innocence. Keeping an eye on him is Capt. Nick Detillo (Dennis Farina), an acquaintance from two years ago, and Tom and Jo and do come across some small clues, it is obvious that they are slowly falling for each other. Eventually when trapped, Tom finally gets the truth from Nick, that Jimmy was the killer, he has been copycatting the crimes, and he was the one who killed his father, but in the end of course the guilty are caught and the good guys go back to the better life. Also starring Tom Sizemore as Det. Danny Detillo, Brion James as Det. Eddie Eiler, Timothy Busfield as Tony Sacco and Poseidon's Andre Braugher as Dist. Atty. Frank Morris. The acting was a little flat in parts, and they could have been a few more explosive and gun filled chase and action sequences, I will admit as well I didn't exactly pay the fullest attention while watching, but I guess as a cop looking for a serial killer story is is okay, an alright crime thriller. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The killer was caught or was he?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A homicide detective tracking a serial killer alienates himself from his fellow officers when he suggests that this killer who also killed his father/police Ltd in a high speed car chase may be one of their own men. He gets demoted to the harbour patrol, but still his obsession grows to prove that it was an officer that murdered his father and the girls. A very presentable, slick cop after serial killer thriller with a dependable cast (Bruce Willis, Sarah Jessica Parker, Denis Farina, Brion James, Tom Sizemore and Robert Pastorelli) and interesting backdrop (the beat isn't the streets, but a river system) despite the same old-same, same-old plotting with stock clich&eacute;s and some very implausible revelations. Yes it does go over-the-top for its outlandish climax, but its always exciting, eccentric and high-octane in its routine action and this can said about Brad Fiedel's scorching music too. The opening car chase sequence is actually quite well done by director Rowdy Herrington (who does a durable job throughout with the tough thrills and humid dramas), the taut script keeps it suspenseful and before the killer murders the girl/s he plays the seductively catchy tune Li'l Red Riding Hood by Sam the Sham and the Pharaohs. Willis provides your usual gruff, maverick cop who likes to get on the bottle (because of past events that sees him not a favourite of the men in blue) and Parker sexes-it up as his greenhorn partner. James is great in the role as the smarmy detective always looking to pick a fight with Willis' character and Farina is solid as usual. Also showing up in small parts are Tom Atkins and John Mahoney. Mindless early 90s action fun. "I used to be a homicide detective. I lost my shield because I said a cop killed my father"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loyalty above all else, except Honour. | V.Good Thriller |
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gashmanflirty@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just what you expect from Bruce Willis in that decade. He plays the character of drunken failure but always comes out on the good side.I enjoyed it from start to finish. V.good thriller of the 90's with good character personalities working off each other/ j. Parker gave it the romance feel and it worked well. The film itself had v.good action sequences and the length of the film was probably just about right. The consistent negative feeling towards Hardy throughput the film from other cops adds to effort that he has to put in to prove he is right and gain vindication. This struggle allows the film to develop its journey. Thanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I quite liked it, not a classic but entertaining enough.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Striking Distance is set in Pittsburgh where Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) has just had to testify against his partner & cousin Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli), on his way to a policeman's ball with his father Vincent (John Mahoney) they get a call to say that a wanted murderer is being pursued. The two Hardy's decide to help out & give chase but end up crashing their car, when Tom regains consciousness he finds the murder suspect gone & his father dead. Two years later & Tom has been forced to take a job as a river patrol man as he has become an alcoholic loser, suddenly dead bodies begin to be found in the rivers around Pittsburgh that Tom patrol. Tom is convinced the killer is back but discovers that officially the new murders have no connection to the earlier ones, Tom is sure that a big cover-up is going on & that the killer is targeting him personally... Written & directed by Rowdy Herrington there doesn't seem to be much love for this much maligned action thriller with even star Bruce Willis saying 'it sucked' while on a chat-show in 2004, hey Bruce I have news for you Striking Distance is nowhere near the worst film you have appeared in. Hudson Hawk (1991), Color of Night (1994) & Cop Out (2010) anyone? Anyway, Striking Distance was known under the title Three Rivers during production & is a decent enough action thriller. One suspects that maybe Willis was trying to star in another Die Hard (1988) but his character here is much less likable or quotable. The script is nothing more than a string of cop film clich&eacute;s stringed together around a fairly basic murder mystery plot & every so often there's a big action set-piece. As it is I quite liked Striking Distance, there are a few decent one-liners, the character's although clich&eacute;d are given life by a good cast or pro's & there's enough action here to satisfy most. There's a particularly good car chase at the start. As I said the clich&eacute;s come thick & fast, a disgraced alcoholic cop, a cover-up, a killer who taunts the cops, feelings of guilt & remorse & loss, honour & family connections. At just under 100 minutes maybe it's a little long but there's enough going on to keep ones interest even if the murder mystery may be a little easy to figure out & a bit too improbable to take seriously. Also the ending features a little overkill when it comes to the villain dying as he comes back from apparently being dead at least four times in ten minutes! There are some good action set-pieces here including a great car chase with one of my personal favourite moments from any chase from any film when the cars start jumping over those humps & shoot up in the air one behind the other. There are boat chases, shoot-outs, fights & a bit of suspense as a mystery killer stalks & kills a few people too. Nicely enough shot there's not much style here but it looks alright. With a supposed budget of about $30,000,000 this has the usual glossy Hollywood production values & is well made. There's a very good cast here including Bruce Willis, Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James & Tom Atkins with the only weak link the ever awful Sarah Jessica Parker in an early role. Striking Distance is a pretty good action thriller, it has a reasonable murder mystery, some clich&eacute;d cop drama & some good action scenes. It's certainly no worse than a lot of routine Hollywood action thrillers, you could do a lot worse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific mystery action thriller with the man himself in the lead role...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I often start Bruce Willis reviews with a disclaimer...I LOVE Bruce Willis. He can rarely do wrong with the exception of most the 2000's (small joke.) Striking Distance was solidly into his leading man career that made him an action superstar. Striking Distance didn't appear to have the enormous budget of like minded Willis vehicles (30 million vs 70 million for Die Hard 2, 3 years earlier) but that is part of its charm. Striking Distance is part mystery, part thriller, a dash of action, and some great character depth even if the lead character is a little bit predictable as a washed up, alcoholic, traumatically scarred former cop. Willis plays the broody alcoholic like nobodies business. The mystery is solid, and the action scenes are well done. It even features one of the best and most underplayed car/boat chase scenes in action film history...or at least the nineties. A terrific supporting cast of whose who nineties character actors help move the story along and support Willis throughout. Sometimes movie watchers like mystery, dislike action, or some variation of such but Striking Distance gives a little of all of the major genres to make it the perfect film for just pure entertainment. Bruce Willis is the iconic macho man. I could watch him do just about anything. As the aforementioned brooding former cop spending his days as barely more than a security guard on the waters. The character is not revolutionary and can be considered predictable but Willis makes Tom Hardy the best he can possibly be and that's a bad ass good guy. Remember Sarah Jessica Parker before she was Sex and The City's Carrie Bradshaw? Me neither but she is cute and vivacious as fellow boat cop Jo Christman. The character doesn't truly fit into the dreary, dark and often foreboding setting but somehow Parker impressively makes it work. Equally impressive is the fact that Parker and Willis do have decent chemistry and their romance somehow works although it feels forced into the story at times. The whose who supporting cast I mentioned include talented character actors, and TV actors. The most noteworthy are Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James, Robert Pastorelli (really terrific), and John Mahoney (small role but really terrific as Willis' decorated cop father.) Director Rowdy Herrington isn't big in Hollywood but he can be attributed to helming the 80's classic Roadhouse and now Striking Distance. Given his ability to direct two big leading men and let them be what the audiences love should account for something. I have a feeling though Herrington's directing ability ends there. Given something without a leading man probably wouldn't account for much although I haven't seen any of his other work. Striking Distance is just plainly entertaining. It isn't mind blowing and it isn't likely to be most peoples favorite film but it is one that I frequently go back to on a lazy Sunday afternoon for some simple, well made entertainment. It also isn't necessarily considering one of Willis' big films by any means but at the same time is gem amongst his work from the nineties. Definitely worth watching at least once and you'll find its charm beneath the surface. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG this has to be the most horrible movie in history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glennataylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would rather watch reruns of the Smother's brothers. This movie is beyond pathetic. SJP is hideous, i wouldn't sleep with her for $5000. I actually met Demi and her mother during the filming of this movie, I served her lunch. They were both beautiful and delightful. If this (SJP) bitch could be more annoying and ugly it would be difficult, I would rather sleep with Oprah. Hideous, ugly, nasty, no-talent Pig.Behind that is the bad, really bad acting of the rest of the 'cast". No plot, bad acting, predictable scenes, it's like Woody Allen decided to make another bad movie that wasn't "supposed" to be funny. It is so contrived and horrid it's ridiculous, I want to vomit when i SEE HER. If I could break her face with a hammer I would be the happiest man on Earth. She can't act, she is ugly, she is pathetic. F>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>> I hate her guts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder and revenge on the waters, in a high octane thriller that strikes back
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like John Q, Striking Distance is another film, that leaves me in an enigma, of how panned it was. This is just as good as a lot of other Willis actioners. Most of Willis's films I like, and this is no exception. It's really a very well plotted revenge thriller, with a great car chase, I might add, which left this flick playing over a couple of months in Adelaide. I like the family angle to it. Willis like his father, (John Mahoney, before Frasier, and years after Code Of Silence, which he made a brief appearance in) is a Pittsburgh cop. So is his Uncle (Dennis Farina) and his two other sons, one of them who's on trial for battery, where Willis gone up against him, telling the court the real version, much to the bitter dislike of his fellow officers. Like Willis's character, Tom Hardy, (catchy) says "Look where telling the truth's got me". Sadly at the end of the chase, things went awry, where Mahoney is executed. There's a bigger picture to this story, and I'm not gonna spoil it for ya. Soon after, Farina's bad cop son, where things are not looking to good for him, threatens to jump off the bridge saying "Cops don't go to prison. I'm not going". Well, bad cops do. Well, he jumps. His body's never recovered. Cut to a couple of years later, disgraced cop, Willis, now drowning his sorrows in alcohol, and making the best of his stinking situation, now works as a river cop. Everything's just dandy. He lives on a houseboat, has a cat, even gets a surprise visit later from Farina's other out of control, boozing son, now ex cop, (Tom Sizemore, quite impressive here) who like the other cops, initially had it in for Hardy too. Things are looking up when he's partnered with Jo, new to the job. But now things are about to become a living hell, where for Hardy, his haunted past returns, though he's always been haunted, since those tragic events years prior. A score of dead young women, start surfacing on the river waters, all of who have been sexually involved with Willis. He's convinced this is the work of the same killer, responsible for his father's execution. So here's a great thriller ride for you. Too, as an added treat, we have an unrelated action scene on a houseboat, where some hijackers have taken it over, so it's good ol Bruce to the rescue. Too near the end, in it's horrifying revelation, where the killer comes into light, we really learn about family and loyalty, where again to finish the killer off, a cattle crod is used, that instantly had me remembering that scene in The Last Boy Scout. And like the end of Cobra, Willis gets to punch out the loud mouthed cop. See, this film has everything, including a bit of romance and a nice after ending. For Willis fans, specially. Check out the classic opening with the remote control car, cool like the rest of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance-Strike **** for this Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We could literally call this excellent thriller ALL IN THE FAMILY as it deals with a family of police caught up in a series of serial killings that eventually takes the life of the father of Bruce Willis. Scorned by police when he turns his own cousin in on an unrelated police matter, and his persistence that the man found guilty of the crime is innocent and that the real killer is none other than a police officer. The plot twists are great and there is plenty of action. Bruce Willis has the perfect part for himself and he is aided by Sarah Jessica Palmer, who has another assigned agenda on her part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full of holes, clich&eacute;s, emoting, but a decent car chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    plex
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see Bruce Willis develop his 2-dimensional acting "chops" in this, one of his earliest action flicks. He basically has 3 emotions: the overly subdued "I'm to cool to care" tone, the aloof/smug tone, and the yelling tone. The facial contortions he exhibits when he shoots a gun is so ham and often repeated throughout his career. ( Don't get me wrong, some of his films, if not his work, I am very fond of). You either love Sarah J, Parker or not. But it strikes me odd that she has been in SO many love scenes and starred in the Sex & The City shows and movies, yet she obviously takes herself too serious as their must be a no-nip clause in all of her contracts. I guess whats good enough for serious actresses like Helen Mirren, Susan Sarandon, Kate Winslet, and Julianne Moore isn't good enough for her. The film: This is a 19 year old movie, so I am going to assume the plot has been well covered here. But I couldn't get passed a couple of things: Great opening car chase scene, highly frenetic, however father and son are having a completely sedate personal conversation. Its one thing to be in control of your emotions, its another being inhuman. So they get in this rolling car crash, its the middle of the day and apparently they all just sat there for hours and hours because its dark when the other cops ( some involved in the pursuit) arrive at the scene. Second big thing, you have our villain, a cop. He's on the bridge for the longest time. All of his relatives are cops, his dad is a cop. There's is the omnipotent river patrol, who our protagonist joins later in the film. Yet, when the villain jumps in, the river patrol cant immediately find him? After all, all of the other dead bodies are found, and apparently the river is pretty clean ( of course not) because we see night-time underwater sequences. Wouldn't they want his body recovered? They certainly had the resources. Minor things: Why was the guy who dumped a throw-rug so anxious to risk life&limb and his car ( which explodes) over it? Was this our villain? Never explained. The worst things for me had to be Sarah's mushy court-room testimony, and Brion James ( who I like in other films) who is so over-the-top angry about everything its just plain humorous, or his diatribe in the end when he eats crow and ego strokes Bruce. Really cheesy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Land shark.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hardy is a fifth-generation cop. When his father dies during the chase of a serial killer, Hardy further complicates matters by implicating his partner and cousin Jimmy in a police brutality case. Two years after Jimmy is believed to have committed suicide, women from Hardy's past start to turn up dead, and his father's alleged killer is found. Believing that the alleged killer is a patsy, Hardy conducts his own illegal investigation into his father's own death, and the women's deaths as well. Hardy and the killer ultimately lock horns in a showdown that ties all the loose ends on both case. It's pretty formulaic stuff for Willis, during the time I like to refer to as his 'chubby era'. He had a pretty bad run of films between 93 to 95, and was finally broke by DHWAV in the summer of 95. It's fun stuff though while it lasts, Cop turns alcoholic, argues a lot with Farina and James, and the killer turns up at the end, but isn't surprising as his name is pretty high up on the credits at the beginning. Parker is fine, but if her character was cut out of the story, it wouldn't damage the narrative. If your a Willis fine, it's a good movie with no surprises.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard the title and who starred in somewhere, I am pretty sure it was from seeing the DVD cover, I guess I watched it just to see some reasonable action fun with the two lead stars I knew. Basically Det. Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) comes from a generation of cops, and he is devastated when his father Vince (John Mahoney) dies during the chase of a serial killer, and after he gets himself in an argument with his partner and cousin Det. Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli). Two years later Tom is working as part of the river rescue police, but is pulled back into action with new partner Jo Christman (Sarah Jessica Parker) when possibly the same killer, nicknamed the Polish Hill strangler, is on the loose again. The victims seem to be women that Tom knew, making him a prime suspect, and no-one apart from maybe Jo believes it is the same killer from the past, and he will have to find the right clues to prove his innocence. Keeping an eye on him is Capt. Nick Detillo (Dennis Farina), an acquaintance from two years ago, and Tom and Jo and do come across some small clues, it is obvious that they are slowly falling for each other. Eventually when trapped, Tom finally gets the truth from Nick, that Jimmy was the killer, he has been copycatting the crimes, and he was the one who killed his father, but in the end of course the guilty are caught and the good guys go back to the better life. Also starring Tom Sizemore as Det. Danny Detillo, Brion James as Det. Eddie Eiler, Timothy Busfield as Tony Sacco and Poseidon's Andre Braugher as Dist. Atty. Frank Morris. The acting was a little flat in parts, and they could have been a few more explosive and gun filled chase and action sequences, I will admit as well I didn't exactly pay the fullest attention while watching, but I guess as a cop looking for a serial killer story is is okay, an alright crime thriller. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The killer was caught or was he?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A homicide detective tracking a serial killer alienates himself from his fellow officers when he suggests that this killer who also killed his father/police Ltd in a high speed car chase may be one of their own men. He gets demoted to the harbour patrol, but still his obsession grows to prove that it was an officer that murdered his father and the girls. A very presentable, slick cop after serial killer thriller with a dependable cast (Bruce Willis, Sarah Jessica Parker, Denis Farina, Brion James, Tom Sizemore and Robert Pastorelli) and interesting backdrop (the beat isn't the streets, but a river system) despite the same old-same, same-old plotting with stock clich&eacute;s and some very implausible revelations. Yes it does go over-the-top for its outlandish climax, but its always exciting, eccentric and high-octane in its routine action and this can said about Brad Fiedel's scorching music too. The opening car chase sequence is actually quite well done by director Rowdy Herrington (who does a durable job throughout with the tough thrills and humid dramas), the taut script keeps it suspenseful and before the killer murders the girl/s he plays the seductively catchy tune Li'l Red Riding Hood by Sam the Sham and the Pharaohs. Willis provides your usual gruff, maverick cop who likes to get on the bottle (because of past events that sees him not a favourite of the men in blue) and Parker sexes-it up as his greenhorn partner. James is great in the role as the smarmy detective always looking to pick a fight with Willis' character and Farina is solid as usual. Also showing up in small parts are Tom Atkins and John Mahoney. Mindless early 90s action fun. "I used to be a homicide detective. I lost my shield because I said a cop killed my father"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loyalty above all else, except Honour. | V.Good Thriller |
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gashmanflirty@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just what you expect from Bruce Willis in that decade. He plays the character of drunken failure but always comes out on the good side.I enjoyed it from start to finish. V.good thriller of the 90's with good character personalities working off each other/ j. Parker gave it the romance feel and it worked well. The film itself had v.good action sequences and the length of the film was probably just about right. The consistent negative feeling towards Hardy throughput the film from other cops adds to effort that he has to put in to prove he is right and gain vindication. This struggle allows the film to develop its journey. Thanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I quite liked it, not a classic but entertaining enough.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Striking Distance is set in Pittsburgh where Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) has just had to testify against his partner & cousin Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli), on his way to a policeman's ball with his father Vincent (John Mahoney) they get a call to say that a wanted murderer is being pursued. The two Hardy's decide to help out & give chase but end up crashing their car, when Tom regains consciousness he finds the murder suspect gone & his father dead. Two years later & Tom has been forced to take a job as a river patrol man as he has become an alcoholic loser, suddenly dead bodies begin to be found in the rivers around Pittsburgh that Tom patrol. Tom is convinced the killer is back but discovers that officially the new murders have no connection to the earlier ones, Tom is sure that a big cover-up is going on & that the killer is targeting him personally... Written & directed by Rowdy Herrington there doesn't seem to be much love for this much maligned action thriller with even star Bruce Willis saying 'it sucked' while on a chat-show in 2004, hey Bruce I have news for you Striking Distance is nowhere near the worst film you have appeared in. Hudson Hawk (1991), Color of Night (1994) & Cop Out (2010) anyone? Anyway, Striking Distance was known under the title Three Rivers during production & is a decent enough action thriller. One suspects that maybe Willis was trying to star in another Die Hard (1988) but his character here is much less likable or quotable. The script is nothing more than a string of cop film clich&eacute;s stringed together around a fairly basic murder mystery plot & every so often there's a big action set-piece. As it is I quite liked Striking Distance, there are a few decent one-liners, the character's although clich&eacute;d are given life by a good cast or pro's & there's enough action here to satisfy most. There's a particularly good car chase at the start. As I said the clich&eacute;s come thick & fast, a disgraced alcoholic cop, a cover-up, a killer who taunts the cops, feelings of guilt & remorse & loss, honour & family connections. At just under 100 minutes maybe it's a little long but there's enough going on to keep ones interest even if the murder mystery may be a little easy to figure out & a bit too improbable to take seriously. Also the ending features a little overkill when it comes to the villain dying as he comes back from apparently being dead at least four times in ten minutes! There are some good action set-pieces here including a great car chase with one of my personal favourite moments from any chase from any film when the cars start jumping over those humps & shoot up in the air one behind the other. There are boat chases, shoot-outs, fights & a bit of suspense as a mystery killer stalks & kills a few people too. Nicely enough shot there's not much style here but it looks alright. With a supposed budget of about $30,000,000 this has the usual glossy Hollywood production values & is well made. There's a very good cast here including Bruce Willis, Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James & Tom Atkins with the only weak link the ever awful Sarah Jessica Parker in an early role. Striking Distance is a pretty good action thriller, it has a reasonable murder mystery, some clich&eacute;d cop drama & some good action scenes. It's certainly no worse than a lot of routine Hollywood action thrillers, you could do a lot worse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific mystery action thriller with the man himself in the lead role...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I often start Bruce Willis reviews with a disclaimer...I LOVE Bruce Willis. He can rarely do wrong with the exception of most the 2000's (small joke.) Striking Distance was solidly into his leading man career that made him an action superstar. Striking Distance didn't appear to have the enormous budget of like minded Willis vehicles (30 million vs 70 million for Die Hard 2, 3 years earlier) but that is part of its charm. Striking Distance is part mystery, part thriller, a dash of action, and some great character depth even if the lead character is a little bit predictable as a washed up, alcoholic, traumatically scarred former cop. Willis plays the broody alcoholic like nobodies business. The mystery is solid, and the action scenes are well done. It even features one of the best and most underplayed car/boat chase scenes in action film history...or at least the nineties. A terrific supporting cast of whose who nineties character actors help move the story along and support Willis throughout. Sometimes movie watchers like mystery, dislike action, or some variation of such but Striking Distance gives a little of all of the major genres to make it the perfect film for just pure entertainment. Bruce Willis is the iconic macho man. I could watch him do just about anything. As the aforementioned brooding former cop spending his days as barely more than a security guard on the waters. The character is not revolutionary and can be considered predictable but Willis makes Tom Hardy the best he can possibly be and that's a bad ass good guy. Remember Sarah Jessica Parker before she was Sex and The City's Carrie Bradshaw? Me neither but she is cute and vivacious as fellow boat cop Jo Christman. The character doesn't truly fit into the dreary, dark and often foreboding setting but somehow Parker impressively makes it work. Equally impressive is the fact that Parker and Willis do have decent chemistry and their romance somehow works although it feels forced into the story at times. The whose who supporting cast I mentioned include talented character actors, and TV actors. The most noteworthy are Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James, Robert Pastorelli (really terrific), and John Mahoney (small role but really terrific as Willis' decorated cop father.) Director Rowdy Herrington isn't big in Hollywood but he can be attributed to helming the 80's classic Roadhouse and now Striking Distance. Given his ability to direct two big leading men and let them be what the audiences love should account for something. I have a feeling though Herrington's directing ability ends there. Given something without a leading man probably wouldn't account for much although I haven't seen any of his other work. Striking Distance is just plainly entertaining. It isn't mind blowing and it isn't likely to be most peoples favorite film but it is one that I frequently go back to on a lazy Sunday afternoon for some simple, well made entertainment. It also isn't necessarily considering one of Willis' big films by any means but at the same time is gem amongst his work from the nineties. Definitely worth watching at least once and you'll find its charm beneath the surface. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG this has to be the most horrible movie in history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glennataylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would rather watch reruns of the Smother's brothers. This movie is beyond pathetic. SJP is hideous, i wouldn't sleep with her for $5000. I actually met Demi and her mother during the filming of this movie, I served her lunch. They were both beautiful and delightful. If this (SJP) bitch could be more annoying and ugly it would be difficult, I would rather sleep with Oprah. Hideous, ugly, nasty, no-talent Pig.Behind that is the bad, really bad acting of the rest of the 'cast". No plot, bad acting, predictable scenes, it's like Woody Allen decided to make another bad movie that wasn't "supposed" to be funny. It is so contrived and horrid it's ridiculous, I want to vomit when i SEE HER. If I could break her face with a hammer I would be the happiest man on Earth. She can't act, she is ugly, she is pathetic. F>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>> I hate her guts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder and revenge on the waters, in a high octane thriller that strikes back
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like John Q, Striking Distance is another film, that leaves me in an enigma, of how panned it was. This is just as good as a lot of other Willis actioners. Most of Willis's films I like, and this is no exception. It's really a very well plotted revenge thriller, with a great car chase, I might add, which left this flick playing over a couple of months in Adelaide. I like the family angle to it. Willis like his father, (John Mahoney, before Frasier, and years after Code Of Silence, which he made a brief appearance in) is a Pittsburgh cop. So is his Uncle (Dennis Farina) and his two other sons, one of them who's on trial for battery, where Willis gone up against him, telling the court the real version, much to the bitter dislike of his fellow officers. Like Willis's character, Tom Hardy, (catchy) says "Look where telling the truth's got me". Sadly at the end of the chase, things went awry, where Mahoney is executed. There's a bigger picture to this story, and I'm not gonna spoil it for ya. Soon after, Farina's bad cop son, where things are not looking to good for him, threatens to jump off the bridge saying "Cops don't go to prison. I'm not going". Well, bad cops do. Well, he jumps. His body's never recovered. Cut to a couple of years later, disgraced cop, Willis, now drowning his sorrows in alcohol, and making the best of his stinking situation, now works as a river cop. Everything's just dandy. He lives on a houseboat, has a cat, even gets a surprise visit later from Farina's other out of control, boozing son, now ex cop, (Tom Sizemore, quite impressive here) who like the other cops, initially had it in for Hardy too. Things are looking up when he's partnered with Jo, new to the job. But now things are about to become a living hell, where for Hardy, his haunted past returns, though he's always been haunted, since those tragic events years prior. A score of dead young women, start surfacing on the river waters, all of who have been sexually involved with Willis. He's convinced this is the work of the same killer, responsible for his father's execution. So here's a great thriller ride for you. Too, as an added treat, we have an unrelated action scene on a houseboat, where some hijackers have taken it over, so it's good ol Bruce to the rescue. Too near the end, in it's horrifying revelation, where the killer comes into light, we really learn about family and loyalty, where again to finish the killer off, a cattle crod is used, that instantly had me remembering that scene in The Last Boy Scout. And like the end of Cobra, Willis gets to punch out the loud mouthed cop. See, this film has everything, including a bit of romance and a nice after ending. For Willis fans, specially. Check out the classic opening with the remote control car, cool like the rest of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance-Strike **** for this Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We could literally call this excellent thriller ALL IN THE FAMILY as it deals with a family of police caught up in a series of serial killings that eventually takes the life of the father of Bruce Willis. Scorned by police when he turns his own cousin in on an unrelated police matter, and his persistence that the man found guilty of the crime is innocent and that the real killer is none other than a police officer. The plot twists are great and there is plenty of action. Bruce Willis has the perfect part for himself and he is aided by Sarah Jessica Palmer, who has another assigned agenda on her part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full of holes, clich&eacute;s, emoting, but a decent car chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    plex
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see Bruce Willis develop his 2-dimensional acting "chops" in this, one of his earliest action flicks. He basically has 3 emotions: the overly subdued "I'm to cool to care" tone, the aloof/smug tone, and the yelling tone. The facial contortions he exhibits when he shoots a gun is so ham and often repeated throughout his career. ( Don't get me wrong, some of his films, if not his work, I am very fond of). You either love Sarah J, Parker or not. But it strikes me odd that she has been in SO many love scenes and starred in the Sex & The City shows and movies, yet she obviously takes herself too serious as their must be a no-nip clause in all of her contracts. I guess whats good enough for serious actresses like Helen Mirren, Susan Sarandon, Kate Winslet, and Julianne Moore isn't good enough for her. The film: This is a 19 year old movie, so I am going to assume the plot has been well covered here. But I couldn't get passed a couple of things: Great opening car chase scene, highly frenetic, however father and son are having a completely sedate personal conversation. Its one thing to be in control of your emotions, its another being inhuman. So they get in this rolling car crash, its the middle of the day and apparently they all just sat there for hours and hours because its dark when the other cops ( some involved in the pursuit) arrive at the scene. Second big thing, you have our villain, a cop. He's on the bridge for the longest time. All of his relatives are cops, his dad is a cop. There's is the omnipotent river patrol, who our protagonist joins later in the film. Yet, when the villain jumps in, the river patrol cant immediately find him? After all, all of the other dead bodies are found, and apparently the river is pretty clean ( of course not) because we see night-time underwater sequences. Wouldn't they want his body recovered? They certainly had the resources. Minor things: Why was the guy who dumped a throw-rug so anxious to risk life&limb and his car ( which explodes) over it? Was this our villain? Never explained. The worst things for me had to be Sarah's mushy court-room testimony, and Brion James ( who I like in other films) who is so over-the-top angry about everything its just plain humorous, or his diatribe in the end when he eats crow and ego strokes Bruce. Really cheesy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Land shark.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hardy is a fifth-generation cop. When his father dies during the chase of a serial killer, Hardy further complicates matters by implicating his partner and cousin Jimmy in a police brutality case. Two years after Jimmy is believed to have committed suicide, women from Hardy's past start to turn up dead, and his father's alleged killer is found. Believing that the alleged killer is a patsy, Hardy conducts his own illegal investigation into his father's own death, and the women's deaths as well. Hardy and the killer ultimately lock horns in a showdown that ties all the loose ends on both case. It's pretty formulaic stuff for Willis, during the time I like to refer to as his 'chubby era'. He had a pretty bad run of films between 93 to 95, and was finally broke by DHWAV in the summer of 95. It's fun stuff though while it lasts, Cop turns alcoholic, argues a lot with Farina and James, and the killer turns up at the end, but isn't surprising as his name is pretty high up on the credits at the beginning. Parker is fine, but if her character was cut out of the story, it wouldn't damage the narrative. If your a Willis fine, it's a good movie with no surprises.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard the title and who starred in somewhere, I am pretty sure it was from seeing the DVD cover, I guess I watched it just to see some reasonable action fun with the two lead stars I knew. Basically Det. Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) comes from a generation of cops, and he is devastated when his father Vince (John Mahoney) dies during the chase of a serial killer, and after he gets himself in an argument with his partner and cousin Det. Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli). Two years later Tom is working as part of the river rescue police, but is pulled back into action with new partner Jo Christman (Sarah Jessica Parker) when possibly the same killer, nicknamed the Polish Hill strangler, is on the loose again. The victims seem to be women that Tom knew, making him a prime suspect, and no-one apart from maybe Jo believes it is the same killer from the past, and he will have to find the right clues to prove his innocence. Keeping an eye on him is Capt. Nick Detillo (Dennis Farina), an acquaintance from two years ago, and Tom and Jo and do come across some small clues, it is obvious that they are slowly falling for each other. Eventually when trapped, Tom finally gets the truth from Nick, that Jimmy was the killer, he has been copycatting the crimes, and he was the one who killed his father, but in the end of course the guilty are caught and the good guys go back to the better life. Also starring Tom Sizemore as Det. Danny Detillo, Brion James as Det. Eddie Eiler, Timothy Busfield as Tony Sacco and Poseidon's Andre Braugher as Dist. Atty. Frank Morris. The acting was a little flat in parts, and they could have been a few more explosive and gun filled chase and action sequences, I will admit as well I didn't exactly pay the fullest attention while watching, but I guess as a cop looking for a serial killer story is is okay, an alright crime thriller. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The killer was caught or was he?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A homicide detective tracking a serial killer alienates himself from his fellow officers when he suggests that this killer who also killed his father/police Ltd in a high speed car chase may be one of their own men. He gets demoted to the harbour patrol, but still his obsession grows to prove that it was an officer that murdered his father and the girls. A very presentable, slick cop after serial killer thriller with a dependable cast (Bruce Willis, Sarah Jessica Parker, Denis Farina, Brion James, Tom Sizemore and Robert Pastorelli) and interesting backdrop (the beat isn't the streets, but a river system) despite the same old-same, same-old plotting with stock clich&eacute;s and some very implausible revelations. Yes it does go over-the-top for its outlandish climax, but its always exciting, eccentric and high-octane in its routine action and this can said about Brad Fiedel's scorching music too. The opening car chase sequence is actually quite well done by director Rowdy Herrington (who does a durable job throughout with the tough thrills and humid dramas), the taut script keeps it suspenseful and before the killer murders the girl/s he plays the seductively catchy tune Li'l Red Riding Hood by Sam the Sham and the Pharaohs. Willis provides your usual gruff, maverick cop who likes to get on the bottle (because of past events that sees him not a favourite of the men in blue) and Parker sexes-it up as his greenhorn partner. James is great in the role as the smarmy detective always looking to pick a fight with Willis' character and Farina is solid as usual. Also showing up in small parts are Tom Atkins and John Mahoney. Mindless early 90s action fun. "I used to be a homicide detective. I lost my shield because I said a cop killed my father"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loyalty above all else, except Honour. | V.Good Thriller |
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gashmanflirty@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just what you expect from Bruce Willis in that decade. He plays the character of drunken failure but always comes out on the good side.I enjoyed it from start to finish. V.good thriller of the 90's with good character personalities working off each other/ j. Parker gave it the romance feel and it worked well. The film itself had v.good action sequences and the length of the film was probably just about right. The consistent negative feeling towards Hardy throughput the film from other cops adds to effort that he has to put in to prove he is right and gain vindication. This struggle allows the film to develop its journey. Thanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I quite liked it, not a classic but entertaining enough.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Striking Distance is set in Pittsburgh where Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) has just had to testify against his partner & cousin Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli), on his way to a policeman's ball with his father Vincent (John Mahoney) they get a call to say that a wanted murderer is being pursued. The two Hardy's decide to help out & give chase but end up crashing their car, when Tom regains consciousness he finds the murder suspect gone & his father dead. Two years later & Tom has been forced to take a job as a river patrol man as he has become an alcoholic loser, suddenly dead bodies begin to be found in the rivers around Pittsburgh that Tom patrol. Tom is convinced the killer is back but discovers that officially the new murders have no connection to the earlier ones, Tom is sure that a big cover-up is going on & that the killer is targeting him personally... Written & directed by Rowdy Herrington there doesn't seem to be much love for this much maligned action thriller with even star Bruce Willis saying 'it sucked' while on a chat-show in 2004, hey Bruce I have news for you Striking Distance is nowhere near the worst film you have appeared in. Hudson Hawk (1991), Color of Night (1994) & Cop Out (2010) anyone? Anyway, Striking Distance was known under the title Three Rivers during production & is a decent enough action thriller. One suspects that maybe Willis was trying to star in another Die Hard (1988) but his character here is much less likable or quotable. The script is nothing more than a string of cop film clich&eacute;s stringed together around a fairly basic murder mystery plot & every so often there's a big action set-piece. As it is I quite liked Striking Distance, there are a few decent one-liners, the character's although clich&eacute;d are given life by a good cast or pro's & there's enough action here to satisfy most. There's a particularly good car chase at the start. As I said the clich&eacute;s come thick & fast, a disgraced alcoholic cop, a cover-up, a killer who taunts the cops, feelings of guilt & remorse & loss, honour & family connections. At just under 100 minutes maybe it's a little long but there's enough going on to keep ones interest even if the murder mystery may be a little easy to figure out & a bit too improbable to take seriously. Also the ending features a little overkill when it comes to the villain dying as he comes back from apparently being dead at least four times in ten minutes! There are some good action set-pieces here including a great car chase with one of my personal favourite moments from any chase from any film when the cars start jumping over those humps & shoot up in the air one behind the other. There are boat chases, shoot-outs, fights & a bit of suspense as a mystery killer stalks & kills a few people too. Nicely enough shot there's not much style here but it looks alright. With a supposed budget of about $30,000,000 this has the usual glossy Hollywood production values & is well made. There's a very good cast here including Bruce Willis, Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James & Tom Atkins with the only weak link the ever awful Sarah Jessica Parker in an early role. Striking Distance is a pretty good action thriller, it has a reasonable murder mystery, some clich&eacute;d cop drama & some good action scenes. It's certainly no worse than a lot of routine Hollywood action thrillers, you could do a lot worse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific mystery action thriller with the man himself in the lead role...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I often start Bruce Willis reviews with a disclaimer...I LOVE Bruce Willis. He can rarely do wrong with the exception of most the 2000's (small joke.) Striking Distance was solidly into his leading man career that made him an action superstar. Striking Distance didn't appear to have the enormous budget of like minded Willis vehicles (30 million vs 70 million for Die Hard 2, 3 years earlier) but that is part of its charm. Striking Distance is part mystery, part thriller, a dash of action, and some great character depth even if the lead character is a little bit predictable as a washed up, alcoholic, traumatically scarred former cop. Willis plays the broody alcoholic like nobodies business. The mystery is solid, and the action scenes are well done. It even features one of the best and most underplayed car/boat chase scenes in action film history...or at least the nineties. A terrific supporting cast of whose who nineties character actors help move the story along and support Willis throughout. Sometimes movie watchers like mystery, dislike action, or some variation of such but Striking Distance gives a little of all of the major genres to make it the perfect film for just pure entertainment. Bruce Willis is the iconic macho man. I could watch him do just about anything. As the aforementioned brooding former cop spending his days as barely more than a security guard on the waters. The character is not revolutionary and can be considered predictable but Willis makes Tom Hardy the best he can possibly be and that's a bad ass good guy. Remember Sarah Jessica Parker before she was Sex and The City's Carrie Bradshaw? Me neither but she is cute and vivacious as fellow boat cop Jo Christman. The character doesn't truly fit into the dreary, dark and often foreboding setting but somehow Parker impressively makes it work. Equally impressive is the fact that Parker and Willis do have decent chemistry and their romance somehow works although it feels forced into the story at times. The whose who supporting cast I mentioned include talented character actors, and TV actors. The most noteworthy are Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James, Robert Pastorelli (really terrific), and John Mahoney (small role but really terrific as Willis' decorated cop father.) Director Rowdy Herrington isn't big in Hollywood but he can be attributed to helming the 80's classic Roadhouse and now Striking Distance. Given his ability to direct two big leading men and let them be what the audiences love should account for something. I have a feeling though Herrington's directing ability ends there. Given something without a leading man probably wouldn't account for much although I haven't seen any of his other work. Striking Distance is just plainly entertaining. It isn't mind blowing and it isn't likely to be most peoples favorite film but it is one that I frequently go back to on a lazy Sunday afternoon for some simple, well made entertainment. It also isn't necessarily considering one of Willis' big films by any means but at the same time is gem amongst his work from the nineties. Definitely worth watching at least once and you'll find its charm beneath the surface. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG this has to be the most horrible movie in history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glennataylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would rather watch reruns of the Smother's brothers. This movie is beyond pathetic. SJP is hideous, i wouldn't sleep with her for $5000. I actually met Demi and her mother during the filming of this movie, I served her lunch. They were both beautiful and delightful. If this (SJP) bitch could be more annoying and ugly it would be difficult, I would rather sleep with Oprah. Hideous, ugly, nasty, no-talent Pig.Behind that is the bad, really bad acting of the rest of the 'cast". No plot, bad acting, predictable scenes, it's like Woody Allen decided to make another bad movie that wasn't "supposed" to be funny. It is so contrived and horrid it's ridiculous, I want to vomit when i SEE HER. If I could break her face with a hammer I would be the happiest man on Earth. She can't act, she is ugly, she is pathetic. F>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>> I hate her guts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder and revenge on the waters, in a high octane thriller that strikes back
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like John Q, Striking Distance is another film, that leaves me in an enigma, of how panned it was. This is just as good as a lot of other Willis actioners. Most of Willis's films I like, and this is no exception. It's really a very well plotted revenge thriller, with a great car chase, I might add, which left this flick playing over a couple of months in Adelaide. I like the family angle to it. Willis like his father, (John Mahoney, before Frasier, and years after Code Of Silence, which he made a brief appearance in) is a Pittsburgh cop. So is his Uncle (Dennis Farina) and his two other sons, one of them who's on trial for battery, where Willis gone up against him, telling the court the real version, much to the bitter dislike of his fellow officers. Like Willis's character, Tom Hardy, (catchy) says "Look where telling the truth's got me". Sadly at the end of the chase, things went awry, where Mahoney is executed. There's a bigger picture to this story, and I'm not gonna spoil it for ya. Soon after, Farina's bad cop son, where things are not looking to good for him, threatens to jump off the bridge saying "Cops don't go to prison. I'm not going". Well, bad cops do. Well, he jumps. His body's never recovered. Cut to a couple of years later, disgraced cop, Willis, now drowning his sorrows in alcohol, and making the best of his stinking situation, now works as a river cop. Everything's just dandy. He lives on a houseboat, has a cat, even gets a surprise visit later from Farina's other out of control, boozing son, now ex cop, (Tom Sizemore, quite impressive here) who like the other cops, initially had it in for Hardy too. Things are looking up when he's partnered with Jo, new to the job. But now things are about to become a living hell, where for Hardy, his haunted past returns, though he's always been haunted, since those tragic events years prior. A score of dead young women, start surfacing on the river waters, all of who have been sexually involved with Willis. He's convinced this is the work of the same killer, responsible for his father's execution. So here's a great thriller ride for you. Too, as an added treat, we have an unrelated action scene on a houseboat, where some hijackers have taken it over, so it's good ol Bruce to the rescue. Too near the end, in it's horrifying revelation, where the killer comes into light, we really learn about family and loyalty, where again to finish the killer off, a cattle crod is used, that instantly had me remembering that scene in The Last Boy Scout. And like the end of Cobra, Willis gets to punch out the loud mouthed cop. See, this film has everything, including a bit of romance and a nice after ending. For Willis fans, specially. Check out the classic opening with the remote control car, cool like the rest of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance-Strike **** for this Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We could literally call this excellent thriller ALL IN THE FAMILY as it deals with a family of police caught up in a series of serial killings that eventually takes the life of the father of Bruce Willis. Scorned by police when he turns his own cousin in on an unrelated police matter, and his persistence that the man found guilty of the crime is innocent and that the real killer is none other than a police officer. The plot twists are great and there is plenty of action. Bruce Willis has the perfect part for himself and he is aided by Sarah Jessica Palmer, who has another assigned agenda on her part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full of holes, clich&eacute;s, emoting, but a decent car chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    plex
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see Bruce Willis develop his 2-dimensional acting "chops" in this, one of his earliest action flicks. He basically has 3 emotions: the overly subdued "I'm to cool to care" tone, the aloof/smug tone, and the yelling tone. The facial contortions he exhibits when he shoots a gun is so ham and often repeated throughout his career. ( Don't get me wrong, some of his films, if not his work, I am very fond of). You either love Sarah J, Parker or not. But it strikes me odd that she has been in SO many love scenes and starred in the Sex & The City shows and movies, yet she obviously takes herself too serious as their must be a no-nip clause in all of her contracts. I guess whats good enough for serious actresses like Helen Mirren, Susan Sarandon, Kate Winslet, and Julianne Moore isn't good enough for her. The film: This is a 19 year old movie, so I am going to assume the plot has been well covered here. But I couldn't get passed a couple of things: Great opening car chase scene, highly frenetic, however father and son are having a completely sedate personal conversation. Its one thing to be in control of your emotions, its another being inhuman. So they get in this rolling car crash, its the middle of the day and apparently they all just sat there for hours and hours because its dark when the other cops ( some involved in the pursuit) arrive at the scene. Second big thing, you have our villain, a cop. He's on the bridge for the longest time. All of his relatives are cops, his dad is a cop. There's is the omnipotent river patrol, who our protagonist joins later in the film. Yet, when the villain jumps in, the river patrol cant immediately find him? After all, all of the other dead bodies are found, and apparently the river is pretty clean ( of course not) because we see night-time underwater sequences. Wouldn't they want his body recovered? They certainly had the resources. Minor things: Why was the guy who dumped a throw-rug so anxious to risk life&limb and his car ( which explodes) over it? Was this our villain? Never explained. The worst things for me had to be Sarah's mushy court-room testimony, and Brion James ( who I like in other films) who is so over-the-top angry about everything its just plain humorous, or his diatribe in the end when he eats crow and ego strokes Bruce. Really cheesy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Land shark.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hardy is a fifth-generation cop. When his father dies during the chase of a serial killer, Hardy further complicates matters by implicating his partner and cousin Jimmy in a police brutality case. Two years after Jimmy is believed to have committed suicide, women from Hardy's past start to turn up dead, and his father's alleged killer is found. Believing that the alleged killer is a patsy, Hardy conducts his own illegal investigation into his father's own death, and the women's deaths as well. Hardy and the killer ultimately lock horns in a showdown that ties all the loose ends on both case. It's pretty formulaic stuff for Willis, during the time I like to refer to as his 'chubby era'. He had a pretty bad run of films between 93 to 95, and was finally broke by DHWAV in the summer of 95. It's fun stuff though while it lasts, Cop turns alcoholic, argues a lot with Farina and James, and the killer turns up at the end, but isn't surprising as his name is pretty high up on the credits at the beginning. Parker is fine, but if her character was cut out of the story, it wouldn't damage the narrative. If your a Willis fine, it's a good movie with no surprises.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard the title and who starred in somewhere, I am pretty sure it was from seeing the DVD cover, I guess I watched it just to see some reasonable action fun with the two lead stars I knew. Basically Det. Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) comes from a generation of cops, and he is devastated when his father Vince (John Mahoney) dies during the chase of a serial killer, and after he gets himself in an argument with his partner and cousin Det. Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli). Two years later Tom is working as part of the river rescue police, but is pulled back into action with new partner Jo Christman (Sarah Jessica Parker) when possibly the same killer, nicknamed the Polish Hill strangler, is on the loose again. The victims seem to be women that Tom knew, making him a prime suspect, and no-one apart from maybe Jo believes it is the same killer from the past, and he will have to find the right clues to prove his innocence. Keeping an eye on him is Capt. Nick Detillo (Dennis Farina), an acquaintance from two years ago, and Tom and Jo and do come across some small clues, it is obvious that they are slowly falling for each other. Eventually when trapped, Tom finally gets the truth from Nick, that Jimmy was the killer, he has been copycatting the crimes, and he was the one who killed his father, but in the end of course the guilty are caught and the good guys go back to the better life. Also starring Tom Sizemore as Det. Danny Detillo, Brion James as Det. Eddie Eiler, Timothy Busfield as Tony Sacco and Poseidon's Andre Braugher as Dist. Atty. Frank Morris. The acting was a little flat in parts, and they could have been a few more explosive and gun filled chase and action sequences, I will admit as well I didn't exactly pay the fullest attention while watching, but I guess as a cop looking for a serial killer story is is okay, an alright crime thriller. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The killer was caught or was he?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A homicide detective tracking a serial killer alienates himself from his fellow officers when he suggests that this killer who also killed his father/police Ltd in a high speed car chase may be one of their own men. He gets demoted to the harbour patrol, but still his obsession grows to prove that it was an officer that murdered his father and the girls. A very presentable, slick cop after serial killer thriller with a dependable cast (Bruce Willis, Sarah Jessica Parker, Denis Farina, Brion James, Tom Sizemore and Robert Pastorelli) and interesting backdrop (the beat isn't the streets, but a river system) despite the same old-same, same-old plotting with stock clich&eacute;s and some very implausible revelations. Yes it does go over-the-top for its outlandish climax, but its always exciting, eccentric and high-octane in its routine action and this can said about Brad Fiedel's scorching music too. The opening car chase sequence is actually quite well done by director Rowdy Herrington (who does a durable job throughout with the tough thrills and humid dramas), the taut script keeps it suspenseful and before the killer murders the girl/s he plays the seductively catchy tune Li'l Red Riding Hood by Sam the Sham and the Pharaohs. Willis provides your usual gruff, maverick cop who likes to get on the bottle (because of past events that sees him not a favourite of the men in blue) and Parker sexes-it up as his greenhorn partner. James is great in the role as the smarmy detective always looking to pick a fight with Willis' character and Farina is solid as usual. Also showing up in small parts are Tom Atkins and John Mahoney. Mindless early 90s action fun. "I used to be a homicide detective. I lost my shield because I said a cop killed my father"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loyalty above all else, except Honour. | V.Good Thriller |
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gashmanflirty@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just what you expect from Bruce Willis in that decade. He plays the character of drunken failure but always comes out on the good side.I enjoyed it from start to finish. V.good thriller of the 90's with good character personalities working off each other/ j. Parker gave it the romance feel and it worked well. The film itself had v.good action sequences and the length of the film was probably just about right. The consistent negative feeling towards Hardy throughput the film from other cops adds to effort that he has to put in to prove he is right and gain vindication. This struggle allows the film to develop its journey. Thanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I quite liked it, not a classic but entertaining enough.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Striking Distance is set in Pittsburgh where Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) has just had to testify against his partner & cousin Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli), on his way to a policeman's ball with his father Vincent (John Mahoney) they get a call to say that a wanted murderer is being pursued. The two Hardy's decide to help out & give chase but end up crashing their car, when Tom regains consciousness he finds the murder suspect gone & his father dead. Two years later & Tom has been forced to take a job as a river patrol man as he has become an alcoholic loser, suddenly dead bodies begin to be found in the rivers around Pittsburgh that Tom patrol. Tom is convinced the killer is back but discovers that officially the new murders have no connection to the earlier ones, Tom is sure that a big cover-up is going on & that the killer is targeting him personally... Written & directed by Rowdy Herrington there doesn't seem to be much love for this much maligned action thriller with even star Bruce Willis saying 'it sucked' while on a chat-show in 2004, hey Bruce I have news for you Striking Distance is nowhere near the worst film you have appeared in. Hudson Hawk (1991), Color of Night (1994) & Cop Out (2010) anyone? Anyway, Striking Distance was known under the title Three Rivers during production & is a decent enough action thriller. One suspects that maybe Willis was trying to star in another Die Hard (1988) but his character here is much less likable or quotable. The script is nothing more than a string of cop film clich&eacute;s stringed together around a fairly basic murder mystery plot & every so often there's a big action set-piece. As it is I quite liked Striking Distance, there are a few decent one-liners, the character's although clich&eacute;d are given life by a good cast or pro's & there's enough action here to satisfy most. There's a particularly good car chase at the start. As I said the clich&eacute;s come thick & fast, a disgraced alcoholic cop, a cover-up, a killer who taunts the cops, feelings of guilt & remorse & loss, honour & family connections. At just under 100 minutes maybe it's a little long but there's enough going on to keep ones interest even if the murder mystery may be a little easy to figure out & a bit too improbable to take seriously. Also the ending features a little overkill when it comes to the villain dying as he comes back from apparently being dead at least four times in ten minutes! There are some good action set-pieces here including a great car chase with one of my personal favourite moments from any chase from any film when the cars start jumping over those humps & shoot up in the air one behind the other. There are boat chases, shoot-outs, fights & a bit of suspense as a mystery killer stalks & kills a few people too. Nicely enough shot there's not much style here but it looks alright. With a supposed budget of about $30,000,000 this has the usual glossy Hollywood production values & is well made. There's a very good cast here including Bruce Willis, Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James & Tom Atkins with the only weak link the ever awful Sarah Jessica Parker in an early role. Striking Distance is a pretty good action thriller, it has a reasonable murder mystery, some clich&eacute;d cop drama & some good action scenes. It's certainly no worse than a lot of routine Hollywood action thrillers, you could do a lot worse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific mystery action thriller with the man himself in the lead role...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I often start Bruce Willis reviews with a disclaimer...I LOVE Bruce Willis. He can rarely do wrong with the exception of most the 2000's (small joke.) Striking Distance was solidly into his leading man career that made him an action superstar. Striking Distance didn't appear to have the enormous budget of like minded Willis vehicles (30 million vs 70 million for Die Hard 2, 3 years earlier) but that is part of its charm. Striking Distance is part mystery, part thriller, a dash of action, and some great character depth even if the lead character is a little bit predictable as a washed up, alcoholic, traumatically scarred former cop. Willis plays the broody alcoholic like nobodies business. The mystery is solid, and the action scenes are well done. It even features one of the best and most underplayed car/boat chase scenes in action film history...or at least the nineties. A terrific supporting cast of whose who nineties character actors help move the story along and support Willis throughout. Sometimes movie watchers like mystery, dislike action, or some variation of such but Striking Distance gives a little of all of the major genres to make it the perfect film for just pure entertainment. Bruce Willis is the iconic macho man. I could watch him do just about anything. As the aforementioned brooding former cop spending his days as barely more than a security guard on the waters. The character is not revolutionary and can be considered predictable but Willis makes Tom Hardy the best he can possibly be and that's a bad ass good guy. Remember Sarah Jessica Parker before she was Sex and The City's Carrie Bradshaw? Me neither but she is cute and vivacious as fellow boat cop Jo Christman. The character doesn't truly fit into the dreary, dark and often foreboding setting but somehow Parker impressively makes it work. Equally impressive is the fact that Parker and Willis do have decent chemistry and their romance somehow works although it feels forced into the story at times. The whose who supporting cast I mentioned include talented character actors, and TV actors. The most noteworthy are Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James, Robert Pastorelli (really terrific), and John Mahoney (small role but really terrific as Willis' decorated cop father.) Director Rowdy Herrington isn't big in Hollywood but he can be attributed to helming the 80's classic Roadhouse and now Striking Distance. Given his ability to direct two big leading men and let them be what the audiences love should account for something. I have a feeling though Herrington's directing ability ends there. Given something without a leading man probably wouldn't account for much although I haven't seen any of his other work. Striking Distance is just plainly entertaining. It isn't mind blowing and it isn't likely to be most peoples favorite film but it is one that I frequently go back to on a lazy Sunday afternoon for some simple, well made entertainment. It also isn't necessarily considering one of Willis' big films by any means but at the same time is gem amongst his work from the nineties. Definitely worth watching at least once and you'll find its charm beneath the surface. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG this has to be the most horrible movie in history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glennataylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would rather watch reruns of the Smother's brothers. This movie is beyond pathetic. SJP is hideous, i wouldn't sleep with her for $5000. I actually met Demi and her mother during the filming of this movie, I served her lunch. They were both beautiful and delightful. If this (SJP) bitch could be more annoying and ugly it would be difficult, I would rather sleep with Oprah. Hideous, ugly, nasty, no-talent Pig.Behind that is the bad, really bad acting of the rest of the 'cast". No plot, bad acting, predictable scenes, it's like Woody Allen decided to make another bad movie that wasn't "supposed" to be funny. It is so contrived and horrid it's ridiculous, I want to vomit when i SEE HER. If I could break her face with a hammer I would be the happiest man on Earth. She can't act, she is ugly, she is pathetic. F>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>> I hate her guts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder and revenge on the waters, in a high octane thriller that strikes back
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like John Q, Striking Distance is another film, that leaves me in an enigma, of how panned it was. This is just as good as a lot of other Willis actioners. Most of Willis's films I like, and this is no exception. It's really a very well plotted revenge thriller, with a great car chase, I might add, which left this flick playing over a couple of months in Adelaide. I like the family angle to it. Willis like his father, (John Mahoney, before Frasier, and years after Code Of Silence, which he made a brief appearance in) is a Pittsburgh cop. So is his Uncle (Dennis Farina) and his two other sons, one of them who's on trial for battery, where Willis gone up against him, telling the court the real version, much to the bitter dislike of his fellow officers. Like Willis's character, Tom Hardy, (catchy) says "Look where telling the truth's got me". Sadly at the end of the chase, things went awry, where Mahoney is executed. There's a bigger picture to this story, and I'm not gonna spoil it for ya. Soon after, Farina's bad cop son, where things are not looking to good for him, threatens to jump off the bridge saying "Cops don't go to prison. I'm not going". Well, bad cops do. Well, he jumps. His body's never recovered. Cut to a couple of years later, disgraced cop, Willis, now drowning his sorrows in alcohol, and making the best of his stinking situation, now works as a river cop. Everything's just dandy. He lives on a houseboat, has a cat, even gets a surprise visit later from Farina's other out of control, boozing son, now ex cop, (Tom Sizemore, quite impressive here) who like the other cops, initially had it in for Hardy too. Things are looking up when he's partnered with Jo, new to the job. But now things are about to become a living hell, where for Hardy, his haunted past returns, though he's always been haunted, since those tragic events years prior. A score of dead young women, start surfacing on the river waters, all of who have been sexually involved with Willis. He's convinced this is the work of the same killer, responsible for his father's execution. So here's a great thriller ride for you. Too, as an added treat, we have an unrelated action scene on a houseboat, where some hijackers have taken it over, so it's good ol Bruce to the rescue. Too near the end, in it's horrifying revelation, where the killer comes into light, we really learn about family and loyalty, where again to finish the killer off, a cattle crod is used, that instantly had me remembering that scene in The Last Boy Scout. And like the end of Cobra, Willis gets to punch out the loud mouthed cop. See, this film has everything, including a bit of romance and a nice after ending. For Willis fans, specially. Check out the classic opening with the remote control car, cool like the rest of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance-Strike **** for this Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We could literally call this excellent thriller ALL IN THE FAMILY as it deals with a family of police caught up in a series of serial killings that eventually takes the life of the father of Bruce Willis. Scorned by police when he turns his own cousin in on an unrelated police matter, and his persistence that the man found guilty of the crime is innocent and that the real killer is none other than a police officer. The plot twists are great and there is plenty of action. Bruce Willis has the perfect part for himself and he is aided by Sarah Jessica Palmer, who has another assigned agenda on her part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full of holes, clich&eacute;s, emoting, but a decent car chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    plex
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see Bruce Willis develop his 2-dimensional acting "chops" in this, one of his earliest action flicks. He basically has 3 emotions: the overly subdued "I'm to cool to care" tone, the aloof/smug tone, and the yelling tone. The facial contortions he exhibits when he shoots a gun is so ham and often repeated throughout his career. ( Don't get me wrong, some of his films, if not his work, I am very fond of). You either love Sarah J, Parker or not. But it strikes me odd that she has been in SO many love scenes and starred in the Sex & The City shows and movies, yet she obviously takes herself too serious as their must be a no-nip clause in all of her contracts. I guess whats good enough for serious actresses like Helen Mirren, Susan Sarandon, Kate Winslet, and Julianne Moore isn't good enough for her. The film: This is a 19 year old movie, so I am going to assume the plot has been well covered here. But I couldn't get passed a couple of things: Great opening car chase scene, highly frenetic, however father and son are having a completely sedate personal conversation. Its one thing to be in control of your emotions, its another being inhuman. So they get in this rolling car crash, its the middle of the day and apparently they all just sat there for hours and hours because its dark when the other cops ( some involved in the pursuit) arrive at the scene. Second big thing, you have our villain, a cop. He's on the bridge for the longest time. All of his relatives are cops, his dad is a cop. There's is the omnipotent river patrol, who our protagonist joins later in the film. Yet, when the villain jumps in, the river patrol cant immediately find him? After all, all of the other dead bodies are found, and apparently the river is pretty clean ( of course not) because we see night-time underwater sequences. Wouldn't they want his body recovered? They certainly had the resources. Minor things: Why was the guy who dumped a throw-rug so anxious to risk life&limb and his car ( which explodes) over it? Was this our villain? Never explained. The worst things for me had to be Sarah's mushy court-room testimony, and Brion James ( who I like in other films) who is so over-the-top angry about everything its just plain humorous, or his diatribe in the end when he eats crow and ego strokes Bruce. Really cheesy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Land shark.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hardy is a fifth-generation cop. When his father dies during the chase of a serial killer, Hardy further complicates matters by implicating his partner and cousin Jimmy in a police brutality case. Two years after Jimmy is believed to have committed suicide, women from Hardy's past start to turn up dead, and his father's alleged killer is found. Believing that the alleged killer is a patsy, Hardy conducts his own illegal investigation into his father's own death, and the women's deaths as well. Hardy and the killer ultimately lock horns in a showdown that ties all the loose ends on both case. It's pretty formulaic stuff for Willis, during the time I like to refer to as his 'chubby era'. He had a pretty bad run of films between 93 to 95, and was finally broke by DHWAV in the summer of 95. It's fun stuff though while it lasts, Cop turns alcoholic, argues a lot with Farina and James, and the killer turns up at the end, but isn't surprising as his name is pretty high up on the credits at the beginning. Parker is fine, but if her character was cut out of the story, it wouldn't damage the narrative. If your a Willis fine, it's a good movie with no surprises.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard the title and who starred in somewhere, I am pretty sure it was from seeing the DVD cover, I guess I watched it just to see some reasonable action fun with the two lead stars I knew. Basically Det. Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) comes from a generation of cops, and he is devastated when his father Vince (John Mahoney) dies during the chase of a serial killer, and after he gets himself in an argument with his partner and cousin Det. Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli). Two years later Tom is working as part of the river rescue police, but is pulled back into action with new partner Jo Christman (Sarah Jessica Parker) when possibly the same killer, nicknamed the Polish Hill strangler, is on the loose again. The victims seem to be women that Tom knew, making him a prime suspect, and no-one apart from maybe Jo believes it is the same killer from the past, and he will have to find the right clues to prove his innocence. Keeping an eye on him is Capt. Nick Detillo (Dennis Farina), an acquaintance from two years ago, and Tom and Jo and do come across some small clues, it is obvious that they are slowly falling for each other. Eventually when trapped, Tom finally gets the truth from Nick, that Jimmy was the killer, he has been copycatting the crimes, and he was the one who killed his father, but in the end of course the guilty are caught and the good guys go back to the better life. Also starring Tom Sizemore as Det. Danny Detillo, Brion James as Det. Eddie Eiler, Timothy Busfield as Tony Sacco and Poseidon's Andre Braugher as Dist. Atty. Frank Morris. The acting was a little flat in parts, and they could have been a few more explosive and gun filled chase and action sequences, I will admit as well I didn't exactly pay the fullest attention while watching, but I guess as a cop looking for a serial killer story is is okay, an alright crime thriller. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The killer was caught or was he?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A homicide detective tracking a serial killer alienates himself from his fellow officers when he suggests that this killer who also killed his father/police Ltd in a high speed car chase may be one of their own men. He gets demoted to the harbour patrol, but still his obsession grows to prove that it was an officer that murdered his father and the girls. A very presentable, slick cop after serial killer thriller with a dependable cast (Bruce Willis, Sarah Jessica Parker, Denis Farina, Brion James, Tom Sizemore and Robert Pastorelli) and interesting backdrop (the beat isn't the streets, but a river system) despite the same old-same, same-old plotting with stock clich&eacute;s and some very implausible revelations. Yes it does go over-the-top for its outlandish climax, but its always exciting, eccentric and high-octane in its routine action and this can said about Brad Fiedel's scorching music too. The opening car chase sequence is actually quite well done by director Rowdy Herrington (who does a durable job throughout with the tough thrills and humid dramas), the taut script keeps it suspenseful and before the killer murders the girl/s he plays the seductively catchy tune Li'l Red Riding Hood by Sam the Sham and the Pharaohs. Willis provides your usual gruff, maverick cop who likes to get on the bottle (because of past events that sees him not a favourite of the men in blue) and Parker sexes-it up as his greenhorn partner. James is great in the role as the smarmy detective always looking to pick a fight with Willis' character and Farina is solid as usual. Also showing up in small parts are Tom Atkins and John Mahoney. Mindless early 90s action fun. "I used to be a homicide detective. I lost my shield because I said a cop killed my father"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loyalty above all else, except Honour. | V.Good Thriller |
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gashmanflirty@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just what you expect from Bruce Willis in that decade. He plays the character of drunken failure but always comes out on the good side.I enjoyed it from start to finish. V.good thriller of the 90's with good character personalities working off each other/ j. Parker gave it the romance feel and it worked well. The film itself had v.good action sequences and the length of the film was probably just about right. The consistent negative feeling towards Hardy throughput the film from other cops adds to effort that he has to put in to prove he is right and gain vindication. This struggle allows the film to develop its journey. Thanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I quite liked it, not a classic but entertaining enough.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Striking Distance is set in Pittsburgh where Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) has just had to testify against his partner & cousin Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli), on his way to a policeman's ball with his father Vincent (John Mahoney) they get a call to say that a wanted murderer is being pursued. The two Hardy's decide to help out & give chase but end up crashing their car, when Tom regains consciousness he finds the murder suspect gone & his father dead. Two years later & Tom has been forced to take a job as a river patrol man as he has become an alcoholic loser, suddenly dead bodies begin to be found in the rivers around Pittsburgh that Tom patrol. Tom is convinced the killer is back but discovers that officially the new murders have no connection to the earlier ones, Tom is sure that a big cover-up is going on & that the killer is targeting him personally... Written & directed by Rowdy Herrington there doesn't seem to be much love for this much maligned action thriller with even star Bruce Willis saying 'it sucked' while on a chat-show in 2004, hey Bruce I have news for you Striking Distance is nowhere near the worst film you have appeared in. Hudson Hawk (1991), Color of Night (1994) & Cop Out (2010) anyone? Anyway, Striking Distance was known under the title Three Rivers during production & is a decent enough action thriller. One suspects that maybe Willis was trying to star in another Die Hard (1988) but his character here is much less likable or quotable. The script is nothing more than a string of cop film clich&eacute;s stringed together around a fairly basic murder mystery plot & every so often there's a big action set-piece. As it is I quite liked Striking Distance, there are a few decent one-liners, the character's although clich&eacute;d are given life by a good cast or pro's & there's enough action here to satisfy most. There's a particularly good car chase at the start. As I said the clich&eacute;s come thick & fast, a disgraced alcoholic cop, a cover-up, a killer who taunts the cops, feelings of guilt & remorse & loss, honour & family connections. At just under 100 minutes maybe it's a little long but there's enough going on to keep ones interest even if the murder mystery may be a little easy to figure out & a bit too improbable to take seriously. Also the ending features a little overkill when it comes to the villain dying as he comes back from apparently being dead at least four times in ten minutes! There are some good action set-pieces here including a great car chase with one of my personal favourite moments from any chase from any film when the cars start jumping over those humps & shoot up in the air one behind the other. There are boat chases, shoot-outs, fights & a bit of suspense as a mystery killer stalks & kills a few people too. Nicely enough shot there's not much style here but it looks alright. With a supposed budget of about $30,000,000 this has the usual glossy Hollywood production values & is well made. There's a very good cast here including Bruce Willis, Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James & Tom Atkins with the only weak link the ever awful Sarah Jessica Parker in an early role. Striking Distance is a pretty good action thriller, it has a reasonable murder mystery, some clich&eacute;d cop drama & some good action scenes. It's certainly no worse than a lot of routine Hollywood action thrillers, you could do a lot worse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific mystery action thriller with the man himself in the lead role...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I often start Bruce Willis reviews with a disclaimer...I LOVE Bruce Willis. He can rarely do wrong with the exception of most the 2000's (small joke.) Striking Distance was solidly into his leading man career that made him an action superstar. Striking Distance didn't appear to have the enormous budget of like minded Willis vehicles (30 million vs 70 million for Die Hard 2, 3 years earlier) but that is part of its charm. Striking Distance is part mystery, part thriller, a dash of action, and some great character depth even if the lead character is a little bit predictable as a washed up, alcoholic, traumatically scarred former cop. Willis plays the broody alcoholic like nobodies business. The mystery is solid, and the action scenes are well done. It even features one of the best and most underplayed car/boat chase scenes in action film history...or at least the nineties. A terrific supporting cast of whose who nineties character actors help move the story along and support Willis throughout. Sometimes movie watchers like mystery, dislike action, or some variation of such but Striking Distance gives a little of all of the major genres to make it the perfect film for just pure entertainment. Bruce Willis is the iconic macho man. I could watch him do just about anything. As the aforementioned brooding former cop spending his days as barely more than a security guard on the waters. The character is not revolutionary and can be considered predictable but Willis makes Tom Hardy the best he can possibly be and that's a bad ass good guy. Remember Sarah Jessica Parker before she was Sex and The City's Carrie Bradshaw? Me neither but she is cute and vivacious as fellow boat cop Jo Christman. The character doesn't truly fit into the dreary, dark and often foreboding setting but somehow Parker impressively makes it work. Equally impressive is the fact that Parker and Willis do have decent chemistry and their romance somehow works although it feels forced into the story at times. The whose who supporting cast I mentioned include talented character actors, and TV actors. The most noteworthy are Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James, Robert Pastorelli (really terrific), and John Mahoney (small role but really terrific as Willis' decorated cop father.) Director Rowdy Herrington isn't big in Hollywood but he can be attributed to helming the 80's classic Roadhouse and now Striking Distance. Given his ability to direct two big leading men and let them be what the audiences love should account for something. I have a feeling though Herrington's directing ability ends there. Given something without a leading man probably wouldn't account for much although I haven't seen any of his other work. Striking Distance is just plainly entertaining. It isn't mind blowing and it isn't likely to be most peoples favorite film but it is one that I frequently go back to on a lazy Sunday afternoon for some simple, well made entertainment. It also isn't necessarily considering one of Willis' big films by any means but at the same time is gem amongst his work from the nineties. Definitely worth watching at least once and you'll find its charm beneath the surface. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG this has to be the most horrible movie in history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glennataylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would rather watch reruns of the Smother's brothers. This movie is beyond pathetic. SJP is hideous, i wouldn't sleep with her for $5000. I actually met Demi and her mother during the filming of this movie, I served her lunch. They were both beautiful and delightful. If this (SJP) bitch could be more annoying and ugly it would be difficult, I would rather sleep with Oprah. Hideous, ugly, nasty, no-talent Pig.Behind that is the bad, really bad acting of the rest of the 'cast". No plot, bad acting, predictable scenes, it's like Woody Allen decided to make another bad movie that wasn't "supposed" to be funny. It is so contrived and horrid it's ridiculous, I want to vomit when i SEE HER. If I could break her face with a hammer I would be the happiest man on Earth. She can't act, she is ugly, she is pathetic. F>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>> I hate her guts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder and revenge on the waters, in a high octane thriller that strikes back
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like John Q, Striking Distance is another film, that leaves me in an enigma, of how panned it was. This is just as good as a lot of other Willis actioners. Most of Willis's films I like, and this is no exception. It's really a very well plotted revenge thriller, with a great car chase, I might add, which left this flick playing over a couple of months in Adelaide. I like the family angle to it. Willis like his father, (John Mahoney, before Frasier, and years after Code Of Silence, which he made a brief appearance in) is a Pittsburgh cop. So is his Uncle (Dennis Farina) and his two other sons, one of them who's on trial for battery, where Willis gone up against him, telling the court the real version, much to the bitter dislike of his fellow officers. Like Willis's character, Tom Hardy, (catchy) says "Look where telling the truth's got me". Sadly at the end of the chase, things went awry, where Mahoney is executed. There's a bigger picture to this story, and I'm not gonna spoil it for ya. Soon after, Farina's bad cop son, where things are not looking to good for him, threatens to jump off the bridge saying "Cops don't go to prison. I'm not going". Well, bad cops do. Well, he jumps. His body's never recovered. Cut to a couple of years later, disgraced cop, Willis, now drowning his sorrows in alcohol, and making the best of his stinking situation, now works as a river cop. Everything's just dandy. He lives on a houseboat, has a cat, even gets a surprise visit later from Farina's other out of control, boozing son, now ex cop, (Tom Sizemore, quite impressive here) who like the other cops, initially had it in for Hardy too. Things are looking up when he's partnered with Jo, new to the job. But now things are about to become a living hell, where for Hardy, his haunted past returns, though he's always been haunted, since those tragic events years prior. A score of dead young women, start surfacing on the river waters, all of who have been sexually involved with Willis. He's convinced this is the work of the same killer, responsible for his father's execution. So here's a great thriller ride for you. Too, as an added treat, we have an unrelated action scene on a houseboat, where some hijackers have taken it over, so it's good ol Bruce to the rescue. Too near the end, in it's horrifying revelation, where the killer comes into light, we really learn about family and loyalty, where again to finish the killer off, a cattle crod is used, that instantly had me remembering that scene in The Last Boy Scout. And like the end of Cobra, Willis gets to punch out the loud mouthed cop. See, this film has everything, including a bit of romance and a nice after ending. For Willis fans, specially. Check out the classic opening with the remote control car, cool like the rest of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance-Strike **** for this Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We could literally call this excellent thriller ALL IN THE FAMILY as it deals with a family of police caught up in a series of serial killings that eventually takes the life of the father of Bruce Willis. Scorned by police when he turns his own cousin in on an unrelated police matter, and his persistence that the man found guilty of the crime is innocent and that the real killer is none other than a police officer. The plot twists are great and there is plenty of action. Bruce Willis has the perfect part for himself and he is aided by Sarah Jessica Palmer, who has another assigned agenda on her part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full of holes, clich&eacute;s, emoting, but a decent car chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    plex
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see Bruce Willis develop his 2-dimensional acting "chops" in this, one of his earliest action flicks. He basically has 3 emotions: the overly subdued "I'm to cool to care" tone, the aloof/smug tone, and the yelling tone. The facial contortions he exhibits when he shoots a gun is so ham and often repeated throughout his career. ( Don't get me wrong, some of his films, if not his work, I am very fond of). You either love Sarah J, Parker or not. But it strikes me odd that she has been in SO many love scenes and starred in the Sex & The City shows and movies, yet she obviously takes herself too serious as their must be a no-nip clause in all of her contracts. I guess whats good enough for serious actresses like Helen Mirren, Susan Sarandon, Kate Winslet, and Julianne Moore isn't good enough for her. The film: This is a 19 year old movie, so I am going to assume the plot has been well covered here. But I couldn't get passed a couple of things: Great opening car chase scene, highly frenetic, however father and son are having a completely sedate personal conversation. Its one thing to be in control of your emotions, its another being inhuman. So they get in this rolling car crash, its the middle of the day and apparently they all just sat there for hours and hours because its dark when the other cops ( some involved in the pursuit) arrive at the scene. Second big thing, you have our villain, a cop. He's on the bridge for the longest time. All of his relatives are cops, his dad is a cop. There's is the omnipotent river patrol, who our protagonist joins later in the film. Yet, when the villain jumps in, the river patrol cant immediately find him? After all, all of the other dead bodies are found, and apparently the river is pretty clean ( of course not) because we see night-time underwater sequences. Wouldn't they want his body recovered? They certainly had the resources. Minor things: Why was the guy who dumped a throw-rug so anxious to risk life&limb and his car ( which explodes) over it? Was this our villain? Never explained. The worst things for me had to be Sarah's mushy court-room testimony, and Brion James ( who I like in other films) who is so over-the-top angry about everything its just plain humorous, or his diatribe in the end when he eats crow and ego strokes Bruce. Really cheesy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Land shark.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hardy is a fifth-generation cop. When his father dies during the chase of a serial killer, Hardy further complicates matters by implicating his partner and cousin Jimmy in a police brutality case. Two years after Jimmy is believed to have committed suicide, women from Hardy's past start to turn up dead, and his father's alleged killer is found. Believing that the alleged killer is a patsy, Hardy conducts his own illegal investigation into his father's own death, and the women's deaths as well. Hardy and the killer ultimately lock horns in a showdown that ties all the loose ends on both case. It's pretty formulaic stuff for Willis, during the time I like to refer to as his 'chubby era'. He had a pretty bad run of films between 93 to 95, and was finally broke by DHWAV in the summer of 95. It's fun stuff though while it lasts, Cop turns alcoholic, argues a lot with Farina and James, and the killer turns up at the end, but isn't surprising as his name is pretty high up on the credits at the beginning. Parker is fine, but if her character was cut out of the story, it wouldn't damage the narrative. If your a Willis fine, it's a good movie with no surprises.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard the title and who starred in somewhere, I am pretty sure it was from seeing the DVD cover, I guess I watched it just to see some reasonable action fun with the two lead stars I knew. Basically Det. Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) comes from a generation of cops, and he is devastated when his father Vince (John Mahoney) dies during the chase of a serial killer, and after he gets himself in an argument with his partner and cousin Det. Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli). Two years later Tom is working as part of the river rescue police, but is pulled back into action with new partner Jo Christman (Sarah Jessica Parker) when possibly the same killer, nicknamed the Polish Hill strangler, is on the loose again. The victims seem to be women that Tom knew, making him a prime suspect, and no-one apart from maybe Jo believes it is the same killer from the past, and he will have to find the right clues to prove his innocence. Keeping an eye on him is Capt. Nick Detillo (Dennis Farina), an acquaintance from two years ago, and Tom and Jo and do come across some small clues, it is obvious that they are slowly falling for each other. Eventually when trapped, Tom finally gets the truth from Nick, that Jimmy was the killer, he has been copycatting the crimes, and he was the one who killed his father, but in the end of course the guilty are caught and the good guys go back to the better life. Also starring Tom Sizemore as Det. Danny Detillo, Brion James as Det. Eddie Eiler, Timothy Busfield as Tony Sacco and Poseidon's Andre Braugher as Dist. Atty. Frank Morris. The acting was a little flat in parts, and they could have been a few more explosive and gun filled chase and action sequences, I will admit as well I didn't exactly pay the fullest attention while watching, but I guess as a cop looking for a serial killer story is is okay, an alright crime thriller. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The killer was caught or was he?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A homicide detective tracking a serial killer alienates himself from his fellow officers when he suggests that this killer who also killed his father/police Ltd in a high speed car chase may be one of their own men. He gets demoted to the harbour patrol, but still his obsession grows to prove that it was an officer that murdered his father and the girls. A very presentable, slick cop after serial killer thriller with a dependable cast (Bruce Willis, Sarah Jessica Parker, Denis Farina, Brion James, Tom Sizemore and Robert Pastorelli) and interesting backdrop (the beat isn't the streets, but a river system) despite the same old-same, same-old plotting with stock clich&eacute;s and some very implausible revelations. Yes it does go over-the-top for its outlandish climax, but its always exciting, eccentric and high-octane in its routine action and this can said about Brad Fiedel's scorching music too. The opening car chase sequence is actually quite well done by director Rowdy Herrington (who does a durable job throughout with the tough thrills and humid dramas), the taut script keeps it suspenseful and before the killer murders the girl/s he plays the seductively catchy tune Li'l Red Riding Hood by Sam the Sham and the Pharaohs. Willis provides your usual gruff, maverick cop who likes to get on the bottle (because of past events that sees him not a favourite of the men in blue) and Parker sexes-it up as his greenhorn partner. James is great in the role as the smarmy detective always looking to pick a fight with Willis' character and Farina is solid as usual. Also showing up in small parts are Tom Atkins and John Mahoney. Mindless early 90s action fun. "I used to be a homicide detective. I lost my shield because I said a cop killed my father"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loyalty above all else, except Honour. | V.Good Thriller |
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gashmanflirty@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just what you expect from Bruce Willis in that decade. He plays the character of drunken failure but always comes out on the good side.I enjoyed it from start to finish. V.good thriller of the 90's with good character personalities working off each other/ j. Parker gave it the romance feel and it worked well. The film itself had v.good action sequences and the length of the film was probably just about right. The consistent negative feeling towards Hardy throughput the film from other cops adds to effort that he has to put in to prove he is right and gain vindication. This struggle allows the film to develop its journey. Thanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I quite liked it, not a classic but entertaining enough.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Striking Distance is set in Pittsburgh where Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) has just had to testify against his partner & cousin Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli), on his way to a policeman's ball with his father Vincent (John Mahoney) they get a call to say that a wanted murderer is being pursued. The two Hardy's decide to help out & give chase but end up crashing their car, when Tom regains consciousness he finds the murder suspect gone & his father dead. Two years later & Tom has been forced to take a job as a river patrol man as he has become an alcoholic loser, suddenly dead bodies begin to be found in the rivers around Pittsburgh that Tom patrol. Tom is convinced the killer is back but discovers that officially the new murders have no connection to the earlier ones, Tom is sure that a big cover-up is going on & that the killer is targeting him personally... Written & directed by Rowdy Herrington there doesn't seem to be much love for this much maligned action thriller with even star Bruce Willis saying 'it sucked' while on a chat-show in 2004, hey Bruce I have news for you Striking Distance is nowhere near the worst film you have appeared in. Hudson Hawk (1991), Color of Night (1994) & Cop Out (2010) anyone? Anyway, Striking Distance was known under the title Three Rivers during production & is a decent enough action thriller. One suspects that maybe Willis was trying to star in another Die Hard (1988) but his character here is much less likable or quotable. The script is nothing more than a string of cop film clich&eacute;s stringed together around a fairly basic murder mystery plot & every so often there's a big action set-piece. As it is I quite liked Striking Distance, there are a few decent one-liners, the character's although clich&eacute;d are given life by a good cast or pro's & there's enough action here to satisfy most. There's a particularly good car chase at the start. As I said the clich&eacute;s come thick & fast, a disgraced alcoholic cop, a cover-up, a killer who taunts the cops, feelings of guilt & remorse & loss, honour & family connections. At just under 100 minutes maybe it's a little long but there's enough going on to keep ones interest even if the murder mystery may be a little easy to figure out & a bit too improbable to take seriously. Also the ending features a little overkill when it comes to the villain dying as he comes back from apparently being dead at least four times in ten minutes! There are some good action set-pieces here including a great car chase with one of my personal favourite moments from any chase from any film when the cars start jumping over those humps & shoot up in the air one behind the other. There are boat chases, shoot-outs, fights & a bit of suspense as a mystery killer stalks & kills a few people too. Nicely enough shot there's not much style here but it looks alright. With a supposed budget of about $30,000,000 this has the usual glossy Hollywood production values & is well made. There's a very good cast here including Bruce Willis, Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James & Tom Atkins with the only weak link the ever awful Sarah Jessica Parker in an early role. Striking Distance is a pretty good action thriller, it has a reasonable murder mystery, some clich&eacute;d cop drama & some good action scenes. It's certainly no worse than a lot of routine Hollywood action thrillers, you could do a lot worse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific mystery action thriller with the man himself in the lead role...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I often start Bruce Willis reviews with a disclaimer...I LOVE Bruce Willis. He can rarely do wrong with the exception of most the 2000's (small joke.) Striking Distance was solidly into his leading man career that made him an action superstar. Striking Distance didn't appear to have the enormous budget of like minded Willis vehicles (30 million vs 70 million for Die Hard 2, 3 years earlier) but that is part of its charm. Striking Distance is part mystery, part thriller, a dash of action, and some great character depth even if the lead character is a little bit predictable as a washed up, alcoholic, traumatically scarred former cop. Willis plays the broody alcoholic like nobodies business. The mystery is solid, and the action scenes are well done. It even features one of the best and most underplayed car/boat chase scenes in action film history...or at least the nineties. A terrific supporting cast of whose who nineties character actors help move the story along and support Willis throughout. Sometimes movie watchers like mystery, dislike action, or some variation of such but Striking Distance gives a little of all of the major genres to make it the perfect film for just pure entertainment. Bruce Willis is the iconic macho man. I could watch him do just about anything. As the aforementioned brooding former cop spending his days as barely more than a security guard on the waters. The character is not revolutionary and can be considered predictable but Willis makes Tom Hardy the best he can possibly be and that's a bad ass good guy. Remember Sarah Jessica Parker before she was Sex and The City's Carrie Bradshaw? Me neither but she is cute and vivacious as fellow boat cop Jo Christman. The character doesn't truly fit into the dreary, dark and often foreboding setting but somehow Parker impressively makes it work. Equally impressive is the fact that Parker and Willis do have decent chemistry and their romance somehow works although it feels forced into the story at times. The whose who supporting cast I mentioned include talented character actors, and TV actors. The most noteworthy are Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James, Robert Pastorelli (really terrific), and John Mahoney (small role but really terrific as Willis' decorated cop father.) Director Rowdy Herrington isn't big in Hollywood but he can be attributed to helming the 80's classic Roadhouse and now Striking Distance. Given his ability to direct two big leading men and let them be what the audiences love should account for something. I have a feeling though Herrington's directing ability ends there. Given something without a leading man probably wouldn't account for much although I haven't seen any of his other work. Striking Distance is just plainly entertaining. It isn't mind blowing and it isn't likely to be most peoples favorite film but it is one that I frequently go back to on a lazy Sunday afternoon for some simple, well made entertainment. It also isn't necessarily considering one of Willis' big films by any means but at the same time is gem amongst his work from the nineties. Definitely worth watching at least once and you'll find its charm beneath the surface. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG this has to be the most horrible movie in history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glennataylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would rather watch reruns of the Smother's brothers. This movie is beyond pathetic. SJP is hideous, i wouldn't sleep with her for $5000. I actually met Demi and her mother during the filming of this movie, I served her lunch. They were both beautiful and delightful. If this (SJP) bitch could be more annoying and ugly it would be difficult, I would rather sleep with Oprah. Hideous, ugly, nasty, no-talent Pig.Behind that is the bad, really bad acting of the rest of the 'cast". No plot, bad acting, predictable scenes, it's like Woody Allen decided to make another bad movie that wasn't "supposed" to be funny. It is so contrived and horrid it's ridiculous, I want to vomit when i SEE HER. If I could break her face with a hammer I would be the happiest man on Earth. She can't act, she is ugly, she is pathetic. F>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>> I hate her guts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder and revenge on the waters, in a high octane thriller that strikes back
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like John Q, Striking Distance is another film, that leaves me in an enigma, of how panned it was. This is just as good as a lot of other Willis actioners. Most of Willis's films I like, and this is no exception. It's really a very well plotted revenge thriller, with a great car chase, I might add, which left this flick playing over a couple of months in Adelaide. I like the family angle to it. Willis like his father, (John Mahoney, before Frasier, and years after Code Of Silence, which he made a brief appearance in) is a Pittsburgh cop. So is his Uncle (Dennis Farina) and his two other sons, one of them who's on trial for battery, where Willis gone up against him, telling the court the real version, much to the bitter dislike of his fellow officers. Like Willis's character, Tom Hardy, (catchy) says "Look where telling the truth's got me". Sadly at the end of the chase, things went awry, where Mahoney is executed. There's a bigger picture to this story, and I'm not gonna spoil it for ya. Soon after, Farina's bad cop son, where things are not looking to good for him, threatens to jump off the bridge saying "Cops don't go to prison. I'm not going". Well, bad cops do. Well, he jumps. His body's never recovered. Cut to a couple of years later, disgraced cop, Willis, now drowning his sorrows in alcohol, and making the best of his stinking situation, now works as a river cop. Everything's just dandy. He lives on a houseboat, has a cat, even gets a surprise visit later from Farina's other out of control, boozing son, now ex cop, (Tom Sizemore, quite impressive here) who like the other cops, initially had it in for Hardy too. Things are looking up when he's partnered with Jo, new to the job. But now things are about to become a living hell, where for Hardy, his haunted past returns, though he's always been haunted, since those tragic events years prior. A score of dead young women, start surfacing on the river waters, all of who have been sexually involved with Willis. He's convinced this is the work of the same killer, responsible for his father's execution. So here's a great thriller ride for you. Too, as an added treat, we have an unrelated action scene on a houseboat, where some hijackers have taken it over, so it's good ol Bruce to the rescue. Too near the end, in it's horrifying revelation, where the killer comes into light, we really learn about family and loyalty, where again to finish the killer off, a cattle crod is used, that instantly had me remembering that scene in The Last Boy Scout. And like the end of Cobra, Willis gets to punch out the loud mouthed cop. See, this film has everything, including a bit of romance and a nice after ending. For Willis fans, specially. Check out the classic opening with the remote control car, cool like the rest of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance-Strike **** for this Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We could literally call this excellent thriller ALL IN THE FAMILY as it deals with a family of police caught up in a series of serial killings that eventually takes the life of the father of Bruce Willis. Scorned by police when he turns his own cousin in on an unrelated police matter, and his persistence that the man found guilty of the crime is innocent and that the real killer is none other than a police officer. The plot twists are great and there is plenty of action. Bruce Willis has the perfect part for himself and he is aided by Sarah Jessica Palmer, who has another assigned agenda on her part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full of holes, clich&eacute;s, emoting, but a decent car chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    plex
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see Bruce Willis develop his 2-dimensional acting "chops" in this, one of his earliest action flicks. He basically has 3 emotions: the overly subdued "I'm to cool to care" tone, the aloof/smug tone, and the yelling tone. The facial contortions he exhibits when he shoots a gun is so ham and often repeated throughout his career. ( Don't get me wrong, some of his films, if not his work, I am very fond of). You either love Sarah J, Parker or not. But it strikes me odd that she has been in SO many love scenes and starred in the Sex & The City shows and movies, yet she obviously takes herself too serious as their must be a no-nip clause in all of her contracts. I guess whats good enough for serious actresses like Helen Mirren, Susan Sarandon, Kate Winslet, and Julianne Moore isn't good enough for her. The film: This is a 19 year old movie, so I am going to assume the plot has been well covered here. But I couldn't get passed a couple of things: Great opening car chase scene, highly frenetic, however father and son are having a completely sedate personal conversation. Its one thing to be in control of your emotions, its another being inhuman. So they get in this rolling car crash, its the middle of the day and apparently they all just sat there for hours and hours because its dark when the other cops ( some involved in the pursuit) arrive at the scene. Second big thing, you have our villain, a cop. He's on the bridge for the longest time. All of his relatives are cops, his dad is a cop. There's is the omnipotent river patrol, who our protagonist joins later in the film. Yet, when the villain jumps in, the river patrol cant immediately find him? After all, all of the other dead bodies are found, and apparently the river is pretty clean ( of course not) because we see night-time underwater sequences. Wouldn't they want his body recovered? They certainly had the resources. Minor things: Why was the guy who dumped a throw-rug so anxious to risk life&limb and his car ( which explodes) over it? Was this our villain? Never explained. The worst things for me had to be Sarah's mushy court-room testimony, and Brion James ( who I like in other films) who is so over-the-top angry about everything its just plain humorous, or his diatribe in the end when he eats crow and ego strokes Bruce. Really cheesy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Land shark.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hardy is a fifth-generation cop. When his father dies during the chase of a serial killer, Hardy further complicates matters by implicating his partner and cousin Jimmy in a police brutality case. Two years after Jimmy is believed to have committed suicide, women from Hardy's past start to turn up dead, and his father's alleged killer is found. Believing that the alleged killer is a patsy, Hardy conducts his own illegal investigation into his father's own death, and the women's deaths as well. Hardy and the killer ultimately lock horns in a showdown that ties all the loose ends on both case. It's pretty formulaic stuff for Willis, during the time I like to refer to as his 'chubby era'. He had a pretty bad run of films between 93 to 95, and was finally broke by DHWAV in the summer of 95. It's fun stuff though while it lasts, Cop turns alcoholic, argues a lot with Farina and James, and the killer turns up at the end, but isn't surprising as his name is pretty high up on the credits at the beginning. Parker is fine, but if her character was cut out of the story, it wouldn't damage the narrative. If your a Willis fine, it's a good movie with no surprises.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard the title and who starred in somewhere, I am pretty sure it was from seeing the DVD cover, I guess I watched it just to see some reasonable action fun with the two lead stars I knew. Basically Det. Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) comes from a generation of cops, and he is devastated when his father Vince (John Mahoney) dies during the chase of a serial killer, and after he gets himself in an argument with his partner and cousin Det. Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli). Two years later Tom is working as part of the river rescue police, but is pulled back into action with new partner Jo Christman (Sarah Jessica Parker) when possibly the same killer, nicknamed the Polish Hill strangler, is on the loose again. The victims seem to be women that Tom knew, making him a prime suspect, and no-one apart from maybe Jo believes it is the same killer from the past, and he will have to find the right clues to prove his innocence. Keeping an eye on him is Capt. Nick Detillo (Dennis Farina), an acquaintance from two years ago, and Tom and Jo and do come across some small clues, it is obvious that they are slowly falling for each other. Eventually when trapped, Tom finally gets the truth from Nick, that Jimmy was the killer, he has been copycatting the crimes, and he was the one who killed his father, but in the end of course the guilty are caught and the good guys go back to the better life. Also starring Tom Sizemore as Det. Danny Detillo, Brion James as Det. Eddie Eiler, Timothy Busfield as Tony Sacco and Poseidon's Andre Braugher as Dist. Atty. Frank Morris. The acting was a little flat in parts, and they could have been a few more explosive and gun filled chase and action sequences, I will admit as well I didn't exactly pay the fullest attention while watching, but I guess as a cop looking for a serial killer story is is okay, an alright crime thriller. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The killer was caught or was he?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A homicide detective tracking a serial killer alienates himself from his fellow officers when he suggests that this killer who also killed his father/police Ltd in a high speed car chase may be one of their own men. He gets demoted to the harbour patrol, but still his obsession grows to prove that it was an officer that murdered his father and the girls. A very presentable, slick cop after serial killer thriller with a dependable cast (Bruce Willis, Sarah Jessica Parker, Denis Farina, Brion James, Tom Sizemore and Robert Pastorelli) and interesting backdrop (the beat isn't the streets, but a river system) despite the same old-same, same-old plotting with stock clich&eacute;s and some very implausible revelations. Yes it does go over-the-top for its outlandish climax, but its always exciting, eccentric and high-octane in its routine action and this can said about Brad Fiedel's scorching music too. The opening car chase sequence is actually quite well done by director Rowdy Herrington (who does a durable job throughout with the tough thrills and humid dramas), the taut script keeps it suspenseful and before the killer murders the girl/s he plays the seductively catchy tune Li'l Red Riding Hood by Sam the Sham and the Pharaohs. Willis provides your usual gruff, maverick cop who likes to get on the bottle (because of past events that sees him not a favourite of the men in blue) and Parker sexes-it up as his greenhorn partner. James is great in the role as the smarmy detective always looking to pick a fight with Willis' character and Farina is solid as usual. Also showing up in small parts are Tom Atkins and John Mahoney. Mindless early 90s action fun. "I used to be a homicide detective. I lost my shield because I said a cop killed my father"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loyalty above all else, except Honour. | V.Good Thriller |
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gashmanflirty@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just what you expect from Bruce Willis in that decade. He plays the character of drunken failure but always comes out on the good side.I enjoyed it from start to finish. V.good thriller of the 90's with good character personalities working off each other/ j. Parker gave it the romance feel and it worked well. The film itself had v.good action sequences and the length of the film was probably just about right. The consistent negative feeling towards Hardy throughput the film from other cops adds to effort that he has to put in to prove he is right and gain vindication. This struggle allows the film to develop its journey. Thanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I quite liked it, not a classic but entertaining enough.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Striking Distance is set in Pittsburgh where Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) has just had to testify against his partner & cousin Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli), on his way to a policeman's ball with his father Vincent (John Mahoney) they get a call to say that a wanted murderer is being pursued. The two Hardy's decide to help out & give chase but end up crashing their car, when Tom regains consciousness he finds the murder suspect gone & his father dead. Two years later & Tom has been forced to take a job as a river patrol man as he has become an alcoholic loser, suddenly dead bodies begin to be found in the rivers around Pittsburgh that Tom patrol. Tom is convinced the killer is back but discovers that officially the new murders have no connection to the earlier ones, Tom is sure that a big cover-up is going on & that the killer is targeting him personally... Written & directed by Rowdy Herrington there doesn't seem to be much love for this much maligned action thriller with even star Bruce Willis saying 'it sucked' while on a chat-show in 2004, hey Bruce I have news for you Striking Distance is nowhere near the worst film you have appeared in. Hudson Hawk (1991), Color of Night (1994) & Cop Out (2010) anyone? Anyway, Striking Distance was known under the title Three Rivers during production & is a decent enough action thriller. One suspects that maybe Willis was trying to star in another Die Hard (1988) but his character here is much less likable or quotable. The script is nothing more than a string of cop film clich&eacute;s stringed together around a fairly basic murder mystery plot & every so often there's a big action set-piece. As it is I quite liked Striking Distance, there are a few decent one-liners, the character's although clich&eacute;d are given life by a good cast or pro's & there's enough action here to satisfy most. There's a particularly good car chase at the start. As I said the clich&eacute;s come thick & fast, a disgraced alcoholic cop, a cover-up, a killer who taunts the cops, feelings of guilt & remorse & loss, honour & family connections. At just under 100 minutes maybe it's a little long but there's enough going on to keep ones interest even if the murder mystery may be a little easy to figure out & a bit too improbable to take seriously. Also the ending features a little overkill when it comes to the villain dying as he comes back from apparently being dead at least four times in ten minutes! There are some good action set-pieces here including a great car chase with one of my personal favourite moments from any chase from any film when the cars start jumping over those humps & shoot up in the air one behind the other. There are boat chases, shoot-outs, fights & a bit of suspense as a mystery killer stalks & kills a few people too. Nicely enough shot there's not much style here but it looks alright. With a supposed budget of about $30,000,000 this has the usual glossy Hollywood production values & is well made. There's a very good cast here including Bruce Willis, Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James & Tom Atkins with the only weak link the ever awful Sarah Jessica Parker in an early role. Striking Distance is a pretty good action thriller, it has a reasonable murder mystery, some clich&eacute;d cop drama & some good action scenes. It's certainly no worse than a lot of routine Hollywood action thrillers, you could do a lot worse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific mystery action thriller with the man himself in the lead role...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I often start Bruce Willis reviews with a disclaimer...I LOVE Bruce Willis. He can rarely do wrong with the exception of most the 2000's (small joke.) Striking Distance was solidly into his leading man career that made him an action superstar. Striking Distance didn't appear to have the enormous budget of like minded Willis vehicles (30 million vs 70 million for Die Hard 2, 3 years earlier) but that is part of its charm. Striking Distance is part mystery, part thriller, a dash of action, and some great character depth even if the lead character is a little bit predictable as a washed up, alcoholic, traumatically scarred former cop. Willis plays the broody alcoholic like nobodies business. The mystery is solid, and the action scenes are well done. It even features one of the best and most underplayed car/boat chase scenes in action film history...or at least the nineties. A terrific supporting cast of whose who nineties character actors help move the story along and support Willis throughout. Sometimes movie watchers like mystery, dislike action, or some variation of such but Striking Distance gives a little of all of the major genres to make it the perfect film for just pure entertainment. Bruce Willis is the iconic macho man. I could watch him do just about anything. As the aforementioned brooding former cop spending his days as barely more than a security guard on the waters. The character is not revolutionary and can be considered predictable but Willis makes Tom Hardy the best he can possibly be and that's a bad ass good guy. Remember Sarah Jessica Parker before she was Sex and The City's Carrie Bradshaw? Me neither but she is cute and vivacious as fellow boat cop Jo Christman. The character doesn't truly fit into the dreary, dark and often foreboding setting but somehow Parker impressively makes it work. Equally impressive is the fact that Parker and Willis do have decent chemistry and their romance somehow works although it feels forced into the story at times. The whose who supporting cast I mentioned include talented character actors, and TV actors. The most noteworthy are Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James, Robert Pastorelli (really terrific), and John Mahoney (small role but really terrific as Willis' decorated cop father.) Director Rowdy Herrington isn't big in Hollywood but he can be attributed to helming the 80's classic Roadhouse and now Striking Distance. Given his ability to direct two big leading men and let them be what the audiences love should account for something. I have a feeling though Herrington's directing ability ends there. Given something without a leading man probably wouldn't account for much although I haven't seen any of his other work. Striking Distance is just plainly entertaining. It isn't mind blowing and it isn't likely to be most peoples favorite film but it is one that I frequently go back to on a lazy Sunday afternoon for some simple, well made entertainment. It also isn't necessarily considering one of Willis' big films by any means but at the same time is gem amongst his work from the nineties. Definitely worth watching at least once and you'll find its charm beneath the surface. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG this has to be the most horrible movie in history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    glennataylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would rather watch reruns of the Smother's brothers. This movie is beyond pathetic. SJP is hideous, i wouldn't sleep with her for $5000. I actually met Demi and her mother during the filming of this movie, I served her lunch. They were both beautiful and delightful. If this (SJP) bitch could be more annoying and ugly it would be difficult, I would rather sleep with Oprah. Hideous, ugly, nasty, no-talent Pig.Behind that is the bad, really bad acting of the rest of the 'cast". No plot, bad acting, predictable scenes, it's like Woody Allen decided to make another bad movie that wasn't "supposed" to be funny. It is so contrived and horrid it's ridiculous, I want to vomit when i SEE HER. If I could break her face with a hammer I would be the happiest man on Earth. She can't act, she is ugly, she is pathetic. F>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>> I hate her guts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder and revenge on the waters, in a high octane thriller that strikes back
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like John Q, Striking Distance is another film, that leaves me in an enigma, of how panned it was. This is just as good as a lot of other Willis actioners. Most of Willis's films I like, and this is no exception. It's really a very well plotted revenge thriller, with a great car chase, I might add, which left this flick playing over a couple of months in Adelaide. I like the family angle to it. Willis like his father, (John Mahoney, before Frasier, and years after Code Of Silence, which he made a brief appearance in) is a Pittsburgh cop. So is his Uncle (Dennis Farina) and his two other sons, one of them who's on trial for battery, where Willis gone up against him, telling the court the real version, much to the bitter dislike of his fellow officers. Like Willis's character, Tom Hardy, (catchy) says "Look where telling the truth's got me". Sadly at the end of the chase, things went awry, where Mahoney is executed. There's a bigger picture to this story, and I'm not gonna spoil it for ya. Soon after, Farina's bad cop son, where things are not looking to good for him, threatens to jump off the bridge saying "Cops don't go to prison. I'm not going". Well, bad cops do. Well, he jumps. His body's never recovered. Cut to a couple of years later, disgraced cop, Willis, now drowning his sorrows in alcohol, and making the best of his stinking situation, now works as a river cop. Everything's just dandy. He lives on a houseboat, has a cat, even gets a surprise visit later from Farina's other out of control, boozing son, now ex cop, (Tom Sizemore, quite impressive here) who like the other cops, initially had it in for Hardy too. Things are looking up when he's partnered with Jo, new to the job. But now things are about to become a living hell, where for Hardy, his haunted past returns, though he's always been haunted, since those tragic events years prior. A score of dead young women, start surfacing on the river waters, all of who have been sexually involved with Willis. He's convinced this is the work of the same killer, responsible for his father's execution. So here's a great thriller ride for you. Too, as an added treat, we have an unrelated action scene on a houseboat, where some hijackers have taken it over, so it's good ol Bruce to the rescue. Too near the end, in it's horrifying revelation, where the killer comes into light, we really learn about family and loyalty, where again to finish the killer off, a cattle crod is used, that instantly had me remembering that scene in The Last Boy Scout. And like the end of Cobra, Willis gets to punch out the loud mouthed cop. See, this film has everything, including a bit of romance and a nice after ending. For Willis fans, specially. Check out the classic opening with the remote control car, cool like the rest of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance-Strike **** for this Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We could literally call this excellent thriller ALL IN THE FAMILY as it deals with a family of police caught up in a series of serial killings that eventually takes the life of the father of Bruce Willis. Scorned by police when he turns his own cousin in on an unrelated police matter, and his persistence that the man found guilty of the crime is innocent and that the real killer is none other than a police officer. The plot twists are great and there is plenty of action. Bruce Willis has the perfect part for himself and he is aided by Sarah Jessica Palmer, who has another assigned agenda on her part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full of holes, clich&eacute;s, emoting, but a decent car chase
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    plex
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see Bruce Willis develop his 2-dimensional acting "chops" in this, one of his earliest action flicks. He basically has 3 emotions: the overly subdued "I'm to cool to care" tone, the aloof/smug tone, and the yelling tone. The facial contortions he exhibits when he shoots a gun is so ham and often repeated throughout his career. ( Don't get me wrong, some of his films, if not his work, I am very fond of). You either love Sarah J, Parker or not. But it strikes me odd that she has been in SO many love scenes and starred in the Sex & The City shows and movies, yet she obviously takes herself too serious as their must be a no-nip clause in all of her contracts. I guess whats good enough for serious actresses like Helen Mirren, Susan Sarandon, Kate Winslet, and Julianne Moore isn't good enough for her. The film: This is a 19 year old movie, so I am going to assume the plot has been well covered here. But I couldn't get passed a couple of things: Great opening car chase scene, highly frenetic, however father and son are having a completely sedate personal conversation. Its one thing to be in control of your emotions, its another being inhuman. So they get in this rolling car crash, its the middle of the day and apparently they all just sat there for hours and hours because its dark when the other cops ( some involved in the pursuit) arrive at the scene. Second big thing, you have our villain, a cop. He's on the bridge for the longest time. All of his relatives are cops, his dad is a cop. There's is the omnipotent river patrol, who our protagonist joins later in the film. Yet, when the villain jumps in, the river patrol cant immediately find him? After all, all of the other dead bodies are found, and apparently the river is pretty clean ( of course not) because we see night-time underwater sequences. Wouldn't they want his body recovered? They certainly had the resources. Minor things: Why was the guy who dumped a throw-rug so anxious to risk life&limb and his car ( which explodes) over it? Was this our villain? Never explained. The worst things for me had to be Sarah's mushy court-room testimony, and Brion James ( who I like in other films) who is so over-the-top angry about everything its just plain humorous, or his diatribe in the end when he eats crow and ego strokes Bruce. Really cheesy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Land shark.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hardy is a fifth-generation cop. When his father dies during the chase of a serial killer, Hardy further complicates matters by implicating his partner and cousin Jimmy in a police brutality case. Two years after Jimmy is believed to have committed suicide, women from Hardy's past start to turn up dead, and his father's alleged killer is found. Believing that the alleged killer is a patsy, Hardy conducts his own illegal investigation into his father's own death, and the women's deaths as well. Hardy and the killer ultimately lock horns in a showdown that ties all the loose ends on both case. It's pretty formulaic stuff for Willis, during the time I like to refer to as his 'chubby era'. He had a pretty bad run of films between 93 to 95, and was finally broke by DHWAV in the summer of 95. It's fun stuff though while it lasts, Cop turns alcoholic, argues a lot with Farina and James, and the killer turns up at the end, but isn't surprising as his name is pretty high up on the credits at the beginning. Parker is fine, but if her character was cut out of the story, it wouldn't damage the narrative. If your a Willis fine, it's a good movie with no surprises.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Striking Distance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard the title and who starred in somewhere, I am pretty sure it was from seeing the DVD cover, I guess I watched it just to see some reasonable action fun with the two lead stars I knew. Basically Det. Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) comes from a generation of cops, and he is devastated when his father Vince (John Mahoney) dies during the chase of a serial killer, and after he gets himself in an argument with his partner and cousin Det. Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli). Two years later Tom is working as part of the river rescue police, but is pulled back into action with new partner Jo Christman (Sarah Jessica Parker) when possibly the same killer, nicknamed the Polish Hill strangler, is on the loose again. The victims seem to be women that Tom knew, making him a prime suspect, and no-one apart from maybe Jo believes it is the same killer from the past, and he will have to find the right clues to prove his innocence. Keeping an eye on him is Capt. Nick Detillo (Dennis Farina), an acquaintance from two years ago, and Tom and Jo and do come across some small clues, it is obvious that they are slowly falling for each other. Eventually when trapped, Tom finally gets the truth from Nick, that Jimmy was the killer, he has been copycatting the crimes, and he was the one who killed his father, but in the end of course the guilty are caught and the good guys go back to the better life. Also starring Tom Sizemore as Det. Danny Detillo, Brion James as Det. Eddie Eiler, Timothy Busfield as Tony Sacco and Poseidon's Andre Braugher as Dist. Atty. Frank Morris. The acting was a little flat in parts, and they could have been a few more explosive and gun filled chase and action sequences, I will admit as well I didn't exactly pay the fullest attention while watching, but I guess as a cop looking for a serial killer story is is okay, an alright crime thriller. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The killer was caught or was he?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A homicide detective tracking a serial killer alienates himself from his fellow officers when he suggests that this killer who also killed his father/police Ltd in a high speed car chase may be one of their own men. He gets demoted to the harbour patrol, but still his obsession grows to prove that it was an officer that murdered his father and the girls. A very presentable, slick cop after serial killer thriller with a dependable cast (Bruce Willis, Sarah Jessica Parker, Denis Farina, Brion James, Tom Sizemore and Robert Pastorelli) and interesting backdrop (the beat isn't the streets, but a river system) despite the same old-same, same-old plotting with stock clich&eacute;s and some very implausible revelations. Yes it does go over-the-top for its outlandish climax, but its always exciting, eccentric and high-octane in its routine action and this can said about Brad Fiedel's scorching music too. The opening car chase sequence is actually quite well done by director Rowdy Herrington (who does a durable job throughout with the tough thrills and humid dramas), the taut script keeps it suspenseful and before the killer murders the girl/s he plays the seductively catchy tune Li'l Red Riding Hood by Sam the Sham and the Pharaohs. Willis provides your usual gruff, maverick cop who likes to get on the bottle (because of past events that sees him not a favourite of the men in blue) and Parker sexes-it up as his greenhorn partner. James is great in the role as the smarmy detective always looking to pick a fight with Willis' character and Farina is solid as usual. Also showing up in small parts are Tom Atkins and John Mahoney. Mindless early 90s action fun. "I used to be a homicide detective. I lost my shield because I said a cop killed my father"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loyalty above all else, except Honour. | V.Good Thriller |
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gashmanflirty@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just what you expect from Bruce Willis in that decade. He plays the character of drunken failure but always comes out on the good side.I enjoyed it from start to finish. V.good thriller of the 90's with good character personalities working off each other/ j. Parker gave it the romance feel and it worked well. The film itself had v.good action sequences and the length of the film was probably just about right. The consistent negative feeling towards Hardy throughput the film from other cops adds to effort that he has to put in to prove he is right and gain vindication. This struggle allows the film to develop its journey. Thanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I quite liked it, not a classic but entertaining enough.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Striking Distance is set in Pittsburgh where Tom Hardy (Bruce Willis) has just had to testify against his partner & cousin Jimmy Detillo (Robert Pastorelli), on his way to a policeman's ball with his father Vincent (John Mahoney) they get a call to say that a wanted murderer is being pursued. The two Hardy's decide to help out & give chase but end up crashing their car, when Tom regains consciousness he finds the murder suspect gone & his father dead. Two years later & Tom has been forced to take a job as a river patrol man as he has become an alcoholic loser, suddenly dead bodies begin to be found in the rivers around Pittsburgh that Tom patrol. Tom is convinced the killer is back but discovers that officially the new murders have no connection to the earlier ones, Tom is sure that a big cover-up is going on & that the killer is targeting him personally... Written & directed by Rowdy Herrington there doesn't seem to be much love for this much maligned action thriller with even star Bruce Willis saying 'it sucked' while on a chat-show in 2004, hey Bruce I have news for you Striking Distance is nowhere near the worst film you have appeared in. Hudson Hawk (1991), Color of Night (1994) & Cop Out (2010) anyone? Anyway, Striking Distance was known under the title Three Rivers during production & is a decent enough action thriller. One suspects that maybe Willis was trying to star in another Die Hard (1988) but his character here is much less likable or quotable. The script is nothing more than a string of cop film clich&eacute;s stringed together around a fairly basic murder mystery plot & every so often there's a big action set-piece. As it is I quite liked Striking Distance, there are a few decent one-liners, the character's although clich&eacute;d are given life by a good cast or pro's & there's enough action here to satisfy most. There's a particularly good car chase at the start. As I said the clich&eacute;s come thick & fast, a disgraced alcoholic cop, a cover-up, a killer who taunts the cops, feelings of guilt & remorse & loss, honour & family connections. At just under 100 minutes maybe it's a little long but there's enough going on to keep ones interest even if the murder mystery may be a little easy to figure out & a bit too improbable to take seriously. Also the ending features a little overkill when it comes to the villain dying as he comes back from apparently being dead at least four times in ten minutes! There are some good action set-pieces here including a great car chase with one of my personal favourite moments from any chase from any film when the cars start jumping over those humps & shoot up in the air one behind the other. There are boat chases, shoot-outs, fights & a bit of suspense as a mystery killer stalks & kills a few people too. Nicely enough shot there's not much style here but it looks alright. With a supposed budget of about $30,000,000 this has the usual glossy Hollywood production values & is well made. There's a very good cast here including Bruce Willis, Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James & Tom Atkins with the only weak link the ever awful Sarah Jessica Parker in an early role. Striking Distance is a pretty good action thriller, it has a reasonable murder mystery, some clich&eacute;d cop drama & some good action scenes. It's certainly no worse than a lot of routine Hollywood action thrillers, you could do a lot worse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific mystery action thriller with the man himself in the lead role...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I often start Bruce Willis reviews with a disclaimer...I LOVE Bruce Willis. He can rarely do wrong with the exception of most the 2000's (small joke.) Striking Distance was solidly into his leading man career that made him an action superstar. Striking Distance didn't appear to have the enormous budget of like minded Willis vehicles (30 million vs 70 million for Die Hard 2, 3 years earlier) but that is part of its charm. Striking Distance is part mystery, part thriller, a dash of action, and some great character depth even if the lead character is a little bit predictable as a washed up, alcoholic, traumatically scarred former cop. Willis plays the broody alcoholic like nobodies business. The mystery is solid, and the action scenes are well done. It even features one of the best and most underplayed car/boat chase scenes in action film history...or at least the nineties. A terrific supporting cast of whose who nineties character actors help move the story along and support Willis throughout. Sometimes movie watchers like mystery, dislike action, or some variation of such but Striking Distance gives a little of all of the major genres to make it the perfect film for just pure entertainment. Bruce Willis is the iconic macho man. I could watch him do just about anything. As the aforementioned brooding former cop spending his days as barely more than a security guard on the waters. The character is not revolutionary and can be considered predictable but Willis makes Tom Hardy the best he can possibly be and that's a bad ass good guy. Remember Sarah Jessica Parker before she was Sex and The City's Carrie Bradshaw? Me neither but she is cute and vivacious as fellow boat cop Jo Christman. The character doesn't truly fit into the dreary, dark and often foreboding setting but somehow Parker impressively makes it work. Equally impressive is the fact that Parker and Willis do have decent chemistry and their romance somehow works although it feels forced into the story at times. The whose who supporting cast I mentioned include talented character actors, and TV actors. The most noteworthy are Dennis Farina, Tom Sizemore, Brion James, Robert Pastorelli (really terrific), and John Mahoney (small role but really terrific as Willis' decorated cop father.) Director Rowdy Herrington isn't big in Hollywood but he can be attributed to helming the 80's classic Roadhouse and now Striking Distance. Given his ability to direct two big leading men and let them be what the audiences love should account for something. I have a feeling though Herrington's directing ability ends there. Given something without a leading man probably wouldn't account for much although I haven't seen any of his other work. Striking Distance is just plainly entertaining. It isn't mind blowing and it isn't likely to be most peoples favorite film but it is one that I frequently go back to on a lazy Sunday afternoon for some simple, well made entertainment. It also isn't necessarily considering one of Willis' big films by any means but at the same time is gem amongst his work from the nineties. Definitely worth watching at least once and you'll find its charm beneath the surface. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
