<filme>
 <id>
  410
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116778
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Kingpin - Estes Loucos Reis do Boliche
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A star bowler whose career was prematurely "cut off" hopes to ride a new prodigy to success and riches.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Roy Munson was raised to be the best bowler in the world (trained early on by his father). But a fellow bowler, Ernie McCracken and a misunderstanding with some rough punks, leaves poor Roy with the loss of his bowling hand! Not to let this get him down, he gets a prosthetic hand and becomes a travelling sales man. But it's really all down hill for him from that night on until ... One day he meets Ishmael who is Amish and sneaks away from the farm to bowl (his fellow Amish would disown him if they knew)! Roy convinces Ishmael to let him be his trainer and he'll make him the best bowler the world has ever seen. Reluctantly Ishmael agrees to go on the road and shortly afterwards actually finds that life outside the farm is quite fun. Soon their paths cross that of Ernie McCracken who is still a top ranking bowler. While Roy's career and life have landed in the toilet bowl, Ernie is still drawing huge crowds and all the babes! They both square off for the ultimate bowling championship .....
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sport
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bowling
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   amish
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tournament
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pennsylvania
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   lancaster county
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Bobby Farrelly
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Peter Farrelly
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Barry Fanaro
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Mort Nathan
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Woody Harrelson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Randy Quaid
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bill Murray
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a STRIK.....OK no pins...i mean puns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DjangoLand
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only recently decided to somewhat commit to participating in contributing reviews to IMDb and reality hit me in the face when realising that it was 17 years ago when this classic came out. 17 years, and boy do i miss these kind of films, When the Farrelly brothers made great comedy movies. Of course they have taken their feet of the pedals, but their first 4 were instant classics. It may not be a laugh out loud film that has you giggling all the way through, but it has a certain charm to it (despite the crudeness) that keeps you smiling throughout. There are plenty of hilarious moments and great one liners. Bill Murray is fantastic as Big Ern and gels brilliantly with Woody Harrelson. The rest of the cast play their parts to make this a must see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Funniest Movies Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_the_Hobo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bowling legend Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) loses a hand to a group of drunks after trying to con them with fellow bowler Ernie McCracken (Bill Murray). Now a drunk promoter with a fake rubber hand, Munson is a shadow of his former self until he hears the fateful sound of a strike. Amish prodigy Ishmael (Randy Quaid) stands to be Munson's shot at winning the largest tournament in the country, but the road there is paved with consequence. This is one of the funniest movies ever made. The Farrelly brothers have given us countless laughs, but this is their best. It brings together some of the most unexpected actors, many out of their element in a comedy, to flawlessly turn a script into a comedic work of art. The laughs are typical Farrelly gross out while remaining truly, deeply funny. Woody Harrelson turns in one of his best performances as the down-but-not-out Munson, wearing a ridiculous wig, outdated clothing, and always his fake rubber hand. Each scene he's in is a lesson in how to lead a comedy, and reminds one of his early days on "Cheers" as the bartender Woody Boyd. His co-star in Quaid is the same; whether it be the murderous, greedy Sheriff is "Hard Rain", or here as the hilariously simple sure relative of the "Vacation" movies Cousin Eddie, Randy Quaid proves his ever surprising versatility as an actor. Bill Murray also fires on all cylinders as the over the top McCracken, Harrelson's arch-nemesis. Murray's last scene is one of the best in the movie; with his hair tossed every which way and his eyes flooding with tears he makes you shocked that he's only been nominated for one Oscar. Vanessa Angel is mostly eye candy but she doesn't have to make up for any acting downfalls. "Kingpin" is well-casted, well-written, consistently engaging and always funny. It brings together a diverse cast and a great script to make one of the funniest movies of our time. Strike it off your bucket list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You have a monkey?....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roy Munson was the best bowler in the world. But a fellow bowler, Ernie McCracken and a misunderstanding with some rough punks, left Roy with the loss of his bowling hand. He gets a prosthetic hand and becomes a travelling salesman. But it's really all down hill for him from that night on until he meets Ishmael who is Amish and sneaks away from the farm to bowl. Roy convinces Ishmael to let him be his trainer and he'll make him the best bowler the world has ever seen. Reluctantly Ishmael agrees to go on the road and shortly afterwards actually finds that life outside the farm is quite fun. Soon their paths cross that of Ernie McCracken who is still a top ranking bowler. While Roy's career and life have landed in the toilet bowl, Ernie is still drawing huge crowds.... Whilenot as good as Dumb and Dumber, the Farrellys comedy still felt pretty fresh and new for it's time of release. If this was released now, it wouldn't have has the plaudits is had, it would probably end up on late night TV, and wouldn't have the great cast. Harrelson is great as Roy, but cannot hold up to Quaid and a brilliant Murray, whenever they are on screen, the film really shines and becomes funny. Sadly, the rest of the film relies on horrid toilet humour and scenes that try and push the boundaries for a '12' movie, it doesn't work and the film has aged badly. That said, the hair is great in this movie, and while the Farrellys haven't really made a good original film for fourteen years, they proved with their first three movies they were a little left-field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hangover cure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jason_curtis24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely hilarious, deadpan stupid at times, and more reserved and subtle at others - its the perfect hangover cure. Harrelson is fantastic as a hard-done-by bowler who got done over ('Munsoned' is the phrase later used, which is his actual name in the film to his annoyance) and is out for another shot at the big time. His sidekick is an innocent religious countryman whose style contrasts well with all the others - Murray is just great, but could have been in it more. One scene, for me, really stands out. Certainly in terms of Gramsci esque masculine humour - Murray is in a eaterie with Harrelson and tells him to 'go outside and eat that', then he tells a waitress to come back after washing off her perfume, finally he says 'hi' to a fit bird sat across the way. Her mum says 'hi' and Murray says 'not you - hi'. The younger fit bird smiles and says 'hi'. This film is just great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny enough comedy,but slightly dry,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin is a funny movie with some laugh out loud scenes,a well thought out storyline and some pretty good actors,but I feel the movie goes on a bit,being two hours long and most animated films would only be an hour and a half,and find a lot of the humor to be a bit dry,not the Farrelly brothers finest work. A former bowler named Roy who hasn't bowled for over twenty years meets Ishmael,who is a natural bowler,Roy wants to get him to bowl for some professional games but it is hard to get him to take part because Ishmael is part of an Amish community,Roy eventually gets to Ishmael when pretends to be Amish himself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Comedy I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    schuster_mark
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I take my comedy seriously (no pun intended). I grew up watching the original cast of SNL, three stooges and actors like Gene Wilder. They all had something special, and I think remain extremely special 30 years later. Kingpin has that rare "something special". I had to watch this movie a few times before I fully appreciated the "once in a lifetime" performances by Harrelson and Murray, and outstanding writing by the Farrelly brothers. This movie, unlike most other comedies I've seen, continually provides genuinely funny moments throughout the entire movie. There are very few comedies I have ever watched that I can say the same about. It's like all the stars in the sky aligned for one perfect moment and in that moment they filmed "Kingpin". Now, this film may not be for every one. It's crude, rude and in your face comedy. It's typical Farrelly brother fare. If you like that, or even if you don't and just like the silly comedy of Bill Murray (before he went all serious) - then this movie is well worth a watch. Definitely a 10 out of 10 in my book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bowl me over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Following their success with "Dumb and Dumber", the Farrelly brothers directed "Kingpin", about a mangled bowler (Woody Harrelson) who trains an Amish man (Randy Quaid) to bowl. Since this is the guys behind "There's Something About Mary", there are naturally a few scenes with no purpose except to have a gross-out gag. But it is pretty funny throughout most of the movie, with a lot of mild gags. I suspect that the Amish didn't like it. But I liked it, and I recommend it. Also starring Vanessa Angel, Bill Murray, Chris Elliott, William Jordan and Lin Shaye (the sunburned neighbor in "TSAM" and the retiring flight attendant in "Snakes on a Plane").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Laughs from a Terrific Cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin (1996) *** (out of 4) Bowler Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) has everything in front of him until another bowler (Bill Murray) sells him out to a group of men they've just hustled and they end up cutting off Munson bowling hand, which puts an end to his career. Seventeen years later Munson is a worthless drunk who sees his chance back in the hopes of a Amish man (Randy Quaid) who he plans on getting to Reno for a big tournament. This was the Farrelly brothers follow-up to DUMB AND DUMBER and unlike that film, this one here wasn't a huge hit out of the gate and instead it took sometime to build up its cult following. I'm really not sure why this movie didn't hit it big when first released but time has been quite friendly to the raunchy comedy as it's certainly one of the better comedies of its period thanks in large part to a terrific cast, a nice story and plenty of big laughs. I think the story itself really isn't anything too special as it's pretty much your typical road movie with the biggest difference being the bowling subplot. I think what really makes this film so special are the three leads who are so perfect in their roles that you really can't imagine anyone else in the world playing them. Harrelson has always been an underrated comic actor and he does a very good job here and manages to get laughs out of the smallest stuff. Just the way he laughs or looks at someone can get a laugh but even better is the way he sells some of the jokes including a hilarious bit on the Amish farm where he pretends to know what he's doing, which leads him to "milking" a bull. Quaid can play an idiot like no other and make it look very easy. The way he brings this Amish guy to life is a lot of fun to watch because you really do feel as if you're watching someone real and someone experiencing the real world for the first time. Murray does what only he can as that type of comedy isn't easy and I can't think of anyone else who can pull it off. Apparently Murray ad-libbed just about every word in the film and the way he pulls this character off really helps bring in the laughs. Vanessa Angel fits in with the boys very well and manages a few nice laughs of her own as does Chris Elliott in his brief scenes. I think the film would have benefited had it lost about ten-minutes worth of footage because at just under two-hours the film is a little too long. The stuff with Angel's boyfriend isn't the funniest bits here and everything that happens with him in the second half should have been left out. The great thing about KINGPIN is that it never really delivers the type of laugh that you might expect and that's why the film works so well. The movie will have a scene set up and you might think you know where it's going but the funny part is seeing how different it plays out. The movie has some fairly low-taste laughs but the brothers were clearly just warming up as THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT MARY was just two years away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crude, rude, silly and........hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Can't believe this isn't rated higher, I have always loved this totally silly movie since I saw it in the theater years ago. There are some lulls here and there and maybe too much character development (if that's possible) but Woody is spot on, Murry is just insanely funny with his hair don't, and the rest of the cast is great too. Ishmael's slow decline into every vice there is is great. I'm sure this is not to everyones taste and I'm glad, not all of us are into bull seamen and oral sex with old lady jokes but for those who are you will be quite content. Even the bowling is funny in this early Farrelly brothers film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and bleak
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taygeta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike Harrelson's other masterpiece, White Men Can't Jump, this comedy certainly promises laughs and repeated viewings. On the other hand, there is a constant feeling of desolation and sadness. Ultimately this film could be described as being real. The performances from every cast member serve to create distinct and memorable characters, including the genius Bill Murray as the veritable king of the pins. Depending on who you are speaking with, this movie may have even spawned a dictionary worthy term, although I will leave it out of this review in the interest of little disclosure. "10 frames, that's for Quakers!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a STRIK.....OK no pins...i mean puns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DjangoLand
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only recently decided to somewhat commit to participating in contributing reviews to IMDb and reality hit me in the face when realising that it was 17 years ago when this classic came out. 17 years, and boy do i miss these kind of films, When the Farrelly brothers made great comedy movies. Of course they have taken their feet of the pedals, but their first 4 were instant classics. It may not be a laugh out loud film that has you giggling all the way through, but it has a certain charm to it (despite the crudeness) that keeps you smiling throughout. There are plenty of hilarious moments and great one liners. Bill Murray is fantastic as Big Ern and gels brilliantly with Woody Harrelson. The rest of the cast play their parts to make this a must see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Funniest Movies Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_the_Hobo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bowling legend Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) loses a hand to a group of drunks after trying to con them with fellow bowler Ernie McCracken (Bill Murray). Now a drunk promoter with a fake rubber hand, Munson is a shadow of his former self until he hears the fateful sound of a strike. Amish prodigy Ishmael (Randy Quaid) stands to be Munson's shot at winning the largest tournament in the country, but the road there is paved with consequence. This is one of the funniest movies ever made. The Farrelly brothers have given us countless laughs, but this is their best. It brings together some of the most unexpected actors, many out of their element in a comedy, to flawlessly turn a script into a comedic work of art. The laughs are typical Farrelly gross out while remaining truly, deeply funny. Woody Harrelson turns in one of his best performances as the down-but-not-out Munson, wearing a ridiculous wig, outdated clothing, and always his fake rubber hand. Each scene he's in is a lesson in how to lead a comedy, and reminds one of his early days on "Cheers" as the bartender Woody Boyd. His co-star in Quaid is the same; whether it be the murderous, greedy Sheriff is "Hard Rain", or here as the hilariously simple sure relative of the "Vacation" movies Cousin Eddie, Randy Quaid proves his ever surprising versatility as an actor. Bill Murray also fires on all cylinders as the over the top McCracken, Harrelson's arch-nemesis. Murray's last scene is one of the best in the movie; with his hair tossed every which way and his eyes flooding with tears he makes you shocked that he's only been nominated for one Oscar. Vanessa Angel is mostly eye candy but she doesn't have to make up for any acting downfalls. "Kingpin" is well-casted, well-written, consistently engaging and always funny. It brings together a diverse cast and a great script to make one of the funniest movies of our time. Strike it off your bucket list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You have a monkey?....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roy Munson was the best bowler in the world. But a fellow bowler, Ernie McCracken and a misunderstanding with some rough punks, left Roy with the loss of his bowling hand. He gets a prosthetic hand and becomes a travelling salesman. But it's really all down hill for him from that night on until he meets Ishmael who is Amish and sneaks away from the farm to bowl. Roy convinces Ishmael to let him be his trainer and he'll make him the best bowler the world has ever seen. Reluctantly Ishmael agrees to go on the road and shortly afterwards actually finds that life outside the farm is quite fun. Soon their paths cross that of Ernie McCracken who is still a top ranking bowler. While Roy's career and life have landed in the toilet bowl, Ernie is still drawing huge crowds.... Whilenot as good as Dumb and Dumber, the Farrellys comedy still felt pretty fresh and new for it's time of release. If this was released now, it wouldn't have has the plaudits is had, it would probably end up on late night TV, and wouldn't have the great cast. Harrelson is great as Roy, but cannot hold up to Quaid and a brilliant Murray, whenever they are on screen, the film really shines and becomes funny. Sadly, the rest of the film relies on horrid toilet humour and scenes that try and push the boundaries for a '12' movie, it doesn't work and the film has aged badly. That said, the hair is great in this movie, and while the Farrellys haven't really made a good original film for fourteen years, they proved with their first three movies they were a little left-field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hangover cure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jason_curtis24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely hilarious, deadpan stupid at times, and more reserved and subtle at others - its the perfect hangover cure. Harrelson is fantastic as a hard-done-by bowler who got done over ('Munsoned' is the phrase later used, which is his actual name in the film to his annoyance) and is out for another shot at the big time. His sidekick is an innocent religious countryman whose style contrasts well with all the others - Murray is just great, but could have been in it more. One scene, for me, really stands out. Certainly in terms of Gramsci esque masculine humour - Murray is in a eaterie with Harrelson and tells him to 'go outside and eat that', then he tells a waitress to come back after washing off her perfume, finally he says 'hi' to a fit bird sat across the way. Her mum says 'hi' and Murray says 'not you - hi'. The younger fit bird smiles and says 'hi'. This film is just great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny enough comedy,but slightly dry,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin is a funny movie with some laugh out loud scenes,a well thought out storyline and some pretty good actors,but I feel the movie goes on a bit,being two hours long and most animated films would only be an hour and a half,and find a lot of the humor to be a bit dry,not the Farrelly brothers finest work. A former bowler named Roy who hasn't bowled for over twenty years meets Ishmael,who is a natural bowler,Roy wants to get him to bowl for some professional games but it is hard to get him to take part because Ishmael is part of an Amish community,Roy eventually gets to Ishmael when pretends to be Amish himself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Comedy I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    schuster_mark
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I take my comedy seriously (no pun intended). I grew up watching the original cast of SNL, three stooges and actors like Gene Wilder. They all had something special, and I think remain extremely special 30 years later. Kingpin has that rare "something special". I had to watch this movie a few times before I fully appreciated the "once in a lifetime" performances by Harrelson and Murray, and outstanding writing by the Farrelly brothers. This movie, unlike most other comedies I've seen, continually provides genuinely funny moments throughout the entire movie. There are very few comedies I have ever watched that I can say the same about. It's like all the stars in the sky aligned for one perfect moment and in that moment they filmed "Kingpin". Now, this film may not be for every one. It's crude, rude and in your face comedy. It's typical Farrelly brother fare. If you like that, or even if you don't and just like the silly comedy of Bill Murray (before he went all serious) - then this movie is well worth a watch. Definitely a 10 out of 10 in my book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bowl me over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Following their success with "Dumb and Dumber", the Farrelly brothers directed "Kingpin", about a mangled bowler (Woody Harrelson) who trains an Amish man (Randy Quaid) to bowl. Since this is the guys behind "There's Something About Mary", there are naturally a few scenes with no purpose except to have a gross-out gag. But it is pretty funny throughout most of the movie, with a lot of mild gags. I suspect that the Amish didn't like it. But I liked it, and I recommend it. Also starring Vanessa Angel, Bill Murray, Chris Elliott, William Jordan and Lin Shaye (the sunburned neighbor in "TSAM" and the retiring flight attendant in "Snakes on a Plane").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Laughs from a Terrific Cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin (1996) *** (out of 4) Bowler Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) has everything in front of him until another bowler (Bill Murray) sells him out to a group of men they've just hustled and they end up cutting off Munson bowling hand, which puts an end to his career. Seventeen years later Munson is a worthless drunk who sees his chance back in the hopes of a Amish man (Randy Quaid) who he plans on getting to Reno for a big tournament. This was the Farrelly brothers follow-up to DUMB AND DUMBER and unlike that film, this one here wasn't a huge hit out of the gate and instead it took sometime to build up its cult following. I'm really not sure why this movie didn't hit it big when first released but time has been quite friendly to the raunchy comedy as it's certainly one of the better comedies of its period thanks in large part to a terrific cast, a nice story and plenty of big laughs. I think the story itself really isn't anything too special as it's pretty much your typical road movie with the biggest difference being the bowling subplot. I think what really makes this film so special are the three leads who are so perfect in their roles that you really can't imagine anyone else in the world playing them. Harrelson has always been an underrated comic actor and he does a very good job here and manages to get laughs out of the smallest stuff. Just the way he laughs or looks at someone can get a laugh but even better is the way he sells some of the jokes including a hilarious bit on the Amish farm where he pretends to know what he's doing, which leads him to "milking" a bull. Quaid can play an idiot like no other and make it look very easy. The way he brings this Amish guy to life is a lot of fun to watch because you really do feel as if you're watching someone real and someone experiencing the real world for the first time. Murray does what only he can as that type of comedy isn't easy and I can't think of anyone else who can pull it off. Apparently Murray ad-libbed just about every word in the film and the way he pulls this character off really helps bring in the laughs. Vanessa Angel fits in with the boys very well and manages a few nice laughs of her own as does Chris Elliott in his brief scenes. I think the film would have benefited had it lost about ten-minutes worth of footage because at just under two-hours the film is a little too long. The stuff with Angel's boyfriend isn't the funniest bits here and everything that happens with him in the second half should have been left out. The great thing about KINGPIN is that it never really delivers the type of laugh that you might expect and that's why the film works so well. The movie will have a scene set up and you might think you know where it's going but the funny part is seeing how different it plays out. The movie has some fairly low-taste laughs but the brothers were clearly just warming up as THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT MARY was just two years away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crude, rude, silly and........hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Can't believe this isn't rated higher, I have always loved this totally silly movie since I saw it in the theater years ago. There are some lulls here and there and maybe too much character development (if that's possible) but Woody is spot on, Murry is just insanely funny with his hair don't, and the rest of the cast is great too. Ishmael's slow decline into every vice there is is great. I'm sure this is not to everyones taste and I'm glad, not all of us are into bull seamen and oral sex with old lady jokes but for those who are you will be quite content. Even the bowling is funny in this early Farrelly brothers film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and bleak
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taygeta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike Harrelson's other masterpiece, White Men Can't Jump, this comedy certainly promises laughs and repeated viewings. On the other hand, there is a constant feeling of desolation and sadness. Ultimately this film could be described as being real. The performances from every cast member serve to create distinct and memorable characters, including the genius Bill Murray as the veritable king of the pins. Depending on who you are speaking with, this movie may have even spawned a dictionary worthy term, although I will leave it out of this review in the interest of little disclosure. "10 frames, that's for Quakers!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a STRIK.....OK no pins...i mean puns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DjangoLand
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only recently decided to somewhat commit to participating in contributing reviews to IMDb and reality hit me in the face when realising that it was 17 years ago when this classic came out. 17 years, and boy do i miss these kind of films, When the Farrelly brothers made great comedy movies. Of course they have taken their feet of the pedals, but their first 4 were instant classics. It may not be a laugh out loud film that has you giggling all the way through, but it has a certain charm to it (despite the crudeness) that keeps you smiling throughout. There are plenty of hilarious moments and great one liners. Bill Murray is fantastic as Big Ern and gels brilliantly with Woody Harrelson. The rest of the cast play their parts to make this a must see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Funniest Movies Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_the_Hobo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bowling legend Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) loses a hand to a group of drunks after trying to con them with fellow bowler Ernie McCracken (Bill Murray). Now a drunk promoter with a fake rubber hand, Munson is a shadow of his former self until he hears the fateful sound of a strike. Amish prodigy Ishmael (Randy Quaid) stands to be Munson's shot at winning the largest tournament in the country, but the road there is paved with consequence. This is one of the funniest movies ever made. The Farrelly brothers have given us countless laughs, but this is their best. It brings together some of the most unexpected actors, many out of their element in a comedy, to flawlessly turn a script into a comedic work of art. The laughs are typical Farrelly gross out while remaining truly, deeply funny. Woody Harrelson turns in one of his best performances as the down-but-not-out Munson, wearing a ridiculous wig, outdated clothing, and always his fake rubber hand. Each scene he's in is a lesson in how to lead a comedy, and reminds one of his early days on "Cheers" as the bartender Woody Boyd. His co-star in Quaid is the same; whether it be the murderous, greedy Sheriff is "Hard Rain", or here as the hilariously simple sure relative of the "Vacation" movies Cousin Eddie, Randy Quaid proves his ever surprising versatility as an actor. Bill Murray also fires on all cylinders as the over the top McCracken, Harrelson's arch-nemesis. Murray's last scene is one of the best in the movie; with his hair tossed every which way and his eyes flooding with tears he makes you shocked that he's only been nominated for one Oscar. Vanessa Angel is mostly eye candy but she doesn't have to make up for any acting downfalls. "Kingpin" is well-casted, well-written, consistently engaging and always funny. It brings together a diverse cast and a great script to make one of the funniest movies of our time. Strike it off your bucket list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You have a monkey?....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roy Munson was the best bowler in the world. But a fellow bowler, Ernie McCracken and a misunderstanding with some rough punks, left Roy with the loss of his bowling hand. He gets a prosthetic hand and becomes a travelling salesman. But it's really all down hill for him from that night on until he meets Ishmael who is Amish and sneaks away from the farm to bowl. Roy convinces Ishmael to let him be his trainer and he'll make him the best bowler the world has ever seen. Reluctantly Ishmael agrees to go on the road and shortly afterwards actually finds that life outside the farm is quite fun. Soon their paths cross that of Ernie McCracken who is still a top ranking bowler. While Roy's career and life have landed in the toilet bowl, Ernie is still drawing huge crowds.... Whilenot as good as Dumb and Dumber, the Farrellys comedy still felt pretty fresh and new for it's time of release. If this was released now, it wouldn't have has the plaudits is had, it would probably end up on late night TV, and wouldn't have the great cast. Harrelson is great as Roy, but cannot hold up to Quaid and a brilliant Murray, whenever they are on screen, the film really shines and becomes funny. Sadly, the rest of the film relies on horrid toilet humour and scenes that try and push the boundaries for a '12' movie, it doesn't work and the film has aged badly. That said, the hair is great in this movie, and while the Farrellys haven't really made a good original film for fourteen years, they proved with their first three movies they were a little left-field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hangover cure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jason_curtis24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely hilarious, deadpan stupid at times, and more reserved and subtle at others - its the perfect hangover cure. Harrelson is fantastic as a hard-done-by bowler who got done over ('Munsoned' is the phrase later used, which is his actual name in the film to his annoyance) and is out for another shot at the big time. His sidekick is an innocent religious countryman whose style contrasts well with all the others - Murray is just great, but could have been in it more. One scene, for me, really stands out. Certainly in terms of Gramsci esque masculine humour - Murray is in a eaterie with Harrelson and tells him to 'go outside and eat that', then he tells a waitress to come back after washing off her perfume, finally he says 'hi' to a fit bird sat across the way. Her mum says 'hi' and Murray says 'not you - hi'. The younger fit bird smiles and says 'hi'. This film is just great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny enough comedy,but slightly dry,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin is a funny movie with some laugh out loud scenes,a well thought out storyline and some pretty good actors,but I feel the movie goes on a bit,being two hours long and most animated films would only be an hour and a half,and find a lot of the humor to be a bit dry,not the Farrelly brothers finest work. A former bowler named Roy who hasn't bowled for over twenty years meets Ishmael,who is a natural bowler,Roy wants to get him to bowl for some professional games but it is hard to get him to take part because Ishmael is part of an Amish community,Roy eventually gets to Ishmael when pretends to be Amish himself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Comedy I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    schuster_mark
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I take my comedy seriously (no pun intended). I grew up watching the original cast of SNL, three stooges and actors like Gene Wilder. They all had something special, and I think remain extremely special 30 years later. Kingpin has that rare "something special". I had to watch this movie a few times before I fully appreciated the "once in a lifetime" performances by Harrelson and Murray, and outstanding writing by the Farrelly brothers. This movie, unlike most other comedies I've seen, continually provides genuinely funny moments throughout the entire movie. There are very few comedies I have ever watched that I can say the same about. It's like all the stars in the sky aligned for one perfect moment and in that moment they filmed "Kingpin". Now, this film may not be for every one. It's crude, rude and in your face comedy. It's typical Farrelly brother fare. If you like that, or even if you don't and just like the silly comedy of Bill Murray (before he went all serious) - then this movie is well worth a watch. Definitely a 10 out of 10 in my book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bowl me over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Following their success with "Dumb and Dumber", the Farrelly brothers directed "Kingpin", about a mangled bowler (Woody Harrelson) who trains an Amish man (Randy Quaid) to bowl. Since this is the guys behind "There's Something About Mary", there are naturally a few scenes with no purpose except to have a gross-out gag. But it is pretty funny throughout most of the movie, with a lot of mild gags. I suspect that the Amish didn't like it. But I liked it, and I recommend it. Also starring Vanessa Angel, Bill Murray, Chris Elliott, William Jordan and Lin Shaye (the sunburned neighbor in "TSAM" and the retiring flight attendant in "Snakes on a Plane").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Laughs from a Terrific Cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin (1996) *** (out of 4) Bowler Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) has everything in front of him until another bowler (Bill Murray) sells him out to a group of men they've just hustled and they end up cutting off Munson bowling hand, which puts an end to his career. Seventeen years later Munson is a worthless drunk who sees his chance back in the hopes of a Amish man (Randy Quaid) who he plans on getting to Reno for a big tournament. This was the Farrelly brothers follow-up to DUMB AND DUMBER and unlike that film, this one here wasn't a huge hit out of the gate and instead it took sometime to build up its cult following. I'm really not sure why this movie didn't hit it big when first released but time has been quite friendly to the raunchy comedy as it's certainly one of the better comedies of its period thanks in large part to a terrific cast, a nice story and plenty of big laughs. I think the story itself really isn't anything too special as it's pretty much your typical road movie with the biggest difference being the bowling subplot. I think what really makes this film so special are the three leads who are so perfect in their roles that you really can't imagine anyone else in the world playing them. Harrelson has always been an underrated comic actor and he does a very good job here and manages to get laughs out of the smallest stuff. Just the way he laughs or looks at someone can get a laugh but even better is the way he sells some of the jokes including a hilarious bit on the Amish farm where he pretends to know what he's doing, which leads him to "milking" a bull. Quaid can play an idiot like no other and make it look very easy. The way he brings this Amish guy to life is a lot of fun to watch because you really do feel as if you're watching someone real and someone experiencing the real world for the first time. Murray does what only he can as that type of comedy isn't easy and I can't think of anyone else who can pull it off. Apparently Murray ad-libbed just about every word in the film and the way he pulls this character off really helps bring in the laughs. Vanessa Angel fits in with the boys very well and manages a few nice laughs of her own as does Chris Elliott in his brief scenes. I think the film would have benefited had it lost about ten-minutes worth of footage because at just under two-hours the film is a little too long. The stuff with Angel's boyfriend isn't the funniest bits here and everything that happens with him in the second half should have been left out. The great thing about KINGPIN is that it never really delivers the type of laugh that you might expect and that's why the film works so well. The movie will have a scene set up and you might think you know where it's going but the funny part is seeing how different it plays out. The movie has some fairly low-taste laughs but the brothers were clearly just warming up as THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT MARY was just two years away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crude, rude, silly and........hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Can't believe this isn't rated higher, I have always loved this totally silly movie since I saw it in the theater years ago. There are some lulls here and there and maybe too much character development (if that's possible) but Woody is spot on, Murry is just insanely funny with his hair don't, and the rest of the cast is great too. Ishmael's slow decline into every vice there is is great. I'm sure this is not to everyones taste and I'm glad, not all of us are into bull seamen and oral sex with old lady jokes but for those who are you will be quite content. Even the bowling is funny in this early Farrelly brothers film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and bleak
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taygeta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike Harrelson's other masterpiece, White Men Can't Jump, this comedy certainly promises laughs and repeated viewings. On the other hand, there is a constant feeling of desolation and sadness. Ultimately this film could be described as being real. The performances from every cast member serve to create distinct and memorable characters, including the genius Bill Murray as the veritable king of the pins. Depending on who you are speaking with, this movie may have even spawned a dictionary worthy term, although I will leave it out of this review in the interest of little disclosure. "10 frames, that's for Quakers!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a STRIK.....OK no pins...i mean puns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DjangoLand
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only recently decided to somewhat commit to participating in contributing reviews to IMDb and reality hit me in the face when realising that it was 17 years ago when this classic came out. 17 years, and boy do i miss these kind of films, When the Farrelly brothers made great comedy movies. Of course they have taken their feet of the pedals, but their first 4 were instant classics. It may not be a laugh out loud film that has you giggling all the way through, but it has a certain charm to it (despite the crudeness) that keeps you smiling throughout. There are plenty of hilarious moments and great one liners. Bill Murray is fantastic as Big Ern and gels brilliantly with Woody Harrelson. The rest of the cast play their parts to make this a must see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Funniest Movies Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_the_Hobo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bowling legend Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) loses a hand to a group of drunks after trying to con them with fellow bowler Ernie McCracken (Bill Murray). Now a drunk promoter with a fake rubber hand, Munson is a shadow of his former self until he hears the fateful sound of a strike. Amish prodigy Ishmael (Randy Quaid) stands to be Munson's shot at winning the largest tournament in the country, but the road there is paved with consequence. This is one of the funniest movies ever made. The Farrelly brothers have given us countless laughs, but this is their best. It brings together some of the most unexpected actors, many out of their element in a comedy, to flawlessly turn a script into a comedic work of art. The laughs are typical Farrelly gross out while remaining truly, deeply funny. Woody Harrelson turns in one of his best performances as the down-but-not-out Munson, wearing a ridiculous wig, outdated clothing, and always his fake rubber hand. Each scene he's in is a lesson in how to lead a comedy, and reminds one of his early days on "Cheers" as the bartender Woody Boyd. His co-star in Quaid is the same; whether it be the murderous, greedy Sheriff is "Hard Rain", or here as the hilariously simple sure relative of the "Vacation" movies Cousin Eddie, Randy Quaid proves his ever surprising versatility as an actor. Bill Murray also fires on all cylinders as the over the top McCracken, Harrelson's arch-nemesis. Murray's last scene is one of the best in the movie; with his hair tossed every which way and his eyes flooding with tears he makes you shocked that he's only been nominated for one Oscar. Vanessa Angel is mostly eye candy but she doesn't have to make up for any acting downfalls. "Kingpin" is well-casted, well-written, consistently engaging and always funny. It brings together a diverse cast and a great script to make one of the funniest movies of our time. Strike it off your bucket list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You have a monkey?....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roy Munson was the best bowler in the world. But a fellow bowler, Ernie McCracken and a misunderstanding with some rough punks, left Roy with the loss of his bowling hand. He gets a prosthetic hand and becomes a travelling salesman. But it's really all down hill for him from that night on until he meets Ishmael who is Amish and sneaks away from the farm to bowl. Roy convinces Ishmael to let him be his trainer and he'll make him the best bowler the world has ever seen. Reluctantly Ishmael agrees to go on the road and shortly afterwards actually finds that life outside the farm is quite fun. Soon their paths cross that of Ernie McCracken who is still a top ranking bowler. While Roy's career and life have landed in the toilet bowl, Ernie is still drawing huge crowds.... Whilenot as good as Dumb and Dumber, the Farrellys comedy still felt pretty fresh and new for it's time of release. If this was released now, it wouldn't have has the plaudits is had, it would probably end up on late night TV, and wouldn't have the great cast. Harrelson is great as Roy, but cannot hold up to Quaid and a brilliant Murray, whenever they are on screen, the film really shines and becomes funny. Sadly, the rest of the film relies on horrid toilet humour and scenes that try and push the boundaries for a '12' movie, it doesn't work and the film has aged badly. That said, the hair is great in this movie, and while the Farrellys haven't really made a good original film for fourteen years, they proved with their first three movies they were a little left-field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hangover cure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jason_curtis24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely hilarious, deadpan stupid at times, and more reserved and subtle at others - its the perfect hangover cure. Harrelson is fantastic as a hard-done-by bowler who got done over ('Munsoned' is the phrase later used, which is his actual name in the film to his annoyance) and is out for another shot at the big time. His sidekick is an innocent religious countryman whose style contrasts well with all the others - Murray is just great, but could have been in it more. One scene, for me, really stands out. Certainly in terms of Gramsci esque masculine humour - Murray is in a eaterie with Harrelson and tells him to 'go outside and eat that', then he tells a waitress to come back after washing off her perfume, finally he says 'hi' to a fit bird sat across the way. Her mum says 'hi' and Murray says 'not you - hi'. The younger fit bird smiles and says 'hi'. This film is just great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny enough comedy,but slightly dry,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin is a funny movie with some laugh out loud scenes,a well thought out storyline and some pretty good actors,but I feel the movie goes on a bit,being two hours long and most animated films would only be an hour and a half,and find a lot of the humor to be a bit dry,not the Farrelly brothers finest work. A former bowler named Roy who hasn't bowled for over twenty years meets Ishmael,who is a natural bowler,Roy wants to get him to bowl for some professional games but it is hard to get him to take part because Ishmael is part of an Amish community,Roy eventually gets to Ishmael when pretends to be Amish himself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Comedy I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    schuster_mark
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I take my comedy seriously (no pun intended). I grew up watching the original cast of SNL, three stooges and actors like Gene Wilder. They all had something special, and I think remain extremely special 30 years later. Kingpin has that rare "something special". I had to watch this movie a few times before I fully appreciated the "once in a lifetime" performances by Harrelson and Murray, and outstanding writing by the Farrelly brothers. This movie, unlike most other comedies I've seen, continually provides genuinely funny moments throughout the entire movie. There are very few comedies I have ever watched that I can say the same about. It's like all the stars in the sky aligned for one perfect moment and in that moment they filmed "Kingpin". Now, this film may not be for every one. It's crude, rude and in your face comedy. It's typical Farrelly brother fare. If you like that, or even if you don't and just like the silly comedy of Bill Murray (before he went all serious) - then this movie is well worth a watch. Definitely a 10 out of 10 in my book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bowl me over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Following their success with "Dumb and Dumber", the Farrelly brothers directed "Kingpin", about a mangled bowler (Woody Harrelson) who trains an Amish man (Randy Quaid) to bowl. Since this is the guys behind "There's Something About Mary", there are naturally a few scenes with no purpose except to have a gross-out gag. But it is pretty funny throughout most of the movie, with a lot of mild gags. I suspect that the Amish didn't like it. But I liked it, and I recommend it. Also starring Vanessa Angel, Bill Murray, Chris Elliott, William Jordan and Lin Shaye (the sunburned neighbor in "TSAM" and the retiring flight attendant in "Snakes on a Plane").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Laughs from a Terrific Cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin (1996) *** (out of 4) Bowler Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) has everything in front of him until another bowler (Bill Murray) sells him out to a group of men they've just hustled and they end up cutting off Munson bowling hand, which puts an end to his career. Seventeen years later Munson is a worthless drunk who sees his chance back in the hopes of a Amish man (Randy Quaid) who he plans on getting to Reno for a big tournament. This was the Farrelly brothers follow-up to DUMB AND DUMBER and unlike that film, this one here wasn't a huge hit out of the gate and instead it took sometime to build up its cult following. I'm really not sure why this movie didn't hit it big when first released but time has been quite friendly to the raunchy comedy as it's certainly one of the better comedies of its period thanks in large part to a terrific cast, a nice story and plenty of big laughs. I think the story itself really isn't anything too special as it's pretty much your typical road movie with the biggest difference being the bowling subplot. I think what really makes this film so special are the three leads who are so perfect in their roles that you really can't imagine anyone else in the world playing them. Harrelson has always been an underrated comic actor and he does a very good job here and manages to get laughs out of the smallest stuff. Just the way he laughs or looks at someone can get a laugh but even better is the way he sells some of the jokes including a hilarious bit on the Amish farm where he pretends to know what he's doing, which leads him to "milking" a bull. Quaid can play an idiot like no other and make it look very easy. The way he brings this Amish guy to life is a lot of fun to watch because you really do feel as if you're watching someone real and someone experiencing the real world for the first time. Murray does what only he can as that type of comedy isn't easy and I can't think of anyone else who can pull it off. Apparently Murray ad-libbed just about every word in the film and the way he pulls this character off really helps bring in the laughs. Vanessa Angel fits in with the boys very well and manages a few nice laughs of her own as does Chris Elliott in his brief scenes. I think the film would have benefited had it lost about ten-minutes worth of footage because at just under two-hours the film is a little too long. The stuff with Angel's boyfriend isn't the funniest bits here and everything that happens with him in the second half should have been left out. The great thing about KINGPIN is that it never really delivers the type of laugh that you might expect and that's why the film works so well. The movie will have a scene set up and you might think you know where it's going but the funny part is seeing how different it plays out. The movie has some fairly low-taste laughs but the brothers were clearly just warming up as THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT MARY was just two years away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crude, rude, silly and........hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Can't believe this isn't rated higher, I have always loved this totally silly movie since I saw it in the theater years ago. There are some lulls here and there and maybe too much character development (if that's possible) but Woody is spot on, Murry is just insanely funny with his hair don't, and the rest of the cast is great too. Ishmael's slow decline into every vice there is is great. I'm sure this is not to everyones taste and I'm glad, not all of us are into bull seamen and oral sex with old lady jokes but for those who are you will be quite content. Even the bowling is funny in this early Farrelly brothers film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and bleak
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taygeta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike Harrelson's other masterpiece, White Men Can't Jump, this comedy certainly promises laughs and repeated viewings. On the other hand, there is a constant feeling of desolation and sadness. Ultimately this film could be described as being real. The performances from every cast member serve to create distinct and memorable characters, including the genius Bill Murray as the veritable king of the pins. Depending on who you are speaking with, this movie may have even spawned a dictionary worthy term, although I will leave it out of this review in the interest of little disclosure. "10 frames, that's for Quakers!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a STRIK.....OK no pins...i mean puns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DjangoLand
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only recently decided to somewhat commit to participating in contributing reviews to IMDb and reality hit me in the face when realising that it was 17 years ago when this classic came out. 17 years, and boy do i miss these kind of films, When the Farrelly brothers made great comedy movies. Of course they have taken their feet of the pedals, but their first 4 were instant classics. It may not be a laugh out loud film that has you giggling all the way through, but it has a certain charm to it (despite the crudeness) that keeps you smiling throughout. There are plenty of hilarious moments and great one liners. Bill Murray is fantastic as Big Ern and gels brilliantly with Woody Harrelson. The rest of the cast play their parts to make this a must see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Funniest Movies Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_the_Hobo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bowling legend Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) loses a hand to a group of drunks after trying to con them with fellow bowler Ernie McCracken (Bill Murray). Now a drunk promoter with a fake rubber hand, Munson is a shadow of his former self until he hears the fateful sound of a strike. Amish prodigy Ishmael (Randy Quaid) stands to be Munson's shot at winning the largest tournament in the country, but the road there is paved with consequence. This is one of the funniest movies ever made. The Farrelly brothers have given us countless laughs, but this is their best. It brings together some of the most unexpected actors, many out of their element in a comedy, to flawlessly turn a script into a comedic work of art. The laughs are typical Farrelly gross out while remaining truly, deeply funny. Woody Harrelson turns in one of his best performances as the down-but-not-out Munson, wearing a ridiculous wig, outdated clothing, and always his fake rubber hand. Each scene he's in is a lesson in how to lead a comedy, and reminds one of his early days on "Cheers" as the bartender Woody Boyd. His co-star in Quaid is the same; whether it be the murderous, greedy Sheriff is "Hard Rain", or here as the hilariously simple sure relative of the "Vacation" movies Cousin Eddie, Randy Quaid proves his ever surprising versatility as an actor. Bill Murray also fires on all cylinders as the over the top McCracken, Harrelson's arch-nemesis. Murray's last scene is one of the best in the movie; with his hair tossed every which way and his eyes flooding with tears he makes you shocked that he's only been nominated for one Oscar. Vanessa Angel is mostly eye candy but she doesn't have to make up for any acting downfalls. "Kingpin" is well-casted, well-written, consistently engaging and always funny. It brings together a diverse cast and a great script to make one of the funniest movies of our time. Strike it off your bucket list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You have a monkey?....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roy Munson was the best bowler in the world. But a fellow bowler, Ernie McCracken and a misunderstanding with some rough punks, left Roy with the loss of his bowling hand. He gets a prosthetic hand and becomes a travelling salesman. But it's really all down hill for him from that night on until he meets Ishmael who is Amish and sneaks away from the farm to bowl. Roy convinces Ishmael to let him be his trainer and he'll make him the best bowler the world has ever seen. Reluctantly Ishmael agrees to go on the road and shortly afterwards actually finds that life outside the farm is quite fun. Soon their paths cross that of Ernie McCracken who is still a top ranking bowler. While Roy's career and life have landed in the toilet bowl, Ernie is still drawing huge crowds.... Whilenot as good as Dumb and Dumber, the Farrellys comedy still felt pretty fresh and new for it's time of release. If this was released now, it wouldn't have has the plaudits is had, it would probably end up on late night TV, and wouldn't have the great cast. Harrelson is great as Roy, but cannot hold up to Quaid and a brilliant Murray, whenever they are on screen, the film really shines and becomes funny. Sadly, the rest of the film relies on horrid toilet humour and scenes that try and push the boundaries for a '12' movie, it doesn't work and the film has aged badly. That said, the hair is great in this movie, and while the Farrellys haven't really made a good original film for fourteen years, they proved with their first three movies they were a little left-field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hangover cure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jason_curtis24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely hilarious, deadpan stupid at times, and more reserved and subtle at others - its the perfect hangover cure. Harrelson is fantastic as a hard-done-by bowler who got done over ('Munsoned' is the phrase later used, which is his actual name in the film to his annoyance) and is out for another shot at the big time. His sidekick is an innocent religious countryman whose style contrasts well with all the others - Murray is just great, but could have been in it more. One scene, for me, really stands out. Certainly in terms of Gramsci esque masculine humour - Murray is in a eaterie with Harrelson and tells him to 'go outside and eat that', then he tells a waitress to come back after washing off her perfume, finally he says 'hi' to a fit bird sat across the way. Her mum says 'hi' and Murray says 'not you - hi'. The younger fit bird smiles and says 'hi'. This film is just great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny enough comedy,but slightly dry,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin is a funny movie with some laugh out loud scenes,a well thought out storyline and some pretty good actors,but I feel the movie goes on a bit,being two hours long and most animated films would only be an hour and a half,and find a lot of the humor to be a bit dry,not the Farrelly brothers finest work. A former bowler named Roy who hasn't bowled for over twenty years meets Ishmael,who is a natural bowler,Roy wants to get him to bowl for some professional games but it is hard to get him to take part because Ishmael is part of an Amish community,Roy eventually gets to Ishmael when pretends to be Amish himself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Comedy I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    schuster_mark
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I take my comedy seriously (no pun intended). I grew up watching the original cast of SNL, three stooges and actors like Gene Wilder. They all had something special, and I think remain extremely special 30 years later. Kingpin has that rare "something special". I had to watch this movie a few times before I fully appreciated the "once in a lifetime" performances by Harrelson and Murray, and outstanding writing by the Farrelly brothers. This movie, unlike most other comedies I've seen, continually provides genuinely funny moments throughout the entire movie. There are very few comedies I have ever watched that I can say the same about. It's like all the stars in the sky aligned for one perfect moment and in that moment they filmed "Kingpin". Now, this film may not be for every one. It's crude, rude and in your face comedy. It's typical Farrelly brother fare. If you like that, or even if you don't and just like the silly comedy of Bill Murray (before he went all serious) - then this movie is well worth a watch. Definitely a 10 out of 10 in my book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bowl me over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Following their success with "Dumb and Dumber", the Farrelly brothers directed "Kingpin", about a mangled bowler (Woody Harrelson) who trains an Amish man (Randy Quaid) to bowl. Since this is the guys behind "There's Something About Mary", there are naturally a few scenes with no purpose except to have a gross-out gag. But it is pretty funny throughout most of the movie, with a lot of mild gags. I suspect that the Amish didn't like it. But I liked it, and I recommend it. Also starring Vanessa Angel, Bill Murray, Chris Elliott, William Jordan and Lin Shaye (the sunburned neighbor in "TSAM" and the retiring flight attendant in "Snakes on a Plane").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Laughs from a Terrific Cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin (1996) *** (out of 4) Bowler Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) has everything in front of him until another bowler (Bill Murray) sells him out to a group of men they've just hustled and they end up cutting off Munson bowling hand, which puts an end to his career. Seventeen years later Munson is a worthless drunk who sees his chance back in the hopes of a Amish man (Randy Quaid) who he plans on getting to Reno for a big tournament. This was the Farrelly brothers follow-up to DUMB AND DUMBER and unlike that film, this one here wasn't a huge hit out of the gate and instead it took sometime to build up its cult following. I'm really not sure why this movie didn't hit it big when first released but time has been quite friendly to the raunchy comedy as it's certainly one of the better comedies of its period thanks in large part to a terrific cast, a nice story and plenty of big laughs. I think the story itself really isn't anything too special as it's pretty much your typical road movie with the biggest difference being the bowling subplot. I think what really makes this film so special are the three leads who are so perfect in their roles that you really can't imagine anyone else in the world playing them. Harrelson has always been an underrated comic actor and he does a very good job here and manages to get laughs out of the smallest stuff. Just the way he laughs or looks at someone can get a laugh but even better is the way he sells some of the jokes including a hilarious bit on the Amish farm where he pretends to know what he's doing, which leads him to "milking" a bull. Quaid can play an idiot like no other and make it look very easy. The way he brings this Amish guy to life is a lot of fun to watch because you really do feel as if you're watching someone real and someone experiencing the real world for the first time. Murray does what only he can as that type of comedy isn't easy and I can't think of anyone else who can pull it off. Apparently Murray ad-libbed just about every word in the film and the way he pulls this character off really helps bring in the laughs. Vanessa Angel fits in with the boys very well and manages a few nice laughs of her own as does Chris Elliott in his brief scenes. I think the film would have benefited had it lost about ten-minutes worth of footage because at just under two-hours the film is a little too long. The stuff with Angel's boyfriend isn't the funniest bits here and everything that happens with him in the second half should have been left out. The great thing about KINGPIN is that it never really delivers the type of laugh that you might expect and that's why the film works so well. The movie will have a scene set up and you might think you know where it's going but the funny part is seeing how different it plays out. The movie has some fairly low-taste laughs but the brothers were clearly just warming up as THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT MARY was just two years away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crude, rude, silly and........hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Can't believe this isn't rated higher, I have always loved this totally silly movie since I saw it in the theater years ago. There are some lulls here and there and maybe too much character development (if that's possible) but Woody is spot on, Murry is just insanely funny with his hair don't, and the rest of the cast is great too. Ishmael's slow decline into every vice there is is great. I'm sure this is not to everyones taste and I'm glad, not all of us are into bull seamen and oral sex with old lady jokes but for those who are you will be quite content. Even the bowling is funny in this early Farrelly brothers film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and bleak
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taygeta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike Harrelson's other masterpiece, White Men Can't Jump, this comedy certainly promises laughs and repeated viewings. On the other hand, there is a constant feeling of desolation and sadness. Ultimately this film could be described as being real. The performances from every cast member serve to create distinct and memorable characters, including the genius Bill Murray as the veritable king of the pins. Depending on who you are speaking with, this movie may have even spawned a dictionary worthy term, although I will leave it out of this review in the interest of little disclosure. "10 frames, that's for Quakers!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a STRIK.....OK no pins...i mean puns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DjangoLand
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only recently decided to somewhat commit to participating in contributing reviews to IMDb and reality hit me in the face when realising that it was 17 years ago when this classic came out. 17 years, and boy do i miss these kind of films, When the Farrelly brothers made great comedy movies. Of course they have taken their feet of the pedals, but their first 4 were instant classics. It may not be a laugh out loud film that has you giggling all the way through, but it has a certain charm to it (despite the crudeness) that keeps you smiling throughout. There are plenty of hilarious moments and great one liners. Bill Murray is fantastic as Big Ern and gels brilliantly with Woody Harrelson. The rest of the cast play their parts to make this a must see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Funniest Movies Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_the_Hobo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bowling legend Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) loses a hand to a group of drunks after trying to con them with fellow bowler Ernie McCracken (Bill Murray). Now a drunk promoter with a fake rubber hand, Munson is a shadow of his former self until he hears the fateful sound of a strike. Amish prodigy Ishmael (Randy Quaid) stands to be Munson's shot at winning the largest tournament in the country, but the road there is paved with consequence. This is one of the funniest movies ever made. The Farrelly brothers have given us countless laughs, but this is their best. It brings together some of the most unexpected actors, many out of their element in a comedy, to flawlessly turn a script into a comedic work of art. The laughs are typical Farrelly gross out while remaining truly, deeply funny. Woody Harrelson turns in one of his best performances as the down-but-not-out Munson, wearing a ridiculous wig, outdated clothing, and always his fake rubber hand. Each scene he's in is a lesson in how to lead a comedy, and reminds one of his early days on "Cheers" as the bartender Woody Boyd. His co-star in Quaid is the same; whether it be the murderous, greedy Sheriff is "Hard Rain", or here as the hilariously simple sure relative of the "Vacation" movies Cousin Eddie, Randy Quaid proves his ever surprising versatility as an actor. Bill Murray also fires on all cylinders as the over the top McCracken, Harrelson's arch-nemesis. Murray's last scene is one of the best in the movie; with his hair tossed every which way and his eyes flooding with tears he makes you shocked that he's only been nominated for one Oscar. Vanessa Angel is mostly eye candy but she doesn't have to make up for any acting downfalls. "Kingpin" is well-casted, well-written, consistently engaging and always funny. It brings together a diverse cast and a great script to make one of the funniest movies of our time. Strike it off your bucket list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You have a monkey?....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roy Munson was the best bowler in the world. But a fellow bowler, Ernie McCracken and a misunderstanding with some rough punks, left Roy with the loss of his bowling hand. He gets a prosthetic hand and becomes a travelling salesman. But it's really all down hill for him from that night on until he meets Ishmael who is Amish and sneaks away from the farm to bowl. Roy convinces Ishmael to let him be his trainer and he'll make him the best bowler the world has ever seen. Reluctantly Ishmael agrees to go on the road and shortly afterwards actually finds that life outside the farm is quite fun. Soon their paths cross that of Ernie McCracken who is still a top ranking bowler. While Roy's career and life have landed in the toilet bowl, Ernie is still drawing huge crowds.... Whilenot as good as Dumb and Dumber, the Farrellys comedy still felt pretty fresh and new for it's time of release. If this was released now, it wouldn't have has the plaudits is had, it would probably end up on late night TV, and wouldn't have the great cast. Harrelson is great as Roy, but cannot hold up to Quaid and a brilliant Murray, whenever they are on screen, the film really shines and becomes funny. Sadly, the rest of the film relies on horrid toilet humour and scenes that try and push the boundaries for a '12' movie, it doesn't work and the film has aged badly. That said, the hair is great in this movie, and while the Farrellys haven't really made a good original film for fourteen years, they proved with their first three movies they were a little left-field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hangover cure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jason_curtis24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely hilarious, deadpan stupid at times, and more reserved and subtle at others - its the perfect hangover cure. Harrelson is fantastic as a hard-done-by bowler who got done over ('Munsoned' is the phrase later used, which is his actual name in the film to his annoyance) and is out for another shot at the big time. His sidekick is an innocent religious countryman whose style contrasts well with all the others - Murray is just great, but could have been in it more. One scene, for me, really stands out. Certainly in terms of Gramsci esque masculine humour - Murray is in a eaterie with Harrelson and tells him to 'go outside and eat that', then he tells a waitress to come back after washing off her perfume, finally he says 'hi' to a fit bird sat across the way. Her mum says 'hi' and Murray says 'not you - hi'. The younger fit bird smiles and says 'hi'. This film is just great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny enough comedy,but slightly dry,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin is a funny movie with some laugh out loud scenes,a well thought out storyline and some pretty good actors,but I feel the movie goes on a bit,being two hours long and most animated films would only be an hour and a half,and find a lot of the humor to be a bit dry,not the Farrelly brothers finest work. A former bowler named Roy who hasn't bowled for over twenty years meets Ishmael,who is a natural bowler,Roy wants to get him to bowl for some professional games but it is hard to get him to take part because Ishmael is part of an Amish community,Roy eventually gets to Ishmael when pretends to be Amish himself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Comedy I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    schuster_mark
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I take my comedy seriously (no pun intended). I grew up watching the original cast of SNL, three stooges and actors like Gene Wilder. They all had something special, and I think remain extremely special 30 years later. Kingpin has that rare "something special". I had to watch this movie a few times before I fully appreciated the "once in a lifetime" performances by Harrelson and Murray, and outstanding writing by the Farrelly brothers. This movie, unlike most other comedies I've seen, continually provides genuinely funny moments throughout the entire movie. There are very few comedies I have ever watched that I can say the same about. It's like all the stars in the sky aligned for one perfect moment and in that moment they filmed "Kingpin". Now, this film may not be for every one. It's crude, rude and in your face comedy. It's typical Farrelly brother fare. If you like that, or even if you don't and just like the silly comedy of Bill Murray (before he went all serious) - then this movie is well worth a watch. Definitely a 10 out of 10 in my book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bowl me over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Following their success with "Dumb and Dumber", the Farrelly brothers directed "Kingpin", about a mangled bowler (Woody Harrelson) who trains an Amish man (Randy Quaid) to bowl. Since this is the guys behind "There's Something About Mary", there are naturally a few scenes with no purpose except to have a gross-out gag. But it is pretty funny throughout most of the movie, with a lot of mild gags. I suspect that the Amish didn't like it. But I liked it, and I recommend it. Also starring Vanessa Angel, Bill Murray, Chris Elliott, William Jordan and Lin Shaye (the sunburned neighbor in "TSAM" and the retiring flight attendant in "Snakes on a Plane").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Laughs from a Terrific Cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin (1996) *** (out of 4) Bowler Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) has everything in front of him until another bowler (Bill Murray) sells him out to a group of men they've just hustled and they end up cutting off Munson bowling hand, which puts an end to his career. Seventeen years later Munson is a worthless drunk who sees his chance back in the hopes of a Amish man (Randy Quaid) who he plans on getting to Reno for a big tournament. This was the Farrelly brothers follow-up to DUMB AND DUMBER and unlike that film, this one here wasn't a huge hit out of the gate and instead it took sometime to build up its cult following. I'm really not sure why this movie didn't hit it big when first released but time has been quite friendly to the raunchy comedy as it's certainly one of the better comedies of its period thanks in large part to a terrific cast, a nice story and plenty of big laughs. I think the story itself really isn't anything too special as it's pretty much your typical road movie with the biggest difference being the bowling subplot. I think what really makes this film so special are the three leads who are so perfect in their roles that you really can't imagine anyone else in the world playing them. Harrelson has always been an underrated comic actor and he does a very good job here and manages to get laughs out of the smallest stuff. Just the way he laughs or looks at someone can get a laugh but even better is the way he sells some of the jokes including a hilarious bit on the Amish farm where he pretends to know what he's doing, which leads him to "milking" a bull. Quaid can play an idiot like no other and make it look very easy. The way he brings this Amish guy to life is a lot of fun to watch because you really do feel as if you're watching someone real and someone experiencing the real world for the first time. Murray does what only he can as that type of comedy isn't easy and I can't think of anyone else who can pull it off. Apparently Murray ad-libbed just about every word in the film and the way he pulls this character off really helps bring in the laughs. Vanessa Angel fits in with the boys very well and manages a few nice laughs of her own as does Chris Elliott in his brief scenes. I think the film would have benefited had it lost about ten-minutes worth of footage because at just under two-hours the film is a little too long. The stuff with Angel's boyfriend isn't the funniest bits here and everything that happens with him in the second half should have been left out. The great thing about KINGPIN is that it never really delivers the type of laugh that you might expect and that's why the film works so well. The movie will have a scene set up and you might think you know where it's going but the funny part is seeing how different it plays out. The movie has some fairly low-taste laughs but the brothers were clearly just warming up as THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT MARY was just two years away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crude, rude, silly and........hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Can't believe this isn't rated higher, I have always loved this totally silly movie since I saw it in the theater years ago. There are some lulls here and there and maybe too much character development (if that's possible) but Woody is spot on, Murry is just insanely funny with his hair don't, and the rest of the cast is great too. Ishmael's slow decline into every vice there is is great. I'm sure this is not to everyones taste and I'm glad, not all of us are into bull seamen and oral sex with old lady jokes but for those who are you will be quite content. Even the bowling is funny in this early Farrelly brothers film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and bleak
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taygeta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike Harrelson's other masterpiece, White Men Can't Jump, this comedy certainly promises laughs and repeated viewings. On the other hand, there is a constant feeling of desolation and sadness. Ultimately this film could be described as being real. The performances from every cast member serve to create distinct and memorable characters, including the genius Bill Murray as the veritable king of the pins. Depending on who you are speaking with, this movie may have even spawned a dictionary worthy term, although I will leave it out of this review in the interest of little disclosure. "10 frames, that's for Quakers!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a STRIK.....OK no pins...i mean puns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DjangoLand
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only recently decided to somewhat commit to participating in contributing reviews to IMDb and reality hit me in the face when realising that it was 17 years ago when this classic came out. 17 years, and boy do i miss these kind of films, When the Farrelly brothers made great comedy movies. Of course they have taken their feet of the pedals, but their first 4 were instant classics. It may not be a laugh out loud film that has you giggling all the way through, but it has a certain charm to it (despite the crudeness) that keeps you smiling throughout. There are plenty of hilarious moments and great one liners. Bill Murray is fantastic as Big Ern and gels brilliantly with Woody Harrelson. The rest of the cast play their parts to make this a must see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Funniest Movies Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_the_Hobo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bowling legend Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) loses a hand to a group of drunks after trying to con them with fellow bowler Ernie McCracken (Bill Murray). Now a drunk promoter with a fake rubber hand, Munson is a shadow of his former self until he hears the fateful sound of a strike. Amish prodigy Ishmael (Randy Quaid) stands to be Munson's shot at winning the largest tournament in the country, but the road there is paved with consequence. This is one of the funniest movies ever made. The Farrelly brothers have given us countless laughs, but this is their best. It brings together some of the most unexpected actors, many out of their element in a comedy, to flawlessly turn a script into a comedic work of art. The laughs are typical Farrelly gross out while remaining truly, deeply funny. Woody Harrelson turns in one of his best performances as the down-but-not-out Munson, wearing a ridiculous wig, outdated clothing, and always his fake rubber hand. Each scene he's in is a lesson in how to lead a comedy, and reminds one of his early days on "Cheers" as the bartender Woody Boyd. His co-star in Quaid is the same; whether it be the murderous, greedy Sheriff is "Hard Rain", or here as the hilariously simple sure relative of the "Vacation" movies Cousin Eddie, Randy Quaid proves his ever surprising versatility as an actor. Bill Murray also fires on all cylinders as the over the top McCracken, Harrelson's arch-nemesis. Murray's last scene is one of the best in the movie; with his hair tossed every which way and his eyes flooding with tears he makes you shocked that he's only been nominated for one Oscar. Vanessa Angel is mostly eye candy but she doesn't have to make up for any acting downfalls. "Kingpin" is well-casted, well-written, consistently engaging and always funny. It brings together a diverse cast and a great script to make one of the funniest movies of our time. Strike it off your bucket list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You have a monkey?....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roy Munson was the best bowler in the world. But a fellow bowler, Ernie McCracken and a misunderstanding with some rough punks, left Roy with the loss of his bowling hand. He gets a prosthetic hand and becomes a travelling salesman. But it's really all down hill for him from that night on until he meets Ishmael who is Amish and sneaks away from the farm to bowl. Roy convinces Ishmael to let him be his trainer and he'll make him the best bowler the world has ever seen. Reluctantly Ishmael agrees to go on the road and shortly afterwards actually finds that life outside the farm is quite fun. Soon their paths cross that of Ernie McCracken who is still a top ranking bowler. While Roy's career and life have landed in the toilet bowl, Ernie is still drawing huge crowds.... Whilenot as good as Dumb and Dumber, the Farrellys comedy still felt pretty fresh and new for it's time of release. If this was released now, it wouldn't have has the plaudits is had, it would probably end up on late night TV, and wouldn't have the great cast. Harrelson is great as Roy, but cannot hold up to Quaid and a brilliant Murray, whenever they are on screen, the film really shines and becomes funny. Sadly, the rest of the film relies on horrid toilet humour and scenes that try and push the boundaries for a '12' movie, it doesn't work and the film has aged badly. That said, the hair is great in this movie, and while the Farrellys haven't really made a good original film for fourteen years, they proved with their first three movies they were a little left-field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hangover cure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jason_curtis24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely hilarious, deadpan stupid at times, and more reserved and subtle at others - its the perfect hangover cure. Harrelson is fantastic as a hard-done-by bowler who got done over ('Munsoned' is the phrase later used, which is his actual name in the film to his annoyance) and is out for another shot at the big time. His sidekick is an innocent religious countryman whose style contrasts well with all the others - Murray is just great, but could have been in it more. One scene, for me, really stands out. Certainly in terms of Gramsci esque masculine humour - Murray is in a eaterie with Harrelson and tells him to 'go outside and eat that', then he tells a waitress to come back after washing off her perfume, finally he says 'hi' to a fit bird sat across the way. Her mum says 'hi' and Murray says 'not you - hi'. The younger fit bird smiles and says 'hi'. This film is just great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny enough comedy,but slightly dry,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin is a funny movie with some laugh out loud scenes,a well thought out storyline and some pretty good actors,but I feel the movie goes on a bit,being two hours long and most animated films would only be an hour and a half,and find a lot of the humor to be a bit dry,not the Farrelly brothers finest work. A former bowler named Roy who hasn't bowled for over twenty years meets Ishmael,who is a natural bowler,Roy wants to get him to bowl for some professional games but it is hard to get him to take part because Ishmael is part of an Amish community,Roy eventually gets to Ishmael when pretends to be Amish himself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Comedy I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    schuster_mark
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I take my comedy seriously (no pun intended). I grew up watching the original cast of SNL, three stooges and actors like Gene Wilder. They all had something special, and I think remain extremely special 30 years later. Kingpin has that rare "something special". I had to watch this movie a few times before I fully appreciated the "once in a lifetime" performances by Harrelson and Murray, and outstanding writing by the Farrelly brothers. This movie, unlike most other comedies I've seen, continually provides genuinely funny moments throughout the entire movie. There are very few comedies I have ever watched that I can say the same about. It's like all the stars in the sky aligned for one perfect moment and in that moment they filmed "Kingpin". Now, this film may not be for every one. It's crude, rude and in your face comedy. It's typical Farrelly brother fare. If you like that, or even if you don't and just like the silly comedy of Bill Murray (before he went all serious) - then this movie is well worth a watch. Definitely a 10 out of 10 in my book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bowl me over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Following their success with "Dumb and Dumber", the Farrelly brothers directed "Kingpin", about a mangled bowler (Woody Harrelson) who trains an Amish man (Randy Quaid) to bowl. Since this is the guys behind "There's Something About Mary", there are naturally a few scenes with no purpose except to have a gross-out gag. But it is pretty funny throughout most of the movie, with a lot of mild gags. I suspect that the Amish didn't like it. But I liked it, and I recommend it. Also starring Vanessa Angel, Bill Murray, Chris Elliott, William Jordan and Lin Shaye (the sunburned neighbor in "TSAM" and the retiring flight attendant in "Snakes on a Plane").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Laughs from a Terrific Cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin (1996) *** (out of 4) Bowler Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) has everything in front of him until another bowler (Bill Murray) sells him out to a group of men they've just hustled and they end up cutting off Munson bowling hand, which puts an end to his career. Seventeen years later Munson is a worthless drunk who sees his chance back in the hopes of a Amish man (Randy Quaid) who he plans on getting to Reno for a big tournament. This was the Farrelly brothers follow-up to DUMB AND DUMBER and unlike that film, this one here wasn't a huge hit out of the gate and instead it took sometime to build up its cult following. I'm really not sure why this movie didn't hit it big when first released but time has been quite friendly to the raunchy comedy as it's certainly one of the better comedies of its period thanks in large part to a terrific cast, a nice story and plenty of big laughs. I think the story itself really isn't anything too special as it's pretty much your typical road movie with the biggest difference being the bowling subplot. I think what really makes this film so special are the three leads who are so perfect in their roles that you really can't imagine anyone else in the world playing them. Harrelson has always been an underrated comic actor and he does a very good job here and manages to get laughs out of the smallest stuff. Just the way he laughs or looks at someone can get a laugh but even better is the way he sells some of the jokes including a hilarious bit on the Amish farm where he pretends to know what he's doing, which leads him to "milking" a bull. Quaid can play an idiot like no other and make it look very easy. The way he brings this Amish guy to life is a lot of fun to watch because you really do feel as if you're watching someone real and someone experiencing the real world for the first time. Murray does what only he can as that type of comedy isn't easy and I can't think of anyone else who can pull it off. Apparently Murray ad-libbed just about every word in the film and the way he pulls this character off really helps bring in the laughs. Vanessa Angel fits in with the boys very well and manages a few nice laughs of her own as does Chris Elliott in his brief scenes. I think the film would have benefited had it lost about ten-minutes worth of footage because at just under two-hours the film is a little too long. The stuff with Angel's boyfriend isn't the funniest bits here and everything that happens with him in the second half should have been left out. The great thing about KINGPIN is that it never really delivers the type of laugh that you might expect and that's why the film works so well. The movie will have a scene set up and you might think you know where it's going but the funny part is seeing how different it plays out. The movie has some fairly low-taste laughs but the brothers were clearly just warming up as THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT MARY was just two years away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crude, rude, silly and........hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Can't believe this isn't rated higher, I have always loved this totally silly movie since I saw it in the theater years ago. There are some lulls here and there and maybe too much character development (if that's possible) but Woody is spot on, Murry is just insanely funny with his hair don't, and the rest of the cast is great too. Ishmael's slow decline into every vice there is is great. I'm sure this is not to everyones taste and I'm glad, not all of us are into bull seamen and oral sex with old lady jokes but for those who are you will be quite content. Even the bowling is funny in this early Farrelly brothers film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and bleak
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taygeta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike Harrelson's other masterpiece, White Men Can't Jump, this comedy certainly promises laughs and repeated viewings. On the other hand, there is a constant feeling of desolation and sadness. Ultimately this film could be described as being real. The performances from every cast member serve to create distinct and memorable characters, including the genius Bill Murray as the veritable king of the pins. Depending on who you are speaking with, this movie may have even spawned a dictionary worthy term, although I will leave it out of this review in the interest of little disclosure. "10 frames, that's for Quakers!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a STRIK.....OK no pins...i mean puns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DjangoLand
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only recently decided to somewhat commit to participating in contributing reviews to IMDb and reality hit me in the face when realising that it was 17 years ago when this classic came out. 17 years, and boy do i miss these kind of films, When the Farrelly brothers made great comedy movies. Of course they have taken their feet of the pedals, but their first 4 were instant classics. It may not be a laugh out loud film that has you giggling all the way through, but it has a certain charm to it (despite the crudeness) that keeps you smiling throughout. There are plenty of hilarious moments and great one liners. Bill Murray is fantastic as Big Ern and gels brilliantly with Woody Harrelson. The rest of the cast play their parts to make this a must see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Funniest Movies Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_the_Hobo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bowling legend Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) loses a hand to a group of drunks after trying to con them with fellow bowler Ernie McCracken (Bill Murray). Now a drunk promoter with a fake rubber hand, Munson is a shadow of his former self until he hears the fateful sound of a strike. Amish prodigy Ishmael (Randy Quaid) stands to be Munson's shot at winning the largest tournament in the country, but the road there is paved with consequence. This is one of the funniest movies ever made. The Farrelly brothers have given us countless laughs, but this is their best. It brings together some of the most unexpected actors, many out of their element in a comedy, to flawlessly turn a script into a comedic work of art. The laughs are typical Farrelly gross out while remaining truly, deeply funny. Woody Harrelson turns in one of his best performances as the down-but-not-out Munson, wearing a ridiculous wig, outdated clothing, and always his fake rubber hand. Each scene he's in is a lesson in how to lead a comedy, and reminds one of his early days on "Cheers" as the bartender Woody Boyd. His co-star in Quaid is the same; whether it be the murderous, greedy Sheriff is "Hard Rain", or here as the hilariously simple sure relative of the "Vacation" movies Cousin Eddie, Randy Quaid proves his ever surprising versatility as an actor. Bill Murray also fires on all cylinders as the over the top McCracken, Harrelson's arch-nemesis. Murray's last scene is one of the best in the movie; with his hair tossed every which way and his eyes flooding with tears he makes you shocked that he's only been nominated for one Oscar. Vanessa Angel is mostly eye candy but she doesn't have to make up for any acting downfalls. "Kingpin" is well-casted, well-written, consistently engaging and always funny. It brings together a diverse cast and a great script to make one of the funniest movies of our time. Strike it off your bucket list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You have a monkey?....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roy Munson was the best bowler in the world. But a fellow bowler, Ernie McCracken and a misunderstanding with some rough punks, left Roy with the loss of his bowling hand. He gets a prosthetic hand and becomes a travelling salesman. But it's really all down hill for him from that night on until he meets Ishmael who is Amish and sneaks away from the farm to bowl. Roy convinces Ishmael to let him be his trainer and he'll make him the best bowler the world has ever seen. Reluctantly Ishmael agrees to go on the road and shortly afterwards actually finds that life outside the farm is quite fun. Soon their paths cross that of Ernie McCracken who is still a top ranking bowler. While Roy's career and life have landed in the toilet bowl, Ernie is still drawing huge crowds.... Whilenot as good as Dumb and Dumber, the Farrellys comedy still felt pretty fresh and new for it's time of release. If this was released now, it wouldn't have has the plaudits is had, it would probably end up on late night TV, and wouldn't have the great cast. Harrelson is great as Roy, but cannot hold up to Quaid and a brilliant Murray, whenever they are on screen, the film really shines and becomes funny. Sadly, the rest of the film relies on horrid toilet humour and scenes that try and push the boundaries for a '12' movie, it doesn't work and the film has aged badly. That said, the hair is great in this movie, and while the Farrellys haven't really made a good original film for fourteen years, they proved with their first three movies they were a little left-field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hangover cure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jason_curtis24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely hilarious, deadpan stupid at times, and more reserved and subtle at others - its the perfect hangover cure. Harrelson is fantastic as a hard-done-by bowler who got done over ('Munsoned' is the phrase later used, which is his actual name in the film to his annoyance) and is out for another shot at the big time. His sidekick is an innocent religious countryman whose style contrasts well with all the others - Murray is just great, but could have been in it more. One scene, for me, really stands out. Certainly in terms of Gramsci esque masculine humour - Murray is in a eaterie with Harrelson and tells him to 'go outside and eat that', then he tells a waitress to come back after washing off her perfume, finally he says 'hi' to a fit bird sat across the way. Her mum says 'hi' and Murray says 'not you - hi'. The younger fit bird smiles and says 'hi'. This film is just great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny enough comedy,but slightly dry,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin is a funny movie with some laugh out loud scenes,a well thought out storyline and some pretty good actors,but I feel the movie goes on a bit,being two hours long and most animated films would only be an hour and a half,and find a lot of the humor to be a bit dry,not the Farrelly brothers finest work. A former bowler named Roy who hasn't bowled for over twenty years meets Ishmael,who is a natural bowler,Roy wants to get him to bowl for some professional games but it is hard to get him to take part because Ishmael is part of an Amish community,Roy eventually gets to Ishmael when pretends to be Amish himself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Comedy I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    schuster_mark
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I take my comedy seriously (no pun intended). I grew up watching the original cast of SNL, three stooges and actors like Gene Wilder. They all had something special, and I think remain extremely special 30 years later. Kingpin has that rare "something special". I had to watch this movie a few times before I fully appreciated the "once in a lifetime" performances by Harrelson and Murray, and outstanding writing by the Farrelly brothers. This movie, unlike most other comedies I've seen, continually provides genuinely funny moments throughout the entire movie. There are very few comedies I have ever watched that I can say the same about. It's like all the stars in the sky aligned for one perfect moment and in that moment they filmed "Kingpin". Now, this film may not be for every one. It's crude, rude and in your face comedy. It's typical Farrelly brother fare. If you like that, or even if you don't and just like the silly comedy of Bill Murray (before he went all serious) - then this movie is well worth a watch. Definitely a 10 out of 10 in my book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bowl me over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Following their success with "Dumb and Dumber", the Farrelly brothers directed "Kingpin", about a mangled bowler (Woody Harrelson) who trains an Amish man (Randy Quaid) to bowl. Since this is the guys behind "There's Something About Mary", there are naturally a few scenes with no purpose except to have a gross-out gag. But it is pretty funny throughout most of the movie, with a lot of mild gags. I suspect that the Amish didn't like it. But I liked it, and I recommend it. Also starring Vanessa Angel, Bill Murray, Chris Elliott, William Jordan and Lin Shaye (the sunburned neighbor in "TSAM" and the retiring flight attendant in "Snakes on a Plane").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Laughs from a Terrific Cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin (1996) *** (out of 4) Bowler Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) has everything in front of him until another bowler (Bill Murray) sells him out to a group of men they've just hustled and they end up cutting off Munson bowling hand, which puts an end to his career. Seventeen years later Munson is a worthless drunk who sees his chance back in the hopes of a Amish man (Randy Quaid) who he plans on getting to Reno for a big tournament. This was the Farrelly brothers follow-up to DUMB AND DUMBER and unlike that film, this one here wasn't a huge hit out of the gate and instead it took sometime to build up its cult following. I'm really not sure why this movie didn't hit it big when first released but time has been quite friendly to the raunchy comedy as it's certainly one of the better comedies of its period thanks in large part to a terrific cast, a nice story and plenty of big laughs. I think the story itself really isn't anything too special as it's pretty much your typical road movie with the biggest difference being the bowling subplot. I think what really makes this film so special are the three leads who are so perfect in their roles that you really can't imagine anyone else in the world playing them. Harrelson has always been an underrated comic actor and he does a very good job here and manages to get laughs out of the smallest stuff. Just the way he laughs or looks at someone can get a laugh but even better is the way he sells some of the jokes including a hilarious bit on the Amish farm where he pretends to know what he's doing, which leads him to "milking" a bull. Quaid can play an idiot like no other and make it look very easy. The way he brings this Amish guy to life is a lot of fun to watch because you really do feel as if you're watching someone real and someone experiencing the real world for the first time. Murray does what only he can as that type of comedy isn't easy and I can't think of anyone else who can pull it off. Apparently Murray ad-libbed just about every word in the film and the way he pulls this character off really helps bring in the laughs. Vanessa Angel fits in with the boys very well and manages a few nice laughs of her own as does Chris Elliott in his brief scenes. I think the film would have benefited had it lost about ten-minutes worth of footage because at just under two-hours the film is a little too long. The stuff with Angel's boyfriend isn't the funniest bits here and everything that happens with him in the second half should have been left out. The great thing about KINGPIN is that it never really delivers the type of laugh that you might expect and that's why the film works so well. The movie will have a scene set up and you might think you know where it's going but the funny part is seeing how different it plays out. The movie has some fairly low-taste laughs but the brothers were clearly just warming up as THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT MARY was just two years away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crude, rude, silly and........hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Can't believe this isn't rated higher, I have always loved this totally silly movie since I saw it in the theater years ago. There are some lulls here and there and maybe too much character development (if that's possible) but Woody is spot on, Murry is just insanely funny with his hair don't, and the rest of the cast is great too. Ishmael's slow decline into every vice there is is great. I'm sure this is not to everyones taste and I'm glad, not all of us are into bull seamen and oral sex with old lady jokes but for those who are you will be quite content. Even the bowling is funny in this early Farrelly brothers film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and bleak
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taygeta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike Harrelson's other masterpiece, White Men Can't Jump, this comedy certainly promises laughs and repeated viewings. On the other hand, there is a constant feeling of desolation and sadness. Ultimately this film could be described as being real. The performances from every cast member serve to create distinct and memorable characters, including the genius Bill Murray as the veritable king of the pins. Depending on who you are speaking with, this movie may have even spawned a dictionary worthy term, although I will leave it out of this review in the interest of little disclosure. "10 frames, that's for Quakers!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a STRIK.....OK no pins...i mean puns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DjangoLand
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only recently decided to somewhat commit to participating in contributing reviews to IMDb and reality hit me in the face when realising that it was 17 years ago when this classic came out. 17 years, and boy do i miss these kind of films, When the Farrelly brothers made great comedy movies. Of course they have taken their feet of the pedals, but their first 4 were instant classics. It may not be a laugh out loud film that has you giggling all the way through, but it has a certain charm to it (despite the crudeness) that keeps you smiling throughout. There are plenty of hilarious moments and great one liners. Bill Murray is fantastic as Big Ern and gels brilliantly with Woody Harrelson. The rest of the cast play their parts to make this a must see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Funniest Movies Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_the_Hobo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bowling legend Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) loses a hand to a group of drunks after trying to con them with fellow bowler Ernie McCracken (Bill Murray). Now a drunk promoter with a fake rubber hand, Munson is a shadow of his former self until he hears the fateful sound of a strike. Amish prodigy Ishmael (Randy Quaid) stands to be Munson's shot at winning the largest tournament in the country, but the road there is paved with consequence. This is one of the funniest movies ever made. The Farrelly brothers have given us countless laughs, but this is their best. It brings together some of the most unexpected actors, many out of their element in a comedy, to flawlessly turn a script into a comedic work of art. The laughs are typical Farrelly gross out while remaining truly, deeply funny. Woody Harrelson turns in one of his best performances as the down-but-not-out Munson, wearing a ridiculous wig, outdated clothing, and always his fake rubber hand. Each scene he's in is a lesson in how to lead a comedy, and reminds one of his early days on "Cheers" as the bartender Woody Boyd. His co-star in Quaid is the same; whether it be the murderous, greedy Sheriff is "Hard Rain", or here as the hilariously simple sure relative of the "Vacation" movies Cousin Eddie, Randy Quaid proves his ever surprising versatility as an actor. Bill Murray also fires on all cylinders as the over the top McCracken, Harrelson's arch-nemesis. Murray's last scene is one of the best in the movie; with his hair tossed every which way and his eyes flooding with tears he makes you shocked that he's only been nominated for one Oscar. Vanessa Angel is mostly eye candy but she doesn't have to make up for any acting downfalls. "Kingpin" is well-casted, well-written, consistently engaging and always funny. It brings together a diverse cast and a great script to make one of the funniest movies of our time. Strike it off your bucket list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You have a monkey?....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roy Munson was the best bowler in the world. But a fellow bowler, Ernie McCracken and a misunderstanding with some rough punks, left Roy with the loss of his bowling hand. He gets a prosthetic hand and becomes a travelling salesman. But it's really all down hill for him from that night on until he meets Ishmael who is Amish and sneaks away from the farm to bowl. Roy convinces Ishmael to let him be his trainer and he'll make him the best bowler the world has ever seen. Reluctantly Ishmael agrees to go on the road and shortly afterwards actually finds that life outside the farm is quite fun. Soon their paths cross that of Ernie McCracken who is still a top ranking bowler. While Roy's career and life have landed in the toilet bowl, Ernie is still drawing huge crowds.... Whilenot as good as Dumb and Dumber, the Farrellys comedy still felt pretty fresh and new for it's time of release. If this was released now, it wouldn't have has the plaudits is had, it would probably end up on late night TV, and wouldn't have the great cast. Harrelson is great as Roy, but cannot hold up to Quaid and a brilliant Murray, whenever they are on screen, the film really shines and becomes funny. Sadly, the rest of the film relies on horrid toilet humour and scenes that try and push the boundaries for a '12' movie, it doesn't work and the film has aged badly. That said, the hair is great in this movie, and while the Farrellys haven't really made a good original film for fourteen years, they proved with their first three movies they were a little left-field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hangover cure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jason_curtis24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely hilarious, deadpan stupid at times, and more reserved and subtle at others - its the perfect hangover cure. Harrelson is fantastic as a hard-done-by bowler who got done over ('Munsoned' is the phrase later used, which is his actual name in the film to his annoyance) and is out for another shot at the big time. His sidekick is an innocent religious countryman whose style contrasts well with all the others - Murray is just great, but could have been in it more. One scene, for me, really stands out. Certainly in terms of Gramsci esque masculine humour - Murray is in a eaterie with Harrelson and tells him to 'go outside and eat that', then he tells a waitress to come back after washing off her perfume, finally he says 'hi' to a fit bird sat across the way. Her mum says 'hi' and Murray says 'not you - hi'. The younger fit bird smiles and says 'hi'. This film is just great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny enough comedy,but slightly dry,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin is a funny movie with some laugh out loud scenes,a well thought out storyline and some pretty good actors,but I feel the movie goes on a bit,being two hours long and most animated films would only be an hour and a half,and find a lot of the humor to be a bit dry,not the Farrelly brothers finest work. A former bowler named Roy who hasn't bowled for over twenty years meets Ishmael,who is a natural bowler,Roy wants to get him to bowl for some professional games but it is hard to get him to take part because Ishmael is part of an Amish community,Roy eventually gets to Ishmael when pretends to be Amish himself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Comedy I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    schuster_mark
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I take my comedy seriously (no pun intended). I grew up watching the original cast of SNL, three stooges and actors like Gene Wilder. They all had something special, and I think remain extremely special 30 years later. Kingpin has that rare "something special". I had to watch this movie a few times before I fully appreciated the "once in a lifetime" performances by Harrelson and Murray, and outstanding writing by the Farrelly brothers. This movie, unlike most other comedies I've seen, continually provides genuinely funny moments throughout the entire movie. There are very few comedies I have ever watched that I can say the same about. It's like all the stars in the sky aligned for one perfect moment and in that moment they filmed "Kingpin". Now, this film may not be for every one. It's crude, rude and in your face comedy. It's typical Farrelly brother fare. If you like that, or even if you don't and just like the silly comedy of Bill Murray (before he went all serious) - then this movie is well worth a watch. Definitely a 10 out of 10 in my book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bowl me over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Following their success with "Dumb and Dumber", the Farrelly brothers directed "Kingpin", about a mangled bowler (Woody Harrelson) who trains an Amish man (Randy Quaid) to bowl. Since this is the guys behind "There's Something About Mary", there are naturally a few scenes with no purpose except to have a gross-out gag. But it is pretty funny throughout most of the movie, with a lot of mild gags. I suspect that the Amish didn't like it. But I liked it, and I recommend it. Also starring Vanessa Angel, Bill Murray, Chris Elliott, William Jordan and Lin Shaye (the sunburned neighbor in "TSAM" and the retiring flight attendant in "Snakes on a Plane").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Laughs from a Terrific Cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin (1996) *** (out of 4) Bowler Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) has everything in front of him until another bowler (Bill Murray) sells him out to a group of men they've just hustled and they end up cutting off Munson bowling hand, which puts an end to his career. Seventeen years later Munson is a worthless drunk who sees his chance back in the hopes of a Amish man (Randy Quaid) who he plans on getting to Reno for a big tournament. This was the Farrelly brothers follow-up to DUMB AND DUMBER and unlike that film, this one here wasn't a huge hit out of the gate and instead it took sometime to build up its cult following. I'm really not sure why this movie didn't hit it big when first released but time has been quite friendly to the raunchy comedy as it's certainly one of the better comedies of its period thanks in large part to a terrific cast, a nice story and plenty of big laughs. I think the story itself really isn't anything too special as it's pretty much your typical road movie with the biggest difference being the bowling subplot. I think what really makes this film so special are the three leads who are so perfect in their roles that you really can't imagine anyone else in the world playing them. Harrelson has always been an underrated comic actor and he does a very good job here and manages to get laughs out of the smallest stuff. Just the way he laughs or looks at someone can get a laugh but even better is the way he sells some of the jokes including a hilarious bit on the Amish farm where he pretends to know what he's doing, which leads him to "milking" a bull. Quaid can play an idiot like no other and make it look very easy. The way he brings this Amish guy to life is a lot of fun to watch because you really do feel as if you're watching someone real and someone experiencing the real world for the first time. Murray does what only he can as that type of comedy isn't easy and I can't think of anyone else who can pull it off. Apparently Murray ad-libbed just about every word in the film and the way he pulls this character off really helps bring in the laughs. Vanessa Angel fits in with the boys very well and manages a few nice laughs of her own as does Chris Elliott in his brief scenes. I think the film would have benefited had it lost about ten-minutes worth of footage because at just under two-hours the film is a little too long. The stuff with Angel's boyfriend isn't the funniest bits here and everything that happens with him in the second half should have been left out. The great thing about KINGPIN is that it never really delivers the type of laugh that you might expect and that's why the film works so well. The movie will have a scene set up and you might think you know where it's going but the funny part is seeing how different it plays out. The movie has some fairly low-taste laughs but the brothers were clearly just warming up as THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT MARY was just two years away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crude, rude, silly and........hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Can't believe this isn't rated higher, I have always loved this totally silly movie since I saw it in the theater years ago. There are some lulls here and there and maybe too much character development (if that's possible) but Woody is spot on, Murry is just insanely funny with his hair don't, and the rest of the cast is great too. Ishmael's slow decline into every vice there is is great. I'm sure this is not to everyones taste and I'm glad, not all of us are into bull seamen and oral sex with old lady jokes but for those who are you will be quite content. Even the bowling is funny in this early Farrelly brothers film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and bleak
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taygeta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike Harrelson's other masterpiece, White Men Can't Jump, this comedy certainly promises laughs and repeated viewings. On the other hand, there is a constant feeling of desolation and sadness. Ultimately this film could be described as being real. The performances from every cast member serve to create distinct and memorable characters, including the genius Bill Murray as the veritable king of the pins. Depending on who you are speaking with, this movie may have even spawned a dictionary worthy term, although I will leave it out of this review in the interest of little disclosure. "10 frames, that's for Quakers!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a STRIK.....OK no pins...i mean puns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DjangoLand
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only recently decided to somewhat commit to participating in contributing reviews to IMDb and reality hit me in the face when realising that it was 17 years ago when this classic came out. 17 years, and boy do i miss these kind of films, When the Farrelly brothers made great comedy movies. Of course they have taken their feet of the pedals, but their first 4 were instant classics. It may not be a laugh out loud film that has you giggling all the way through, but it has a certain charm to it (despite the crudeness) that keeps you smiling throughout. There are plenty of hilarious moments and great one liners. Bill Murray is fantastic as Big Ern and gels brilliantly with Woody Harrelson. The rest of the cast play their parts to make this a must see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Funniest Movies Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_the_Hobo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bowling legend Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) loses a hand to a group of drunks after trying to con them with fellow bowler Ernie McCracken (Bill Murray). Now a drunk promoter with a fake rubber hand, Munson is a shadow of his former self until he hears the fateful sound of a strike. Amish prodigy Ishmael (Randy Quaid) stands to be Munson's shot at winning the largest tournament in the country, but the road there is paved with consequence. This is one of the funniest movies ever made. The Farrelly brothers have given us countless laughs, but this is their best. It brings together some of the most unexpected actors, many out of their element in a comedy, to flawlessly turn a script into a comedic work of art. The laughs are typical Farrelly gross out while remaining truly, deeply funny. Woody Harrelson turns in one of his best performances as the down-but-not-out Munson, wearing a ridiculous wig, outdated clothing, and always his fake rubber hand. Each scene he's in is a lesson in how to lead a comedy, and reminds one of his early days on "Cheers" as the bartender Woody Boyd. His co-star in Quaid is the same; whether it be the murderous, greedy Sheriff is "Hard Rain", or here as the hilariously simple sure relative of the "Vacation" movies Cousin Eddie, Randy Quaid proves his ever surprising versatility as an actor. Bill Murray also fires on all cylinders as the over the top McCracken, Harrelson's arch-nemesis. Murray's last scene is one of the best in the movie; with his hair tossed every which way and his eyes flooding with tears he makes you shocked that he's only been nominated for one Oscar. Vanessa Angel is mostly eye candy but she doesn't have to make up for any acting downfalls. "Kingpin" is well-casted, well-written, consistently engaging and always funny. It brings together a diverse cast and a great script to make one of the funniest movies of our time. Strike it off your bucket list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You have a monkey?....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roy Munson was the best bowler in the world. But a fellow bowler, Ernie McCracken and a misunderstanding with some rough punks, left Roy with the loss of his bowling hand. He gets a prosthetic hand and becomes a travelling salesman. But it's really all down hill for him from that night on until he meets Ishmael who is Amish and sneaks away from the farm to bowl. Roy convinces Ishmael to let him be his trainer and he'll make him the best bowler the world has ever seen. Reluctantly Ishmael agrees to go on the road and shortly afterwards actually finds that life outside the farm is quite fun. Soon their paths cross that of Ernie McCracken who is still a top ranking bowler. While Roy's career and life have landed in the toilet bowl, Ernie is still drawing huge crowds.... Whilenot as good as Dumb and Dumber, the Farrellys comedy still felt pretty fresh and new for it's time of release. If this was released now, it wouldn't have has the plaudits is had, it would probably end up on late night TV, and wouldn't have the great cast. Harrelson is great as Roy, but cannot hold up to Quaid and a brilliant Murray, whenever they are on screen, the film really shines and becomes funny. Sadly, the rest of the film relies on horrid toilet humour and scenes that try and push the boundaries for a '12' movie, it doesn't work and the film has aged badly. That said, the hair is great in this movie, and while the Farrellys haven't really made a good original film for fourteen years, they proved with their first three movies they were a little left-field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hangover cure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jason_curtis24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely hilarious, deadpan stupid at times, and more reserved and subtle at others - its the perfect hangover cure. Harrelson is fantastic as a hard-done-by bowler who got done over ('Munsoned' is the phrase later used, which is his actual name in the film to his annoyance) and is out for another shot at the big time. His sidekick is an innocent religious countryman whose style contrasts well with all the others - Murray is just great, but could have been in it more. One scene, for me, really stands out. Certainly in terms of Gramsci esque masculine humour - Murray is in a eaterie with Harrelson and tells him to 'go outside and eat that', then he tells a waitress to come back after washing off her perfume, finally he says 'hi' to a fit bird sat across the way. Her mum says 'hi' and Murray says 'not you - hi'. The younger fit bird smiles and says 'hi'. This film is just great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny enough comedy,but slightly dry,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin is a funny movie with some laugh out loud scenes,a well thought out storyline and some pretty good actors,but I feel the movie goes on a bit,being two hours long and most animated films would only be an hour and a half,and find a lot of the humor to be a bit dry,not the Farrelly brothers finest work. A former bowler named Roy who hasn't bowled for over twenty years meets Ishmael,who is a natural bowler,Roy wants to get him to bowl for some professional games but it is hard to get him to take part because Ishmael is part of an Amish community,Roy eventually gets to Ishmael when pretends to be Amish himself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Comedy I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    schuster_mark
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I take my comedy seriously (no pun intended). I grew up watching the original cast of SNL, three stooges and actors like Gene Wilder. They all had something special, and I think remain extremely special 30 years later. Kingpin has that rare "something special". I had to watch this movie a few times before I fully appreciated the "once in a lifetime" performances by Harrelson and Murray, and outstanding writing by the Farrelly brothers. This movie, unlike most other comedies I've seen, continually provides genuinely funny moments throughout the entire movie. There are very few comedies I have ever watched that I can say the same about. It's like all the stars in the sky aligned for one perfect moment and in that moment they filmed "Kingpin". Now, this film may not be for every one. It's crude, rude and in your face comedy. It's typical Farrelly brother fare. If you like that, or even if you don't and just like the silly comedy of Bill Murray (before he went all serious) - then this movie is well worth a watch. Definitely a 10 out of 10 in my book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bowl me over
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Following their success with "Dumb and Dumber", the Farrelly brothers directed "Kingpin", about a mangled bowler (Woody Harrelson) who trains an Amish man (Randy Quaid) to bowl. Since this is the guys behind "There's Something About Mary", there are naturally a few scenes with no purpose except to have a gross-out gag. But it is pretty funny throughout most of the movie, with a lot of mild gags. I suspect that the Amish didn't like it. But I liked it, and I recommend it. Also starring Vanessa Angel, Bill Murray, Chris Elliott, William Jordan and Lin Shaye (the sunburned neighbor in "TSAM" and the retiring flight attendant in "Snakes on a Plane").
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Laughs from a Terrific Cast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kingpin (1996) *** (out of 4) Bowler Roy Munson (Woody Harrelson) has everything in front of him until another bowler (Bill Murray) sells him out to a group of men they've just hustled and they end up cutting off Munson bowling hand, which puts an end to his career. Seventeen years later Munson is a worthless drunk who sees his chance back in the hopes of a Amish man (Randy Quaid) who he plans on getting to Reno for a big tournament. This was the Farrelly brothers follow-up to DUMB AND DUMBER and unlike that film, this one here wasn't a huge hit out of the gate and instead it took sometime to build up its cult following. I'm really not sure why this movie didn't hit it big when first released but time has been quite friendly to the raunchy comedy as it's certainly one of the better comedies of its period thanks in large part to a terrific cast, a nice story and plenty of big laughs. I think the story itself really isn't anything too special as it's pretty much your typical road movie with the biggest difference being the bowling subplot. I think what really makes this film so special are the three leads who are so perfect in their roles that you really can't imagine anyone else in the world playing them. Harrelson has always been an underrated comic actor and he does a very good job here and manages to get laughs out of the smallest stuff. Just the way he laughs or looks at someone can get a laugh but even better is the way he sells some of the jokes including a hilarious bit on the Amish farm where he pretends to know what he's doing, which leads him to "milking" a bull. Quaid can play an idiot like no other and make it look very easy. The way he brings this Amish guy to life is a lot of fun to watch because you really do feel as if you're watching someone real and someone experiencing the real world for the first time. Murray does what only he can as that type of comedy isn't easy and I can't think of anyone else who can pull it off. Apparently Murray ad-libbed just about every word in the film and the way he pulls this character off really helps bring in the laughs. Vanessa Angel fits in with the boys very well and manages a few nice laughs of her own as does Chris Elliott in his brief scenes. I think the film would have benefited had it lost about ten-minutes worth of footage because at just under two-hours the film is a little too long. The stuff with Angel's boyfriend isn't the funniest bits here and everything that happens with him in the second half should have been left out. The great thing about KINGPIN is that it never really delivers the type of laugh that you might expect and that's why the film works so well. The movie will have a scene set up and you might think you know where it's going but the funny part is seeing how different it plays out. The movie has some fairly low-taste laughs but the brothers were clearly just warming up as THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT MARY was just two years away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crude, rude, silly and........hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    headly66
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Can't believe this isn't rated higher, I have always loved this totally silly movie since I saw it in the theater years ago. There are some lulls here and there and maybe too much character development (if that's possible) but Woody is spot on, Murry is just insanely funny with his hair don't, and the rest of the cast is great too. Ishmael's slow decline into every vice there is is great. I'm sure this is not to everyones taste and I'm glad, not all of us are into bull seamen and oral sex with old lady jokes but for those who are you will be quite content. Even the bowling is funny in this early Farrelly brothers film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful and bleak
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    taygeta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike Harrelson's other masterpiece, White Men Can't Jump, this comedy certainly promises laughs and repeated viewings. On the other hand, there is a constant feeling of desolation and sadness. Ultimately this film could be described as being real. The performances from every cast member serve to create distinct and memorable characters, including the genius Bill Murray as the veritable king of the pins. Depending on who you are speaking with, this movie may have even spawned a dictionary worthy term, although I will leave it out of this review in the interest of little disclosure. "10 frames, that's for Quakers!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
