<filme>
 <id>
  414
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0084370
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1982
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Cara Muito Baratinado
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A dissolute matinee idol is slated to appear on a live TV variety show.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Benjy Stone is the junior writer on the top rated variety/comedy show, in the mid 50s (the early years). Its a new medium and the rules were not fully established. Alan Swann, an Erol Flynn type actor with a drinking problem is to be that weeks guest star. When King Kaiser, the headliner wants to throw Swann off the show, Benjy makes a pitch to save his childhood hero, and is made Swann's babysitter. On top of this, a union boss doesn't care for Kaiser's parody of him and has plans to stop the show.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   star
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   movie star
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   television
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   live television
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jewish
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Richard Benjamin
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Norman Steinberg
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Dennis Palumbo
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Peter O'Toole
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mark Linn-Baker
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jessica Harper
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peter the Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjnxn-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exuding charm in every frame this is a lovingly made evocation of the early years of live television. Perfectly cast in every role and with a wonderful sense of period this will captivate you from the first scene all the way through to the touching finale. Director Benjamin wisely filled his parts with only one star and the rest talented character actors, anything else would have thrown the balance of the film off. Of those character actors all are terrific but a few stand out. Mark Linn Baker is ideal as Benjy, the schlubby protagonist, Lainie Kazan a scream as his mother and Selma Diamond a no nonsense delight as the wardrobe woman with her ever present cigarette dangling from her lips. Though she doesn't have much of a part keep an eye out for Gloria Stuart in a lovely scene dancing with Peter O'Toole. All of them and the other cast members are wonderful but the film wouldn't mean a thing if the part of Alan Swann wasn't believably cast. Fortunately the film makers were able to get Peter O'Toole, radiating star quality and charisma, and he could not possibly be better. Tender, humorous, dramatic, almost always over the top and also always a bit sad this is without question some of his best work in a career full of great performances. The fact that O'Toole himself at times behaved off camera as the character does in the film only adds to the pleasure of his work. A beautiful jewel of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wacky Load of Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hilarious, an unexpected joy. The laughs keep coming, thanks to an expert cast and a big dose of Jewish humor. No one seems in charge of getting the weekly TV show together for an audience of 20-million. Instead, everyone backstage appears to be rushing around like spinning tops. Even the alleged star King Kaiser (Bologna) can't seem to keep the order of his skits straight. Looks to me like bibulous guest star Alan Swann (O'Toole) should fit right in, drunk or sober. Then there's poor young schlemiel (Linn-Baker) who gets to baby-sit Swann when not pursuing a fruitless romance with the comely K.C. (Harper). Mix in a bunch of mobsters who don't like being made fun of, and you've got a finale to end all finales, even if the mayhem is every TV producer's nightmare. Now I'm really curious whether the old Sid Caesar show was really as wild backstage as the movie presents it. At the time, I was a faithful watcher, so the hijinks here come as a special revelation. But what else could you expect from backstage characters like Caesar's writers Mel Brooks and Woody Allen. Anyhow, this was Dick Benjamin's first directorial outing even though you'd never know it. Then too, credit O'Toole with coming up with a really sly performance that alternates between drunken stupor and charming finesse. I particularly like it when Swann reveals his real self but still shifts gears into the movie swashbuckler when needed. All in all, it's a wacko comedy well deserving its place on Premiere's Top 50 comedies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good-Hearted Story of Dissipation and Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jpark4
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this movie five or six times. &nbsp;I liked it the first time I saw it, and I like it a little more each time I see it. &nbsp;It is a small film in many ways-no blockbuster, but with a big heart. &nbsp;Peter O'Toole is the biggest star in the film, and he does a superb job as the ex-Technicolor swashbuckler who has seen his last days as a leading man, finding solace in booze and casual sex. &nbsp;Mark Linn-Baker plays a young aspiring comedy writer, a great fan of Swann's, who is working as an intern on a comedy show in the early days of television, whose job it is to keep Alan Swann (O'Toole) in line while he prepares for a guest appearance. &nbsp;Helping him in this endeavor is Swann's driver and nursemaid &nbsp;Alfie Bumbacelli (Tony DiBenedetto). &nbsp; Together, they keep hold of Swann's coattails through several booze driven adventures leading up to show night and a hilarious and touching denouement. &nbsp;The story is funny and poignant, with a nice payoff. &nbsp;The characters are all likable, and the acting is uniformly good. &nbsp;It is a story of dissipation and redemption, handled with a nice touch that keeps the lighter side in the fore, but still able to make it's more "sober" points. &nbsp;Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not amazing, but Bravo O'Toole...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    halley-devestern
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've heard people gushing about this movie for years and have always been interested in seeing it. I finally had the chance to see it for the first time today on TCM. I'm sad to say I was quite disappointed overall, but I did enjoy Peter O'Toole's performance immensely. This movie could have been truly amazing if the direction and editing were better. The cast is wonderful (I like Mark Linn-Baker, but a better director would have reined in his youthful over-acting here), the script is good and the story is charming. But the pace is tediously slow. As they say in the industry, you could have driven a truck through the pauses between the lines. Yikes. The movie could still have been tightened up in post-production editing, but no soap. And I'm not a youngster whose attention span has been irrevocably destroyed by the Internet. It's a sad day for me, I had been really looking forward to this movie. But, as always, Bravo O'Toole. What a treasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Year; My Favorite Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlktrout
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was in Germany when the film came out so didn't see it for the first time until 1984 or so, but I have seen it probably almost every year since then. I should have it memorized by now, but somehow each viewing I find something new and special. I've loved it since the first time I saw it. There is little I can add to the basic story--a washed-up Errol Flynn type of action movie star goes on a live television comedy program in the 1950s. O'Toole is just masterful in the part and according to director Benjamin, he even insisted on doing all his own stunts (some of which were dangerous!). I could believe him as a movie hero and as a real-life washout. Joseph Balogna is just hysterical as the Sid Caesar TV star, rough, bombastic, occasionally mean, but kind under the crust, and utterly fearless. I grinned at every sight of him. Mark Linn-Baker is superb as the kid from Brooklyn who finds himself rubbing shoulders with his childhood hero and discovering the statue has feet of clay. His embarrassment over his background and his weird family rings true and yet are hilarious; I forget the name of the actress who plays his mother, but she is screamingly funny. I just can't say how much I love this movie, how inspiring I find it, how it touches my heart. But it's my favorite movie, and in a house where we own something like 5,000 movies and most of our conversations contain at least one movie quote, this film is quoted almost daily, so that's saying something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely an under-appreciated comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's quite surprising to find out about a movie that no one has ever told you off before but turns out to be a real hidden treasure. "My Favorite Year" is a more than great comedy, that is fun, as well as funny to watch. Key to what makes this a great movie to watch, is that it's being a fun one throughout. It's a fast going, snappy comedy, that doesn't necessarily force or exaggerate its comedy, to any extreme forms. It's playing things more subtly and more often relies on its dialog and actors, rather than on any comical situations. It makes the movie very pleasant and likable, also because it manages to maintain its good quick pace throughout its entire running time. The story really doesn't matter all that much for this movie, other than taking the characters from the one place and situation to the other. I'm not saying that it isn't any good but to me it just wasn't important for what this movie was all about and trying to do. Even the weaker moments in this movie and its story still work out well, thanks to its characters and the actors portraying them. Peter O'Toole plays Errol Flynn, even though his character is named differently in the movie. But he is Flynn and even plays some of the sequences out of some classic Errol Flynn movies. This all was great fun to watch and his presence truly adds a lot to this movie as well. He's perfectly classy and often despicable at the same time. But Mark Linn-Baker was also truly great! Whatever went wrong with his career? He was not only a great comedy actor but simply just a great actor in general as well. The movie has a more old fashioned type of comedy vibe to it, like a '40's production, which is also the time period this movie is being set in (well, the '50's but still), so it's no big surprise or a coincidence all. If you are a fan of these type of snappy and screwball like comedies, from the '40's mostly, changes are you will also absolutely love this movie as well! Anyway, this movie is an extremely fun and recommendable one, for everybody! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dying is easy.......Comedy is hard!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lenie Colacino
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So says Alan Swann and he is so right. Peter O'Toole shows that there is a great actor inside of a great comedic performance. His remarkable portrayal of Swann stands out among all his other performances because Swann, in so many ways, is a thinly veiled O'Toole. His timing, physical grace and delivery rival the all time greats including Chaplin, Laurel, and Gleason. The pacing, casting and plot are expertly woven by director Richard Benjamin to create an inside look at early T. V. production and a crazy Jewish family. The scene of Swan attending dinner in Brooklyn with staff writer Benjy Stone's family is one of the funniest in screen history due in equal parts to the fantastic performances of O'Toole, Lou Jacobi (as a scene-stealing "Uncle Mortie") and Lainie Kazan as the mother of all Jewish mothers. As Swann, O'Toole manages to be loathsome, endearing, infuriating, charming and vulnerable. Kudos to Bill Macy as Benjy's crass boss and Joseph Bologna as the hot-tempered but indomitable King Kaiser. My Favorite Year never disappoints in delivering laughs and perhaps a sentimental tear as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet, funny comedy about 1950s television
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sweet comedy about 50s television (specifically 'Your Show of Shows'), and the week that a fading film great (clearly based on Errol Flynn) guest stars. A simply terrific comic performance by Peter O'Toole as the almost washed up star, close to matched in a supporting role by Joe Bologna as a tough cantankerous Sid Cesar stand in. On the other hand, there's something of the feeling of a TV sitcom to a lot of it, with stagy blocking, and obvious schmaltz. And some of the supporting characters are out of another movie, just a little too cartoony to fit with the broad, but reality based leads. My feelings about the film are also affected by the fact that I remember the script, with it's more bittersweet ending, as having more heart and soul than the final product. None-the-less, this is a charming, well-acted comedy, and deserves it's good reputation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Peter O'Toole is unquestionably the star of "My Favorite Year" in the part of an aging film star, whose major preoccupations are having sex with beautiful young women and getting roaring drunk, he's not the only actor to acquit himself well in this film. Joseph Bologna as King Kaiser, a TV comedian, imitates Sid Caesar with considerable success, Mark Linn-Baker is very good as a junior writer on the show assigned to make sure that Alan Swann (O'Toole's character modeled on Errol Flynn) is actually on hand when the show is broadcast, and Jessica Baker is charming as the young writer's love interest. But O'Toole dominates the comedy just as he dominated his best known dramatic films, and he is hilarious, reminding us that his star, when at its brightest, shown brilliantly not alone because he was physically beautiful but because the guy could really act. His imitation of a drunk is priceless, even though, in fact, O'Toole unfortunately had a good deal of experience to go with his acting talent on this particular matter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "This Is For Ladies Only!" "So Is This, Ma'am, But Every Now And Then I Have To Run A Little Water Through It."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Benjy Stone is the junior writer on the top rated variety/comedy show, in the mid 50s (the early years). Its a new medium and the rules were not fully established. Alan Swann, an Erol Flynn type actor with a drinking problem is to be that weeks guest star. When King Kaiser, the headliner wants to throw Swann off the show, Benjy makes a pitch to save his childhood hero, and is made Swann's babysitter. On top of this, a union boss doesn't care for Kaiser's parody of him and has plans to stop the show. Boy Peter O'Toole Creates One Of The Greatest One Of The Best Comedy Characters Of All Time In This Movie Allan Swann. Peter O'Toole Also Is Funny From Start To Finish. I Am Surprised No-One Has Remade This Movie. It Would Be Better Than Any Comedy Released Since 2006(Besides Superhero Movie(I Do Watch A Lot Of Stupid Comedy's)). Now Let Me See Whats 'My Favourite Year'...For Movies. I Personally Enjoyed The Year 2005 For Movies Not Because It Made My Favourite Movie (It Didn't). But The Quantity Of Good Movies That Year Was Great. I Loved This Movie As A Comedy. Its Gonna Be A Classic To Me. Rating: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peter the Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjnxn-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exuding charm in every frame this is a lovingly made evocation of the early years of live television. Perfectly cast in every role and with a wonderful sense of period this will captivate you from the first scene all the way through to the touching finale. Director Benjamin wisely filled his parts with only one star and the rest talented character actors, anything else would have thrown the balance of the film off. Of those character actors all are terrific but a few stand out. Mark Linn Baker is ideal as Benjy, the schlubby protagonist, Lainie Kazan a scream as his mother and Selma Diamond a no nonsense delight as the wardrobe woman with her ever present cigarette dangling from her lips. Though she doesn't have much of a part keep an eye out for Gloria Stuart in a lovely scene dancing with Peter O'Toole. All of them and the other cast members are wonderful but the film wouldn't mean a thing if the part of Alan Swann wasn't believably cast. Fortunately the film makers were able to get Peter O'Toole, radiating star quality and charisma, and he could not possibly be better. Tender, humorous, dramatic, almost always over the top and also always a bit sad this is without question some of his best work in a career full of great performances. The fact that O'Toole himself at times behaved off camera as the character does in the film only adds to the pleasure of his work. A beautiful jewel of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wacky Load of Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hilarious, an unexpected joy. The laughs keep coming, thanks to an expert cast and a big dose of Jewish humor. No one seems in charge of getting the weekly TV show together for an audience of 20-million. Instead, everyone backstage appears to be rushing around like spinning tops. Even the alleged star King Kaiser (Bologna) can't seem to keep the order of his skits straight. Looks to me like bibulous guest star Alan Swann (O'Toole) should fit right in, drunk or sober. Then there's poor young schlemiel (Linn-Baker) who gets to baby-sit Swann when not pursuing a fruitless romance with the comely K.C. (Harper). Mix in a bunch of mobsters who don't like being made fun of, and you've got a finale to end all finales, even if the mayhem is every TV producer's nightmare. Now I'm really curious whether the old Sid Caesar show was really as wild backstage as the movie presents it. At the time, I was a faithful watcher, so the hijinks here come as a special revelation. But what else could you expect from backstage characters like Caesar's writers Mel Brooks and Woody Allen. Anyhow, this was Dick Benjamin's first directorial outing even though you'd never know it. Then too, credit O'Toole with coming up with a really sly performance that alternates between drunken stupor and charming finesse. I particularly like it when Swann reveals his real self but still shifts gears into the movie swashbuckler when needed. All in all, it's a wacko comedy well deserving its place on Premiere's Top 50 comedies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good-Hearted Story of Dissipation and Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jpark4
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this movie five or six times. &nbsp;I liked it the first time I saw it, and I like it a little more each time I see it. &nbsp;It is a small film in many ways-no blockbuster, but with a big heart. &nbsp;Peter O'Toole is the biggest star in the film, and he does a superb job as the ex-Technicolor swashbuckler who has seen his last days as a leading man, finding solace in booze and casual sex. &nbsp;Mark Linn-Baker plays a young aspiring comedy writer, a great fan of Swann's, who is working as an intern on a comedy show in the early days of television, whose job it is to keep Alan Swann (O'Toole) in line while he prepares for a guest appearance. &nbsp;Helping him in this endeavor is Swann's driver and nursemaid &nbsp;Alfie Bumbacelli (Tony DiBenedetto). &nbsp; Together, they keep hold of Swann's coattails through several booze driven adventures leading up to show night and a hilarious and touching denouement. &nbsp;The story is funny and poignant, with a nice payoff. &nbsp;The characters are all likable, and the acting is uniformly good. &nbsp;It is a story of dissipation and redemption, handled with a nice touch that keeps the lighter side in the fore, but still able to make it's more "sober" points. &nbsp;Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not amazing, but Bravo O'Toole...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    halley-devestern
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've heard people gushing about this movie for years and have always been interested in seeing it. I finally had the chance to see it for the first time today on TCM. I'm sad to say I was quite disappointed overall, but I did enjoy Peter O'Toole's performance immensely. This movie could have been truly amazing if the direction and editing were better. The cast is wonderful (I like Mark Linn-Baker, but a better director would have reined in his youthful over-acting here), the script is good and the story is charming. But the pace is tediously slow. As they say in the industry, you could have driven a truck through the pauses between the lines. Yikes. The movie could still have been tightened up in post-production editing, but no soap. And I'm not a youngster whose attention span has been irrevocably destroyed by the Internet. It's a sad day for me, I had been really looking forward to this movie. But, as always, Bravo O'Toole. What a treasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Year; My Favorite Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlktrout
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was in Germany when the film came out so didn't see it for the first time until 1984 or so, but I have seen it probably almost every year since then. I should have it memorized by now, but somehow each viewing I find something new and special. I've loved it since the first time I saw it. There is little I can add to the basic story--a washed-up Errol Flynn type of action movie star goes on a live television comedy program in the 1950s. O'Toole is just masterful in the part and according to director Benjamin, he even insisted on doing all his own stunts (some of which were dangerous!). I could believe him as a movie hero and as a real-life washout. Joseph Balogna is just hysterical as the Sid Caesar TV star, rough, bombastic, occasionally mean, but kind under the crust, and utterly fearless. I grinned at every sight of him. Mark Linn-Baker is superb as the kid from Brooklyn who finds himself rubbing shoulders with his childhood hero and discovering the statue has feet of clay. His embarrassment over his background and his weird family rings true and yet are hilarious; I forget the name of the actress who plays his mother, but she is screamingly funny. I just can't say how much I love this movie, how inspiring I find it, how it touches my heart. But it's my favorite movie, and in a house where we own something like 5,000 movies and most of our conversations contain at least one movie quote, this film is quoted almost daily, so that's saying something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely an under-appreciated comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's quite surprising to find out about a movie that no one has ever told you off before but turns out to be a real hidden treasure. "My Favorite Year" is a more than great comedy, that is fun, as well as funny to watch. Key to what makes this a great movie to watch, is that it's being a fun one throughout. It's a fast going, snappy comedy, that doesn't necessarily force or exaggerate its comedy, to any extreme forms. It's playing things more subtly and more often relies on its dialog and actors, rather than on any comical situations. It makes the movie very pleasant and likable, also because it manages to maintain its good quick pace throughout its entire running time. The story really doesn't matter all that much for this movie, other than taking the characters from the one place and situation to the other. I'm not saying that it isn't any good but to me it just wasn't important for what this movie was all about and trying to do. Even the weaker moments in this movie and its story still work out well, thanks to its characters and the actors portraying them. Peter O'Toole plays Errol Flynn, even though his character is named differently in the movie. But he is Flynn and even plays some of the sequences out of some classic Errol Flynn movies. This all was great fun to watch and his presence truly adds a lot to this movie as well. He's perfectly classy and often despicable at the same time. But Mark Linn-Baker was also truly great! Whatever went wrong with his career? He was not only a great comedy actor but simply just a great actor in general as well. The movie has a more old fashioned type of comedy vibe to it, like a '40's production, which is also the time period this movie is being set in (well, the '50's but still), so it's no big surprise or a coincidence all. If you are a fan of these type of snappy and screwball like comedies, from the '40's mostly, changes are you will also absolutely love this movie as well! Anyway, this movie is an extremely fun and recommendable one, for everybody! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dying is easy.......Comedy is hard!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lenie Colacino
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So says Alan Swann and he is so right. Peter O'Toole shows that there is a great actor inside of a great comedic performance. His remarkable portrayal of Swann stands out among all his other performances because Swann, in so many ways, is a thinly veiled O'Toole. His timing, physical grace and delivery rival the all time greats including Chaplin, Laurel, and Gleason. The pacing, casting and plot are expertly woven by director Richard Benjamin to create an inside look at early T. V. production and a crazy Jewish family. The scene of Swan attending dinner in Brooklyn with staff writer Benjy Stone's family is one of the funniest in screen history due in equal parts to the fantastic performances of O'Toole, Lou Jacobi (as a scene-stealing "Uncle Mortie") and Lainie Kazan as the mother of all Jewish mothers. As Swann, O'Toole manages to be loathsome, endearing, infuriating, charming and vulnerable. Kudos to Bill Macy as Benjy's crass boss and Joseph Bologna as the hot-tempered but indomitable King Kaiser. My Favorite Year never disappoints in delivering laughs and perhaps a sentimental tear as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet, funny comedy about 1950s television
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sweet comedy about 50s television (specifically 'Your Show of Shows'), and the week that a fading film great (clearly based on Errol Flynn) guest stars. A simply terrific comic performance by Peter O'Toole as the almost washed up star, close to matched in a supporting role by Joe Bologna as a tough cantankerous Sid Cesar stand in. On the other hand, there's something of the feeling of a TV sitcom to a lot of it, with stagy blocking, and obvious schmaltz. And some of the supporting characters are out of another movie, just a little too cartoony to fit with the broad, but reality based leads. My feelings about the film are also affected by the fact that I remember the script, with it's more bittersweet ending, as having more heart and soul than the final product. None-the-less, this is a charming, well-acted comedy, and deserves it's good reputation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Peter O'Toole is unquestionably the star of "My Favorite Year" in the part of an aging film star, whose major preoccupations are having sex with beautiful young women and getting roaring drunk, he's not the only actor to acquit himself well in this film. Joseph Bologna as King Kaiser, a TV comedian, imitates Sid Caesar with considerable success, Mark Linn-Baker is very good as a junior writer on the show assigned to make sure that Alan Swann (O'Toole's character modeled on Errol Flynn) is actually on hand when the show is broadcast, and Jessica Baker is charming as the young writer's love interest. But O'Toole dominates the comedy just as he dominated his best known dramatic films, and he is hilarious, reminding us that his star, when at its brightest, shown brilliantly not alone because he was physically beautiful but because the guy could really act. His imitation of a drunk is priceless, even though, in fact, O'Toole unfortunately had a good deal of experience to go with his acting talent on this particular matter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "This Is For Ladies Only!" "So Is This, Ma'am, But Every Now And Then I Have To Run A Little Water Through It."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Benjy Stone is the junior writer on the top rated variety/comedy show, in the mid 50s (the early years). Its a new medium and the rules were not fully established. Alan Swann, an Erol Flynn type actor with a drinking problem is to be that weeks guest star. When King Kaiser, the headliner wants to throw Swann off the show, Benjy makes a pitch to save his childhood hero, and is made Swann's babysitter. On top of this, a union boss doesn't care for Kaiser's parody of him and has plans to stop the show. Boy Peter O'Toole Creates One Of The Greatest One Of The Best Comedy Characters Of All Time In This Movie Allan Swann. Peter O'Toole Also Is Funny From Start To Finish. I Am Surprised No-One Has Remade This Movie. It Would Be Better Than Any Comedy Released Since 2006(Besides Superhero Movie(I Do Watch A Lot Of Stupid Comedy's)). Now Let Me See Whats 'My Favourite Year'...For Movies. I Personally Enjoyed The Year 2005 For Movies Not Because It Made My Favourite Movie (It Didn't). But The Quantity Of Good Movies That Year Was Great. I Loved This Movie As A Comedy. Its Gonna Be A Classic To Me. Rating: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peter the Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjnxn-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exuding charm in every frame this is a lovingly made evocation of the early years of live television. Perfectly cast in every role and with a wonderful sense of period this will captivate you from the first scene all the way through to the touching finale. Director Benjamin wisely filled his parts with only one star and the rest talented character actors, anything else would have thrown the balance of the film off. Of those character actors all are terrific but a few stand out. Mark Linn Baker is ideal as Benjy, the schlubby protagonist, Lainie Kazan a scream as his mother and Selma Diamond a no nonsense delight as the wardrobe woman with her ever present cigarette dangling from her lips. Though she doesn't have much of a part keep an eye out for Gloria Stuart in a lovely scene dancing with Peter O'Toole. All of them and the other cast members are wonderful but the film wouldn't mean a thing if the part of Alan Swann wasn't believably cast. Fortunately the film makers were able to get Peter O'Toole, radiating star quality and charisma, and he could not possibly be better. Tender, humorous, dramatic, almost always over the top and also always a bit sad this is without question some of his best work in a career full of great performances. The fact that O'Toole himself at times behaved off camera as the character does in the film only adds to the pleasure of his work. A beautiful jewel of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wacky Load of Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hilarious, an unexpected joy. The laughs keep coming, thanks to an expert cast and a big dose of Jewish humor. No one seems in charge of getting the weekly TV show together for an audience of 20-million. Instead, everyone backstage appears to be rushing around like spinning tops. Even the alleged star King Kaiser (Bologna) can't seem to keep the order of his skits straight. Looks to me like bibulous guest star Alan Swann (O'Toole) should fit right in, drunk or sober. Then there's poor young schlemiel (Linn-Baker) who gets to baby-sit Swann when not pursuing a fruitless romance with the comely K.C. (Harper). Mix in a bunch of mobsters who don't like being made fun of, and you've got a finale to end all finales, even if the mayhem is every TV producer's nightmare. Now I'm really curious whether the old Sid Caesar show was really as wild backstage as the movie presents it. At the time, I was a faithful watcher, so the hijinks here come as a special revelation. But what else could you expect from backstage characters like Caesar's writers Mel Brooks and Woody Allen. Anyhow, this was Dick Benjamin's first directorial outing even though you'd never know it. Then too, credit O'Toole with coming up with a really sly performance that alternates between drunken stupor and charming finesse. I particularly like it when Swann reveals his real self but still shifts gears into the movie swashbuckler when needed. All in all, it's a wacko comedy well deserving its place on Premiere's Top 50 comedies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good-Hearted Story of Dissipation and Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jpark4
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this movie five or six times. &nbsp;I liked it the first time I saw it, and I like it a little more each time I see it. &nbsp;It is a small film in many ways-no blockbuster, but with a big heart. &nbsp;Peter O'Toole is the biggest star in the film, and he does a superb job as the ex-Technicolor swashbuckler who has seen his last days as a leading man, finding solace in booze and casual sex. &nbsp;Mark Linn-Baker plays a young aspiring comedy writer, a great fan of Swann's, who is working as an intern on a comedy show in the early days of television, whose job it is to keep Alan Swann (O'Toole) in line while he prepares for a guest appearance. &nbsp;Helping him in this endeavor is Swann's driver and nursemaid &nbsp;Alfie Bumbacelli (Tony DiBenedetto). &nbsp; Together, they keep hold of Swann's coattails through several booze driven adventures leading up to show night and a hilarious and touching denouement. &nbsp;The story is funny and poignant, with a nice payoff. &nbsp;The characters are all likable, and the acting is uniformly good. &nbsp;It is a story of dissipation and redemption, handled with a nice touch that keeps the lighter side in the fore, but still able to make it's more "sober" points. &nbsp;Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not amazing, but Bravo O'Toole...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    halley-devestern
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've heard people gushing about this movie for years and have always been interested in seeing it. I finally had the chance to see it for the first time today on TCM. I'm sad to say I was quite disappointed overall, but I did enjoy Peter O'Toole's performance immensely. This movie could have been truly amazing if the direction and editing were better. The cast is wonderful (I like Mark Linn-Baker, but a better director would have reined in his youthful over-acting here), the script is good and the story is charming. But the pace is tediously slow. As they say in the industry, you could have driven a truck through the pauses between the lines. Yikes. The movie could still have been tightened up in post-production editing, but no soap. And I'm not a youngster whose attention span has been irrevocably destroyed by the Internet. It's a sad day for me, I had been really looking forward to this movie. But, as always, Bravo O'Toole. What a treasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Year; My Favorite Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlktrout
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was in Germany when the film came out so didn't see it for the first time until 1984 or so, but I have seen it probably almost every year since then. I should have it memorized by now, but somehow each viewing I find something new and special. I've loved it since the first time I saw it. There is little I can add to the basic story--a washed-up Errol Flynn type of action movie star goes on a live television comedy program in the 1950s. O'Toole is just masterful in the part and according to director Benjamin, he even insisted on doing all his own stunts (some of which were dangerous!). I could believe him as a movie hero and as a real-life washout. Joseph Balogna is just hysterical as the Sid Caesar TV star, rough, bombastic, occasionally mean, but kind under the crust, and utterly fearless. I grinned at every sight of him. Mark Linn-Baker is superb as the kid from Brooklyn who finds himself rubbing shoulders with his childhood hero and discovering the statue has feet of clay. His embarrassment over his background and his weird family rings true and yet are hilarious; I forget the name of the actress who plays his mother, but she is screamingly funny. I just can't say how much I love this movie, how inspiring I find it, how it touches my heart. But it's my favorite movie, and in a house where we own something like 5,000 movies and most of our conversations contain at least one movie quote, this film is quoted almost daily, so that's saying something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely an under-appreciated comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's quite surprising to find out about a movie that no one has ever told you off before but turns out to be a real hidden treasure. "My Favorite Year" is a more than great comedy, that is fun, as well as funny to watch. Key to what makes this a great movie to watch, is that it's being a fun one throughout. It's a fast going, snappy comedy, that doesn't necessarily force or exaggerate its comedy, to any extreme forms. It's playing things more subtly and more often relies on its dialog and actors, rather than on any comical situations. It makes the movie very pleasant and likable, also because it manages to maintain its good quick pace throughout its entire running time. The story really doesn't matter all that much for this movie, other than taking the characters from the one place and situation to the other. I'm not saying that it isn't any good but to me it just wasn't important for what this movie was all about and trying to do. Even the weaker moments in this movie and its story still work out well, thanks to its characters and the actors portraying them. Peter O'Toole plays Errol Flynn, even though his character is named differently in the movie. But he is Flynn and even plays some of the sequences out of some classic Errol Flynn movies. This all was great fun to watch and his presence truly adds a lot to this movie as well. He's perfectly classy and often despicable at the same time. But Mark Linn-Baker was also truly great! Whatever went wrong with his career? He was not only a great comedy actor but simply just a great actor in general as well. The movie has a more old fashioned type of comedy vibe to it, like a '40's production, which is also the time period this movie is being set in (well, the '50's but still), so it's no big surprise or a coincidence all. If you are a fan of these type of snappy and screwball like comedies, from the '40's mostly, changes are you will also absolutely love this movie as well! Anyway, this movie is an extremely fun and recommendable one, for everybody! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dying is easy.......Comedy is hard!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lenie Colacino
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So says Alan Swann and he is so right. Peter O'Toole shows that there is a great actor inside of a great comedic performance. His remarkable portrayal of Swann stands out among all his other performances because Swann, in so many ways, is a thinly veiled O'Toole. His timing, physical grace and delivery rival the all time greats including Chaplin, Laurel, and Gleason. The pacing, casting and plot are expertly woven by director Richard Benjamin to create an inside look at early T. V. production and a crazy Jewish family. The scene of Swan attending dinner in Brooklyn with staff writer Benjy Stone's family is one of the funniest in screen history due in equal parts to the fantastic performances of O'Toole, Lou Jacobi (as a scene-stealing "Uncle Mortie") and Lainie Kazan as the mother of all Jewish mothers. As Swann, O'Toole manages to be loathsome, endearing, infuriating, charming and vulnerable. Kudos to Bill Macy as Benjy's crass boss and Joseph Bologna as the hot-tempered but indomitable King Kaiser. My Favorite Year never disappoints in delivering laughs and perhaps a sentimental tear as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet, funny comedy about 1950s television
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sweet comedy about 50s television (specifically 'Your Show of Shows'), and the week that a fading film great (clearly based on Errol Flynn) guest stars. A simply terrific comic performance by Peter O'Toole as the almost washed up star, close to matched in a supporting role by Joe Bologna as a tough cantankerous Sid Cesar stand in. On the other hand, there's something of the feeling of a TV sitcom to a lot of it, with stagy blocking, and obvious schmaltz. And some of the supporting characters are out of another movie, just a little too cartoony to fit with the broad, but reality based leads. My feelings about the film are also affected by the fact that I remember the script, with it's more bittersweet ending, as having more heart and soul than the final product. None-the-less, this is a charming, well-acted comedy, and deserves it's good reputation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Peter O'Toole is unquestionably the star of "My Favorite Year" in the part of an aging film star, whose major preoccupations are having sex with beautiful young women and getting roaring drunk, he's not the only actor to acquit himself well in this film. Joseph Bologna as King Kaiser, a TV comedian, imitates Sid Caesar with considerable success, Mark Linn-Baker is very good as a junior writer on the show assigned to make sure that Alan Swann (O'Toole's character modeled on Errol Flynn) is actually on hand when the show is broadcast, and Jessica Baker is charming as the young writer's love interest. But O'Toole dominates the comedy just as he dominated his best known dramatic films, and he is hilarious, reminding us that his star, when at its brightest, shown brilliantly not alone because he was physically beautiful but because the guy could really act. His imitation of a drunk is priceless, even though, in fact, O'Toole unfortunately had a good deal of experience to go with his acting talent on this particular matter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "This Is For Ladies Only!" "So Is This, Ma'am, But Every Now And Then I Have To Run A Little Water Through It."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Benjy Stone is the junior writer on the top rated variety/comedy show, in the mid 50s (the early years). Its a new medium and the rules were not fully established. Alan Swann, an Erol Flynn type actor with a drinking problem is to be that weeks guest star. When King Kaiser, the headliner wants to throw Swann off the show, Benjy makes a pitch to save his childhood hero, and is made Swann's babysitter. On top of this, a union boss doesn't care for Kaiser's parody of him and has plans to stop the show. Boy Peter O'Toole Creates One Of The Greatest One Of The Best Comedy Characters Of All Time In This Movie Allan Swann. Peter O'Toole Also Is Funny From Start To Finish. I Am Surprised No-One Has Remade This Movie. It Would Be Better Than Any Comedy Released Since 2006(Besides Superhero Movie(I Do Watch A Lot Of Stupid Comedy's)). Now Let Me See Whats 'My Favourite Year'...For Movies. I Personally Enjoyed The Year 2005 For Movies Not Because It Made My Favourite Movie (It Didn't). But The Quantity Of Good Movies That Year Was Great. I Loved This Movie As A Comedy. Its Gonna Be A Classic To Me. Rating: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peter the Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjnxn-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exuding charm in every frame this is a lovingly made evocation of the early years of live television. Perfectly cast in every role and with a wonderful sense of period this will captivate you from the first scene all the way through to the touching finale. Director Benjamin wisely filled his parts with only one star and the rest talented character actors, anything else would have thrown the balance of the film off. Of those character actors all are terrific but a few stand out. Mark Linn Baker is ideal as Benjy, the schlubby protagonist, Lainie Kazan a scream as his mother and Selma Diamond a no nonsense delight as the wardrobe woman with her ever present cigarette dangling from her lips. Though she doesn't have much of a part keep an eye out for Gloria Stuart in a lovely scene dancing with Peter O'Toole. All of them and the other cast members are wonderful but the film wouldn't mean a thing if the part of Alan Swann wasn't believably cast. Fortunately the film makers were able to get Peter O'Toole, radiating star quality and charisma, and he could not possibly be better. Tender, humorous, dramatic, almost always over the top and also always a bit sad this is without question some of his best work in a career full of great performances. The fact that O'Toole himself at times behaved off camera as the character does in the film only adds to the pleasure of his work. A beautiful jewel of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wacky Load of Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hilarious, an unexpected joy. The laughs keep coming, thanks to an expert cast and a big dose of Jewish humor. No one seems in charge of getting the weekly TV show together for an audience of 20-million. Instead, everyone backstage appears to be rushing around like spinning tops. Even the alleged star King Kaiser (Bologna) can't seem to keep the order of his skits straight. Looks to me like bibulous guest star Alan Swann (O'Toole) should fit right in, drunk or sober. Then there's poor young schlemiel (Linn-Baker) who gets to baby-sit Swann when not pursuing a fruitless romance with the comely K.C. (Harper). Mix in a bunch of mobsters who don't like being made fun of, and you've got a finale to end all finales, even if the mayhem is every TV producer's nightmare. Now I'm really curious whether the old Sid Caesar show was really as wild backstage as the movie presents it. At the time, I was a faithful watcher, so the hijinks here come as a special revelation. But what else could you expect from backstage characters like Caesar's writers Mel Brooks and Woody Allen. Anyhow, this was Dick Benjamin's first directorial outing even though you'd never know it. Then too, credit O'Toole with coming up with a really sly performance that alternates between drunken stupor and charming finesse. I particularly like it when Swann reveals his real self but still shifts gears into the movie swashbuckler when needed. All in all, it's a wacko comedy well deserving its place on Premiere's Top 50 comedies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good-Hearted Story of Dissipation and Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jpark4
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this movie five or six times. &nbsp;I liked it the first time I saw it, and I like it a little more each time I see it. &nbsp;It is a small film in many ways-no blockbuster, but with a big heart. &nbsp;Peter O'Toole is the biggest star in the film, and he does a superb job as the ex-Technicolor swashbuckler who has seen his last days as a leading man, finding solace in booze and casual sex. &nbsp;Mark Linn-Baker plays a young aspiring comedy writer, a great fan of Swann's, who is working as an intern on a comedy show in the early days of television, whose job it is to keep Alan Swann (O'Toole) in line while he prepares for a guest appearance. &nbsp;Helping him in this endeavor is Swann's driver and nursemaid &nbsp;Alfie Bumbacelli (Tony DiBenedetto). &nbsp; Together, they keep hold of Swann's coattails through several booze driven adventures leading up to show night and a hilarious and touching denouement. &nbsp;The story is funny and poignant, with a nice payoff. &nbsp;The characters are all likable, and the acting is uniformly good. &nbsp;It is a story of dissipation and redemption, handled with a nice touch that keeps the lighter side in the fore, but still able to make it's more "sober" points. &nbsp;Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not amazing, but Bravo O'Toole...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    halley-devestern
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've heard people gushing about this movie for years and have always been interested in seeing it. I finally had the chance to see it for the first time today on TCM. I'm sad to say I was quite disappointed overall, but I did enjoy Peter O'Toole's performance immensely. This movie could have been truly amazing if the direction and editing were better. The cast is wonderful (I like Mark Linn-Baker, but a better director would have reined in his youthful over-acting here), the script is good and the story is charming. But the pace is tediously slow. As they say in the industry, you could have driven a truck through the pauses between the lines. Yikes. The movie could still have been tightened up in post-production editing, but no soap. And I'm not a youngster whose attention span has been irrevocably destroyed by the Internet. It's a sad day for me, I had been really looking forward to this movie. But, as always, Bravo O'Toole. What a treasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Year; My Favorite Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlktrout
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was in Germany when the film came out so didn't see it for the first time until 1984 or so, but I have seen it probably almost every year since then. I should have it memorized by now, but somehow each viewing I find something new and special. I've loved it since the first time I saw it. There is little I can add to the basic story--a washed-up Errol Flynn type of action movie star goes on a live television comedy program in the 1950s. O'Toole is just masterful in the part and according to director Benjamin, he even insisted on doing all his own stunts (some of which were dangerous!). I could believe him as a movie hero and as a real-life washout. Joseph Balogna is just hysterical as the Sid Caesar TV star, rough, bombastic, occasionally mean, but kind under the crust, and utterly fearless. I grinned at every sight of him. Mark Linn-Baker is superb as the kid from Brooklyn who finds himself rubbing shoulders with his childhood hero and discovering the statue has feet of clay. His embarrassment over his background and his weird family rings true and yet are hilarious; I forget the name of the actress who plays his mother, but she is screamingly funny. I just can't say how much I love this movie, how inspiring I find it, how it touches my heart. But it's my favorite movie, and in a house where we own something like 5,000 movies and most of our conversations contain at least one movie quote, this film is quoted almost daily, so that's saying something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely an under-appreciated comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's quite surprising to find out about a movie that no one has ever told you off before but turns out to be a real hidden treasure. "My Favorite Year" is a more than great comedy, that is fun, as well as funny to watch. Key to what makes this a great movie to watch, is that it's being a fun one throughout. It's a fast going, snappy comedy, that doesn't necessarily force or exaggerate its comedy, to any extreme forms. It's playing things more subtly and more often relies on its dialog and actors, rather than on any comical situations. It makes the movie very pleasant and likable, also because it manages to maintain its good quick pace throughout its entire running time. The story really doesn't matter all that much for this movie, other than taking the characters from the one place and situation to the other. I'm not saying that it isn't any good but to me it just wasn't important for what this movie was all about and trying to do. Even the weaker moments in this movie and its story still work out well, thanks to its characters and the actors portraying them. Peter O'Toole plays Errol Flynn, even though his character is named differently in the movie. But he is Flynn and even plays some of the sequences out of some classic Errol Flynn movies. This all was great fun to watch and his presence truly adds a lot to this movie as well. He's perfectly classy and often despicable at the same time. But Mark Linn-Baker was also truly great! Whatever went wrong with his career? He was not only a great comedy actor but simply just a great actor in general as well. The movie has a more old fashioned type of comedy vibe to it, like a '40's production, which is also the time period this movie is being set in (well, the '50's but still), so it's no big surprise or a coincidence all. If you are a fan of these type of snappy and screwball like comedies, from the '40's mostly, changes are you will also absolutely love this movie as well! Anyway, this movie is an extremely fun and recommendable one, for everybody! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dying is easy.......Comedy is hard!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lenie Colacino
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So says Alan Swann and he is so right. Peter O'Toole shows that there is a great actor inside of a great comedic performance. His remarkable portrayal of Swann stands out among all his other performances because Swann, in so many ways, is a thinly veiled O'Toole. His timing, physical grace and delivery rival the all time greats including Chaplin, Laurel, and Gleason. The pacing, casting and plot are expertly woven by director Richard Benjamin to create an inside look at early T. V. production and a crazy Jewish family. The scene of Swan attending dinner in Brooklyn with staff writer Benjy Stone's family is one of the funniest in screen history due in equal parts to the fantastic performances of O'Toole, Lou Jacobi (as a scene-stealing "Uncle Mortie") and Lainie Kazan as the mother of all Jewish mothers. As Swann, O'Toole manages to be loathsome, endearing, infuriating, charming and vulnerable. Kudos to Bill Macy as Benjy's crass boss and Joseph Bologna as the hot-tempered but indomitable King Kaiser. My Favorite Year never disappoints in delivering laughs and perhaps a sentimental tear as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet, funny comedy about 1950s television
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sweet comedy about 50s television (specifically 'Your Show of Shows'), and the week that a fading film great (clearly based on Errol Flynn) guest stars. A simply terrific comic performance by Peter O'Toole as the almost washed up star, close to matched in a supporting role by Joe Bologna as a tough cantankerous Sid Cesar stand in. On the other hand, there's something of the feeling of a TV sitcom to a lot of it, with stagy blocking, and obvious schmaltz. And some of the supporting characters are out of another movie, just a little too cartoony to fit with the broad, but reality based leads. My feelings about the film are also affected by the fact that I remember the script, with it's more bittersweet ending, as having more heart and soul than the final product. None-the-less, this is a charming, well-acted comedy, and deserves it's good reputation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Peter O'Toole is unquestionably the star of "My Favorite Year" in the part of an aging film star, whose major preoccupations are having sex with beautiful young women and getting roaring drunk, he's not the only actor to acquit himself well in this film. Joseph Bologna as King Kaiser, a TV comedian, imitates Sid Caesar with considerable success, Mark Linn-Baker is very good as a junior writer on the show assigned to make sure that Alan Swann (O'Toole's character modeled on Errol Flynn) is actually on hand when the show is broadcast, and Jessica Baker is charming as the young writer's love interest. But O'Toole dominates the comedy just as he dominated his best known dramatic films, and he is hilarious, reminding us that his star, when at its brightest, shown brilliantly not alone because he was physically beautiful but because the guy could really act. His imitation of a drunk is priceless, even though, in fact, O'Toole unfortunately had a good deal of experience to go with his acting talent on this particular matter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "This Is For Ladies Only!" "So Is This, Ma'am, But Every Now And Then I Have To Run A Little Water Through It."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Benjy Stone is the junior writer on the top rated variety/comedy show, in the mid 50s (the early years). Its a new medium and the rules were not fully established. Alan Swann, an Erol Flynn type actor with a drinking problem is to be that weeks guest star. When King Kaiser, the headliner wants to throw Swann off the show, Benjy makes a pitch to save his childhood hero, and is made Swann's babysitter. On top of this, a union boss doesn't care for Kaiser's parody of him and has plans to stop the show. Boy Peter O'Toole Creates One Of The Greatest One Of The Best Comedy Characters Of All Time In This Movie Allan Swann. Peter O'Toole Also Is Funny From Start To Finish. I Am Surprised No-One Has Remade This Movie. It Would Be Better Than Any Comedy Released Since 2006(Besides Superhero Movie(I Do Watch A Lot Of Stupid Comedy's)). Now Let Me See Whats 'My Favourite Year'...For Movies. I Personally Enjoyed The Year 2005 For Movies Not Because It Made My Favourite Movie (It Didn't). But The Quantity Of Good Movies That Year Was Great. I Loved This Movie As A Comedy. Its Gonna Be A Classic To Me. Rating: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peter the Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjnxn-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exuding charm in every frame this is a lovingly made evocation of the early years of live television. Perfectly cast in every role and with a wonderful sense of period this will captivate you from the first scene all the way through to the touching finale. Director Benjamin wisely filled his parts with only one star and the rest talented character actors, anything else would have thrown the balance of the film off. Of those character actors all are terrific but a few stand out. Mark Linn Baker is ideal as Benjy, the schlubby protagonist, Lainie Kazan a scream as his mother and Selma Diamond a no nonsense delight as the wardrobe woman with her ever present cigarette dangling from her lips. Though she doesn't have much of a part keep an eye out for Gloria Stuart in a lovely scene dancing with Peter O'Toole. All of them and the other cast members are wonderful but the film wouldn't mean a thing if the part of Alan Swann wasn't believably cast. Fortunately the film makers were able to get Peter O'Toole, radiating star quality and charisma, and he could not possibly be better. Tender, humorous, dramatic, almost always over the top and also always a bit sad this is without question some of his best work in a career full of great performances. The fact that O'Toole himself at times behaved off camera as the character does in the film only adds to the pleasure of his work. A beautiful jewel of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wacky Load of Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hilarious, an unexpected joy. The laughs keep coming, thanks to an expert cast and a big dose of Jewish humor. No one seems in charge of getting the weekly TV show together for an audience of 20-million. Instead, everyone backstage appears to be rushing around like spinning tops. Even the alleged star King Kaiser (Bologna) can't seem to keep the order of his skits straight. Looks to me like bibulous guest star Alan Swann (O'Toole) should fit right in, drunk or sober. Then there's poor young schlemiel (Linn-Baker) who gets to baby-sit Swann when not pursuing a fruitless romance with the comely K.C. (Harper). Mix in a bunch of mobsters who don't like being made fun of, and you've got a finale to end all finales, even if the mayhem is every TV producer's nightmare. Now I'm really curious whether the old Sid Caesar show was really as wild backstage as the movie presents it. At the time, I was a faithful watcher, so the hijinks here come as a special revelation. But what else could you expect from backstage characters like Caesar's writers Mel Brooks and Woody Allen. Anyhow, this was Dick Benjamin's first directorial outing even though you'd never know it. Then too, credit O'Toole with coming up with a really sly performance that alternates between drunken stupor and charming finesse. I particularly like it when Swann reveals his real self but still shifts gears into the movie swashbuckler when needed. All in all, it's a wacko comedy well deserving its place on Premiere's Top 50 comedies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good-Hearted Story of Dissipation and Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jpark4
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this movie five or six times. &nbsp;I liked it the first time I saw it, and I like it a little more each time I see it. &nbsp;It is a small film in many ways-no blockbuster, but with a big heart. &nbsp;Peter O'Toole is the biggest star in the film, and he does a superb job as the ex-Technicolor swashbuckler who has seen his last days as a leading man, finding solace in booze and casual sex. &nbsp;Mark Linn-Baker plays a young aspiring comedy writer, a great fan of Swann's, who is working as an intern on a comedy show in the early days of television, whose job it is to keep Alan Swann (O'Toole) in line while he prepares for a guest appearance. &nbsp;Helping him in this endeavor is Swann's driver and nursemaid &nbsp;Alfie Bumbacelli (Tony DiBenedetto). &nbsp; Together, they keep hold of Swann's coattails through several booze driven adventures leading up to show night and a hilarious and touching denouement. &nbsp;The story is funny and poignant, with a nice payoff. &nbsp;The characters are all likable, and the acting is uniformly good. &nbsp;It is a story of dissipation and redemption, handled with a nice touch that keeps the lighter side in the fore, but still able to make it's more "sober" points. &nbsp;Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not amazing, but Bravo O'Toole...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    halley-devestern
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've heard people gushing about this movie for years and have always been interested in seeing it. I finally had the chance to see it for the first time today on TCM. I'm sad to say I was quite disappointed overall, but I did enjoy Peter O'Toole's performance immensely. This movie could have been truly amazing if the direction and editing were better. The cast is wonderful (I like Mark Linn-Baker, but a better director would have reined in his youthful over-acting here), the script is good and the story is charming. But the pace is tediously slow. As they say in the industry, you could have driven a truck through the pauses between the lines. Yikes. The movie could still have been tightened up in post-production editing, but no soap. And I'm not a youngster whose attention span has been irrevocably destroyed by the Internet. It's a sad day for me, I had been really looking forward to this movie. But, as always, Bravo O'Toole. What a treasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Year; My Favorite Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlktrout
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was in Germany when the film came out so didn't see it for the first time until 1984 or so, but I have seen it probably almost every year since then. I should have it memorized by now, but somehow each viewing I find something new and special. I've loved it since the first time I saw it. There is little I can add to the basic story--a washed-up Errol Flynn type of action movie star goes on a live television comedy program in the 1950s. O'Toole is just masterful in the part and according to director Benjamin, he even insisted on doing all his own stunts (some of which were dangerous!). I could believe him as a movie hero and as a real-life washout. Joseph Balogna is just hysterical as the Sid Caesar TV star, rough, bombastic, occasionally mean, but kind under the crust, and utterly fearless. I grinned at every sight of him. Mark Linn-Baker is superb as the kid from Brooklyn who finds himself rubbing shoulders with his childhood hero and discovering the statue has feet of clay. His embarrassment over his background and his weird family rings true and yet are hilarious; I forget the name of the actress who plays his mother, but she is screamingly funny. I just can't say how much I love this movie, how inspiring I find it, how it touches my heart. But it's my favorite movie, and in a house where we own something like 5,000 movies and most of our conversations contain at least one movie quote, this film is quoted almost daily, so that's saying something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely an under-appreciated comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's quite surprising to find out about a movie that no one has ever told you off before but turns out to be a real hidden treasure. "My Favorite Year" is a more than great comedy, that is fun, as well as funny to watch. Key to what makes this a great movie to watch, is that it's being a fun one throughout. It's a fast going, snappy comedy, that doesn't necessarily force or exaggerate its comedy, to any extreme forms. It's playing things more subtly and more often relies on its dialog and actors, rather than on any comical situations. It makes the movie very pleasant and likable, also because it manages to maintain its good quick pace throughout its entire running time. The story really doesn't matter all that much for this movie, other than taking the characters from the one place and situation to the other. I'm not saying that it isn't any good but to me it just wasn't important for what this movie was all about and trying to do. Even the weaker moments in this movie and its story still work out well, thanks to its characters and the actors portraying them. Peter O'Toole plays Errol Flynn, even though his character is named differently in the movie. But he is Flynn and even plays some of the sequences out of some classic Errol Flynn movies. This all was great fun to watch and his presence truly adds a lot to this movie as well. He's perfectly classy and often despicable at the same time. But Mark Linn-Baker was also truly great! Whatever went wrong with his career? He was not only a great comedy actor but simply just a great actor in general as well. The movie has a more old fashioned type of comedy vibe to it, like a '40's production, which is also the time period this movie is being set in (well, the '50's but still), so it's no big surprise or a coincidence all. If you are a fan of these type of snappy and screwball like comedies, from the '40's mostly, changes are you will also absolutely love this movie as well! Anyway, this movie is an extremely fun and recommendable one, for everybody! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dying is easy.......Comedy is hard!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lenie Colacino
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So says Alan Swann and he is so right. Peter O'Toole shows that there is a great actor inside of a great comedic performance. His remarkable portrayal of Swann stands out among all his other performances because Swann, in so many ways, is a thinly veiled O'Toole. His timing, physical grace and delivery rival the all time greats including Chaplin, Laurel, and Gleason. The pacing, casting and plot are expertly woven by director Richard Benjamin to create an inside look at early T. V. production and a crazy Jewish family. The scene of Swan attending dinner in Brooklyn with staff writer Benjy Stone's family is one of the funniest in screen history due in equal parts to the fantastic performances of O'Toole, Lou Jacobi (as a scene-stealing "Uncle Mortie") and Lainie Kazan as the mother of all Jewish mothers. As Swann, O'Toole manages to be loathsome, endearing, infuriating, charming and vulnerable. Kudos to Bill Macy as Benjy's crass boss and Joseph Bologna as the hot-tempered but indomitable King Kaiser. My Favorite Year never disappoints in delivering laughs and perhaps a sentimental tear as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet, funny comedy about 1950s television
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sweet comedy about 50s television (specifically 'Your Show of Shows'), and the week that a fading film great (clearly based on Errol Flynn) guest stars. A simply terrific comic performance by Peter O'Toole as the almost washed up star, close to matched in a supporting role by Joe Bologna as a tough cantankerous Sid Cesar stand in. On the other hand, there's something of the feeling of a TV sitcom to a lot of it, with stagy blocking, and obvious schmaltz. And some of the supporting characters are out of another movie, just a little too cartoony to fit with the broad, but reality based leads. My feelings about the film are also affected by the fact that I remember the script, with it's more bittersweet ending, as having more heart and soul than the final product. None-the-less, this is a charming, well-acted comedy, and deserves it's good reputation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Peter O'Toole is unquestionably the star of "My Favorite Year" in the part of an aging film star, whose major preoccupations are having sex with beautiful young women and getting roaring drunk, he's not the only actor to acquit himself well in this film. Joseph Bologna as King Kaiser, a TV comedian, imitates Sid Caesar with considerable success, Mark Linn-Baker is very good as a junior writer on the show assigned to make sure that Alan Swann (O'Toole's character modeled on Errol Flynn) is actually on hand when the show is broadcast, and Jessica Baker is charming as the young writer's love interest. But O'Toole dominates the comedy just as he dominated his best known dramatic films, and he is hilarious, reminding us that his star, when at its brightest, shown brilliantly not alone because he was physically beautiful but because the guy could really act. His imitation of a drunk is priceless, even though, in fact, O'Toole unfortunately had a good deal of experience to go with his acting talent on this particular matter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "This Is For Ladies Only!" "So Is This, Ma'am, But Every Now And Then I Have To Run A Little Water Through It."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Benjy Stone is the junior writer on the top rated variety/comedy show, in the mid 50s (the early years). Its a new medium and the rules were not fully established. Alan Swann, an Erol Flynn type actor with a drinking problem is to be that weeks guest star. When King Kaiser, the headliner wants to throw Swann off the show, Benjy makes a pitch to save his childhood hero, and is made Swann's babysitter. On top of this, a union boss doesn't care for Kaiser's parody of him and has plans to stop the show. Boy Peter O'Toole Creates One Of The Greatest One Of The Best Comedy Characters Of All Time In This Movie Allan Swann. Peter O'Toole Also Is Funny From Start To Finish. I Am Surprised No-One Has Remade This Movie. It Would Be Better Than Any Comedy Released Since 2006(Besides Superhero Movie(I Do Watch A Lot Of Stupid Comedy's)). Now Let Me See Whats 'My Favourite Year'...For Movies. I Personally Enjoyed The Year 2005 For Movies Not Because It Made My Favourite Movie (It Didn't). But The Quantity Of Good Movies That Year Was Great. I Loved This Movie As A Comedy. Its Gonna Be A Classic To Me. Rating: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peter the Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjnxn-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exuding charm in every frame this is a lovingly made evocation of the early years of live television. Perfectly cast in every role and with a wonderful sense of period this will captivate you from the first scene all the way through to the touching finale. Director Benjamin wisely filled his parts with only one star and the rest talented character actors, anything else would have thrown the balance of the film off. Of those character actors all are terrific but a few stand out. Mark Linn Baker is ideal as Benjy, the schlubby protagonist, Lainie Kazan a scream as his mother and Selma Diamond a no nonsense delight as the wardrobe woman with her ever present cigarette dangling from her lips. Though she doesn't have much of a part keep an eye out for Gloria Stuart in a lovely scene dancing with Peter O'Toole. All of them and the other cast members are wonderful but the film wouldn't mean a thing if the part of Alan Swann wasn't believably cast. Fortunately the film makers were able to get Peter O'Toole, radiating star quality and charisma, and he could not possibly be better. Tender, humorous, dramatic, almost always over the top and also always a bit sad this is without question some of his best work in a career full of great performances. The fact that O'Toole himself at times behaved off camera as the character does in the film only adds to the pleasure of his work. A beautiful jewel of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wacky Load of Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hilarious, an unexpected joy. The laughs keep coming, thanks to an expert cast and a big dose of Jewish humor. No one seems in charge of getting the weekly TV show together for an audience of 20-million. Instead, everyone backstage appears to be rushing around like spinning tops. Even the alleged star King Kaiser (Bologna) can't seem to keep the order of his skits straight. Looks to me like bibulous guest star Alan Swann (O'Toole) should fit right in, drunk or sober. Then there's poor young schlemiel (Linn-Baker) who gets to baby-sit Swann when not pursuing a fruitless romance with the comely K.C. (Harper). Mix in a bunch of mobsters who don't like being made fun of, and you've got a finale to end all finales, even if the mayhem is every TV producer's nightmare. Now I'm really curious whether the old Sid Caesar show was really as wild backstage as the movie presents it. At the time, I was a faithful watcher, so the hijinks here come as a special revelation. But what else could you expect from backstage characters like Caesar's writers Mel Brooks and Woody Allen. Anyhow, this was Dick Benjamin's first directorial outing even though you'd never know it. Then too, credit O'Toole with coming up with a really sly performance that alternates between drunken stupor and charming finesse. I particularly like it when Swann reveals his real self but still shifts gears into the movie swashbuckler when needed. All in all, it's a wacko comedy well deserving its place on Premiere's Top 50 comedies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good-Hearted Story of Dissipation and Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jpark4
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this movie five or six times. &nbsp;I liked it the first time I saw it, and I like it a little more each time I see it. &nbsp;It is a small film in many ways-no blockbuster, but with a big heart. &nbsp;Peter O'Toole is the biggest star in the film, and he does a superb job as the ex-Technicolor swashbuckler who has seen his last days as a leading man, finding solace in booze and casual sex. &nbsp;Mark Linn-Baker plays a young aspiring comedy writer, a great fan of Swann's, who is working as an intern on a comedy show in the early days of television, whose job it is to keep Alan Swann (O'Toole) in line while he prepares for a guest appearance. &nbsp;Helping him in this endeavor is Swann's driver and nursemaid &nbsp;Alfie Bumbacelli (Tony DiBenedetto). &nbsp; Together, they keep hold of Swann's coattails through several booze driven adventures leading up to show night and a hilarious and touching denouement. &nbsp;The story is funny and poignant, with a nice payoff. &nbsp;The characters are all likable, and the acting is uniformly good. &nbsp;It is a story of dissipation and redemption, handled with a nice touch that keeps the lighter side in the fore, but still able to make it's more "sober" points. &nbsp;Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not amazing, but Bravo O'Toole...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    halley-devestern
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've heard people gushing about this movie for years and have always been interested in seeing it. I finally had the chance to see it for the first time today on TCM. I'm sad to say I was quite disappointed overall, but I did enjoy Peter O'Toole's performance immensely. This movie could have been truly amazing if the direction and editing were better. The cast is wonderful (I like Mark Linn-Baker, but a better director would have reined in his youthful over-acting here), the script is good and the story is charming. But the pace is tediously slow. As they say in the industry, you could have driven a truck through the pauses between the lines. Yikes. The movie could still have been tightened up in post-production editing, but no soap. And I'm not a youngster whose attention span has been irrevocably destroyed by the Internet. It's a sad day for me, I had been really looking forward to this movie. But, as always, Bravo O'Toole. What a treasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Year; My Favorite Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlktrout
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was in Germany when the film came out so didn't see it for the first time until 1984 or so, but I have seen it probably almost every year since then. I should have it memorized by now, but somehow each viewing I find something new and special. I've loved it since the first time I saw it. There is little I can add to the basic story--a washed-up Errol Flynn type of action movie star goes on a live television comedy program in the 1950s. O'Toole is just masterful in the part and according to director Benjamin, he even insisted on doing all his own stunts (some of which were dangerous!). I could believe him as a movie hero and as a real-life washout. Joseph Balogna is just hysterical as the Sid Caesar TV star, rough, bombastic, occasionally mean, but kind under the crust, and utterly fearless. I grinned at every sight of him. Mark Linn-Baker is superb as the kid from Brooklyn who finds himself rubbing shoulders with his childhood hero and discovering the statue has feet of clay. His embarrassment over his background and his weird family rings true and yet are hilarious; I forget the name of the actress who plays his mother, but she is screamingly funny. I just can't say how much I love this movie, how inspiring I find it, how it touches my heart. But it's my favorite movie, and in a house where we own something like 5,000 movies and most of our conversations contain at least one movie quote, this film is quoted almost daily, so that's saying something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely an under-appreciated comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's quite surprising to find out about a movie that no one has ever told you off before but turns out to be a real hidden treasure. "My Favorite Year" is a more than great comedy, that is fun, as well as funny to watch. Key to what makes this a great movie to watch, is that it's being a fun one throughout. It's a fast going, snappy comedy, that doesn't necessarily force or exaggerate its comedy, to any extreme forms. It's playing things more subtly and more often relies on its dialog and actors, rather than on any comical situations. It makes the movie very pleasant and likable, also because it manages to maintain its good quick pace throughout its entire running time. The story really doesn't matter all that much for this movie, other than taking the characters from the one place and situation to the other. I'm not saying that it isn't any good but to me it just wasn't important for what this movie was all about and trying to do. Even the weaker moments in this movie and its story still work out well, thanks to its characters and the actors portraying them. Peter O'Toole plays Errol Flynn, even though his character is named differently in the movie. But he is Flynn and even plays some of the sequences out of some classic Errol Flynn movies. This all was great fun to watch and his presence truly adds a lot to this movie as well. He's perfectly classy and often despicable at the same time. But Mark Linn-Baker was also truly great! Whatever went wrong with his career? He was not only a great comedy actor but simply just a great actor in general as well. The movie has a more old fashioned type of comedy vibe to it, like a '40's production, which is also the time period this movie is being set in (well, the '50's but still), so it's no big surprise or a coincidence all. If you are a fan of these type of snappy and screwball like comedies, from the '40's mostly, changes are you will also absolutely love this movie as well! Anyway, this movie is an extremely fun and recommendable one, for everybody! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dying is easy.......Comedy is hard!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lenie Colacino
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So says Alan Swann and he is so right. Peter O'Toole shows that there is a great actor inside of a great comedic performance. His remarkable portrayal of Swann stands out among all his other performances because Swann, in so many ways, is a thinly veiled O'Toole. His timing, physical grace and delivery rival the all time greats including Chaplin, Laurel, and Gleason. The pacing, casting and plot are expertly woven by director Richard Benjamin to create an inside look at early T. V. production and a crazy Jewish family. The scene of Swan attending dinner in Brooklyn with staff writer Benjy Stone's family is one of the funniest in screen history due in equal parts to the fantastic performances of O'Toole, Lou Jacobi (as a scene-stealing "Uncle Mortie") and Lainie Kazan as the mother of all Jewish mothers. As Swann, O'Toole manages to be loathsome, endearing, infuriating, charming and vulnerable. Kudos to Bill Macy as Benjy's crass boss and Joseph Bologna as the hot-tempered but indomitable King Kaiser. My Favorite Year never disappoints in delivering laughs and perhaps a sentimental tear as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet, funny comedy about 1950s television
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sweet comedy about 50s television (specifically 'Your Show of Shows'), and the week that a fading film great (clearly based on Errol Flynn) guest stars. A simply terrific comic performance by Peter O'Toole as the almost washed up star, close to matched in a supporting role by Joe Bologna as a tough cantankerous Sid Cesar stand in. On the other hand, there's something of the feeling of a TV sitcom to a lot of it, with stagy blocking, and obvious schmaltz. And some of the supporting characters are out of another movie, just a little too cartoony to fit with the broad, but reality based leads. My feelings about the film are also affected by the fact that I remember the script, with it's more bittersweet ending, as having more heart and soul than the final product. None-the-less, this is a charming, well-acted comedy, and deserves it's good reputation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Peter O'Toole is unquestionably the star of "My Favorite Year" in the part of an aging film star, whose major preoccupations are having sex with beautiful young women and getting roaring drunk, he's not the only actor to acquit himself well in this film. Joseph Bologna as King Kaiser, a TV comedian, imitates Sid Caesar with considerable success, Mark Linn-Baker is very good as a junior writer on the show assigned to make sure that Alan Swann (O'Toole's character modeled on Errol Flynn) is actually on hand when the show is broadcast, and Jessica Baker is charming as the young writer's love interest. But O'Toole dominates the comedy just as he dominated his best known dramatic films, and he is hilarious, reminding us that his star, when at its brightest, shown brilliantly not alone because he was physically beautiful but because the guy could really act. His imitation of a drunk is priceless, even though, in fact, O'Toole unfortunately had a good deal of experience to go with his acting talent on this particular matter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "This Is For Ladies Only!" "So Is This, Ma'am, But Every Now And Then I Have To Run A Little Water Through It."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Benjy Stone is the junior writer on the top rated variety/comedy show, in the mid 50s (the early years). Its a new medium and the rules were not fully established. Alan Swann, an Erol Flynn type actor with a drinking problem is to be that weeks guest star. When King Kaiser, the headliner wants to throw Swann off the show, Benjy makes a pitch to save his childhood hero, and is made Swann's babysitter. On top of this, a union boss doesn't care for Kaiser's parody of him and has plans to stop the show. Boy Peter O'Toole Creates One Of The Greatest One Of The Best Comedy Characters Of All Time In This Movie Allan Swann. Peter O'Toole Also Is Funny From Start To Finish. I Am Surprised No-One Has Remade This Movie. It Would Be Better Than Any Comedy Released Since 2006(Besides Superhero Movie(I Do Watch A Lot Of Stupid Comedy's)). Now Let Me See Whats 'My Favourite Year'...For Movies. I Personally Enjoyed The Year 2005 For Movies Not Because It Made My Favourite Movie (It Didn't). But The Quantity Of Good Movies That Year Was Great. I Loved This Movie As A Comedy. Its Gonna Be A Classic To Me. Rating: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peter the Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjnxn-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exuding charm in every frame this is a lovingly made evocation of the early years of live television. Perfectly cast in every role and with a wonderful sense of period this will captivate you from the first scene all the way through to the touching finale. Director Benjamin wisely filled his parts with only one star and the rest talented character actors, anything else would have thrown the balance of the film off. Of those character actors all are terrific but a few stand out. Mark Linn Baker is ideal as Benjy, the schlubby protagonist, Lainie Kazan a scream as his mother and Selma Diamond a no nonsense delight as the wardrobe woman with her ever present cigarette dangling from her lips. Though she doesn't have much of a part keep an eye out for Gloria Stuart in a lovely scene dancing with Peter O'Toole. All of them and the other cast members are wonderful but the film wouldn't mean a thing if the part of Alan Swann wasn't believably cast. Fortunately the film makers were able to get Peter O'Toole, radiating star quality and charisma, and he could not possibly be better. Tender, humorous, dramatic, almost always over the top and also always a bit sad this is without question some of his best work in a career full of great performances. The fact that O'Toole himself at times behaved off camera as the character does in the film only adds to the pleasure of his work. A beautiful jewel of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wacky Load of Laughs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hilarious, an unexpected joy. The laughs keep coming, thanks to an expert cast and a big dose of Jewish humor. No one seems in charge of getting the weekly TV show together for an audience of 20-million. Instead, everyone backstage appears to be rushing around like spinning tops. Even the alleged star King Kaiser (Bologna) can't seem to keep the order of his skits straight. Looks to me like bibulous guest star Alan Swann (O'Toole) should fit right in, drunk or sober. Then there's poor young schlemiel (Linn-Baker) who gets to baby-sit Swann when not pursuing a fruitless romance with the comely K.C. (Harper). Mix in a bunch of mobsters who don't like being made fun of, and you've got a finale to end all finales, even if the mayhem is every TV producer's nightmare. Now I'm really curious whether the old Sid Caesar show was really as wild backstage as the movie presents it. At the time, I was a faithful watcher, so the hijinks here come as a special revelation. But what else could you expect from backstage characters like Caesar's writers Mel Brooks and Woody Allen. Anyhow, this was Dick Benjamin's first directorial outing even though you'd never know it. Then too, credit O'Toole with coming up with a really sly performance that alternates between drunken stupor and charming finesse. I particularly like it when Swann reveals his real self but still shifts gears into the movie swashbuckler when needed. All in all, it's a wacko comedy well deserving its place on Premiere's Top 50 comedies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good-Hearted Story of Dissipation and Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jpark4
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this movie five or six times. &nbsp;I liked it the first time I saw it, and I like it a little more each time I see it. &nbsp;It is a small film in many ways-no blockbuster, but with a big heart. &nbsp;Peter O'Toole is the biggest star in the film, and he does a superb job as the ex-Technicolor swashbuckler who has seen his last days as a leading man, finding solace in booze and casual sex. &nbsp;Mark Linn-Baker plays a young aspiring comedy writer, a great fan of Swann's, who is working as an intern on a comedy show in the early days of television, whose job it is to keep Alan Swann (O'Toole) in line while he prepares for a guest appearance. &nbsp;Helping him in this endeavor is Swann's driver and nursemaid &nbsp;Alfie Bumbacelli (Tony DiBenedetto). &nbsp; Together, they keep hold of Swann's coattails through several booze driven adventures leading up to show night and a hilarious and touching denouement. &nbsp;The story is funny and poignant, with a nice payoff. &nbsp;The characters are all likable, and the acting is uniformly good. &nbsp;It is a story of dissipation and redemption, handled with a nice touch that keeps the lighter side in the fore, but still able to make it's more "sober" points. &nbsp;Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not amazing, but Bravo O'Toole...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    halley-devestern
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've heard people gushing about this movie for years and have always been interested in seeing it. I finally had the chance to see it for the first time today on TCM. I'm sad to say I was quite disappointed overall, but I did enjoy Peter O'Toole's performance immensely. This movie could have been truly amazing if the direction and editing were better. The cast is wonderful (I like Mark Linn-Baker, but a better director would have reined in his youthful over-acting here), the script is good and the story is charming. But the pace is tediously slow. As they say in the industry, you could have driven a truck through the pauses between the lines. Yikes. The movie could still have been tightened up in post-production editing, but no soap. And I'm not a youngster whose attention span has been irrevocably destroyed by the Internet. It's a sad day for me, I had been really looking forward to this movie. But, as always, Bravo O'Toole. What a treasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Year; My Favorite Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlktrout
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was in Germany when the film came out so didn't see it for the first time until 1984 or so, but I have seen it probably almost every year since then. I should have it memorized by now, but somehow each viewing I find something new and special. I've loved it since the first time I saw it. There is little I can add to the basic story--a washed-up Errol Flynn type of action movie star goes on a live television comedy program in the 1950s. O'Toole is just masterful in the part and according to director Benjamin, he even insisted on doing all his own stunts (some of which were dangerous!). I could believe him as a movie hero and as a real-life washout. Joseph Balogna is just hysterical as the Sid Caesar TV star, rough, bombastic, occasionally mean, but kind under the crust, and utterly fearless. I grinned at every sight of him. Mark Linn-Baker is superb as the kid from Brooklyn who finds himself rubbing shoulders with his childhood hero and discovering the statue has feet of clay. His embarrassment over his background and his weird family rings true and yet are hilarious; I forget the name of the actress who plays his mother, but she is screamingly funny. I just can't say how much I love this movie, how inspiring I find it, how it touches my heart. But it's my favorite movie, and in a house where we own something like 5,000 movies and most of our conversations contain at least one movie quote, this film is quoted almost daily, so that's saying something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely an under-appreciated comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's quite surprising to find out about a movie that no one has ever told you off before but turns out to be a real hidden treasure. "My Favorite Year" is a more than great comedy, that is fun, as well as funny to watch. Key to what makes this a great movie to watch, is that it's being a fun one throughout. It's a fast going, snappy comedy, that doesn't necessarily force or exaggerate its comedy, to any extreme forms. It's playing things more subtly and more often relies on its dialog and actors, rather than on any comical situations. It makes the movie very pleasant and likable, also because it manages to maintain its good quick pace throughout its entire running time. The story really doesn't matter all that much for this movie, other than taking the characters from the one place and situation to the other. I'm not saying that it isn't any good but to me it just wasn't important for what this movie was all about and trying to do. Even the weaker moments in this movie and its story still work out well, thanks to its characters and the actors portraying them. Peter O'Toole plays Errol Flynn, even though his character is named differently in the movie. But he is Flynn and even plays some of the sequences out of some classic Errol Flynn movies. This all was great fun to watch and his presence truly adds a lot to this movie as well. He's perfectly classy and often despicable at the same time. But Mark Linn-Baker was also truly great! Whatever went wrong with his career? He was not only a great comedy actor but simply just a great actor in general as well. The movie has a more old fashioned type of comedy vibe to it, like a '40's production, which is also the time period this movie is being set in (well, the '50's but still), so it's no big surprise or a coincidence all. If you are a fan of these type of snappy and screwball like comedies, from the '40's mostly, changes are you will also absolutely love this movie as well! Anyway, this movie is an extremely fun and recommendable one, for everybody! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dying is easy.......Comedy is hard!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lenie Colacino
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So says Alan Swann and he is so right. Peter O'Toole shows that there is a great actor inside of a great comedic performance. His remarkable portrayal of Swann stands out among all his other performances because Swann, in so many ways, is a thinly veiled O'Toole. His timing, physical grace and delivery rival the all time greats including Chaplin, Laurel, and Gleason. The pacing, casting and plot are expertly woven by director Richard Benjamin to create an inside look at early T. V. production and a crazy Jewish family. The scene of Swan attending dinner in Brooklyn with staff writer Benjy Stone's family is one of the funniest in screen history due in equal parts to the fantastic performances of O'Toole, Lou Jacobi (as a scene-stealing "Uncle Mortie") and Lainie Kazan as the mother of all Jewish mothers. As Swann, O'Toole manages to be loathsome, endearing, infuriating, charming and vulnerable. Kudos to Bill Macy as Benjy's crass boss and Joseph Bologna as the hot-tempered but indomitable King Kaiser. My Favorite Year never disappoints in delivering laughs and perhaps a sentimental tear as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet, funny comedy about 1950s television
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sweet comedy about 50s television (specifically 'Your Show of Shows'), and the week that a fading film great (clearly based on Errol Flynn) guest stars. A simply terrific comic performance by Peter O'Toole as the almost washed up star, close to matched in a supporting role by Joe Bologna as a tough cantankerous Sid Cesar stand in. On the other hand, there's something of the feeling of a TV sitcom to a lot of it, with stagy blocking, and obvious schmaltz. And some of the supporting characters are out of another movie, just a little too cartoony to fit with the broad, but reality based leads. My feelings about the film are also affected by the fact that I remember the script, with it's more bittersweet ending, as having more heart and soul than the final product. None-the-less, this is a charming, well-acted comedy, and deserves it's good reputation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (normangelman@verizon.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Peter O'Toole is unquestionably the star of "My Favorite Year" in the part of an aging film star, whose major preoccupations are having sex with beautiful young women and getting roaring drunk, he's not the only actor to acquit himself well in this film. Joseph Bologna as King Kaiser, a TV comedian, imitates Sid Caesar with considerable success, Mark Linn-Baker is very good as a junior writer on the show assigned to make sure that Alan Swann (O'Toole's character modeled on Errol Flynn) is actually on hand when the show is broadcast, and Jessica Baker is charming as the young writer's love interest. But O'Toole dominates the comedy just as he dominated his best known dramatic films, and he is hilarious, reminding us that his star, when at its brightest, shown brilliantly not alone because he was physically beautiful but because the guy could really act. His imitation of a drunk is priceless, even though, in fact, O'Toole unfortunately had a good deal of experience to go with his acting talent on this particular matter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "This Is For Ladies Only!" "So Is This, Ma'am, But Every Now And Then I Have To Run A Little Water Through It."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Benjy Stone is the junior writer on the top rated variety/comedy show, in the mid 50s (the early years). Its a new medium and the rules were not fully established. Alan Swann, an Erol Flynn type actor with a drinking problem is to be that weeks guest star. When King Kaiser, the headliner wants to throw Swann off the show, Benjy makes a pitch to save his childhood hero, and is made Swann's babysitter. On top of this, a union boss doesn't care for Kaiser's parody of him and has plans to stop the show. Boy Peter O'Toole Creates One Of The Greatest One Of The Best Comedy Characters Of All Time In This Movie Allan Swann. Peter O'Toole Also Is Funny From Start To Finish. I Am Surprised No-One Has Remade This Movie. It Would Be Better Than Any Comedy Released Since 2006(Besides Superhero Movie(I Do Watch A Lot Of Stupid Comedy's)). Now Let Me See Whats 'My Favourite Year'...For Movies. I Personally Enjoyed The Year 2005 For Movies Not Because It Made My Favourite Movie (It Didn't). But The Quantity Of Good Movies That Year Was Great. I Loved This Movie As A Comedy. Its Gonna Be A Classic To Me. Rating: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
