<filme>
 <id>
  418
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0042332
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1950
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Cinderela
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  When Cinderella's cruel stepmother prevents her from attending the Royal Ball, she gets some unexpected help from the lovable mice Gus and Jaq, and from her Fairy Godmother.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In a far away, long ago kingdom, Cinderella is living happily with her mother and father until her mother dies. Cinderella's father remarries a cold, cruel woman who has two daughters, Drizella and Anastasia. When the father dies, Cinderella's wicked stepmother turns her into a virtual servant in her own house. Meanwhile, across town in the castle, the King determines that his son the Prince should find a suitable bride and provide him with a required number of grandchildren. So the King invites every eligible maiden in the kingdom to a fancy dress ball, where his son will be able to choose his bride. Cinderella has no suitable party dress for a ball, but her friends the mice, led by Jaques and Gus, and the birds lend a hand in making her one, a dress the evil stepsisters immediately tear apart on the evening of the ball. At this point, enter the Fairy Godmother, the pumpkin carriage, the royal ball, the stroke of midnight, the glass slipper, and the rest, as they say, is fairy tale ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Animation
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   ball
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cinderella
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fairy godmother
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fairy tale
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   prince
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Clyde Geronimi
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Wilfred Jackson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Bill Peet
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Erdman Penner
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ilene Woods
  </ator>
  <ator>
   James MacDonald
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Eleanor Audley
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The thing-a-ma-bob that does the job is bibidi bobidi boo"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not the best of Walt Disney's feature length animated films, but any film that has Bibidi Bobbidi Boo and A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes has to rate as good in anyone's standards. I saw this for the first time as a small child on Walt Disney's Disneyland hour and it was as effective on the big screen as well as the small. I don't think there's anyone who is literate in the western world who does not know the story of Cinderella. The story is intact and kept in the mythical medieval times it was written for. As a subplot to the main story we have the story of Cinderella and her relationship with the animals around the house. The pecking order is dog, cat, mice with a horse thrown in for good measure. Naturally the evil stepmother who is voiced by Eleanor Audley has the cat as her favorite. What does that say about us cat lovers. Ilene Woods voices and sings A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes which Perry Como made a big hit record of. Bibidi Bobidi Boo is sung by Verna Felton who voices the Fairy Godmother. She's unforgettable in this role although she's better known as Hilda Crocker, Spring Byington's Ethel Mertz on December Bride. This is one eternal film that I hope my niece let's my new grandnephew check out and his sister or brother to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still a gem and my favourite as a child, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ipacitti
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney's classic Cinderella: My favourite as a child, I would watch it all the time and when I look back. I can't think why.. The animation, the story, the characters, the songs...it's all magical and captivating but when I watched it again not long ago, I was questioning why I thought all of that when I was younger. Disney was still developing and getting into good stories and movie making at the time, it was 1950, so what do you expect from a Disney film at that time period? Snow White was bad so this sort of saved it, it was better and more believable so I guess that's why. But I think Disney didn't suck in all ages to a good DECENT Disney Movie until the 1970's onwards. Sleeping Beauty was 1960 so it wasn't THAT good either. Do you get my gist? The oldest movies were the most boring and less effective, to me, anyway. My goal isn't to discourage anyone from hating this movie because it is in fact a timeless classic, just not as much when you're a hormonal teenager. It's better suited for kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Childhood Classic of My Children and Mine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a small kingdom, the happily child Cinderella loses her beloved mother and his father marries with the cruel Lady Tremaine, who has the mean daughters Drizella and Anastasia. When her father dies, Cinderella becomes a servant in her own house and her stepmother and sisters feels only hatred for her. Cinderella's only friends are four mice, a dog and a horse that live in the house. When the King decides that his son, the Prince, should get married, he invites every maiden in his kingdom to a ball in order that the Prince could choose his bride. However, Cinderella's cruel stepmother does not allow her to attend the ball. When Cinderella is hopeless of going to the Royal Ball, her Fairy Godmother appears and uses magic to help her to make her dream come true. But she must leave the ball before midnight since the magic effect will end. "Cinderella" is one of the classics produced by Disney that belongs not only to my childhood, but also to my daughter and my son's childhoods. This adorable fairytale is wonderful and should be mandatory to every child in the world. I do not have much to say, since I believe that most of the readers certainly know the story of "Cinderella". I feel sorry for those that have written stupid things about this lovely fantasy  what a poor childhood they had. My vote is ten. Title (Brazil): "Cinderela" ("Cinderella")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true Disney classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been so many versions of the Cinderella story that you may be surprised to find that some of the elements that you think are a part of the story are missing. Gone are Buttons and Barron Hardup figures that we see in Pantomime and instead we have a selection of cute animals (this is Disney after all) that will either warm your heart or annoy you badly. Cinderella herself is a typical Disney princess but the film moves along at a quick pace after quite a slow first 20 minutes. For it's age it looks stunning and the humour does not date. Although it probably appeal more to girls than boys there is a lot of fun for them to enjoy in the film as well what with the bumbling king and his servant. Overall a classic Disney film that is well worth seeing to bring back some childhood memories.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinderella" isn't Disney's best, but I think many people will be able to identify with the main character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Walt Disney's 12th full-length animated feature Cinderella (1950) was one of the first movies that I ever saw as a child along with Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937) and Mary Poppins (1964). If there's something we all know from our childhoods, it's that the first few movies we see (especially if they're Disney movies like this) are going to remain in our memories for quite some time. It was a great film to watch as a child, and for the most part, I still liked the film looking back at it as an adult. Unfortunately, due to some serious story flaws, Cinderella doesn't stand the test of time as well as either Snow White or Mary Poppins do. You know the story to this one. A young woman named Cinderella is forced to work as a maid to her evil stepmother and two stepsisters after her father passed away. Despite the terrible treatment she gets all around from them, Cinderella still remains kind and gentle. Furthermore, she at least has a few animal friends in the form of mice, birds, and other animals in the farm nearby. One day, the kingdom announces that the prince has returned and a ball will be held to celebrate this occasion. Every single person is to attend meaning Cinderella is eligible to go. However, her stepmother does not let her go and gives her more chores to do. That's when her fairy godmother comes in and.well, I think it's safe to say that you know the rest, so I won't spoil the rest for whoever hasn't seen it yet. So what issues do I have with Cinderella looking back at it as a young adult? Well, let's discuss the biggest issue I have with the entire film. The film makes the serious mistake of placing at least half the focus of the movie on the side characters rather than on the main characters Cinderella and Prince Charming. I'm particularly disdainful of the fact that more than a quarter of the film is focused on the adventures with the mice and the cat and yet we only see Prince Charming for around 2-3 minutes. Now why did the storytellers of this film feel like this was the right direction to go? They even spend more time on the King and the Grand Duke more than they do with Prince Charming to the point where it should be the King who should be married and not the prince. I realize that it was hard to draw realistic human characters when Snow White was being made and I think the animators did a great job on animating the human halves of the fawns in Fantasia. So there's absolutely no excuse for Disney's storytellers to drop the ball like that on the prince character and deprive him of having any personality, no excuse for that whatsoever. In addition to the prince not having enough screen time or any personality, the mice have way more screen time than they should be having and there's only so much of their over cutesiness that I can take. While these mice characters are at least useful to the main plot some of the time, a film that is titled Cinderella is supposed to be mainly focused on Cinderella, not over 25% focused on a Tom and Jerry like subplot. The high-pitched voices on these mice don't help either. In fact, they make the problem even worse in my opinion. I should probably start analyzing the positive aspects of Cinderella now. Even despite the criticisms that the main character Cinderella gets for not being an assertive enough character, I have to be honest and say that I still liked her enough character wise. I particularly admired how after all the misery she has been put under from her step family, she still maintains her kindness and positivity almost all the time. If that wasn't enough, she also tries to spread that positivity to everybody and every creature around her, so that they can all get along. So for that aspect alone, I think she's a good role model for young girls to look up to. Of course, I thought the stepmother was a well written Disney villain. Who wouldn't think so? She doesn't need any evil laughter to become more intimidating for our main character. The fact that she simply keeps forcing her do more chores and not even give her any credit whatsoever is enough for me. Even though it's a little unusual that more time is spent with the King and the Grand Duke than on the Prince, I still think that they're enjoyable comic relief and they do keep the plot in motion as characters of this nature should be doing. The soundtrack by Oliver Wallace has a couple memorable tunes that I'm sure most of us are familiar with such as "Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo", "Sing Sweet Nightingale", "So This is Love", and "A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes". Though it isn't as richly detailed as the earliest Disney pictures are, the animation here is nice and colorful in its own right. Overall, I think that Cinderella is alright. If this film didn't make the serious storytelling errors that it did and if it focused more on the central characters, then I think Cinderella would be a more timeless Disney picture as a result. But for what it is for the time being, it's still a nice picture with a positive, harmless message for children about the importance of kindness and hard work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classical and A Soft Re-Telling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KatherinePetersdorf
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did enjoy this movie when I was a child. It was great at such a young idea to believe in love at first sight. I also enjoyed the ideal that a girl who was worthless and nothing could become someone amazing and marry the perfect man. I didn't enjoy her singing voice, though. I thought the vocal actress for singing was too high, my ears are sensitive and high soprano doesn't float my boat. I kind of enjoyed the second Cinderella more, it was probably because I was overwhelmed by the original story. When I was young I read the Grimms version, with the cut off of parts of the step sister's feet to wear the shoes, and all the other gore, but Disney did a good job of making it nice. I preferred Dark though :P
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that great... feels like tom and jerry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jumpelaj
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really wanted to like this movie but it is not romantic or classic. It adds nothing to the basic story of Cinderella that we have always heard. The scenes are very pretty and the animation is very good but the most part of the film focuses on the mouse-friends of Cinderella and the mean cat belonging to the step mother. It feels like tom and jerry and by the end of the film you are too tired of watching the animal characters. As another reviewer has mentioned there is no background given of Cinderella or any insight into who she is or what she is all about and no screen time what so ever to the prince himself. It starts well and then gets very very bland. The fairy Godmother is very lovable and so is the King but there is nothing that Cinderella herself brings to the movie. I would recommend watching Enchanted instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another childhood classic from Disney
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Along with 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' 'Cinderella' was one of my favourite Disney films as a child. This film was engaging for the most part, but I feel that the announcement of the ball took longer than it should have done due to a somewhat overlong segment of Cinderella doing her duties and a couple of the scenes involving the king and the duke were slightly irrelevant to the film's main plot. The mice were hard to understand when I heard them speak for the first time in this film for several years but they were cute, funny and active supporting characters nonetheless. Also the film's location setting (probably a toss-up between France and the Netherlands) and time period are hard to determine. The ending was rushed yet memorable with some twists and turns leading up to it. The best aspects of this film were the prologue that consists of a moving back-story of Cinderella and her step-family; beautiful illustrations; very young versions of Cinderella and her stepsisters and simple animation, which got better as the film progressed; the memorable songs (In particular the opening song, 'A Dream is a Wish,' 'Sing Sweet Nightingale,' the brief song sung by the mice before they made Cinderella's dress, 'Bibbidy Bobbidy Boo' and the song that plays when Cinderella dances with the prince); the bubble sequence during 'Sing Sweet Nightingale;' the dressmaking scene and the Fairy Godmother scene. In conclusion, this film isn't quite as enjoyable as 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' but it was worth another look after several years. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1st out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After spending most of the 1940s with package films, Disney was on turmoil with this last film and if it was successful, they would make more movies but if they were not, they would close the studio, and this film was a big hit in 1950. The story is about a young woman named Cinderella who has become a servant in her own home by her own stepmother. When the royal family throws a ball for Prince Charming's return, Cinderella sneaks out of her house to go to the ball, and unknowingly bumps into Prince Charming. The plot is not the most complicated, as it is practically the same as the fairy tale, but they perform it so well. The characters are also very interesting, except Prince Charming. Cinderella is a nice, genuine, spunky (for the classic princesses), level eased girl. Lady Tremaine is a crude, selfish, manipulative villain, who has so much impact in everything she is doing; great villain. The stepsisters are Lady Tremaine's pawns, but their foolish, bratty behaviour is hilarious. The King is extremely cold and enjoyable at the same time, but he does not come off as extremely threatening. Prince Charming is barely in the movie, and faces the same problems that Snow's Prince had (they could not animate a realistic male character yet). The mice are cute, fun characters that provide our comic relief. The songs, everybody remembers them, from "A Dream is a Wish Your Heart Makes", "Bibbidi Bobbidi Bo", "So This Is Love", etc. they are so soothing, and not overly energetic and fast. Disney's most memorable songs are in this movie. The animation is top notch. It is so stylistic, and the backgrounds are so beautiful. Cinderella's design, as all the other characters (excluding Prince Charming) are designed really well, and Disney really got the character movements down. This is one of the best animated movies they have ever done. Everything flows well with this movie, and the only thing that I wish would have been better is if they took away some of the scenes with the mice, so we could have seen more of what the royals were thinking, but this movie is practically flawless. This film is perfect for the entire family. Little girls will like the dresses and mice, boys will love the slapstick humour, and the adults will enjoy the animation, story, and the undertones of the movies. You should definitely give this movie a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a charming and beautifully made animated film. "Cinderella" is everything that an animated fairy-tale should be. It was delightful and highly enjoyable from beginning to end, showing in every single scene form this movie a "magic" that most of the animated films from the recent years lack, with wonderful designs and a exquisite level of detail in every frame. Personally, I consider this movie to be the best adaptation of the classic fairy tale written by Charles Perrault. Movies like "Cinderella" shows why the time when this was made was considered "The Golden Age of Animation".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The thing-a-ma-bob that does the job is bibidi bobidi boo"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not the best of Walt Disney's feature length animated films, but any film that has Bibidi Bobbidi Boo and A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes has to rate as good in anyone's standards. I saw this for the first time as a small child on Walt Disney's Disneyland hour and it was as effective on the big screen as well as the small. I don't think there's anyone who is literate in the western world who does not know the story of Cinderella. The story is intact and kept in the mythical medieval times it was written for. As a subplot to the main story we have the story of Cinderella and her relationship with the animals around the house. The pecking order is dog, cat, mice with a horse thrown in for good measure. Naturally the evil stepmother who is voiced by Eleanor Audley has the cat as her favorite. What does that say about us cat lovers. Ilene Woods voices and sings A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes which Perry Como made a big hit record of. Bibidi Bobidi Boo is sung by Verna Felton who voices the Fairy Godmother. She's unforgettable in this role although she's better known as Hilda Crocker, Spring Byington's Ethel Mertz on December Bride. This is one eternal film that I hope my niece let's my new grandnephew check out and his sister or brother to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still a gem and my favourite as a child, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ipacitti
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney's classic Cinderella: My favourite as a child, I would watch it all the time and when I look back. I can't think why.. The animation, the story, the characters, the songs...it's all magical and captivating but when I watched it again not long ago, I was questioning why I thought all of that when I was younger. Disney was still developing and getting into good stories and movie making at the time, it was 1950, so what do you expect from a Disney film at that time period? Snow White was bad so this sort of saved it, it was better and more believable so I guess that's why. But I think Disney didn't suck in all ages to a good DECENT Disney Movie until the 1970's onwards. Sleeping Beauty was 1960 so it wasn't THAT good either. Do you get my gist? The oldest movies were the most boring and less effective, to me, anyway. My goal isn't to discourage anyone from hating this movie because it is in fact a timeless classic, just not as much when you're a hormonal teenager. It's better suited for kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Childhood Classic of My Children and Mine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a small kingdom, the happily child Cinderella loses her beloved mother and his father marries with the cruel Lady Tremaine, who has the mean daughters Drizella and Anastasia. When her father dies, Cinderella becomes a servant in her own house and her stepmother and sisters feels only hatred for her. Cinderella's only friends are four mice, a dog and a horse that live in the house. When the King decides that his son, the Prince, should get married, he invites every maiden in his kingdom to a ball in order that the Prince could choose his bride. However, Cinderella's cruel stepmother does not allow her to attend the ball. When Cinderella is hopeless of going to the Royal Ball, her Fairy Godmother appears and uses magic to help her to make her dream come true. But she must leave the ball before midnight since the magic effect will end. "Cinderella" is one of the classics produced by Disney that belongs not only to my childhood, but also to my daughter and my son's childhoods. This adorable fairytale is wonderful and should be mandatory to every child in the world. I do not have much to say, since I believe that most of the readers certainly know the story of "Cinderella". I feel sorry for those that have written stupid things about this lovely fantasy  what a poor childhood they had. My vote is ten. Title (Brazil): "Cinderela" ("Cinderella")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true Disney classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been so many versions of the Cinderella story that you may be surprised to find that some of the elements that you think are a part of the story are missing. Gone are Buttons and Barron Hardup figures that we see in Pantomime and instead we have a selection of cute animals (this is Disney after all) that will either warm your heart or annoy you badly. Cinderella herself is a typical Disney princess but the film moves along at a quick pace after quite a slow first 20 minutes. For it's age it looks stunning and the humour does not date. Although it probably appeal more to girls than boys there is a lot of fun for them to enjoy in the film as well what with the bumbling king and his servant. Overall a classic Disney film that is well worth seeing to bring back some childhood memories.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinderella" isn't Disney's best, but I think many people will be able to identify with the main character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Walt Disney's 12th full-length animated feature Cinderella (1950) was one of the first movies that I ever saw as a child along with Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937) and Mary Poppins (1964). If there's something we all know from our childhoods, it's that the first few movies we see (especially if they're Disney movies like this) are going to remain in our memories for quite some time. It was a great film to watch as a child, and for the most part, I still liked the film looking back at it as an adult. Unfortunately, due to some serious story flaws, Cinderella doesn't stand the test of time as well as either Snow White or Mary Poppins do. You know the story to this one. A young woman named Cinderella is forced to work as a maid to her evil stepmother and two stepsisters after her father passed away. Despite the terrible treatment she gets all around from them, Cinderella still remains kind and gentle. Furthermore, she at least has a few animal friends in the form of mice, birds, and other animals in the farm nearby. One day, the kingdom announces that the prince has returned and a ball will be held to celebrate this occasion. Every single person is to attend meaning Cinderella is eligible to go. However, her stepmother does not let her go and gives her more chores to do. That's when her fairy godmother comes in and.well, I think it's safe to say that you know the rest, so I won't spoil the rest for whoever hasn't seen it yet. So what issues do I have with Cinderella looking back at it as a young adult? Well, let's discuss the biggest issue I have with the entire film. The film makes the serious mistake of placing at least half the focus of the movie on the side characters rather than on the main characters Cinderella and Prince Charming. I'm particularly disdainful of the fact that more than a quarter of the film is focused on the adventures with the mice and the cat and yet we only see Prince Charming for around 2-3 minutes. Now why did the storytellers of this film feel like this was the right direction to go? They even spend more time on the King and the Grand Duke more than they do with Prince Charming to the point where it should be the King who should be married and not the prince. I realize that it was hard to draw realistic human characters when Snow White was being made and I think the animators did a great job on animating the human halves of the fawns in Fantasia. So there's absolutely no excuse for Disney's storytellers to drop the ball like that on the prince character and deprive him of having any personality, no excuse for that whatsoever. In addition to the prince not having enough screen time or any personality, the mice have way more screen time than they should be having and there's only so much of their over cutesiness that I can take. While these mice characters are at least useful to the main plot some of the time, a film that is titled Cinderella is supposed to be mainly focused on Cinderella, not over 25% focused on a Tom and Jerry like subplot. The high-pitched voices on these mice don't help either. In fact, they make the problem even worse in my opinion. I should probably start analyzing the positive aspects of Cinderella now. Even despite the criticisms that the main character Cinderella gets for not being an assertive enough character, I have to be honest and say that I still liked her enough character wise. I particularly admired how after all the misery she has been put under from her step family, she still maintains her kindness and positivity almost all the time. If that wasn't enough, she also tries to spread that positivity to everybody and every creature around her, so that they can all get along. So for that aspect alone, I think she's a good role model for young girls to look up to. Of course, I thought the stepmother was a well written Disney villain. Who wouldn't think so? She doesn't need any evil laughter to become more intimidating for our main character. The fact that she simply keeps forcing her do more chores and not even give her any credit whatsoever is enough for me. Even though it's a little unusual that more time is spent with the King and the Grand Duke than on the Prince, I still think that they're enjoyable comic relief and they do keep the plot in motion as characters of this nature should be doing. The soundtrack by Oliver Wallace has a couple memorable tunes that I'm sure most of us are familiar with such as "Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo", "Sing Sweet Nightingale", "So This is Love", and "A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes". Though it isn't as richly detailed as the earliest Disney pictures are, the animation here is nice and colorful in its own right. Overall, I think that Cinderella is alright. If this film didn't make the serious storytelling errors that it did and if it focused more on the central characters, then I think Cinderella would be a more timeless Disney picture as a result. But for what it is for the time being, it's still a nice picture with a positive, harmless message for children about the importance of kindness and hard work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classical and A Soft Re-Telling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KatherinePetersdorf
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did enjoy this movie when I was a child. It was great at such a young idea to believe in love at first sight. I also enjoyed the ideal that a girl who was worthless and nothing could become someone amazing and marry the perfect man. I didn't enjoy her singing voice, though. I thought the vocal actress for singing was too high, my ears are sensitive and high soprano doesn't float my boat. I kind of enjoyed the second Cinderella more, it was probably because I was overwhelmed by the original story. When I was young I read the Grimms version, with the cut off of parts of the step sister's feet to wear the shoes, and all the other gore, but Disney did a good job of making it nice. I preferred Dark though :P
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that great... feels like tom and jerry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jumpelaj
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really wanted to like this movie but it is not romantic or classic. It adds nothing to the basic story of Cinderella that we have always heard. The scenes are very pretty and the animation is very good but the most part of the film focuses on the mouse-friends of Cinderella and the mean cat belonging to the step mother. It feels like tom and jerry and by the end of the film you are too tired of watching the animal characters. As another reviewer has mentioned there is no background given of Cinderella or any insight into who she is or what she is all about and no screen time what so ever to the prince himself. It starts well and then gets very very bland. The fairy Godmother is very lovable and so is the King but there is nothing that Cinderella herself brings to the movie. I would recommend watching Enchanted instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another childhood classic from Disney
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Along with 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' 'Cinderella' was one of my favourite Disney films as a child. This film was engaging for the most part, but I feel that the announcement of the ball took longer than it should have done due to a somewhat overlong segment of Cinderella doing her duties and a couple of the scenes involving the king and the duke were slightly irrelevant to the film's main plot. The mice were hard to understand when I heard them speak for the first time in this film for several years but they were cute, funny and active supporting characters nonetheless. Also the film's location setting (probably a toss-up between France and the Netherlands) and time period are hard to determine. The ending was rushed yet memorable with some twists and turns leading up to it. The best aspects of this film were the prologue that consists of a moving back-story of Cinderella and her step-family; beautiful illustrations; very young versions of Cinderella and her stepsisters and simple animation, which got better as the film progressed; the memorable songs (In particular the opening song, 'A Dream is a Wish,' 'Sing Sweet Nightingale,' the brief song sung by the mice before they made Cinderella's dress, 'Bibbidy Bobbidy Boo' and the song that plays when Cinderella dances with the prince); the bubble sequence during 'Sing Sweet Nightingale;' the dressmaking scene and the Fairy Godmother scene. In conclusion, this film isn't quite as enjoyable as 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' but it was worth another look after several years. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1st out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After spending most of the 1940s with package films, Disney was on turmoil with this last film and if it was successful, they would make more movies but if they were not, they would close the studio, and this film was a big hit in 1950. The story is about a young woman named Cinderella who has become a servant in her own home by her own stepmother. When the royal family throws a ball for Prince Charming's return, Cinderella sneaks out of her house to go to the ball, and unknowingly bumps into Prince Charming. The plot is not the most complicated, as it is practically the same as the fairy tale, but they perform it so well. The characters are also very interesting, except Prince Charming. Cinderella is a nice, genuine, spunky (for the classic princesses), level eased girl. Lady Tremaine is a crude, selfish, manipulative villain, who has so much impact in everything she is doing; great villain. The stepsisters are Lady Tremaine's pawns, but their foolish, bratty behaviour is hilarious. The King is extremely cold and enjoyable at the same time, but he does not come off as extremely threatening. Prince Charming is barely in the movie, and faces the same problems that Snow's Prince had (they could not animate a realistic male character yet). The mice are cute, fun characters that provide our comic relief. The songs, everybody remembers them, from "A Dream is a Wish Your Heart Makes", "Bibbidi Bobbidi Bo", "So This Is Love", etc. they are so soothing, and not overly energetic and fast. Disney's most memorable songs are in this movie. The animation is top notch. It is so stylistic, and the backgrounds are so beautiful. Cinderella's design, as all the other characters (excluding Prince Charming) are designed really well, and Disney really got the character movements down. This is one of the best animated movies they have ever done. Everything flows well with this movie, and the only thing that I wish would have been better is if they took away some of the scenes with the mice, so we could have seen more of what the royals were thinking, but this movie is practically flawless. This film is perfect for the entire family. Little girls will like the dresses and mice, boys will love the slapstick humour, and the adults will enjoy the animation, story, and the undertones of the movies. You should definitely give this movie a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a charming and beautifully made animated film. "Cinderella" is everything that an animated fairy-tale should be. It was delightful and highly enjoyable from beginning to end, showing in every single scene form this movie a "magic" that most of the animated films from the recent years lack, with wonderful designs and a exquisite level of detail in every frame. Personally, I consider this movie to be the best adaptation of the classic fairy tale written by Charles Perrault. Movies like "Cinderella" shows why the time when this was made was considered "The Golden Age of Animation".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The thing-a-ma-bob that does the job is bibidi bobidi boo"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not the best of Walt Disney's feature length animated films, but any film that has Bibidi Bobbidi Boo and A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes has to rate as good in anyone's standards. I saw this for the first time as a small child on Walt Disney's Disneyland hour and it was as effective on the big screen as well as the small. I don't think there's anyone who is literate in the western world who does not know the story of Cinderella. The story is intact and kept in the mythical medieval times it was written for. As a subplot to the main story we have the story of Cinderella and her relationship with the animals around the house. The pecking order is dog, cat, mice with a horse thrown in for good measure. Naturally the evil stepmother who is voiced by Eleanor Audley has the cat as her favorite. What does that say about us cat lovers. Ilene Woods voices and sings A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes which Perry Como made a big hit record of. Bibidi Bobidi Boo is sung by Verna Felton who voices the Fairy Godmother. She's unforgettable in this role although she's better known as Hilda Crocker, Spring Byington's Ethel Mertz on December Bride. This is one eternal film that I hope my niece let's my new grandnephew check out and his sister or brother to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still a gem and my favourite as a child, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ipacitti
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney's classic Cinderella: My favourite as a child, I would watch it all the time and when I look back. I can't think why.. The animation, the story, the characters, the songs...it's all magical and captivating but when I watched it again not long ago, I was questioning why I thought all of that when I was younger. Disney was still developing and getting into good stories and movie making at the time, it was 1950, so what do you expect from a Disney film at that time period? Snow White was bad so this sort of saved it, it was better and more believable so I guess that's why. But I think Disney didn't suck in all ages to a good DECENT Disney Movie until the 1970's onwards. Sleeping Beauty was 1960 so it wasn't THAT good either. Do you get my gist? The oldest movies were the most boring and less effective, to me, anyway. My goal isn't to discourage anyone from hating this movie because it is in fact a timeless classic, just not as much when you're a hormonal teenager. It's better suited for kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Childhood Classic of My Children and Mine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a small kingdom, the happily child Cinderella loses her beloved mother and his father marries with the cruel Lady Tremaine, who has the mean daughters Drizella and Anastasia. When her father dies, Cinderella becomes a servant in her own house and her stepmother and sisters feels only hatred for her. Cinderella's only friends are four mice, a dog and a horse that live in the house. When the King decides that his son, the Prince, should get married, he invites every maiden in his kingdom to a ball in order that the Prince could choose his bride. However, Cinderella's cruel stepmother does not allow her to attend the ball. When Cinderella is hopeless of going to the Royal Ball, her Fairy Godmother appears and uses magic to help her to make her dream come true. But she must leave the ball before midnight since the magic effect will end. "Cinderella" is one of the classics produced by Disney that belongs not only to my childhood, but also to my daughter and my son's childhoods. This adorable fairytale is wonderful and should be mandatory to every child in the world. I do not have much to say, since I believe that most of the readers certainly know the story of "Cinderella". I feel sorry for those that have written stupid things about this lovely fantasy  what a poor childhood they had. My vote is ten. Title (Brazil): "Cinderela" ("Cinderella")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true Disney classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been so many versions of the Cinderella story that you may be surprised to find that some of the elements that you think are a part of the story are missing. Gone are Buttons and Barron Hardup figures that we see in Pantomime and instead we have a selection of cute animals (this is Disney after all) that will either warm your heart or annoy you badly. Cinderella herself is a typical Disney princess but the film moves along at a quick pace after quite a slow first 20 minutes. For it's age it looks stunning and the humour does not date. Although it probably appeal more to girls than boys there is a lot of fun for them to enjoy in the film as well what with the bumbling king and his servant. Overall a classic Disney film that is well worth seeing to bring back some childhood memories.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinderella" isn't Disney's best, but I think many people will be able to identify with the main character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Walt Disney's 12th full-length animated feature Cinderella (1950) was one of the first movies that I ever saw as a child along with Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937) and Mary Poppins (1964). If there's something we all know from our childhoods, it's that the first few movies we see (especially if they're Disney movies like this) are going to remain in our memories for quite some time. It was a great film to watch as a child, and for the most part, I still liked the film looking back at it as an adult. Unfortunately, due to some serious story flaws, Cinderella doesn't stand the test of time as well as either Snow White or Mary Poppins do. You know the story to this one. A young woman named Cinderella is forced to work as a maid to her evil stepmother and two stepsisters after her father passed away. Despite the terrible treatment she gets all around from them, Cinderella still remains kind and gentle. Furthermore, she at least has a few animal friends in the form of mice, birds, and other animals in the farm nearby. One day, the kingdom announces that the prince has returned and a ball will be held to celebrate this occasion. Every single person is to attend meaning Cinderella is eligible to go. However, her stepmother does not let her go and gives her more chores to do. That's when her fairy godmother comes in and.well, I think it's safe to say that you know the rest, so I won't spoil the rest for whoever hasn't seen it yet. So what issues do I have with Cinderella looking back at it as a young adult? Well, let's discuss the biggest issue I have with the entire film. The film makes the serious mistake of placing at least half the focus of the movie on the side characters rather than on the main characters Cinderella and Prince Charming. I'm particularly disdainful of the fact that more than a quarter of the film is focused on the adventures with the mice and the cat and yet we only see Prince Charming for around 2-3 minutes. Now why did the storytellers of this film feel like this was the right direction to go? They even spend more time on the King and the Grand Duke more than they do with Prince Charming to the point where it should be the King who should be married and not the prince. I realize that it was hard to draw realistic human characters when Snow White was being made and I think the animators did a great job on animating the human halves of the fawns in Fantasia. So there's absolutely no excuse for Disney's storytellers to drop the ball like that on the prince character and deprive him of having any personality, no excuse for that whatsoever. In addition to the prince not having enough screen time or any personality, the mice have way more screen time than they should be having and there's only so much of their over cutesiness that I can take. While these mice characters are at least useful to the main plot some of the time, a film that is titled Cinderella is supposed to be mainly focused on Cinderella, not over 25% focused on a Tom and Jerry like subplot. The high-pitched voices on these mice don't help either. In fact, they make the problem even worse in my opinion. I should probably start analyzing the positive aspects of Cinderella now. Even despite the criticisms that the main character Cinderella gets for not being an assertive enough character, I have to be honest and say that I still liked her enough character wise. I particularly admired how after all the misery she has been put under from her step family, she still maintains her kindness and positivity almost all the time. If that wasn't enough, she also tries to spread that positivity to everybody and every creature around her, so that they can all get along. So for that aspect alone, I think she's a good role model for young girls to look up to. Of course, I thought the stepmother was a well written Disney villain. Who wouldn't think so? She doesn't need any evil laughter to become more intimidating for our main character. The fact that she simply keeps forcing her do more chores and not even give her any credit whatsoever is enough for me. Even though it's a little unusual that more time is spent with the King and the Grand Duke than on the Prince, I still think that they're enjoyable comic relief and they do keep the plot in motion as characters of this nature should be doing. The soundtrack by Oliver Wallace has a couple memorable tunes that I'm sure most of us are familiar with such as "Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo", "Sing Sweet Nightingale", "So This is Love", and "A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes". Though it isn't as richly detailed as the earliest Disney pictures are, the animation here is nice and colorful in its own right. Overall, I think that Cinderella is alright. If this film didn't make the serious storytelling errors that it did and if it focused more on the central characters, then I think Cinderella would be a more timeless Disney picture as a result. But for what it is for the time being, it's still a nice picture with a positive, harmless message for children about the importance of kindness and hard work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classical and A Soft Re-Telling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KatherinePetersdorf
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did enjoy this movie when I was a child. It was great at such a young idea to believe in love at first sight. I also enjoyed the ideal that a girl who was worthless and nothing could become someone amazing and marry the perfect man. I didn't enjoy her singing voice, though. I thought the vocal actress for singing was too high, my ears are sensitive and high soprano doesn't float my boat. I kind of enjoyed the second Cinderella more, it was probably because I was overwhelmed by the original story. When I was young I read the Grimms version, with the cut off of parts of the step sister's feet to wear the shoes, and all the other gore, but Disney did a good job of making it nice. I preferred Dark though :P
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that great... feels like tom and jerry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jumpelaj
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really wanted to like this movie but it is not romantic or classic. It adds nothing to the basic story of Cinderella that we have always heard. The scenes are very pretty and the animation is very good but the most part of the film focuses on the mouse-friends of Cinderella and the mean cat belonging to the step mother. It feels like tom and jerry and by the end of the film you are too tired of watching the animal characters. As another reviewer has mentioned there is no background given of Cinderella or any insight into who she is or what she is all about and no screen time what so ever to the prince himself. It starts well and then gets very very bland. The fairy Godmother is very lovable and so is the King but there is nothing that Cinderella herself brings to the movie. I would recommend watching Enchanted instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another childhood classic from Disney
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Along with 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' 'Cinderella' was one of my favourite Disney films as a child. This film was engaging for the most part, but I feel that the announcement of the ball took longer than it should have done due to a somewhat overlong segment of Cinderella doing her duties and a couple of the scenes involving the king and the duke were slightly irrelevant to the film's main plot. The mice were hard to understand when I heard them speak for the first time in this film for several years but they were cute, funny and active supporting characters nonetheless. Also the film's location setting (probably a toss-up between France and the Netherlands) and time period are hard to determine. The ending was rushed yet memorable with some twists and turns leading up to it. The best aspects of this film were the prologue that consists of a moving back-story of Cinderella and her step-family; beautiful illustrations; very young versions of Cinderella and her stepsisters and simple animation, which got better as the film progressed; the memorable songs (In particular the opening song, 'A Dream is a Wish,' 'Sing Sweet Nightingale,' the brief song sung by the mice before they made Cinderella's dress, 'Bibbidy Bobbidy Boo' and the song that plays when Cinderella dances with the prince); the bubble sequence during 'Sing Sweet Nightingale;' the dressmaking scene and the Fairy Godmother scene. In conclusion, this film isn't quite as enjoyable as 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' but it was worth another look after several years. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1st out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After spending most of the 1940s with package films, Disney was on turmoil with this last film and if it was successful, they would make more movies but if they were not, they would close the studio, and this film was a big hit in 1950. The story is about a young woman named Cinderella who has become a servant in her own home by her own stepmother. When the royal family throws a ball for Prince Charming's return, Cinderella sneaks out of her house to go to the ball, and unknowingly bumps into Prince Charming. The plot is not the most complicated, as it is practically the same as the fairy tale, but they perform it so well. The characters are also very interesting, except Prince Charming. Cinderella is a nice, genuine, spunky (for the classic princesses), level eased girl. Lady Tremaine is a crude, selfish, manipulative villain, who has so much impact in everything she is doing; great villain. The stepsisters are Lady Tremaine's pawns, but their foolish, bratty behaviour is hilarious. The King is extremely cold and enjoyable at the same time, but he does not come off as extremely threatening. Prince Charming is barely in the movie, and faces the same problems that Snow's Prince had (they could not animate a realistic male character yet). The mice are cute, fun characters that provide our comic relief. The songs, everybody remembers them, from "A Dream is a Wish Your Heart Makes", "Bibbidi Bobbidi Bo", "So This Is Love", etc. they are so soothing, and not overly energetic and fast. Disney's most memorable songs are in this movie. The animation is top notch. It is so stylistic, and the backgrounds are so beautiful. Cinderella's design, as all the other characters (excluding Prince Charming) are designed really well, and Disney really got the character movements down. This is one of the best animated movies they have ever done. Everything flows well with this movie, and the only thing that I wish would have been better is if they took away some of the scenes with the mice, so we could have seen more of what the royals were thinking, but this movie is practically flawless. This film is perfect for the entire family. Little girls will like the dresses and mice, boys will love the slapstick humour, and the adults will enjoy the animation, story, and the undertones of the movies. You should definitely give this movie a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a charming and beautifully made animated film. "Cinderella" is everything that an animated fairy-tale should be. It was delightful and highly enjoyable from beginning to end, showing in every single scene form this movie a "magic" that most of the animated films from the recent years lack, with wonderful designs and a exquisite level of detail in every frame. Personally, I consider this movie to be the best adaptation of the classic fairy tale written by Charles Perrault. Movies like "Cinderella" shows why the time when this was made was considered "The Golden Age of Animation".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The thing-a-ma-bob that does the job is bibidi bobidi boo"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not the best of Walt Disney's feature length animated films, but any film that has Bibidi Bobbidi Boo and A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes has to rate as good in anyone's standards. I saw this for the first time as a small child on Walt Disney's Disneyland hour and it was as effective on the big screen as well as the small. I don't think there's anyone who is literate in the western world who does not know the story of Cinderella. The story is intact and kept in the mythical medieval times it was written for. As a subplot to the main story we have the story of Cinderella and her relationship with the animals around the house. The pecking order is dog, cat, mice with a horse thrown in for good measure. Naturally the evil stepmother who is voiced by Eleanor Audley has the cat as her favorite. What does that say about us cat lovers. Ilene Woods voices and sings A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes which Perry Como made a big hit record of. Bibidi Bobidi Boo is sung by Verna Felton who voices the Fairy Godmother. She's unforgettable in this role although she's better known as Hilda Crocker, Spring Byington's Ethel Mertz on December Bride. This is one eternal film that I hope my niece let's my new grandnephew check out and his sister or brother to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still a gem and my favourite as a child, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ipacitti
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney's classic Cinderella: My favourite as a child, I would watch it all the time and when I look back. I can't think why.. The animation, the story, the characters, the songs...it's all magical and captivating but when I watched it again not long ago, I was questioning why I thought all of that when I was younger. Disney was still developing and getting into good stories and movie making at the time, it was 1950, so what do you expect from a Disney film at that time period? Snow White was bad so this sort of saved it, it was better and more believable so I guess that's why. But I think Disney didn't suck in all ages to a good DECENT Disney Movie until the 1970's onwards. Sleeping Beauty was 1960 so it wasn't THAT good either. Do you get my gist? The oldest movies were the most boring and less effective, to me, anyway. My goal isn't to discourage anyone from hating this movie because it is in fact a timeless classic, just not as much when you're a hormonal teenager. It's better suited for kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Childhood Classic of My Children and Mine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a small kingdom, the happily child Cinderella loses her beloved mother and his father marries with the cruel Lady Tremaine, who has the mean daughters Drizella and Anastasia. When her father dies, Cinderella becomes a servant in her own house and her stepmother and sisters feels only hatred for her. Cinderella's only friends are four mice, a dog and a horse that live in the house. When the King decides that his son, the Prince, should get married, he invites every maiden in his kingdom to a ball in order that the Prince could choose his bride. However, Cinderella's cruel stepmother does not allow her to attend the ball. When Cinderella is hopeless of going to the Royal Ball, her Fairy Godmother appears and uses magic to help her to make her dream come true. But she must leave the ball before midnight since the magic effect will end. "Cinderella" is one of the classics produced by Disney that belongs not only to my childhood, but also to my daughter and my son's childhoods. This adorable fairytale is wonderful and should be mandatory to every child in the world. I do not have much to say, since I believe that most of the readers certainly know the story of "Cinderella". I feel sorry for those that have written stupid things about this lovely fantasy  what a poor childhood they had. My vote is ten. Title (Brazil): "Cinderela" ("Cinderella")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true Disney classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been so many versions of the Cinderella story that you may be surprised to find that some of the elements that you think are a part of the story are missing. Gone are Buttons and Barron Hardup figures that we see in Pantomime and instead we have a selection of cute animals (this is Disney after all) that will either warm your heart or annoy you badly. Cinderella herself is a typical Disney princess but the film moves along at a quick pace after quite a slow first 20 minutes. For it's age it looks stunning and the humour does not date. Although it probably appeal more to girls than boys there is a lot of fun for them to enjoy in the film as well what with the bumbling king and his servant. Overall a classic Disney film that is well worth seeing to bring back some childhood memories.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinderella" isn't Disney's best, but I think many people will be able to identify with the main character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Walt Disney's 12th full-length animated feature Cinderella (1950) was one of the first movies that I ever saw as a child along with Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937) and Mary Poppins (1964). If there's something we all know from our childhoods, it's that the first few movies we see (especially if they're Disney movies like this) are going to remain in our memories for quite some time. It was a great film to watch as a child, and for the most part, I still liked the film looking back at it as an adult. Unfortunately, due to some serious story flaws, Cinderella doesn't stand the test of time as well as either Snow White or Mary Poppins do. You know the story to this one. A young woman named Cinderella is forced to work as a maid to her evil stepmother and two stepsisters after her father passed away. Despite the terrible treatment she gets all around from them, Cinderella still remains kind and gentle. Furthermore, she at least has a few animal friends in the form of mice, birds, and other animals in the farm nearby. One day, the kingdom announces that the prince has returned and a ball will be held to celebrate this occasion. Every single person is to attend meaning Cinderella is eligible to go. However, her stepmother does not let her go and gives her more chores to do. That's when her fairy godmother comes in and.well, I think it's safe to say that you know the rest, so I won't spoil the rest for whoever hasn't seen it yet. So what issues do I have with Cinderella looking back at it as a young adult? Well, let's discuss the biggest issue I have with the entire film. The film makes the serious mistake of placing at least half the focus of the movie on the side characters rather than on the main characters Cinderella and Prince Charming. I'm particularly disdainful of the fact that more than a quarter of the film is focused on the adventures with the mice and the cat and yet we only see Prince Charming for around 2-3 minutes. Now why did the storytellers of this film feel like this was the right direction to go? They even spend more time on the King and the Grand Duke more than they do with Prince Charming to the point where it should be the King who should be married and not the prince. I realize that it was hard to draw realistic human characters when Snow White was being made and I think the animators did a great job on animating the human halves of the fawns in Fantasia. So there's absolutely no excuse for Disney's storytellers to drop the ball like that on the prince character and deprive him of having any personality, no excuse for that whatsoever. In addition to the prince not having enough screen time or any personality, the mice have way more screen time than they should be having and there's only so much of their over cutesiness that I can take. While these mice characters are at least useful to the main plot some of the time, a film that is titled Cinderella is supposed to be mainly focused on Cinderella, not over 25% focused on a Tom and Jerry like subplot. The high-pitched voices on these mice don't help either. In fact, they make the problem even worse in my opinion. I should probably start analyzing the positive aspects of Cinderella now. Even despite the criticisms that the main character Cinderella gets for not being an assertive enough character, I have to be honest and say that I still liked her enough character wise. I particularly admired how after all the misery she has been put under from her step family, she still maintains her kindness and positivity almost all the time. If that wasn't enough, she also tries to spread that positivity to everybody and every creature around her, so that they can all get along. So for that aspect alone, I think she's a good role model for young girls to look up to. Of course, I thought the stepmother was a well written Disney villain. Who wouldn't think so? She doesn't need any evil laughter to become more intimidating for our main character. The fact that she simply keeps forcing her do more chores and not even give her any credit whatsoever is enough for me. Even though it's a little unusual that more time is spent with the King and the Grand Duke than on the Prince, I still think that they're enjoyable comic relief and they do keep the plot in motion as characters of this nature should be doing. The soundtrack by Oliver Wallace has a couple memorable tunes that I'm sure most of us are familiar with such as "Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo", "Sing Sweet Nightingale", "So This is Love", and "A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes". Though it isn't as richly detailed as the earliest Disney pictures are, the animation here is nice and colorful in its own right. Overall, I think that Cinderella is alright. If this film didn't make the serious storytelling errors that it did and if it focused more on the central characters, then I think Cinderella would be a more timeless Disney picture as a result. But for what it is for the time being, it's still a nice picture with a positive, harmless message for children about the importance of kindness and hard work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classical and A Soft Re-Telling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KatherinePetersdorf
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did enjoy this movie when I was a child. It was great at such a young idea to believe in love at first sight. I also enjoyed the ideal that a girl who was worthless and nothing could become someone amazing and marry the perfect man. I didn't enjoy her singing voice, though. I thought the vocal actress for singing was too high, my ears are sensitive and high soprano doesn't float my boat. I kind of enjoyed the second Cinderella more, it was probably because I was overwhelmed by the original story. When I was young I read the Grimms version, with the cut off of parts of the step sister's feet to wear the shoes, and all the other gore, but Disney did a good job of making it nice. I preferred Dark though :P
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that great... feels like tom and jerry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jumpelaj
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really wanted to like this movie but it is not romantic or classic. It adds nothing to the basic story of Cinderella that we have always heard. The scenes are very pretty and the animation is very good but the most part of the film focuses on the mouse-friends of Cinderella and the mean cat belonging to the step mother. It feels like tom and jerry and by the end of the film you are too tired of watching the animal characters. As another reviewer has mentioned there is no background given of Cinderella or any insight into who she is or what she is all about and no screen time what so ever to the prince himself. It starts well and then gets very very bland. The fairy Godmother is very lovable and so is the King but there is nothing that Cinderella herself brings to the movie. I would recommend watching Enchanted instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another childhood classic from Disney
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Along with 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' 'Cinderella' was one of my favourite Disney films as a child. This film was engaging for the most part, but I feel that the announcement of the ball took longer than it should have done due to a somewhat overlong segment of Cinderella doing her duties and a couple of the scenes involving the king and the duke were slightly irrelevant to the film's main plot. The mice were hard to understand when I heard them speak for the first time in this film for several years but they were cute, funny and active supporting characters nonetheless. Also the film's location setting (probably a toss-up between France and the Netherlands) and time period are hard to determine. The ending was rushed yet memorable with some twists and turns leading up to it. The best aspects of this film were the prologue that consists of a moving back-story of Cinderella and her step-family; beautiful illustrations; very young versions of Cinderella and her stepsisters and simple animation, which got better as the film progressed; the memorable songs (In particular the opening song, 'A Dream is a Wish,' 'Sing Sweet Nightingale,' the brief song sung by the mice before they made Cinderella's dress, 'Bibbidy Bobbidy Boo' and the song that plays when Cinderella dances with the prince); the bubble sequence during 'Sing Sweet Nightingale;' the dressmaking scene and the Fairy Godmother scene. In conclusion, this film isn't quite as enjoyable as 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' but it was worth another look after several years. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1st out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After spending most of the 1940s with package films, Disney was on turmoil with this last film and if it was successful, they would make more movies but if they were not, they would close the studio, and this film was a big hit in 1950. The story is about a young woman named Cinderella who has become a servant in her own home by her own stepmother. When the royal family throws a ball for Prince Charming's return, Cinderella sneaks out of her house to go to the ball, and unknowingly bumps into Prince Charming. The plot is not the most complicated, as it is practically the same as the fairy tale, but they perform it so well. The characters are also very interesting, except Prince Charming. Cinderella is a nice, genuine, spunky (for the classic princesses), level eased girl. Lady Tremaine is a crude, selfish, manipulative villain, who has so much impact in everything she is doing; great villain. The stepsisters are Lady Tremaine's pawns, but their foolish, bratty behaviour is hilarious. The King is extremely cold and enjoyable at the same time, but he does not come off as extremely threatening. Prince Charming is barely in the movie, and faces the same problems that Snow's Prince had (they could not animate a realistic male character yet). The mice are cute, fun characters that provide our comic relief. The songs, everybody remembers them, from "A Dream is a Wish Your Heart Makes", "Bibbidi Bobbidi Bo", "So This Is Love", etc. they are so soothing, and not overly energetic and fast. Disney's most memorable songs are in this movie. The animation is top notch. It is so stylistic, and the backgrounds are so beautiful. Cinderella's design, as all the other characters (excluding Prince Charming) are designed really well, and Disney really got the character movements down. This is one of the best animated movies they have ever done. Everything flows well with this movie, and the only thing that I wish would have been better is if they took away some of the scenes with the mice, so we could have seen more of what the royals were thinking, but this movie is practically flawless. This film is perfect for the entire family. Little girls will like the dresses and mice, boys will love the slapstick humour, and the adults will enjoy the animation, story, and the undertones of the movies. You should definitely give this movie a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a charming and beautifully made animated film. "Cinderella" is everything that an animated fairy-tale should be. It was delightful and highly enjoyable from beginning to end, showing in every single scene form this movie a "magic" that most of the animated films from the recent years lack, with wonderful designs and a exquisite level of detail in every frame. Personally, I consider this movie to be the best adaptation of the classic fairy tale written by Charles Perrault. Movies like "Cinderella" shows why the time when this was made was considered "The Golden Age of Animation".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The thing-a-ma-bob that does the job is bibidi bobidi boo"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not the best of Walt Disney's feature length animated films, but any film that has Bibidi Bobbidi Boo and A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes has to rate as good in anyone's standards. I saw this for the first time as a small child on Walt Disney's Disneyland hour and it was as effective on the big screen as well as the small. I don't think there's anyone who is literate in the western world who does not know the story of Cinderella. The story is intact and kept in the mythical medieval times it was written for. As a subplot to the main story we have the story of Cinderella and her relationship with the animals around the house. The pecking order is dog, cat, mice with a horse thrown in for good measure. Naturally the evil stepmother who is voiced by Eleanor Audley has the cat as her favorite. What does that say about us cat lovers. Ilene Woods voices and sings A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes which Perry Como made a big hit record of. Bibidi Bobidi Boo is sung by Verna Felton who voices the Fairy Godmother. She's unforgettable in this role although she's better known as Hilda Crocker, Spring Byington's Ethel Mertz on December Bride. This is one eternal film that I hope my niece let's my new grandnephew check out and his sister or brother to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still a gem and my favourite as a child, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ipacitti
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney's classic Cinderella: My favourite as a child, I would watch it all the time and when I look back. I can't think why.. The animation, the story, the characters, the songs...it's all magical and captivating but when I watched it again not long ago, I was questioning why I thought all of that when I was younger. Disney was still developing and getting into good stories and movie making at the time, it was 1950, so what do you expect from a Disney film at that time period? Snow White was bad so this sort of saved it, it was better and more believable so I guess that's why. But I think Disney didn't suck in all ages to a good DECENT Disney Movie until the 1970's onwards. Sleeping Beauty was 1960 so it wasn't THAT good either. Do you get my gist? The oldest movies were the most boring and less effective, to me, anyway. My goal isn't to discourage anyone from hating this movie because it is in fact a timeless classic, just not as much when you're a hormonal teenager. It's better suited for kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Childhood Classic of My Children and Mine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a small kingdom, the happily child Cinderella loses her beloved mother and his father marries with the cruel Lady Tremaine, who has the mean daughters Drizella and Anastasia. When her father dies, Cinderella becomes a servant in her own house and her stepmother and sisters feels only hatred for her. Cinderella's only friends are four mice, a dog and a horse that live in the house. When the King decides that his son, the Prince, should get married, he invites every maiden in his kingdom to a ball in order that the Prince could choose his bride. However, Cinderella's cruel stepmother does not allow her to attend the ball. When Cinderella is hopeless of going to the Royal Ball, her Fairy Godmother appears and uses magic to help her to make her dream come true. But she must leave the ball before midnight since the magic effect will end. "Cinderella" is one of the classics produced by Disney that belongs not only to my childhood, but also to my daughter and my son's childhoods. This adorable fairytale is wonderful and should be mandatory to every child in the world. I do not have much to say, since I believe that most of the readers certainly know the story of "Cinderella". I feel sorry for those that have written stupid things about this lovely fantasy  what a poor childhood they had. My vote is ten. Title (Brazil): "Cinderela" ("Cinderella")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true Disney classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been so many versions of the Cinderella story that you may be surprised to find that some of the elements that you think are a part of the story are missing. Gone are Buttons and Barron Hardup figures that we see in Pantomime and instead we have a selection of cute animals (this is Disney after all) that will either warm your heart or annoy you badly. Cinderella herself is a typical Disney princess but the film moves along at a quick pace after quite a slow first 20 minutes. For it's age it looks stunning and the humour does not date. Although it probably appeal more to girls than boys there is a lot of fun for them to enjoy in the film as well what with the bumbling king and his servant. Overall a classic Disney film that is well worth seeing to bring back some childhood memories.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinderella" isn't Disney's best, but I think many people will be able to identify with the main character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Walt Disney's 12th full-length animated feature Cinderella (1950) was one of the first movies that I ever saw as a child along with Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937) and Mary Poppins (1964). If there's something we all know from our childhoods, it's that the first few movies we see (especially if they're Disney movies like this) are going to remain in our memories for quite some time. It was a great film to watch as a child, and for the most part, I still liked the film looking back at it as an adult. Unfortunately, due to some serious story flaws, Cinderella doesn't stand the test of time as well as either Snow White or Mary Poppins do. You know the story to this one. A young woman named Cinderella is forced to work as a maid to her evil stepmother and two stepsisters after her father passed away. Despite the terrible treatment she gets all around from them, Cinderella still remains kind and gentle. Furthermore, she at least has a few animal friends in the form of mice, birds, and other animals in the farm nearby. One day, the kingdom announces that the prince has returned and a ball will be held to celebrate this occasion. Every single person is to attend meaning Cinderella is eligible to go. However, her stepmother does not let her go and gives her more chores to do. That's when her fairy godmother comes in and.well, I think it's safe to say that you know the rest, so I won't spoil the rest for whoever hasn't seen it yet. So what issues do I have with Cinderella looking back at it as a young adult? Well, let's discuss the biggest issue I have with the entire film. The film makes the serious mistake of placing at least half the focus of the movie on the side characters rather than on the main characters Cinderella and Prince Charming. I'm particularly disdainful of the fact that more than a quarter of the film is focused on the adventures with the mice and the cat and yet we only see Prince Charming for around 2-3 minutes. Now why did the storytellers of this film feel like this was the right direction to go? They even spend more time on the King and the Grand Duke more than they do with Prince Charming to the point where it should be the King who should be married and not the prince. I realize that it was hard to draw realistic human characters when Snow White was being made and I think the animators did a great job on animating the human halves of the fawns in Fantasia. So there's absolutely no excuse for Disney's storytellers to drop the ball like that on the prince character and deprive him of having any personality, no excuse for that whatsoever. In addition to the prince not having enough screen time or any personality, the mice have way more screen time than they should be having and there's only so much of their over cutesiness that I can take. While these mice characters are at least useful to the main plot some of the time, a film that is titled Cinderella is supposed to be mainly focused on Cinderella, not over 25% focused on a Tom and Jerry like subplot. The high-pitched voices on these mice don't help either. In fact, they make the problem even worse in my opinion. I should probably start analyzing the positive aspects of Cinderella now. Even despite the criticisms that the main character Cinderella gets for not being an assertive enough character, I have to be honest and say that I still liked her enough character wise. I particularly admired how after all the misery she has been put under from her step family, she still maintains her kindness and positivity almost all the time. If that wasn't enough, she also tries to spread that positivity to everybody and every creature around her, so that they can all get along. So for that aspect alone, I think she's a good role model for young girls to look up to. Of course, I thought the stepmother was a well written Disney villain. Who wouldn't think so? She doesn't need any evil laughter to become more intimidating for our main character. The fact that she simply keeps forcing her do more chores and not even give her any credit whatsoever is enough for me. Even though it's a little unusual that more time is spent with the King and the Grand Duke than on the Prince, I still think that they're enjoyable comic relief and they do keep the plot in motion as characters of this nature should be doing. The soundtrack by Oliver Wallace has a couple memorable tunes that I'm sure most of us are familiar with such as "Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo", "Sing Sweet Nightingale", "So This is Love", and "A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes". Though it isn't as richly detailed as the earliest Disney pictures are, the animation here is nice and colorful in its own right. Overall, I think that Cinderella is alright. If this film didn't make the serious storytelling errors that it did and if it focused more on the central characters, then I think Cinderella would be a more timeless Disney picture as a result. But for what it is for the time being, it's still a nice picture with a positive, harmless message for children about the importance of kindness and hard work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classical and A Soft Re-Telling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KatherinePetersdorf
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did enjoy this movie when I was a child. It was great at such a young idea to believe in love at first sight. I also enjoyed the ideal that a girl who was worthless and nothing could become someone amazing and marry the perfect man. I didn't enjoy her singing voice, though. I thought the vocal actress for singing was too high, my ears are sensitive and high soprano doesn't float my boat. I kind of enjoyed the second Cinderella more, it was probably because I was overwhelmed by the original story. When I was young I read the Grimms version, with the cut off of parts of the step sister's feet to wear the shoes, and all the other gore, but Disney did a good job of making it nice. I preferred Dark though :P
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that great... feels like tom and jerry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jumpelaj
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really wanted to like this movie but it is not romantic or classic. It adds nothing to the basic story of Cinderella that we have always heard. The scenes are very pretty and the animation is very good but the most part of the film focuses on the mouse-friends of Cinderella and the mean cat belonging to the step mother. It feels like tom and jerry and by the end of the film you are too tired of watching the animal characters. As another reviewer has mentioned there is no background given of Cinderella or any insight into who she is or what she is all about and no screen time what so ever to the prince himself. It starts well and then gets very very bland. The fairy Godmother is very lovable and so is the King but there is nothing that Cinderella herself brings to the movie. I would recommend watching Enchanted instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another childhood classic from Disney
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Along with 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' 'Cinderella' was one of my favourite Disney films as a child. This film was engaging for the most part, but I feel that the announcement of the ball took longer than it should have done due to a somewhat overlong segment of Cinderella doing her duties and a couple of the scenes involving the king and the duke were slightly irrelevant to the film's main plot. The mice were hard to understand when I heard them speak for the first time in this film for several years but they were cute, funny and active supporting characters nonetheless. Also the film's location setting (probably a toss-up between France and the Netherlands) and time period are hard to determine. The ending was rushed yet memorable with some twists and turns leading up to it. The best aspects of this film were the prologue that consists of a moving back-story of Cinderella and her step-family; beautiful illustrations; very young versions of Cinderella and her stepsisters and simple animation, which got better as the film progressed; the memorable songs (In particular the opening song, 'A Dream is a Wish,' 'Sing Sweet Nightingale,' the brief song sung by the mice before they made Cinderella's dress, 'Bibbidy Bobbidy Boo' and the song that plays when Cinderella dances with the prince); the bubble sequence during 'Sing Sweet Nightingale;' the dressmaking scene and the Fairy Godmother scene. In conclusion, this film isn't quite as enjoyable as 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' but it was worth another look after several years. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1st out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After spending most of the 1940s with package films, Disney was on turmoil with this last film and if it was successful, they would make more movies but if they were not, they would close the studio, and this film was a big hit in 1950. The story is about a young woman named Cinderella who has become a servant in her own home by her own stepmother. When the royal family throws a ball for Prince Charming's return, Cinderella sneaks out of her house to go to the ball, and unknowingly bumps into Prince Charming. The plot is not the most complicated, as it is practically the same as the fairy tale, but they perform it so well. The characters are also very interesting, except Prince Charming. Cinderella is a nice, genuine, spunky (for the classic princesses), level eased girl. Lady Tremaine is a crude, selfish, manipulative villain, who has so much impact in everything she is doing; great villain. The stepsisters are Lady Tremaine's pawns, but their foolish, bratty behaviour is hilarious. The King is extremely cold and enjoyable at the same time, but he does not come off as extremely threatening. Prince Charming is barely in the movie, and faces the same problems that Snow's Prince had (they could not animate a realistic male character yet). The mice are cute, fun characters that provide our comic relief. The songs, everybody remembers them, from "A Dream is a Wish Your Heart Makes", "Bibbidi Bobbidi Bo", "So This Is Love", etc. they are so soothing, and not overly energetic and fast. Disney's most memorable songs are in this movie. The animation is top notch. It is so stylistic, and the backgrounds are so beautiful. Cinderella's design, as all the other characters (excluding Prince Charming) are designed really well, and Disney really got the character movements down. This is one of the best animated movies they have ever done. Everything flows well with this movie, and the only thing that I wish would have been better is if they took away some of the scenes with the mice, so we could have seen more of what the royals were thinking, but this movie is practically flawless. This film is perfect for the entire family. Little girls will like the dresses and mice, boys will love the slapstick humour, and the adults will enjoy the animation, story, and the undertones of the movies. You should definitely give this movie a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a charming and beautifully made animated film. "Cinderella" is everything that an animated fairy-tale should be. It was delightful and highly enjoyable from beginning to end, showing in every single scene form this movie a "magic" that most of the animated films from the recent years lack, with wonderful designs and a exquisite level of detail in every frame. Personally, I consider this movie to be the best adaptation of the classic fairy tale written by Charles Perrault. Movies like "Cinderella" shows why the time when this was made was considered "The Golden Age of Animation".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The thing-a-ma-bob that does the job is bibidi bobidi boo"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not the best of Walt Disney's feature length animated films, but any film that has Bibidi Bobbidi Boo and A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes has to rate as good in anyone's standards. I saw this for the first time as a small child on Walt Disney's Disneyland hour and it was as effective on the big screen as well as the small. I don't think there's anyone who is literate in the western world who does not know the story of Cinderella. The story is intact and kept in the mythical medieval times it was written for. As a subplot to the main story we have the story of Cinderella and her relationship with the animals around the house. The pecking order is dog, cat, mice with a horse thrown in for good measure. Naturally the evil stepmother who is voiced by Eleanor Audley has the cat as her favorite. What does that say about us cat lovers. Ilene Woods voices and sings A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes which Perry Como made a big hit record of. Bibidi Bobidi Boo is sung by Verna Felton who voices the Fairy Godmother. She's unforgettable in this role although she's better known as Hilda Crocker, Spring Byington's Ethel Mertz on December Bride. This is one eternal film that I hope my niece let's my new grandnephew check out and his sister or brother to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still a gem and my favourite as a child, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ipacitti
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney's classic Cinderella: My favourite as a child, I would watch it all the time and when I look back. I can't think why.. The animation, the story, the characters, the songs...it's all magical and captivating but when I watched it again not long ago, I was questioning why I thought all of that when I was younger. Disney was still developing and getting into good stories and movie making at the time, it was 1950, so what do you expect from a Disney film at that time period? Snow White was bad so this sort of saved it, it was better and more believable so I guess that's why. But I think Disney didn't suck in all ages to a good DECENT Disney Movie until the 1970's onwards. Sleeping Beauty was 1960 so it wasn't THAT good either. Do you get my gist? The oldest movies were the most boring and less effective, to me, anyway. My goal isn't to discourage anyone from hating this movie because it is in fact a timeless classic, just not as much when you're a hormonal teenager. It's better suited for kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Childhood Classic of My Children and Mine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a small kingdom, the happily child Cinderella loses her beloved mother and his father marries with the cruel Lady Tremaine, who has the mean daughters Drizella and Anastasia. When her father dies, Cinderella becomes a servant in her own house and her stepmother and sisters feels only hatred for her. Cinderella's only friends are four mice, a dog and a horse that live in the house. When the King decides that his son, the Prince, should get married, he invites every maiden in his kingdom to a ball in order that the Prince could choose his bride. However, Cinderella's cruel stepmother does not allow her to attend the ball. When Cinderella is hopeless of going to the Royal Ball, her Fairy Godmother appears and uses magic to help her to make her dream come true. But she must leave the ball before midnight since the magic effect will end. "Cinderella" is one of the classics produced by Disney that belongs not only to my childhood, but also to my daughter and my son's childhoods. This adorable fairytale is wonderful and should be mandatory to every child in the world. I do not have much to say, since I believe that most of the readers certainly know the story of "Cinderella". I feel sorry for those that have written stupid things about this lovely fantasy  what a poor childhood they had. My vote is ten. Title (Brazil): "Cinderela" ("Cinderella")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true Disney classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been so many versions of the Cinderella story that you may be surprised to find that some of the elements that you think are a part of the story are missing. Gone are Buttons and Barron Hardup figures that we see in Pantomime and instead we have a selection of cute animals (this is Disney after all) that will either warm your heart or annoy you badly. Cinderella herself is a typical Disney princess but the film moves along at a quick pace after quite a slow first 20 minutes. For it's age it looks stunning and the humour does not date. Although it probably appeal more to girls than boys there is a lot of fun for them to enjoy in the film as well what with the bumbling king and his servant. Overall a classic Disney film that is well worth seeing to bring back some childhood memories.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinderella" isn't Disney's best, but I think many people will be able to identify with the main character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Walt Disney's 12th full-length animated feature Cinderella (1950) was one of the first movies that I ever saw as a child along with Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937) and Mary Poppins (1964). If there's something we all know from our childhoods, it's that the first few movies we see (especially if they're Disney movies like this) are going to remain in our memories for quite some time. It was a great film to watch as a child, and for the most part, I still liked the film looking back at it as an adult. Unfortunately, due to some serious story flaws, Cinderella doesn't stand the test of time as well as either Snow White or Mary Poppins do. You know the story to this one. A young woman named Cinderella is forced to work as a maid to her evil stepmother and two stepsisters after her father passed away. Despite the terrible treatment she gets all around from them, Cinderella still remains kind and gentle. Furthermore, she at least has a few animal friends in the form of mice, birds, and other animals in the farm nearby. One day, the kingdom announces that the prince has returned and a ball will be held to celebrate this occasion. Every single person is to attend meaning Cinderella is eligible to go. However, her stepmother does not let her go and gives her more chores to do. That's when her fairy godmother comes in and.well, I think it's safe to say that you know the rest, so I won't spoil the rest for whoever hasn't seen it yet. So what issues do I have with Cinderella looking back at it as a young adult? Well, let's discuss the biggest issue I have with the entire film. The film makes the serious mistake of placing at least half the focus of the movie on the side characters rather than on the main characters Cinderella and Prince Charming. I'm particularly disdainful of the fact that more than a quarter of the film is focused on the adventures with the mice and the cat and yet we only see Prince Charming for around 2-3 minutes. Now why did the storytellers of this film feel like this was the right direction to go? They even spend more time on the King and the Grand Duke more than they do with Prince Charming to the point where it should be the King who should be married and not the prince. I realize that it was hard to draw realistic human characters when Snow White was being made and I think the animators did a great job on animating the human halves of the fawns in Fantasia. So there's absolutely no excuse for Disney's storytellers to drop the ball like that on the prince character and deprive him of having any personality, no excuse for that whatsoever. In addition to the prince not having enough screen time or any personality, the mice have way more screen time than they should be having and there's only so much of their over cutesiness that I can take. While these mice characters are at least useful to the main plot some of the time, a film that is titled Cinderella is supposed to be mainly focused on Cinderella, not over 25% focused on a Tom and Jerry like subplot. The high-pitched voices on these mice don't help either. In fact, they make the problem even worse in my opinion. I should probably start analyzing the positive aspects of Cinderella now. Even despite the criticisms that the main character Cinderella gets for not being an assertive enough character, I have to be honest and say that I still liked her enough character wise. I particularly admired how after all the misery she has been put under from her step family, she still maintains her kindness and positivity almost all the time. If that wasn't enough, she also tries to spread that positivity to everybody and every creature around her, so that they can all get along. So for that aspect alone, I think she's a good role model for young girls to look up to. Of course, I thought the stepmother was a well written Disney villain. Who wouldn't think so? She doesn't need any evil laughter to become more intimidating for our main character. The fact that she simply keeps forcing her do more chores and not even give her any credit whatsoever is enough for me. Even though it's a little unusual that more time is spent with the King and the Grand Duke than on the Prince, I still think that they're enjoyable comic relief and they do keep the plot in motion as characters of this nature should be doing. The soundtrack by Oliver Wallace has a couple memorable tunes that I'm sure most of us are familiar with such as "Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo", "Sing Sweet Nightingale", "So This is Love", and "A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes". Though it isn't as richly detailed as the earliest Disney pictures are, the animation here is nice and colorful in its own right. Overall, I think that Cinderella is alright. If this film didn't make the serious storytelling errors that it did and if it focused more on the central characters, then I think Cinderella would be a more timeless Disney picture as a result. But for what it is for the time being, it's still a nice picture with a positive, harmless message for children about the importance of kindness and hard work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classical and A Soft Re-Telling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KatherinePetersdorf
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did enjoy this movie when I was a child. It was great at such a young idea to believe in love at first sight. I also enjoyed the ideal that a girl who was worthless and nothing could become someone amazing and marry the perfect man. I didn't enjoy her singing voice, though. I thought the vocal actress for singing was too high, my ears are sensitive and high soprano doesn't float my boat. I kind of enjoyed the second Cinderella more, it was probably because I was overwhelmed by the original story. When I was young I read the Grimms version, with the cut off of parts of the step sister's feet to wear the shoes, and all the other gore, but Disney did a good job of making it nice. I preferred Dark though :P
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that great... feels like tom and jerry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jumpelaj
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really wanted to like this movie but it is not romantic or classic. It adds nothing to the basic story of Cinderella that we have always heard. The scenes are very pretty and the animation is very good but the most part of the film focuses on the mouse-friends of Cinderella and the mean cat belonging to the step mother. It feels like tom and jerry and by the end of the film you are too tired of watching the animal characters. As another reviewer has mentioned there is no background given of Cinderella or any insight into who she is or what she is all about and no screen time what so ever to the prince himself. It starts well and then gets very very bland. The fairy Godmother is very lovable and so is the King but there is nothing that Cinderella herself brings to the movie. I would recommend watching Enchanted instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another childhood classic from Disney
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Along with 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' 'Cinderella' was one of my favourite Disney films as a child. This film was engaging for the most part, but I feel that the announcement of the ball took longer than it should have done due to a somewhat overlong segment of Cinderella doing her duties and a couple of the scenes involving the king and the duke were slightly irrelevant to the film's main plot. The mice were hard to understand when I heard them speak for the first time in this film for several years but they were cute, funny and active supporting characters nonetheless. Also the film's location setting (probably a toss-up between France and the Netherlands) and time period are hard to determine. The ending was rushed yet memorable with some twists and turns leading up to it. The best aspects of this film were the prologue that consists of a moving back-story of Cinderella and her step-family; beautiful illustrations; very young versions of Cinderella and her stepsisters and simple animation, which got better as the film progressed; the memorable songs (In particular the opening song, 'A Dream is a Wish,' 'Sing Sweet Nightingale,' the brief song sung by the mice before they made Cinderella's dress, 'Bibbidy Bobbidy Boo' and the song that plays when Cinderella dances with the prince); the bubble sequence during 'Sing Sweet Nightingale;' the dressmaking scene and the Fairy Godmother scene. In conclusion, this film isn't quite as enjoyable as 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' but it was worth another look after several years. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1st out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After spending most of the 1940s with package films, Disney was on turmoil with this last film and if it was successful, they would make more movies but if they were not, they would close the studio, and this film was a big hit in 1950. The story is about a young woman named Cinderella who has become a servant in her own home by her own stepmother. When the royal family throws a ball for Prince Charming's return, Cinderella sneaks out of her house to go to the ball, and unknowingly bumps into Prince Charming. The plot is not the most complicated, as it is practically the same as the fairy tale, but they perform it so well. The characters are also very interesting, except Prince Charming. Cinderella is a nice, genuine, spunky (for the classic princesses), level eased girl. Lady Tremaine is a crude, selfish, manipulative villain, who has so much impact in everything she is doing; great villain. The stepsisters are Lady Tremaine's pawns, but their foolish, bratty behaviour is hilarious. The King is extremely cold and enjoyable at the same time, but he does not come off as extremely threatening. Prince Charming is barely in the movie, and faces the same problems that Snow's Prince had (they could not animate a realistic male character yet). The mice are cute, fun characters that provide our comic relief. The songs, everybody remembers them, from "A Dream is a Wish Your Heart Makes", "Bibbidi Bobbidi Bo", "So This Is Love", etc. they are so soothing, and not overly energetic and fast. Disney's most memorable songs are in this movie. The animation is top notch. It is so stylistic, and the backgrounds are so beautiful. Cinderella's design, as all the other characters (excluding Prince Charming) are designed really well, and Disney really got the character movements down. This is one of the best animated movies they have ever done. Everything flows well with this movie, and the only thing that I wish would have been better is if they took away some of the scenes with the mice, so we could have seen more of what the royals were thinking, but this movie is practically flawless. This film is perfect for the entire family. Little girls will like the dresses and mice, boys will love the slapstick humour, and the adults will enjoy the animation, story, and the undertones of the movies. You should definitely give this movie a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a charming and beautifully made animated film. "Cinderella" is everything that an animated fairy-tale should be. It was delightful and highly enjoyable from beginning to end, showing in every single scene form this movie a "magic" that most of the animated films from the recent years lack, with wonderful designs and a exquisite level of detail in every frame. Personally, I consider this movie to be the best adaptation of the classic fairy tale written by Charles Perrault. Movies like "Cinderella" shows why the time when this was made was considered "The Golden Age of Animation".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The thing-a-ma-bob that does the job is bibidi bobidi boo"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not the best of Walt Disney's feature length animated films, but any film that has Bibidi Bobbidi Boo and A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes has to rate as good in anyone's standards. I saw this for the first time as a small child on Walt Disney's Disneyland hour and it was as effective on the big screen as well as the small. I don't think there's anyone who is literate in the western world who does not know the story of Cinderella. The story is intact and kept in the mythical medieval times it was written for. As a subplot to the main story we have the story of Cinderella and her relationship with the animals around the house. The pecking order is dog, cat, mice with a horse thrown in for good measure. Naturally the evil stepmother who is voiced by Eleanor Audley has the cat as her favorite. What does that say about us cat lovers. Ilene Woods voices and sings A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes which Perry Como made a big hit record of. Bibidi Bobidi Boo is sung by Verna Felton who voices the Fairy Godmother. She's unforgettable in this role although she's better known as Hilda Crocker, Spring Byington's Ethel Mertz on December Bride. This is one eternal film that I hope my niece let's my new grandnephew check out and his sister or brother to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still a gem and my favourite as a child, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ipacitti
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney's classic Cinderella: My favourite as a child, I would watch it all the time and when I look back. I can't think why.. The animation, the story, the characters, the songs...it's all magical and captivating but when I watched it again not long ago, I was questioning why I thought all of that when I was younger. Disney was still developing and getting into good stories and movie making at the time, it was 1950, so what do you expect from a Disney film at that time period? Snow White was bad so this sort of saved it, it was better and more believable so I guess that's why. But I think Disney didn't suck in all ages to a good DECENT Disney Movie until the 1970's onwards. Sleeping Beauty was 1960 so it wasn't THAT good either. Do you get my gist? The oldest movies were the most boring and less effective, to me, anyway. My goal isn't to discourage anyone from hating this movie because it is in fact a timeless classic, just not as much when you're a hormonal teenager. It's better suited for kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Childhood Classic of My Children and Mine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a small kingdom, the happily child Cinderella loses her beloved mother and his father marries with the cruel Lady Tremaine, who has the mean daughters Drizella and Anastasia. When her father dies, Cinderella becomes a servant in her own house and her stepmother and sisters feels only hatred for her. Cinderella's only friends are four mice, a dog and a horse that live in the house. When the King decides that his son, the Prince, should get married, he invites every maiden in his kingdom to a ball in order that the Prince could choose his bride. However, Cinderella's cruel stepmother does not allow her to attend the ball. When Cinderella is hopeless of going to the Royal Ball, her Fairy Godmother appears and uses magic to help her to make her dream come true. But she must leave the ball before midnight since the magic effect will end. "Cinderella" is one of the classics produced by Disney that belongs not only to my childhood, but also to my daughter and my son's childhoods. This adorable fairytale is wonderful and should be mandatory to every child in the world. I do not have much to say, since I believe that most of the readers certainly know the story of "Cinderella". I feel sorry for those that have written stupid things about this lovely fantasy  what a poor childhood they had. My vote is ten. Title (Brazil): "Cinderela" ("Cinderella")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true Disney classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been so many versions of the Cinderella story that you may be surprised to find that some of the elements that you think are a part of the story are missing. Gone are Buttons and Barron Hardup figures that we see in Pantomime and instead we have a selection of cute animals (this is Disney after all) that will either warm your heart or annoy you badly. Cinderella herself is a typical Disney princess but the film moves along at a quick pace after quite a slow first 20 minutes. For it's age it looks stunning and the humour does not date. Although it probably appeal more to girls than boys there is a lot of fun for them to enjoy in the film as well what with the bumbling king and his servant. Overall a classic Disney film that is well worth seeing to bring back some childhood memories.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinderella" isn't Disney's best, but I think many people will be able to identify with the main character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Walt Disney's 12th full-length animated feature Cinderella (1950) was one of the first movies that I ever saw as a child along with Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937) and Mary Poppins (1964). If there's something we all know from our childhoods, it's that the first few movies we see (especially if they're Disney movies like this) are going to remain in our memories for quite some time. It was a great film to watch as a child, and for the most part, I still liked the film looking back at it as an adult. Unfortunately, due to some serious story flaws, Cinderella doesn't stand the test of time as well as either Snow White or Mary Poppins do. You know the story to this one. A young woman named Cinderella is forced to work as a maid to her evil stepmother and two stepsisters after her father passed away. Despite the terrible treatment she gets all around from them, Cinderella still remains kind and gentle. Furthermore, she at least has a few animal friends in the form of mice, birds, and other animals in the farm nearby. One day, the kingdom announces that the prince has returned and a ball will be held to celebrate this occasion. Every single person is to attend meaning Cinderella is eligible to go. However, her stepmother does not let her go and gives her more chores to do. That's when her fairy godmother comes in and.well, I think it's safe to say that you know the rest, so I won't spoil the rest for whoever hasn't seen it yet. So what issues do I have with Cinderella looking back at it as a young adult? Well, let's discuss the biggest issue I have with the entire film. The film makes the serious mistake of placing at least half the focus of the movie on the side characters rather than on the main characters Cinderella and Prince Charming. I'm particularly disdainful of the fact that more than a quarter of the film is focused on the adventures with the mice and the cat and yet we only see Prince Charming for around 2-3 minutes. Now why did the storytellers of this film feel like this was the right direction to go? They even spend more time on the King and the Grand Duke more than they do with Prince Charming to the point where it should be the King who should be married and not the prince. I realize that it was hard to draw realistic human characters when Snow White was being made and I think the animators did a great job on animating the human halves of the fawns in Fantasia. So there's absolutely no excuse for Disney's storytellers to drop the ball like that on the prince character and deprive him of having any personality, no excuse for that whatsoever. In addition to the prince not having enough screen time or any personality, the mice have way more screen time than they should be having and there's only so much of their over cutesiness that I can take. While these mice characters are at least useful to the main plot some of the time, a film that is titled Cinderella is supposed to be mainly focused on Cinderella, not over 25% focused on a Tom and Jerry like subplot. The high-pitched voices on these mice don't help either. In fact, they make the problem even worse in my opinion. I should probably start analyzing the positive aspects of Cinderella now. Even despite the criticisms that the main character Cinderella gets for not being an assertive enough character, I have to be honest and say that I still liked her enough character wise. I particularly admired how after all the misery she has been put under from her step family, she still maintains her kindness and positivity almost all the time. If that wasn't enough, she also tries to spread that positivity to everybody and every creature around her, so that they can all get along. So for that aspect alone, I think she's a good role model for young girls to look up to. Of course, I thought the stepmother was a well written Disney villain. Who wouldn't think so? She doesn't need any evil laughter to become more intimidating for our main character. The fact that she simply keeps forcing her do more chores and not even give her any credit whatsoever is enough for me. Even though it's a little unusual that more time is spent with the King and the Grand Duke than on the Prince, I still think that they're enjoyable comic relief and they do keep the plot in motion as characters of this nature should be doing. The soundtrack by Oliver Wallace has a couple memorable tunes that I'm sure most of us are familiar with such as "Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo", "Sing Sweet Nightingale", "So This is Love", and "A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes". Though it isn't as richly detailed as the earliest Disney pictures are, the animation here is nice and colorful in its own right. Overall, I think that Cinderella is alright. If this film didn't make the serious storytelling errors that it did and if it focused more on the central characters, then I think Cinderella would be a more timeless Disney picture as a result. But for what it is for the time being, it's still a nice picture with a positive, harmless message for children about the importance of kindness and hard work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classical and A Soft Re-Telling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KatherinePetersdorf
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did enjoy this movie when I was a child. It was great at such a young idea to believe in love at first sight. I also enjoyed the ideal that a girl who was worthless and nothing could become someone amazing and marry the perfect man. I didn't enjoy her singing voice, though. I thought the vocal actress for singing was too high, my ears are sensitive and high soprano doesn't float my boat. I kind of enjoyed the second Cinderella more, it was probably because I was overwhelmed by the original story. When I was young I read the Grimms version, with the cut off of parts of the step sister's feet to wear the shoes, and all the other gore, but Disney did a good job of making it nice. I preferred Dark though :P
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that great... feels like tom and jerry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jumpelaj
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really wanted to like this movie but it is not romantic or classic. It adds nothing to the basic story of Cinderella that we have always heard. The scenes are very pretty and the animation is very good but the most part of the film focuses on the mouse-friends of Cinderella and the mean cat belonging to the step mother. It feels like tom and jerry and by the end of the film you are too tired of watching the animal characters. As another reviewer has mentioned there is no background given of Cinderella or any insight into who she is or what she is all about and no screen time what so ever to the prince himself. It starts well and then gets very very bland. The fairy Godmother is very lovable and so is the King but there is nothing that Cinderella herself brings to the movie. I would recommend watching Enchanted instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another childhood classic from Disney
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Along with 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' 'Cinderella' was one of my favourite Disney films as a child. This film was engaging for the most part, but I feel that the announcement of the ball took longer than it should have done due to a somewhat overlong segment of Cinderella doing her duties and a couple of the scenes involving the king and the duke were slightly irrelevant to the film's main plot. The mice were hard to understand when I heard them speak for the first time in this film for several years but they were cute, funny and active supporting characters nonetheless. Also the film's location setting (probably a toss-up between France and the Netherlands) and time period are hard to determine. The ending was rushed yet memorable with some twists and turns leading up to it. The best aspects of this film were the prologue that consists of a moving back-story of Cinderella and her step-family; beautiful illustrations; very young versions of Cinderella and her stepsisters and simple animation, which got better as the film progressed; the memorable songs (In particular the opening song, 'A Dream is a Wish,' 'Sing Sweet Nightingale,' the brief song sung by the mice before they made Cinderella's dress, 'Bibbidy Bobbidy Boo' and the song that plays when Cinderella dances with the prince); the bubble sequence during 'Sing Sweet Nightingale;' the dressmaking scene and the Fairy Godmother scene. In conclusion, this film isn't quite as enjoyable as 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' but it was worth another look after several years. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1st out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After spending most of the 1940s with package films, Disney was on turmoil with this last film and if it was successful, they would make more movies but if they were not, they would close the studio, and this film was a big hit in 1950. The story is about a young woman named Cinderella who has become a servant in her own home by her own stepmother. When the royal family throws a ball for Prince Charming's return, Cinderella sneaks out of her house to go to the ball, and unknowingly bumps into Prince Charming. The plot is not the most complicated, as it is practically the same as the fairy tale, but they perform it so well. The characters are also very interesting, except Prince Charming. Cinderella is a nice, genuine, spunky (for the classic princesses), level eased girl. Lady Tremaine is a crude, selfish, manipulative villain, who has so much impact in everything she is doing; great villain. The stepsisters are Lady Tremaine's pawns, but their foolish, bratty behaviour is hilarious. The King is extremely cold and enjoyable at the same time, but he does not come off as extremely threatening. Prince Charming is barely in the movie, and faces the same problems that Snow's Prince had (they could not animate a realistic male character yet). The mice are cute, fun characters that provide our comic relief. The songs, everybody remembers them, from "A Dream is a Wish Your Heart Makes", "Bibbidi Bobbidi Bo", "So This Is Love", etc. they are so soothing, and not overly energetic and fast. Disney's most memorable songs are in this movie. The animation is top notch. It is so stylistic, and the backgrounds are so beautiful. Cinderella's design, as all the other characters (excluding Prince Charming) are designed really well, and Disney really got the character movements down. This is one of the best animated movies they have ever done. Everything flows well with this movie, and the only thing that I wish would have been better is if they took away some of the scenes with the mice, so we could have seen more of what the royals were thinking, but this movie is practically flawless. This film is perfect for the entire family. Little girls will like the dresses and mice, boys will love the slapstick humour, and the adults will enjoy the animation, story, and the undertones of the movies. You should definitely give this movie a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a charming and beautifully made animated film. "Cinderella" is everything that an animated fairy-tale should be. It was delightful and highly enjoyable from beginning to end, showing in every single scene form this movie a "magic" that most of the animated films from the recent years lack, with wonderful designs and a exquisite level of detail in every frame. Personally, I consider this movie to be the best adaptation of the classic fairy tale written by Charles Perrault. Movies like "Cinderella" shows why the time when this was made was considered "The Golden Age of Animation".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The thing-a-ma-bob that does the job is bibidi bobidi boo"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not the best of Walt Disney's feature length animated films, but any film that has Bibidi Bobbidi Boo and A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes has to rate as good in anyone's standards. I saw this for the first time as a small child on Walt Disney's Disneyland hour and it was as effective on the big screen as well as the small. I don't think there's anyone who is literate in the western world who does not know the story of Cinderella. The story is intact and kept in the mythical medieval times it was written for. As a subplot to the main story we have the story of Cinderella and her relationship with the animals around the house. The pecking order is dog, cat, mice with a horse thrown in for good measure. Naturally the evil stepmother who is voiced by Eleanor Audley has the cat as her favorite. What does that say about us cat lovers. Ilene Woods voices and sings A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes which Perry Como made a big hit record of. Bibidi Bobidi Boo is sung by Verna Felton who voices the Fairy Godmother. She's unforgettable in this role although she's better known as Hilda Crocker, Spring Byington's Ethel Mertz on December Bride. This is one eternal film that I hope my niece let's my new grandnephew check out and his sister or brother to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still a gem and my favourite as a child, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ipacitti
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney's classic Cinderella: My favourite as a child, I would watch it all the time and when I look back. I can't think why.. The animation, the story, the characters, the songs...it's all magical and captivating but when I watched it again not long ago, I was questioning why I thought all of that when I was younger. Disney was still developing and getting into good stories and movie making at the time, it was 1950, so what do you expect from a Disney film at that time period? Snow White was bad so this sort of saved it, it was better and more believable so I guess that's why. But I think Disney didn't suck in all ages to a good DECENT Disney Movie until the 1970's onwards. Sleeping Beauty was 1960 so it wasn't THAT good either. Do you get my gist? The oldest movies were the most boring and less effective, to me, anyway. My goal isn't to discourage anyone from hating this movie because it is in fact a timeless classic, just not as much when you're a hormonal teenager. It's better suited for kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Childhood Classic of My Children and Mine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a small kingdom, the happily child Cinderella loses her beloved mother and his father marries with the cruel Lady Tremaine, who has the mean daughters Drizella and Anastasia. When her father dies, Cinderella becomes a servant in her own house and her stepmother and sisters feels only hatred for her. Cinderella's only friends are four mice, a dog and a horse that live in the house. When the King decides that his son, the Prince, should get married, he invites every maiden in his kingdom to a ball in order that the Prince could choose his bride. However, Cinderella's cruel stepmother does not allow her to attend the ball. When Cinderella is hopeless of going to the Royal Ball, her Fairy Godmother appears and uses magic to help her to make her dream come true. But she must leave the ball before midnight since the magic effect will end. "Cinderella" is one of the classics produced by Disney that belongs not only to my childhood, but also to my daughter and my son's childhoods. This adorable fairytale is wonderful and should be mandatory to every child in the world. I do not have much to say, since I believe that most of the readers certainly know the story of "Cinderella". I feel sorry for those that have written stupid things about this lovely fantasy  what a poor childhood they had. My vote is ten. Title (Brazil): "Cinderela" ("Cinderella")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true Disney classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been so many versions of the Cinderella story that you may be surprised to find that some of the elements that you think are a part of the story are missing. Gone are Buttons and Barron Hardup figures that we see in Pantomime and instead we have a selection of cute animals (this is Disney after all) that will either warm your heart or annoy you badly. Cinderella herself is a typical Disney princess but the film moves along at a quick pace after quite a slow first 20 minutes. For it's age it looks stunning and the humour does not date. Although it probably appeal more to girls than boys there is a lot of fun for them to enjoy in the film as well what with the bumbling king and his servant. Overall a classic Disney film that is well worth seeing to bring back some childhood memories.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinderella" isn't Disney's best, but I think many people will be able to identify with the main character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Walt Disney's 12th full-length animated feature Cinderella (1950) was one of the first movies that I ever saw as a child along with Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937) and Mary Poppins (1964). If there's something we all know from our childhoods, it's that the first few movies we see (especially if they're Disney movies like this) are going to remain in our memories for quite some time. It was a great film to watch as a child, and for the most part, I still liked the film looking back at it as an adult. Unfortunately, due to some serious story flaws, Cinderella doesn't stand the test of time as well as either Snow White or Mary Poppins do. You know the story to this one. A young woman named Cinderella is forced to work as a maid to her evil stepmother and two stepsisters after her father passed away. Despite the terrible treatment she gets all around from them, Cinderella still remains kind and gentle. Furthermore, she at least has a few animal friends in the form of mice, birds, and other animals in the farm nearby. One day, the kingdom announces that the prince has returned and a ball will be held to celebrate this occasion. Every single person is to attend meaning Cinderella is eligible to go. However, her stepmother does not let her go and gives her more chores to do. That's when her fairy godmother comes in and.well, I think it's safe to say that you know the rest, so I won't spoil the rest for whoever hasn't seen it yet. So what issues do I have with Cinderella looking back at it as a young adult? Well, let's discuss the biggest issue I have with the entire film. The film makes the serious mistake of placing at least half the focus of the movie on the side characters rather than on the main characters Cinderella and Prince Charming. I'm particularly disdainful of the fact that more than a quarter of the film is focused on the adventures with the mice and the cat and yet we only see Prince Charming for around 2-3 minutes. Now why did the storytellers of this film feel like this was the right direction to go? They even spend more time on the King and the Grand Duke more than they do with Prince Charming to the point where it should be the King who should be married and not the prince. I realize that it was hard to draw realistic human characters when Snow White was being made and I think the animators did a great job on animating the human halves of the fawns in Fantasia. So there's absolutely no excuse for Disney's storytellers to drop the ball like that on the prince character and deprive him of having any personality, no excuse for that whatsoever. In addition to the prince not having enough screen time or any personality, the mice have way more screen time than they should be having and there's only so much of their over cutesiness that I can take. While these mice characters are at least useful to the main plot some of the time, a film that is titled Cinderella is supposed to be mainly focused on Cinderella, not over 25% focused on a Tom and Jerry like subplot. The high-pitched voices on these mice don't help either. In fact, they make the problem even worse in my opinion. I should probably start analyzing the positive aspects of Cinderella now. Even despite the criticisms that the main character Cinderella gets for not being an assertive enough character, I have to be honest and say that I still liked her enough character wise. I particularly admired how after all the misery she has been put under from her step family, she still maintains her kindness and positivity almost all the time. If that wasn't enough, she also tries to spread that positivity to everybody and every creature around her, so that they can all get along. So for that aspect alone, I think she's a good role model for young girls to look up to. Of course, I thought the stepmother was a well written Disney villain. Who wouldn't think so? She doesn't need any evil laughter to become more intimidating for our main character. The fact that she simply keeps forcing her do more chores and not even give her any credit whatsoever is enough for me. Even though it's a little unusual that more time is spent with the King and the Grand Duke than on the Prince, I still think that they're enjoyable comic relief and they do keep the plot in motion as characters of this nature should be doing. The soundtrack by Oliver Wallace has a couple memorable tunes that I'm sure most of us are familiar with such as "Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo", "Sing Sweet Nightingale", "So This is Love", and "A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes". Though it isn't as richly detailed as the earliest Disney pictures are, the animation here is nice and colorful in its own right. Overall, I think that Cinderella is alright. If this film didn't make the serious storytelling errors that it did and if it focused more on the central characters, then I think Cinderella would be a more timeless Disney picture as a result. But for what it is for the time being, it's still a nice picture with a positive, harmless message for children about the importance of kindness and hard work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classical and A Soft Re-Telling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KatherinePetersdorf
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did enjoy this movie when I was a child. It was great at such a young idea to believe in love at first sight. I also enjoyed the ideal that a girl who was worthless and nothing could become someone amazing and marry the perfect man. I didn't enjoy her singing voice, though. I thought the vocal actress for singing was too high, my ears are sensitive and high soprano doesn't float my boat. I kind of enjoyed the second Cinderella more, it was probably because I was overwhelmed by the original story. When I was young I read the Grimms version, with the cut off of parts of the step sister's feet to wear the shoes, and all the other gore, but Disney did a good job of making it nice. I preferred Dark though :P
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that great... feels like tom and jerry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jumpelaj
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really wanted to like this movie but it is not romantic or classic. It adds nothing to the basic story of Cinderella that we have always heard. The scenes are very pretty and the animation is very good but the most part of the film focuses on the mouse-friends of Cinderella and the mean cat belonging to the step mother. It feels like tom and jerry and by the end of the film you are too tired of watching the animal characters. As another reviewer has mentioned there is no background given of Cinderella or any insight into who she is or what she is all about and no screen time what so ever to the prince himself. It starts well and then gets very very bland. The fairy Godmother is very lovable and so is the King but there is nothing that Cinderella herself brings to the movie. I would recommend watching Enchanted instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another childhood classic from Disney
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Along with 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' 'Cinderella' was one of my favourite Disney films as a child. This film was engaging for the most part, but I feel that the announcement of the ball took longer than it should have done due to a somewhat overlong segment of Cinderella doing her duties and a couple of the scenes involving the king and the duke were slightly irrelevant to the film's main plot. The mice were hard to understand when I heard them speak for the first time in this film for several years but they were cute, funny and active supporting characters nonetheless. Also the film's location setting (probably a toss-up between France and the Netherlands) and time period are hard to determine. The ending was rushed yet memorable with some twists and turns leading up to it. The best aspects of this film were the prologue that consists of a moving back-story of Cinderella and her step-family; beautiful illustrations; very young versions of Cinderella and her stepsisters and simple animation, which got better as the film progressed; the memorable songs (In particular the opening song, 'A Dream is a Wish,' 'Sing Sweet Nightingale,' the brief song sung by the mice before they made Cinderella's dress, 'Bibbidy Bobbidy Boo' and the song that plays when Cinderella dances with the prince); the bubble sequence during 'Sing Sweet Nightingale;' the dressmaking scene and the Fairy Godmother scene. In conclusion, this film isn't quite as enjoyable as 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' but it was worth another look after several years. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1st out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After spending most of the 1940s with package films, Disney was on turmoil with this last film and if it was successful, they would make more movies but if they were not, they would close the studio, and this film was a big hit in 1950. The story is about a young woman named Cinderella who has become a servant in her own home by her own stepmother. When the royal family throws a ball for Prince Charming's return, Cinderella sneaks out of her house to go to the ball, and unknowingly bumps into Prince Charming. The plot is not the most complicated, as it is practically the same as the fairy tale, but they perform it so well. The characters are also very interesting, except Prince Charming. Cinderella is a nice, genuine, spunky (for the classic princesses), level eased girl. Lady Tremaine is a crude, selfish, manipulative villain, who has so much impact in everything she is doing; great villain. The stepsisters are Lady Tremaine's pawns, but their foolish, bratty behaviour is hilarious. The King is extremely cold and enjoyable at the same time, but he does not come off as extremely threatening. Prince Charming is barely in the movie, and faces the same problems that Snow's Prince had (they could not animate a realistic male character yet). The mice are cute, fun characters that provide our comic relief. The songs, everybody remembers them, from "A Dream is a Wish Your Heart Makes", "Bibbidi Bobbidi Bo", "So This Is Love", etc. they are so soothing, and not overly energetic and fast. Disney's most memorable songs are in this movie. The animation is top notch. It is so stylistic, and the backgrounds are so beautiful. Cinderella's design, as all the other characters (excluding Prince Charming) are designed really well, and Disney really got the character movements down. This is one of the best animated movies they have ever done. Everything flows well with this movie, and the only thing that I wish would have been better is if they took away some of the scenes with the mice, so we could have seen more of what the royals were thinking, but this movie is practically flawless. This film is perfect for the entire family. Little girls will like the dresses and mice, boys will love the slapstick humour, and the adults will enjoy the animation, story, and the undertones of the movies. You should definitely give this movie a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a charming and beautifully made animated film. "Cinderella" is everything that an animated fairy-tale should be. It was delightful and highly enjoyable from beginning to end, showing in every single scene form this movie a "magic" that most of the animated films from the recent years lack, with wonderful designs and a exquisite level of detail in every frame. Personally, I consider this movie to be the best adaptation of the classic fairy tale written by Charles Perrault. Movies like "Cinderella" shows why the time when this was made was considered "The Golden Age of Animation".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The thing-a-ma-bob that does the job is bibidi bobidi boo"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not the best of Walt Disney's feature length animated films, but any film that has Bibidi Bobbidi Boo and A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes has to rate as good in anyone's standards. I saw this for the first time as a small child on Walt Disney's Disneyland hour and it was as effective on the big screen as well as the small. I don't think there's anyone who is literate in the western world who does not know the story of Cinderella. The story is intact and kept in the mythical medieval times it was written for. As a subplot to the main story we have the story of Cinderella and her relationship with the animals around the house. The pecking order is dog, cat, mice with a horse thrown in for good measure. Naturally the evil stepmother who is voiced by Eleanor Audley has the cat as her favorite. What does that say about us cat lovers. Ilene Woods voices and sings A Dream Is A Wish Your Heart Makes which Perry Como made a big hit record of. Bibidi Bobidi Boo is sung by Verna Felton who voices the Fairy Godmother. She's unforgettable in this role although she's better known as Hilda Crocker, Spring Byington's Ethel Mertz on December Bride. This is one eternal film that I hope my niece let's my new grandnephew check out and his sister or brother to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still a gem and my favourite as a child, but...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ipacitti
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney's classic Cinderella: My favourite as a child, I would watch it all the time and when I look back. I can't think why.. The animation, the story, the characters, the songs...it's all magical and captivating but when I watched it again not long ago, I was questioning why I thought all of that when I was younger. Disney was still developing and getting into good stories and movie making at the time, it was 1950, so what do you expect from a Disney film at that time period? Snow White was bad so this sort of saved it, it was better and more believable so I guess that's why. But I think Disney didn't suck in all ages to a good DECENT Disney Movie until the 1970's onwards. Sleeping Beauty was 1960 so it wasn't THAT good either. Do you get my gist? The oldest movies were the most boring and less effective, to me, anyway. My goal isn't to discourage anyone from hating this movie because it is in fact a timeless classic, just not as much when you're a hormonal teenager. It's better suited for kids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Childhood Classic of My Children and Mine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In a small kingdom, the happily child Cinderella loses her beloved mother and his father marries with the cruel Lady Tremaine, who has the mean daughters Drizella and Anastasia. When her father dies, Cinderella becomes a servant in her own house and her stepmother and sisters feels only hatred for her. Cinderella's only friends are four mice, a dog and a horse that live in the house. When the King decides that his son, the Prince, should get married, he invites every maiden in his kingdom to a ball in order that the Prince could choose his bride. However, Cinderella's cruel stepmother does not allow her to attend the ball. When Cinderella is hopeless of going to the Royal Ball, her Fairy Godmother appears and uses magic to help her to make her dream come true. But she must leave the ball before midnight since the magic effect will end. "Cinderella" is one of the classics produced by Disney that belongs not only to my childhood, but also to my daughter and my son's childhoods. This adorable fairytale is wonderful and should be mandatory to every child in the world. I do not have much to say, since I believe that most of the readers certainly know the story of "Cinderella". I feel sorry for those that have written stupid things about this lovely fantasy  what a poor childhood they had. My vote is ten. Title (Brazil): "Cinderela" ("Cinderella")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true Disney classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A56T
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been so many versions of the Cinderella story that you may be surprised to find that some of the elements that you think are a part of the story are missing. Gone are Buttons and Barron Hardup figures that we see in Pantomime and instead we have a selection of cute animals (this is Disney after all) that will either warm your heart or annoy you badly. Cinderella herself is a typical Disney princess but the film moves along at a quick pace after quite a slow first 20 minutes. For it's age it looks stunning and the humour does not date. Although it probably appeal more to girls than boys there is a lot of fun for them to enjoy in the film as well what with the bumbling king and his servant. Overall a classic Disney film that is well worth seeing to bring back some childhood memories.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Cinderella" isn't Disney's best, but I think many people will be able to identify with the main character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Walt Disney's 12th full-length animated feature Cinderella (1950) was one of the first movies that I ever saw as a child along with Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937) and Mary Poppins (1964). If there's something we all know from our childhoods, it's that the first few movies we see (especially if they're Disney movies like this) are going to remain in our memories for quite some time. It was a great film to watch as a child, and for the most part, I still liked the film looking back at it as an adult. Unfortunately, due to some serious story flaws, Cinderella doesn't stand the test of time as well as either Snow White or Mary Poppins do. You know the story to this one. A young woman named Cinderella is forced to work as a maid to her evil stepmother and two stepsisters after her father passed away. Despite the terrible treatment she gets all around from them, Cinderella still remains kind and gentle. Furthermore, she at least has a few animal friends in the form of mice, birds, and other animals in the farm nearby. One day, the kingdom announces that the prince has returned and a ball will be held to celebrate this occasion. Every single person is to attend meaning Cinderella is eligible to go. However, her stepmother does not let her go and gives her more chores to do. That's when her fairy godmother comes in and.well, I think it's safe to say that you know the rest, so I won't spoil the rest for whoever hasn't seen it yet. So what issues do I have with Cinderella looking back at it as a young adult? Well, let's discuss the biggest issue I have with the entire film. The film makes the serious mistake of placing at least half the focus of the movie on the side characters rather than on the main characters Cinderella and Prince Charming. I'm particularly disdainful of the fact that more than a quarter of the film is focused on the adventures with the mice and the cat and yet we only see Prince Charming for around 2-3 minutes. Now why did the storytellers of this film feel like this was the right direction to go? They even spend more time on the King and the Grand Duke more than they do with Prince Charming to the point where it should be the King who should be married and not the prince. I realize that it was hard to draw realistic human characters when Snow White was being made and I think the animators did a great job on animating the human halves of the fawns in Fantasia. So there's absolutely no excuse for Disney's storytellers to drop the ball like that on the prince character and deprive him of having any personality, no excuse for that whatsoever. In addition to the prince not having enough screen time or any personality, the mice have way more screen time than they should be having and there's only so much of their over cutesiness that I can take. While these mice characters are at least useful to the main plot some of the time, a film that is titled Cinderella is supposed to be mainly focused on Cinderella, not over 25% focused on a Tom and Jerry like subplot. The high-pitched voices on these mice don't help either. In fact, they make the problem even worse in my opinion. I should probably start analyzing the positive aspects of Cinderella now. Even despite the criticisms that the main character Cinderella gets for not being an assertive enough character, I have to be honest and say that I still liked her enough character wise. I particularly admired how after all the misery she has been put under from her step family, she still maintains her kindness and positivity almost all the time. If that wasn't enough, she also tries to spread that positivity to everybody and every creature around her, so that they can all get along. So for that aspect alone, I think she's a good role model for young girls to look up to. Of course, I thought the stepmother was a well written Disney villain. Who wouldn't think so? She doesn't need any evil laughter to become more intimidating for our main character. The fact that she simply keeps forcing her do more chores and not even give her any credit whatsoever is enough for me. Even though it's a little unusual that more time is spent with the King and the Grand Duke than on the Prince, I still think that they're enjoyable comic relief and they do keep the plot in motion as characters of this nature should be doing. The soundtrack by Oliver Wallace has a couple memorable tunes that I'm sure most of us are familiar with such as "Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo", "Sing Sweet Nightingale", "So This is Love", and "A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes". Though it isn't as richly detailed as the earliest Disney pictures are, the animation here is nice and colorful in its own right. Overall, I think that Cinderella is alright. If this film didn't make the serious storytelling errors that it did and if it focused more on the central characters, then I think Cinderella would be a more timeless Disney picture as a result. But for what it is for the time being, it's still a nice picture with a positive, harmless message for children about the importance of kindness and hard work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classical and A Soft Re-Telling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KatherinePetersdorf
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did enjoy this movie when I was a child. It was great at such a young idea to believe in love at first sight. I also enjoyed the ideal that a girl who was worthless and nothing could become someone amazing and marry the perfect man. I didn't enjoy her singing voice, though. I thought the vocal actress for singing was too high, my ears are sensitive and high soprano doesn't float my boat. I kind of enjoyed the second Cinderella more, it was probably because I was overwhelmed by the original story. When I was young I read the Grimms version, with the cut off of parts of the step sister's feet to wear the shoes, and all the other gore, but Disney did a good job of making it nice. I preferred Dark though :P
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that great... feels like tom and jerry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jumpelaj
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really wanted to like this movie but it is not romantic or classic. It adds nothing to the basic story of Cinderella that we have always heard. The scenes are very pretty and the animation is very good but the most part of the film focuses on the mouse-friends of Cinderella and the mean cat belonging to the step mother. It feels like tom and jerry and by the end of the film you are too tired of watching the animal characters. As another reviewer has mentioned there is no background given of Cinderella or any insight into who she is or what she is all about and no screen time what so ever to the prince himself. It starts well and then gets very very bland. The fairy Godmother is very lovable and so is the King but there is nothing that Cinderella herself brings to the movie. I would recommend watching Enchanted instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another childhood classic from Disney
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Along with 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' 'Cinderella' was one of my favourite Disney films as a child. This film was engaging for the most part, but I feel that the announcement of the ball took longer than it should have done due to a somewhat overlong segment of Cinderella doing her duties and a couple of the scenes involving the king and the duke were slightly irrelevant to the film's main plot. The mice were hard to understand when I heard them speak for the first time in this film for several years but they were cute, funny and active supporting characters nonetheless. Also the film's location setting (probably a toss-up between France and the Netherlands) and time period are hard to determine. The ending was rushed yet memorable with some twists and turns leading up to it. The best aspects of this film were the prologue that consists of a moving back-story of Cinderella and her step-family; beautiful illustrations; very young versions of Cinderella and her stepsisters and simple animation, which got better as the film progressed; the memorable songs (In particular the opening song, 'A Dream is a Wish,' 'Sing Sweet Nightingale,' the brief song sung by the mice before they made Cinderella's dress, 'Bibbidy Bobbidy Boo' and the song that plays when Cinderella dances with the prince); the bubble sequence during 'Sing Sweet Nightingale;' the dressmaking scene and the Fairy Godmother scene. In conclusion, this film isn't quite as enjoyable as 'Peter Pan' and 'The Little Mermaid,' but it was worth another look after several years. 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1st out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After spending most of the 1940s with package films, Disney was on turmoil with this last film and if it was successful, they would make more movies but if they were not, they would close the studio, and this film was a big hit in 1950. The story is about a young woman named Cinderella who has become a servant in her own home by her own stepmother. When the royal family throws a ball for Prince Charming's return, Cinderella sneaks out of her house to go to the ball, and unknowingly bumps into Prince Charming. The plot is not the most complicated, as it is practically the same as the fairy tale, but they perform it so well. The characters are also very interesting, except Prince Charming. Cinderella is a nice, genuine, spunky (for the classic princesses), level eased girl. Lady Tremaine is a crude, selfish, manipulative villain, who has so much impact in everything she is doing; great villain. The stepsisters are Lady Tremaine's pawns, but their foolish, bratty behaviour is hilarious. The King is extremely cold and enjoyable at the same time, but he does not come off as extremely threatening. Prince Charming is barely in the movie, and faces the same problems that Snow's Prince had (they could not animate a realistic male character yet). The mice are cute, fun characters that provide our comic relief. The songs, everybody remembers them, from "A Dream is a Wish Your Heart Makes", "Bibbidi Bobbidi Bo", "So This Is Love", etc. they are so soothing, and not overly energetic and fast. Disney's most memorable songs are in this movie. The animation is top notch. It is so stylistic, and the backgrounds are so beautiful. Cinderella's design, as all the other characters (excluding Prince Charming) are designed really well, and Disney really got the character movements down. This is one of the best animated movies they have ever done. Everything flows well with this movie, and the only thing that I wish would have been better is if they took away some of the scenes with the mice, so we could have seen more of what the royals were thinking, but this movie is practically flawless. This film is perfect for the entire family. Little girls will like the dresses and mice, boys will love the slapstick humour, and the adults will enjoy the animation, story, and the undertones of the movies. You should definitely give this movie a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was such a charming and beautifully made animated film. "Cinderella" is everything that an animated fairy-tale should be. It was delightful and highly enjoyable from beginning to end, showing in every single scene form this movie a "magic" that most of the animated films from the recent years lack, with wonderful designs and a exquisite level of detail in every frame. Personally, I consider this movie to be the best adaptation of the classic fairy tale written by Charles Perrault. Movies like "Cinderella" shows why the time when this was made was considered "The Golden Age of Animation".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
