<filme>
 <id>
  422
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115491
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Aladdin e os 40 Ladr&otilde;es (Vide
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  At long last, Aladdin is about to marry the Princess Jasmine. Despite the presence and encouragement of his friends Genie, Carpet, and Abu, he is fearful and anxious. He is most worried as ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  At long last, Aladdin is about to marry the Princess Jasmine. Despite the presence and encouragement of his friends Genie, Carpet, and Abu, he is fearful and anxious. He is most worried as to what kind of father he will be, having never known his own. But when the 40 Thieves disrupt the wedding trying to steal a magical oracular talisman, Aladdin is drawn into a dangerous quest to stop the thieves...and find his long-lost father.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Animation
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   wedding
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   genie
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   princess
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   midas touch
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   reference to bing crosby
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Tad Stones
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Mark McCorkle
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Robert Schooley
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Scott Weinger
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robin Williams
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Rhys-Davies
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arabian night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I was a kid insanely in love with 1994's "The Return of Jafar". I watched thousand of times with every relative that came into home. Last weeks I was surfing channels on cable and saw "Aladdin and the King of Thieves" passing, which made me wonder: "Have I ever seen that picture?". So I decided it would be a good idea to watch this, you know, just in case. I can state this movie is very creative, with some eventual funny lines-- mainly coming from Genie, I admit it. There are some nice songs to entertaining the spectator instead of telling a never ending story. Sometimes the relationship Aladdin has with his father looks too shallow for a children movie, but it doesn't spoil the movie's overall quality. Princess Jasmine sometimes is forgotten and she barely comes up in the screen. Director makes some metalinguistic scenes with reference to other Disney movies, providing an old spectator like me (I'm 21) a nostalgic feeling. All in all, this isn't as great as 1994's installment, but does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really enjoyed this movie and it took me until NOW to see it where have I been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisafordeay
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie today and let me tell ya I laughed so much at it why because Robin Williams is in this movie better than ever YEAH. The film chronicles on Aladdin's big day with Jasmine,but problems arise when Aladdin's long lost father returns and he is working for the King Of Thieves(hence the title). So its up to Aladdin to track him down and help him retrive this golden hand that he is looking for. The animation is great(and hey I never knew there was a studio Down Under eh LOL),the songs are good I liked the first song There's a Party Here In Agrabah as well as Out Of Thin Air. The impressions are so funny I laughed when I saw the Mrs Doubtfire one and the Rocky Balboa one too. Overall if you liked the first Aladdin then sit back,relax and enjoy the epic finally of Aladdin which is one of my all time favourite movies ever. And even at the age of 22 I still love this movie. Can you imagine it took me 22 years to see this film even though it was made in 1996 and I was 6 years old at the time and it took me till now to see it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not on par with the original, but way better than Return of Jafar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having been disappointed with Return of Jafar, I thought that this might even be worse than that film. Boy, was I wrong. Sure, it's not on par with the original classic, but it's in my opinion a slight improvement over ROJ. There are some color changes and it could've been a little bit longer, but those flaws doesn't matter. What really matters is that it brought a nostalgic feeling to the original film by being an even better DTV Disney sequel than others. The story is very original and the father-son relation worked really well throughout the entire film. The animation is beautiful and fluid with some nice visual scenery especially the island that had the Hand of Midas which is by far the strongest aspect of the animation along with it's fine character designs. The characters are likable and the voice acting is neat especially the new cameos John Rhys Davis and Jerry Orbach (Lumiere from Beauty and the Beast is in this, by the way). The songs aren't on par with the songs from the original film, but they're still a lot of fun to listen to. Overall, not excellent, but a slight improvement over Return of Jafar and totally recommended to others who have not seen it yet!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Done on the cheap
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EpeeBill
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like how Disney expanded their version of the Aladdin story in their TV series and the direct to DVD sequels, but this one kind of let me down. The voice acting is great and I really liked the music, but the quality of the animation is quite poor by Disney standards. Normally, I wouldn't be so particular about the art but the drop in quality from the first movie, to the TV show to this sequel is precipitous. The color palette is so muted it seems like the animators were told only to use a maximum of 16 throughout the entire running time. The familiar characters are still quite recognizable, but they all lack detail and depth that you come to expect from Disney. I know that the direct-to-DVD products are given smaller budgets, but that doesn't justify just how cheap this movie looks. There are still lots of redeeming parts of this movie, but the lack of visual polish is too distracting for me to enjoy them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far too US orientated (spoiler included)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gdcox
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't watch this if you are not American as they have tried to make all the humour colloquial machine gun US and tragically succeeded. The concept of a genie as a permanent character with unlimited assistance is absurd both in terms of the original story and the fact that he could have whipped the opposition after five minute, but somehow doesn't bother enough. Concept of bad father and struggle of same interacting with the son is very good though far too subtle for any child under ten I would suggest and end the end of the day is bad role model for the young. Technically, seems fine. I don't know why I am forced to do ten lines when a film is so bad. This policy should be reviewed. Five lines is more than enough for a film rated bad by the reviewer .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tolly Maggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people argue over which is better: Return of Jafar or King of Thieves. To be more specific, they actually argue over which one is WORSE. When I watched this film, both as a child and an adult, I didn't see much wrong with it. In fact, I really enjoyed it! The animation had picked up again to a fantastic standard compared to the last movie, with quality only dropping in short moments. However, while the animation didn't quite seem to stay on par at all moments, I thought the music was sublime. Very emotional music which is used to convey emotions successfully in creative dramatic ways. One example of this would be in Aladdin's fight to join the thieves. Most of the diegetic sound drops out, leaving only the sounds of fire and lighting, leaving the music to convey the process of emotions running through the characters: Sa'luk's thirst for Alladin's blood to vent his rage for Cassim, Cassim's fear of losing the son he only just found, and Aladdin's desperation to survive. Very creative and poetic, with similarly poetic scenes later in the film. Although the characters' goals and reasons for alternating in decisions can be confusing, if you keep up with it it remains logical and the narrative successfully develops. The narrative kept me interested, and I thought it worked being a short film (Just over an hour). The plot doesn't drag too much, there is often a sense in development in both the story and the characters, and the action is meaningful. One other part of this film which is always entertaining is the genie's (Robin Williams') small 'sketches' that, while they seem to stray from the plot, are very entertaining, witty and comical. It was clear Williams had a lot of contribution to his character and the jokes that were made. Overall, I found this film very entertaining: Both as a child and an adult.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than The Return Of Jafar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So Aladdin and Jasmine are getting married (finally) and their wedding is crashed by the 40 thieves who are there to steal a magical oracle that allows anyone who has it to ask it one question. The King of Thieves wants to know where the magical hand of Midus is. Aladdin finds out the King of thieves is his father and they find the hand of Midas together. The hand of Midas was the only thing cool about this film, some of Robin Williams improvised stuff is funny as well. It had even worse quality than the last one and looked low budget and about neck and neck with the TV show as far as quality goes. I was glad to see CCH Pounder as the voice of the oracle and that was a bonus, but nothing can save this film for me, it was really boring, kids might enjoy it if they don't require too much to entertain them. 2/10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK straight to video 3rd entry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dwpollar
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1st watched 2/14/2010 -- 4 out of 10(Dir-Tad Stones): OK straight to video 3rd entry in the Walt Disney Aladdin series tries hard to be like the Disney movies of old that we love(but that's also it's problem -- it tries too hard!!) It has the many songs, the good guy-bad guy theme, and the guy gets the girl scenario but it obviously has less heart and funds to pull it off. It was made by the TV animation studio and it kind of has that look and feel to it with it's incomplete, un-realistic backgrounds but otherwise looks OK. Robin Williams as the Genie is funny at times(but overbearing at others)and some of the other minor characters brings some laughs but the movie tries to be too grand and too good even though it wasn't meant to be. The story is about Aladdin and Jasmine getting married but is interrupted by the forty thieves. We later find out that Aladdin's father is the king of thieves and he goes on a quest to bring him back and reform him. There is a bad leader of the thieves who keeps fighting with Aladdin's father over the kingship of the thieves, who amazingly is voiced by Jerry Orbach, in a very different role for him. They are then lured to the ultimate treasure of Midas's hand by an oracle and they eventually have to decide what's really important(the treasure or the people). As most Disney films, it all works itself out in the end but the movie overall doesn't deliver the kind of craftsmanship in the story that usually keeps us interested in a Disney movie. A good try by the TV animators but it's not quite what it could have been. Given a little more money and time it could have been a worthwhile effort but instead it's pretty mediocre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should Have Gotten a Theatrical Release.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerekra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most of the time when straight to video Disney Sequels are made you can understand why the film was not released in theatres. However in the case of Aladdin and the King of Thieves I feel that this film should have been released in the theatres. Aladdin and Jasmine have their wedding interrupted by an attack by the Forty Thieves. Soon Aladdin learns that his father is the King of Thieves. He brings his father back to Agraba hoping that he will reform, however Aladdins father has hopes of finding the ultimate treasure no matter the cost. The artwork for this film is way better than in The Return of Jafar. Also the story is excellent and action packed. One of the main reasons why this film works is the return of Robin Williams. He is as hilarious as ever as the Genie, and actually I think that he is much more funny in this film as opposed to the first Aladdin film. Genie is hilarious in this film and that is the major reason this film is great. Also I like how Aladdin's father is in this film. A great idea and I think that this somewhat is similar to the third Indiana Jones film. Not only is the idea similar but the fact that they got the actor who played Sallah in the Indiana Jones Trilogy (his name escapes me) makes the idea work all that much better. Also there is a good villain in Suluk, a sort of huge evil guy with a sharp claw thing on one of his hands. I guess the one flaw might be the lack of great songs. If they had improved on that a little this film would have been perfect. But I would rather there be great humor, action, and story than a few great songs. If they had improved the artwork a little, and added some awesomer music this would have been a great film to release in theatres. Of all the Disney sequels that have been released straight to video, this is BY FAR the best. I recommend this film greatly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great End to the Trilogy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soodynem
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to say, this is without a doubt one of the only watchable direct-to-video features Disney has ever given us. Now, for those who haven't seen this, and have seen the likes of, oh, I don't know, The Hunchback of Notre Dame II or Tarzan and Jane, you may ask how this is possible. Start with the voice actors. You have the complete original cast back on board (minus Jonathan Freeman, for obvious reasons), plus a few extras. Jasmine may sound slightly different than she used to, but my spies tell me that she is indeed the same actress. John Rhys-Davies provides his voice for Aladdin's father, and the King of Thieves, Cassim. Jerry Orbach (of Beauty and the Beast fame) plays one of the forty thieves, Sa'luk. And finally, the star of the show has returned. I like Dan Castellaneta, and I think he did an acceptable job as the Genie, but Robin Williams is still the best. In fact, William's performance here could be best described as 'unleashed'. The Genie impersonates no less than five Disney characters, including Mickey Mouse himself, becomes an entire army (comprised of SWAT, cavalry, paratroopers, bagpipe men, the ED-209, and Pocahontas), picks up an elephant with his bare hands, and comforts Jasmine as Mrs. Doubtfire, albeit a bearded version. This movie has a coherent plot, which is, you know, strange for a Disney sequel. Some may say it was stolen from 'The Last Crusade' and I'd have to agree. You know, hero meets father, father is looking for some important artifact, appears to love it more than his family, but doesn't. Yeah. Except instead of the Holy Grail, we have this awesome Hand of Midas that can turn anything into gold. The villain foundation is not as good as the original, but Jerry Orbach still manages give us the next best thing with a grey-skinned, muscle-bound, wolverine-claw using man known as Sa'luk. I would rate his death scene as one of the best in cinematic history. Songs Ha. Well they don't measure up to the originals, but they do the best they can do. Genie is so over-the-top with his two songs that it's almost unbelievable, and the forty thieves song is quite entertaining. Just, uh, pretend that you can't hear the sappy song Aladdin and Jasmine sing about his childhood, as it may induce vomiting and/or cancer. After the exercise of utter futility that was 'The Return of Jafar', this movie gives us some of the best direct-to-video animation you'll see out there. It's truly a satisfying film that provide a satisfying ending. While I'd rate 'Aladdin' 9 stars, 'Jafar' would get 2 and this would get 7 to 8. It's that good, check it out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arabian night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I was a kid insanely in love with 1994's "The Return of Jafar". I watched thousand of times with every relative that came into home. Last weeks I was surfing channels on cable and saw "Aladdin and the King of Thieves" passing, which made me wonder: "Have I ever seen that picture?". So I decided it would be a good idea to watch this, you know, just in case. I can state this movie is very creative, with some eventual funny lines-- mainly coming from Genie, I admit it. There are some nice songs to entertaining the spectator instead of telling a never ending story. Sometimes the relationship Aladdin has with his father looks too shallow for a children movie, but it doesn't spoil the movie's overall quality. Princess Jasmine sometimes is forgotten and she barely comes up in the screen. Director makes some metalinguistic scenes with reference to other Disney movies, providing an old spectator like me (I'm 21) a nostalgic feeling. All in all, this isn't as great as 1994's installment, but does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really enjoyed this movie and it took me until NOW to see it where have I been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisafordeay
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie today and let me tell ya I laughed so much at it why because Robin Williams is in this movie better than ever YEAH. The film chronicles on Aladdin's big day with Jasmine,but problems arise when Aladdin's long lost father returns and he is working for the King Of Thieves(hence the title). So its up to Aladdin to track him down and help him retrive this golden hand that he is looking for. The animation is great(and hey I never knew there was a studio Down Under eh LOL),the songs are good I liked the first song There's a Party Here In Agrabah as well as Out Of Thin Air. The impressions are so funny I laughed when I saw the Mrs Doubtfire one and the Rocky Balboa one too. Overall if you liked the first Aladdin then sit back,relax and enjoy the epic finally of Aladdin which is one of my all time favourite movies ever. And even at the age of 22 I still love this movie. Can you imagine it took me 22 years to see this film even though it was made in 1996 and I was 6 years old at the time and it took me till now to see it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not on par with the original, but way better than Return of Jafar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having been disappointed with Return of Jafar, I thought that this might even be worse than that film. Boy, was I wrong. Sure, it's not on par with the original classic, but it's in my opinion a slight improvement over ROJ. There are some color changes and it could've been a little bit longer, but those flaws doesn't matter. What really matters is that it brought a nostalgic feeling to the original film by being an even better DTV Disney sequel than others. The story is very original and the father-son relation worked really well throughout the entire film. The animation is beautiful and fluid with some nice visual scenery especially the island that had the Hand of Midas which is by far the strongest aspect of the animation along with it's fine character designs. The characters are likable and the voice acting is neat especially the new cameos John Rhys Davis and Jerry Orbach (Lumiere from Beauty and the Beast is in this, by the way). The songs aren't on par with the songs from the original film, but they're still a lot of fun to listen to. Overall, not excellent, but a slight improvement over Return of Jafar and totally recommended to others who have not seen it yet!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Done on the cheap
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EpeeBill
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like how Disney expanded their version of the Aladdin story in their TV series and the direct to DVD sequels, but this one kind of let me down. The voice acting is great and I really liked the music, but the quality of the animation is quite poor by Disney standards. Normally, I wouldn't be so particular about the art but the drop in quality from the first movie, to the TV show to this sequel is precipitous. The color palette is so muted it seems like the animators were told only to use a maximum of 16 throughout the entire running time. The familiar characters are still quite recognizable, but they all lack detail and depth that you come to expect from Disney. I know that the direct-to-DVD products are given smaller budgets, but that doesn't justify just how cheap this movie looks. There are still lots of redeeming parts of this movie, but the lack of visual polish is too distracting for me to enjoy them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far too US orientated (spoiler included)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gdcox
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't watch this if you are not American as they have tried to make all the humour colloquial machine gun US and tragically succeeded. The concept of a genie as a permanent character with unlimited assistance is absurd both in terms of the original story and the fact that he could have whipped the opposition after five minute, but somehow doesn't bother enough. Concept of bad father and struggle of same interacting with the son is very good though far too subtle for any child under ten I would suggest and end the end of the day is bad role model for the young. Technically, seems fine. I don't know why I am forced to do ten lines when a film is so bad. This policy should be reviewed. Five lines is more than enough for a film rated bad by the reviewer .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tolly Maggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people argue over which is better: Return of Jafar or King of Thieves. To be more specific, they actually argue over which one is WORSE. When I watched this film, both as a child and an adult, I didn't see much wrong with it. In fact, I really enjoyed it! The animation had picked up again to a fantastic standard compared to the last movie, with quality only dropping in short moments. However, while the animation didn't quite seem to stay on par at all moments, I thought the music was sublime. Very emotional music which is used to convey emotions successfully in creative dramatic ways. One example of this would be in Aladdin's fight to join the thieves. Most of the diegetic sound drops out, leaving only the sounds of fire and lighting, leaving the music to convey the process of emotions running through the characters: Sa'luk's thirst for Alladin's blood to vent his rage for Cassim, Cassim's fear of losing the son he only just found, and Aladdin's desperation to survive. Very creative and poetic, with similarly poetic scenes later in the film. Although the characters' goals and reasons for alternating in decisions can be confusing, if you keep up with it it remains logical and the narrative successfully develops. The narrative kept me interested, and I thought it worked being a short film (Just over an hour). The plot doesn't drag too much, there is often a sense in development in both the story and the characters, and the action is meaningful. One other part of this film which is always entertaining is the genie's (Robin Williams') small 'sketches' that, while they seem to stray from the plot, are very entertaining, witty and comical. It was clear Williams had a lot of contribution to his character and the jokes that were made. Overall, I found this film very entertaining: Both as a child and an adult.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than The Return Of Jafar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So Aladdin and Jasmine are getting married (finally) and their wedding is crashed by the 40 thieves who are there to steal a magical oracle that allows anyone who has it to ask it one question. The King of Thieves wants to know where the magical hand of Midus is. Aladdin finds out the King of thieves is his father and they find the hand of Midas together. The hand of Midas was the only thing cool about this film, some of Robin Williams improvised stuff is funny as well. It had even worse quality than the last one and looked low budget and about neck and neck with the TV show as far as quality goes. I was glad to see CCH Pounder as the voice of the oracle and that was a bonus, but nothing can save this film for me, it was really boring, kids might enjoy it if they don't require too much to entertain them. 2/10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK straight to video 3rd entry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dwpollar
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1st watched 2/14/2010 -- 4 out of 10(Dir-Tad Stones): OK straight to video 3rd entry in the Walt Disney Aladdin series tries hard to be like the Disney movies of old that we love(but that's also it's problem -- it tries too hard!!) It has the many songs, the good guy-bad guy theme, and the guy gets the girl scenario but it obviously has less heart and funds to pull it off. It was made by the TV animation studio and it kind of has that look and feel to it with it's incomplete, un-realistic backgrounds but otherwise looks OK. Robin Williams as the Genie is funny at times(but overbearing at others)and some of the other minor characters brings some laughs but the movie tries to be too grand and too good even though it wasn't meant to be. The story is about Aladdin and Jasmine getting married but is interrupted by the forty thieves. We later find out that Aladdin's father is the king of thieves and he goes on a quest to bring him back and reform him. There is a bad leader of the thieves who keeps fighting with Aladdin's father over the kingship of the thieves, who amazingly is voiced by Jerry Orbach, in a very different role for him. They are then lured to the ultimate treasure of Midas's hand by an oracle and they eventually have to decide what's really important(the treasure or the people). As most Disney films, it all works itself out in the end but the movie overall doesn't deliver the kind of craftsmanship in the story that usually keeps us interested in a Disney movie. A good try by the TV animators but it's not quite what it could have been. Given a little more money and time it could have been a worthwhile effort but instead it's pretty mediocre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should Have Gotten a Theatrical Release.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerekra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most of the time when straight to video Disney Sequels are made you can understand why the film was not released in theatres. However in the case of Aladdin and the King of Thieves I feel that this film should have been released in the theatres. Aladdin and Jasmine have their wedding interrupted by an attack by the Forty Thieves. Soon Aladdin learns that his father is the King of Thieves. He brings his father back to Agraba hoping that he will reform, however Aladdins father has hopes of finding the ultimate treasure no matter the cost. The artwork for this film is way better than in The Return of Jafar. Also the story is excellent and action packed. One of the main reasons why this film works is the return of Robin Williams. He is as hilarious as ever as the Genie, and actually I think that he is much more funny in this film as opposed to the first Aladdin film. Genie is hilarious in this film and that is the major reason this film is great. Also I like how Aladdin's father is in this film. A great idea and I think that this somewhat is similar to the third Indiana Jones film. Not only is the idea similar but the fact that they got the actor who played Sallah in the Indiana Jones Trilogy (his name escapes me) makes the idea work all that much better. Also there is a good villain in Suluk, a sort of huge evil guy with a sharp claw thing on one of his hands. I guess the one flaw might be the lack of great songs. If they had improved on that a little this film would have been perfect. But I would rather there be great humor, action, and story than a few great songs. If they had improved the artwork a little, and added some awesomer music this would have been a great film to release in theatres. Of all the Disney sequels that have been released straight to video, this is BY FAR the best. I recommend this film greatly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great End to the Trilogy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soodynem
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to say, this is without a doubt one of the only watchable direct-to-video features Disney has ever given us. Now, for those who haven't seen this, and have seen the likes of, oh, I don't know, The Hunchback of Notre Dame II or Tarzan and Jane, you may ask how this is possible. Start with the voice actors. You have the complete original cast back on board (minus Jonathan Freeman, for obvious reasons), plus a few extras. Jasmine may sound slightly different than she used to, but my spies tell me that she is indeed the same actress. John Rhys-Davies provides his voice for Aladdin's father, and the King of Thieves, Cassim. Jerry Orbach (of Beauty and the Beast fame) plays one of the forty thieves, Sa'luk. And finally, the star of the show has returned. I like Dan Castellaneta, and I think he did an acceptable job as the Genie, but Robin Williams is still the best. In fact, William's performance here could be best described as 'unleashed'. The Genie impersonates no less than five Disney characters, including Mickey Mouse himself, becomes an entire army (comprised of SWAT, cavalry, paratroopers, bagpipe men, the ED-209, and Pocahontas), picks up an elephant with his bare hands, and comforts Jasmine as Mrs. Doubtfire, albeit a bearded version. This movie has a coherent plot, which is, you know, strange for a Disney sequel. Some may say it was stolen from 'The Last Crusade' and I'd have to agree. You know, hero meets father, father is looking for some important artifact, appears to love it more than his family, but doesn't. Yeah. Except instead of the Holy Grail, we have this awesome Hand of Midas that can turn anything into gold. The villain foundation is not as good as the original, but Jerry Orbach still manages give us the next best thing with a grey-skinned, muscle-bound, wolverine-claw using man known as Sa'luk. I would rate his death scene as one of the best in cinematic history. Songs Ha. Well they don't measure up to the originals, but they do the best they can do. Genie is so over-the-top with his two songs that it's almost unbelievable, and the forty thieves song is quite entertaining. Just, uh, pretend that you can't hear the sappy song Aladdin and Jasmine sing about his childhood, as it may induce vomiting and/or cancer. After the exercise of utter futility that was 'The Return of Jafar', this movie gives us some of the best direct-to-video animation you'll see out there. It's truly a satisfying film that provide a satisfying ending. While I'd rate 'Aladdin' 9 stars, 'Jafar' would get 2 and this would get 7 to 8. It's that good, check it out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arabian night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I was a kid insanely in love with 1994's "The Return of Jafar". I watched thousand of times with every relative that came into home. Last weeks I was surfing channels on cable and saw "Aladdin and the King of Thieves" passing, which made me wonder: "Have I ever seen that picture?". So I decided it would be a good idea to watch this, you know, just in case. I can state this movie is very creative, with some eventual funny lines-- mainly coming from Genie, I admit it. There are some nice songs to entertaining the spectator instead of telling a never ending story. Sometimes the relationship Aladdin has with his father looks too shallow for a children movie, but it doesn't spoil the movie's overall quality. Princess Jasmine sometimes is forgotten and she barely comes up in the screen. Director makes some metalinguistic scenes with reference to other Disney movies, providing an old spectator like me (I'm 21) a nostalgic feeling. All in all, this isn't as great as 1994's installment, but does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really enjoyed this movie and it took me until NOW to see it where have I been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisafordeay
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie today and let me tell ya I laughed so much at it why because Robin Williams is in this movie better than ever YEAH. The film chronicles on Aladdin's big day with Jasmine,but problems arise when Aladdin's long lost father returns and he is working for the King Of Thieves(hence the title). So its up to Aladdin to track him down and help him retrive this golden hand that he is looking for. The animation is great(and hey I never knew there was a studio Down Under eh LOL),the songs are good I liked the first song There's a Party Here In Agrabah as well as Out Of Thin Air. The impressions are so funny I laughed when I saw the Mrs Doubtfire one and the Rocky Balboa one too. Overall if you liked the first Aladdin then sit back,relax and enjoy the epic finally of Aladdin which is one of my all time favourite movies ever. And even at the age of 22 I still love this movie. Can you imagine it took me 22 years to see this film even though it was made in 1996 and I was 6 years old at the time and it took me till now to see it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not on par with the original, but way better than Return of Jafar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having been disappointed with Return of Jafar, I thought that this might even be worse than that film. Boy, was I wrong. Sure, it's not on par with the original classic, but it's in my opinion a slight improvement over ROJ. There are some color changes and it could've been a little bit longer, but those flaws doesn't matter. What really matters is that it brought a nostalgic feeling to the original film by being an even better DTV Disney sequel than others. The story is very original and the father-son relation worked really well throughout the entire film. The animation is beautiful and fluid with some nice visual scenery especially the island that had the Hand of Midas which is by far the strongest aspect of the animation along with it's fine character designs. The characters are likable and the voice acting is neat especially the new cameos John Rhys Davis and Jerry Orbach (Lumiere from Beauty and the Beast is in this, by the way). The songs aren't on par with the songs from the original film, but they're still a lot of fun to listen to. Overall, not excellent, but a slight improvement over Return of Jafar and totally recommended to others who have not seen it yet!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Done on the cheap
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EpeeBill
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like how Disney expanded their version of the Aladdin story in their TV series and the direct to DVD sequels, but this one kind of let me down. The voice acting is great and I really liked the music, but the quality of the animation is quite poor by Disney standards. Normally, I wouldn't be so particular about the art but the drop in quality from the first movie, to the TV show to this sequel is precipitous. The color palette is so muted it seems like the animators were told only to use a maximum of 16 throughout the entire running time. The familiar characters are still quite recognizable, but they all lack detail and depth that you come to expect from Disney. I know that the direct-to-DVD products are given smaller budgets, but that doesn't justify just how cheap this movie looks. There are still lots of redeeming parts of this movie, but the lack of visual polish is too distracting for me to enjoy them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far too US orientated (spoiler included)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gdcox
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't watch this if you are not American as they have tried to make all the humour colloquial machine gun US and tragically succeeded. The concept of a genie as a permanent character with unlimited assistance is absurd both in terms of the original story and the fact that he could have whipped the opposition after five minute, but somehow doesn't bother enough. Concept of bad father and struggle of same interacting with the son is very good though far too subtle for any child under ten I would suggest and end the end of the day is bad role model for the young. Technically, seems fine. I don't know why I am forced to do ten lines when a film is so bad. This policy should be reviewed. Five lines is more than enough for a film rated bad by the reviewer .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tolly Maggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people argue over which is better: Return of Jafar or King of Thieves. To be more specific, they actually argue over which one is WORSE. When I watched this film, both as a child and an adult, I didn't see much wrong with it. In fact, I really enjoyed it! The animation had picked up again to a fantastic standard compared to the last movie, with quality only dropping in short moments. However, while the animation didn't quite seem to stay on par at all moments, I thought the music was sublime. Very emotional music which is used to convey emotions successfully in creative dramatic ways. One example of this would be in Aladdin's fight to join the thieves. Most of the diegetic sound drops out, leaving only the sounds of fire and lighting, leaving the music to convey the process of emotions running through the characters: Sa'luk's thirst for Alladin's blood to vent his rage for Cassim, Cassim's fear of losing the son he only just found, and Aladdin's desperation to survive. Very creative and poetic, with similarly poetic scenes later in the film. Although the characters' goals and reasons for alternating in decisions can be confusing, if you keep up with it it remains logical and the narrative successfully develops. The narrative kept me interested, and I thought it worked being a short film (Just over an hour). The plot doesn't drag too much, there is often a sense in development in both the story and the characters, and the action is meaningful. One other part of this film which is always entertaining is the genie's (Robin Williams') small 'sketches' that, while they seem to stray from the plot, are very entertaining, witty and comical. It was clear Williams had a lot of contribution to his character and the jokes that were made. Overall, I found this film very entertaining: Both as a child and an adult.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than The Return Of Jafar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So Aladdin and Jasmine are getting married (finally) and their wedding is crashed by the 40 thieves who are there to steal a magical oracle that allows anyone who has it to ask it one question. The King of Thieves wants to know where the magical hand of Midus is. Aladdin finds out the King of thieves is his father and they find the hand of Midas together. The hand of Midas was the only thing cool about this film, some of Robin Williams improvised stuff is funny as well. It had even worse quality than the last one and looked low budget and about neck and neck with the TV show as far as quality goes. I was glad to see CCH Pounder as the voice of the oracle and that was a bonus, but nothing can save this film for me, it was really boring, kids might enjoy it if they don't require too much to entertain them. 2/10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK straight to video 3rd entry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dwpollar
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1st watched 2/14/2010 -- 4 out of 10(Dir-Tad Stones): OK straight to video 3rd entry in the Walt Disney Aladdin series tries hard to be like the Disney movies of old that we love(but that's also it's problem -- it tries too hard!!) It has the many songs, the good guy-bad guy theme, and the guy gets the girl scenario but it obviously has less heart and funds to pull it off. It was made by the TV animation studio and it kind of has that look and feel to it with it's incomplete, un-realistic backgrounds but otherwise looks OK. Robin Williams as the Genie is funny at times(but overbearing at others)and some of the other minor characters brings some laughs but the movie tries to be too grand and too good even though it wasn't meant to be. The story is about Aladdin and Jasmine getting married but is interrupted by the forty thieves. We later find out that Aladdin's father is the king of thieves and he goes on a quest to bring him back and reform him. There is a bad leader of the thieves who keeps fighting with Aladdin's father over the kingship of the thieves, who amazingly is voiced by Jerry Orbach, in a very different role for him. They are then lured to the ultimate treasure of Midas's hand by an oracle and they eventually have to decide what's really important(the treasure or the people). As most Disney films, it all works itself out in the end but the movie overall doesn't deliver the kind of craftsmanship in the story that usually keeps us interested in a Disney movie. A good try by the TV animators but it's not quite what it could have been. Given a little more money and time it could have been a worthwhile effort but instead it's pretty mediocre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should Have Gotten a Theatrical Release.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerekra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most of the time when straight to video Disney Sequels are made you can understand why the film was not released in theatres. However in the case of Aladdin and the King of Thieves I feel that this film should have been released in the theatres. Aladdin and Jasmine have their wedding interrupted by an attack by the Forty Thieves. Soon Aladdin learns that his father is the King of Thieves. He brings his father back to Agraba hoping that he will reform, however Aladdins father has hopes of finding the ultimate treasure no matter the cost. The artwork for this film is way better than in The Return of Jafar. Also the story is excellent and action packed. One of the main reasons why this film works is the return of Robin Williams. He is as hilarious as ever as the Genie, and actually I think that he is much more funny in this film as opposed to the first Aladdin film. Genie is hilarious in this film and that is the major reason this film is great. Also I like how Aladdin's father is in this film. A great idea and I think that this somewhat is similar to the third Indiana Jones film. Not only is the idea similar but the fact that they got the actor who played Sallah in the Indiana Jones Trilogy (his name escapes me) makes the idea work all that much better. Also there is a good villain in Suluk, a sort of huge evil guy with a sharp claw thing on one of his hands. I guess the one flaw might be the lack of great songs. If they had improved on that a little this film would have been perfect. But I would rather there be great humor, action, and story than a few great songs. If they had improved the artwork a little, and added some awesomer music this would have been a great film to release in theatres. Of all the Disney sequels that have been released straight to video, this is BY FAR the best. I recommend this film greatly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great End to the Trilogy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soodynem
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to say, this is without a doubt one of the only watchable direct-to-video features Disney has ever given us. Now, for those who haven't seen this, and have seen the likes of, oh, I don't know, The Hunchback of Notre Dame II or Tarzan and Jane, you may ask how this is possible. Start with the voice actors. You have the complete original cast back on board (minus Jonathan Freeman, for obvious reasons), plus a few extras. Jasmine may sound slightly different than she used to, but my spies tell me that she is indeed the same actress. John Rhys-Davies provides his voice for Aladdin's father, and the King of Thieves, Cassim. Jerry Orbach (of Beauty and the Beast fame) plays one of the forty thieves, Sa'luk. And finally, the star of the show has returned. I like Dan Castellaneta, and I think he did an acceptable job as the Genie, but Robin Williams is still the best. In fact, William's performance here could be best described as 'unleashed'. The Genie impersonates no less than five Disney characters, including Mickey Mouse himself, becomes an entire army (comprised of SWAT, cavalry, paratroopers, bagpipe men, the ED-209, and Pocahontas), picks up an elephant with his bare hands, and comforts Jasmine as Mrs. Doubtfire, albeit a bearded version. This movie has a coherent plot, which is, you know, strange for a Disney sequel. Some may say it was stolen from 'The Last Crusade' and I'd have to agree. You know, hero meets father, father is looking for some important artifact, appears to love it more than his family, but doesn't. Yeah. Except instead of the Holy Grail, we have this awesome Hand of Midas that can turn anything into gold. The villain foundation is not as good as the original, but Jerry Orbach still manages give us the next best thing with a grey-skinned, muscle-bound, wolverine-claw using man known as Sa'luk. I would rate his death scene as one of the best in cinematic history. Songs Ha. Well they don't measure up to the originals, but they do the best they can do. Genie is so over-the-top with his two songs that it's almost unbelievable, and the forty thieves song is quite entertaining. Just, uh, pretend that you can't hear the sappy song Aladdin and Jasmine sing about his childhood, as it may induce vomiting and/or cancer. After the exercise of utter futility that was 'The Return of Jafar', this movie gives us some of the best direct-to-video animation you'll see out there. It's truly a satisfying film that provide a satisfying ending. While I'd rate 'Aladdin' 9 stars, 'Jafar' would get 2 and this would get 7 to 8. It's that good, check it out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arabian night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I was a kid insanely in love with 1994's "The Return of Jafar". I watched thousand of times with every relative that came into home. Last weeks I was surfing channels on cable and saw "Aladdin and the King of Thieves" passing, which made me wonder: "Have I ever seen that picture?". So I decided it would be a good idea to watch this, you know, just in case. I can state this movie is very creative, with some eventual funny lines-- mainly coming from Genie, I admit it. There are some nice songs to entertaining the spectator instead of telling a never ending story. Sometimes the relationship Aladdin has with his father looks too shallow for a children movie, but it doesn't spoil the movie's overall quality. Princess Jasmine sometimes is forgotten and she barely comes up in the screen. Director makes some metalinguistic scenes with reference to other Disney movies, providing an old spectator like me (I'm 21) a nostalgic feeling. All in all, this isn't as great as 1994's installment, but does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really enjoyed this movie and it took me until NOW to see it where have I been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisafordeay
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie today and let me tell ya I laughed so much at it why because Robin Williams is in this movie better than ever YEAH. The film chronicles on Aladdin's big day with Jasmine,but problems arise when Aladdin's long lost father returns and he is working for the King Of Thieves(hence the title). So its up to Aladdin to track him down and help him retrive this golden hand that he is looking for. The animation is great(and hey I never knew there was a studio Down Under eh LOL),the songs are good I liked the first song There's a Party Here In Agrabah as well as Out Of Thin Air. The impressions are so funny I laughed when I saw the Mrs Doubtfire one and the Rocky Balboa one too. Overall if you liked the first Aladdin then sit back,relax and enjoy the epic finally of Aladdin which is one of my all time favourite movies ever. And even at the age of 22 I still love this movie. Can you imagine it took me 22 years to see this film even though it was made in 1996 and I was 6 years old at the time and it took me till now to see it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not on par with the original, but way better than Return of Jafar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having been disappointed with Return of Jafar, I thought that this might even be worse than that film. Boy, was I wrong. Sure, it's not on par with the original classic, but it's in my opinion a slight improvement over ROJ. There are some color changes and it could've been a little bit longer, but those flaws doesn't matter. What really matters is that it brought a nostalgic feeling to the original film by being an even better DTV Disney sequel than others. The story is very original and the father-son relation worked really well throughout the entire film. The animation is beautiful and fluid with some nice visual scenery especially the island that had the Hand of Midas which is by far the strongest aspect of the animation along with it's fine character designs. The characters are likable and the voice acting is neat especially the new cameos John Rhys Davis and Jerry Orbach (Lumiere from Beauty and the Beast is in this, by the way). The songs aren't on par with the songs from the original film, but they're still a lot of fun to listen to. Overall, not excellent, but a slight improvement over Return of Jafar and totally recommended to others who have not seen it yet!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Done on the cheap
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EpeeBill
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like how Disney expanded their version of the Aladdin story in their TV series and the direct to DVD sequels, but this one kind of let me down. The voice acting is great and I really liked the music, but the quality of the animation is quite poor by Disney standards. Normally, I wouldn't be so particular about the art but the drop in quality from the first movie, to the TV show to this sequel is precipitous. The color palette is so muted it seems like the animators were told only to use a maximum of 16 throughout the entire running time. The familiar characters are still quite recognizable, but they all lack detail and depth that you come to expect from Disney. I know that the direct-to-DVD products are given smaller budgets, but that doesn't justify just how cheap this movie looks. There are still lots of redeeming parts of this movie, but the lack of visual polish is too distracting for me to enjoy them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far too US orientated (spoiler included)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gdcox
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't watch this if you are not American as they have tried to make all the humour colloquial machine gun US and tragically succeeded. The concept of a genie as a permanent character with unlimited assistance is absurd both in terms of the original story and the fact that he could have whipped the opposition after five minute, but somehow doesn't bother enough. Concept of bad father and struggle of same interacting with the son is very good though far too subtle for any child under ten I would suggest and end the end of the day is bad role model for the young. Technically, seems fine. I don't know why I am forced to do ten lines when a film is so bad. This policy should be reviewed. Five lines is more than enough for a film rated bad by the reviewer .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tolly Maggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people argue over which is better: Return of Jafar or King of Thieves. To be more specific, they actually argue over which one is WORSE. When I watched this film, both as a child and an adult, I didn't see much wrong with it. In fact, I really enjoyed it! The animation had picked up again to a fantastic standard compared to the last movie, with quality only dropping in short moments. However, while the animation didn't quite seem to stay on par at all moments, I thought the music was sublime. Very emotional music which is used to convey emotions successfully in creative dramatic ways. One example of this would be in Aladdin's fight to join the thieves. Most of the diegetic sound drops out, leaving only the sounds of fire and lighting, leaving the music to convey the process of emotions running through the characters: Sa'luk's thirst for Alladin's blood to vent his rage for Cassim, Cassim's fear of losing the son he only just found, and Aladdin's desperation to survive. Very creative and poetic, with similarly poetic scenes later in the film. Although the characters' goals and reasons for alternating in decisions can be confusing, if you keep up with it it remains logical and the narrative successfully develops. The narrative kept me interested, and I thought it worked being a short film (Just over an hour). The plot doesn't drag too much, there is often a sense in development in both the story and the characters, and the action is meaningful. One other part of this film which is always entertaining is the genie's (Robin Williams') small 'sketches' that, while they seem to stray from the plot, are very entertaining, witty and comical. It was clear Williams had a lot of contribution to his character and the jokes that were made. Overall, I found this film very entertaining: Both as a child and an adult.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than The Return Of Jafar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So Aladdin and Jasmine are getting married (finally) and their wedding is crashed by the 40 thieves who are there to steal a magical oracle that allows anyone who has it to ask it one question. The King of Thieves wants to know where the magical hand of Midus is. Aladdin finds out the King of thieves is his father and they find the hand of Midas together. The hand of Midas was the only thing cool about this film, some of Robin Williams improvised stuff is funny as well. It had even worse quality than the last one and looked low budget and about neck and neck with the TV show as far as quality goes. I was glad to see CCH Pounder as the voice of the oracle and that was a bonus, but nothing can save this film for me, it was really boring, kids might enjoy it if they don't require too much to entertain them. 2/10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK straight to video 3rd entry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dwpollar
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1st watched 2/14/2010 -- 4 out of 10(Dir-Tad Stones): OK straight to video 3rd entry in the Walt Disney Aladdin series tries hard to be like the Disney movies of old that we love(but that's also it's problem -- it tries too hard!!) It has the many songs, the good guy-bad guy theme, and the guy gets the girl scenario but it obviously has less heart and funds to pull it off. It was made by the TV animation studio and it kind of has that look and feel to it with it's incomplete, un-realistic backgrounds but otherwise looks OK. Robin Williams as the Genie is funny at times(but overbearing at others)and some of the other minor characters brings some laughs but the movie tries to be too grand and too good even though it wasn't meant to be. The story is about Aladdin and Jasmine getting married but is interrupted by the forty thieves. We later find out that Aladdin's father is the king of thieves and he goes on a quest to bring him back and reform him. There is a bad leader of the thieves who keeps fighting with Aladdin's father over the kingship of the thieves, who amazingly is voiced by Jerry Orbach, in a very different role for him. They are then lured to the ultimate treasure of Midas's hand by an oracle and they eventually have to decide what's really important(the treasure or the people). As most Disney films, it all works itself out in the end but the movie overall doesn't deliver the kind of craftsmanship in the story that usually keeps us interested in a Disney movie. A good try by the TV animators but it's not quite what it could have been. Given a little more money and time it could have been a worthwhile effort but instead it's pretty mediocre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should Have Gotten a Theatrical Release.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerekra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most of the time when straight to video Disney Sequels are made you can understand why the film was not released in theatres. However in the case of Aladdin and the King of Thieves I feel that this film should have been released in the theatres. Aladdin and Jasmine have their wedding interrupted by an attack by the Forty Thieves. Soon Aladdin learns that his father is the King of Thieves. He brings his father back to Agraba hoping that he will reform, however Aladdins father has hopes of finding the ultimate treasure no matter the cost. The artwork for this film is way better than in The Return of Jafar. Also the story is excellent and action packed. One of the main reasons why this film works is the return of Robin Williams. He is as hilarious as ever as the Genie, and actually I think that he is much more funny in this film as opposed to the first Aladdin film. Genie is hilarious in this film and that is the major reason this film is great. Also I like how Aladdin's father is in this film. A great idea and I think that this somewhat is similar to the third Indiana Jones film. Not only is the idea similar but the fact that they got the actor who played Sallah in the Indiana Jones Trilogy (his name escapes me) makes the idea work all that much better. Also there is a good villain in Suluk, a sort of huge evil guy with a sharp claw thing on one of his hands. I guess the one flaw might be the lack of great songs. If they had improved on that a little this film would have been perfect. But I would rather there be great humor, action, and story than a few great songs. If they had improved the artwork a little, and added some awesomer music this would have been a great film to release in theatres. Of all the Disney sequels that have been released straight to video, this is BY FAR the best. I recommend this film greatly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great End to the Trilogy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soodynem
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to say, this is without a doubt one of the only watchable direct-to-video features Disney has ever given us. Now, for those who haven't seen this, and have seen the likes of, oh, I don't know, The Hunchback of Notre Dame II or Tarzan and Jane, you may ask how this is possible. Start with the voice actors. You have the complete original cast back on board (minus Jonathan Freeman, for obvious reasons), plus a few extras. Jasmine may sound slightly different than she used to, but my spies tell me that she is indeed the same actress. John Rhys-Davies provides his voice for Aladdin's father, and the King of Thieves, Cassim. Jerry Orbach (of Beauty and the Beast fame) plays one of the forty thieves, Sa'luk. And finally, the star of the show has returned. I like Dan Castellaneta, and I think he did an acceptable job as the Genie, but Robin Williams is still the best. In fact, William's performance here could be best described as 'unleashed'. The Genie impersonates no less than five Disney characters, including Mickey Mouse himself, becomes an entire army (comprised of SWAT, cavalry, paratroopers, bagpipe men, the ED-209, and Pocahontas), picks up an elephant with his bare hands, and comforts Jasmine as Mrs. Doubtfire, albeit a bearded version. This movie has a coherent plot, which is, you know, strange for a Disney sequel. Some may say it was stolen from 'The Last Crusade' and I'd have to agree. You know, hero meets father, father is looking for some important artifact, appears to love it more than his family, but doesn't. Yeah. Except instead of the Holy Grail, we have this awesome Hand of Midas that can turn anything into gold. The villain foundation is not as good as the original, but Jerry Orbach still manages give us the next best thing with a grey-skinned, muscle-bound, wolverine-claw using man known as Sa'luk. I would rate his death scene as one of the best in cinematic history. Songs Ha. Well they don't measure up to the originals, but they do the best they can do. Genie is so over-the-top with his two songs that it's almost unbelievable, and the forty thieves song is quite entertaining. Just, uh, pretend that you can't hear the sappy song Aladdin and Jasmine sing about his childhood, as it may induce vomiting and/or cancer. After the exercise of utter futility that was 'The Return of Jafar', this movie gives us some of the best direct-to-video animation you'll see out there. It's truly a satisfying film that provide a satisfying ending. While I'd rate 'Aladdin' 9 stars, 'Jafar' would get 2 and this would get 7 to 8. It's that good, check it out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arabian night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I was a kid insanely in love with 1994's "The Return of Jafar". I watched thousand of times with every relative that came into home. Last weeks I was surfing channels on cable and saw "Aladdin and the King of Thieves" passing, which made me wonder: "Have I ever seen that picture?". So I decided it would be a good idea to watch this, you know, just in case. I can state this movie is very creative, with some eventual funny lines-- mainly coming from Genie, I admit it. There are some nice songs to entertaining the spectator instead of telling a never ending story. Sometimes the relationship Aladdin has with his father looks too shallow for a children movie, but it doesn't spoil the movie's overall quality. Princess Jasmine sometimes is forgotten and she barely comes up in the screen. Director makes some metalinguistic scenes with reference to other Disney movies, providing an old spectator like me (I'm 21) a nostalgic feeling. All in all, this isn't as great as 1994's installment, but does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really enjoyed this movie and it took me until NOW to see it where have I been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisafordeay
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie today and let me tell ya I laughed so much at it why because Robin Williams is in this movie better than ever YEAH. The film chronicles on Aladdin's big day with Jasmine,but problems arise when Aladdin's long lost father returns and he is working for the King Of Thieves(hence the title). So its up to Aladdin to track him down and help him retrive this golden hand that he is looking for. The animation is great(and hey I never knew there was a studio Down Under eh LOL),the songs are good I liked the first song There's a Party Here In Agrabah as well as Out Of Thin Air. The impressions are so funny I laughed when I saw the Mrs Doubtfire one and the Rocky Balboa one too. Overall if you liked the first Aladdin then sit back,relax and enjoy the epic finally of Aladdin which is one of my all time favourite movies ever. And even at the age of 22 I still love this movie. Can you imagine it took me 22 years to see this film even though it was made in 1996 and I was 6 years old at the time and it took me till now to see it. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not on par with the original, but way better than Return of Jafar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having been disappointed with Return of Jafar, I thought that this might even be worse than that film. Boy, was I wrong. Sure, it's not on par with the original classic, but it's in my opinion a slight improvement over ROJ. There are some color changes and it could've been a little bit longer, but those flaws doesn't matter. What really matters is that it brought a nostalgic feeling to the original film by being an even better DTV Disney sequel than others. The story is very original and the father-son relation worked really well throughout the entire film. The animation is beautiful and fluid with some nice visual scenery especially the island that had the Hand of Midas which is by far the strongest aspect of the animation along with it's fine character designs. The characters are likable and the voice acting is neat especially the new cameos John Rhys Davis and Jerry Orbach (Lumiere from Beauty and the Beast is in this, by the way). The songs aren't on par with the songs from the original film, but they're still a lot of fun to listen to. Overall, not excellent, but a slight improvement over Return of Jafar and totally recommended to others who have not seen it yet!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Done on the cheap
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EpeeBill
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like how Disney expanded their version of the Aladdin story in their TV series and the direct to DVD sequels, but this one kind of let me down. The voice acting is great and I really liked the music, but the quality of the animation is quite poor by Disney standards. Normally, I wouldn't be so particular about the art but the drop in quality from the first movie, to the TV show to this sequel is precipitous. The color palette is so muted it seems like the animators were told only to use a maximum of 16 throughout the entire running time. The familiar characters are still quite recognizable, but they all lack detail and depth that you come to expect from Disney. I know that the direct-to-DVD products are given smaller budgets, but that doesn't justify just how cheap this movie looks. There are still lots of redeeming parts of this movie, but the lack of visual polish is too distracting for me to enjoy them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far too US orientated (spoiler included)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gdcox
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't watch this if you are not American as they have tried to make all the humour colloquial machine gun US and tragically succeeded. The concept of a genie as a permanent character with unlimited assistance is absurd both in terms of the original story and the fact that he could have whipped the opposition after five minute, but somehow doesn't bother enough. Concept of bad father and struggle of same interacting with the son is very good though far too subtle for any child under ten I would suggest and end the end of the day is bad role model for the young. Technically, seems fine. I don't know why I am forced to do ten lines when a film is so bad. This policy should be reviewed. Five lines is more than enough for a film rated bad by the reviewer .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tolly Maggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people argue over which is better: Return of Jafar or King of Thieves. To be more specific, they actually argue over which one is WORSE. When I watched this film, both as a child and an adult, I didn't see much wrong with it. In fact, I really enjoyed it! The animation had picked up again to a fantastic standard compared to the last movie, with quality only dropping in short moments. However, while the animation didn't quite seem to stay on par at all moments, I thought the music was sublime. Very emotional music which is used to convey emotions successfully in creative dramatic ways. One example of this would be in Aladdin's fight to join the thieves. Most of the diegetic sound drops out, leaving only the sounds of fire and lighting, leaving the music to convey the process of emotions running through the characters: Sa'luk's thirst for Alladin's blood to vent his rage for Cassim, Cassim's fear of losing the son he only just found, and Aladdin's desperation to survive. Very creative and poetic, with similarly poetic scenes later in the film. Although the characters' goals and reasons for alternating in decisions can be confusing, if you keep up with it it remains logical and the narrative successfully develops. The narrative kept me interested, and I thought it worked being a short film (Just over an hour). The plot doesn't drag too much, there is often a sense in development in both the story and the characters, and the action is meaningful. One other part of this film which is always entertaining is the genie's (Robin Williams') small 'sketches' that, while they seem to stray from the plot, are very entertaining, witty and comical. It was clear Williams had a lot of contribution to his character and the jokes that were made. Overall, I found this film very entertaining: Both as a child and an adult.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than The Return Of Jafar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Arlis Fuson
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So Aladdin and Jasmine are getting married (finally) and their wedding is crashed by the 40 thieves who are there to steal a magical oracle that allows anyone who has it to ask it one question. The King of Thieves wants to know where the magical hand of Midus is. Aladdin finds out the King of thieves is his father and they find the hand of Midas together. The hand of Midas was the only thing cool about this film, some of Robin Williams improvised stuff is funny as well. It had even worse quality than the last one and looked low budget and about neck and neck with the TV show as far as quality goes. I was glad to see CCH Pounder as the voice of the oracle and that was a bonus, but nothing can save this film for me, it was really boring, kids might enjoy it if they don't require too much to entertain them. 2/10 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK straight to video 3rd entry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dwpollar
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1st watched 2/14/2010 -- 4 out of 10(Dir-Tad Stones): OK straight to video 3rd entry in the Walt Disney Aladdin series tries hard to be like the Disney movies of old that we love(but that's also it's problem -- it tries too hard!!) It has the many songs, the good guy-bad guy theme, and the guy gets the girl scenario but it obviously has less heart and funds to pull it off. It was made by the TV animation studio and it kind of has that look and feel to it with it's incomplete, un-realistic backgrounds but otherwise looks OK. Robin Williams as the Genie is funny at times(but overbearing at others)and some of the other minor characters brings some laughs but the movie tries to be too grand and too good even though it wasn't meant to be. The story is about Aladdin and Jasmine getting married but is interrupted by the forty thieves. We later find out that Aladdin's father is the king of thieves and he goes on a quest to bring him back and reform him. There is a bad leader of the thieves who keeps fighting with Aladdin's father over the kingship of the thieves, who amazingly is voiced by Jerry Orbach, in a very different role for him. They are then lured to the ultimate treasure of Midas's hand by an oracle and they eventually have to decide what's really important(the treasure or the people). As most Disney films, it all works itself out in the end but the movie overall doesn't deliver the kind of craftsmanship in the story that usually keeps us interested in a Disney movie. A good try by the TV animators but it's not quite what it could have been. Given a little more money and time it could have been a worthwhile effort but instead it's pretty mediocre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should Have Gotten a Theatrical Release.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerekra
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most of the time when straight to video Disney Sequels are made you can understand why the film was not released in theatres. However in the case of Aladdin and the King of Thieves I feel that this film should have been released in the theatres. Aladdin and Jasmine have their wedding interrupted by an attack by the Forty Thieves. Soon Aladdin learns that his father is the King of Thieves. He brings his father back to Agraba hoping that he will reform, however Aladdins father has hopes of finding the ultimate treasure no matter the cost. The artwork for this film is way better than in The Return of Jafar. Also the story is excellent and action packed. One of the main reasons why this film works is the return of Robin Williams. He is as hilarious as ever as the Genie, and actually I think that he is much more funny in this film as opposed to the first Aladdin film. Genie is hilarious in this film and that is the major reason this film is great. Also I like how Aladdin's father is in this film. A great idea and I think that this somewhat is similar to the third Indiana Jones film. Not only is the idea similar but the fact that they got the actor who played Sallah in the Indiana Jones Trilogy (his name escapes me) makes the idea work all that much better. Also there is a good villain in Suluk, a sort of huge evil guy with a sharp claw thing on one of his hands. I guess the one flaw might be the lack of great songs. If they had improved on that a little this film would have been perfect. But I would rather there be great humor, action, and story than a few great songs. If they had improved the artwork a little, and added some awesomer music this would have been a great film to release in theatres. Of all the Disney sequels that have been released straight to video, this is BY FAR the best. I recommend this film greatly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great End to the Trilogy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soodynem
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to say, this is without a doubt one of the only watchable direct-to-video features Disney has ever given us. Now, for those who haven't seen this, and have seen the likes of, oh, I don't know, The Hunchback of Notre Dame II or Tarzan and Jane, you may ask how this is possible. Start with the voice actors. You have the complete original cast back on board (minus Jonathan Freeman, for obvious reasons), plus a few extras. Jasmine may sound slightly different than she used to, but my spies tell me that she is indeed the same actress. John Rhys-Davies provides his voice for Aladdin's father, and the King of Thieves, Cassim. Jerry Orbach (of Beauty and the Beast fame) plays one of the forty thieves, Sa'luk. And finally, the star of the show has returned. I like Dan Castellaneta, and I think he did an acceptable job as the Genie, but Robin Williams is still the best. In fact, William's performance here could be best described as 'unleashed'. The Genie impersonates no less than five Disney characters, including Mickey Mouse himself, becomes an entire army (comprised of SWAT, cavalry, paratroopers, bagpipe men, the ED-209, and Pocahontas), picks up an elephant with his bare hands, and comforts Jasmine as Mrs. Doubtfire, albeit a bearded version. This movie has a coherent plot, which is, you know, strange for a Disney sequel. Some may say it was stolen from 'The Last Crusade' and I'd have to agree. You know, hero meets father, father is looking for some important artifact, appears to love it more than his family, but doesn't. Yeah. Except instead of the Holy Grail, we have this awesome Hand of Midas that can turn anything into gold. The villain foundation is not as good as the original, but Jerry Orbach still manages give us the next best thing with a grey-skinned, muscle-bound, wolverine-claw using man known as Sa'luk. I would rate his death scene as one of the best in cinematic history. Songs Ha. Well they don't measure up to the originals, but they do the best they can do. Genie is so over-the-top with his two songs that it's almost unbelievable, and the forty thieves song is quite entertaining. Just, uh, pretend that you can't hear the sappy song Aladdin and Jasmine sing about his childhood, as it may induce vomiting and/or cancer. After the exercise of utter futility that was 'The Return of Jafar', this movie gives us some of the best direct-to-video animation you'll see out there. It's truly a satisfying film that provide a satisfying ending. While I'd rate 'Aladdin' 9 stars, 'Jafar' would get 2 and this would get 7 to 8. It's that good, check it out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
