<filme>
 <id>
  426
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092106
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1986
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Transformers - O Filme
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The Autobots must stop a colossal planet consuming robot who goes after the Autobot Matrix of Leadership. At the same time, they must defend themselves against an all-out attack from the Decepticons.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  It is the year 2005. And the battle between the heroic Autobots led by Optimus Prime and the evil Decepticons led by Megatron. Two warring factions of transforming robots from the planet Cybertron. The Autobots must save their homeworld from an evil entity known as Unicron, who's ready to consume anything that stands in its way. At the same time, they must defend themselves against an all-out attack from the Decepticons. Along the way, lives are lost, battles are fought, and a new Autobot leader is born as another dies.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Animation
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   planet
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   robot
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   battle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   transforming robot
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   year 2005
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Nelson Shin
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ron Friedman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Orson Welles
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert Stack
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Leonard Nimoy
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheesy Fun for the Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B. Transformers the Movie is a good, cheesy animated movie that ends the well done television series and does some surprising things but is rather entertaining. The war is still going on between the Autobots and Decepticons, but what they don't know is that there is a huge transformer that shaped like a planet heading towards them, devouring everything in its path. The opening battle on Earth is a rather tense one for the Autobots. Their base gets badly destroyed and lose one of their own that made quite a stir with fans after they saw it, Megatron kills Optimus Prime. He gives the Matrix to Ultra Magnus and puts him in charge and the Autobots head away from their base in search for their own who were eaten by the planet transformer, Unicron. Megatron after the battle got badly hurt and Starscream, wanting to be in charge, lets him go into space with others hurt and is picked up by Unicron and is now called Galvatron and working for Unicron.. Galvatron goes to Cybertron in search for Starscream and kills him and now all the Decepticons are his again with his new allies made for him by Unicron. The Autobots fly out, but are attacked by Galvatron and some land on a planet covered with trash and Hot Rod, Cub, and the Dinobots land on another planet. Hot Rod and Cub are taken prisoner and are trialed on how they will die by the planets ruler. Meanwhile, Galvatron went after the group on the rundown planet and they start hunting them and Ultra Magnus tries to use the Matrix for Prime said it will be used in their darkest hour. It doesn't open, and Galvatron blows him up. Then the inhabitants of the planet battle them. Then Cub and Hot Rod show up and save them and the junkbots rebuild Ultra Magnus and go help the Autobots fight Unicron. Meanwhile, Galvatron returns with the Matrix and wants to be in charge but won't and then the Autbots arrive to fight Unicron and save their own while Hot Rod has a final showdown with Galvatron. This is epic with him taking the Matrix and uses it against Unicron and turns into Rodimus Prime. The Decepticons die and the Autobots take back Cybertron. The movie has cheesy animation but is entertaining with some decent music, good characters, and is a great conclusion with a badass villain. Good for the fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'One shall stand, one shall fall..'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    markbyam
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film simply blew me away the first time I saw it. And still does today 20 years later. Right from The opening sequence, to the level of violence between the Decepticons and Autobots (which is totally justified) is spot on. They didn't hold back or try and soften the conflict and it was portrayed superbly. Everything from the soundtrack to the characters, and the dialogue works perfectly. Especially the dialogue which you just wouldn't get in a kids film nowadays. So many good one liners. The speech between Megatron and Prime is just pure brilliance with a fight scene that follows animated to perfection. The voice casting is exceptional and every action sequence is pulled off with such style and finesse. It even has one of the saddest scenes of any film that still makes me teary today. Once very rarely something comes along that just works in every single way...even more. Transformers the movie 1986 is an example of this. I feel privileged to have seen this as a child. Til all are one! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Me Grimlock love this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the release of the explosive Michael Bay trilogy, any newcomers to the shape-shifting franchise should be aware of the original 1986 animated feature because that's where it all started (sort of). Hasbro's Transformers became such a huge hit thanks to a combination of both the toys and the original G1 TV series of the same name. Robots changing into vehicles, guns, and even animals was such an incredible and original concept that it's hard to ignore. After running for two seasons at the time, Hasbro decided to make a full-length movie starring the Autobots and Decepticons. Plot: The year is 2005 (imagine that) as the Autobots, led by the heroic Optimus Prime, prepare to retake their home world Cybertron from the clutches of the evil Megatron and his Decepticons. However, a terrifying intergalactic force has arrived on the scene that's proved to be literally bigger than their petty war, the planet-sized Unicron (Orsen Welles). With the power of this new foe greater than anything imagined, it will take a new generation of heroes to stop this menace. Time to transform and role out! Next to "Revenge of the Fallen", this is by far my favorite film of the franchise. Seeing how the Transformers were before their live-action release was a real pleasure to see. Many of the famous characters, Autobot and Decepticon alike, get to have there little moments of action and glory, especially the Dinobots, who are my all-time favorite characters. The action scenes are just spectacular and it's pretty much non-stop. Call me old-fashioned, but I love the music, which is typical 80s soundtrack and it fits perfectly with this movie, such as Stan Bush's "The Touch" which is made famous because of this movie. The animation is also worth noting, definitely superior to the animation of the TV series. The film also became famous by taking risky moves with the old characters while introducing new ones. Optimus Prime and Megatron (Peter Cullen and Frank Welker) are still going at it as their rivalry never seems to end, though both go through some major changes. The Dinobots are fun to watch and bad to the bone. The other classic Autobots and Decepticons are cool in their own unique ways. Hot Rod makes for a good hero and Kup is a fun old robot who likes to think about the old days of the war. Orson Welles was great as Unicron and we're talking about his final role before he passed away. He provided true menace to his character with his voice; forget "Citizen Kane", Transformers man! There are very few things to nitpick around here, but overall, this movie is definitely worth buying, partly because of the nostalgia factor. With a great story, stellar voice cast, lovable and diverse cast of characters, great action scenes, and fun music, The Transformers The Movie is sure to please any fan. Nine out of ten, so check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The definition of nostalgia . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tanis_38
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no way to objectively review this film. It was my absolute favorite movie as a kid and I wore out my VHS copy. Seeing it now as an adult, I cannot see it through anything but child- like eyes and with overwhelming feelings of happy, sweet, nostalgia. Is it a great movie? I am not sure. Is the soundtrack cheesy 80's rock? Maybe. Is it my favorite Transformers movie? Absolutely. Will it always bring a smile to my face? I have one right now just thinking about it. Sure, the animation is wildly inconsistent, going from pretty amazing to laughably bad "Sunday Morning cartoon fare" from scene to scene. Sure, it can be seen as one big commercial for the future toy products of the series. But none of that matters when you are 8 years old. The Optimus Prime death scene was borderline traumatizing. The film is surprisingly violent by today's standards and outright gutsy in its willingness to kill off series regulars. It held no punches and if you were a kid in the 80's there is no way you can hear "You Got the Touch" and not smile, picturing Optimus Prime going to town on the Decepticons. This will always be in my top favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie with Transformers that has real emotion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevenbeech
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the first of the new Transformers movies and I can honestly say that the best thing in that film was Bernie Mac. 2 and a quarter hours of blowing stuff up isn't a movie. This is a movie. This is a movie that has real heart, real emotion, real themes at its core and one of the best film soundtracks ever. Sure there a bits where it drags a little and you want it to get back to the main action but it all makes sense in the end. This film probably won't make a massive amount of sense to the average 12 year old I must say, but to the 30 somethings amongst us it carries a great deal of our childhoods with it and along with that I feel a massive emotional attachment to it. The film deals with themes such as loyalty, friendship, the transition from youth to adulthood, the acceptance of responsibility, respect for elders, working toward a common goal and much else all backed by a superb 80's soft metal soundtrack composed by the much underrated Stan Bush. The soundtrack is the driving force behind much of the emotion of the movie, watch the scene where Hot Rod becomes Rodimus Prime without The Touch and its nowhere near as effective. Watch Optimus take out the decepticons without The Touch and you won't pull for him. Watch Hot Rod and Kup escape the Sharkticons without Dare playing and it doesn't work as well. This is a movie worth seeing. If only to compare it to the newer rebooted films which are technically superior and have had more spent on the catering for the cast than this movie probably cost to make but don't have the plot lines, heart, story or sheer entertainment value that this 80's throwback does.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Depressing first, then confusing and becoming more uninteresting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martyshoemark
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Transformers: The Movie was not as good as any of the episodes from the Generation One cartoon episodes from Seasons 1 to 2. Season 2 was an abundance of entertaining adventures of the Transformers in which both evil and justice battle each other while suffering the same troubles. The movie had clearly killed off so many beloved characters besides Prime, these included Prowl, Brawn, Ironhide, Ratchet, Wheeljack, and Starscream. However, the music and dramatic atmosphere of their death scenes were made to appear as if their deaths would not be tragic for the TV show audiences. The film quickly rushed into bringing upon new characters that hardly were introduced as well. The movie seemed to have just taken a not-so-much-of-an-advantage portion of its' length to add in complex plot structures that don't affect the main story of the movie, but instead to make sure this will be a bridge to Season 3 in the TV show. The Quintessons' entrance was clearly unnecessary in the plot and was only put in so that Season 3 can be established right away. The main villain of the story, Unicron, is really simple, he's just a misanthrope who wants to destroy EVERYTHING. Why? We don't know, that's just trying to make a character as a big, simple problem, which is a weak point common in several fictional stories. His voice actor, Orson Welles, was correct that this story is about a big toy attacking smaller toys. A lot of the plot was cheaply winged off of Star Wars such as the light sabers sounds, Arcee's cinnamon bun hairstyle like Leia's, and especially the climax between Hot Rod and Galvatron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly more that meets the Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TJMBuddlake
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though, i was born in 89, i still somehow grew to love transformers. I used to watch the old cartoons on reruns (now you can watch it on Toonamiaftermath.com) and I loved every bit of it. Now, 13 or so years later, I was able to finally get a copy of this movie and got a chance to watch it. OH MY GOD! This is the best transformers movie (better than the live action ones). The story was awesome, the voice cast was phenomenal. Peter Cullen, Casey Kasem, Judd Nelson, Leonard Nimoy and Orson Welles did a great job. Of course, i'm happy that all my favorites were featured (Cliffjumper and Hot Rod). This was definitely a defining moment for the transformers. In addition, the music was awesome. Stan Bush is freaking amazing. The song, The Touch will never get old. This is definitely one for any fans of the franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Transformer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Including this animated movie and the 3 live action Michael Bay movies from the Transformers universe this is by far the best version of a story about TF. The movie has its cheesy moments but it's what I enjoyed about the TF TV show and toy line of the 1980's when I was a kid. If I knew that Bay would bastardize the series like he has with a bunch of penis, fart jokes, racism and Shia LaBeouf I don't think I would've ever bothered to watch any of his movies about TF. The movie is basically TF trying to transition from their early toy lines with the Optimus Prime and MMegatron eras as the respective leaders of the Autobots and Decepticons to the more updated version with Rodimus Prime and Galvatron being the leaders. They even were able to woo Orson Welles into playing the voice of Unicron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Micheal Bay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nnguyen0297
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transformers the movie. What can I say about this movie? Well I guess I can start by saying that it is the most action packed animated film I have ever seen! That's technically what this movie is. It's just 1hr and 20min of non-stop shooting, explosion, fighting,and adventure. Well of course there's more to the plot. The film opens with a giant planet named Unicron that looks like the Death Star eating another planet. Then it shifts to the Autobots who're about to lead a shuttle to search for more energon cubes. Unfortunately for them, The evil Decepticons raids their ship and kill all the members. This really got a lot of fans angry because they saw a lot of their favorite characters die 10 minutes into the movie. The only reason they killed so many characters is so they can add new characters and release more toys. They were taking a big risk killing off so many characters. Anyway, the Decepticons takes over the ship and they are spotted by the Autobot Hot Rod. Hot Rod and some other Autobots attacks the ship, and an all out battle rages. During the battle, Optimus Prime (the leader of the Autobots)confronts Megatron(the leader of the Decepticons). They engage in an all out battles that left all fans cheering because they waited so long to see these two rivals fight to the death. After a while, It seemed that Optimus won, but Megatron played a dirty trick and wounded Optimus pretty badly. But Optimus with all the strength he had left gave Megatron one last punch that left him crippled. The Decepticons escape, and optimus with his last breath, gave the Matrix and his leadership to Ultra Magnus. Mean while, an injured Megatron gets betrayed by his minion Starscream and gets pushed off into space. There, he meets Unicron who makes Megatron one of his minions. In exchange, he gives Megatron a new and more powerful body and rename him Galvatron. He also gives Megatron 3 robots named Relector. With his new power, he kills Starscream and takes over the decepticons again. Now Unicron is forcing him to kill the Autobots and destroy the All Sparks. Now the Autobots have to face Galvatron and Unicron at the same time. I'm not gonna spoil the rest because this is where the movie gets really good. I'm a casual fan of Transformers, and I must say, this film really impressed me. Some people hate it because it had to much violent action, some random music use, and there's to many references to Star Wars. Yes there is a whole bunch of action, but that's what's awesome about it. How many movies have you seen where something blows up every 5 seconds? Yeah, sometimes the action can be a little uneven, and the animation might be laggy from time to time, but this was made in the 80s so give it some slack. There are many references to Star Wars however. Like the character Hot rod is related to Luke, Unicron looks like the Death Star, Arcee has the princess Leah hairstyle, Optimus Prime talks to Hot Rod in his ghost form much like how Ben Kenobi talks to Luke. But i didn't really mind that. So many movies copied things from Star wars up to the point that you don't care anymore. As for the music however, it is completely random. Like when Hot Rod opens the Matrix and the song "The Touch" starts playing in the background. It also has the most random use of Weird Al Yankovic's "Dare to be Stupid". They played that song when the Autobots where fighting some other random robots in some random planet. And after they made peace with those robots, they started dancing to the exact same song! Despite all these negative feature to this film, it's awesome and anyone will love it. I give it~ 3.5/5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relic of the 80s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhtsosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How does it feel to jump back 25 years, into a remnant of your childhood? Does the past hold up with the memories you once associated with it, or will it seem silly and outdated? I recently relived a portion of my childhood in watching the original Transformers cartoon movie from 1986. It is appropriately titled "Transformers: The Movie." I never did see this movie as a child, although I watched the show on and off in some of my early years. I recently decided to watch the movie, partially out of interest to see the movie for the first time, but mainly to relive something out of my childhood. I wanted to see how it would hold up after 15 years of no transformers cartoons. To keep things straight, Transformers is not a "good" movie. The story is heavily episodic and jumpy, as if several TV episodes were crammed together. The quality of animation was alright for its time, but hasn't aged well. The soundtrack is heavy on the 1980s power rock/ pop (think Top Gun), also not having aged well. The movie is cheesy and silly, and in all honesty, somewhat ridiculous. However, the movie, while definitely not good, works as a guilty pleasure fun movie. As dumb as it was viewing it, I highly enjoyed it. With each cheesy line, I was more drawn into it. Viewing it wasn't like the phrase about "you can't turn away from watching a car crash." It was highly nostalgic. A part of me did wonder how we enjoyed such things as kids. While the movie is silly, it is highly exploitive in a sense of how much of it is focused on robot-on- robot action. Movies aren't made like this anymore. Transformers gets in, has no story but a ton of robot fighting, some cheesy 80s tunes to boost the mood, and gets out after 80 minutes. It's almost as if the movie knows exactly what it is, and does exactly what it can do. Transformers doesn't jump out as a must see movie. For people in their 20s and older, it can be charming, as a relic to a different age of TV. For people too young to remember it originally, it will jump out as an example of the questioning "Is this REALLY what you used to watch?" It is pretty much a toy commercial in disguise. However, it is worth viewing, both because it is a pure relic from the 1980s, but also because it comes from a time of more pure filmmaking. Transformers does exactly what it is sent out to do. While it wasn't aiming very high, it works. You could certainly do much worse than checking this out. 6/10. Go download the soundtrack if you need a new workout mix.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheesy Fun for the Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B. Transformers the Movie is a good, cheesy animated movie that ends the well done television series and does some surprising things but is rather entertaining. The war is still going on between the Autobots and Decepticons, but what they don't know is that there is a huge transformer that shaped like a planet heading towards them, devouring everything in its path. The opening battle on Earth is a rather tense one for the Autobots. Their base gets badly destroyed and lose one of their own that made quite a stir with fans after they saw it, Megatron kills Optimus Prime. He gives the Matrix to Ultra Magnus and puts him in charge and the Autobots head away from their base in search for their own who were eaten by the planet transformer, Unicron. Megatron after the battle got badly hurt and Starscream, wanting to be in charge, lets him go into space with others hurt and is picked up by Unicron and is now called Galvatron and working for Unicron.. Galvatron goes to Cybertron in search for Starscream and kills him and now all the Decepticons are his again with his new allies made for him by Unicron. The Autobots fly out, but are attacked by Galvatron and some land on a planet covered with trash and Hot Rod, Cub, and the Dinobots land on another planet. Hot Rod and Cub are taken prisoner and are trialed on how they will die by the planets ruler. Meanwhile, Galvatron went after the group on the rundown planet and they start hunting them and Ultra Magnus tries to use the Matrix for Prime said it will be used in their darkest hour. It doesn't open, and Galvatron blows him up. Then the inhabitants of the planet battle them. Then Cub and Hot Rod show up and save them and the junkbots rebuild Ultra Magnus and go help the Autobots fight Unicron. Meanwhile, Galvatron returns with the Matrix and wants to be in charge but won't and then the Autbots arrive to fight Unicron and save their own while Hot Rod has a final showdown with Galvatron. This is epic with him taking the Matrix and uses it against Unicron and turns into Rodimus Prime. The Decepticons die and the Autobots take back Cybertron. The movie has cheesy animation but is entertaining with some decent music, good characters, and is a great conclusion with a badass villain. Good for the fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'One shall stand, one shall fall..'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    markbyam
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film simply blew me away the first time I saw it. And still does today 20 years later. Right from The opening sequence, to the level of violence between the Decepticons and Autobots (which is totally justified) is spot on. They didn't hold back or try and soften the conflict and it was portrayed superbly. Everything from the soundtrack to the characters, and the dialogue works perfectly. Especially the dialogue which you just wouldn't get in a kids film nowadays. So many good one liners. The speech between Megatron and Prime is just pure brilliance with a fight scene that follows animated to perfection. The voice casting is exceptional and every action sequence is pulled off with such style and finesse. It even has one of the saddest scenes of any film that still makes me teary today. Once very rarely something comes along that just works in every single way...even more. Transformers the movie 1986 is an example of this. I feel privileged to have seen this as a child. Til all are one! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Me Grimlock love this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the release of the explosive Michael Bay trilogy, any newcomers to the shape-shifting franchise should be aware of the original 1986 animated feature because that's where it all started (sort of). Hasbro's Transformers became such a huge hit thanks to a combination of both the toys and the original G1 TV series of the same name. Robots changing into vehicles, guns, and even animals was such an incredible and original concept that it's hard to ignore. After running for two seasons at the time, Hasbro decided to make a full-length movie starring the Autobots and Decepticons. Plot: The year is 2005 (imagine that) as the Autobots, led by the heroic Optimus Prime, prepare to retake their home world Cybertron from the clutches of the evil Megatron and his Decepticons. However, a terrifying intergalactic force has arrived on the scene that's proved to be literally bigger than their petty war, the planet-sized Unicron (Orsen Welles). With the power of this new foe greater than anything imagined, it will take a new generation of heroes to stop this menace. Time to transform and role out! Next to "Revenge of the Fallen", this is by far my favorite film of the franchise. Seeing how the Transformers were before their live-action release was a real pleasure to see. Many of the famous characters, Autobot and Decepticon alike, get to have there little moments of action and glory, especially the Dinobots, who are my all-time favorite characters. The action scenes are just spectacular and it's pretty much non-stop. Call me old-fashioned, but I love the music, which is typical 80s soundtrack and it fits perfectly with this movie, such as Stan Bush's "The Touch" which is made famous because of this movie. The animation is also worth noting, definitely superior to the animation of the TV series. The film also became famous by taking risky moves with the old characters while introducing new ones. Optimus Prime and Megatron (Peter Cullen and Frank Welker) are still going at it as their rivalry never seems to end, though both go through some major changes. The Dinobots are fun to watch and bad to the bone. The other classic Autobots and Decepticons are cool in their own unique ways. Hot Rod makes for a good hero and Kup is a fun old robot who likes to think about the old days of the war. Orson Welles was great as Unicron and we're talking about his final role before he passed away. He provided true menace to his character with his voice; forget "Citizen Kane", Transformers man! There are very few things to nitpick around here, but overall, this movie is definitely worth buying, partly because of the nostalgia factor. With a great story, stellar voice cast, lovable and diverse cast of characters, great action scenes, and fun music, The Transformers The Movie is sure to please any fan. Nine out of ten, so check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The definition of nostalgia . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tanis_38
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no way to objectively review this film. It was my absolute favorite movie as a kid and I wore out my VHS copy. Seeing it now as an adult, I cannot see it through anything but child- like eyes and with overwhelming feelings of happy, sweet, nostalgia. Is it a great movie? I am not sure. Is the soundtrack cheesy 80's rock? Maybe. Is it my favorite Transformers movie? Absolutely. Will it always bring a smile to my face? I have one right now just thinking about it. Sure, the animation is wildly inconsistent, going from pretty amazing to laughably bad "Sunday Morning cartoon fare" from scene to scene. Sure, it can be seen as one big commercial for the future toy products of the series. But none of that matters when you are 8 years old. The Optimus Prime death scene was borderline traumatizing. The film is surprisingly violent by today's standards and outright gutsy in its willingness to kill off series regulars. It held no punches and if you were a kid in the 80's there is no way you can hear "You Got the Touch" and not smile, picturing Optimus Prime going to town on the Decepticons. This will always be in my top favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie with Transformers that has real emotion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevenbeech
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the first of the new Transformers movies and I can honestly say that the best thing in that film was Bernie Mac. 2 and a quarter hours of blowing stuff up isn't a movie. This is a movie. This is a movie that has real heart, real emotion, real themes at its core and one of the best film soundtracks ever. Sure there a bits where it drags a little and you want it to get back to the main action but it all makes sense in the end. This film probably won't make a massive amount of sense to the average 12 year old I must say, but to the 30 somethings amongst us it carries a great deal of our childhoods with it and along with that I feel a massive emotional attachment to it. The film deals with themes such as loyalty, friendship, the transition from youth to adulthood, the acceptance of responsibility, respect for elders, working toward a common goal and much else all backed by a superb 80's soft metal soundtrack composed by the much underrated Stan Bush. The soundtrack is the driving force behind much of the emotion of the movie, watch the scene where Hot Rod becomes Rodimus Prime without The Touch and its nowhere near as effective. Watch Optimus take out the decepticons without The Touch and you won't pull for him. Watch Hot Rod and Kup escape the Sharkticons without Dare playing and it doesn't work as well. This is a movie worth seeing. If only to compare it to the newer rebooted films which are technically superior and have had more spent on the catering for the cast than this movie probably cost to make but don't have the plot lines, heart, story or sheer entertainment value that this 80's throwback does.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Depressing first, then confusing and becoming more uninteresting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martyshoemark
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Transformers: The Movie was not as good as any of the episodes from the Generation One cartoon episodes from Seasons 1 to 2. Season 2 was an abundance of entertaining adventures of the Transformers in which both evil and justice battle each other while suffering the same troubles. The movie had clearly killed off so many beloved characters besides Prime, these included Prowl, Brawn, Ironhide, Ratchet, Wheeljack, and Starscream. However, the music and dramatic atmosphere of their death scenes were made to appear as if their deaths would not be tragic for the TV show audiences. The film quickly rushed into bringing upon new characters that hardly were introduced as well. The movie seemed to have just taken a not-so-much-of-an-advantage portion of its' length to add in complex plot structures that don't affect the main story of the movie, but instead to make sure this will be a bridge to Season 3 in the TV show. The Quintessons' entrance was clearly unnecessary in the plot and was only put in so that Season 3 can be established right away. The main villain of the story, Unicron, is really simple, he's just a misanthrope who wants to destroy EVERYTHING. Why? We don't know, that's just trying to make a character as a big, simple problem, which is a weak point common in several fictional stories. His voice actor, Orson Welles, was correct that this story is about a big toy attacking smaller toys. A lot of the plot was cheaply winged off of Star Wars such as the light sabers sounds, Arcee's cinnamon bun hairstyle like Leia's, and especially the climax between Hot Rod and Galvatron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly more that meets the Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TJMBuddlake
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though, i was born in 89, i still somehow grew to love transformers. I used to watch the old cartoons on reruns (now you can watch it on Toonamiaftermath.com) and I loved every bit of it. Now, 13 or so years later, I was able to finally get a copy of this movie and got a chance to watch it. OH MY GOD! This is the best transformers movie (better than the live action ones). The story was awesome, the voice cast was phenomenal. Peter Cullen, Casey Kasem, Judd Nelson, Leonard Nimoy and Orson Welles did a great job. Of course, i'm happy that all my favorites were featured (Cliffjumper and Hot Rod). This was definitely a defining moment for the transformers. In addition, the music was awesome. Stan Bush is freaking amazing. The song, The Touch will never get old. This is definitely one for any fans of the franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Transformer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Including this animated movie and the 3 live action Michael Bay movies from the Transformers universe this is by far the best version of a story about TF. The movie has its cheesy moments but it's what I enjoyed about the TF TV show and toy line of the 1980's when I was a kid. If I knew that Bay would bastardize the series like he has with a bunch of penis, fart jokes, racism and Shia LaBeouf I don't think I would've ever bothered to watch any of his movies about TF. The movie is basically TF trying to transition from their early toy lines with the Optimus Prime and MMegatron eras as the respective leaders of the Autobots and Decepticons to the more updated version with Rodimus Prime and Galvatron being the leaders. They even were able to woo Orson Welles into playing the voice of Unicron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Micheal Bay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nnguyen0297
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transformers the movie. What can I say about this movie? Well I guess I can start by saying that it is the most action packed animated film I have ever seen! That's technically what this movie is. It's just 1hr and 20min of non-stop shooting, explosion, fighting,and adventure. Well of course there's more to the plot. The film opens with a giant planet named Unicron that looks like the Death Star eating another planet. Then it shifts to the Autobots who're about to lead a shuttle to search for more energon cubes. Unfortunately for them, The evil Decepticons raids their ship and kill all the members. This really got a lot of fans angry because they saw a lot of their favorite characters die 10 minutes into the movie. The only reason they killed so many characters is so they can add new characters and release more toys. They were taking a big risk killing off so many characters. Anyway, the Decepticons takes over the ship and they are spotted by the Autobot Hot Rod. Hot Rod and some other Autobots attacks the ship, and an all out battle rages. During the battle, Optimus Prime (the leader of the Autobots)confronts Megatron(the leader of the Decepticons). They engage in an all out battles that left all fans cheering because they waited so long to see these two rivals fight to the death. After a while, It seemed that Optimus won, but Megatron played a dirty trick and wounded Optimus pretty badly. But Optimus with all the strength he had left gave Megatron one last punch that left him crippled. The Decepticons escape, and optimus with his last breath, gave the Matrix and his leadership to Ultra Magnus. Mean while, an injured Megatron gets betrayed by his minion Starscream and gets pushed off into space. There, he meets Unicron who makes Megatron one of his minions. In exchange, he gives Megatron a new and more powerful body and rename him Galvatron. He also gives Megatron 3 robots named Relector. With his new power, he kills Starscream and takes over the decepticons again. Now Unicron is forcing him to kill the Autobots and destroy the All Sparks. Now the Autobots have to face Galvatron and Unicron at the same time. I'm not gonna spoil the rest because this is where the movie gets really good. I'm a casual fan of Transformers, and I must say, this film really impressed me. Some people hate it because it had to much violent action, some random music use, and there's to many references to Star Wars. Yes there is a whole bunch of action, but that's what's awesome about it. How many movies have you seen where something blows up every 5 seconds? Yeah, sometimes the action can be a little uneven, and the animation might be laggy from time to time, but this was made in the 80s so give it some slack. There are many references to Star Wars however. Like the character Hot rod is related to Luke, Unicron looks like the Death Star, Arcee has the princess Leah hairstyle, Optimus Prime talks to Hot Rod in his ghost form much like how Ben Kenobi talks to Luke. But i didn't really mind that. So many movies copied things from Star wars up to the point that you don't care anymore. As for the music however, it is completely random. Like when Hot Rod opens the Matrix and the song "The Touch" starts playing in the background. It also has the most random use of Weird Al Yankovic's "Dare to be Stupid". They played that song when the Autobots where fighting some other random robots in some random planet. And after they made peace with those robots, they started dancing to the exact same song! Despite all these negative feature to this film, it's awesome and anyone will love it. I give it~ 3.5/5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relic of the 80s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhtsosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How does it feel to jump back 25 years, into a remnant of your childhood? Does the past hold up with the memories you once associated with it, or will it seem silly and outdated? I recently relived a portion of my childhood in watching the original Transformers cartoon movie from 1986. It is appropriately titled "Transformers: The Movie." I never did see this movie as a child, although I watched the show on and off in some of my early years. I recently decided to watch the movie, partially out of interest to see the movie for the first time, but mainly to relive something out of my childhood. I wanted to see how it would hold up after 15 years of no transformers cartoons. To keep things straight, Transformers is not a "good" movie. The story is heavily episodic and jumpy, as if several TV episodes were crammed together. The quality of animation was alright for its time, but hasn't aged well. The soundtrack is heavy on the 1980s power rock/ pop (think Top Gun), also not having aged well. The movie is cheesy and silly, and in all honesty, somewhat ridiculous. However, the movie, while definitely not good, works as a guilty pleasure fun movie. As dumb as it was viewing it, I highly enjoyed it. With each cheesy line, I was more drawn into it. Viewing it wasn't like the phrase about "you can't turn away from watching a car crash." It was highly nostalgic. A part of me did wonder how we enjoyed such things as kids. While the movie is silly, it is highly exploitive in a sense of how much of it is focused on robot-on- robot action. Movies aren't made like this anymore. Transformers gets in, has no story but a ton of robot fighting, some cheesy 80s tunes to boost the mood, and gets out after 80 minutes. It's almost as if the movie knows exactly what it is, and does exactly what it can do. Transformers doesn't jump out as a must see movie. For people in their 20s and older, it can be charming, as a relic to a different age of TV. For people too young to remember it originally, it will jump out as an example of the questioning "Is this REALLY what you used to watch?" It is pretty much a toy commercial in disguise. However, it is worth viewing, both because it is a pure relic from the 1980s, but also because it comes from a time of more pure filmmaking. Transformers does exactly what it is sent out to do. While it wasn't aiming very high, it works. You could certainly do much worse than checking this out. 6/10. Go download the soundtrack if you need a new workout mix.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheesy Fun for the Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B. Transformers the Movie is a good, cheesy animated movie that ends the well done television series and does some surprising things but is rather entertaining. The war is still going on between the Autobots and Decepticons, but what they don't know is that there is a huge transformer that shaped like a planet heading towards them, devouring everything in its path. The opening battle on Earth is a rather tense one for the Autobots. Their base gets badly destroyed and lose one of their own that made quite a stir with fans after they saw it, Megatron kills Optimus Prime. He gives the Matrix to Ultra Magnus and puts him in charge and the Autobots head away from their base in search for their own who were eaten by the planet transformer, Unicron. Megatron after the battle got badly hurt and Starscream, wanting to be in charge, lets him go into space with others hurt and is picked up by Unicron and is now called Galvatron and working for Unicron.. Galvatron goes to Cybertron in search for Starscream and kills him and now all the Decepticons are his again with his new allies made for him by Unicron. The Autobots fly out, but are attacked by Galvatron and some land on a planet covered with trash and Hot Rod, Cub, and the Dinobots land on another planet. Hot Rod and Cub are taken prisoner and are trialed on how they will die by the planets ruler. Meanwhile, Galvatron went after the group on the rundown planet and they start hunting them and Ultra Magnus tries to use the Matrix for Prime said it will be used in their darkest hour. It doesn't open, and Galvatron blows him up. Then the inhabitants of the planet battle them. Then Cub and Hot Rod show up and save them and the junkbots rebuild Ultra Magnus and go help the Autobots fight Unicron. Meanwhile, Galvatron returns with the Matrix and wants to be in charge but won't and then the Autbots arrive to fight Unicron and save their own while Hot Rod has a final showdown with Galvatron. This is epic with him taking the Matrix and uses it against Unicron and turns into Rodimus Prime. The Decepticons die and the Autobots take back Cybertron. The movie has cheesy animation but is entertaining with some decent music, good characters, and is a great conclusion with a badass villain. Good for the fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'One shall stand, one shall fall..'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    markbyam
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film simply blew me away the first time I saw it. And still does today 20 years later. Right from The opening sequence, to the level of violence between the Decepticons and Autobots (which is totally justified) is spot on. They didn't hold back or try and soften the conflict and it was portrayed superbly. Everything from the soundtrack to the characters, and the dialogue works perfectly. Especially the dialogue which you just wouldn't get in a kids film nowadays. So many good one liners. The speech between Megatron and Prime is just pure brilliance with a fight scene that follows animated to perfection. The voice casting is exceptional and every action sequence is pulled off with such style and finesse. It even has one of the saddest scenes of any film that still makes me teary today. Once very rarely something comes along that just works in every single way...even more. Transformers the movie 1986 is an example of this. I feel privileged to have seen this as a child. Til all are one! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Me Grimlock love this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the release of the explosive Michael Bay trilogy, any newcomers to the shape-shifting franchise should be aware of the original 1986 animated feature because that's where it all started (sort of). Hasbro's Transformers became such a huge hit thanks to a combination of both the toys and the original G1 TV series of the same name. Robots changing into vehicles, guns, and even animals was such an incredible and original concept that it's hard to ignore. After running for two seasons at the time, Hasbro decided to make a full-length movie starring the Autobots and Decepticons. Plot: The year is 2005 (imagine that) as the Autobots, led by the heroic Optimus Prime, prepare to retake their home world Cybertron from the clutches of the evil Megatron and his Decepticons. However, a terrifying intergalactic force has arrived on the scene that's proved to be literally bigger than their petty war, the planet-sized Unicron (Orsen Welles). With the power of this new foe greater than anything imagined, it will take a new generation of heroes to stop this menace. Time to transform and role out! Next to "Revenge of the Fallen", this is by far my favorite film of the franchise. Seeing how the Transformers were before their live-action release was a real pleasure to see. Many of the famous characters, Autobot and Decepticon alike, get to have there little moments of action and glory, especially the Dinobots, who are my all-time favorite characters. The action scenes are just spectacular and it's pretty much non-stop. Call me old-fashioned, but I love the music, which is typical 80s soundtrack and it fits perfectly with this movie, such as Stan Bush's "The Touch" which is made famous because of this movie. The animation is also worth noting, definitely superior to the animation of the TV series. The film also became famous by taking risky moves with the old characters while introducing new ones. Optimus Prime and Megatron (Peter Cullen and Frank Welker) are still going at it as their rivalry never seems to end, though both go through some major changes. The Dinobots are fun to watch and bad to the bone. The other classic Autobots and Decepticons are cool in their own unique ways. Hot Rod makes for a good hero and Kup is a fun old robot who likes to think about the old days of the war. Orson Welles was great as Unicron and we're talking about his final role before he passed away. He provided true menace to his character with his voice; forget "Citizen Kane", Transformers man! There are very few things to nitpick around here, but overall, this movie is definitely worth buying, partly because of the nostalgia factor. With a great story, stellar voice cast, lovable and diverse cast of characters, great action scenes, and fun music, The Transformers The Movie is sure to please any fan. Nine out of ten, so check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The definition of nostalgia . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tanis_38
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no way to objectively review this film. It was my absolute favorite movie as a kid and I wore out my VHS copy. Seeing it now as an adult, I cannot see it through anything but child- like eyes and with overwhelming feelings of happy, sweet, nostalgia. Is it a great movie? I am not sure. Is the soundtrack cheesy 80's rock? Maybe. Is it my favorite Transformers movie? Absolutely. Will it always bring a smile to my face? I have one right now just thinking about it. Sure, the animation is wildly inconsistent, going from pretty amazing to laughably bad "Sunday Morning cartoon fare" from scene to scene. Sure, it can be seen as one big commercial for the future toy products of the series. But none of that matters when you are 8 years old. The Optimus Prime death scene was borderline traumatizing. The film is surprisingly violent by today's standards and outright gutsy in its willingness to kill off series regulars. It held no punches and if you were a kid in the 80's there is no way you can hear "You Got the Touch" and not smile, picturing Optimus Prime going to town on the Decepticons. This will always be in my top favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie with Transformers that has real emotion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevenbeech
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the first of the new Transformers movies and I can honestly say that the best thing in that film was Bernie Mac. 2 and a quarter hours of blowing stuff up isn't a movie. This is a movie. This is a movie that has real heart, real emotion, real themes at its core and one of the best film soundtracks ever. Sure there a bits where it drags a little and you want it to get back to the main action but it all makes sense in the end. This film probably won't make a massive amount of sense to the average 12 year old I must say, but to the 30 somethings amongst us it carries a great deal of our childhoods with it and along with that I feel a massive emotional attachment to it. The film deals with themes such as loyalty, friendship, the transition from youth to adulthood, the acceptance of responsibility, respect for elders, working toward a common goal and much else all backed by a superb 80's soft metal soundtrack composed by the much underrated Stan Bush. The soundtrack is the driving force behind much of the emotion of the movie, watch the scene where Hot Rod becomes Rodimus Prime without The Touch and its nowhere near as effective. Watch Optimus take out the decepticons without The Touch and you won't pull for him. Watch Hot Rod and Kup escape the Sharkticons without Dare playing and it doesn't work as well. This is a movie worth seeing. If only to compare it to the newer rebooted films which are technically superior and have had more spent on the catering for the cast than this movie probably cost to make but don't have the plot lines, heart, story or sheer entertainment value that this 80's throwback does.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Depressing first, then confusing and becoming more uninteresting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martyshoemark
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Transformers: The Movie was not as good as any of the episodes from the Generation One cartoon episodes from Seasons 1 to 2. Season 2 was an abundance of entertaining adventures of the Transformers in which both evil and justice battle each other while suffering the same troubles. The movie had clearly killed off so many beloved characters besides Prime, these included Prowl, Brawn, Ironhide, Ratchet, Wheeljack, and Starscream. However, the music and dramatic atmosphere of their death scenes were made to appear as if their deaths would not be tragic for the TV show audiences. The film quickly rushed into bringing upon new characters that hardly were introduced as well. The movie seemed to have just taken a not-so-much-of-an-advantage portion of its' length to add in complex plot structures that don't affect the main story of the movie, but instead to make sure this will be a bridge to Season 3 in the TV show. The Quintessons' entrance was clearly unnecessary in the plot and was only put in so that Season 3 can be established right away. The main villain of the story, Unicron, is really simple, he's just a misanthrope who wants to destroy EVERYTHING. Why? We don't know, that's just trying to make a character as a big, simple problem, which is a weak point common in several fictional stories. His voice actor, Orson Welles, was correct that this story is about a big toy attacking smaller toys. A lot of the plot was cheaply winged off of Star Wars such as the light sabers sounds, Arcee's cinnamon bun hairstyle like Leia's, and especially the climax between Hot Rod and Galvatron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly more that meets the Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TJMBuddlake
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though, i was born in 89, i still somehow grew to love transformers. I used to watch the old cartoons on reruns (now you can watch it on Toonamiaftermath.com) and I loved every bit of it. Now, 13 or so years later, I was able to finally get a copy of this movie and got a chance to watch it. OH MY GOD! This is the best transformers movie (better than the live action ones). The story was awesome, the voice cast was phenomenal. Peter Cullen, Casey Kasem, Judd Nelson, Leonard Nimoy and Orson Welles did a great job. Of course, i'm happy that all my favorites were featured (Cliffjumper and Hot Rod). This was definitely a defining moment for the transformers. In addition, the music was awesome. Stan Bush is freaking amazing. The song, The Touch will never get old. This is definitely one for any fans of the franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Transformer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Including this animated movie and the 3 live action Michael Bay movies from the Transformers universe this is by far the best version of a story about TF. The movie has its cheesy moments but it's what I enjoyed about the TF TV show and toy line of the 1980's when I was a kid. If I knew that Bay would bastardize the series like he has with a bunch of penis, fart jokes, racism and Shia LaBeouf I don't think I would've ever bothered to watch any of his movies about TF. The movie is basically TF trying to transition from their early toy lines with the Optimus Prime and MMegatron eras as the respective leaders of the Autobots and Decepticons to the more updated version with Rodimus Prime and Galvatron being the leaders. They even were able to woo Orson Welles into playing the voice of Unicron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Micheal Bay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nnguyen0297
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transformers the movie. What can I say about this movie? Well I guess I can start by saying that it is the most action packed animated film I have ever seen! That's technically what this movie is. It's just 1hr and 20min of non-stop shooting, explosion, fighting,and adventure. Well of course there's more to the plot. The film opens with a giant planet named Unicron that looks like the Death Star eating another planet. Then it shifts to the Autobots who're about to lead a shuttle to search for more energon cubes. Unfortunately for them, The evil Decepticons raids their ship and kill all the members. This really got a lot of fans angry because they saw a lot of their favorite characters die 10 minutes into the movie. The only reason they killed so many characters is so they can add new characters and release more toys. They were taking a big risk killing off so many characters. Anyway, the Decepticons takes over the ship and they are spotted by the Autobot Hot Rod. Hot Rod and some other Autobots attacks the ship, and an all out battle rages. During the battle, Optimus Prime (the leader of the Autobots)confronts Megatron(the leader of the Decepticons). They engage in an all out battles that left all fans cheering because they waited so long to see these two rivals fight to the death. After a while, It seemed that Optimus won, but Megatron played a dirty trick and wounded Optimus pretty badly. But Optimus with all the strength he had left gave Megatron one last punch that left him crippled. The Decepticons escape, and optimus with his last breath, gave the Matrix and his leadership to Ultra Magnus. Mean while, an injured Megatron gets betrayed by his minion Starscream and gets pushed off into space. There, he meets Unicron who makes Megatron one of his minions. In exchange, he gives Megatron a new and more powerful body and rename him Galvatron. He also gives Megatron 3 robots named Relector. With his new power, he kills Starscream and takes over the decepticons again. Now Unicron is forcing him to kill the Autobots and destroy the All Sparks. Now the Autobots have to face Galvatron and Unicron at the same time. I'm not gonna spoil the rest because this is where the movie gets really good. I'm a casual fan of Transformers, and I must say, this film really impressed me. Some people hate it because it had to much violent action, some random music use, and there's to many references to Star Wars. Yes there is a whole bunch of action, but that's what's awesome about it. How many movies have you seen where something blows up every 5 seconds? Yeah, sometimes the action can be a little uneven, and the animation might be laggy from time to time, but this was made in the 80s so give it some slack. There are many references to Star Wars however. Like the character Hot rod is related to Luke, Unicron looks like the Death Star, Arcee has the princess Leah hairstyle, Optimus Prime talks to Hot Rod in his ghost form much like how Ben Kenobi talks to Luke. But i didn't really mind that. So many movies copied things from Star wars up to the point that you don't care anymore. As for the music however, it is completely random. Like when Hot Rod opens the Matrix and the song "The Touch" starts playing in the background. It also has the most random use of Weird Al Yankovic's "Dare to be Stupid". They played that song when the Autobots where fighting some other random robots in some random planet. And after they made peace with those robots, they started dancing to the exact same song! Despite all these negative feature to this film, it's awesome and anyone will love it. I give it~ 3.5/5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relic of the 80s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhtsosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How does it feel to jump back 25 years, into a remnant of your childhood? Does the past hold up with the memories you once associated with it, or will it seem silly and outdated? I recently relived a portion of my childhood in watching the original Transformers cartoon movie from 1986. It is appropriately titled "Transformers: The Movie." I never did see this movie as a child, although I watched the show on and off in some of my early years. I recently decided to watch the movie, partially out of interest to see the movie for the first time, but mainly to relive something out of my childhood. I wanted to see how it would hold up after 15 years of no transformers cartoons. To keep things straight, Transformers is not a "good" movie. The story is heavily episodic and jumpy, as if several TV episodes were crammed together. The quality of animation was alright for its time, but hasn't aged well. The soundtrack is heavy on the 1980s power rock/ pop (think Top Gun), also not having aged well. The movie is cheesy and silly, and in all honesty, somewhat ridiculous. However, the movie, while definitely not good, works as a guilty pleasure fun movie. As dumb as it was viewing it, I highly enjoyed it. With each cheesy line, I was more drawn into it. Viewing it wasn't like the phrase about "you can't turn away from watching a car crash." It was highly nostalgic. A part of me did wonder how we enjoyed such things as kids. While the movie is silly, it is highly exploitive in a sense of how much of it is focused on robot-on- robot action. Movies aren't made like this anymore. Transformers gets in, has no story but a ton of robot fighting, some cheesy 80s tunes to boost the mood, and gets out after 80 minutes. It's almost as if the movie knows exactly what it is, and does exactly what it can do. Transformers doesn't jump out as a must see movie. For people in their 20s and older, it can be charming, as a relic to a different age of TV. For people too young to remember it originally, it will jump out as an example of the questioning "Is this REALLY what you used to watch?" It is pretty much a toy commercial in disguise. However, it is worth viewing, both because it is a pure relic from the 1980s, but also because it comes from a time of more pure filmmaking. Transformers does exactly what it is sent out to do. While it wasn't aiming very high, it works. You could certainly do much worse than checking this out. 6/10. Go download the soundtrack if you need a new workout mix.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheesy Fun for the Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B. Transformers the Movie is a good, cheesy animated movie that ends the well done television series and does some surprising things but is rather entertaining. The war is still going on between the Autobots and Decepticons, but what they don't know is that there is a huge transformer that shaped like a planet heading towards them, devouring everything in its path. The opening battle on Earth is a rather tense one for the Autobots. Their base gets badly destroyed and lose one of their own that made quite a stir with fans after they saw it, Megatron kills Optimus Prime. He gives the Matrix to Ultra Magnus and puts him in charge and the Autobots head away from their base in search for their own who were eaten by the planet transformer, Unicron. Megatron after the battle got badly hurt and Starscream, wanting to be in charge, lets him go into space with others hurt and is picked up by Unicron and is now called Galvatron and working for Unicron.. Galvatron goes to Cybertron in search for Starscream and kills him and now all the Decepticons are his again with his new allies made for him by Unicron. The Autobots fly out, but are attacked by Galvatron and some land on a planet covered with trash and Hot Rod, Cub, and the Dinobots land on another planet. Hot Rod and Cub are taken prisoner and are trialed on how they will die by the planets ruler. Meanwhile, Galvatron went after the group on the rundown planet and they start hunting them and Ultra Magnus tries to use the Matrix for Prime said it will be used in their darkest hour. It doesn't open, and Galvatron blows him up. Then the inhabitants of the planet battle them. Then Cub and Hot Rod show up and save them and the junkbots rebuild Ultra Magnus and go help the Autobots fight Unicron. Meanwhile, Galvatron returns with the Matrix and wants to be in charge but won't and then the Autbots arrive to fight Unicron and save their own while Hot Rod has a final showdown with Galvatron. This is epic with him taking the Matrix and uses it against Unicron and turns into Rodimus Prime. The Decepticons die and the Autobots take back Cybertron. The movie has cheesy animation but is entertaining with some decent music, good characters, and is a great conclusion with a badass villain. Good for the fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'One shall stand, one shall fall..'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    markbyam
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film simply blew me away the first time I saw it. And still does today 20 years later. Right from The opening sequence, to the level of violence between the Decepticons and Autobots (which is totally justified) is spot on. They didn't hold back or try and soften the conflict and it was portrayed superbly. Everything from the soundtrack to the characters, and the dialogue works perfectly. Especially the dialogue which you just wouldn't get in a kids film nowadays. So many good one liners. The speech between Megatron and Prime is just pure brilliance with a fight scene that follows animated to perfection. The voice casting is exceptional and every action sequence is pulled off with such style and finesse. It even has one of the saddest scenes of any film that still makes me teary today. Once very rarely something comes along that just works in every single way...even more. Transformers the movie 1986 is an example of this. I feel privileged to have seen this as a child. Til all are one! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Me Grimlock love this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the release of the explosive Michael Bay trilogy, any newcomers to the shape-shifting franchise should be aware of the original 1986 animated feature because that's where it all started (sort of). Hasbro's Transformers became such a huge hit thanks to a combination of both the toys and the original G1 TV series of the same name. Robots changing into vehicles, guns, and even animals was such an incredible and original concept that it's hard to ignore. After running for two seasons at the time, Hasbro decided to make a full-length movie starring the Autobots and Decepticons. Plot: The year is 2005 (imagine that) as the Autobots, led by the heroic Optimus Prime, prepare to retake their home world Cybertron from the clutches of the evil Megatron and his Decepticons. However, a terrifying intergalactic force has arrived on the scene that's proved to be literally bigger than their petty war, the planet-sized Unicron (Orsen Welles). With the power of this new foe greater than anything imagined, it will take a new generation of heroes to stop this menace. Time to transform and role out! Next to "Revenge of the Fallen", this is by far my favorite film of the franchise. Seeing how the Transformers were before their live-action release was a real pleasure to see. Many of the famous characters, Autobot and Decepticon alike, get to have there little moments of action and glory, especially the Dinobots, who are my all-time favorite characters. The action scenes are just spectacular and it's pretty much non-stop. Call me old-fashioned, but I love the music, which is typical 80s soundtrack and it fits perfectly with this movie, such as Stan Bush's "The Touch" which is made famous because of this movie. The animation is also worth noting, definitely superior to the animation of the TV series. The film also became famous by taking risky moves with the old characters while introducing new ones. Optimus Prime and Megatron (Peter Cullen and Frank Welker) are still going at it as their rivalry never seems to end, though both go through some major changes. The Dinobots are fun to watch and bad to the bone. The other classic Autobots and Decepticons are cool in their own unique ways. Hot Rod makes for a good hero and Kup is a fun old robot who likes to think about the old days of the war. Orson Welles was great as Unicron and we're talking about his final role before he passed away. He provided true menace to his character with his voice; forget "Citizen Kane", Transformers man! There are very few things to nitpick around here, but overall, this movie is definitely worth buying, partly because of the nostalgia factor. With a great story, stellar voice cast, lovable and diverse cast of characters, great action scenes, and fun music, The Transformers The Movie is sure to please any fan. Nine out of ten, so check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The definition of nostalgia . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tanis_38
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no way to objectively review this film. It was my absolute favorite movie as a kid and I wore out my VHS copy. Seeing it now as an adult, I cannot see it through anything but child- like eyes and with overwhelming feelings of happy, sweet, nostalgia. Is it a great movie? I am not sure. Is the soundtrack cheesy 80's rock? Maybe. Is it my favorite Transformers movie? Absolutely. Will it always bring a smile to my face? I have one right now just thinking about it. Sure, the animation is wildly inconsistent, going from pretty amazing to laughably bad "Sunday Morning cartoon fare" from scene to scene. Sure, it can be seen as one big commercial for the future toy products of the series. But none of that matters when you are 8 years old. The Optimus Prime death scene was borderline traumatizing. The film is surprisingly violent by today's standards and outright gutsy in its willingness to kill off series regulars. It held no punches and if you were a kid in the 80's there is no way you can hear "You Got the Touch" and not smile, picturing Optimus Prime going to town on the Decepticons. This will always be in my top favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie with Transformers that has real emotion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevenbeech
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the first of the new Transformers movies and I can honestly say that the best thing in that film was Bernie Mac. 2 and a quarter hours of blowing stuff up isn't a movie. This is a movie. This is a movie that has real heart, real emotion, real themes at its core and one of the best film soundtracks ever. Sure there a bits where it drags a little and you want it to get back to the main action but it all makes sense in the end. This film probably won't make a massive amount of sense to the average 12 year old I must say, but to the 30 somethings amongst us it carries a great deal of our childhoods with it and along with that I feel a massive emotional attachment to it. The film deals with themes such as loyalty, friendship, the transition from youth to adulthood, the acceptance of responsibility, respect for elders, working toward a common goal and much else all backed by a superb 80's soft metal soundtrack composed by the much underrated Stan Bush. The soundtrack is the driving force behind much of the emotion of the movie, watch the scene where Hot Rod becomes Rodimus Prime without The Touch and its nowhere near as effective. Watch Optimus take out the decepticons without The Touch and you won't pull for him. Watch Hot Rod and Kup escape the Sharkticons without Dare playing and it doesn't work as well. This is a movie worth seeing. If only to compare it to the newer rebooted films which are technically superior and have had more spent on the catering for the cast than this movie probably cost to make but don't have the plot lines, heart, story or sheer entertainment value that this 80's throwback does.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Depressing first, then confusing and becoming more uninteresting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martyshoemark
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Transformers: The Movie was not as good as any of the episodes from the Generation One cartoon episodes from Seasons 1 to 2. Season 2 was an abundance of entertaining adventures of the Transformers in which both evil and justice battle each other while suffering the same troubles. The movie had clearly killed off so many beloved characters besides Prime, these included Prowl, Brawn, Ironhide, Ratchet, Wheeljack, and Starscream. However, the music and dramatic atmosphere of their death scenes were made to appear as if their deaths would not be tragic for the TV show audiences. The film quickly rushed into bringing upon new characters that hardly were introduced as well. The movie seemed to have just taken a not-so-much-of-an-advantage portion of its' length to add in complex plot structures that don't affect the main story of the movie, but instead to make sure this will be a bridge to Season 3 in the TV show. The Quintessons' entrance was clearly unnecessary in the plot and was only put in so that Season 3 can be established right away. The main villain of the story, Unicron, is really simple, he's just a misanthrope who wants to destroy EVERYTHING. Why? We don't know, that's just trying to make a character as a big, simple problem, which is a weak point common in several fictional stories. His voice actor, Orson Welles, was correct that this story is about a big toy attacking smaller toys. A lot of the plot was cheaply winged off of Star Wars such as the light sabers sounds, Arcee's cinnamon bun hairstyle like Leia's, and especially the climax between Hot Rod and Galvatron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly more that meets the Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TJMBuddlake
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though, i was born in 89, i still somehow grew to love transformers. I used to watch the old cartoons on reruns (now you can watch it on Toonamiaftermath.com) and I loved every bit of it. Now, 13 or so years later, I was able to finally get a copy of this movie and got a chance to watch it. OH MY GOD! This is the best transformers movie (better than the live action ones). The story was awesome, the voice cast was phenomenal. Peter Cullen, Casey Kasem, Judd Nelson, Leonard Nimoy and Orson Welles did a great job. Of course, i'm happy that all my favorites were featured (Cliffjumper and Hot Rod). This was definitely a defining moment for the transformers. In addition, the music was awesome. Stan Bush is freaking amazing. The song, The Touch will never get old. This is definitely one for any fans of the franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Transformer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Including this animated movie and the 3 live action Michael Bay movies from the Transformers universe this is by far the best version of a story about TF. The movie has its cheesy moments but it's what I enjoyed about the TF TV show and toy line of the 1980's when I was a kid. If I knew that Bay would bastardize the series like he has with a bunch of penis, fart jokes, racism and Shia LaBeouf I don't think I would've ever bothered to watch any of his movies about TF. The movie is basically TF trying to transition from their early toy lines with the Optimus Prime and MMegatron eras as the respective leaders of the Autobots and Decepticons to the more updated version with Rodimus Prime and Galvatron being the leaders. They even were able to woo Orson Welles into playing the voice of Unicron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Micheal Bay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nnguyen0297
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transformers the movie. What can I say about this movie? Well I guess I can start by saying that it is the most action packed animated film I have ever seen! That's technically what this movie is. It's just 1hr and 20min of non-stop shooting, explosion, fighting,and adventure. Well of course there's more to the plot. The film opens with a giant planet named Unicron that looks like the Death Star eating another planet. Then it shifts to the Autobots who're about to lead a shuttle to search for more energon cubes. Unfortunately for them, The evil Decepticons raids their ship and kill all the members. This really got a lot of fans angry because they saw a lot of their favorite characters die 10 minutes into the movie. The only reason they killed so many characters is so they can add new characters and release more toys. They were taking a big risk killing off so many characters. Anyway, the Decepticons takes over the ship and they are spotted by the Autobot Hot Rod. Hot Rod and some other Autobots attacks the ship, and an all out battle rages. During the battle, Optimus Prime (the leader of the Autobots)confronts Megatron(the leader of the Decepticons). They engage in an all out battles that left all fans cheering because they waited so long to see these two rivals fight to the death. After a while, It seemed that Optimus won, but Megatron played a dirty trick and wounded Optimus pretty badly. But Optimus with all the strength he had left gave Megatron one last punch that left him crippled. The Decepticons escape, and optimus with his last breath, gave the Matrix and his leadership to Ultra Magnus. Mean while, an injured Megatron gets betrayed by his minion Starscream and gets pushed off into space. There, he meets Unicron who makes Megatron one of his minions. In exchange, he gives Megatron a new and more powerful body and rename him Galvatron. He also gives Megatron 3 robots named Relector. With his new power, he kills Starscream and takes over the decepticons again. Now Unicron is forcing him to kill the Autobots and destroy the All Sparks. Now the Autobots have to face Galvatron and Unicron at the same time. I'm not gonna spoil the rest because this is where the movie gets really good. I'm a casual fan of Transformers, and I must say, this film really impressed me. Some people hate it because it had to much violent action, some random music use, and there's to many references to Star Wars. Yes there is a whole bunch of action, but that's what's awesome about it. How many movies have you seen where something blows up every 5 seconds? Yeah, sometimes the action can be a little uneven, and the animation might be laggy from time to time, but this was made in the 80s so give it some slack. There are many references to Star Wars however. Like the character Hot rod is related to Luke, Unicron looks like the Death Star, Arcee has the princess Leah hairstyle, Optimus Prime talks to Hot Rod in his ghost form much like how Ben Kenobi talks to Luke. But i didn't really mind that. So many movies copied things from Star wars up to the point that you don't care anymore. As for the music however, it is completely random. Like when Hot Rod opens the Matrix and the song "The Touch" starts playing in the background. It also has the most random use of Weird Al Yankovic's "Dare to be Stupid". They played that song when the Autobots where fighting some other random robots in some random planet. And after they made peace with those robots, they started dancing to the exact same song! Despite all these negative feature to this film, it's awesome and anyone will love it. I give it~ 3.5/5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relic of the 80s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhtsosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How does it feel to jump back 25 years, into a remnant of your childhood? Does the past hold up with the memories you once associated with it, or will it seem silly and outdated? I recently relived a portion of my childhood in watching the original Transformers cartoon movie from 1986. It is appropriately titled "Transformers: The Movie." I never did see this movie as a child, although I watched the show on and off in some of my early years. I recently decided to watch the movie, partially out of interest to see the movie for the first time, but mainly to relive something out of my childhood. I wanted to see how it would hold up after 15 years of no transformers cartoons. To keep things straight, Transformers is not a "good" movie. The story is heavily episodic and jumpy, as if several TV episodes were crammed together. The quality of animation was alright for its time, but hasn't aged well. The soundtrack is heavy on the 1980s power rock/ pop (think Top Gun), also not having aged well. The movie is cheesy and silly, and in all honesty, somewhat ridiculous. However, the movie, while definitely not good, works as a guilty pleasure fun movie. As dumb as it was viewing it, I highly enjoyed it. With each cheesy line, I was more drawn into it. Viewing it wasn't like the phrase about "you can't turn away from watching a car crash." It was highly nostalgic. A part of me did wonder how we enjoyed such things as kids. While the movie is silly, it is highly exploitive in a sense of how much of it is focused on robot-on- robot action. Movies aren't made like this anymore. Transformers gets in, has no story but a ton of robot fighting, some cheesy 80s tunes to boost the mood, and gets out after 80 minutes. It's almost as if the movie knows exactly what it is, and does exactly what it can do. Transformers doesn't jump out as a must see movie. For people in their 20s and older, it can be charming, as a relic to a different age of TV. For people too young to remember it originally, it will jump out as an example of the questioning "Is this REALLY what you used to watch?" It is pretty much a toy commercial in disguise. However, it is worth viewing, both because it is a pure relic from the 1980s, but also because it comes from a time of more pure filmmaking. Transformers does exactly what it is sent out to do. While it wasn't aiming very high, it works. You could certainly do much worse than checking this out. 6/10. Go download the soundtrack if you need a new workout mix.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheesy Fun for the Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B. Transformers the Movie is a good, cheesy animated movie that ends the well done television series and does some surprising things but is rather entertaining. The war is still going on between the Autobots and Decepticons, but what they don't know is that there is a huge transformer that shaped like a planet heading towards them, devouring everything in its path. The opening battle on Earth is a rather tense one for the Autobots. Their base gets badly destroyed and lose one of their own that made quite a stir with fans after they saw it, Megatron kills Optimus Prime. He gives the Matrix to Ultra Magnus and puts him in charge and the Autobots head away from their base in search for their own who were eaten by the planet transformer, Unicron. Megatron after the battle got badly hurt and Starscream, wanting to be in charge, lets him go into space with others hurt and is picked up by Unicron and is now called Galvatron and working for Unicron.. Galvatron goes to Cybertron in search for Starscream and kills him and now all the Decepticons are his again with his new allies made for him by Unicron. The Autobots fly out, but are attacked by Galvatron and some land on a planet covered with trash and Hot Rod, Cub, and the Dinobots land on another planet. Hot Rod and Cub are taken prisoner and are trialed on how they will die by the planets ruler. Meanwhile, Galvatron went after the group on the rundown planet and they start hunting them and Ultra Magnus tries to use the Matrix for Prime said it will be used in their darkest hour. It doesn't open, and Galvatron blows him up. Then the inhabitants of the planet battle them. Then Cub and Hot Rod show up and save them and the junkbots rebuild Ultra Magnus and go help the Autobots fight Unicron. Meanwhile, Galvatron returns with the Matrix and wants to be in charge but won't and then the Autbots arrive to fight Unicron and save their own while Hot Rod has a final showdown with Galvatron. This is epic with him taking the Matrix and uses it against Unicron and turns into Rodimus Prime. The Decepticons die and the Autobots take back Cybertron. The movie has cheesy animation but is entertaining with some decent music, good characters, and is a great conclusion with a badass villain. Good for the fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'One shall stand, one shall fall..'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    markbyam
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film simply blew me away the first time I saw it. And still does today 20 years later. Right from The opening sequence, to the level of violence between the Decepticons and Autobots (which is totally justified) is spot on. They didn't hold back or try and soften the conflict and it was portrayed superbly. Everything from the soundtrack to the characters, and the dialogue works perfectly. Especially the dialogue which you just wouldn't get in a kids film nowadays. So many good one liners. The speech between Megatron and Prime is just pure brilliance with a fight scene that follows animated to perfection. The voice casting is exceptional and every action sequence is pulled off with such style and finesse. It even has one of the saddest scenes of any film that still makes me teary today. Once very rarely something comes along that just works in every single way...even more. Transformers the movie 1986 is an example of this. I feel privileged to have seen this as a child. Til all are one! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Me Grimlock love this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the release of the explosive Michael Bay trilogy, any newcomers to the shape-shifting franchise should be aware of the original 1986 animated feature because that's where it all started (sort of). Hasbro's Transformers became such a huge hit thanks to a combination of both the toys and the original G1 TV series of the same name. Robots changing into vehicles, guns, and even animals was such an incredible and original concept that it's hard to ignore. After running for two seasons at the time, Hasbro decided to make a full-length movie starring the Autobots and Decepticons. Plot: The year is 2005 (imagine that) as the Autobots, led by the heroic Optimus Prime, prepare to retake their home world Cybertron from the clutches of the evil Megatron and his Decepticons. However, a terrifying intergalactic force has arrived on the scene that's proved to be literally bigger than their petty war, the planet-sized Unicron (Orsen Welles). With the power of this new foe greater than anything imagined, it will take a new generation of heroes to stop this menace. Time to transform and role out! Next to "Revenge of the Fallen", this is by far my favorite film of the franchise. Seeing how the Transformers were before their live-action release was a real pleasure to see. Many of the famous characters, Autobot and Decepticon alike, get to have there little moments of action and glory, especially the Dinobots, who are my all-time favorite characters. The action scenes are just spectacular and it's pretty much non-stop. Call me old-fashioned, but I love the music, which is typical 80s soundtrack and it fits perfectly with this movie, such as Stan Bush's "The Touch" which is made famous because of this movie. The animation is also worth noting, definitely superior to the animation of the TV series. The film also became famous by taking risky moves with the old characters while introducing new ones. Optimus Prime and Megatron (Peter Cullen and Frank Welker) are still going at it as their rivalry never seems to end, though both go through some major changes. The Dinobots are fun to watch and bad to the bone. The other classic Autobots and Decepticons are cool in their own unique ways. Hot Rod makes for a good hero and Kup is a fun old robot who likes to think about the old days of the war. Orson Welles was great as Unicron and we're talking about his final role before he passed away. He provided true menace to his character with his voice; forget "Citizen Kane", Transformers man! There are very few things to nitpick around here, but overall, this movie is definitely worth buying, partly because of the nostalgia factor. With a great story, stellar voice cast, lovable and diverse cast of characters, great action scenes, and fun music, The Transformers The Movie is sure to please any fan. Nine out of ten, so check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The definition of nostalgia . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tanis_38
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no way to objectively review this film. It was my absolute favorite movie as a kid and I wore out my VHS copy. Seeing it now as an adult, I cannot see it through anything but child- like eyes and with overwhelming feelings of happy, sweet, nostalgia. Is it a great movie? I am not sure. Is the soundtrack cheesy 80's rock? Maybe. Is it my favorite Transformers movie? Absolutely. Will it always bring a smile to my face? I have one right now just thinking about it. Sure, the animation is wildly inconsistent, going from pretty amazing to laughably bad "Sunday Morning cartoon fare" from scene to scene. Sure, it can be seen as one big commercial for the future toy products of the series. But none of that matters when you are 8 years old. The Optimus Prime death scene was borderline traumatizing. The film is surprisingly violent by today's standards and outright gutsy in its willingness to kill off series regulars. It held no punches and if you were a kid in the 80's there is no way you can hear "You Got the Touch" and not smile, picturing Optimus Prime going to town on the Decepticons. This will always be in my top favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie with Transformers that has real emotion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevenbeech
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the first of the new Transformers movies and I can honestly say that the best thing in that film was Bernie Mac. 2 and a quarter hours of blowing stuff up isn't a movie. This is a movie. This is a movie that has real heart, real emotion, real themes at its core and one of the best film soundtracks ever. Sure there a bits where it drags a little and you want it to get back to the main action but it all makes sense in the end. This film probably won't make a massive amount of sense to the average 12 year old I must say, but to the 30 somethings amongst us it carries a great deal of our childhoods with it and along with that I feel a massive emotional attachment to it. The film deals with themes such as loyalty, friendship, the transition from youth to adulthood, the acceptance of responsibility, respect for elders, working toward a common goal and much else all backed by a superb 80's soft metal soundtrack composed by the much underrated Stan Bush. The soundtrack is the driving force behind much of the emotion of the movie, watch the scene where Hot Rod becomes Rodimus Prime without The Touch and its nowhere near as effective. Watch Optimus take out the decepticons without The Touch and you won't pull for him. Watch Hot Rod and Kup escape the Sharkticons without Dare playing and it doesn't work as well. This is a movie worth seeing. If only to compare it to the newer rebooted films which are technically superior and have had more spent on the catering for the cast than this movie probably cost to make but don't have the plot lines, heart, story or sheer entertainment value that this 80's throwback does.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Depressing first, then confusing and becoming more uninteresting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martyshoemark
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Transformers: The Movie was not as good as any of the episodes from the Generation One cartoon episodes from Seasons 1 to 2. Season 2 was an abundance of entertaining adventures of the Transformers in which both evil and justice battle each other while suffering the same troubles. The movie had clearly killed off so many beloved characters besides Prime, these included Prowl, Brawn, Ironhide, Ratchet, Wheeljack, and Starscream. However, the music and dramatic atmosphere of their death scenes were made to appear as if their deaths would not be tragic for the TV show audiences. The film quickly rushed into bringing upon new characters that hardly were introduced as well. The movie seemed to have just taken a not-so-much-of-an-advantage portion of its' length to add in complex plot structures that don't affect the main story of the movie, but instead to make sure this will be a bridge to Season 3 in the TV show. The Quintessons' entrance was clearly unnecessary in the plot and was only put in so that Season 3 can be established right away. The main villain of the story, Unicron, is really simple, he's just a misanthrope who wants to destroy EVERYTHING. Why? We don't know, that's just trying to make a character as a big, simple problem, which is a weak point common in several fictional stories. His voice actor, Orson Welles, was correct that this story is about a big toy attacking smaller toys. A lot of the plot was cheaply winged off of Star Wars such as the light sabers sounds, Arcee's cinnamon bun hairstyle like Leia's, and especially the climax between Hot Rod and Galvatron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly more that meets the Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TJMBuddlake
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though, i was born in 89, i still somehow grew to love transformers. I used to watch the old cartoons on reruns (now you can watch it on Toonamiaftermath.com) and I loved every bit of it. Now, 13 or so years later, I was able to finally get a copy of this movie and got a chance to watch it. OH MY GOD! This is the best transformers movie (better than the live action ones). The story was awesome, the voice cast was phenomenal. Peter Cullen, Casey Kasem, Judd Nelson, Leonard Nimoy and Orson Welles did a great job. Of course, i'm happy that all my favorites were featured (Cliffjumper and Hot Rod). This was definitely a defining moment for the transformers. In addition, the music was awesome. Stan Bush is freaking amazing. The song, The Touch will never get old. This is definitely one for any fans of the franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Transformer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Including this animated movie and the 3 live action Michael Bay movies from the Transformers universe this is by far the best version of a story about TF. The movie has its cheesy moments but it's what I enjoyed about the TF TV show and toy line of the 1980's when I was a kid. If I knew that Bay would bastardize the series like he has with a bunch of penis, fart jokes, racism and Shia LaBeouf I don't think I would've ever bothered to watch any of his movies about TF. The movie is basically TF trying to transition from their early toy lines with the Optimus Prime and MMegatron eras as the respective leaders of the Autobots and Decepticons to the more updated version with Rodimus Prime and Galvatron being the leaders. They even were able to woo Orson Welles into playing the voice of Unicron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Micheal Bay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nnguyen0297
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transformers the movie. What can I say about this movie? Well I guess I can start by saying that it is the most action packed animated film I have ever seen! That's technically what this movie is. It's just 1hr and 20min of non-stop shooting, explosion, fighting,and adventure. Well of course there's more to the plot. The film opens with a giant planet named Unicron that looks like the Death Star eating another planet. Then it shifts to the Autobots who're about to lead a shuttle to search for more energon cubes. Unfortunately for them, The evil Decepticons raids their ship and kill all the members. This really got a lot of fans angry because they saw a lot of their favorite characters die 10 minutes into the movie. The only reason they killed so many characters is so they can add new characters and release more toys. They were taking a big risk killing off so many characters. Anyway, the Decepticons takes over the ship and they are spotted by the Autobot Hot Rod. Hot Rod and some other Autobots attacks the ship, and an all out battle rages. During the battle, Optimus Prime (the leader of the Autobots)confronts Megatron(the leader of the Decepticons). They engage in an all out battles that left all fans cheering because they waited so long to see these two rivals fight to the death. After a while, It seemed that Optimus won, but Megatron played a dirty trick and wounded Optimus pretty badly. But Optimus with all the strength he had left gave Megatron one last punch that left him crippled. The Decepticons escape, and optimus with his last breath, gave the Matrix and his leadership to Ultra Magnus. Mean while, an injured Megatron gets betrayed by his minion Starscream and gets pushed off into space. There, he meets Unicron who makes Megatron one of his minions. In exchange, he gives Megatron a new and more powerful body and rename him Galvatron. He also gives Megatron 3 robots named Relector. With his new power, he kills Starscream and takes over the decepticons again. Now Unicron is forcing him to kill the Autobots and destroy the All Sparks. Now the Autobots have to face Galvatron and Unicron at the same time. I'm not gonna spoil the rest because this is where the movie gets really good. I'm a casual fan of Transformers, and I must say, this film really impressed me. Some people hate it because it had to much violent action, some random music use, and there's to many references to Star Wars. Yes there is a whole bunch of action, but that's what's awesome about it. How many movies have you seen where something blows up every 5 seconds? Yeah, sometimes the action can be a little uneven, and the animation might be laggy from time to time, but this was made in the 80s so give it some slack. There are many references to Star Wars however. Like the character Hot rod is related to Luke, Unicron looks like the Death Star, Arcee has the princess Leah hairstyle, Optimus Prime talks to Hot Rod in his ghost form much like how Ben Kenobi talks to Luke. But i didn't really mind that. So many movies copied things from Star wars up to the point that you don't care anymore. As for the music however, it is completely random. Like when Hot Rod opens the Matrix and the song "The Touch" starts playing in the background. It also has the most random use of Weird Al Yankovic's "Dare to be Stupid". They played that song when the Autobots where fighting some other random robots in some random planet. And after they made peace with those robots, they started dancing to the exact same song! Despite all these negative feature to this film, it's awesome and anyone will love it. I give it~ 3.5/5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relic of the 80s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhtsosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How does it feel to jump back 25 years, into a remnant of your childhood? Does the past hold up with the memories you once associated with it, or will it seem silly and outdated? I recently relived a portion of my childhood in watching the original Transformers cartoon movie from 1986. It is appropriately titled "Transformers: The Movie." I never did see this movie as a child, although I watched the show on and off in some of my early years. I recently decided to watch the movie, partially out of interest to see the movie for the first time, but mainly to relive something out of my childhood. I wanted to see how it would hold up after 15 years of no transformers cartoons. To keep things straight, Transformers is not a "good" movie. The story is heavily episodic and jumpy, as if several TV episodes were crammed together. The quality of animation was alright for its time, but hasn't aged well. The soundtrack is heavy on the 1980s power rock/ pop (think Top Gun), also not having aged well. The movie is cheesy and silly, and in all honesty, somewhat ridiculous. However, the movie, while definitely not good, works as a guilty pleasure fun movie. As dumb as it was viewing it, I highly enjoyed it. With each cheesy line, I was more drawn into it. Viewing it wasn't like the phrase about "you can't turn away from watching a car crash." It was highly nostalgic. A part of me did wonder how we enjoyed such things as kids. While the movie is silly, it is highly exploitive in a sense of how much of it is focused on robot-on- robot action. Movies aren't made like this anymore. Transformers gets in, has no story but a ton of robot fighting, some cheesy 80s tunes to boost the mood, and gets out after 80 minutes. It's almost as if the movie knows exactly what it is, and does exactly what it can do. Transformers doesn't jump out as a must see movie. For people in their 20s and older, it can be charming, as a relic to a different age of TV. For people too young to remember it originally, it will jump out as an example of the questioning "Is this REALLY what you used to watch?" It is pretty much a toy commercial in disguise. However, it is worth viewing, both because it is a pure relic from the 1980s, but also because it comes from a time of more pure filmmaking. Transformers does exactly what it is sent out to do. While it wasn't aiming very high, it works. You could certainly do much worse than checking this out. 6/10. Go download the soundtrack if you need a new workout mix.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheesy Fun for the Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B. Transformers the Movie is a good, cheesy animated movie that ends the well done television series and does some surprising things but is rather entertaining. The war is still going on between the Autobots and Decepticons, but what they don't know is that there is a huge transformer that shaped like a planet heading towards them, devouring everything in its path. The opening battle on Earth is a rather tense one for the Autobots. Their base gets badly destroyed and lose one of their own that made quite a stir with fans after they saw it, Megatron kills Optimus Prime. He gives the Matrix to Ultra Magnus and puts him in charge and the Autobots head away from their base in search for their own who were eaten by the planet transformer, Unicron. Megatron after the battle got badly hurt and Starscream, wanting to be in charge, lets him go into space with others hurt and is picked up by Unicron and is now called Galvatron and working for Unicron.. Galvatron goes to Cybertron in search for Starscream and kills him and now all the Decepticons are his again with his new allies made for him by Unicron. The Autobots fly out, but are attacked by Galvatron and some land on a planet covered with trash and Hot Rod, Cub, and the Dinobots land on another planet. Hot Rod and Cub are taken prisoner and are trialed on how they will die by the planets ruler. Meanwhile, Galvatron went after the group on the rundown planet and they start hunting them and Ultra Magnus tries to use the Matrix for Prime said it will be used in their darkest hour. It doesn't open, and Galvatron blows him up. Then the inhabitants of the planet battle them. Then Cub and Hot Rod show up and save them and the junkbots rebuild Ultra Magnus and go help the Autobots fight Unicron. Meanwhile, Galvatron returns with the Matrix and wants to be in charge but won't and then the Autbots arrive to fight Unicron and save their own while Hot Rod has a final showdown with Galvatron. This is epic with him taking the Matrix and uses it against Unicron and turns into Rodimus Prime. The Decepticons die and the Autobots take back Cybertron. The movie has cheesy animation but is entertaining with some decent music, good characters, and is a great conclusion with a badass villain. Good for the fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'One shall stand, one shall fall..'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    markbyam
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film simply blew me away the first time I saw it. And still does today 20 years later. Right from The opening sequence, to the level of violence between the Decepticons and Autobots (which is totally justified) is spot on. They didn't hold back or try and soften the conflict and it was portrayed superbly. Everything from the soundtrack to the characters, and the dialogue works perfectly. Especially the dialogue which you just wouldn't get in a kids film nowadays. So many good one liners. The speech between Megatron and Prime is just pure brilliance with a fight scene that follows animated to perfection. The voice casting is exceptional and every action sequence is pulled off with such style and finesse. It even has one of the saddest scenes of any film that still makes me teary today. Once very rarely something comes along that just works in every single way...even more. Transformers the movie 1986 is an example of this. I feel privileged to have seen this as a child. Til all are one! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Me Grimlock love this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the release of the explosive Michael Bay trilogy, any newcomers to the shape-shifting franchise should be aware of the original 1986 animated feature because that's where it all started (sort of). Hasbro's Transformers became such a huge hit thanks to a combination of both the toys and the original G1 TV series of the same name. Robots changing into vehicles, guns, and even animals was such an incredible and original concept that it's hard to ignore. After running for two seasons at the time, Hasbro decided to make a full-length movie starring the Autobots and Decepticons. Plot: The year is 2005 (imagine that) as the Autobots, led by the heroic Optimus Prime, prepare to retake their home world Cybertron from the clutches of the evil Megatron and his Decepticons. However, a terrifying intergalactic force has arrived on the scene that's proved to be literally bigger than their petty war, the planet-sized Unicron (Orsen Welles). With the power of this new foe greater than anything imagined, it will take a new generation of heroes to stop this menace. Time to transform and role out! Next to "Revenge of the Fallen", this is by far my favorite film of the franchise. Seeing how the Transformers were before their live-action release was a real pleasure to see. Many of the famous characters, Autobot and Decepticon alike, get to have there little moments of action and glory, especially the Dinobots, who are my all-time favorite characters. The action scenes are just spectacular and it's pretty much non-stop. Call me old-fashioned, but I love the music, which is typical 80s soundtrack and it fits perfectly with this movie, such as Stan Bush's "The Touch" which is made famous because of this movie. The animation is also worth noting, definitely superior to the animation of the TV series. The film also became famous by taking risky moves with the old characters while introducing new ones. Optimus Prime and Megatron (Peter Cullen and Frank Welker) are still going at it as their rivalry never seems to end, though both go through some major changes. The Dinobots are fun to watch and bad to the bone. The other classic Autobots and Decepticons are cool in their own unique ways. Hot Rod makes for a good hero and Kup is a fun old robot who likes to think about the old days of the war. Orson Welles was great as Unicron and we're talking about his final role before he passed away. He provided true menace to his character with his voice; forget "Citizen Kane", Transformers man! There are very few things to nitpick around here, but overall, this movie is definitely worth buying, partly because of the nostalgia factor. With a great story, stellar voice cast, lovable and diverse cast of characters, great action scenes, and fun music, The Transformers The Movie is sure to please any fan. Nine out of ten, so check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The definition of nostalgia . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tanis_38
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no way to objectively review this film. It was my absolute favorite movie as a kid and I wore out my VHS copy. Seeing it now as an adult, I cannot see it through anything but child- like eyes and with overwhelming feelings of happy, sweet, nostalgia. Is it a great movie? I am not sure. Is the soundtrack cheesy 80's rock? Maybe. Is it my favorite Transformers movie? Absolutely. Will it always bring a smile to my face? I have one right now just thinking about it. Sure, the animation is wildly inconsistent, going from pretty amazing to laughably bad "Sunday Morning cartoon fare" from scene to scene. Sure, it can be seen as one big commercial for the future toy products of the series. But none of that matters when you are 8 years old. The Optimus Prime death scene was borderline traumatizing. The film is surprisingly violent by today's standards and outright gutsy in its willingness to kill off series regulars. It held no punches and if you were a kid in the 80's there is no way you can hear "You Got the Touch" and not smile, picturing Optimus Prime going to town on the Decepticons. This will always be in my top favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie with Transformers that has real emotion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevenbeech
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the first of the new Transformers movies and I can honestly say that the best thing in that film was Bernie Mac. 2 and a quarter hours of blowing stuff up isn't a movie. This is a movie. This is a movie that has real heart, real emotion, real themes at its core and one of the best film soundtracks ever. Sure there a bits where it drags a little and you want it to get back to the main action but it all makes sense in the end. This film probably won't make a massive amount of sense to the average 12 year old I must say, but to the 30 somethings amongst us it carries a great deal of our childhoods with it and along with that I feel a massive emotional attachment to it. The film deals with themes such as loyalty, friendship, the transition from youth to adulthood, the acceptance of responsibility, respect for elders, working toward a common goal and much else all backed by a superb 80's soft metal soundtrack composed by the much underrated Stan Bush. The soundtrack is the driving force behind much of the emotion of the movie, watch the scene where Hot Rod becomes Rodimus Prime without The Touch and its nowhere near as effective. Watch Optimus take out the decepticons without The Touch and you won't pull for him. Watch Hot Rod and Kup escape the Sharkticons without Dare playing and it doesn't work as well. This is a movie worth seeing. If only to compare it to the newer rebooted films which are technically superior and have had more spent on the catering for the cast than this movie probably cost to make but don't have the plot lines, heart, story or sheer entertainment value that this 80's throwback does.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Depressing first, then confusing and becoming more uninteresting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martyshoemark
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Transformers: The Movie was not as good as any of the episodes from the Generation One cartoon episodes from Seasons 1 to 2. Season 2 was an abundance of entertaining adventures of the Transformers in which both evil and justice battle each other while suffering the same troubles. The movie had clearly killed off so many beloved characters besides Prime, these included Prowl, Brawn, Ironhide, Ratchet, Wheeljack, and Starscream. However, the music and dramatic atmosphere of their death scenes were made to appear as if their deaths would not be tragic for the TV show audiences. The film quickly rushed into bringing upon new characters that hardly were introduced as well. The movie seemed to have just taken a not-so-much-of-an-advantage portion of its' length to add in complex plot structures that don't affect the main story of the movie, but instead to make sure this will be a bridge to Season 3 in the TV show. The Quintessons' entrance was clearly unnecessary in the plot and was only put in so that Season 3 can be established right away. The main villain of the story, Unicron, is really simple, he's just a misanthrope who wants to destroy EVERYTHING. Why? We don't know, that's just trying to make a character as a big, simple problem, which is a weak point common in several fictional stories. His voice actor, Orson Welles, was correct that this story is about a big toy attacking smaller toys. A lot of the plot was cheaply winged off of Star Wars such as the light sabers sounds, Arcee's cinnamon bun hairstyle like Leia's, and especially the climax between Hot Rod and Galvatron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly more that meets the Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TJMBuddlake
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though, i was born in 89, i still somehow grew to love transformers. I used to watch the old cartoons on reruns (now you can watch it on Toonamiaftermath.com) and I loved every bit of it. Now, 13 or so years later, I was able to finally get a copy of this movie and got a chance to watch it. OH MY GOD! This is the best transformers movie (better than the live action ones). The story was awesome, the voice cast was phenomenal. Peter Cullen, Casey Kasem, Judd Nelson, Leonard Nimoy and Orson Welles did a great job. Of course, i'm happy that all my favorites were featured (Cliffjumper and Hot Rod). This was definitely a defining moment for the transformers. In addition, the music was awesome. Stan Bush is freaking amazing. The song, The Touch will never get old. This is definitely one for any fans of the franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Transformer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Including this animated movie and the 3 live action Michael Bay movies from the Transformers universe this is by far the best version of a story about TF. The movie has its cheesy moments but it's what I enjoyed about the TF TV show and toy line of the 1980's when I was a kid. If I knew that Bay would bastardize the series like he has with a bunch of penis, fart jokes, racism and Shia LaBeouf I don't think I would've ever bothered to watch any of his movies about TF. The movie is basically TF trying to transition from their early toy lines with the Optimus Prime and MMegatron eras as the respective leaders of the Autobots and Decepticons to the more updated version with Rodimus Prime and Galvatron being the leaders. They even were able to woo Orson Welles into playing the voice of Unicron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Micheal Bay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nnguyen0297
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transformers the movie. What can I say about this movie? Well I guess I can start by saying that it is the most action packed animated film I have ever seen! That's technically what this movie is. It's just 1hr and 20min of non-stop shooting, explosion, fighting,and adventure. Well of course there's more to the plot. The film opens with a giant planet named Unicron that looks like the Death Star eating another planet. Then it shifts to the Autobots who're about to lead a shuttle to search for more energon cubes. Unfortunately for them, The evil Decepticons raids their ship and kill all the members. This really got a lot of fans angry because they saw a lot of their favorite characters die 10 minutes into the movie. The only reason they killed so many characters is so they can add new characters and release more toys. They were taking a big risk killing off so many characters. Anyway, the Decepticons takes over the ship and they are spotted by the Autobot Hot Rod. Hot Rod and some other Autobots attacks the ship, and an all out battle rages. During the battle, Optimus Prime (the leader of the Autobots)confronts Megatron(the leader of the Decepticons). They engage in an all out battles that left all fans cheering because they waited so long to see these two rivals fight to the death. After a while, It seemed that Optimus won, but Megatron played a dirty trick and wounded Optimus pretty badly. But Optimus with all the strength he had left gave Megatron one last punch that left him crippled. The Decepticons escape, and optimus with his last breath, gave the Matrix and his leadership to Ultra Magnus. Mean while, an injured Megatron gets betrayed by his minion Starscream and gets pushed off into space. There, he meets Unicron who makes Megatron one of his minions. In exchange, he gives Megatron a new and more powerful body and rename him Galvatron. He also gives Megatron 3 robots named Relector. With his new power, he kills Starscream and takes over the decepticons again. Now Unicron is forcing him to kill the Autobots and destroy the All Sparks. Now the Autobots have to face Galvatron and Unicron at the same time. I'm not gonna spoil the rest because this is where the movie gets really good. I'm a casual fan of Transformers, and I must say, this film really impressed me. Some people hate it because it had to much violent action, some random music use, and there's to many references to Star Wars. Yes there is a whole bunch of action, but that's what's awesome about it. How many movies have you seen where something blows up every 5 seconds? Yeah, sometimes the action can be a little uneven, and the animation might be laggy from time to time, but this was made in the 80s so give it some slack. There are many references to Star Wars however. Like the character Hot rod is related to Luke, Unicron looks like the Death Star, Arcee has the princess Leah hairstyle, Optimus Prime talks to Hot Rod in his ghost form much like how Ben Kenobi talks to Luke. But i didn't really mind that. So many movies copied things from Star wars up to the point that you don't care anymore. As for the music however, it is completely random. Like when Hot Rod opens the Matrix and the song "The Touch" starts playing in the background. It also has the most random use of Weird Al Yankovic's "Dare to be Stupid". They played that song when the Autobots where fighting some other random robots in some random planet. And after they made peace with those robots, they started dancing to the exact same song! Despite all these negative feature to this film, it's awesome and anyone will love it. I give it~ 3.5/5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relic of the 80s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhtsosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How does it feel to jump back 25 years, into a remnant of your childhood? Does the past hold up with the memories you once associated with it, or will it seem silly and outdated? I recently relived a portion of my childhood in watching the original Transformers cartoon movie from 1986. It is appropriately titled "Transformers: The Movie." I never did see this movie as a child, although I watched the show on and off in some of my early years. I recently decided to watch the movie, partially out of interest to see the movie for the first time, but mainly to relive something out of my childhood. I wanted to see how it would hold up after 15 years of no transformers cartoons. To keep things straight, Transformers is not a "good" movie. The story is heavily episodic and jumpy, as if several TV episodes were crammed together. The quality of animation was alright for its time, but hasn't aged well. The soundtrack is heavy on the 1980s power rock/ pop (think Top Gun), also not having aged well. The movie is cheesy and silly, and in all honesty, somewhat ridiculous. However, the movie, while definitely not good, works as a guilty pleasure fun movie. As dumb as it was viewing it, I highly enjoyed it. With each cheesy line, I was more drawn into it. Viewing it wasn't like the phrase about "you can't turn away from watching a car crash." It was highly nostalgic. A part of me did wonder how we enjoyed such things as kids. While the movie is silly, it is highly exploitive in a sense of how much of it is focused on robot-on- robot action. Movies aren't made like this anymore. Transformers gets in, has no story but a ton of robot fighting, some cheesy 80s tunes to boost the mood, and gets out after 80 minutes. It's almost as if the movie knows exactly what it is, and does exactly what it can do. Transformers doesn't jump out as a must see movie. For people in their 20s and older, it can be charming, as a relic to a different age of TV. For people too young to remember it originally, it will jump out as an example of the questioning "Is this REALLY what you used to watch?" It is pretty much a toy commercial in disguise. However, it is worth viewing, both because it is a pure relic from the 1980s, but also because it comes from a time of more pure filmmaking. Transformers does exactly what it is sent out to do. While it wasn't aiming very high, it works. You could certainly do much worse than checking this out. 6/10. Go download the soundtrack if you need a new workout mix.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheesy Fun for the Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B. Transformers the Movie is a good, cheesy animated movie that ends the well done television series and does some surprising things but is rather entertaining. The war is still going on between the Autobots and Decepticons, but what they don't know is that there is a huge transformer that shaped like a planet heading towards them, devouring everything in its path. The opening battle on Earth is a rather tense one for the Autobots. Their base gets badly destroyed and lose one of their own that made quite a stir with fans after they saw it, Megatron kills Optimus Prime. He gives the Matrix to Ultra Magnus and puts him in charge and the Autobots head away from their base in search for their own who were eaten by the planet transformer, Unicron. Megatron after the battle got badly hurt and Starscream, wanting to be in charge, lets him go into space with others hurt and is picked up by Unicron and is now called Galvatron and working for Unicron.. Galvatron goes to Cybertron in search for Starscream and kills him and now all the Decepticons are his again with his new allies made for him by Unicron. The Autobots fly out, but are attacked by Galvatron and some land on a planet covered with trash and Hot Rod, Cub, and the Dinobots land on another planet. Hot Rod and Cub are taken prisoner and are trialed on how they will die by the planets ruler. Meanwhile, Galvatron went after the group on the rundown planet and they start hunting them and Ultra Magnus tries to use the Matrix for Prime said it will be used in their darkest hour. It doesn't open, and Galvatron blows him up. Then the inhabitants of the planet battle them. Then Cub and Hot Rod show up and save them and the junkbots rebuild Ultra Magnus and go help the Autobots fight Unicron. Meanwhile, Galvatron returns with the Matrix and wants to be in charge but won't and then the Autbots arrive to fight Unicron and save their own while Hot Rod has a final showdown with Galvatron. This is epic with him taking the Matrix and uses it against Unicron and turns into Rodimus Prime. The Decepticons die and the Autobots take back Cybertron. The movie has cheesy animation but is entertaining with some decent music, good characters, and is a great conclusion with a badass villain. Good for the fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'One shall stand, one shall fall..'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    markbyam
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film simply blew me away the first time I saw it. And still does today 20 years later. Right from The opening sequence, to the level of violence between the Decepticons and Autobots (which is totally justified) is spot on. They didn't hold back or try and soften the conflict and it was portrayed superbly. Everything from the soundtrack to the characters, and the dialogue works perfectly. Especially the dialogue which you just wouldn't get in a kids film nowadays. So many good one liners. The speech between Megatron and Prime is just pure brilliance with a fight scene that follows animated to perfection. The voice casting is exceptional and every action sequence is pulled off with such style and finesse. It even has one of the saddest scenes of any film that still makes me teary today. Once very rarely something comes along that just works in every single way...even more. Transformers the movie 1986 is an example of this. I feel privileged to have seen this as a child. Til all are one! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Me Grimlock love this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the release of the explosive Michael Bay trilogy, any newcomers to the shape-shifting franchise should be aware of the original 1986 animated feature because that's where it all started (sort of). Hasbro's Transformers became such a huge hit thanks to a combination of both the toys and the original G1 TV series of the same name. Robots changing into vehicles, guns, and even animals was such an incredible and original concept that it's hard to ignore. After running for two seasons at the time, Hasbro decided to make a full-length movie starring the Autobots and Decepticons. Plot: The year is 2005 (imagine that) as the Autobots, led by the heroic Optimus Prime, prepare to retake their home world Cybertron from the clutches of the evil Megatron and his Decepticons. However, a terrifying intergalactic force has arrived on the scene that's proved to be literally bigger than their petty war, the planet-sized Unicron (Orsen Welles). With the power of this new foe greater than anything imagined, it will take a new generation of heroes to stop this menace. Time to transform and role out! Next to "Revenge of the Fallen", this is by far my favorite film of the franchise. Seeing how the Transformers were before their live-action release was a real pleasure to see. Many of the famous characters, Autobot and Decepticon alike, get to have there little moments of action and glory, especially the Dinobots, who are my all-time favorite characters. The action scenes are just spectacular and it's pretty much non-stop. Call me old-fashioned, but I love the music, which is typical 80s soundtrack and it fits perfectly with this movie, such as Stan Bush's "The Touch" which is made famous because of this movie. The animation is also worth noting, definitely superior to the animation of the TV series. The film also became famous by taking risky moves with the old characters while introducing new ones. Optimus Prime and Megatron (Peter Cullen and Frank Welker) are still going at it as their rivalry never seems to end, though both go through some major changes. The Dinobots are fun to watch and bad to the bone. The other classic Autobots and Decepticons are cool in their own unique ways. Hot Rod makes for a good hero and Kup is a fun old robot who likes to think about the old days of the war. Orson Welles was great as Unicron and we're talking about his final role before he passed away. He provided true menace to his character with his voice; forget "Citizen Kane", Transformers man! There are very few things to nitpick around here, but overall, this movie is definitely worth buying, partly because of the nostalgia factor. With a great story, stellar voice cast, lovable and diverse cast of characters, great action scenes, and fun music, The Transformers The Movie is sure to please any fan. Nine out of ten, so check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The definition of nostalgia . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tanis_38
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no way to objectively review this film. It was my absolute favorite movie as a kid and I wore out my VHS copy. Seeing it now as an adult, I cannot see it through anything but child- like eyes and with overwhelming feelings of happy, sweet, nostalgia. Is it a great movie? I am not sure. Is the soundtrack cheesy 80's rock? Maybe. Is it my favorite Transformers movie? Absolutely. Will it always bring a smile to my face? I have one right now just thinking about it. Sure, the animation is wildly inconsistent, going from pretty amazing to laughably bad "Sunday Morning cartoon fare" from scene to scene. Sure, it can be seen as one big commercial for the future toy products of the series. But none of that matters when you are 8 years old. The Optimus Prime death scene was borderline traumatizing. The film is surprisingly violent by today's standards and outright gutsy in its willingness to kill off series regulars. It held no punches and if you were a kid in the 80's there is no way you can hear "You Got the Touch" and not smile, picturing Optimus Prime going to town on the Decepticons. This will always be in my top favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie with Transformers that has real emotion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevenbeech
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the first of the new Transformers movies and I can honestly say that the best thing in that film was Bernie Mac. 2 and a quarter hours of blowing stuff up isn't a movie. This is a movie. This is a movie that has real heart, real emotion, real themes at its core and one of the best film soundtracks ever. Sure there a bits where it drags a little and you want it to get back to the main action but it all makes sense in the end. This film probably won't make a massive amount of sense to the average 12 year old I must say, but to the 30 somethings amongst us it carries a great deal of our childhoods with it and along with that I feel a massive emotional attachment to it. The film deals with themes such as loyalty, friendship, the transition from youth to adulthood, the acceptance of responsibility, respect for elders, working toward a common goal and much else all backed by a superb 80's soft metal soundtrack composed by the much underrated Stan Bush. The soundtrack is the driving force behind much of the emotion of the movie, watch the scene where Hot Rod becomes Rodimus Prime without The Touch and its nowhere near as effective. Watch Optimus take out the decepticons without The Touch and you won't pull for him. Watch Hot Rod and Kup escape the Sharkticons without Dare playing and it doesn't work as well. This is a movie worth seeing. If only to compare it to the newer rebooted films which are technically superior and have had more spent on the catering for the cast than this movie probably cost to make but don't have the plot lines, heart, story or sheer entertainment value that this 80's throwback does.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Depressing first, then confusing and becoming more uninteresting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martyshoemark
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Transformers: The Movie was not as good as any of the episodes from the Generation One cartoon episodes from Seasons 1 to 2. Season 2 was an abundance of entertaining adventures of the Transformers in which both evil and justice battle each other while suffering the same troubles. The movie had clearly killed off so many beloved characters besides Prime, these included Prowl, Brawn, Ironhide, Ratchet, Wheeljack, and Starscream. However, the music and dramatic atmosphere of their death scenes were made to appear as if their deaths would not be tragic for the TV show audiences. The film quickly rushed into bringing upon new characters that hardly were introduced as well. The movie seemed to have just taken a not-so-much-of-an-advantage portion of its' length to add in complex plot structures that don't affect the main story of the movie, but instead to make sure this will be a bridge to Season 3 in the TV show. The Quintessons' entrance was clearly unnecessary in the plot and was only put in so that Season 3 can be established right away. The main villain of the story, Unicron, is really simple, he's just a misanthrope who wants to destroy EVERYTHING. Why? We don't know, that's just trying to make a character as a big, simple problem, which is a weak point common in several fictional stories. His voice actor, Orson Welles, was correct that this story is about a big toy attacking smaller toys. A lot of the plot was cheaply winged off of Star Wars such as the light sabers sounds, Arcee's cinnamon bun hairstyle like Leia's, and especially the climax between Hot Rod and Galvatron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly more that meets the Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TJMBuddlake
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though, i was born in 89, i still somehow grew to love transformers. I used to watch the old cartoons on reruns (now you can watch it on Toonamiaftermath.com) and I loved every bit of it. Now, 13 or so years later, I was able to finally get a copy of this movie and got a chance to watch it. OH MY GOD! This is the best transformers movie (better than the live action ones). The story was awesome, the voice cast was phenomenal. Peter Cullen, Casey Kasem, Judd Nelson, Leonard Nimoy and Orson Welles did a great job. Of course, i'm happy that all my favorites were featured (Cliffjumper and Hot Rod). This was definitely a defining moment for the transformers. In addition, the music was awesome. Stan Bush is freaking amazing. The song, The Touch will never get old. This is definitely one for any fans of the franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Transformer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Including this animated movie and the 3 live action Michael Bay movies from the Transformers universe this is by far the best version of a story about TF. The movie has its cheesy moments but it's what I enjoyed about the TF TV show and toy line of the 1980's when I was a kid. If I knew that Bay would bastardize the series like he has with a bunch of penis, fart jokes, racism and Shia LaBeouf I don't think I would've ever bothered to watch any of his movies about TF. The movie is basically TF trying to transition from their early toy lines with the Optimus Prime and MMegatron eras as the respective leaders of the Autobots and Decepticons to the more updated version with Rodimus Prime and Galvatron being the leaders. They even were able to woo Orson Welles into playing the voice of Unicron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Micheal Bay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nnguyen0297
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transformers the movie. What can I say about this movie? Well I guess I can start by saying that it is the most action packed animated film I have ever seen! That's technically what this movie is. It's just 1hr and 20min of non-stop shooting, explosion, fighting,and adventure. Well of course there's more to the plot. The film opens with a giant planet named Unicron that looks like the Death Star eating another planet. Then it shifts to the Autobots who're about to lead a shuttle to search for more energon cubes. Unfortunately for them, The evil Decepticons raids their ship and kill all the members. This really got a lot of fans angry because they saw a lot of their favorite characters die 10 minutes into the movie. The only reason they killed so many characters is so they can add new characters and release more toys. They were taking a big risk killing off so many characters. Anyway, the Decepticons takes over the ship and they are spotted by the Autobot Hot Rod. Hot Rod and some other Autobots attacks the ship, and an all out battle rages. During the battle, Optimus Prime (the leader of the Autobots)confronts Megatron(the leader of the Decepticons). They engage in an all out battles that left all fans cheering because they waited so long to see these two rivals fight to the death. After a while, It seemed that Optimus won, but Megatron played a dirty trick and wounded Optimus pretty badly. But Optimus with all the strength he had left gave Megatron one last punch that left him crippled. The Decepticons escape, and optimus with his last breath, gave the Matrix and his leadership to Ultra Magnus. Mean while, an injured Megatron gets betrayed by his minion Starscream and gets pushed off into space. There, he meets Unicron who makes Megatron one of his minions. In exchange, he gives Megatron a new and more powerful body and rename him Galvatron. He also gives Megatron 3 robots named Relector. With his new power, he kills Starscream and takes over the decepticons again. Now Unicron is forcing him to kill the Autobots and destroy the All Sparks. Now the Autobots have to face Galvatron and Unicron at the same time. I'm not gonna spoil the rest because this is where the movie gets really good. I'm a casual fan of Transformers, and I must say, this film really impressed me. Some people hate it because it had to much violent action, some random music use, and there's to many references to Star Wars. Yes there is a whole bunch of action, but that's what's awesome about it. How many movies have you seen where something blows up every 5 seconds? Yeah, sometimes the action can be a little uneven, and the animation might be laggy from time to time, but this was made in the 80s so give it some slack. There are many references to Star Wars however. Like the character Hot rod is related to Luke, Unicron looks like the Death Star, Arcee has the princess Leah hairstyle, Optimus Prime talks to Hot Rod in his ghost form much like how Ben Kenobi talks to Luke. But i didn't really mind that. So many movies copied things from Star wars up to the point that you don't care anymore. As for the music however, it is completely random. Like when Hot Rod opens the Matrix and the song "The Touch" starts playing in the background. It also has the most random use of Weird Al Yankovic's "Dare to be Stupid". They played that song when the Autobots where fighting some other random robots in some random planet. And after they made peace with those robots, they started dancing to the exact same song! Despite all these negative feature to this film, it's awesome and anyone will love it. I give it~ 3.5/5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relic of the 80s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhtsosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How does it feel to jump back 25 years, into a remnant of your childhood? Does the past hold up with the memories you once associated with it, or will it seem silly and outdated? I recently relived a portion of my childhood in watching the original Transformers cartoon movie from 1986. It is appropriately titled "Transformers: The Movie." I never did see this movie as a child, although I watched the show on and off in some of my early years. I recently decided to watch the movie, partially out of interest to see the movie for the first time, but mainly to relive something out of my childhood. I wanted to see how it would hold up after 15 years of no transformers cartoons. To keep things straight, Transformers is not a "good" movie. The story is heavily episodic and jumpy, as if several TV episodes were crammed together. The quality of animation was alright for its time, but hasn't aged well. The soundtrack is heavy on the 1980s power rock/ pop (think Top Gun), also not having aged well. The movie is cheesy and silly, and in all honesty, somewhat ridiculous. However, the movie, while definitely not good, works as a guilty pleasure fun movie. As dumb as it was viewing it, I highly enjoyed it. With each cheesy line, I was more drawn into it. Viewing it wasn't like the phrase about "you can't turn away from watching a car crash." It was highly nostalgic. A part of me did wonder how we enjoyed such things as kids. While the movie is silly, it is highly exploitive in a sense of how much of it is focused on robot-on- robot action. Movies aren't made like this anymore. Transformers gets in, has no story but a ton of robot fighting, some cheesy 80s tunes to boost the mood, and gets out after 80 minutes. It's almost as if the movie knows exactly what it is, and does exactly what it can do. Transformers doesn't jump out as a must see movie. For people in their 20s and older, it can be charming, as a relic to a different age of TV. For people too young to remember it originally, it will jump out as an example of the questioning "Is this REALLY what you used to watch?" It is pretty much a toy commercial in disguise. However, it is worth viewing, both because it is a pure relic from the 1980s, but also because it comes from a time of more pure filmmaking. Transformers does exactly what it is sent out to do. While it wasn't aiming very high, it works. You could certainly do much worse than checking this out. 6/10. Go download the soundtrack if you need a new workout mix.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheesy Fun for the Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B. Transformers the Movie is a good, cheesy animated movie that ends the well done television series and does some surprising things but is rather entertaining. The war is still going on between the Autobots and Decepticons, but what they don't know is that there is a huge transformer that shaped like a planet heading towards them, devouring everything in its path. The opening battle on Earth is a rather tense one for the Autobots. Their base gets badly destroyed and lose one of their own that made quite a stir with fans after they saw it, Megatron kills Optimus Prime. He gives the Matrix to Ultra Magnus and puts him in charge and the Autobots head away from their base in search for their own who were eaten by the planet transformer, Unicron. Megatron after the battle got badly hurt and Starscream, wanting to be in charge, lets him go into space with others hurt and is picked up by Unicron and is now called Galvatron and working for Unicron.. Galvatron goes to Cybertron in search for Starscream and kills him and now all the Decepticons are his again with his new allies made for him by Unicron. The Autobots fly out, but are attacked by Galvatron and some land on a planet covered with trash and Hot Rod, Cub, and the Dinobots land on another planet. Hot Rod and Cub are taken prisoner and are trialed on how they will die by the planets ruler. Meanwhile, Galvatron went after the group on the rundown planet and they start hunting them and Ultra Magnus tries to use the Matrix for Prime said it will be used in their darkest hour. It doesn't open, and Galvatron blows him up. Then the inhabitants of the planet battle them. Then Cub and Hot Rod show up and save them and the junkbots rebuild Ultra Magnus and go help the Autobots fight Unicron. Meanwhile, Galvatron returns with the Matrix and wants to be in charge but won't and then the Autbots arrive to fight Unicron and save their own while Hot Rod has a final showdown with Galvatron. This is epic with him taking the Matrix and uses it against Unicron and turns into Rodimus Prime. The Decepticons die and the Autobots take back Cybertron. The movie has cheesy animation but is entertaining with some decent music, good characters, and is a great conclusion with a badass villain. Good for the fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'One shall stand, one shall fall..'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    markbyam
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film simply blew me away the first time I saw it. And still does today 20 years later. Right from The opening sequence, to the level of violence between the Decepticons and Autobots (which is totally justified) is spot on. They didn't hold back or try and soften the conflict and it was portrayed superbly. Everything from the soundtrack to the characters, and the dialogue works perfectly. Especially the dialogue which you just wouldn't get in a kids film nowadays. So many good one liners. The speech between Megatron and Prime is just pure brilliance with a fight scene that follows animated to perfection. The voice casting is exceptional and every action sequence is pulled off with such style and finesse. It even has one of the saddest scenes of any film that still makes me teary today. Once very rarely something comes along that just works in every single way...even more. Transformers the movie 1986 is an example of this. I feel privileged to have seen this as a child. Til all are one! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Me Grimlock love this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the release of the explosive Michael Bay trilogy, any newcomers to the shape-shifting franchise should be aware of the original 1986 animated feature because that's where it all started (sort of). Hasbro's Transformers became such a huge hit thanks to a combination of both the toys and the original G1 TV series of the same name. Robots changing into vehicles, guns, and even animals was such an incredible and original concept that it's hard to ignore. After running for two seasons at the time, Hasbro decided to make a full-length movie starring the Autobots and Decepticons. Plot: The year is 2005 (imagine that) as the Autobots, led by the heroic Optimus Prime, prepare to retake their home world Cybertron from the clutches of the evil Megatron and his Decepticons. However, a terrifying intergalactic force has arrived on the scene that's proved to be literally bigger than their petty war, the planet-sized Unicron (Orsen Welles). With the power of this new foe greater than anything imagined, it will take a new generation of heroes to stop this menace. Time to transform and role out! Next to "Revenge of the Fallen", this is by far my favorite film of the franchise. Seeing how the Transformers were before their live-action release was a real pleasure to see. Many of the famous characters, Autobot and Decepticon alike, get to have there little moments of action and glory, especially the Dinobots, who are my all-time favorite characters. The action scenes are just spectacular and it's pretty much non-stop. Call me old-fashioned, but I love the music, which is typical 80s soundtrack and it fits perfectly with this movie, such as Stan Bush's "The Touch" which is made famous because of this movie. The animation is also worth noting, definitely superior to the animation of the TV series. The film also became famous by taking risky moves with the old characters while introducing new ones. Optimus Prime and Megatron (Peter Cullen and Frank Welker) are still going at it as their rivalry never seems to end, though both go through some major changes. The Dinobots are fun to watch and bad to the bone. The other classic Autobots and Decepticons are cool in their own unique ways. Hot Rod makes for a good hero and Kup is a fun old robot who likes to think about the old days of the war. Orson Welles was great as Unicron and we're talking about his final role before he passed away. He provided true menace to his character with his voice; forget "Citizen Kane", Transformers man! There are very few things to nitpick around here, but overall, this movie is definitely worth buying, partly because of the nostalgia factor. With a great story, stellar voice cast, lovable and diverse cast of characters, great action scenes, and fun music, The Transformers The Movie is sure to please any fan. Nine out of ten, so check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The definition of nostalgia . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tanis_38
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no way to objectively review this film. It was my absolute favorite movie as a kid and I wore out my VHS copy. Seeing it now as an adult, I cannot see it through anything but child- like eyes and with overwhelming feelings of happy, sweet, nostalgia. Is it a great movie? I am not sure. Is the soundtrack cheesy 80's rock? Maybe. Is it my favorite Transformers movie? Absolutely. Will it always bring a smile to my face? I have one right now just thinking about it. Sure, the animation is wildly inconsistent, going from pretty amazing to laughably bad "Sunday Morning cartoon fare" from scene to scene. Sure, it can be seen as one big commercial for the future toy products of the series. But none of that matters when you are 8 years old. The Optimus Prime death scene was borderline traumatizing. The film is surprisingly violent by today's standards and outright gutsy in its willingness to kill off series regulars. It held no punches and if you were a kid in the 80's there is no way you can hear "You Got the Touch" and not smile, picturing Optimus Prime going to town on the Decepticons. This will always be in my top favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie with Transformers that has real emotion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevenbeech
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the first of the new Transformers movies and I can honestly say that the best thing in that film was Bernie Mac. 2 and a quarter hours of blowing stuff up isn't a movie. This is a movie. This is a movie that has real heart, real emotion, real themes at its core and one of the best film soundtracks ever. Sure there a bits where it drags a little and you want it to get back to the main action but it all makes sense in the end. This film probably won't make a massive amount of sense to the average 12 year old I must say, but to the 30 somethings amongst us it carries a great deal of our childhoods with it and along with that I feel a massive emotional attachment to it. The film deals with themes such as loyalty, friendship, the transition from youth to adulthood, the acceptance of responsibility, respect for elders, working toward a common goal and much else all backed by a superb 80's soft metal soundtrack composed by the much underrated Stan Bush. The soundtrack is the driving force behind much of the emotion of the movie, watch the scene where Hot Rod becomes Rodimus Prime without The Touch and its nowhere near as effective. Watch Optimus take out the decepticons without The Touch and you won't pull for him. Watch Hot Rod and Kup escape the Sharkticons without Dare playing and it doesn't work as well. This is a movie worth seeing. If only to compare it to the newer rebooted films which are technically superior and have had more spent on the catering for the cast than this movie probably cost to make but don't have the plot lines, heart, story or sheer entertainment value that this 80's throwback does.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Depressing first, then confusing and becoming more uninteresting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martyshoemark
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Transformers: The Movie was not as good as any of the episodes from the Generation One cartoon episodes from Seasons 1 to 2. Season 2 was an abundance of entertaining adventures of the Transformers in which both evil and justice battle each other while suffering the same troubles. The movie had clearly killed off so many beloved characters besides Prime, these included Prowl, Brawn, Ironhide, Ratchet, Wheeljack, and Starscream. However, the music and dramatic atmosphere of their death scenes were made to appear as if their deaths would not be tragic for the TV show audiences. The film quickly rushed into bringing upon new characters that hardly were introduced as well. The movie seemed to have just taken a not-so-much-of-an-advantage portion of its' length to add in complex plot structures that don't affect the main story of the movie, but instead to make sure this will be a bridge to Season 3 in the TV show. The Quintessons' entrance was clearly unnecessary in the plot and was only put in so that Season 3 can be established right away. The main villain of the story, Unicron, is really simple, he's just a misanthrope who wants to destroy EVERYTHING. Why? We don't know, that's just trying to make a character as a big, simple problem, which is a weak point common in several fictional stories. His voice actor, Orson Welles, was correct that this story is about a big toy attacking smaller toys. A lot of the plot was cheaply winged off of Star Wars such as the light sabers sounds, Arcee's cinnamon bun hairstyle like Leia's, and especially the climax between Hot Rod and Galvatron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly more that meets the Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TJMBuddlake
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though, i was born in 89, i still somehow grew to love transformers. I used to watch the old cartoons on reruns (now you can watch it on Toonamiaftermath.com) and I loved every bit of it. Now, 13 or so years later, I was able to finally get a copy of this movie and got a chance to watch it. OH MY GOD! This is the best transformers movie (better than the live action ones). The story was awesome, the voice cast was phenomenal. Peter Cullen, Casey Kasem, Judd Nelson, Leonard Nimoy and Orson Welles did a great job. Of course, i'm happy that all my favorites were featured (Cliffjumper and Hot Rod). This was definitely a defining moment for the transformers. In addition, the music was awesome. Stan Bush is freaking amazing. The song, The Touch will never get old. This is definitely one for any fans of the franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Transformer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Including this animated movie and the 3 live action Michael Bay movies from the Transformers universe this is by far the best version of a story about TF. The movie has its cheesy moments but it's what I enjoyed about the TF TV show and toy line of the 1980's when I was a kid. If I knew that Bay would bastardize the series like he has with a bunch of penis, fart jokes, racism and Shia LaBeouf I don't think I would've ever bothered to watch any of his movies about TF. The movie is basically TF trying to transition from their early toy lines with the Optimus Prime and MMegatron eras as the respective leaders of the Autobots and Decepticons to the more updated version with Rodimus Prime and Galvatron being the leaders. They even were able to woo Orson Welles into playing the voice of Unicron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Micheal Bay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nnguyen0297
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transformers the movie. What can I say about this movie? Well I guess I can start by saying that it is the most action packed animated film I have ever seen! That's technically what this movie is. It's just 1hr and 20min of non-stop shooting, explosion, fighting,and adventure. Well of course there's more to the plot. The film opens with a giant planet named Unicron that looks like the Death Star eating another planet. Then it shifts to the Autobots who're about to lead a shuttle to search for more energon cubes. Unfortunately for them, The evil Decepticons raids their ship and kill all the members. This really got a lot of fans angry because they saw a lot of their favorite characters die 10 minutes into the movie. The only reason they killed so many characters is so they can add new characters and release more toys. They were taking a big risk killing off so many characters. Anyway, the Decepticons takes over the ship and they are spotted by the Autobot Hot Rod. Hot Rod and some other Autobots attacks the ship, and an all out battle rages. During the battle, Optimus Prime (the leader of the Autobots)confronts Megatron(the leader of the Decepticons). They engage in an all out battles that left all fans cheering because they waited so long to see these two rivals fight to the death. After a while, It seemed that Optimus won, but Megatron played a dirty trick and wounded Optimus pretty badly. But Optimus with all the strength he had left gave Megatron one last punch that left him crippled. The Decepticons escape, and optimus with his last breath, gave the Matrix and his leadership to Ultra Magnus. Mean while, an injured Megatron gets betrayed by his minion Starscream and gets pushed off into space. There, he meets Unicron who makes Megatron one of his minions. In exchange, he gives Megatron a new and more powerful body and rename him Galvatron. He also gives Megatron 3 robots named Relector. With his new power, he kills Starscream and takes over the decepticons again. Now Unicron is forcing him to kill the Autobots and destroy the All Sparks. Now the Autobots have to face Galvatron and Unicron at the same time. I'm not gonna spoil the rest because this is where the movie gets really good. I'm a casual fan of Transformers, and I must say, this film really impressed me. Some people hate it because it had to much violent action, some random music use, and there's to many references to Star Wars. Yes there is a whole bunch of action, but that's what's awesome about it. How many movies have you seen where something blows up every 5 seconds? Yeah, sometimes the action can be a little uneven, and the animation might be laggy from time to time, but this was made in the 80s so give it some slack. There are many references to Star Wars however. Like the character Hot rod is related to Luke, Unicron looks like the Death Star, Arcee has the princess Leah hairstyle, Optimus Prime talks to Hot Rod in his ghost form much like how Ben Kenobi talks to Luke. But i didn't really mind that. So many movies copied things from Star wars up to the point that you don't care anymore. As for the music however, it is completely random. Like when Hot Rod opens the Matrix and the song "The Touch" starts playing in the background. It also has the most random use of Weird Al Yankovic's "Dare to be Stupid". They played that song when the Autobots where fighting some other random robots in some random planet. And after they made peace with those robots, they started dancing to the exact same song! Despite all these negative feature to this film, it's awesome and anyone will love it. I give it~ 3.5/5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relic of the 80s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhtsosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How does it feel to jump back 25 years, into a remnant of your childhood? Does the past hold up with the memories you once associated with it, or will it seem silly and outdated? I recently relived a portion of my childhood in watching the original Transformers cartoon movie from 1986. It is appropriately titled "Transformers: The Movie." I never did see this movie as a child, although I watched the show on and off in some of my early years. I recently decided to watch the movie, partially out of interest to see the movie for the first time, but mainly to relive something out of my childhood. I wanted to see how it would hold up after 15 years of no transformers cartoons. To keep things straight, Transformers is not a "good" movie. The story is heavily episodic and jumpy, as if several TV episodes were crammed together. The quality of animation was alright for its time, but hasn't aged well. The soundtrack is heavy on the 1980s power rock/ pop (think Top Gun), also not having aged well. The movie is cheesy and silly, and in all honesty, somewhat ridiculous. However, the movie, while definitely not good, works as a guilty pleasure fun movie. As dumb as it was viewing it, I highly enjoyed it. With each cheesy line, I was more drawn into it. Viewing it wasn't like the phrase about "you can't turn away from watching a car crash." It was highly nostalgic. A part of me did wonder how we enjoyed such things as kids. While the movie is silly, it is highly exploitive in a sense of how much of it is focused on robot-on- robot action. Movies aren't made like this anymore. Transformers gets in, has no story but a ton of robot fighting, some cheesy 80s tunes to boost the mood, and gets out after 80 minutes. It's almost as if the movie knows exactly what it is, and does exactly what it can do. Transformers doesn't jump out as a must see movie. For people in their 20s and older, it can be charming, as a relic to a different age of TV. For people too young to remember it originally, it will jump out as an example of the questioning "Is this REALLY what you used to watch?" It is pretty much a toy commercial in disguise. However, it is worth viewing, both because it is a pure relic from the 1980s, but also because it comes from a time of more pure filmmaking. Transformers does exactly what it is sent out to do. While it wasn't aiming very high, it works. You could certainly do much worse than checking this out. 6/10. Go download the soundtrack if you need a new workout mix.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheesy Fun for the Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B. Transformers the Movie is a good, cheesy animated movie that ends the well done television series and does some surprising things but is rather entertaining. The war is still going on between the Autobots and Decepticons, but what they don't know is that there is a huge transformer that shaped like a planet heading towards them, devouring everything in its path. The opening battle on Earth is a rather tense one for the Autobots. Their base gets badly destroyed and lose one of their own that made quite a stir with fans after they saw it, Megatron kills Optimus Prime. He gives the Matrix to Ultra Magnus and puts him in charge and the Autobots head away from their base in search for their own who were eaten by the planet transformer, Unicron. Megatron after the battle got badly hurt and Starscream, wanting to be in charge, lets him go into space with others hurt and is picked up by Unicron and is now called Galvatron and working for Unicron.. Galvatron goes to Cybertron in search for Starscream and kills him and now all the Decepticons are his again with his new allies made for him by Unicron. The Autobots fly out, but are attacked by Galvatron and some land on a planet covered with trash and Hot Rod, Cub, and the Dinobots land on another planet. Hot Rod and Cub are taken prisoner and are trialed on how they will die by the planets ruler. Meanwhile, Galvatron went after the group on the rundown planet and they start hunting them and Ultra Magnus tries to use the Matrix for Prime said it will be used in their darkest hour. It doesn't open, and Galvatron blows him up. Then the inhabitants of the planet battle them. Then Cub and Hot Rod show up and save them and the junkbots rebuild Ultra Magnus and go help the Autobots fight Unicron. Meanwhile, Galvatron returns with the Matrix and wants to be in charge but won't and then the Autbots arrive to fight Unicron and save their own while Hot Rod has a final showdown with Galvatron. This is epic with him taking the Matrix and uses it against Unicron and turns into Rodimus Prime. The Decepticons die and the Autobots take back Cybertron. The movie has cheesy animation but is entertaining with some decent music, good characters, and is a great conclusion with a badass villain. Good for the fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'One shall stand, one shall fall..'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    markbyam
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film simply blew me away the first time I saw it. And still does today 20 years later. Right from The opening sequence, to the level of violence between the Decepticons and Autobots (which is totally justified) is spot on. They didn't hold back or try and soften the conflict and it was portrayed superbly. Everything from the soundtrack to the characters, and the dialogue works perfectly. Especially the dialogue which you just wouldn't get in a kids film nowadays. So many good one liners. The speech between Megatron and Prime is just pure brilliance with a fight scene that follows animated to perfection. The voice casting is exceptional and every action sequence is pulled off with such style and finesse. It even has one of the saddest scenes of any film that still makes me teary today. Once very rarely something comes along that just works in every single way...even more. Transformers the movie 1986 is an example of this. I feel privileged to have seen this as a child. Til all are one! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Me Grimlock love this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the release of the explosive Michael Bay trilogy, any newcomers to the shape-shifting franchise should be aware of the original 1986 animated feature because that's where it all started (sort of). Hasbro's Transformers became such a huge hit thanks to a combination of both the toys and the original G1 TV series of the same name. Robots changing into vehicles, guns, and even animals was such an incredible and original concept that it's hard to ignore. After running for two seasons at the time, Hasbro decided to make a full-length movie starring the Autobots and Decepticons. Plot: The year is 2005 (imagine that) as the Autobots, led by the heroic Optimus Prime, prepare to retake their home world Cybertron from the clutches of the evil Megatron and his Decepticons. However, a terrifying intergalactic force has arrived on the scene that's proved to be literally bigger than their petty war, the planet-sized Unicron (Orsen Welles). With the power of this new foe greater than anything imagined, it will take a new generation of heroes to stop this menace. Time to transform and role out! Next to "Revenge of the Fallen", this is by far my favorite film of the franchise. Seeing how the Transformers were before their live-action release was a real pleasure to see. Many of the famous characters, Autobot and Decepticon alike, get to have there little moments of action and glory, especially the Dinobots, who are my all-time favorite characters. The action scenes are just spectacular and it's pretty much non-stop. Call me old-fashioned, but I love the music, which is typical 80s soundtrack and it fits perfectly with this movie, such as Stan Bush's "The Touch" which is made famous because of this movie. The animation is also worth noting, definitely superior to the animation of the TV series. The film also became famous by taking risky moves with the old characters while introducing new ones. Optimus Prime and Megatron (Peter Cullen and Frank Welker) are still going at it as their rivalry never seems to end, though both go through some major changes. The Dinobots are fun to watch and bad to the bone. The other classic Autobots and Decepticons are cool in their own unique ways. Hot Rod makes for a good hero and Kup is a fun old robot who likes to think about the old days of the war. Orson Welles was great as Unicron and we're talking about his final role before he passed away. He provided true menace to his character with his voice; forget "Citizen Kane", Transformers man! There are very few things to nitpick around here, but overall, this movie is definitely worth buying, partly because of the nostalgia factor. With a great story, stellar voice cast, lovable and diverse cast of characters, great action scenes, and fun music, The Transformers The Movie is sure to please any fan. Nine out of ten, so check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The definition of nostalgia . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tanis_38
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no way to objectively review this film. It was my absolute favorite movie as a kid and I wore out my VHS copy. Seeing it now as an adult, I cannot see it through anything but child- like eyes and with overwhelming feelings of happy, sweet, nostalgia. Is it a great movie? I am not sure. Is the soundtrack cheesy 80's rock? Maybe. Is it my favorite Transformers movie? Absolutely. Will it always bring a smile to my face? I have one right now just thinking about it. Sure, the animation is wildly inconsistent, going from pretty amazing to laughably bad "Sunday Morning cartoon fare" from scene to scene. Sure, it can be seen as one big commercial for the future toy products of the series. But none of that matters when you are 8 years old. The Optimus Prime death scene was borderline traumatizing. The film is surprisingly violent by today's standards and outright gutsy in its willingness to kill off series regulars. It held no punches and if you were a kid in the 80's there is no way you can hear "You Got the Touch" and not smile, picturing Optimus Prime going to town on the Decepticons. This will always be in my top favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie with Transformers that has real emotion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevenbeech
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the first of the new Transformers movies and I can honestly say that the best thing in that film was Bernie Mac. 2 and a quarter hours of blowing stuff up isn't a movie. This is a movie. This is a movie that has real heart, real emotion, real themes at its core and one of the best film soundtracks ever. Sure there a bits where it drags a little and you want it to get back to the main action but it all makes sense in the end. This film probably won't make a massive amount of sense to the average 12 year old I must say, but to the 30 somethings amongst us it carries a great deal of our childhoods with it and along with that I feel a massive emotional attachment to it. The film deals with themes such as loyalty, friendship, the transition from youth to adulthood, the acceptance of responsibility, respect for elders, working toward a common goal and much else all backed by a superb 80's soft metal soundtrack composed by the much underrated Stan Bush. The soundtrack is the driving force behind much of the emotion of the movie, watch the scene where Hot Rod becomes Rodimus Prime without The Touch and its nowhere near as effective. Watch Optimus take out the decepticons without The Touch and you won't pull for him. Watch Hot Rod and Kup escape the Sharkticons without Dare playing and it doesn't work as well. This is a movie worth seeing. If only to compare it to the newer rebooted films which are technically superior and have had more spent on the catering for the cast than this movie probably cost to make but don't have the plot lines, heart, story or sheer entertainment value that this 80's throwback does.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Depressing first, then confusing and becoming more uninteresting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martyshoemark
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Transformers: The Movie was not as good as any of the episodes from the Generation One cartoon episodes from Seasons 1 to 2. Season 2 was an abundance of entertaining adventures of the Transformers in which both evil and justice battle each other while suffering the same troubles. The movie had clearly killed off so many beloved characters besides Prime, these included Prowl, Brawn, Ironhide, Ratchet, Wheeljack, and Starscream. However, the music and dramatic atmosphere of their death scenes were made to appear as if their deaths would not be tragic for the TV show audiences. The film quickly rushed into bringing upon new characters that hardly were introduced as well. The movie seemed to have just taken a not-so-much-of-an-advantage portion of its' length to add in complex plot structures that don't affect the main story of the movie, but instead to make sure this will be a bridge to Season 3 in the TV show. The Quintessons' entrance was clearly unnecessary in the plot and was only put in so that Season 3 can be established right away. The main villain of the story, Unicron, is really simple, he's just a misanthrope who wants to destroy EVERYTHING. Why? We don't know, that's just trying to make a character as a big, simple problem, which is a weak point common in several fictional stories. His voice actor, Orson Welles, was correct that this story is about a big toy attacking smaller toys. A lot of the plot was cheaply winged off of Star Wars such as the light sabers sounds, Arcee's cinnamon bun hairstyle like Leia's, and especially the climax between Hot Rod and Galvatron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly more that meets the Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TJMBuddlake
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though, i was born in 89, i still somehow grew to love transformers. I used to watch the old cartoons on reruns (now you can watch it on Toonamiaftermath.com) and I loved every bit of it. Now, 13 or so years later, I was able to finally get a copy of this movie and got a chance to watch it. OH MY GOD! This is the best transformers movie (better than the live action ones). The story was awesome, the voice cast was phenomenal. Peter Cullen, Casey Kasem, Judd Nelson, Leonard Nimoy and Orson Welles did a great job. Of course, i'm happy that all my favorites were featured (Cliffjumper and Hot Rod). This was definitely a defining moment for the transformers. In addition, the music was awesome. Stan Bush is freaking amazing. The song, The Touch will never get old. This is definitely one for any fans of the franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Transformer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Including this animated movie and the 3 live action Michael Bay movies from the Transformers universe this is by far the best version of a story about TF. The movie has its cheesy moments but it's what I enjoyed about the TF TV show and toy line of the 1980's when I was a kid. If I knew that Bay would bastardize the series like he has with a bunch of penis, fart jokes, racism and Shia LaBeouf I don't think I would've ever bothered to watch any of his movies about TF. The movie is basically TF trying to transition from their early toy lines with the Optimus Prime and MMegatron eras as the respective leaders of the Autobots and Decepticons to the more updated version with Rodimus Prime and Galvatron being the leaders. They even were able to woo Orson Welles into playing the voice of Unicron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Micheal Bay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nnguyen0297
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transformers the movie. What can I say about this movie? Well I guess I can start by saying that it is the most action packed animated film I have ever seen! That's technically what this movie is. It's just 1hr and 20min of non-stop shooting, explosion, fighting,and adventure. Well of course there's more to the plot. The film opens with a giant planet named Unicron that looks like the Death Star eating another planet. Then it shifts to the Autobots who're about to lead a shuttle to search for more energon cubes. Unfortunately for them, The evil Decepticons raids their ship and kill all the members. This really got a lot of fans angry because they saw a lot of their favorite characters die 10 minutes into the movie. The only reason they killed so many characters is so they can add new characters and release more toys. They were taking a big risk killing off so many characters. Anyway, the Decepticons takes over the ship and they are spotted by the Autobot Hot Rod. Hot Rod and some other Autobots attacks the ship, and an all out battle rages. During the battle, Optimus Prime (the leader of the Autobots)confronts Megatron(the leader of the Decepticons). They engage in an all out battles that left all fans cheering because they waited so long to see these two rivals fight to the death. After a while, It seemed that Optimus won, but Megatron played a dirty trick and wounded Optimus pretty badly. But Optimus with all the strength he had left gave Megatron one last punch that left him crippled. The Decepticons escape, and optimus with his last breath, gave the Matrix and his leadership to Ultra Magnus. Mean while, an injured Megatron gets betrayed by his minion Starscream and gets pushed off into space. There, he meets Unicron who makes Megatron one of his minions. In exchange, he gives Megatron a new and more powerful body and rename him Galvatron. He also gives Megatron 3 robots named Relector. With his new power, he kills Starscream and takes over the decepticons again. Now Unicron is forcing him to kill the Autobots and destroy the All Sparks. Now the Autobots have to face Galvatron and Unicron at the same time. I'm not gonna spoil the rest because this is where the movie gets really good. I'm a casual fan of Transformers, and I must say, this film really impressed me. Some people hate it because it had to much violent action, some random music use, and there's to many references to Star Wars. Yes there is a whole bunch of action, but that's what's awesome about it. How many movies have you seen where something blows up every 5 seconds? Yeah, sometimes the action can be a little uneven, and the animation might be laggy from time to time, but this was made in the 80s so give it some slack. There are many references to Star Wars however. Like the character Hot rod is related to Luke, Unicron looks like the Death Star, Arcee has the princess Leah hairstyle, Optimus Prime talks to Hot Rod in his ghost form much like how Ben Kenobi talks to Luke. But i didn't really mind that. So many movies copied things from Star wars up to the point that you don't care anymore. As for the music however, it is completely random. Like when Hot Rod opens the Matrix and the song "The Touch" starts playing in the background. It also has the most random use of Weird Al Yankovic's "Dare to be Stupid". They played that song when the Autobots where fighting some other random robots in some random planet. And after they made peace with those robots, they started dancing to the exact same song! Despite all these negative feature to this film, it's awesome and anyone will love it. I give it~ 3.5/5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relic of the 80s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhtsosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How does it feel to jump back 25 years, into a remnant of your childhood? Does the past hold up with the memories you once associated with it, or will it seem silly and outdated? I recently relived a portion of my childhood in watching the original Transformers cartoon movie from 1986. It is appropriately titled "Transformers: The Movie." I never did see this movie as a child, although I watched the show on and off in some of my early years. I recently decided to watch the movie, partially out of interest to see the movie for the first time, but mainly to relive something out of my childhood. I wanted to see how it would hold up after 15 years of no transformers cartoons. To keep things straight, Transformers is not a "good" movie. The story is heavily episodic and jumpy, as if several TV episodes were crammed together. The quality of animation was alright for its time, but hasn't aged well. The soundtrack is heavy on the 1980s power rock/ pop (think Top Gun), also not having aged well. The movie is cheesy and silly, and in all honesty, somewhat ridiculous. However, the movie, while definitely not good, works as a guilty pleasure fun movie. As dumb as it was viewing it, I highly enjoyed it. With each cheesy line, I was more drawn into it. Viewing it wasn't like the phrase about "you can't turn away from watching a car crash." It was highly nostalgic. A part of me did wonder how we enjoyed such things as kids. While the movie is silly, it is highly exploitive in a sense of how much of it is focused on robot-on- robot action. Movies aren't made like this anymore. Transformers gets in, has no story but a ton of robot fighting, some cheesy 80s tunes to boost the mood, and gets out after 80 minutes. It's almost as if the movie knows exactly what it is, and does exactly what it can do. Transformers doesn't jump out as a must see movie. For people in their 20s and older, it can be charming, as a relic to a different age of TV. For people too young to remember it originally, it will jump out as an example of the questioning "Is this REALLY what you used to watch?" It is pretty much a toy commercial in disguise. However, it is worth viewing, both because it is a pure relic from the 1980s, but also because it comes from a time of more pure filmmaking. Transformers does exactly what it is sent out to do. While it wasn't aiming very high, it works. You could certainly do much worse than checking this out. 6/10. Go download the soundtrack if you need a new workout mix.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cheesy Fun for the Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grade: B. Transformers the Movie is a good, cheesy animated movie that ends the well done television series and does some surprising things but is rather entertaining. The war is still going on between the Autobots and Decepticons, but what they don't know is that there is a huge transformer that shaped like a planet heading towards them, devouring everything in its path. The opening battle on Earth is a rather tense one for the Autobots. Their base gets badly destroyed and lose one of their own that made quite a stir with fans after they saw it, Megatron kills Optimus Prime. He gives the Matrix to Ultra Magnus and puts him in charge and the Autobots head away from their base in search for their own who were eaten by the planet transformer, Unicron. Megatron after the battle got badly hurt and Starscream, wanting to be in charge, lets him go into space with others hurt and is picked up by Unicron and is now called Galvatron and working for Unicron.. Galvatron goes to Cybertron in search for Starscream and kills him and now all the Decepticons are his again with his new allies made for him by Unicron. The Autobots fly out, but are attacked by Galvatron and some land on a planet covered with trash and Hot Rod, Cub, and the Dinobots land on another planet. Hot Rod and Cub are taken prisoner and are trialed on how they will die by the planets ruler. Meanwhile, Galvatron went after the group on the rundown planet and they start hunting them and Ultra Magnus tries to use the Matrix for Prime said it will be used in their darkest hour. It doesn't open, and Galvatron blows him up. Then the inhabitants of the planet battle them. Then Cub and Hot Rod show up and save them and the junkbots rebuild Ultra Magnus and go help the Autobots fight Unicron. Meanwhile, Galvatron returns with the Matrix and wants to be in charge but won't and then the Autbots arrive to fight Unicron and save their own while Hot Rod has a final showdown with Galvatron. This is epic with him taking the Matrix and uses it against Unicron and turns into Rodimus Prime. The Decepticons die and the Autobots take back Cybertron. The movie has cheesy animation but is entertaining with some decent music, good characters, and is a great conclusion with a badass villain. Good for the fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'One shall stand, one shall fall..'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    markbyam
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film simply blew me away the first time I saw it. And still does today 20 years later. Right from The opening sequence, to the level of violence between the Decepticons and Autobots (which is totally justified) is spot on. They didn't hold back or try and soften the conflict and it was portrayed superbly. Everything from the soundtrack to the characters, and the dialogue works perfectly. Especially the dialogue which you just wouldn't get in a kids film nowadays. So many good one liners. The speech between Megatron and Prime is just pure brilliance with a fight scene that follows animated to perfection. The voice casting is exceptional and every action sequence is pulled off with such style and finesse. It even has one of the saddest scenes of any film that still makes me teary today. Once very rarely something comes along that just works in every single way...even more. Transformers the movie 1986 is an example of this. I feel privileged to have seen this as a child. Til all are one! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Me Grimlock love this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the release of the explosive Michael Bay trilogy, any newcomers to the shape-shifting franchise should be aware of the original 1986 animated feature because that's where it all started (sort of). Hasbro's Transformers became such a huge hit thanks to a combination of both the toys and the original G1 TV series of the same name. Robots changing into vehicles, guns, and even animals was such an incredible and original concept that it's hard to ignore. After running for two seasons at the time, Hasbro decided to make a full-length movie starring the Autobots and Decepticons. Plot: The year is 2005 (imagine that) as the Autobots, led by the heroic Optimus Prime, prepare to retake their home world Cybertron from the clutches of the evil Megatron and his Decepticons. However, a terrifying intergalactic force has arrived on the scene that's proved to be literally bigger than their petty war, the planet-sized Unicron (Orsen Welles). With the power of this new foe greater than anything imagined, it will take a new generation of heroes to stop this menace. Time to transform and role out! Next to "Revenge of the Fallen", this is by far my favorite film of the franchise. Seeing how the Transformers were before their live-action release was a real pleasure to see. Many of the famous characters, Autobot and Decepticon alike, get to have there little moments of action and glory, especially the Dinobots, who are my all-time favorite characters. The action scenes are just spectacular and it's pretty much non-stop. Call me old-fashioned, but I love the music, which is typical 80s soundtrack and it fits perfectly with this movie, such as Stan Bush's "The Touch" which is made famous because of this movie. The animation is also worth noting, definitely superior to the animation of the TV series. The film also became famous by taking risky moves with the old characters while introducing new ones. Optimus Prime and Megatron (Peter Cullen and Frank Welker) are still going at it as their rivalry never seems to end, though both go through some major changes. The Dinobots are fun to watch and bad to the bone. The other classic Autobots and Decepticons are cool in their own unique ways. Hot Rod makes for a good hero and Kup is a fun old robot who likes to think about the old days of the war. Orson Welles was great as Unicron and we're talking about his final role before he passed away. He provided true menace to his character with his voice; forget "Citizen Kane", Transformers man! There are very few things to nitpick around here, but overall, this movie is definitely worth buying, partly because of the nostalgia factor. With a great story, stellar voice cast, lovable and diverse cast of characters, great action scenes, and fun music, The Transformers The Movie is sure to please any fan. Nine out of ten, so check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The definition of nostalgia . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tanis_38
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no way to objectively review this film. It was my absolute favorite movie as a kid and I wore out my VHS copy. Seeing it now as an adult, I cannot see it through anything but child- like eyes and with overwhelming feelings of happy, sweet, nostalgia. Is it a great movie? I am not sure. Is the soundtrack cheesy 80's rock? Maybe. Is it my favorite Transformers movie? Absolutely. Will it always bring a smile to my face? I have one right now just thinking about it. Sure, the animation is wildly inconsistent, going from pretty amazing to laughably bad "Sunday Morning cartoon fare" from scene to scene. Sure, it can be seen as one big commercial for the future toy products of the series. But none of that matters when you are 8 years old. The Optimus Prime death scene was borderline traumatizing. The film is surprisingly violent by today's standards and outright gutsy in its willingness to kill off series regulars. It held no punches and if you were a kid in the 80's there is no way you can hear "You Got the Touch" and not smile, picturing Optimus Prime going to town on the Decepticons. This will always be in my top favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie with Transformers that has real emotion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stevenbeech
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the first of the new Transformers movies and I can honestly say that the best thing in that film was Bernie Mac. 2 and a quarter hours of blowing stuff up isn't a movie. This is a movie. This is a movie that has real heart, real emotion, real themes at its core and one of the best film soundtracks ever. Sure there a bits where it drags a little and you want it to get back to the main action but it all makes sense in the end. This film probably won't make a massive amount of sense to the average 12 year old I must say, but to the 30 somethings amongst us it carries a great deal of our childhoods with it and along with that I feel a massive emotional attachment to it. The film deals with themes such as loyalty, friendship, the transition from youth to adulthood, the acceptance of responsibility, respect for elders, working toward a common goal and much else all backed by a superb 80's soft metal soundtrack composed by the much underrated Stan Bush. The soundtrack is the driving force behind much of the emotion of the movie, watch the scene where Hot Rod becomes Rodimus Prime without The Touch and its nowhere near as effective. Watch Optimus take out the decepticons without The Touch and you won't pull for him. Watch Hot Rod and Kup escape the Sharkticons without Dare playing and it doesn't work as well. This is a movie worth seeing. If only to compare it to the newer rebooted films which are technically superior and have had more spent on the catering for the cast than this movie probably cost to make but don't have the plot lines, heart, story or sheer entertainment value that this 80's throwback does.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Depressing first, then confusing and becoming more uninteresting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    martyshoemark
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Transformers: The Movie was not as good as any of the episodes from the Generation One cartoon episodes from Seasons 1 to 2. Season 2 was an abundance of entertaining adventures of the Transformers in which both evil and justice battle each other while suffering the same troubles. The movie had clearly killed off so many beloved characters besides Prime, these included Prowl, Brawn, Ironhide, Ratchet, Wheeljack, and Starscream. However, the music and dramatic atmosphere of their death scenes were made to appear as if their deaths would not be tragic for the TV show audiences. The film quickly rushed into bringing upon new characters that hardly were introduced as well. The movie seemed to have just taken a not-so-much-of-an-advantage portion of its' length to add in complex plot structures that don't affect the main story of the movie, but instead to make sure this will be a bridge to Season 3 in the TV show. The Quintessons' entrance was clearly unnecessary in the plot and was only put in so that Season 3 can be established right away. The main villain of the story, Unicron, is really simple, he's just a misanthrope who wants to destroy EVERYTHING. Why? We don't know, that's just trying to make a character as a big, simple problem, which is a weak point common in several fictional stories. His voice actor, Orson Welles, was correct that this story is about a big toy attacking smaller toys. A lot of the plot was cheaply winged off of Star Wars such as the light sabers sounds, Arcee's cinnamon bun hairstyle like Leia's, and especially the climax between Hot Rod and Galvatron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly more that meets the Eye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TJMBuddlake
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though, i was born in 89, i still somehow grew to love transformers. I used to watch the old cartoons on reruns (now you can watch it on Toonamiaftermath.com) and I loved every bit of it. Now, 13 or so years later, I was able to finally get a copy of this movie and got a chance to watch it. OH MY GOD! This is the best transformers movie (better than the live action ones). The story was awesome, the voice cast was phenomenal. Peter Cullen, Casey Kasem, Judd Nelson, Leonard Nimoy and Orson Welles did a great job. Of course, i'm happy that all my favorites were featured (Cliffjumper and Hot Rod). This was definitely a defining moment for the transformers. In addition, the music was awesome. Stan Bush is freaking amazing. The song, The Touch will never get old. This is definitely one for any fans of the franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Transformer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Including this animated movie and the 3 live action Michael Bay movies from the Transformers universe this is by far the best version of a story about TF. The movie has its cheesy moments but it's what I enjoyed about the TF TV show and toy line of the 1980's when I was a kid. If I knew that Bay would bastardize the series like he has with a bunch of penis, fart jokes, racism and Shia LaBeouf I don't think I would've ever bothered to watch any of his movies about TF. The movie is basically TF trying to transition from their early toy lines with the Optimus Prime and MMegatron eras as the respective leaders of the Autobots and Decepticons to the more updated version with Rodimus Prime and Galvatron being the leaders. They even were able to woo Orson Welles into playing the voice of Unicron.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Micheal Bay
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nnguyen0297
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transformers the movie. What can I say about this movie? Well I guess I can start by saying that it is the most action packed animated film I have ever seen! That's technically what this movie is. It's just 1hr and 20min of non-stop shooting, explosion, fighting,and adventure. Well of course there's more to the plot. The film opens with a giant planet named Unicron that looks like the Death Star eating another planet. Then it shifts to the Autobots who're about to lead a shuttle to search for more energon cubes. Unfortunately for them, The evil Decepticons raids their ship and kill all the members. This really got a lot of fans angry because they saw a lot of their favorite characters die 10 minutes into the movie. The only reason they killed so many characters is so they can add new characters and release more toys. They were taking a big risk killing off so many characters. Anyway, the Decepticons takes over the ship and they are spotted by the Autobot Hot Rod. Hot Rod and some other Autobots attacks the ship, and an all out battle rages. During the battle, Optimus Prime (the leader of the Autobots)confronts Megatron(the leader of the Decepticons). They engage in an all out battles that left all fans cheering because they waited so long to see these two rivals fight to the death. After a while, It seemed that Optimus won, but Megatron played a dirty trick and wounded Optimus pretty badly. But Optimus with all the strength he had left gave Megatron one last punch that left him crippled. The Decepticons escape, and optimus with his last breath, gave the Matrix and his leadership to Ultra Magnus. Mean while, an injured Megatron gets betrayed by his minion Starscream and gets pushed off into space. There, he meets Unicron who makes Megatron one of his minions. In exchange, he gives Megatron a new and more powerful body and rename him Galvatron. He also gives Megatron 3 robots named Relector. With his new power, he kills Starscream and takes over the decepticons again. Now Unicron is forcing him to kill the Autobots and destroy the All Sparks. Now the Autobots have to face Galvatron and Unicron at the same time. I'm not gonna spoil the rest because this is where the movie gets really good. I'm a casual fan of Transformers, and I must say, this film really impressed me. Some people hate it because it had to much violent action, some random music use, and there's to many references to Star Wars. Yes there is a whole bunch of action, but that's what's awesome about it. How many movies have you seen where something blows up every 5 seconds? Yeah, sometimes the action can be a little uneven, and the animation might be laggy from time to time, but this was made in the 80s so give it some slack. There are many references to Star Wars however. Like the character Hot rod is related to Luke, Unicron looks like the Death Star, Arcee has the princess Leah hairstyle, Optimus Prime talks to Hot Rod in his ghost form much like how Ben Kenobi talks to Luke. But i didn't really mind that. So many movies copied things from Star wars up to the point that you don't care anymore. As for the music however, it is completely random. Like when Hot Rod opens the Matrix and the song "The Touch" starts playing in the background. It also has the most random use of Weird Al Yankovic's "Dare to be Stupid". They played that song when the Autobots where fighting some other random robots in some random planet. And after they made peace with those robots, they started dancing to the exact same song! Despite all these negative feature to this film, it's awesome and anyone will love it. I give it~ 3.5/5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relic of the 80s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhtsosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How does it feel to jump back 25 years, into a remnant of your childhood? Does the past hold up with the memories you once associated with it, or will it seem silly and outdated? I recently relived a portion of my childhood in watching the original Transformers cartoon movie from 1986. It is appropriately titled "Transformers: The Movie." I never did see this movie as a child, although I watched the show on and off in some of my early years. I recently decided to watch the movie, partially out of interest to see the movie for the first time, but mainly to relive something out of my childhood. I wanted to see how it would hold up after 15 years of no transformers cartoons. To keep things straight, Transformers is not a "good" movie. The story is heavily episodic and jumpy, as if several TV episodes were crammed together. The quality of animation was alright for its time, but hasn't aged well. The soundtrack is heavy on the 1980s power rock/ pop (think Top Gun), also not having aged well. The movie is cheesy and silly, and in all honesty, somewhat ridiculous. However, the movie, while definitely not good, works as a guilty pleasure fun movie. As dumb as it was viewing it, I highly enjoyed it. With each cheesy line, I was more drawn into it. Viewing it wasn't like the phrase about "you can't turn away from watching a car crash." It was highly nostalgic. A part of me did wonder how we enjoyed such things as kids. While the movie is silly, it is highly exploitive in a sense of how much of it is focused on robot-on- robot action. Movies aren't made like this anymore. Transformers gets in, has no story but a ton of robot fighting, some cheesy 80s tunes to boost the mood, and gets out after 80 minutes. It's almost as if the movie knows exactly what it is, and does exactly what it can do. Transformers doesn't jump out as a must see movie. For people in their 20s and older, it can be charming, as a relic to a different age of TV. For people too young to remember it originally, it will jump out as an example of the questioning "Is this REALLY what you used to watch?" It is pretty much a toy commercial in disguise. However, it is worth viewing, both because it is a pure relic from the 1980s, but also because it comes from a time of more pure filmmaking. Transformers does exactly what it is sent out to do. While it wasn't aiming very high, it works. You could certainly do much worse than checking this out. 6/10. Go download the soundtrack if you need a new workout mix.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
