<filme>
 <id>
  427
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0056592
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1962
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Sol &Eacute; Para Todos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Atticus Finch, a lawyer in the Depression-era South, defends a black man against an undeserved rape charge, and his kids against prejudice.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Based on Harper Lee's Pulitzer Prize winning book of 1961. Atticus Finch is a lawyer in a racially divided Alabama town in the 1930s. He agrees to defend a young black man who is accused of raping a white woman. Many of the townspeople try to get Atticus to pull out of the trial, but he decides to go ahead. How will the trial turn out - and will it change any of the racial tension in the town ?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   children
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   trial
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   lawyer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   alabama
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tree
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Robert Mulligan
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Harper Lee
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Horton Foote
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Gregory Peck
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Megna
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Frank Overton
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful Courtroom Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gregory Peck plays Atticus Finch, an Alabama lawyer who is called upon to defend a black man(played by Brock Peters) who is wrongfully accused of raping a white woman(played by Collin Wilcox) in the 1930's, where such an allegation could get him lynched before a trial. Story also includes Atticus's two children Scout & Jem, and the film is mostly seen from their POV, as they try to understand what's going on and why. Robert Duvall plays a mysterious figure named Boo Radley(played by Robert Duvall) who will have a huge impact on their lives. Superb film with an Academy Award winning performance by Gregory Peck, and fine direction by Robert Mulligan, who creates an evocative atmosphere of small town Alabama life of this period, and the wonder yet naivety of childhood. A first-rate adaptation of Harper Lee's famous novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't cut it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    King Sidharth
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film starts with the same essence as the book, but through experience I've learned not to compare much - they are two very different mediums. The problem begins with the film pacing up and skipping important events that build up motives of the characters and causes shift in their intent. Towards the end all of it looks like a rush. The importance and the the details of how grave the case of a lawyer actually backing up black man is lost in translation across the medium. Well, all of that can be forgiven and the film still somehow works along. But the contextual shock of a man attacking children is totally lost on screenplay, many dialog were changed which the climax dry and juice-less - taking all emotions out of it. Characters, especially Atticus's, were portrayed and played out very well. They are the only reason the film works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Most Overrated Films... Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Widely regarded as one of the greatest courtroom dramas of all time, it was surprising to see that there is not even a single shot of a courtroom in the first half which felt more of a suspense/horror for a completely different reason than what is depicted in the second half. Gregory Peck packs in a powerful performance as Atticus Finch, a righteous lawyer defending a Negro in an alleged rape case. The child actors did a nice job too & this film also introduces Robert Duvall in his first role. To Kill A Mockingbird's theme of prejudice moving us from the path of true judgment is clear but overall, this movie is overlong, somewhat boring & one of the most overrated films of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1962's To Kill A Mockingbird Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Robert Mulligan's Direction, Horton Foote's Screenplay, Russell Harlan's Cinematography, Elmer Bernstein's Score And Gregory Peck's Oscar-Winning Performance As Atticus Finch, It Ranks #25 On The AFI's 10th Anniversary List Of The Greatest American Movies Of All Time In 2007, Atticus Finch Was Voted The Greatest Movie Hero Of The 20th Century In 2003, A Really Robert Duvall In This Film, He Has Been In My Fourth Favorite Film Of All 1972's The Godfather With Marlon Brando And Al Pacino, This Movie Turned 50 Years Old Last Year In 2012, It Was 40 Years Old Just Over Eleven Years Back In 2002.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD is a classic adaption of a classic novel. I remember reading and watching this at school but most of the civil rights-era background when right over my head. Not really worth exploring a movie dealing with mature themes as a kid, but there you go. Watching it again as an adult, it's a delight and as hard-hitting as MISSISSIPPI BURNING, which came much later. I've always liked Gregory Peck and his laconic Atticus Finch is an exploration of a quiet, inherently decent man. It's a subtle performance of amazing strength, with no showy-off 'acting' scenes or the like; Peck's Oscar win was well deserved. I particularly liked the way the narrative develops through the eyes of a pair of innocent children as it adds another layer to the story. The whole sub-plot involving Boo Radley is a classic bit of mischief and I love the way the two plots tie up neatly at the end. The child actors are exceptionally strong and despite the lengthy running time the movie doesn't have any slow spots; it's all relevant and adds to the experience. As I said, this is a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lawyer against a village.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "To Kill a Mockingbird" is a movie based on Harper Lee's book of 1961 (Pulitzer Prize winning). It's a movie that displays the racial racism of the time (1930s) and how people treat each other in such times. It all starts when a black man (Brock Peters) accused of raping a white woman and Gregory Peck (Atticus Finch) represent him as his lawyer. When villagers learn about this representation of Atticus Finch they want to change his mind but Atticus decides to go ahead of it. I liked very much the performances of Gregory Peck as Atticus Finch a lawyer who fights for justice and of course the performances of the two little ones (son and daughter of Atticus Finch) Mary Badham as Scout and Phillip Alford as Jem. I recommend it because I think that this movie shows us a different treatment of a black man in those times from a white man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To grow up is to overcome prejudice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill a Mockingbird is a story about the idea that to grow up is to overcome prejudice. It tries to prove this idea with three plots, one of each type: An external plot seeking justice for a wrongly convicted Tom Robinson A relationship plot between the children and Boo Radley An internal development plot of the children's maturation The external plot is the main driver of the story: a black man has been falsely accused of rape by a white woman. Worse, he is wrongly convicted by a jury of white men after having the audacity to declare that he was helping the woman out of pity. This plot results in a failure as Tom is convicted and killed while trying to escape. The plot has a reversal at the end in which the true criminal (and perpetrator of prejudice) is himself killed and his killing is accepted by the law as eye-for-an-eye for Tom. The external plot unfolds in the formative years of the children and has a distinct impact on their relationship with an ostracized neighbor. They begin by fearing, judging and harassing Boo Radley, only to find that Boo has been helping them from the shadows. The plot ends when the children welcome Boo as a friend. The internal plot of the maturation of the children makes steady progress. They demonstrate an innate acceptance of others (in sharp contrast with the societal mores) and end up overcoming their own fear of Boo by accepting him as a friend (when even society has not accepted him). To Kill a Mockingbird is a wonderful story with a great idea: that growing up means overcoming prejudice. It seems to suggest that children have innate goodness and acceptance but can be molded by grownups and society to become blinded or become mature members of society. This contrasts with the idea that prejudice in any shape or form is childish and dangerous trait in adults and society as a whole. The story makes this point by tying together the three plots at the end: Boo kills the man who embodied prejudice to bring late justice for Tom Robinson, Boo does this to save the children, and the children accept him as a friend even though society still shuns him. It's a great movie. My only beef is the children's internal arc does not have many negative turning points. Their fighting (seemingly negative) is based on justifiable defending of their father's reputation, their jeering at Boo seems playful and child-like rather than childish and their talking Mr Cunningham out of the lynch mob and taking Boo's hand at the end feels a little caricatured and cringe-inducing. Maybe that's just my own feeling. Overall the point of the story is well taken and appreciated. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as heavenly as they say......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most summaries for this movie say that this is a movie about a white lawyer that defends a convicted black man. Well, this can't be far from the truth. This movie is about Atticus Finch and only him. most other characters are introduced just to show how heavenly the man is. Of course the movie is very joyful and should be commended. Gregory Peck puts on a performance that we never see this days. Their is absolutely nothing that signals his an actor and not Atticus Finch. the photography is breath taking and i am thankful that the movie was shot in black and white and not in color because i think i would have barfed if it was in color. But is is the things that the movie is insinuating that i just don't get. Who is the mockingbird? Is it the black man? Is it Boo? Early in the movie we are told that mockingbird are the only kinds of birds that shouldn't be shot because all they do is good things for us. Are we supposed to believe that the black man or Boo shouldn't be shot because they are creatures like mockingbirds that shouldn't be harmed simply because they know less and do everything for the benefit of others??? I have decided to watch the movie another time again but for now all i feel is a 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very overrated film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhkp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book on which this film is based, so I have no idea whether or not it's a good adaptation. I'm amazed Gregory Peck won the Academy Award. He took what seems like a great part, on paper, and managed to give an incredibly boring performance. Along with a lack of personality, his performance is so slowly spoken you could drive a truck through the pauses. I think his whole approach is disastrous. Is this the same actor who had so much life and charm playing a Southern dad back in 1946's The Yearling? It's like he's pickled in a jar, here. I'm amazed he won the Oscar over Peter O'Toole in Lawrence Of Arabia. None of the performances are memorable, including those of the children, except maybe Alice Ghostly's, and even her ebullience seems to have been toned down to fit in with the "Playhouse 90" acting style that pervades everything. And for some reason the fake southern accents of several of the principals are more annoying than fake southern accents usually are in other movies. The art director was the great Henry Bumstead, who (if I remember correctly, from an interview) convinced the filmmakers not to go on location, insisting he could recreate the setting just as well on the backlot. He lied. He also claimed people asked him for years what the location was, so real was the illusion. That may be true but it didn't fool me. Even though it's a good, professional job, probably the best anyone could do, the film seems to need an authentic setting. A somewhat similar film, MGM's Intruder In The Dust (1949) is so much better for being filmed in Oxford, Mississippi. It's also better for having a director (Clarence Brown) who knew how to make most of his camera set-ups interesting. That isn't the case, here. The dramatic high point of the film is ostensibly the courtroom sequence, but the set-ups and cinematography of the nondescript set are so boring, and the acting is so paint-by-the-numbers, it's like an episode of some 1950's sitcom from hell. Dramatically, I have never cared about what happens in the film. I've been forced to sit through it by friends, several times. I always lose interest at some point and my mind wanders. Harper Lee supposedly wanted Spencer Tracy to play Atticus, and, in spite of the fact that he was a couple of years over 60, at the time, and looked even older, he was an exciting actor and might have made everything work. This isn't a terrible film, and of course it has its touching scenes (with several moments greatly enhanced, emotionally, by Elmer Bernstein's score), it just seems incredibly dry, to me, when it should be much more warm and human. The kids and everyone else seem unduly lacking in fun, if not downright depressed, before anything depressing even happens to cause them to be that way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill A Mockingbird is probably one of the most over evaluated movies of all time. The first hour is absolutely boring to death, endless and in the end pointless. The scenes follow one another very disjointly, with no binder, and it goes nowhere. There is no soul and one is close to a flat electroencephalogram watching these children play, because this is almost exclusively what it is about. Then comes the second part dealing mostly with the trial. This is what kind of saves the movie, and still, even if you get more or less carried away by the testimonies and demonstrations with the underlying themes of racism and segregation, it remains rather weak qualitatively. But what is the most disconcerting is the lack of coherence of the feature with the association of two parts that almost have nothing in common. One is under the impression of watching two completely different movies: chronicle of a childhood or anti-racist pamphlet, a choice should have been made...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful Courtroom Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gregory Peck plays Atticus Finch, an Alabama lawyer who is called upon to defend a black man(played by Brock Peters) who is wrongfully accused of raping a white woman(played by Collin Wilcox) in the 1930's, where such an allegation could get him lynched before a trial. Story also includes Atticus's two children Scout & Jem, and the film is mostly seen from their POV, as they try to understand what's going on and why. Robert Duvall plays a mysterious figure named Boo Radley(played by Robert Duvall) who will have a huge impact on their lives. Superb film with an Academy Award winning performance by Gregory Peck, and fine direction by Robert Mulligan, who creates an evocative atmosphere of small town Alabama life of this period, and the wonder yet naivety of childhood. A first-rate adaptation of Harper Lee's famous novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't cut it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    King Sidharth
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film starts with the same essence as the book, but through experience I've learned not to compare much - they are two very different mediums. The problem begins with the film pacing up and skipping important events that build up motives of the characters and causes shift in their intent. Towards the end all of it looks like a rush. The importance and the the details of how grave the case of a lawyer actually backing up black man is lost in translation across the medium. Well, all of that can be forgiven and the film still somehow works along. But the contextual shock of a man attacking children is totally lost on screenplay, many dialog were changed which the climax dry and juice-less - taking all emotions out of it. Characters, especially Atticus's, were portrayed and played out very well. They are the only reason the film works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Most Overrated Films... Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Widely regarded as one of the greatest courtroom dramas of all time, it was surprising to see that there is not even a single shot of a courtroom in the first half which felt more of a suspense/horror for a completely different reason than what is depicted in the second half. Gregory Peck packs in a powerful performance as Atticus Finch, a righteous lawyer defending a Negro in an alleged rape case. The child actors did a nice job too & this film also introduces Robert Duvall in his first role. To Kill A Mockingbird's theme of prejudice moving us from the path of true judgment is clear but overall, this movie is overlong, somewhat boring & one of the most overrated films of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1962's To Kill A Mockingbird Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Robert Mulligan's Direction, Horton Foote's Screenplay, Russell Harlan's Cinematography, Elmer Bernstein's Score And Gregory Peck's Oscar-Winning Performance As Atticus Finch, It Ranks #25 On The AFI's 10th Anniversary List Of The Greatest American Movies Of All Time In 2007, Atticus Finch Was Voted The Greatest Movie Hero Of The 20th Century In 2003, A Really Robert Duvall In This Film, He Has Been In My Fourth Favorite Film Of All 1972's The Godfather With Marlon Brando And Al Pacino, This Movie Turned 50 Years Old Last Year In 2012, It Was 40 Years Old Just Over Eleven Years Back In 2002.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD is a classic adaption of a classic novel. I remember reading and watching this at school but most of the civil rights-era background when right over my head. Not really worth exploring a movie dealing with mature themes as a kid, but there you go. Watching it again as an adult, it's a delight and as hard-hitting as MISSISSIPPI BURNING, which came much later. I've always liked Gregory Peck and his laconic Atticus Finch is an exploration of a quiet, inherently decent man. It's a subtle performance of amazing strength, with no showy-off 'acting' scenes or the like; Peck's Oscar win was well deserved. I particularly liked the way the narrative develops through the eyes of a pair of innocent children as it adds another layer to the story. The whole sub-plot involving Boo Radley is a classic bit of mischief and I love the way the two plots tie up neatly at the end. The child actors are exceptionally strong and despite the lengthy running time the movie doesn't have any slow spots; it's all relevant and adds to the experience. As I said, this is a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lawyer against a village.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "To Kill a Mockingbird" is a movie based on Harper Lee's book of 1961 (Pulitzer Prize winning). It's a movie that displays the racial racism of the time (1930s) and how people treat each other in such times. It all starts when a black man (Brock Peters) accused of raping a white woman and Gregory Peck (Atticus Finch) represent him as his lawyer. When villagers learn about this representation of Atticus Finch they want to change his mind but Atticus decides to go ahead of it. I liked very much the performances of Gregory Peck as Atticus Finch a lawyer who fights for justice and of course the performances of the two little ones (son and daughter of Atticus Finch) Mary Badham as Scout and Phillip Alford as Jem. I recommend it because I think that this movie shows us a different treatment of a black man in those times from a white man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To grow up is to overcome prejudice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill a Mockingbird is a story about the idea that to grow up is to overcome prejudice. It tries to prove this idea with three plots, one of each type: An external plot seeking justice for a wrongly convicted Tom Robinson A relationship plot between the children and Boo Radley An internal development plot of the children's maturation The external plot is the main driver of the story: a black man has been falsely accused of rape by a white woman. Worse, he is wrongly convicted by a jury of white men after having the audacity to declare that he was helping the woman out of pity. This plot results in a failure as Tom is convicted and killed while trying to escape. The plot has a reversal at the end in which the true criminal (and perpetrator of prejudice) is himself killed and his killing is accepted by the law as eye-for-an-eye for Tom. The external plot unfolds in the formative years of the children and has a distinct impact on their relationship with an ostracized neighbor. They begin by fearing, judging and harassing Boo Radley, only to find that Boo has been helping them from the shadows. The plot ends when the children welcome Boo as a friend. The internal plot of the maturation of the children makes steady progress. They demonstrate an innate acceptance of others (in sharp contrast with the societal mores) and end up overcoming their own fear of Boo by accepting him as a friend (when even society has not accepted him). To Kill a Mockingbird is a wonderful story with a great idea: that growing up means overcoming prejudice. It seems to suggest that children have innate goodness and acceptance but can be molded by grownups and society to become blinded or become mature members of society. This contrasts with the idea that prejudice in any shape or form is childish and dangerous trait in adults and society as a whole. The story makes this point by tying together the three plots at the end: Boo kills the man who embodied prejudice to bring late justice for Tom Robinson, Boo does this to save the children, and the children accept him as a friend even though society still shuns him. It's a great movie. My only beef is the children's internal arc does not have many negative turning points. Their fighting (seemingly negative) is based on justifiable defending of their father's reputation, their jeering at Boo seems playful and child-like rather than childish and their talking Mr Cunningham out of the lynch mob and taking Boo's hand at the end feels a little caricatured and cringe-inducing. Maybe that's just my own feeling. Overall the point of the story is well taken and appreciated. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as heavenly as they say......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most summaries for this movie say that this is a movie about a white lawyer that defends a convicted black man. Well, this can't be far from the truth. This movie is about Atticus Finch and only him. most other characters are introduced just to show how heavenly the man is. Of course the movie is very joyful and should be commended. Gregory Peck puts on a performance that we never see this days. Their is absolutely nothing that signals his an actor and not Atticus Finch. the photography is breath taking and i am thankful that the movie was shot in black and white and not in color because i think i would have barfed if it was in color. But is is the things that the movie is insinuating that i just don't get. Who is the mockingbird? Is it the black man? Is it Boo? Early in the movie we are told that mockingbird are the only kinds of birds that shouldn't be shot because all they do is good things for us. Are we supposed to believe that the black man or Boo shouldn't be shot because they are creatures like mockingbirds that shouldn't be harmed simply because they know less and do everything for the benefit of others??? I have decided to watch the movie another time again but for now all i feel is a 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very overrated film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhkp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book on which this film is based, so I have no idea whether or not it's a good adaptation. I'm amazed Gregory Peck won the Academy Award. He took what seems like a great part, on paper, and managed to give an incredibly boring performance. Along with a lack of personality, his performance is so slowly spoken you could drive a truck through the pauses. I think his whole approach is disastrous. Is this the same actor who had so much life and charm playing a Southern dad back in 1946's The Yearling? It's like he's pickled in a jar, here. I'm amazed he won the Oscar over Peter O'Toole in Lawrence Of Arabia. None of the performances are memorable, including those of the children, except maybe Alice Ghostly's, and even her ebullience seems to have been toned down to fit in with the "Playhouse 90" acting style that pervades everything. And for some reason the fake southern accents of several of the principals are more annoying than fake southern accents usually are in other movies. The art director was the great Henry Bumstead, who (if I remember correctly, from an interview) convinced the filmmakers not to go on location, insisting he could recreate the setting just as well on the backlot. He lied. He also claimed people asked him for years what the location was, so real was the illusion. That may be true but it didn't fool me. Even though it's a good, professional job, probably the best anyone could do, the film seems to need an authentic setting. A somewhat similar film, MGM's Intruder In The Dust (1949) is so much better for being filmed in Oxford, Mississippi. It's also better for having a director (Clarence Brown) who knew how to make most of his camera set-ups interesting. That isn't the case, here. The dramatic high point of the film is ostensibly the courtroom sequence, but the set-ups and cinematography of the nondescript set are so boring, and the acting is so paint-by-the-numbers, it's like an episode of some 1950's sitcom from hell. Dramatically, I have never cared about what happens in the film. I've been forced to sit through it by friends, several times. I always lose interest at some point and my mind wanders. Harper Lee supposedly wanted Spencer Tracy to play Atticus, and, in spite of the fact that he was a couple of years over 60, at the time, and looked even older, he was an exciting actor and might have made everything work. This isn't a terrible film, and of course it has its touching scenes (with several moments greatly enhanced, emotionally, by Elmer Bernstein's score), it just seems incredibly dry, to me, when it should be much more warm and human. The kids and everyone else seem unduly lacking in fun, if not downright depressed, before anything depressing even happens to cause them to be that way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill A Mockingbird is probably one of the most over evaluated movies of all time. The first hour is absolutely boring to death, endless and in the end pointless. The scenes follow one another very disjointly, with no binder, and it goes nowhere. There is no soul and one is close to a flat electroencephalogram watching these children play, because this is almost exclusively what it is about. Then comes the second part dealing mostly with the trial. This is what kind of saves the movie, and still, even if you get more or less carried away by the testimonies and demonstrations with the underlying themes of racism and segregation, it remains rather weak qualitatively. But what is the most disconcerting is the lack of coherence of the feature with the association of two parts that almost have nothing in common. One is under the impression of watching two completely different movies: chronicle of a childhood or anti-racist pamphlet, a choice should have been made...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful Courtroom Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gregory Peck plays Atticus Finch, an Alabama lawyer who is called upon to defend a black man(played by Brock Peters) who is wrongfully accused of raping a white woman(played by Collin Wilcox) in the 1930's, where such an allegation could get him lynched before a trial. Story also includes Atticus's two children Scout & Jem, and the film is mostly seen from their POV, as they try to understand what's going on and why. Robert Duvall plays a mysterious figure named Boo Radley(played by Robert Duvall) who will have a huge impact on their lives. Superb film with an Academy Award winning performance by Gregory Peck, and fine direction by Robert Mulligan, who creates an evocative atmosphere of small town Alabama life of this period, and the wonder yet naivety of childhood. A first-rate adaptation of Harper Lee's famous novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't cut it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    King Sidharth
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film starts with the same essence as the book, but through experience I've learned not to compare much - they are two very different mediums. The problem begins with the film pacing up and skipping important events that build up motives of the characters and causes shift in their intent. Towards the end all of it looks like a rush. The importance and the the details of how grave the case of a lawyer actually backing up black man is lost in translation across the medium. Well, all of that can be forgiven and the film still somehow works along. But the contextual shock of a man attacking children is totally lost on screenplay, many dialog were changed which the climax dry and juice-less - taking all emotions out of it. Characters, especially Atticus's, were portrayed and played out very well. They are the only reason the film works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Most Overrated Films... Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Widely regarded as one of the greatest courtroom dramas of all time, it was surprising to see that there is not even a single shot of a courtroom in the first half which felt more of a suspense/horror for a completely different reason than what is depicted in the second half. Gregory Peck packs in a powerful performance as Atticus Finch, a righteous lawyer defending a Negro in an alleged rape case. The child actors did a nice job too & this film also introduces Robert Duvall in his first role. To Kill A Mockingbird's theme of prejudice moving us from the path of true judgment is clear but overall, this movie is overlong, somewhat boring & one of the most overrated films of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1962's To Kill A Mockingbird Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Robert Mulligan's Direction, Horton Foote's Screenplay, Russell Harlan's Cinematography, Elmer Bernstein's Score And Gregory Peck's Oscar-Winning Performance As Atticus Finch, It Ranks #25 On The AFI's 10th Anniversary List Of The Greatest American Movies Of All Time In 2007, Atticus Finch Was Voted The Greatest Movie Hero Of The 20th Century In 2003, A Really Robert Duvall In This Film, He Has Been In My Fourth Favorite Film Of All 1972's The Godfather With Marlon Brando And Al Pacino, This Movie Turned 50 Years Old Last Year In 2012, It Was 40 Years Old Just Over Eleven Years Back In 2002.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD is a classic adaption of a classic novel. I remember reading and watching this at school but most of the civil rights-era background when right over my head. Not really worth exploring a movie dealing with mature themes as a kid, but there you go. Watching it again as an adult, it's a delight and as hard-hitting as MISSISSIPPI BURNING, which came much later. I've always liked Gregory Peck and his laconic Atticus Finch is an exploration of a quiet, inherently decent man. It's a subtle performance of amazing strength, with no showy-off 'acting' scenes or the like; Peck's Oscar win was well deserved. I particularly liked the way the narrative develops through the eyes of a pair of innocent children as it adds another layer to the story. The whole sub-plot involving Boo Radley is a classic bit of mischief and I love the way the two plots tie up neatly at the end. The child actors are exceptionally strong and despite the lengthy running time the movie doesn't have any slow spots; it's all relevant and adds to the experience. As I said, this is a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lawyer against a village.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "To Kill a Mockingbird" is a movie based on Harper Lee's book of 1961 (Pulitzer Prize winning). It's a movie that displays the racial racism of the time (1930s) and how people treat each other in such times. It all starts when a black man (Brock Peters) accused of raping a white woman and Gregory Peck (Atticus Finch) represent him as his lawyer. When villagers learn about this representation of Atticus Finch they want to change his mind but Atticus decides to go ahead of it. I liked very much the performances of Gregory Peck as Atticus Finch a lawyer who fights for justice and of course the performances of the two little ones (son and daughter of Atticus Finch) Mary Badham as Scout and Phillip Alford as Jem. I recommend it because I think that this movie shows us a different treatment of a black man in those times from a white man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To grow up is to overcome prejudice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill a Mockingbird is a story about the idea that to grow up is to overcome prejudice. It tries to prove this idea with three plots, one of each type: An external plot seeking justice for a wrongly convicted Tom Robinson A relationship plot between the children and Boo Radley An internal development plot of the children's maturation The external plot is the main driver of the story: a black man has been falsely accused of rape by a white woman. Worse, he is wrongly convicted by a jury of white men after having the audacity to declare that he was helping the woman out of pity. This plot results in a failure as Tom is convicted and killed while trying to escape. The plot has a reversal at the end in which the true criminal (and perpetrator of prejudice) is himself killed and his killing is accepted by the law as eye-for-an-eye for Tom. The external plot unfolds in the formative years of the children and has a distinct impact on their relationship with an ostracized neighbor. They begin by fearing, judging and harassing Boo Radley, only to find that Boo has been helping them from the shadows. The plot ends when the children welcome Boo as a friend. The internal plot of the maturation of the children makes steady progress. They demonstrate an innate acceptance of others (in sharp contrast with the societal mores) and end up overcoming their own fear of Boo by accepting him as a friend (when even society has not accepted him). To Kill a Mockingbird is a wonderful story with a great idea: that growing up means overcoming prejudice. It seems to suggest that children have innate goodness and acceptance but can be molded by grownups and society to become blinded or become mature members of society. This contrasts with the idea that prejudice in any shape or form is childish and dangerous trait in adults and society as a whole. The story makes this point by tying together the three plots at the end: Boo kills the man who embodied prejudice to bring late justice for Tom Robinson, Boo does this to save the children, and the children accept him as a friend even though society still shuns him. It's a great movie. My only beef is the children's internal arc does not have many negative turning points. Their fighting (seemingly negative) is based on justifiable defending of their father's reputation, their jeering at Boo seems playful and child-like rather than childish and their talking Mr Cunningham out of the lynch mob and taking Boo's hand at the end feels a little caricatured and cringe-inducing. Maybe that's just my own feeling. Overall the point of the story is well taken and appreciated. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as heavenly as they say......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most summaries for this movie say that this is a movie about a white lawyer that defends a convicted black man. Well, this can't be far from the truth. This movie is about Atticus Finch and only him. most other characters are introduced just to show how heavenly the man is. Of course the movie is very joyful and should be commended. Gregory Peck puts on a performance that we never see this days. Their is absolutely nothing that signals his an actor and not Atticus Finch. the photography is breath taking and i am thankful that the movie was shot in black and white and not in color because i think i would have barfed if it was in color. But is is the things that the movie is insinuating that i just don't get. Who is the mockingbird? Is it the black man? Is it Boo? Early in the movie we are told that mockingbird are the only kinds of birds that shouldn't be shot because all they do is good things for us. Are we supposed to believe that the black man or Boo shouldn't be shot because they are creatures like mockingbirds that shouldn't be harmed simply because they know less and do everything for the benefit of others??? I have decided to watch the movie another time again but for now all i feel is a 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very overrated film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhkp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book on which this film is based, so I have no idea whether or not it's a good adaptation. I'm amazed Gregory Peck won the Academy Award. He took what seems like a great part, on paper, and managed to give an incredibly boring performance. Along with a lack of personality, his performance is so slowly spoken you could drive a truck through the pauses. I think his whole approach is disastrous. Is this the same actor who had so much life and charm playing a Southern dad back in 1946's The Yearling? It's like he's pickled in a jar, here. I'm amazed he won the Oscar over Peter O'Toole in Lawrence Of Arabia. None of the performances are memorable, including those of the children, except maybe Alice Ghostly's, and even her ebullience seems to have been toned down to fit in with the "Playhouse 90" acting style that pervades everything. And for some reason the fake southern accents of several of the principals are more annoying than fake southern accents usually are in other movies. The art director was the great Henry Bumstead, who (if I remember correctly, from an interview) convinced the filmmakers not to go on location, insisting he could recreate the setting just as well on the backlot. He lied. He also claimed people asked him for years what the location was, so real was the illusion. That may be true but it didn't fool me. Even though it's a good, professional job, probably the best anyone could do, the film seems to need an authentic setting. A somewhat similar film, MGM's Intruder In The Dust (1949) is so much better for being filmed in Oxford, Mississippi. It's also better for having a director (Clarence Brown) who knew how to make most of his camera set-ups interesting. That isn't the case, here. The dramatic high point of the film is ostensibly the courtroom sequence, but the set-ups and cinematography of the nondescript set are so boring, and the acting is so paint-by-the-numbers, it's like an episode of some 1950's sitcom from hell. Dramatically, I have never cared about what happens in the film. I've been forced to sit through it by friends, several times. I always lose interest at some point and my mind wanders. Harper Lee supposedly wanted Spencer Tracy to play Atticus, and, in spite of the fact that he was a couple of years over 60, at the time, and looked even older, he was an exciting actor and might have made everything work. This isn't a terrible film, and of course it has its touching scenes (with several moments greatly enhanced, emotionally, by Elmer Bernstein's score), it just seems incredibly dry, to me, when it should be much more warm and human. The kids and everyone else seem unduly lacking in fun, if not downright depressed, before anything depressing even happens to cause them to be that way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill A Mockingbird is probably one of the most over evaluated movies of all time. The first hour is absolutely boring to death, endless and in the end pointless. The scenes follow one another very disjointly, with no binder, and it goes nowhere. There is no soul and one is close to a flat electroencephalogram watching these children play, because this is almost exclusively what it is about. Then comes the second part dealing mostly with the trial. This is what kind of saves the movie, and still, even if you get more or less carried away by the testimonies and demonstrations with the underlying themes of racism and segregation, it remains rather weak qualitatively. But what is the most disconcerting is the lack of coherence of the feature with the association of two parts that almost have nothing in common. One is under the impression of watching two completely different movies: chronicle of a childhood or anti-racist pamphlet, a choice should have been made...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful Courtroom Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gregory Peck plays Atticus Finch, an Alabama lawyer who is called upon to defend a black man(played by Brock Peters) who is wrongfully accused of raping a white woman(played by Collin Wilcox) in the 1930's, where such an allegation could get him lynched before a trial. Story also includes Atticus's two children Scout & Jem, and the film is mostly seen from their POV, as they try to understand what's going on and why. Robert Duvall plays a mysterious figure named Boo Radley(played by Robert Duvall) who will have a huge impact on their lives. Superb film with an Academy Award winning performance by Gregory Peck, and fine direction by Robert Mulligan, who creates an evocative atmosphere of small town Alabama life of this period, and the wonder yet naivety of childhood. A first-rate adaptation of Harper Lee's famous novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't cut it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    King Sidharth
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film starts with the same essence as the book, but through experience I've learned not to compare much - they are two very different mediums. The problem begins with the film pacing up and skipping important events that build up motives of the characters and causes shift in their intent. Towards the end all of it looks like a rush. The importance and the the details of how grave the case of a lawyer actually backing up black man is lost in translation across the medium. Well, all of that can be forgiven and the film still somehow works along. But the contextual shock of a man attacking children is totally lost on screenplay, many dialog were changed which the climax dry and juice-less - taking all emotions out of it. Characters, especially Atticus's, were portrayed and played out very well. They are the only reason the film works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Most Overrated Films... Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Widely regarded as one of the greatest courtroom dramas of all time, it was surprising to see that there is not even a single shot of a courtroom in the first half which felt more of a suspense/horror for a completely different reason than what is depicted in the second half. Gregory Peck packs in a powerful performance as Atticus Finch, a righteous lawyer defending a Negro in an alleged rape case. The child actors did a nice job too & this film also introduces Robert Duvall in his first role. To Kill A Mockingbird's theme of prejudice moving us from the path of true judgment is clear but overall, this movie is overlong, somewhat boring & one of the most overrated films of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1962's To Kill A Mockingbird Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Robert Mulligan's Direction, Horton Foote's Screenplay, Russell Harlan's Cinematography, Elmer Bernstein's Score And Gregory Peck's Oscar-Winning Performance As Atticus Finch, It Ranks #25 On The AFI's 10th Anniversary List Of The Greatest American Movies Of All Time In 2007, Atticus Finch Was Voted The Greatest Movie Hero Of The 20th Century In 2003, A Really Robert Duvall In This Film, He Has Been In My Fourth Favorite Film Of All 1972's The Godfather With Marlon Brando And Al Pacino, This Movie Turned 50 Years Old Last Year In 2012, It Was 40 Years Old Just Over Eleven Years Back In 2002.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD is a classic adaption of a classic novel. I remember reading and watching this at school but most of the civil rights-era background when right over my head. Not really worth exploring a movie dealing with mature themes as a kid, but there you go. Watching it again as an adult, it's a delight and as hard-hitting as MISSISSIPPI BURNING, which came much later. I've always liked Gregory Peck and his laconic Atticus Finch is an exploration of a quiet, inherently decent man. It's a subtle performance of amazing strength, with no showy-off 'acting' scenes or the like; Peck's Oscar win was well deserved. I particularly liked the way the narrative develops through the eyes of a pair of innocent children as it adds another layer to the story. The whole sub-plot involving Boo Radley is a classic bit of mischief and I love the way the two plots tie up neatly at the end. The child actors are exceptionally strong and despite the lengthy running time the movie doesn't have any slow spots; it's all relevant and adds to the experience. As I said, this is a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lawyer against a village.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "To Kill a Mockingbird" is a movie based on Harper Lee's book of 1961 (Pulitzer Prize winning). It's a movie that displays the racial racism of the time (1930s) and how people treat each other in such times. It all starts when a black man (Brock Peters) accused of raping a white woman and Gregory Peck (Atticus Finch) represent him as his lawyer. When villagers learn about this representation of Atticus Finch they want to change his mind but Atticus decides to go ahead of it. I liked very much the performances of Gregory Peck as Atticus Finch a lawyer who fights for justice and of course the performances of the two little ones (son and daughter of Atticus Finch) Mary Badham as Scout and Phillip Alford as Jem. I recommend it because I think that this movie shows us a different treatment of a black man in those times from a white man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To grow up is to overcome prejudice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill a Mockingbird is a story about the idea that to grow up is to overcome prejudice. It tries to prove this idea with three plots, one of each type: An external plot seeking justice for a wrongly convicted Tom Robinson A relationship plot between the children and Boo Radley An internal development plot of the children's maturation The external plot is the main driver of the story: a black man has been falsely accused of rape by a white woman. Worse, he is wrongly convicted by a jury of white men after having the audacity to declare that he was helping the woman out of pity. This plot results in a failure as Tom is convicted and killed while trying to escape. The plot has a reversal at the end in which the true criminal (and perpetrator of prejudice) is himself killed and his killing is accepted by the law as eye-for-an-eye for Tom. The external plot unfolds in the formative years of the children and has a distinct impact on their relationship with an ostracized neighbor. They begin by fearing, judging and harassing Boo Radley, only to find that Boo has been helping them from the shadows. The plot ends when the children welcome Boo as a friend. The internal plot of the maturation of the children makes steady progress. They demonstrate an innate acceptance of others (in sharp contrast with the societal mores) and end up overcoming their own fear of Boo by accepting him as a friend (when even society has not accepted him). To Kill a Mockingbird is a wonderful story with a great idea: that growing up means overcoming prejudice. It seems to suggest that children have innate goodness and acceptance but can be molded by grownups and society to become blinded or become mature members of society. This contrasts with the idea that prejudice in any shape or form is childish and dangerous trait in adults and society as a whole. The story makes this point by tying together the three plots at the end: Boo kills the man who embodied prejudice to bring late justice for Tom Robinson, Boo does this to save the children, and the children accept him as a friend even though society still shuns him. It's a great movie. My only beef is the children's internal arc does not have many negative turning points. Their fighting (seemingly negative) is based on justifiable defending of their father's reputation, their jeering at Boo seems playful and child-like rather than childish and their talking Mr Cunningham out of the lynch mob and taking Boo's hand at the end feels a little caricatured and cringe-inducing. Maybe that's just my own feeling. Overall the point of the story is well taken and appreciated. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as heavenly as they say......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most summaries for this movie say that this is a movie about a white lawyer that defends a convicted black man. Well, this can't be far from the truth. This movie is about Atticus Finch and only him. most other characters are introduced just to show how heavenly the man is. Of course the movie is very joyful and should be commended. Gregory Peck puts on a performance that we never see this days. Their is absolutely nothing that signals his an actor and not Atticus Finch. the photography is breath taking and i am thankful that the movie was shot in black and white and not in color because i think i would have barfed if it was in color. But is is the things that the movie is insinuating that i just don't get. Who is the mockingbird? Is it the black man? Is it Boo? Early in the movie we are told that mockingbird are the only kinds of birds that shouldn't be shot because all they do is good things for us. Are we supposed to believe that the black man or Boo shouldn't be shot because they are creatures like mockingbirds that shouldn't be harmed simply because they know less and do everything for the benefit of others??? I have decided to watch the movie another time again but for now all i feel is a 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very overrated film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhkp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book on which this film is based, so I have no idea whether or not it's a good adaptation. I'm amazed Gregory Peck won the Academy Award. He took what seems like a great part, on paper, and managed to give an incredibly boring performance. Along with a lack of personality, his performance is so slowly spoken you could drive a truck through the pauses. I think his whole approach is disastrous. Is this the same actor who had so much life and charm playing a Southern dad back in 1946's The Yearling? It's like he's pickled in a jar, here. I'm amazed he won the Oscar over Peter O'Toole in Lawrence Of Arabia. None of the performances are memorable, including those of the children, except maybe Alice Ghostly's, and even her ebullience seems to have been toned down to fit in with the "Playhouse 90" acting style that pervades everything. And for some reason the fake southern accents of several of the principals are more annoying than fake southern accents usually are in other movies. The art director was the great Henry Bumstead, who (if I remember correctly, from an interview) convinced the filmmakers not to go on location, insisting he could recreate the setting just as well on the backlot. He lied. He also claimed people asked him for years what the location was, so real was the illusion. That may be true but it didn't fool me. Even though it's a good, professional job, probably the best anyone could do, the film seems to need an authentic setting. A somewhat similar film, MGM's Intruder In The Dust (1949) is so much better for being filmed in Oxford, Mississippi. It's also better for having a director (Clarence Brown) who knew how to make most of his camera set-ups interesting. That isn't the case, here. The dramatic high point of the film is ostensibly the courtroom sequence, but the set-ups and cinematography of the nondescript set are so boring, and the acting is so paint-by-the-numbers, it's like an episode of some 1950's sitcom from hell. Dramatically, I have never cared about what happens in the film. I've been forced to sit through it by friends, several times. I always lose interest at some point and my mind wanders. Harper Lee supposedly wanted Spencer Tracy to play Atticus, and, in spite of the fact that he was a couple of years over 60, at the time, and looked even older, he was an exciting actor and might have made everything work. This isn't a terrible film, and of course it has its touching scenes (with several moments greatly enhanced, emotionally, by Elmer Bernstein's score), it just seems incredibly dry, to me, when it should be much more warm and human. The kids and everyone else seem unduly lacking in fun, if not downright depressed, before anything depressing even happens to cause them to be that way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill A Mockingbird is probably one of the most over evaluated movies of all time. The first hour is absolutely boring to death, endless and in the end pointless. The scenes follow one another very disjointly, with no binder, and it goes nowhere. There is no soul and one is close to a flat electroencephalogram watching these children play, because this is almost exclusively what it is about. Then comes the second part dealing mostly with the trial. This is what kind of saves the movie, and still, even if you get more or less carried away by the testimonies and demonstrations with the underlying themes of racism and segregation, it remains rather weak qualitatively. But what is the most disconcerting is the lack of coherence of the feature with the association of two parts that almost have nothing in common. One is under the impression of watching two completely different movies: chronicle of a childhood or anti-racist pamphlet, a choice should have been made...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful Courtroom Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gregory Peck plays Atticus Finch, an Alabama lawyer who is called upon to defend a black man(played by Brock Peters) who is wrongfully accused of raping a white woman(played by Collin Wilcox) in the 1930's, where such an allegation could get him lynched before a trial. Story also includes Atticus's two children Scout & Jem, and the film is mostly seen from their POV, as they try to understand what's going on and why. Robert Duvall plays a mysterious figure named Boo Radley(played by Robert Duvall) who will have a huge impact on their lives. Superb film with an Academy Award winning performance by Gregory Peck, and fine direction by Robert Mulligan, who creates an evocative atmosphere of small town Alabama life of this period, and the wonder yet naivety of childhood. A first-rate adaptation of Harper Lee's famous novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't cut it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    King Sidharth
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film starts with the same essence as the book, but through experience I've learned not to compare much - they are two very different mediums. The problem begins with the film pacing up and skipping important events that build up motives of the characters and causes shift in their intent. Towards the end all of it looks like a rush. The importance and the the details of how grave the case of a lawyer actually backing up black man is lost in translation across the medium. Well, all of that can be forgiven and the film still somehow works along. But the contextual shock of a man attacking children is totally lost on screenplay, many dialog were changed which the climax dry and juice-less - taking all emotions out of it. Characters, especially Atticus's, were portrayed and played out very well. They are the only reason the film works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Most Overrated Films... Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Widely regarded as one of the greatest courtroom dramas of all time, it was surprising to see that there is not even a single shot of a courtroom in the first half which felt more of a suspense/horror for a completely different reason than what is depicted in the second half. Gregory Peck packs in a powerful performance as Atticus Finch, a righteous lawyer defending a Negro in an alleged rape case. The child actors did a nice job too & this film also introduces Robert Duvall in his first role. To Kill A Mockingbird's theme of prejudice moving us from the path of true judgment is clear but overall, this movie is overlong, somewhat boring & one of the most overrated films of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1962's To Kill A Mockingbird Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Robert Mulligan's Direction, Horton Foote's Screenplay, Russell Harlan's Cinematography, Elmer Bernstein's Score And Gregory Peck's Oscar-Winning Performance As Atticus Finch, It Ranks #25 On The AFI's 10th Anniversary List Of The Greatest American Movies Of All Time In 2007, Atticus Finch Was Voted The Greatest Movie Hero Of The 20th Century In 2003, A Really Robert Duvall In This Film, He Has Been In My Fourth Favorite Film Of All 1972's The Godfather With Marlon Brando And Al Pacino, This Movie Turned 50 Years Old Last Year In 2012, It Was 40 Years Old Just Over Eleven Years Back In 2002.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD is a classic adaption of a classic novel. I remember reading and watching this at school but most of the civil rights-era background when right over my head. Not really worth exploring a movie dealing with mature themes as a kid, but there you go. Watching it again as an adult, it's a delight and as hard-hitting as MISSISSIPPI BURNING, which came much later. I've always liked Gregory Peck and his laconic Atticus Finch is an exploration of a quiet, inherently decent man. It's a subtle performance of amazing strength, with no showy-off 'acting' scenes or the like; Peck's Oscar win was well deserved. I particularly liked the way the narrative develops through the eyes of a pair of innocent children as it adds another layer to the story. The whole sub-plot involving Boo Radley is a classic bit of mischief and I love the way the two plots tie up neatly at the end. The child actors are exceptionally strong and despite the lengthy running time the movie doesn't have any slow spots; it's all relevant and adds to the experience. As I said, this is a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lawyer against a village.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "To Kill a Mockingbird" is a movie based on Harper Lee's book of 1961 (Pulitzer Prize winning). It's a movie that displays the racial racism of the time (1930s) and how people treat each other in such times. It all starts when a black man (Brock Peters) accused of raping a white woman and Gregory Peck (Atticus Finch) represent him as his lawyer. When villagers learn about this representation of Atticus Finch they want to change his mind but Atticus decides to go ahead of it. I liked very much the performances of Gregory Peck as Atticus Finch a lawyer who fights for justice and of course the performances of the two little ones (son and daughter of Atticus Finch) Mary Badham as Scout and Phillip Alford as Jem. I recommend it because I think that this movie shows us a different treatment of a black man in those times from a white man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To grow up is to overcome prejudice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill a Mockingbird is a story about the idea that to grow up is to overcome prejudice. It tries to prove this idea with three plots, one of each type: An external plot seeking justice for a wrongly convicted Tom Robinson A relationship plot between the children and Boo Radley An internal development plot of the children's maturation The external plot is the main driver of the story: a black man has been falsely accused of rape by a white woman. Worse, he is wrongly convicted by a jury of white men after having the audacity to declare that he was helping the woman out of pity. This plot results in a failure as Tom is convicted and killed while trying to escape. The plot has a reversal at the end in which the true criminal (and perpetrator of prejudice) is himself killed and his killing is accepted by the law as eye-for-an-eye for Tom. The external plot unfolds in the formative years of the children and has a distinct impact on their relationship with an ostracized neighbor. They begin by fearing, judging and harassing Boo Radley, only to find that Boo has been helping them from the shadows. The plot ends when the children welcome Boo as a friend. The internal plot of the maturation of the children makes steady progress. They demonstrate an innate acceptance of others (in sharp contrast with the societal mores) and end up overcoming their own fear of Boo by accepting him as a friend (when even society has not accepted him). To Kill a Mockingbird is a wonderful story with a great idea: that growing up means overcoming prejudice. It seems to suggest that children have innate goodness and acceptance but can be molded by grownups and society to become blinded or become mature members of society. This contrasts with the idea that prejudice in any shape or form is childish and dangerous trait in adults and society as a whole. The story makes this point by tying together the three plots at the end: Boo kills the man who embodied prejudice to bring late justice for Tom Robinson, Boo does this to save the children, and the children accept him as a friend even though society still shuns him. It's a great movie. My only beef is the children's internal arc does not have many negative turning points. Their fighting (seemingly negative) is based on justifiable defending of their father's reputation, their jeering at Boo seems playful and child-like rather than childish and their talking Mr Cunningham out of the lynch mob and taking Boo's hand at the end feels a little caricatured and cringe-inducing. Maybe that's just my own feeling. Overall the point of the story is well taken and appreciated. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as heavenly as they say......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most summaries for this movie say that this is a movie about a white lawyer that defends a convicted black man. Well, this can't be far from the truth. This movie is about Atticus Finch and only him. most other characters are introduced just to show how heavenly the man is. Of course the movie is very joyful and should be commended. Gregory Peck puts on a performance that we never see this days. Their is absolutely nothing that signals his an actor and not Atticus Finch. the photography is breath taking and i am thankful that the movie was shot in black and white and not in color because i think i would have barfed if it was in color. But is is the things that the movie is insinuating that i just don't get. Who is the mockingbird? Is it the black man? Is it Boo? Early in the movie we are told that mockingbird are the only kinds of birds that shouldn't be shot because all they do is good things for us. Are we supposed to believe that the black man or Boo shouldn't be shot because they are creatures like mockingbirds that shouldn't be harmed simply because they know less and do everything for the benefit of others??? I have decided to watch the movie another time again but for now all i feel is a 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very overrated film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhkp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book on which this film is based, so I have no idea whether or not it's a good adaptation. I'm amazed Gregory Peck won the Academy Award. He took what seems like a great part, on paper, and managed to give an incredibly boring performance. Along with a lack of personality, his performance is so slowly spoken you could drive a truck through the pauses. I think his whole approach is disastrous. Is this the same actor who had so much life and charm playing a Southern dad back in 1946's The Yearling? It's like he's pickled in a jar, here. I'm amazed he won the Oscar over Peter O'Toole in Lawrence Of Arabia. None of the performances are memorable, including those of the children, except maybe Alice Ghostly's, and even her ebullience seems to have been toned down to fit in with the "Playhouse 90" acting style that pervades everything. And for some reason the fake southern accents of several of the principals are more annoying than fake southern accents usually are in other movies. The art director was the great Henry Bumstead, who (if I remember correctly, from an interview) convinced the filmmakers not to go on location, insisting he could recreate the setting just as well on the backlot. He lied. He also claimed people asked him for years what the location was, so real was the illusion. That may be true but it didn't fool me. Even though it's a good, professional job, probably the best anyone could do, the film seems to need an authentic setting. A somewhat similar film, MGM's Intruder In The Dust (1949) is so much better for being filmed in Oxford, Mississippi. It's also better for having a director (Clarence Brown) who knew how to make most of his camera set-ups interesting. That isn't the case, here. The dramatic high point of the film is ostensibly the courtroom sequence, but the set-ups and cinematography of the nondescript set are so boring, and the acting is so paint-by-the-numbers, it's like an episode of some 1950's sitcom from hell. Dramatically, I have never cared about what happens in the film. I've been forced to sit through it by friends, several times. I always lose interest at some point and my mind wanders. Harper Lee supposedly wanted Spencer Tracy to play Atticus, and, in spite of the fact that he was a couple of years over 60, at the time, and looked even older, he was an exciting actor and might have made everything work. This isn't a terrible film, and of course it has its touching scenes (with several moments greatly enhanced, emotionally, by Elmer Bernstein's score), it just seems incredibly dry, to me, when it should be much more warm and human. The kids and everyone else seem unduly lacking in fun, if not downright depressed, before anything depressing even happens to cause them to be that way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill A Mockingbird is probably one of the most over evaluated movies of all time. The first hour is absolutely boring to death, endless and in the end pointless. The scenes follow one another very disjointly, with no binder, and it goes nowhere. There is no soul and one is close to a flat electroencephalogram watching these children play, because this is almost exclusively what it is about. Then comes the second part dealing mostly with the trial. This is what kind of saves the movie, and still, even if you get more or less carried away by the testimonies and demonstrations with the underlying themes of racism and segregation, it remains rather weak qualitatively. But what is the most disconcerting is the lack of coherence of the feature with the association of two parts that almost have nothing in common. One is under the impression of watching two completely different movies: chronicle of a childhood or anti-racist pamphlet, a choice should have been made...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful Courtroom Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gregory Peck plays Atticus Finch, an Alabama lawyer who is called upon to defend a black man(played by Brock Peters) who is wrongfully accused of raping a white woman(played by Collin Wilcox) in the 1930's, where such an allegation could get him lynched before a trial. Story also includes Atticus's two children Scout & Jem, and the film is mostly seen from their POV, as they try to understand what's going on and why. Robert Duvall plays a mysterious figure named Boo Radley(played by Robert Duvall) who will have a huge impact on their lives. Superb film with an Academy Award winning performance by Gregory Peck, and fine direction by Robert Mulligan, who creates an evocative atmosphere of small town Alabama life of this period, and the wonder yet naivety of childhood. A first-rate adaptation of Harper Lee's famous novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't cut it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    King Sidharth
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film starts with the same essence as the book, but through experience I've learned not to compare much - they are two very different mediums. The problem begins with the film pacing up and skipping important events that build up motives of the characters and causes shift in their intent. Towards the end all of it looks like a rush. The importance and the the details of how grave the case of a lawyer actually backing up black man is lost in translation across the medium. Well, all of that can be forgiven and the film still somehow works along. But the contextual shock of a man attacking children is totally lost on screenplay, many dialog were changed which the climax dry and juice-less - taking all emotions out of it. Characters, especially Atticus's, were portrayed and played out very well. They are the only reason the film works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Most Overrated Films... Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Widely regarded as one of the greatest courtroom dramas of all time, it was surprising to see that there is not even a single shot of a courtroom in the first half which felt more of a suspense/horror for a completely different reason than what is depicted in the second half. Gregory Peck packs in a powerful performance as Atticus Finch, a righteous lawyer defending a Negro in an alleged rape case. The child actors did a nice job too & this film also introduces Robert Duvall in his first role. To Kill A Mockingbird's theme of prejudice moving us from the path of true judgment is clear but overall, this movie is overlong, somewhat boring & one of the most overrated films of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1962's To Kill A Mockingbird Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Robert Mulligan's Direction, Horton Foote's Screenplay, Russell Harlan's Cinematography, Elmer Bernstein's Score And Gregory Peck's Oscar-Winning Performance As Atticus Finch, It Ranks #25 On The AFI's 10th Anniversary List Of The Greatest American Movies Of All Time In 2007, Atticus Finch Was Voted The Greatest Movie Hero Of The 20th Century In 2003, A Really Robert Duvall In This Film, He Has Been In My Fourth Favorite Film Of All 1972's The Godfather With Marlon Brando And Al Pacino, This Movie Turned 50 Years Old Last Year In 2012, It Was 40 Years Old Just Over Eleven Years Back In 2002.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD is a classic adaption of a classic novel. I remember reading and watching this at school but most of the civil rights-era background when right over my head. Not really worth exploring a movie dealing with mature themes as a kid, but there you go. Watching it again as an adult, it's a delight and as hard-hitting as MISSISSIPPI BURNING, which came much later. I've always liked Gregory Peck and his laconic Atticus Finch is an exploration of a quiet, inherently decent man. It's a subtle performance of amazing strength, with no showy-off 'acting' scenes or the like; Peck's Oscar win was well deserved. I particularly liked the way the narrative develops through the eyes of a pair of innocent children as it adds another layer to the story. The whole sub-plot involving Boo Radley is a classic bit of mischief and I love the way the two plots tie up neatly at the end. The child actors are exceptionally strong and despite the lengthy running time the movie doesn't have any slow spots; it's all relevant and adds to the experience. As I said, this is a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lawyer against a village.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "To Kill a Mockingbird" is a movie based on Harper Lee's book of 1961 (Pulitzer Prize winning). It's a movie that displays the racial racism of the time (1930s) and how people treat each other in such times. It all starts when a black man (Brock Peters) accused of raping a white woman and Gregory Peck (Atticus Finch) represent him as his lawyer. When villagers learn about this representation of Atticus Finch they want to change his mind but Atticus decides to go ahead of it. I liked very much the performances of Gregory Peck as Atticus Finch a lawyer who fights for justice and of course the performances of the two little ones (son and daughter of Atticus Finch) Mary Badham as Scout and Phillip Alford as Jem. I recommend it because I think that this movie shows us a different treatment of a black man in those times from a white man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To grow up is to overcome prejudice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill a Mockingbird is a story about the idea that to grow up is to overcome prejudice. It tries to prove this idea with three plots, one of each type: An external plot seeking justice for a wrongly convicted Tom Robinson A relationship plot between the children and Boo Radley An internal development plot of the children's maturation The external plot is the main driver of the story: a black man has been falsely accused of rape by a white woman. Worse, he is wrongly convicted by a jury of white men after having the audacity to declare that he was helping the woman out of pity. This plot results in a failure as Tom is convicted and killed while trying to escape. The plot has a reversal at the end in which the true criminal (and perpetrator of prejudice) is himself killed and his killing is accepted by the law as eye-for-an-eye for Tom. The external plot unfolds in the formative years of the children and has a distinct impact on their relationship with an ostracized neighbor. They begin by fearing, judging and harassing Boo Radley, only to find that Boo has been helping them from the shadows. The plot ends when the children welcome Boo as a friend. The internal plot of the maturation of the children makes steady progress. They demonstrate an innate acceptance of others (in sharp contrast with the societal mores) and end up overcoming their own fear of Boo by accepting him as a friend (when even society has not accepted him). To Kill a Mockingbird is a wonderful story with a great idea: that growing up means overcoming prejudice. It seems to suggest that children have innate goodness and acceptance but can be molded by grownups and society to become blinded or become mature members of society. This contrasts with the idea that prejudice in any shape or form is childish and dangerous trait in adults and society as a whole. The story makes this point by tying together the three plots at the end: Boo kills the man who embodied prejudice to bring late justice for Tom Robinson, Boo does this to save the children, and the children accept him as a friend even though society still shuns him. It's a great movie. My only beef is the children's internal arc does not have many negative turning points. Their fighting (seemingly negative) is based on justifiable defending of their father's reputation, their jeering at Boo seems playful and child-like rather than childish and their talking Mr Cunningham out of the lynch mob and taking Boo's hand at the end feels a little caricatured and cringe-inducing. Maybe that's just my own feeling. Overall the point of the story is well taken and appreciated. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as heavenly as they say......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most summaries for this movie say that this is a movie about a white lawyer that defends a convicted black man. Well, this can't be far from the truth. This movie is about Atticus Finch and only him. most other characters are introduced just to show how heavenly the man is. Of course the movie is very joyful and should be commended. Gregory Peck puts on a performance that we never see this days. Their is absolutely nothing that signals his an actor and not Atticus Finch. the photography is breath taking and i am thankful that the movie was shot in black and white and not in color because i think i would have barfed if it was in color. But is is the things that the movie is insinuating that i just don't get. Who is the mockingbird? Is it the black man? Is it Boo? Early in the movie we are told that mockingbird are the only kinds of birds that shouldn't be shot because all they do is good things for us. Are we supposed to believe that the black man or Boo shouldn't be shot because they are creatures like mockingbirds that shouldn't be harmed simply because they know less and do everything for the benefit of others??? I have decided to watch the movie another time again but for now all i feel is a 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very overrated film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhkp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book on which this film is based, so I have no idea whether or not it's a good adaptation. I'm amazed Gregory Peck won the Academy Award. He took what seems like a great part, on paper, and managed to give an incredibly boring performance. Along with a lack of personality, his performance is so slowly spoken you could drive a truck through the pauses. I think his whole approach is disastrous. Is this the same actor who had so much life and charm playing a Southern dad back in 1946's The Yearling? It's like he's pickled in a jar, here. I'm amazed he won the Oscar over Peter O'Toole in Lawrence Of Arabia. None of the performances are memorable, including those of the children, except maybe Alice Ghostly's, and even her ebullience seems to have been toned down to fit in with the "Playhouse 90" acting style that pervades everything. And for some reason the fake southern accents of several of the principals are more annoying than fake southern accents usually are in other movies. The art director was the great Henry Bumstead, who (if I remember correctly, from an interview) convinced the filmmakers not to go on location, insisting he could recreate the setting just as well on the backlot. He lied. He also claimed people asked him for years what the location was, so real was the illusion. That may be true but it didn't fool me. Even though it's a good, professional job, probably the best anyone could do, the film seems to need an authentic setting. A somewhat similar film, MGM's Intruder In The Dust (1949) is so much better for being filmed in Oxford, Mississippi. It's also better for having a director (Clarence Brown) who knew how to make most of his camera set-ups interesting. That isn't the case, here. The dramatic high point of the film is ostensibly the courtroom sequence, but the set-ups and cinematography of the nondescript set are so boring, and the acting is so paint-by-the-numbers, it's like an episode of some 1950's sitcom from hell. Dramatically, I have never cared about what happens in the film. I've been forced to sit through it by friends, several times. I always lose interest at some point and my mind wanders. Harper Lee supposedly wanted Spencer Tracy to play Atticus, and, in spite of the fact that he was a couple of years over 60, at the time, and looked even older, he was an exciting actor and might have made everything work. This isn't a terrible film, and of course it has its touching scenes (with several moments greatly enhanced, emotionally, by Elmer Bernstein's score), it just seems incredibly dry, to me, when it should be much more warm and human. The kids and everyone else seem unduly lacking in fun, if not downright depressed, before anything depressing even happens to cause them to be that way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill A Mockingbird is probably one of the most over evaluated movies of all time. The first hour is absolutely boring to death, endless and in the end pointless. The scenes follow one another very disjointly, with no binder, and it goes nowhere. There is no soul and one is close to a flat electroencephalogram watching these children play, because this is almost exclusively what it is about. Then comes the second part dealing mostly with the trial. This is what kind of saves the movie, and still, even if you get more or less carried away by the testimonies and demonstrations with the underlying themes of racism and segregation, it remains rather weak qualitatively. But what is the most disconcerting is the lack of coherence of the feature with the association of two parts that almost have nothing in common. One is under the impression of watching two completely different movies: chronicle of a childhood or anti-racist pamphlet, a choice should have been made...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful Courtroom Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gregory Peck plays Atticus Finch, an Alabama lawyer who is called upon to defend a black man(played by Brock Peters) who is wrongfully accused of raping a white woman(played by Collin Wilcox) in the 1930's, where such an allegation could get him lynched before a trial. Story also includes Atticus's two children Scout & Jem, and the film is mostly seen from their POV, as they try to understand what's going on and why. Robert Duvall plays a mysterious figure named Boo Radley(played by Robert Duvall) who will have a huge impact on their lives. Superb film with an Academy Award winning performance by Gregory Peck, and fine direction by Robert Mulligan, who creates an evocative atmosphere of small town Alabama life of this period, and the wonder yet naivety of childhood. A first-rate adaptation of Harper Lee's famous novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't cut it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    King Sidharth
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film starts with the same essence as the book, but through experience I've learned not to compare much - they are two very different mediums. The problem begins with the film pacing up and skipping important events that build up motives of the characters and causes shift in their intent. Towards the end all of it looks like a rush. The importance and the the details of how grave the case of a lawyer actually backing up black man is lost in translation across the medium. Well, all of that can be forgiven and the film still somehow works along. But the contextual shock of a man attacking children is totally lost on screenplay, many dialog were changed which the climax dry and juice-less - taking all emotions out of it. Characters, especially Atticus's, were portrayed and played out very well. They are the only reason the film works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Most Overrated Films... Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Widely regarded as one of the greatest courtroom dramas of all time, it was surprising to see that there is not even a single shot of a courtroom in the first half which felt more of a suspense/horror for a completely different reason than what is depicted in the second half. Gregory Peck packs in a powerful performance as Atticus Finch, a righteous lawyer defending a Negro in an alleged rape case. The child actors did a nice job too & this film also introduces Robert Duvall in his first role. To Kill A Mockingbird's theme of prejudice moving us from the path of true judgment is clear but overall, this movie is overlong, somewhat boring & one of the most overrated films of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1962's To Kill A Mockingbird Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Robert Mulligan's Direction, Horton Foote's Screenplay, Russell Harlan's Cinematography, Elmer Bernstein's Score And Gregory Peck's Oscar-Winning Performance As Atticus Finch, It Ranks #25 On The AFI's 10th Anniversary List Of The Greatest American Movies Of All Time In 2007, Atticus Finch Was Voted The Greatest Movie Hero Of The 20th Century In 2003, A Really Robert Duvall In This Film, He Has Been In My Fourth Favorite Film Of All 1972's The Godfather With Marlon Brando And Al Pacino, This Movie Turned 50 Years Old Last Year In 2012, It Was 40 Years Old Just Over Eleven Years Back In 2002.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD is a classic adaption of a classic novel. I remember reading and watching this at school but most of the civil rights-era background when right over my head. Not really worth exploring a movie dealing with mature themes as a kid, but there you go. Watching it again as an adult, it's a delight and as hard-hitting as MISSISSIPPI BURNING, which came much later. I've always liked Gregory Peck and his laconic Atticus Finch is an exploration of a quiet, inherently decent man. It's a subtle performance of amazing strength, with no showy-off 'acting' scenes or the like; Peck's Oscar win was well deserved. I particularly liked the way the narrative develops through the eyes of a pair of innocent children as it adds another layer to the story. The whole sub-plot involving Boo Radley is a classic bit of mischief and I love the way the two plots tie up neatly at the end. The child actors are exceptionally strong and despite the lengthy running time the movie doesn't have any slow spots; it's all relevant and adds to the experience. As I said, this is a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lawyer against a village.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "To Kill a Mockingbird" is a movie based on Harper Lee's book of 1961 (Pulitzer Prize winning). It's a movie that displays the racial racism of the time (1930s) and how people treat each other in such times. It all starts when a black man (Brock Peters) accused of raping a white woman and Gregory Peck (Atticus Finch) represent him as his lawyer. When villagers learn about this representation of Atticus Finch they want to change his mind but Atticus decides to go ahead of it. I liked very much the performances of Gregory Peck as Atticus Finch a lawyer who fights for justice and of course the performances of the two little ones (son and daughter of Atticus Finch) Mary Badham as Scout and Phillip Alford as Jem. I recommend it because I think that this movie shows us a different treatment of a black man in those times from a white man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To grow up is to overcome prejudice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill a Mockingbird is a story about the idea that to grow up is to overcome prejudice. It tries to prove this idea with three plots, one of each type: An external plot seeking justice for a wrongly convicted Tom Robinson A relationship plot between the children and Boo Radley An internal development plot of the children's maturation The external plot is the main driver of the story: a black man has been falsely accused of rape by a white woman. Worse, he is wrongly convicted by a jury of white men after having the audacity to declare that he was helping the woman out of pity. This plot results in a failure as Tom is convicted and killed while trying to escape. The plot has a reversal at the end in which the true criminal (and perpetrator of prejudice) is himself killed and his killing is accepted by the law as eye-for-an-eye for Tom. The external plot unfolds in the formative years of the children and has a distinct impact on their relationship with an ostracized neighbor. They begin by fearing, judging and harassing Boo Radley, only to find that Boo has been helping them from the shadows. The plot ends when the children welcome Boo as a friend. The internal plot of the maturation of the children makes steady progress. They demonstrate an innate acceptance of others (in sharp contrast with the societal mores) and end up overcoming their own fear of Boo by accepting him as a friend (when even society has not accepted him). To Kill a Mockingbird is a wonderful story with a great idea: that growing up means overcoming prejudice. It seems to suggest that children have innate goodness and acceptance but can be molded by grownups and society to become blinded or become mature members of society. This contrasts with the idea that prejudice in any shape or form is childish and dangerous trait in adults and society as a whole. The story makes this point by tying together the three plots at the end: Boo kills the man who embodied prejudice to bring late justice for Tom Robinson, Boo does this to save the children, and the children accept him as a friend even though society still shuns him. It's a great movie. My only beef is the children's internal arc does not have many negative turning points. Their fighting (seemingly negative) is based on justifiable defending of their father's reputation, their jeering at Boo seems playful and child-like rather than childish and their talking Mr Cunningham out of the lynch mob and taking Boo's hand at the end feels a little caricatured and cringe-inducing. Maybe that's just my own feeling. Overall the point of the story is well taken and appreciated. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as heavenly as they say......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most summaries for this movie say that this is a movie about a white lawyer that defends a convicted black man. Well, this can't be far from the truth. This movie is about Atticus Finch and only him. most other characters are introduced just to show how heavenly the man is. Of course the movie is very joyful and should be commended. Gregory Peck puts on a performance that we never see this days. Their is absolutely nothing that signals his an actor and not Atticus Finch. the photography is breath taking and i am thankful that the movie was shot in black and white and not in color because i think i would have barfed if it was in color. But is is the things that the movie is insinuating that i just don't get. Who is the mockingbird? Is it the black man? Is it Boo? Early in the movie we are told that mockingbird are the only kinds of birds that shouldn't be shot because all they do is good things for us. Are we supposed to believe that the black man or Boo shouldn't be shot because they are creatures like mockingbirds that shouldn't be harmed simply because they know less and do everything for the benefit of others??? I have decided to watch the movie another time again but for now all i feel is a 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very overrated film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhkp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book on which this film is based, so I have no idea whether or not it's a good adaptation. I'm amazed Gregory Peck won the Academy Award. He took what seems like a great part, on paper, and managed to give an incredibly boring performance. Along with a lack of personality, his performance is so slowly spoken you could drive a truck through the pauses. I think his whole approach is disastrous. Is this the same actor who had so much life and charm playing a Southern dad back in 1946's The Yearling? It's like he's pickled in a jar, here. I'm amazed he won the Oscar over Peter O'Toole in Lawrence Of Arabia. None of the performances are memorable, including those of the children, except maybe Alice Ghostly's, and even her ebullience seems to have been toned down to fit in with the "Playhouse 90" acting style that pervades everything. And for some reason the fake southern accents of several of the principals are more annoying than fake southern accents usually are in other movies. The art director was the great Henry Bumstead, who (if I remember correctly, from an interview) convinced the filmmakers not to go on location, insisting he could recreate the setting just as well on the backlot. He lied. He also claimed people asked him for years what the location was, so real was the illusion. That may be true but it didn't fool me. Even though it's a good, professional job, probably the best anyone could do, the film seems to need an authentic setting. A somewhat similar film, MGM's Intruder In The Dust (1949) is so much better for being filmed in Oxford, Mississippi. It's also better for having a director (Clarence Brown) who knew how to make most of his camera set-ups interesting. That isn't the case, here. The dramatic high point of the film is ostensibly the courtroom sequence, but the set-ups and cinematography of the nondescript set are so boring, and the acting is so paint-by-the-numbers, it's like an episode of some 1950's sitcom from hell. Dramatically, I have never cared about what happens in the film. I've been forced to sit through it by friends, several times. I always lose interest at some point and my mind wanders. Harper Lee supposedly wanted Spencer Tracy to play Atticus, and, in spite of the fact that he was a couple of years over 60, at the time, and looked even older, he was an exciting actor and might have made everything work. This isn't a terrible film, and of course it has its touching scenes (with several moments greatly enhanced, emotionally, by Elmer Bernstein's score), it just seems incredibly dry, to me, when it should be much more warm and human. The kids and everyone else seem unduly lacking in fun, if not downright depressed, before anything depressing even happens to cause them to be that way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill A Mockingbird is probably one of the most over evaluated movies of all time. The first hour is absolutely boring to death, endless and in the end pointless. The scenes follow one another very disjointly, with no binder, and it goes nowhere. There is no soul and one is close to a flat electroencephalogram watching these children play, because this is almost exclusively what it is about. Then comes the second part dealing mostly with the trial. This is what kind of saves the movie, and still, even if you get more or less carried away by the testimonies and demonstrations with the underlying themes of racism and segregation, it remains rather weak qualitatively. But what is the most disconcerting is the lack of coherence of the feature with the association of two parts that almost have nothing in common. One is under the impression of watching two completely different movies: chronicle of a childhood or anti-racist pamphlet, a choice should have been made...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful Courtroom Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gregory Peck plays Atticus Finch, an Alabama lawyer who is called upon to defend a black man(played by Brock Peters) who is wrongfully accused of raping a white woman(played by Collin Wilcox) in the 1930's, where such an allegation could get him lynched before a trial. Story also includes Atticus's two children Scout & Jem, and the film is mostly seen from their POV, as they try to understand what's going on and why. Robert Duvall plays a mysterious figure named Boo Radley(played by Robert Duvall) who will have a huge impact on their lives. Superb film with an Academy Award winning performance by Gregory Peck, and fine direction by Robert Mulligan, who creates an evocative atmosphere of small town Alabama life of this period, and the wonder yet naivety of childhood. A first-rate adaptation of Harper Lee's famous novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't cut it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    King Sidharth
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film starts with the same essence as the book, but through experience I've learned not to compare much - they are two very different mediums. The problem begins with the film pacing up and skipping important events that build up motives of the characters and causes shift in their intent. Towards the end all of it looks like a rush. The importance and the the details of how grave the case of a lawyer actually backing up black man is lost in translation across the medium. Well, all of that can be forgiven and the film still somehow works along. But the contextual shock of a man attacking children is totally lost on screenplay, many dialog were changed which the climax dry and juice-less - taking all emotions out of it. Characters, especially Atticus's, were portrayed and played out very well. They are the only reason the film works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Most Overrated Films... Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Widely regarded as one of the greatest courtroom dramas of all time, it was surprising to see that there is not even a single shot of a courtroom in the first half which felt more of a suspense/horror for a completely different reason than what is depicted in the second half. Gregory Peck packs in a powerful performance as Atticus Finch, a righteous lawyer defending a Negro in an alleged rape case. The child actors did a nice job too & this film also introduces Robert Duvall in his first role. To Kill A Mockingbird's theme of prejudice moving us from the path of true judgment is clear but overall, this movie is overlong, somewhat boring & one of the most overrated films of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1962's To Kill A Mockingbird Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Robert Mulligan's Direction, Horton Foote's Screenplay, Russell Harlan's Cinematography, Elmer Bernstein's Score And Gregory Peck's Oscar-Winning Performance As Atticus Finch, It Ranks #25 On The AFI's 10th Anniversary List Of The Greatest American Movies Of All Time In 2007, Atticus Finch Was Voted The Greatest Movie Hero Of The 20th Century In 2003, A Really Robert Duvall In This Film, He Has Been In My Fourth Favorite Film Of All 1972's The Godfather With Marlon Brando And Al Pacino, This Movie Turned 50 Years Old Last Year In 2012, It Was 40 Years Old Just Over Eleven Years Back In 2002.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD is a classic adaption of a classic novel. I remember reading and watching this at school but most of the civil rights-era background when right over my head. Not really worth exploring a movie dealing with mature themes as a kid, but there you go. Watching it again as an adult, it's a delight and as hard-hitting as MISSISSIPPI BURNING, which came much later. I've always liked Gregory Peck and his laconic Atticus Finch is an exploration of a quiet, inherently decent man. It's a subtle performance of amazing strength, with no showy-off 'acting' scenes or the like; Peck's Oscar win was well deserved. I particularly liked the way the narrative develops through the eyes of a pair of innocent children as it adds another layer to the story. The whole sub-plot involving Boo Radley is a classic bit of mischief and I love the way the two plots tie up neatly at the end. The child actors are exceptionally strong and despite the lengthy running time the movie doesn't have any slow spots; it's all relevant and adds to the experience. As I said, this is a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lawyer against a village.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "To Kill a Mockingbird" is a movie based on Harper Lee's book of 1961 (Pulitzer Prize winning). It's a movie that displays the racial racism of the time (1930s) and how people treat each other in such times. It all starts when a black man (Brock Peters) accused of raping a white woman and Gregory Peck (Atticus Finch) represent him as his lawyer. When villagers learn about this representation of Atticus Finch they want to change his mind but Atticus decides to go ahead of it. I liked very much the performances of Gregory Peck as Atticus Finch a lawyer who fights for justice and of course the performances of the two little ones (son and daughter of Atticus Finch) Mary Badham as Scout and Phillip Alford as Jem. I recommend it because I think that this movie shows us a different treatment of a black man in those times from a white man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To grow up is to overcome prejudice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill a Mockingbird is a story about the idea that to grow up is to overcome prejudice. It tries to prove this idea with three plots, one of each type: An external plot seeking justice for a wrongly convicted Tom Robinson A relationship plot between the children and Boo Radley An internal development plot of the children's maturation The external plot is the main driver of the story: a black man has been falsely accused of rape by a white woman. Worse, he is wrongly convicted by a jury of white men after having the audacity to declare that he was helping the woman out of pity. This plot results in a failure as Tom is convicted and killed while trying to escape. The plot has a reversal at the end in which the true criminal (and perpetrator of prejudice) is himself killed and his killing is accepted by the law as eye-for-an-eye for Tom. The external plot unfolds in the formative years of the children and has a distinct impact on their relationship with an ostracized neighbor. They begin by fearing, judging and harassing Boo Radley, only to find that Boo has been helping them from the shadows. The plot ends when the children welcome Boo as a friend. The internal plot of the maturation of the children makes steady progress. They demonstrate an innate acceptance of others (in sharp contrast with the societal mores) and end up overcoming their own fear of Boo by accepting him as a friend (when even society has not accepted him). To Kill a Mockingbird is a wonderful story with a great idea: that growing up means overcoming prejudice. It seems to suggest that children have innate goodness and acceptance but can be molded by grownups and society to become blinded or become mature members of society. This contrasts with the idea that prejudice in any shape or form is childish and dangerous trait in adults and society as a whole. The story makes this point by tying together the three plots at the end: Boo kills the man who embodied prejudice to bring late justice for Tom Robinson, Boo does this to save the children, and the children accept him as a friend even though society still shuns him. It's a great movie. My only beef is the children's internal arc does not have many negative turning points. Their fighting (seemingly negative) is based on justifiable defending of their father's reputation, their jeering at Boo seems playful and child-like rather than childish and their talking Mr Cunningham out of the lynch mob and taking Boo's hand at the end feels a little caricatured and cringe-inducing. Maybe that's just my own feeling. Overall the point of the story is well taken and appreciated. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as heavenly as they say......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most summaries for this movie say that this is a movie about a white lawyer that defends a convicted black man. Well, this can't be far from the truth. This movie is about Atticus Finch and only him. most other characters are introduced just to show how heavenly the man is. Of course the movie is very joyful and should be commended. Gregory Peck puts on a performance that we never see this days. Their is absolutely nothing that signals his an actor and not Atticus Finch. the photography is breath taking and i am thankful that the movie was shot in black and white and not in color because i think i would have barfed if it was in color. But is is the things that the movie is insinuating that i just don't get. Who is the mockingbird? Is it the black man? Is it Boo? Early in the movie we are told that mockingbird are the only kinds of birds that shouldn't be shot because all they do is good things for us. Are we supposed to believe that the black man or Boo shouldn't be shot because they are creatures like mockingbirds that shouldn't be harmed simply because they know less and do everything for the benefit of others??? I have decided to watch the movie another time again but for now all i feel is a 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very overrated film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhkp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book on which this film is based, so I have no idea whether or not it's a good adaptation. I'm amazed Gregory Peck won the Academy Award. He took what seems like a great part, on paper, and managed to give an incredibly boring performance. Along with a lack of personality, his performance is so slowly spoken you could drive a truck through the pauses. I think his whole approach is disastrous. Is this the same actor who had so much life and charm playing a Southern dad back in 1946's The Yearling? It's like he's pickled in a jar, here. I'm amazed he won the Oscar over Peter O'Toole in Lawrence Of Arabia. None of the performances are memorable, including those of the children, except maybe Alice Ghostly's, and even her ebullience seems to have been toned down to fit in with the "Playhouse 90" acting style that pervades everything. And for some reason the fake southern accents of several of the principals are more annoying than fake southern accents usually are in other movies. The art director was the great Henry Bumstead, who (if I remember correctly, from an interview) convinced the filmmakers not to go on location, insisting he could recreate the setting just as well on the backlot. He lied. He also claimed people asked him for years what the location was, so real was the illusion. That may be true but it didn't fool me. Even though it's a good, professional job, probably the best anyone could do, the film seems to need an authentic setting. A somewhat similar film, MGM's Intruder In The Dust (1949) is so much better for being filmed in Oxford, Mississippi. It's also better for having a director (Clarence Brown) who knew how to make most of his camera set-ups interesting. That isn't the case, here. The dramatic high point of the film is ostensibly the courtroom sequence, but the set-ups and cinematography of the nondescript set are so boring, and the acting is so paint-by-the-numbers, it's like an episode of some 1950's sitcom from hell. Dramatically, I have never cared about what happens in the film. I've been forced to sit through it by friends, several times. I always lose interest at some point and my mind wanders. Harper Lee supposedly wanted Spencer Tracy to play Atticus, and, in spite of the fact that he was a couple of years over 60, at the time, and looked even older, he was an exciting actor and might have made everything work. This isn't a terrible film, and of course it has its touching scenes (with several moments greatly enhanced, emotionally, by Elmer Bernstein's score), it just seems incredibly dry, to me, when it should be much more warm and human. The kids and everyone else seem unduly lacking in fun, if not downright depressed, before anything depressing even happens to cause them to be that way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill A Mockingbird is probably one of the most over evaluated movies of all time. The first hour is absolutely boring to death, endless and in the end pointless. The scenes follow one another very disjointly, with no binder, and it goes nowhere. There is no soul and one is close to a flat electroencephalogram watching these children play, because this is almost exclusively what it is about. Then comes the second part dealing mostly with the trial. This is what kind of saves the movie, and still, even if you get more or less carried away by the testimonies and demonstrations with the underlying themes of racism and segregation, it remains rather weak qualitatively. But what is the most disconcerting is the lack of coherence of the feature with the association of two parts that almost have nothing in common. One is under the impression of watching two completely different movies: chronicle of a childhood or anti-racist pamphlet, a choice should have been made...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful Courtroom Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gregory Peck plays Atticus Finch, an Alabama lawyer who is called upon to defend a black man(played by Brock Peters) who is wrongfully accused of raping a white woman(played by Collin Wilcox) in the 1930's, where such an allegation could get him lynched before a trial. Story also includes Atticus's two children Scout & Jem, and the film is mostly seen from their POV, as they try to understand what's going on and why. Robert Duvall plays a mysterious figure named Boo Radley(played by Robert Duvall) who will have a huge impact on their lives. Superb film with an Academy Award winning performance by Gregory Peck, and fine direction by Robert Mulligan, who creates an evocative atmosphere of small town Alabama life of this period, and the wonder yet naivety of childhood. A first-rate adaptation of Harper Lee's famous novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't cut it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    King Sidharth
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film starts with the same essence as the book, but through experience I've learned not to compare much - they are two very different mediums. The problem begins with the film pacing up and skipping important events that build up motives of the characters and causes shift in their intent. Towards the end all of it looks like a rush. The importance and the the details of how grave the case of a lawyer actually backing up black man is lost in translation across the medium. Well, all of that can be forgiven and the film still somehow works along. But the contextual shock of a man attacking children is totally lost on screenplay, many dialog were changed which the climax dry and juice-less - taking all emotions out of it. Characters, especially Atticus's, were portrayed and played out very well. They are the only reason the film works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Most Overrated Films... Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Widely regarded as one of the greatest courtroom dramas of all time, it was surprising to see that there is not even a single shot of a courtroom in the first half which felt more of a suspense/horror for a completely different reason than what is depicted in the second half. Gregory Peck packs in a powerful performance as Atticus Finch, a righteous lawyer defending a Negro in an alleged rape case. The child actors did a nice job too & this film also introduces Robert Duvall in his first role. To Kill A Mockingbird's theme of prejudice moving us from the path of true judgment is clear but overall, this movie is overlong, somewhat boring & one of the most overrated films of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1962's To Kill A Mockingbird Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Robert Mulligan's Direction, Horton Foote's Screenplay, Russell Harlan's Cinematography, Elmer Bernstein's Score And Gregory Peck's Oscar-Winning Performance As Atticus Finch, It Ranks #25 On The AFI's 10th Anniversary List Of The Greatest American Movies Of All Time In 2007, Atticus Finch Was Voted The Greatest Movie Hero Of The 20th Century In 2003, A Really Robert Duvall In This Film, He Has Been In My Fourth Favorite Film Of All 1972's The Godfather With Marlon Brando And Al Pacino, This Movie Turned 50 Years Old Last Year In 2012, It Was 40 Years Old Just Over Eleven Years Back In 2002.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD is a classic adaption of a classic novel. I remember reading and watching this at school but most of the civil rights-era background when right over my head. Not really worth exploring a movie dealing with mature themes as a kid, but there you go. Watching it again as an adult, it's a delight and as hard-hitting as MISSISSIPPI BURNING, which came much later. I've always liked Gregory Peck and his laconic Atticus Finch is an exploration of a quiet, inherently decent man. It's a subtle performance of amazing strength, with no showy-off 'acting' scenes or the like; Peck's Oscar win was well deserved. I particularly liked the way the narrative develops through the eyes of a pair of innocent children as it adds another layer to the story. The whole sub-plot involving Boo Radley is a classic bit of mischief and I love the way the two plots tie up neatly at the end. The child actors are exceptionally strong and despite the lengthy running time the movie doesn't have any slow spots; it's all relevant and adds to the experience. As I said, this is a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lawyer against a village.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "To Kill a Mockingbird" is a movie based on Harper Lee's book of 1961 (Pulitzer Prize winning). It's a movie that displays the racial racism of the time (1930s) and how people treat each other in such times. It all starts when a black man (Brock Peters) accused of raping a white woman and Gregory Peck (Atticus Finch) represent him as his lawyer. When villagers learn about this representation of Atticus Finch they want to change his mind but Atticus decides to go ahead of it. I liked very much the performances of Gregory Peck as Atticus Finch a lawyer who fights for justice and of course the performances of the two little ones (son and daughter of Atticus Finch) Mary Badham as Scout and Phillip Alford as Jem. I recommend it because I think that this movie shows us a different treatment of a black man in those times from a white man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To grow up is to overcome prejudice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill a Mockingbird is a story about the idea that to grow up is to overcome prejudice. It tries to prove this idea with three plots, one of each type: An external plot seeking justice for a wrongly convicted Tom Robinson A relationship plot between the children and Boo Radley An internal development plot of the children's maturation The external plot is the main driver of the story: a black man has been falsely accused of rape by a white woman. Worse, he is wrongly convicted by a jury of white men after having the audacity to declare that he was helping the woman out of pity. This plot results in a failure as Tom is convicted and killed while trying to escape. The plot has a reversal at the end in which the true criminal (and perpetrator of prejudice) is himself killed and his killing is accepted by the law as eye-for-an-eye for Tom. The external plot unfolds in the formative years of the children and has a distinct impact on their relationship with an ostracized neighbor. They begin by fearing, judging and harassing Boo Radley, only to find that Boo has been helping them from the shadows. The plot ends when the children welcome Boo as a friend. The internal plot of the maturation of the children makes steady progress. They demonstrate an innate acceptance of others (in sharp contrast with the societal mores) and end up overcoming their own fear of Boo by accepting him as a friend (when even society has not accepted him). To Kill a Mockingbird is a wonderful story with a great idea: that growing up means overcoming prejudice. It seems to suggest that children have innate goodness and acceptance but can be molded by grownups and society to become blinded or become mature members of society. This contrasts with the idea that prejudice in any shape or form is childish and dangerous trait in adults and society as a whole. The story makes this point by tying together the three plots at the end: Boo kills the man who embodied prejudice to bring late justice for Tom Robinson, Boo does this to save the children, and the children accept him as a friend even though society still shuns him. It's a great movie. My only beef is the children's internal arc does not have many negative turning points. Their fighting (seemingly negative) is based on justifiable defending of their father's reputation, their jeering at Boo seems playful and child-like rather than childish and their talking Mr Cunningham out of the lynch mob and taking Boo's hand at the end feels a little caricatured and cringe-inducing. Maybe that's just my own feeling. Overall the point of the story is well taken and appreciated. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as heavenly as they say......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most summaries for this movie say that this is a movie about a white lawyer that defends a convicted black man. Well, this can't be far from the truth. This movie is about Atticus Finch and only him. most other characters are introduced just to show how heavenly the man is. Of course the movie is very joyful and should be commended. Gregory Peck puts on a performance that we never see this days. Their is absolutely nothing that signals his an actor and not Atticus Finch. the photography is breath taking and i am thankful that the movie was shot in black and white and not in color because i think i would have barfed if it was in color. But is is the things that the movie is insinuating that i just don't get. Who is the mockingbird? Is it the black man? Is it Boo? Early in the movie we are told that mockingbird are the only kinds of birds that shouldn't be shot because all they do is good things for us. Are we supposed to believe that the black man or Boo shouldn't be shot because they are creatures like mockingbirds that shouldn't be harmed simply because they know less and do everything for the benefit of others??? I have decided to watch the movie another time again but for now all i feel is a 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very overrated film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhkp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book on which this film is based, so I have no idea whether or not it's a good adaptation. I'm amazed Gregory Peck won the Academy Award. He took what seems like a great part, on paper, and managed to give an incredibly boring performance. Along with a lack of personality, his performance is so slowly spoken you could drive a truck through the pauses. I think his whole approach is disastrous. Is this the same actor who had so much life and charm playing a Southern dad back in 1946's The Yearling? It's like he's pickled in a jar, here. I'm amazed he won the Oscar over Peter O'Toole in Lawrence Of Arabia. None of the performances are memorable, including those of the children, except maybe Alice Ghostly's, and even her ebullience seems to have been toned down to fit in with the "Playhouse 90" acting style that pervades everything. And for some reason the fake southern accents of several of the principals are more annoying than fake southern accents usually are in other movies. The art director was the great Henry Bumstead, who (if I remember correctly, from an interview) convinced the filmmakers not to go on location, insisting he could recreate the setting just as well on the backlot. He lied. He also claimed people asked him for years what the location was, so real was the illusion. That may be true but it didn't fool me. Even though it's a good, professional job, probably the best anyone could do, the film seems to need an authentic setting. A somewhat similar film, MGM's Intruder In The Dust (1949) is so much better for being filmed in Oxford, Mississippi. It's also better for having a director (Clarence Brown) who knew how to make most of his camera set-ups interesting. That isn't the case, here. The dramatic high point of the film is ostensibly the courtroom sequence, but the set-ups and cinematography of the nondescript set are so boring, and the acting is so paint-by-the-numbers, it's like an episode of some 1950's sitcom from hell. Dramatically, I have never cared about what happens in the film. I've been forced to sit through it by friends, several times. I always lose interest at some point and my mind wanders. Harper Lee supposedly wanted Spencer Tracy to play Atticus, and, in spite of the fact that he was a couple of years over 60, at the time, and looked even older, he was an exciting actor and might have made everything work. This isn't a terrible film, and of course it has its touching scenes (with several moments greatly enhanced, emotionally, by Elmer Bernstein's score), it just seems incredibly dry, to me, when it should be much more warm and human. The kids and everyone else seem unduly lacking in fun, if not downright depressed, before anything depressing even happens to cause them to be that way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill A Mockingbird is probably one of the most over evaluated movies of all time. The first hour is absolutely boring to death, endless and in the end pointless. The scenes follow one another very disjointly, with no binder, and it goes nowhere. There is no soul and one is close to a flat electroencephalogram watching these children play, because this is almost exclusively what it is about. Then comes the second part dealing mostly with the trial. This is what kind of saves the movie, and still, even if you get more or less carried away by the testimonies and demonstrations with the underlying themes of racism and segregation, it remains rather weak qualitatively. But what is the most disconcerting is the lack of coherence of the feature with the association of two parts that almost have nothing in common. One is under the impression of watching two completely different movies: chronicle of a childhood or anti-racist pamphlet, a choice should have been made...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful Courtroom Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gregory Peck plays Atticus Finch, an Alabama lawyer who is called upon to defend a black man(played by Brock Peters) who is wrongfully accused of raping a white woman(played by Collin Wilcox) in the 1930's, where such an allegation could get him lynched before a trial. Story also includes Atticus's two children Scout & Jem, and the film is mostly seen from their POV, as they try to understand what's going on and why. Robert Duvall plays a mysterious figure named Boo Radley(played by Robert Duvall) who will have a huge impact on their lives. Superb film with an Academy Award winning performance by Gregory Peck, and fine direction by Robert Mulligan, who creates an evocative atmosphere of small town Alabama life of this period, and the wonder yet naivety of childhood. A first-rate adaptation of Harper Lee's famous novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't cut it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    King Sidharth
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film starts with the same essence as the book, but through experience I've learned not to compare much - they are two very different mediums. The problem begins with the film pacing up and skipping important events that build up motives of the characters and causes shift in their intent. Towards the end all of it looks like a rush. The importance and the the details of how grave the case of a lawyer actually backing up black man is lost in translation across the medium. Well, all of that can be forgiven and the film still somehow works along. But the contextual shock of a man attacking children is totally lost on screenplay, many dialog were changed which the climax dry and juice-less - taking all emotions out of it. Characters, especially Atticus's, were portrayed and played out very well. They are the only reason the film works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Most Overrated Films... Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Widely regarded as one of the greatest courtroom dramas of all time, it was surprising to see that there is not even a single shot of a courtroom in the first half which felt more of a suspense/horror for a completely different reason than what is depicted in the second half. Gregory Peck packs in a powerful performance as Atticus Finch, a righteous lawyer defending a Negro in an alleged rape case. The child actors did a nice job too & this film also introduces Robert Duvall in his first role. To Kill A Mockingbird's theme of prejudice moving us from the path of true judgment is clear but overall, this movie is overlong, somewhat boring & one of the most overrated films of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1962's To Kill A Mockingbird Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Robert Mulligan's Direction, Horton Foote's Screenplay, Russell Harlan's Cinematography, Elmer Bernstein's Score And Gregory Peck's Oscar-Winning Performance As Atticus Finch, It Ranks #25 On The AFI's 10th Anniversary List Of The Greatest American Movies Of All Time In 2007, Atticus Finch Was Voted The Greatest Movie Hero Of The 20th Century In 2003, A Really Robert Duvall In This Film, He Has Been In My Fourth Favorite Film Of All 1972's The Godfather With Marlon Brando And Al Pacino, This Movie Turned 50 Years Old Last Year In 2012, It Was 40 Years Old Just Over Eleven Years Back In 2002.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD is a classic adaption of a classic novel. I remember reading and watching this at school but most of the civil rights-era background when right over my head. Not really worth exploring a movie dealing with mature themes as a kid, but there you go. Watching it again as an adult, it's a delight and as hard-hitting as MISSISSIPPI BURNING, which came much later. I've always liked Gregory Peck and his laconic Atticus Finch is an exploration of a quiet, inherently decent man. It's a subtle performance of amazing strength, with no showy-off 'acting' scenes or the like; Peck's Oscar win was well deserved. I particularly liked the way the narrative develops through the eyes of a pair of innocent children as it adds another layer to the story. The whole sub-plot involving Boo Radley is a classic bit of mischief and I love the way the two plots tie up neatly at the end. The child actors are exceptionally strong and despite the lengthy running time the movie doesn't have any slow spots; it's all relevant and adds to the experience. As I said, this is a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lawyer against a village.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "To Kill a Mockingbird" is a movie based on Harper Lee's book of 1961 (Pulitzer Prize winning). It's a movie that displays the racial racism of the time (1930s) and how people treat each other in such times. It all starts when a black man (Brock Peters) accused of raping a white woman and Gregory Peck (Atticus Finch) represent him as his lawyer. When villagers learn about this representation of Atticus Finch they want to change his mind but Atticus decides to go ahead of it. I liked very much the performances of Gregory Peck as Atticus Finch a lawyer who fights for justice and of course the performances of the two little ones (son and daughter of Atticus Finch) Mary Badham as Scout and Phillip Alford as Jem. I recommend it because I think that this movie shows us a different treatment of a black man in those times from a white man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To grow up is to overcome prejudice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill a Mockingbird is a story about the idea that to grow up is to overcome prejudice. It tries to prove this idea with three plots, one of each type: An external plot seeking justice for a wrongly convicted Tom Robinson A relationship plot between the children and Boo Radley An internal development plot of the children's maturation The external plot is the main driver of the story: a black man has been falsely accused of rape by a white woman. Worse, he is wrongly convicted by a jury of white men after having the audacity to declare that he was helping the woman out of pity. This plot results in a failure as Tom is convicted and killed while trying to escape. The plot has a reversal at the end in which the true criminal (and perpetrator of prejudice) is himself killed and his killing is accepted by the law as eye-for-an-eye for Tom. The external plot unfolds in the formative years of the children and has a distinct impact on their relationship with an ostracized neighbor. They begin by fearing, judging and harassing Boo Radley, only to find that Boo has been helping them from the shadows. The plot ends when the children welcome Boo as a friend. The internal plot of the maturation of the children makes steady progress. They demonstrate an innate acceptance of others (in sharp contrast with the societal mores) and end up overcoming their own fear of Boo by accepting him as a friend (when even society has not accepted him). To Kill a Mockingbird is a wonderful story with a great idea: that growing up means overcoming prejudice. It seems to suggest that children have innate goodness and acceptance but can be molded by grownups and society to become blinded or become mature members of society. This contrasts with the idea that prejudice in any shape or form is childish and dangerous trait in adults and society as a whole. The story makes this point by tying together the three plots at the end: Boo kills the man who embodied prejudice to bring late justice for Tom Robinson, Boo does this to save the children, and the children accept him as a friend even though society still shuns him. It's a great movie. My only beef is the children's internal arc does not have many negative turning points. Their fighting (seemingly negative) is based on justifiable defending of their father's reputation, their jeering at Boo seems playful and child-like rather than childish and their talking Mr Cunningham out of the lynch mob and taking Boo's hand at the end feels a little caricatured and cringe-inducing. Maybe that's just my own feeling. Overall the point of the story is well taken and appreciated. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as heavenly as they say......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most summaries for this movie say that this is a movie about a white lawyer that defends a convicted black man. Well, this can't be far from the truth. This movie is about Atticus Finch and only him. most other characters are introduced just to show how heavenly the man is. Of course the movie is very joyful and should be commended. Gregory Peck puts on a performance that we never see this days. Their is absolutely nothing that signals his an actor and not Atticus Finch. the photography is breath taking and i am thankful that the movie was shot in black and white and not in color because i think i would have barfed if it was in color. But is is the things that the movie is insinuating that i just don't get. Who is the mockingbird? Is it the black man? Is it Boo? Early in the movie we are told that mockingbird are the only kinds of birds that shouldn't be shot because all they do is good things for us. Are we supposed to believe that the black man or Boo shouldn't be shot because they are creatures like mockingbirds that shouldn't be harmed simply because they know less and do everything for the benefit of others??? I have decided to watch the movie another time again but for now all i feel is a 7 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very overrated film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jhkp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the book on which this film is based, so I have no idea whether or not it's a good adaptation. I'm amazed Gregory Peck won the Academy Award. He took what seems like a great part, on paper, and managed to give an incredibly boring performance. Along with a lack of personality, his performance is so slowly spoken you could drive a truck through the pauses. I think his whole approach is disastrous. Is this the same actor who had so much life and charm playing a Southern dad back in 1946's The Yearling? It's like he's pickled in a jar, here. I'm amazed he won the Oscar over Peter O'Toole in Lawrence Of Arabia. None of the performances are memorable, including those of the children, except maybe Alice Ghostly's, and even her ebullience seems to have been toned down to fit in with the "Playhouse 90" acting style that pervades everything. And for some reason the fake southern accents of several of the principals are more annoying than fake southern accents usually are in other movies. The art director was the great Henry Bumstead, who (if I remember correctly, from an interview) convinced the filmmakers not to go on location, insisting he could recreate the setting just as well on the backlot. He lied. He also claimed people asked him for years what the location was, so real was the illusion. That may be true but it didn't fool me. Even though it's a good, professional job, probably the best anyone could do, the film seems to need an authentic setting. A somewhat similar film, MGM's Intruder In The Dust (1949) is so much better for being filmed in Oxford, Mississippi. It's also better for having a director (Clarence Brown) who knew how to make most of his camera set-ups interesting. That isn't the case, here. The dramatic high point of the film is ostensibly the courtroom sequence, but the set-ups and cinematography of the nondescript set are so boring, and the acting is so paint-by-the-numbers, it's like an episode of some 1950's sitcom from hell. Dramatically, I have never cared about what happens in the film. I've been forced to sit through it by friends, several times. I always lose interest at some point and my mind wanders. Harper Lee supposedly wanted Spencer Tracy to play Atticus, and, in spite of the fact that he was a couple of years over 60, at the time, and looked even older, he was an exciting actor and might have made everything work. This isn't a terrible film, and of course it has its touching scenes (with several moments greatly enhanced, emotionally, by Elmer Bernstein's score), it just seems incredibly dry, to me, when it should be much more warm and human. The kids and everyone else seem unduly lacking in fun, if not downright depressed, before anything depressing even happens to cause them to be that way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Kill A Mockingbird is probably one of the most over evaluated movies of all time. The first hour is absolutely boring to death, endless and in the end pointless. The scenes follow one another very disjointly, with no binder, and it goes nowhere. There is no soul and one is close to a flat electroencephalogram watching these children play, because this is almost exclusively what it is about. Then comes the second part dealing mostly with the trial. This is what kind of saves the movie, and still, even if you get more or less carried away by the testimonies and demonstrations with the underlying themes of racism and segregation, it remains rather weak qualitatively. But what is the most disconcerting is the lack of coherence of the feature with the association of two parts that almost have nothing in common. One is under the impression of watching two completely different movies: chronicle of a childhood or anti-racist pamphlet, a choice should have been made...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
