<filme>
 <id>
  43
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109635
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Ass&eacute;dio Sexual
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A computer specialist is sued for sexual harassment by a former lover turned boss who initiated the act forcefully, which threatens both his career and his personal life.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  With his company about to merge, a happily married and successful computer expert is expecting a promotion. Instead the job goes to a woman from another plant with whom he had an affair in his bachelor days. His new boss, not only dangerously sexy but equally dangerously ambitious, has climbed the corporate ladder by exerting undue influence on the CEO. She apparently tries to pick up where they left off but he just about manages to resist. This liaison is soon revealed to be part of her master plan to consolidate power and use Tom as a scapegoat to cover her technical misdeeds. As his position at work comes under increasing pressure he decides to file charges of sexual harassment. This is the last thing the company needs.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   sexual harassment
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   computer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   promotion
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   seduction
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   corporation
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Barry Levinson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Michael Crichton
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Paul Attanasio
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Michael Douglas
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Demi Moore
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Donald Sutherland
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corporate Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays Tom Sanders, a successful computer specialist working for a big firm who is passed over for promotion in favor of an old flame named Meredith Johnson(played by Demi Moore). She is very ambitious, and seems to have undue influence over the CEO, which proves to be the case as Meredith tries to seduce Tom after hours in her office. Tom, a happily married man, is tempted by her beauty, but resists. He is later shocked to learn that she has reported him for sexual harassment, so he has no choice but to sue her, which endangers his future within the company, but Tom will discover that things are not as simple as they seem, and Meredith has another agenda at work... Based on Michael Crichton's novel, and well directed by Barry Levinson, this features fine acting by its stars, and a fascinating story with many twists and turns, that leads to a satisfying finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Naked Truth...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cronostitan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the specialist of the trendy thriller, this movie rather well pinned also speaks about the difficult square in the society that all those can occupy sometimes who do not enough sit - at least not endowed with varied and diverse protections. What it will be necessary to raise it is that Crichton dodges these long sequences of court with strong theatrical echo which we undergo very often among soaps in the TV (and also in John Grisham's books and in adventures of the TV show Ally Mc Beal), instead of it he joins in the life the office among this great number of "small" details that all those sometimes forget who do not work: another tour de force very rich in teaching... Because freedom is also a question of money although people are not globally more free than before in the old time, it is simply wrong!! Careful thus in "politically correct" falsified, in the traps, in the blackmail, in the propaganda, in the jealousy...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full disclosure: this movie stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suppose the idea of Michael Douglas being sexually harassed by Demi Moore could be intriguing. Could be. But in this movie it doesn't end up being intriguing at all. The story fizzles out before it ever really gets going. The movie goes on and on without ever really going anywhere. There's no spark, no sizzle. Attempts at humor fall horribly flat. The only laughs in this movie come from laughing at just how bad it is, most notably in the big climactic virtual reality scene. Wait, big climactic virtual reality scene? Yeah, it's just as stupid as it sounds, an awful idea executed so badly you can't help but laugh at how truly terrible it is. This is a movie which fails in pretty much every way possible. Douglas plays Tom Sanders, the head of production at some high-tech Seattle outfit. There's a big merger on the horizon, Tom expects a big promotion to go with it. But the job he covets goes to Meredith Johnson, a one-time girlfriend of his who celebrates their reunion by trying to rape him in her office. When Tom says no, not before having a little fun of course because the movie needs its obligatory sex scene, Meredith promises to ruin him. And the next day she duly accuses him of sexual harassment. He gets himself a lawyer, accuses her and it's a big he-said, she-said deal which only serves to bore those of us who are unfortunate enough to be watching. Drama and tension are in very short supply. Tedium is the order of the day. Moore's absolutely atrocious acting doesn't help matters. My goodness, she is terrible. The story slogs along, everyone ganging up on poor Tom in some horribly uninteresting conspiracy. It's not just Meredith out to get him, this goes all the way up to the big boss at the top. That character, played by Donald Sutherland, is I suppose meant to seem sinister but the way Sutherland mugs and overacts he just comes off as a buffoon. Just another example of the way this movie completely misses the mark. And just when you think it can't possibly get any worse along comes that absurd virtual reality scene which is simply one of the dumbest things ever seen in any movie. Even after that laughable "climax" the movie doesn't have the decency to just end. More pointless, boring twists to come. The whole thing is just interminable. Movies don't get much worse than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Douglas contends with business foe Demi Moore determined to oust him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Disclosure" is a smoothly done, pleasurable and suspenseful watch in which the action never flags. This is a good solid Hollywood product by all involved. Michael Douglas does his usual fine job -- he makes look easy what is not at all easy -- playing a Silicon Valley production specialist. For reasons unknown, the production line product is failing while the prototypes work. He is being made to look incompetent. Meanwhile, he has a new boss, Demi Moore, who was his old flame. And the big boss, Donald Sutherland, is negotiating a merger that will enrich everyone in the firm, stock options and all that. Preventing Douglas from tracking down the production line issues in Malaysia are this merger and Moore's plot to accuse Douglas of sexual harassment. Douglas fights back, without anger and bitterness, by mediation, accusing her correctly of harassing him. Meanwhile, he's trying to figure out how production has gone wrong. In the narrow world of an operations specialist, he doesn't suspect behind the scenes machinations. But he has a "friend" higher up (a guardian angel) who does, and who spurs him on via anonymous e-mails to dig deeper. As the merger pressures those around him, all of whom stand to gain handsomely by stock options, he finds his associates melting away and, more or less, siding with pressures brought by Sutherland to get Douglas to paper over the production issues. Sutherland absolutely looks the part and steals every scene he is in. His part in all this is ambiguous enough that he can bob and weave and land on his feet. He's a slick one. He didn't get to head the company without this skill. And so we enter the world of Silicon Valley too, and that's part of the movie's charm. The interior sets of the business itself bring this to life, and complement the business rivalries and machinations. The 128m running time passes quickly. Douglas learns a thing or two. The supporting roles are well cast and played. The movie is a business thriller, with the emphasis on emotional pressures, calculation, and psychological conflicts that bring out the varying personalities and motivations of those involved. Dramatic elements are present but not over-emphasized.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demi Moore As A Femme Fatale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is a thriller directed by Barry Levinson that stars Michael Douglas and Demi Moore. It is based on Michael Crichton's novel of the same title.The cast also includes Donald Sutherland, Rosemary Forsyth and Dennis Miller.The film is a combination mystery and thriller about office politics and intrigue in the computer industry in the mid-1990s. Also,it includes the issue of sexual harassment. Tom Sanders is an executive at DigiCom, a leading computer software firm. The company is about to launch a new virtual reality-based data storage system that is expected to revolutionize the industry, and Bob Garvin, the owner of the company, is in the midst of negotiating a merger that could bring $100 million into the firm. However, while Tom is expecting a promotion, he discovers the position has been given instead to a new hire, Meredith Johnson, with whom Tom had an affair years ago, before he was married. After her first day of work, Meredith invites Tom up to her office and makes a concerted attempt to seduce him; while Tom doesn't fight off her advances with very much gusto at first, eventually he decides things have gone too far and leaves in a huff. The next morning, Meredith accuses Tom of sexual harassment, and he realizes this was merely a power ploy to get him out of DigiCom for good; Tom, determined to fight, files a counter-suit, which makes him no friends at the company, since rocking the boat too hard could very well scotch the merger. The story takes some clever twists and turns as it develops into a full- fledged psychological thriller that is effective and gripping, if occasionally contrived as a result of over-plotting.The film is genuinely gripping and well-written.As for the performances,Moore makes an awesome femme fatale while Douglas triumps over evil in a big way.But it is a watchable film as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Crichton winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) not only finds himself passed over for an expected promotion, but his new boss turns out to be an old flame, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). When Meredith makes strong overtures to him, Tom initially goes along, only to refuse her. Furious at his rejection, Meredith accuses him of sexual harassment, so he makes a counter-accusation. Set against the corporate and executive positioning of a complex business deal, Michael Crichton's story (oh how we miss that man's creative output) strikes an interesting balance between techno-thriller, sexual politics commentary, courtroom drama, and urban paranoia thriller. The story is terrific - complex but always followable, gripping and involving, and with emotional ramifications as the essentially decent and blameless Sanders finds himself in an impossible situation. This is a good film, with one of the best payoffs ever, and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the book. No good comes from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everybody's out to get Michael Douglas. Marketed as a controversial examination of a man's charge of sexual harassment against a female co-worker, "Disclosure" is really about paranoia. The reverse discrimination angle is a (albeit large) plot point, but it isn't the crux of the movie. Which is where the movie takes a sharp turn off a cliff. Douglas is a software engineer for a large corporation, and he's been turned down for the big promotion - in favor of a man-eating former lover (Demi Moore). Moore, the new V.P. invites Douglas to her office for a catch-up session, and things get downright steamy. But Douglas is a family man, and he walks away from an enraged (rebuffed) Moore. The next day, Douglas walks into the office to the accusation that he was the one doing the harassing. A very large chunk of the movie is devoted to the harassment charge, with Douglas calling in the help of a media-hungry lawyer (Roma Maffia) to help him with his case. Sordid details emerge, cracks appear in the Douglas household, and and it's not a pretty skirmish. But Moore is just a cog in a larger scheme to eventually make Douglas look incompetent and throw him out on the street. That's what this movie is really about: Douglas is worried about his job. It's all a very conspiratorial and manipulative oppression of the poor white family man, complete with hushed voices in the office. Throw in some deliciously early '90s CGI and a ridiculously lame virtual reality subplot, and you've got the market fresh makings of an overly- long film that never rises above goofy. 3/10; a real chore
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Office Politics, Paranoia & The Abuse Of Power
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the 1990s when an increasing number of women were filling top jobs in the corporate world, a story about a woman sexually harassing a man became a plausible scenario and the topical and controversial nature of the subject resonated strongly enough with the public at that time to make "Disclosure" a great box office success. Whilst the sexual harassment element of the story was shocking and attention grabbing, it soon became apparent that this was just part of a far larger and more pervasive issue i.e. the abuse of power. In the workplace, where social conventions, various legal constraints and political correctness all come into play, there is still no escape from the kind of management conspiracies, office politics and duplicity which are depicted so effectively in "Disclosure" or the kinds of distrust and paranoia that they can so easily generate. Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) heads one of the divisions of a Seattle computer company and is engaged in the development of a product which is vitally important to the success of a planned and very lucrative merger with another company. There are some problems with the product which Tom and his team are currently dealing with and are under considerable pressure to resolve. As a result of some changes which are taking place within the company, Tom's confident that he'll be promoted but it soon transpires that he's been passed over and the job has been given to one of his ex-girlfriends, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). On her first day in the job, Meredith arranges a late meeting with Tom to discuss his division's work but during their meeting she aggressively tries to seduce him and is furious when, after a considerable struggle, she's unsuccessful. Meredith responds to Tom's rejection by accusing him of sexual harassment and asserting that in the circumstances, there's no way that she'd be able to work with him again. The company want to avoid any publicity that could have an adverse impact on the upcoming merger and so try to get Tom to take a transfer to another job in their Austin branch. He can't countenance this idea because of the negative effect it would have on his career and is in a very tight spot. Help unexpectedly arrives in the form of an anonymous e-mail which recommends that he consult an attorney called Catherine Alvarez (Roma Maffia) who's a specialist in sexual harassment cases. Tom decides to fight back and files a counter-suit. The process he has to go through to achieve justice is difficult and painful but irrefutable proof of his innocence is produced and the company agrees to retain him and give him a pay rise. The relief that Tom feels after being cleared of the charges against him is short lived as it quickly becomes apparent that efforts which were originally initiated by Meredith to make him look incompetent have now drawn wider support and he's being set up to be publicly humiliated and undermined at a high profile shareholders' meeting. The way in which Tom copes with this threat then provides the story with its intriguing conclusion. The events in "Disclosure" all take place within the space of one intense week in which Tom's normally affluent and comfortable lifestyle is disrupted as his disappointment at being passed over for promotion turns into discomfort when he discovers the identity of his new boss and then horror as he's threatened with the loss of his job, his wife, his family and his stock options. The false accusation made against him, the plots to make him look incompetent and a workplace where no one can be trusted, create a climate of paranoia which is reinforced when some of his previous innocent actions are characterised as something more sinister and the support of his colleagues is systematically eroded by those high up in the company structure. Michael Douglas gives a good solid performance as the beleaguered Tom and Demi Moore is marvellous as the cold and cruel villain of the piece. Donald Sutherland and Roma Maffia also stand out in their supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexual harassment is about power. When did I have the power? When?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is directed by Barry Levinson and co-adapted to screenplay by Paul Attanasio and Michael Crichton from Crichton's own novel of the same name. It stars Michael Douglas, Demi Moore, Donald Sutherland, Roma Maffia, Dylan Baker, Caroline Goodall and Rosemary Forsyth. Music is scored by Ennio Morricone. Tom Sanders (Douglas) is an executive at DigiCom, a high-tech computer company, who hopes that now it's finally his time to get promotion. Passed over for an outsider, he's further irked when it turns out to be Meredith Johnson (Moore), an old passionate flame of his from years previously. When Meredith arranges for a meeting between the two later that evening, Tom finds himself sexually harassed by her. Spurning her aggressive overtures, Tom is shocked to learn the next day that she has filed a charge of sexual harassment against him. He naturally counters the charge, but this opens up a can of worms for both him and the future of DigiCom. The 1990s practically belonged to Michael Crichton, it seemed for a time that everything he wrote was adapted to the big screen for some form of entertainment. With Jurassic Park still warm and still garnering bucket loads of cash, two other Crichton adaptations worked their way into theatres; both of which were a world away from the family friendly extravaganza of Jurassic Park. One was Rising Sun, a messy wasted potential of a movie, the other was Disclosure, a zeitgeist snatcher that seized the moment. The topic, and the novelty of flipping the gender aggressor, was always going to make Disclosure of much interest, thus the film and the novel made big money: aided still further by the hot casting of Douglas and Moore, who were still draw cards in the early 90s. Crichton, after being displeased with other adaptations of his work, got big say on the screenplay as a written project. So with director Levinson in tow, he set about pushing the buttons of his audience, attempting to continue the heated debates that were brought about previously from Douglas' Fatal Attraction and Basic Instinct. If it's Crichton's or Levinson's fault that it didn't work out that way? I'm not sure, but fact is, is that Disclosure really wasn't that potent back then, and certainly now it's not even lukewarm. There's too much techno babble going on, and an over keenness to stick the nose up at the big business vultures picking the flesh off of the lesser minions. Entering the last half hour of the film, it's easy to forget there has actually been a sexual harassment case! Here's the crux of the matter, if going in to it for a first time viewing expecting this to be a powder-keg of sexual harassment muckiness and legal intrigue, then you are in for a big disappointment. I know, because I was one of the paying patrons at the theatre back in 94! You sense that one of the makers got a bit carried away Yet the film still has much going for it if stripped of that expectation, not least that it packs a pile of tension in that last half hour and the finale is rather rewarding. I'd go as far to say I'm a fan of the film, but it's not the film I originally went to see! There's a trio of interesting and differing female characters at the front of the narrative, even if Moore's stair-master vixen isn't exactly developed beyond being a bitch, and the virtual reality sequences have an appealing charm about them. The cast are turning in good ones, with a notable shout out to Caroline Goodall who wisely underplays it as the wife. While the interior set design (Gary Lewis/Joseph Hodges) for the DigiCom HQ is wonderful with its 90s excess of glass meeting mirrors and open spaces. Which leaves us with what? A film that is not what you expect! Which in this case is both disappointing and a surprise. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stand-alone thriller with a mish-mash of intriguing themes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tale of sexual harassment in the office with a twist  this time, the guy is the victim and the woman the pursuer. Yes, it's another thriller that builds on Michael Douglas's typecasting as a victim of powerful women (following FATAL ATTRACTION and BASIC INSTINCT) but this one plays all the right cards. Part workplace drama, part courtroom thriller, and all the time invested with now-dated-but-then-cutting-edge technology (email, virtual reality) I found Disclosure to be never less than intriguing and well made. The Crichton source material helps, of course; I haven't yet seen a Crichton film that hasn't been thought-provoking and entertaining (even the worst, CONGO, isn't entirely without merit, although the book is loads better). I've been seeing a lot of Douglas in recent months and my opinion of him has steadily improved to the degree that I can't remember him giving a bad performance. He's fine here, providing a key likable anchor for the film to revolve around, and playing opposite him Demi Moore is also a surprise: she oozes sexuality and selfishness in equal measure, proving a powerful enemy at all times. Moore isn't the world's greatest actress but this might well be her best performance in a film. The courtroom scenes, tense and full of electricity, are undoubtedly the film's highlights and there are supporting actors to relish (Donald Sutherland, Allan Rich and in particular a slimy Dylan Baker). It's not a perfect film, but it is a reminder of the kind of solid, sensual thriller that got made during a sometimes forgotten decade of filmmaking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corporate Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays Tom Sanders, a successful computer specialist working for a big firm who is passed over for promotion in favor of an old flame named Meredith Johnson(played by Demi Moore). She is very ambitious, and seems to have undue influence over the CEO, which proves to be the case as Meredith tries to seduce Tom after hours in her office. Tom, a happily married man, is tempted by her beauty, but resists. He is later shocked to learn that she has reported him for sexual harassment, so he has no choice but to sue her, which endangers his future within the company, but Tom will discover that things are not as simple as they seem, and Meredith has another agenda at work... Based on Michael Crichton's novel, and well directed by Barry Levinson, this features fine acting by its stars, and a fascinating story with many twists and turns, that leads to a satisfying finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Naked Truth...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cronostitan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the specialist of the trendy thriller, this movie rather well pinned also speaks about the difficult square in the society that all those can occupy sometimes who do not enough sit - at least not endowed with varied and diverse protections. What it will be necessary to raise it is that Crichton dodges these long sequences of court with strong theatrical echo which we undergo very often among soaps in the TV (and also in John Grisham's books and in adventures of the TV show Ally Mc Beal), instead of it he joins in the life the office among this great number of "small" details that all those sometimes forget who do not work: another tour de force very rich in teaching... Because freedom is also a question of money although people are not globally more free than before in the old time, it is simply wrong!! Careful thus in "politically correct" falsified, in the traps, in the blackmail, in the propaganda, in the jealousy...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full disclosure: this movie stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suppose the idea of Michael Douglas being sexually harassed by Demi Moore could be intriguing. Could be. But in this movie it doesn't end up being intriguing at all. The story fizzles out before it ever really gets going. The movie goes on and on without ever really going anywhere. There's no spark, no sizzle. Attempts at humor fall horribly flat. The only laughs in this movie come from laughing at just how bad it is, most notably in the big climactic virtual reality scene. Wait, big climactic virtual reality scene? Yeah, it's just as stupid as it sounds, an awful idea executed so badly you can't help but laugh at how truly terrible it is. This is a movie which fails in pretty much every way possible. Douglas plays Tom Sanders, the head of production at some high-tech Seattle outfit. There's a big merger on the horizon, Tom expects a big promotion to go with it. But the job he covets goes to Meredith Johnson, a one-time girlfriend of his who celebrates their reunion by trying to rape him in her office. When Tom says no, not before having a little fun of course because the movie needs its obligatory sex scene, Meredith promises to ruin him. And the next day she duly accuses him of sexual harassment. He gets himself a lawyer, accuses her and it's a big he-said, she-said deal which only serves to bore those of us who are unfortunate enough to be watching. Drama and tension are in very short supply. Tedium is the order of the day. Moore's absolutely atrocious acting doesn't help matters. My goodness, she is terrible. The story slogs along, everyone ganging up on poor Tom in some horribly uninteresting conspiracy. It's not just Meredith out to get him, this goes all the way up to the big boss at the top. That character, played by Donald Sutherland, is I suppose meant to seem sinister but the way Sutherland mugs and overacts he just comes off as a buffoon. Just another example of the way this movie completely misses the mark. And just when you think it can't possibly get any worse along comes that absurd virtual reality scene which is simply one of the dumbest things ever seen in any movie. Even after that laughable "climax" the movie doesn't have the decency to just end. More pointless, boring twists to come. The whole thing is just interminable. Movies don't get much worse than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Douglas contends with business foe Demi Moore determined to oust him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Disclosure" is a smoothly done, pleasurable and suspenseful watch in which the action never flags. This is a good solid Hollywood product by all involved. Michael Douglas does his usual fine job -- he makes look easy what is not at all easy -- playing a Silicon Valley production specialist. For reasons unknown, the production line product is failing while the prototypes work. He is being made to look incompetent. Meanwhile, he has a new boss, Demi Moore, who was his old flame. And the big boss, Donald Sutherland, is negotiating a merger that will enrich everyone in the firm, stock options and all that. Preventing Douglas from tracking down the production line issues in Malaysia are this merger and Moore's plot to accuse Douglas of sexual harassment. Douglas fights back, without anger and bitterness, by mediation, accusing her correctly of harassing him. Meanwhile, he's trying to figure out how production has gone wrong. In the narrow world of an operations specialist, he doesn't suspect behind the scenes machinations. But he has a "friend" higher up (a guardian angel) who does, and who spurs him on via anonymous e-mails to dig deeper. As the merger pressures those around him, all of whom stand to gain handsomely by stock options, he finds his associates melting away and, more or less, siding with pressures brought by Sutherland to get Douglas to paper over the production issues. Sutherland absolutely looks the part and steals every scene he is in. His part in all this is ambiguous enough that he can bob and weave and land on his feet. He's a slick one. He didn't get to head the company without this skill. And so we enter the world of Silicon Valley too, and that's part of the movie's charm. The interior sets of the business itself bring this to life, and complement the business rivalries and machinations. The 128m running time passes quickly. Douglas learns a thing or two. The supporting roles are well cast and played. The movie is a business thriller, with the emphasis on emotional pressures, calculation, and psychological conflicts that bring out the varying personalities and motivations of those involved. Dramatic elements are present but not over-emphasized.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demi Moore As A Femme Fatale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is a thriller directed by Barry Levinson that stars Michael Douglas and Demi Moore. It is based on Michael Crichton's novel of the same title.The cast also includes Donald Sutherland, Rosemary Forsyth and Dennis Miller.The film is a combination mystery and thriller about office politics and intrigue in the computer industry in the mid-1990s. Also,it includes the issue of sexual harassment. Tom Sanders is an executive at DigiCom, a leading computer software firm. The company is about to launch a new virtual reality-based data storage system that is expected to revolutionize the industry, and Bob Garvin, the owner of the company, is in the midst of negotiating a merger that could bring $100 million into the firm. However, while Tom is expecting a promotion, he discovers the position has been given instead to a new hire, Meredith Johnson, with whom Tom had an affair years ago, before he was married. After her first day of work, Meredith invites Tom up to her office and makes a concerted attempt to seduce him; while Tom doesn't fight off her advances with very much gusto at first, eventually he decides things have gone too far and leaves in a huff. The next morning, Meredith accuses Tom of sexual harassment, and he realizes this was merely a power ploy to get him out of DigiCom for good; Tom, determined to fight, files a counter-suit, which makes him no friends at the company, since rocking the boat too hard could very well scotch the merger. The story takes some clever twists and turns as it develops into a full- fledged psychological thriller that is effective and gripping, if occasionally contrived as a result of over-plotting.The film is genuinely gripping and well-written.As for the performances,Moore makes an awesome femme fatale while Douglas triumps over evil in a big way.But it is a watchable film as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Crichton winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) not only finds himself passed over for an expected promotion, but his new boss turns out to be an old flame, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). When Meredith makes strong overtures to him, Tom initially goes along, only to refuse her. Furious at his rejection, Meredith accuses him of sexual harassment, so he makes a counter-accusation. Set against the corporate and executive positioning of a complex business deal, Michael Crichton's story (oh how we miss that man's creative output) strikes an interesting balance between techno-thriller, sexual politics commentary, courtroom drama, and urban paranoia thriller. The story is terrific - complex but always followable, gripping and involving, and with emotional ramifications as the essentially decent and blameless Sanders finds himself in an impossible situation. This is a good film, with one of the best payoffs ever, and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the book. No good comes from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everybody's out to get Michael Douglas. Marketed as a controversial examination of a man's charge of sexual harassment against a female co-worker, "Disclosure" is really about paranoia. The reverse discrimination angle is a (albeit large) plot point, but it isn't the crux of the movie. Which is where the movie takes a sharp turn off a cliff. Douglas is a software engineer for a large corporation, and he's been turned down for the big promotion - in favor of a man-eating former lover (Demi Moore). Moore, the new V.P. invites Douglas to her office for a catch-up session, and things get downright steamy. But Douglas is a family man, and he walks away from an enraged (rebuffed) Moore. The next day, Douglas walks into the office to the accusation that he was the one doing the harassing. A very large chunk of the movie is devoted to the harassment charge, with Douglas calling in the help of a media-hungry lawyer (Roma Maffia) to help him with his case. Sordid details emerge, cracks appear in the Douglas household, and and it's not a pretty skirmish. But Moore is just a cog in a larger scheme to eventually make Douglas look incompetent and throw him out on the street. That's what this movie is really about: Douglas is worried about his job. It's all a very conspiratorial and manipulative oppression of the poor white family man, complete with hushed voices in the office. Throw in some deliciously early '90s CGI and a ridiculously lame virtual reality subplot, and you've got the market fresh makings of an overly- long film that never rises above goofy. 3/10; a real chore
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Office Politics, Paranoia & The Abuse Of Power
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the 1990s when an increasing number of women were filling top jobs in the corporate world, a story about a woman sexually harassing a man became a plausible scenario and the topical and controversial nature of the subject resonated strongly enough with the public at that time to make "Disclosure" a great box office success. Whilst the sexual harassment element of the story was shocking and attention grabbing, it soon became apparent that this was just part of a far larger and more pervasive issue i.e. the abuse of power. In the workplace, where social conventions, various legal constraints and political correctness all come into play, there is still no escape from the kind of management conspiracies, office politics and duplicity which are depicted so effectively in "Disclosure" or the kinds of distrust and paranoia that they can so easily generate. Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) heads one of the divisions of a Seattle computer company and is engaged in the development of a product which is vitally important to the success of a planned and very lucrative merger with another company. There are some problems with the product which Tom and his team are currently dealing with and are under considerable pressure to resolve. As a result of some changes which are taking place within the company, Tom's confident that he'll be promoted but it soon transpires that he's been passed over and the job has been given to one of his ex-girlfriends, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). On her first day in the job, Meredith arranges a late meeting with Tom to discuss his division's work but during their meeting she aggressively tries to seduce him and is furious when, after a considerable struggle, she's unsuccessful. Meredith responds to Tom's rejection by accusing him of sexual harassment and asserting that in the circumstances, there's no way that she'd be able to work with him again. The company want to avoid any publicity that could have an adverse impact on the upcoming merger and so try to get Tom to take a transfer to another job in their Austin branch. He can't countenance this idea because of the negative effect it would have on his career and is in a very tight spot. Help unexpectedly arrives in the form of an anonymous e-mail which recommends that he consult an attorney called Catherine Alvarez (Roma Maffia) who's a specialist in sexual harassment cases. Tom decides to fight back and files a counter-suit. The process he has to go through to achieve justice is difficult and painful but irrefutable proof of his innocence is produced and the company agrees to retain him and give him a pay rise. The relief that Tom feels after being cleared of the charges against him is short lived as it quickly becomes apparent that efforts which were originally initiated by Meredith to make him look incompetent have now drawn wider support and he's being set up to be publicly humiliated and undermined at a high profile shareholders' meeting. The way in which Tom copes with this threat then provides the story with its intriguing conclusion. The events in "Disclosure" all take place within the space of one intense week in which Tom's normally affluent and comfortable lifestyle is disrupted as his disappointment at being passed over for promotion turns into discomfort when he discovers the identity of his new boss and then horror as he's threatened with the loss of his job, his wife, his family and his stock options. The false accusation made against him, the plots to make him look incompetent and a workplace where no one can be trusted, create a climate of paranoia which is reinforced when some of his previous innocent actions are characterised as something more sinister and the support of his colleagues is systematically eroded by those high up in the company structure. Michael Douglas gives a good solid performance as the beleaguered Tom and Demi Moore is marvellous as the cold and cruel villain of the piece. Donald Sutherland and Roma Maffia also stand out in their supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexual harassment is about power. When did I have the power? When?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is directed by Barry Levinson and co-adapted to screenplay by Paul Attanasio and Michael Crichton from Crichton's own novel of the same name. It stars Michael Douglas, Demi Moore, Donald Sutherland, Roma Maffia, Dylan Baker, Caroline Goodall and Rosemary Forsyth. Music is scored by Ennio Morricone. Tom Sanders (Douglas) is an executive at DigiCom, a high-tech computer company, who hopes that now it's finally his time to get promotion. Passed over for an outsider, he's further irked when it turns out to be Meredith Johnson (Moore), an old passionate flame of his from years previously. When Meredith arranges for a meeting between the two later that evening, Tom finds himself sexually harassed by her. Spurning her aggressive overtures, Tom is shocked to learn the next day that she has filed a charge of sexual harassment against him. He naturally counters the charge, but this opens up a can of worms for both him and the future of DigiCom. The 1990s practically belonged to Michael Crichton, it seemed for a time that everything he wrote was adapted to the big screen for some form of entertainment. With Jurassic Park still warm and still garnering bucket loads of cash, two other Crichton adaptations worked their way into theatres; both of which were a world away from the family friendly extravaganza of Jurassic Park. One was Rising Sun, a messy wasted potential of a movie, the other was Disclosure, a zeitgeist snatcher that seized the moment. The topic, and the novelty of flipping the gender aggressor, was always going to make Disclosure of much interest, thus the film and the novel made big money: aided still further by the hot casting of Douglas and Moore, who were still draw cards in the early 90s. Crichton, after being displeased with other adaptations of his work, got big say on the screenplay as a written project. So with director Levinson in tow, he set about pushing the buttons of his audience, attempting to continue the heated debates that were brought about previously from Douglas' Fatal Attraction and Basic Instinct. If it's Crichton's or Levinson's fault that it didn't work out that way? I'm not sure, but fact is, is that Disclosure really wasn't that potent back then, and certainly now it's not even lukewarm. There's too much techno babble going on, and an over keenness to stick the nose up at the big business vultures picking the flesh off of the lesser minions. Entering the last half hour of the film, it's easy to forget there has actually been a sexual harassment case! Here's the crux of the matter, if going in to it for a first time viewing expecting this to be a powder-keg of sexual harassment muckiness and legal intrigue, then you are in for a big disappointment. I know, because I was one of the paying patrons at the theatre back in 94! You sense that one of the makers got a bit carried away Yet the film still has much going for it if stripped of that expectation, not least that it packs a pile of tension in that last half hour and the finale is rather rewarding. I'd go as far to say I'm a fan of the film, but it's not the film I originally went to see! There's a trio of interesting and differing female characters at the front of the narrative, even if Moore's stair-master vixen isn't exactly developed beyond being a bitch, and the virtual reality sequences have an appealing charm about them. The cast are turning in good ones, with a notable shout out to Caroline Goodall who wisely underplays it as the wife. While the interior set design (Gary Lewis/Joseph Hodges) for the DigiCom HQ is wonderful with its 90s excess of glass meeting mirrors and open spaces. Which leaves us with what? A film that is not what you expect! Which in this case is both disappointing and a surprise. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stand-alone thriller with a mish-mash of intriguing themes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tale of sexual harassment in the office with a twist  this time, the guy is the victim and the woman the pursuer. Yes, it's another thriller that builds on Michael Douglas's typecasting as a victim of powerful women (following FATAL ATTRACTION and BASIC INSTINCT) but this one plays all the right cards. Part workplace drama, part courtroom thriller, and all the time invested with now-dated-but-then-cutting-edge technology (email, virtual reality) I found Disclosure to be never less than intriguing and well made. The Crichton source material helps, of course; I haven't yet seen a Crichton film that hasn't been thought-provoking and entertaining (even the worst, CONGO, isn't entirely without merit, although the book is loads better). I've been seeing a lot of Douglas in recent months and my opinion of him has steadily improved to the degree that I can't remember him giving a bad performance. He's fine here, providing a key likable anchor for the film to revolve around, and playing opposite him Demi Moore is also a surprise: she oozes sexuality and selfishness in equal measure, proving a powerful enemy at all times. Moore isn't the world's greatest actress but this might well be her best performance in a film. The courtroom scenes, tense and full of electricity, are undoubtedly the film's highlights and there are supporting actors to relish (Donald Sutherland, Allan Rich and in particular a slimy Dylan Baker). It's not a perfect film, but it is a reminder of the kind of solid, sensual thriller that got made during a sometimes forgotten decade of filmmaking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corporate Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays Tom Sanders, a successful computer specialist working for a big firm who is passed over for promotion in favor of an old flame named Meredith Johnson(played by Demi Moore). She is very ambitious, and seems to have undue influence over the CEO, which proves to be the case as Meredith tries to seduce Tom after hours in her office. Tom, a happily married man, is tempted by her beauty, but resists. He is later shocked to learn that she has reported him for sexual harassment, so he has no choice but to sue her, which endangers his future within the company, but Tom will discover that things are not as simple as they seem, and Meredith has another agenda at work... Based on Michael Crichton's novel, and well directed by Barry Levinson, this features fine acting by its stars, and a fascinating story with many twists and turns, that leads to a satisfying finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Naked Truth...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cronostitan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the specialist of the trendy thriller, this movie rather well pinned also speaks about the difficult square in the society that all those can occupy sometimes who do not enough sit - at least not endowed with varied and diverse protections. What it will be necessary to raise it is that Crichton dodges these long sequences of court with strong theatrical echo which we undergo very often among soaps in the TV (and also in John Grisham's books and in adventures of the TV show Ally Mc Beal), instead of it he joins in the life the office among this great number of "small" details that all those sometimes forget who do not work: another tour de force very rich in teaching... Because freedom is also a question of money although people are not globally more free than before in the old time, it is simply wrong!! Careful thus in "politically correct" falsified, in the traps, in the blackmail, in the propaganda, in the jealousy...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full disclosure: this movie stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suppose the idea of Michael Douglas being sexually harassed by Demi Moore could be intriguing. Could be. But in this movie it doesn't end up being intriguing at all. The story fizzles out before it ever really gets going. The movie goes on and on without ever really going anywhere. There's no spark, no sizzle. Attempts at humor fall horribly flat. The only laughs in this movie come from laughing at just how bad it is, most notably in the big climactic virtual reality scene. Wait, big climactic virtual reality scene? Yeah, it's just as stupid as it sounds, an awful idea executed so badly you can't help but laugh at how truly terrible it is. This is a movie which fails in pretty much every way possible. Douglas plays Tom Sanders, the head of production at some high-tech Seattle outfit. There's a big merger on the horizon, Tom expects a big promotion to go with it. But the job he covets goes to Meredith Johnson, a one-time girlfriend of his who celebrates their reunion by trying to rape him in her office. When Tom says no, not before having a little fun of course because the movie needs its obligatory sex scene, Meredith promises to ruin him. And the next day she duly accuses him of sexual harassment. He gets himself a lawyer, accuses her and it's a big he-said, she-said deal which only serves to bore those of us who are unfortunate enough to be watching. Drama and tension are in very short supply. Tedium is the order of the day. Moore's absolutely atrocious acting doesn't help matters. My goodness, she is terrible. The story slogs along, everyone ganging up on poor Tom in some horribly uninteresting conspiracy. It's not just Meredith out to get him, this goes all the way up to the big boss at the top. That character, played by Donald Sutherland, is I suppose meant to seem sinister but the way Sutherland mugs and overacts he just comes off as a buffoon. Just another example of the way this movie completely misses the mark. And just when you think it can't possibly get any worse along comes that absurd virtual reality scene which is simply one of the dumbest things ever seen in any movie. Even after that laughable "climax" the movie doesn't have the decency to just end. More pointless, boring twists to come. The whole thing is just interminable. Movies don't get much worse than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Douglas contends with business foe Demi Moore determined to oust him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Disclosure" is a smoothly done, pleasurable and suspenseful watch in which the action never flags. This is a good solid Hollywood product by all involved. Michael Douglas does his usual fine job -- he makes look easy what is not at all easy -- playing a Silicon Valley production specialist. For reasons unknown, the production line product is failing while the prototypes work. He is being made to look incompetent. Meanwhile, he has a new boss, Demi Moore, who was his old flame. And the big boss, Donald Sutherland, is negotiating a merger that will enrich everyone in the firm, stock options and all that. Preventing Douglas from tracking down the production line issues in Malaysia are this merger and Moore's plot to accuse Douglas of sexual harassment. Douglas fights back, without anger and bitterness, by mediation, accusing her correctly of harassing him. Meanwhile, he's trying to figure out how production has gone wrong. In the narrow world of an operations specialist, he doesn't suspect behind the scenes machinations. But he has a "friend" higher up (a guardian angel) who does, and who spurs him on via anonymous e-mails to dig deeper. As the merger pressures those around him, all of whom stand to gain handsomely by stock options, he finds his associates melting away and, more or less, siding with pressures brought by Sutherland to get Douglas to paper over the production issues. Sutherland absolutely looks the part and steals every scene he is in. His part in all this is ambiguous enough that he can bob and weave and land on his feet. He's a slick one. He didn't get to head the company without this skill. And so we enter the world of Silicon Valley too, and that's part of the movie's charm. The interior sets of the business itself bring this to life, and complement the business rivalries and machinations. The 128m running time passes quickly. Douglas learns a thing or two. The supporting roles are well cast and played. The movie is a business thriller, with the emphasis on emotional pressures, calculation, and psychological conflicts that bring out the varying personalities and motivations of those involved. Dramatic elements are present but not over-emphasized.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demi Moore As A Femme Fatale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is a thriller directed by Barry Levinson that stars Michael Douglas and Demi Moore. It is based on Michael Crichton's novel of the same title.The cast also includes Donald Sutherland, Rosemary Forsyth and Dennis Miller.The film is a combination mystery and thriller about office politics and intrigue in the computer industry in the mid-1990s. Also,it includes the issue of sexual harassment. Tom Sanders is an executive at DigiCom, a leading computer software firm. The company is about to launch a new virtual reality-based data storage system that is expected to revolutionize the industry, and Bob Garvin, the owner of the company, is in the midst of negotiating a merger that could bring $100 million into the firm. However, while Tom is expecting a promotion, he discovers the position has been given instead to a new hire, Meredith Johnson, with whom Tom had an affair years ago, before he was married. After her first day of work, Meredith invites Tom up to her office and makes a concerted attempt to seduce him; while Tom doesn't fight off her advances with very much gusto at first, eventually he decides things have gone too far and leaves in a huff. The next morning, Meredith accuses Tom of sexual harassment, and he realizes this was merely a power ploy to get him out of DigiCom for good; Tom, determined to fight, files a counter-suit, which makes him no friends at the company, since rocking the boat too hard could very well scotch the merger. The story takes some clever twists and turns as it develops into a full- fledged psychological thriller that is effective and gripping, if occasionally contrived as a result of over-plotting.The film is genuinely gripping and well-written.As for the performances,Moore makes an awesome femme fatale while Douglas triumps over evil in a big way.But it is a watchable film as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Crichton winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) not only finds himself passed over for an expected promotion, but his new boss turns out to be an old flame, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). When Meredith makes strong overtures to him, Tom initially goes along, only to refuse her. Furious at his rejection, Meredith accuses him of sexual harassment, so he makes a counter-accusation. Set against the corporate and executive positioning of a complex business deal, Michael Crichton's story (oh how we miss that man's creative output) strikes an interesting balance between techno-thriller, sexual politics commentary, courtroom drama, and urban paranoia thriller. The story is terrific - complex but always followable, gripping and involving, and with emotional ramifications as the essentially decent and blameless Sanders finds himself in an impossible situation. This is a good film, with one of the best payoffs ever, and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the book. No good comes from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everybody's out to get Michael Douglas. Marketed as a controversial examination of a man's charge of sexual harassment against a female co-worker, "Disclosure" is really about paranoia. The reverse discrimination angle is a (albeit large) plot point, but it isn't the crux of the movie. Which is where the movie takes a sharp turn off a cliff. Douglas is a software engineer for a large corporation, and he's been turned down for the big promotion - in favor of a man-eating former lover (Demi Moore). Moore, the new V.P. invites Douglas to her office for a catch-up session, and things get downright steamy. But Douglas is a family man, and he walks away from an enraged (rebuffed) Moore. The next day, Douglas walks into the office to the accusation that he was the one doing the harassing. A very large chunk of the movie is devoted to the harassment charge, with Douglas calling in the help of a media-hungry lawyer (Roma Maffia) to help him with his case. Sordid details emerge, cracks appear in the Douglas household, and and it's not a pretty skirmish. But Moore is just a cog in a larger scheme to eventually make Douglas look incompetent and throw him out on the street. That's what this movie is really about: Douglas is worried about his job. It's all a very conspiratorial and manipulative oppression of the poor white family man, complete with hushed voices in the office. Throw in some deliciously early '90s CGI and a ridiculously lame virtual reality subplot, and you've got the market fresh makings of an overly- long film that never rises above goofy. 3/10; a real chore
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Office Politics, Paranoia & The Abuse Of Power
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the 1990s when an increasing number of women were filling top jobs in the corporate world, a story about a woman sexually harassing a man became a plausible scenario and the topical and controversial nature of the subject resonated strongly enough with the public at that time to make "Disclosure" a great box office success. Whilst the sexual harassment element of the story was shocking and attention grabbing, it soon became apparent that this was just part of a far larger and more pervasive issue i.e. the abuse of power. In the workplace, where social conventions, various legal constraints and political correctness all come into play, there is still no escape from the kind of management conspiracies, office politics and duplicity which are depicted so effectively in "Disclosure" or the kinds of distrust and paranoia that they can so easily generate. Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) heads one of the divisions of a Seattle computer company and is engaged in the development of a product which is vitally important to the success of a planned and very lucrative merger with another company. There are some problems with the product which Tom and his team are currently dealing with and are under considerable pressure to resolve. As a result of some changes which are taking place within the company, Tom's confident that he'll be promoted but it soon transpires that he's been passed over and the job has been given to one of his ex-girlfriends, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). On her first day in the job, Meredith arranges a late meeting with Tom to discuss his division's work but during their meeting she aggressively tries to seduce him and is furious when, after a considerable struggle, she's unsuccessful. Meredith responds to Tom's rejection by accusing him of sexual harassment and asserting that in the circumstances, there's no way that she'd be able to work with him again. The company want to avoid any publicity that could have an adverse impact on the upcoming merger and so try to get Tom to take a transfer to another job in their Austin branch. He can't countenance this idea because of the negative effect it would have on his career and is in a very tight spot. Help unexpectedly arrives in the form of an anonymous e-mail which recommends that he consult an attorney called Catherine Alvarez (Roma Maffia) who's a specialist in sexual harassment cases. Tom decides to fight back and files a counter-suit. The process he has to go through to achieve justice is difficult and painful but irrefutable proof of his innocence is produced and the company agrees to retain him and give him a pay rise. The relief that Tom feels after being cleared of the charges against him is short lived as it quickly becomes apparent that efforts which were originally initiated by Meredith to make him look incompetent have now drawn wider support and he's being set up to be publicly humiliated and undermined at a high profile shareholders' meeting. The way in which Tom copes with this threat then provides the story with its intriguing conclusion. The events in "Disclosure" all take place within the space of one intense week in which Tom's normally affluent and comfortable lifestyle is disrupted as his disappointment at being passed over for promotion turns into discomfort when he discovers the identity of his new boss and then horror as he's threatened with the loss of his job, his wife, his family and his stock options. The false accusation made against him, the plots to make him look incompetent and a workplace where no one can be trusted, create a climate of paranoia which is reinforced when some of his previous innocent actions are characterised as something more sinister and the support of his colleagues is systematically eroded by those high up in the company structure. Michael Douglas gives a good solid performance as the beleaguered Tom and Demi Moore is marvellous as the cold and cruel villain of the piece. Donald Sutherland and Roma Maffia also stand out in their supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexual harassment is about power. When did I have the power? When?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is directed by Barry Levinson and co-adapted to screenplay by Paul Attanasio and Michael Crichton from Crichton's own novel of the same name. It stars Michael Douglas, Demi Moore, Donald Sutherland, Roma Maffia, Dylan Baker, Caroline Goodall and Rosemary Forsyth. Music is scored by Ennio Morricone. Tom Sanders (Douglas) is an executive at DigiCom, a high-tech computer company, who hopes that now it's finally his time to get promotion. Passed over for an outsider, he's further irked when it turns out to be Meredith Johnson (Moore), an old passionate flame of his from years previously. When Meredith arranges for a meeting between the two later that evening, Tom finds himself sexually harassed by her. Spurning her aggressive overtures, Tom is shocked to learn the next day that she has filed a charge of sexual harassment against him. He naturally counters the charge, but this opens up a can of worms for both him and the future of DigiCom. The 1990s practically belonged to Michael Crichton, it seemed for a time that everything he wrote was adapted to the big screen for some form of entertainment. With Jurassic Park still warm and still garnering bucket loads of cash, two other Crichton adaptations worked their way into theatres; both of which were a world away from the family friendly extravaganza of Jurassic Park. One was Rising Sun, a messy wasted potential of a movie, the other was Disclosure, a zeitgeist snatcher that seized the moment. The topic, and the novelty of flipping the gender aggressor, was always going to make Disclosure of much interest, thus the film and the novel made big money: aided still further by the hot casting of Douglas and Moore, who were still draw cards in the early 90s. Crichton, after being displeased with other adaptations of his work, got big say on the screenplay as a written project. So with director Levinson in tow, he set about pushing the buttons of his audience, attempting to continue the heated debates that were brought about previously from Douglas' Fatal Attraction and Basic Instinct. If it's Crichton's or Levinson's fault that it didn't work out that way? I'm not sure, but fact is, is that Disclosure really wasn't that potent back then, and certainly now it's not even lukewarm. There's too much techno babble going on, and an over keenness to stick the nose up at the big business vultures picking the flesh off of the lesser minions. Entering the last half hour of the film, it's easy to forget there has actually been a sexual harassment case! Here's the crux of the matter, if going in to it for a first time viewing expecting this to be a powder-keg of sexual harassment muckiness and legal intrigue, then you are in for a big disappointment. I know, because I was one of the paying patrons at the theatre back in 94! You sense that one of the makers got a bit carried away Yet the film still has much going for it if stripped of that expectation, not least that it packs a pile of tension in that last half hour and the finale is rather rewarding. I'd go as far to say I'm a fan of the film, but it's not the film I originally went to see! There's a trio of interesting and differing female characters at the front of the narrative, even if Moore's stair-master vixen isn't exactly developed beyond being a bitch, and the virtual reality sequences have an appealing charm about them. The cast are turning in good ones, with a notable shout out to Caroline Goodall who wisely underplays it as the wife. While the interior set design (Gary Lewis/Joseph Hodges) for the DigiCom HQ is wonderful with its 90s excess of glass meeting mirrors and open spaces. Which leaves us with what? A film that is not what you expect! Which in this case is both disappointing and a surprise. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stand-alone thriller with a mish-mash of intriguing themes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tale of sexual harassment in the office with a twist  this time, the guy is the victim and the woman the pursuer. Yes, it's another thriller that builds on Michael Douglas's typecasting as a victim of powerful women (following FATAL ATTRACTION and BASIC INSTINCT) but this one plays all the right cards. Part workplace drama, part courtroom thriller, and all the time invested with now-dated-but-then-cutting-edge technology (email, virtual reality) I found Disclosure to be never less than intriguing and well made. The Crichton source material helps, of course; I haven't yet seen a Crichton film that hasn't been thought-provoking and entertaining (even the worst, CONGO, isn't entirely without merit, although the book is loads better). I've been seeing a lot of Douglas in recent months and my opinion of him has steadily improved to the degree that I can't remember him giving a bad performance. He's fine here, providing a key likable anchor for the film to revolve around, and playing opposite him Demi Moore is also a surprise: she oozes sexuality and selfishness in equal measure, proving a powerful enemy at all times. Moore isn't the world's greatest actress but this might well be her best performance in a film. The courtroom scenes, tense and full of electricity, are undoubtedly the film's highlights and there are supporting actors to relish (Donald Sutherland, Allan Rich and in particular a slimy Dylan Baker). It's not a perfect film, but it is a reminder of the kind of solid, sensual thriller that got made during a sometimes forgotten decade of filmmaking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corporate Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays Tom Sanders, a successful computer specialist working for a big firm who is passed over for promotion in favor of an old flame named Meredith Johnson(played by Demi Moore). She is very ambitious, and seems to have undue influence over the CEO, which proves to be the case as Meredith tries to seduce Tom after hours in her office. Tom, a happily married man, is tempted by her beauty, but resists. He is later shocked to learn that she has reported him for sexual harassment, so he has no choice but to sue her, which endangers his future within the company, but Tom will discover that things are not as simple as they seem, and Meredith has another agenda at work... Based on Michael Crichton's novel, and well directed by Barry Levinson, this features fine acting by its stars, and a fascinating story with many twists and turns, that leads to a satisfying finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Naked Truth...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cronostitan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the specialist of the trendy thriller, this movie rather well pinned also speaks about the difficult square in the society that all those can occupy sometimes who do not enough sit - at least not endowed with varied and diverse protections. What it will be necessary to raise it is that Crichton dodges these long sequences of court with strong theatrical echo which we undergo very often among soaps in the TV (and also in John Grisham's books and in adventures of the TV show Ally Mc Beal), instead of it he joins in the life the office among this great number of "small" details that all those sometimes forget who do not work: another tour de force very rich in teaching... Because freedom is also a question of money although people are not globally more free than before in the old time, it is simply wrong!! Careful thus in "politically correct" falsified, in the traps, in the blackmail, in the propaganda, in the jealousy...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full disclosure: this movie stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suppose the idea of Michael Douglas being sexually harassed by Demi Moore could be intriguing. Could be. But in this movie it doesn't end up being intriguing at all. The story fizzles out before it ever really gets going. The movie goes on and on without ever really going anywhere. There's no spark, no sizzle. Attempts at humor fall horribly flat. The only laughs in this movie come from laughing at just how bad it is, most notably in the big climactic virtual reality scene. Wait, big climactic virtual reality scene? Yeah, it's just as stupid as it sounds, an awful idea executed so badly you can't help but laugh at how truly terrible it is. This is a movie which fails in pretty much every way possible. Douglas plays Tom Sanders, the head of production at some high-tech Seattle outfit. There's a big merger on the horizon, Tom expects a big promotion to go with it. But the job he covets goes to Meredith Johnson, a one-time girlfriend of his who celebrates their reunion by trying to rape him in her office. When Tom says no, not before having a little fun of course because the movie needs its obligatory sex scene, Meredith promises to ruin him. And the next day she duly accuses him of sexual harassment. He gets himself a lawyer, accuses her and it's a big he-said, she-said deal which only serves to bore those of us who are unfortunate enough to be watching. Drama and tension are in very short supply. Tedium is the order of the day. Moore's absolutely atrocious acting doesn't help matters. My goodness, she is terrible. The story slogs along, everyone ganging up on poor Tom in some horribly uninteresting conspiracy. It's not just Meredith out to get him, this goes all the way up to the big boss at the top. That character, played by Donald Sutherland, is I suppose meant to seem sinister but the way Sutherland mugs and overacts he just comes off as a buffoon. Just another example of the way this movie completely misses the mark. And just when you think it can't possibly get any worse along comes that absurd virtual reality scene which is simply one of the dumbest things ever seen in any movie. Even after that laughable "climax" the movie doesn't have the decency to just end. More pointless, boring twists to come. The whole thing is just interminable. Movies don't get much worse than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Douglas contends with business foe Demi Moore determined to oust him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Disclosure" is a smoothly done, pleasurable and suspenseful watch in which the action never flags. This is a good solid Hollywood product by all involved. Michael Douglas does his usual fine job -- he makes look easy what is not at all easy -- playing a Silicon Valley production specialist. For reasons unknown, the production line product is failing while the prototypes work. He is being made to look incompetent. Meanwhile, he has a new boss, Demi Moore, who was his old flame. And the big boss, Donald Sutherland, is negotiating a merger that will enrich everyone in the firm, stock options and all that. Preventing Douglas from tracking down the production line issues in Malaysia are this merger and Moore's plot to accuse Douglas of sexual harassment. Douglas fights back, without anger and bitterness, by mediation, accusing her correctly of harassing him. Meanwhile, he's trying to figure out how production has gone wrong. In the narrow world of an operations specialist, he doesn't suspect behind the scenes machinations. But he has a "friend" higher up (a guardian angel) who does, and who spurs him on via anonymous e-mails to dig deeper. As the merger pressures those around him, all of whom stand to gain handsomely by stock options, he finds his associates melting away and, more or less, siding with pressures brought by Sutherland to get Douglas to paper over the production issues. Sutherland absolutely looks the part and steals every scene he is in. His part in all this is ambiguous enough that he can bob and weave and land on his feet. He's a slick one. He didn't get to head the company without this skill. And so we enter the world of Silicon Valley too, and that's part of the movie's charm. The interior sets of the business itself bring this to life, and complement the business rivalries and machinations. The 128m running time passes quickly. Douglas learns a thing or two. The supporting roles are well cast and played. The movie is a business thriller, with the emphasis on emotional pressures, calculation, and psychological conflicts that bring out the varying personalities and motivations of those involved. Dramatic elements are present but not over-emphasized.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demi Moore As A Femme Fatale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is a thriller directed by Barry Levinson that stars Michael Douglas and Demi Moore. It is based on Michael Crichton's novel of the same title.The cast also includes Donald Sutherland, Rosemary Forsyth and Dennis Miller.The film is a combination mystery and thriller about office politics and intrigue in the computer industry in the mid-1990s. Also,it includes the issue of sexual harassment. Tom Sanders is an executive at DigiCom, a leading computer software firm. The company is about to launch a new virtual reality-based data storage system that is expected to revolutionize the industry, and Bob Garvin, the owner of the company, is in the midst of negotiating a merger that could bring $100 million into the firm. However, while Tom is expecting a promotion, he discovers the position has been given instead to a new hire, Meredith Johnson, with whom Tom had an affair years ago, before he was married. After her first day of work, Meredith invites Tom up to her office and makes a concerted attempt to seduce him; while Tom doesn't fight off her advances with very much gusto at first, eventually he decides things have gone too far and leaves in a huff. The next morning, Meredith accuses Tom of sexual harassment, and he realizes this was merely a power ploy to get him out of DigiCom for good; Tom, determined to fight, files a counter-suit, which makes him no friends at the company, since rocking the boat too hard could very well scotch the merger. The story takes some clever twists and turns as it develops into a full- fledged psychological thriller that is effective and gripping, if occasionally contrived as a result of over-plotting.The film is genuinely gripping and well-written.As for the performances,Moore makes an awesome femme fatale while Douglas triumps over evil in a big way.But it is a watchable film as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Crichton winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) not only finds himself passed over for an expected promotion, but his new boss turns out to be an old flame, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). When Meredith makes strong overtures to him, Tom initially goes along, only to refuse her. Furious at his rejection, Meredith accuses him of sexual harassment, so he makes a counter-accusation. Set against the corporate and executive positioning of a complex business deal, Michael Crichton's story (oh how we miss that man's creative output) strikes an interesting balance between techno-thriller, sexual politics commentary, courtroom drama, and urban paranoia thriller. The story is terrific - complex but always followable, gripping and involving, and with emotional ramifications as the essentially decent and blameless Sanders finds himself in an impossible situation. This is a good film, with one of the best payoffs ever, and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the book. No good comes from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everybody's out to get Michael Douglas. Marketed as a controversial examination of a man's charge of sexual harassment against a female co-worker, "Disclosure" is really about paranoia. The reverse discrimination angle is a (albeit large) plot point, but it isn't the crux of the movie. Which is where the movie takes a sharp turn off a cliff. Douglas is a software engineer for a large corporation, and he's been turned down for the big promotion - in favor of a man-eating former lover (Demi Moore). Moore, the new V.P. invites Douglas to her office for a catch-up session, and things get downright steamy. But Douglas is a family man, and he walks away from an enraged (rebuffed) Moore. The next day, Douglas walks into the office to the accusation that he was the one doing the harassing. A very large chunk of the movie is devoted to the harassment charge, with Douglas calling in the help of a media-hungry lawyer (Roma Maffia) to help him with his case. Sordid details emerge, cracks appear in the Douglas household, and and it's not a pretty skirmish. But Moore is just a cog in a larger scheme to eventually make Douglas look incompetent and throw him out on the street. That's what this movie is really about: Douglas is worried about his job. It's all a very conspiratorial and manipulative oppression of the poor white family man, complete with hushed voices in the office. Throw in some deliciously early '90s CGI and a ridiculously lame virtual reality subplot, and you've got the market fresh makings of an overly- long film that never rises above goofy. 3/10; a real chore
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Office Politics, Paranoia & The Abuse Of Power
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the 1990s when an increasing number of women were filling top jobs in the corporate world, a story about a woman sexually harassing a man became a plausible scenario and the topical and controversial nature of the subject resonated strongly enough with the public at that time to make "Disclosure" a great box office success. Whilst the sexual harassment element of the story was shocking and attention grabbing, it soon became apparent that this was just part of a far larger and more pervasive issue i.e. the abuse of power. In the workplace, where social conventions, various legal constraints and political correctness all come into play, there is still no escape from the kind of management conspiracies, office politics and duplicity which are depicted so effectively in "Disclosure" or the kinds of distrust and paranoia that they can so easily generate. Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) heads one of the divisions of a Seattle computer company and is engaged in the development of a product which is vitally important to the success of a planned and very lucrative merger with another company. There are some problems with the product which Tom and his team are currently dealing with and are under considerable pressure to resolve. As a result of some changes which are taking place within the company, Tom's confident that he'll be promoted but it soon transpires that he's been passed over and the job has been given to one of his ex-girlfriends, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). On her first day in the job, Meredith arranges a late meeting with Tom to discuss his division's work but during their meeting she aggressively tries to seduce him and is furious when, after a considerable struggle, she's unsuccessful. Meredith responds to Tom's rejection by accusing him of sexual harassment and asserting that in the circumstances, there's no way that she'd be able to work with him again. The company want to avoid any publicity that could have an adverse impact on the upcoming merger and so try to get Tom to take a transfer to another job in their Austin branch. He can't countenance this idea because of the negative effect it would have on his career and is in a very tight spot. Help unexpectedly arrives in the form of an anonymous e-mail which recommends that he consult an attorney called Catherine Alvarez (Roma Maffia) who's a specialist in sexual harassment cases. Tom decides to fight back and files a counter-suit. The process he has to go through to achieve justice is difficult and painful but irrefutable proof of his innocence is produced and the company agrees to retain him and give him a pay rise. The relief that Tom feels after being cleared of the charges against him is short lived as it quickly becomes apparent that efforts which were originally initiated by Meredith to make him look incompetent have now drawn wider support and he's being set up to be publicly humiliated and undermined at a high profile shareholders' meeting. The way in which Tom copes with this threat then provides the story with its intriguing conclusion. The events in "Disclosure" all take place within the space of one intense week in which Tom's normally affluent and comfortable lifestyle is disrupted as his disappointment at being passed over for promotion turns into discomfort when he discovers the identity of his new boss and then horror as he's threatened with the loss of his job, his wife, his family and his stock options. The false accusation made against him, the plots to make him look incompetent and a workplace where no one can be trusted, create a climate of paranoia which is reinforced when some of his previous innocent actions are characterised as something more sinister and the support of his colleagues is systematically eroded by those high up in the company structure. Michael Douglas gives a good solid performance as the beleaguered Tom and Demi Moore is marvellous as the cold and cruel villain of the piece. Donald Sutherland and Roma Maffia also stand out in their supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexual harassment is about power. When did I have the power? When?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is directed by Barry Levinson and co-adapted to screenplay by Paul Attanasio and Michael Crichton from Crichton's own novel of the same name. It stars Michael Douglas, Demi Moore, Donald Sutherland, Roma Maffia, Dylan Baker, Caroline Goodall and Rosemary Forsyth. Music is scored by Ennio Morricone. Tom Sanders (Douglas) is an executive at DigiCom, a high-tech computer company, who hopes that now it's finally his time to get promotion. Passed over for an outsider, he's further irked when it turns out to be Meredith Johnson (Moore), an old passionate flame of his from years previously. When Meredith arranges for a meeting between the two later that evening, Tom finds himself sexually harassed by her. Spurning her aggressive overtures, Tom is shocked to learn the next day that she has filed a charge of sexual harassment against him. He naturally counters the charge, but this opens up a can of worms for both him and the future of DigiCom. The 1990s practically belonged to Michael Crichton, it seemed for a time that everything he wrote was adapted to the big screen for some form of entertainment. With Jurassic Park still warm and still garnering bucket loads of cash, two other Crichton adaptations worked their way into theatres; both of which were a world away from the family friendly extravaganza of Jurassic Park. One was Rising Sun, a messy wasted potential of a movie, the other was Disclosure, a zeitgeist snatcher that seized the moment. The topic, and the novelty of flipping the gender aggressor, was always going to make Disclosure of much interest, thus the film and the novel made big money: aided still further by the hot casting of Douglas and Moore, who were still draw cards in the early 90s. Crichton, after being displeased with other adaptations of his work, got big say on the screenplay as a written project. So with director Levinson in tow, he set about pushing the buttons of his audience, attempting to continue the heated debates that were brought about previously from Douglas' Fatal Attraction and Basic Instinct. If it's Crichton's or Levinson's fault that it didn't work out that way? I'm not sure, but fact is, is that Disclosure really wasn't that potent back then, and certainly now it's not even lukewarm. There's too much techno babble going on, and an over keenness to stick the nose up at the big business vultures picking the flesh off of the lesser minions. Entering the last half hour of the film, it's easy to forget there has actually been a sexual harassment case! Here's the crux of the matter, if going in to it for a first time viewing expecting this to be a powder-keg of sexual harassment muckiness and legal intrigue, then you are in for a big disappointment. I know, because I was one of the paying patrons at the theatre back in 94! You sense that one of the makers got a bit carried away Yet the film still has much going for it if stripped of that expectation, not least that it packs a pile of tension in that last half hour and the finale is rather rewarding. I'd go as far to say I'm a fan of the film, but it's not the film I originally went to see! There's a trio of interesting and differing female characters at the front of the narrative, even if Moore's stair-master vixen isn't exactly developed beyond being a bitch, and the virtual reality sequences have an appealing charm about them. The cast are turning in good ones, with a notable shout out to Caroline Goodall who wisely underplays it as the wife. While the interior set design (Gary Lewis/Joseph Hodges) for the DigiCom HQ is wonderful with its 90s excess of glass meeting mirrors and open spaces. Which leaves us with what? A film that is not what you expect! Which in this case is both disappointing and a surprise. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stand-alone thriller with a mish-mash of intriguing themes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tale of sexual harassment in the office with a twist  this time, the guy is the victim and the woman the pursuer. Yes, it's another thriller that builds on Michael Douglas's typecasting as a victim of powerful women (following FATAL ATTRACTION and BASIC INSTINCT) but this one plays all the right cards. Part workplace drama, part courtroom thriller, and all the time invested with now-dated-but-then-cutting-edge technology (email, virtual reality) I found Disclosure to be never less than intriguing and well made. The Crichton source material helps, of course; I haven't yet seen a Crichton film that hasn't been thought-provoking and entertaining (even the worst, CONGO, isn't entirely without merit, although the book is loads better). I've been seeing a lot of Douglas in recent months and my opinion of him has steadily improved to the degree that I can't remember him giving a bad performance. He's fine here, providing a key likable anchor for the film to revolve around, and playing opposite him Demi Moore is also a surprise: she oozes sexuality and selfishness in equal measure, proving a powerful enemy at all times. Moore isn't the world's greatest actress but this might well be her best performance in a film. The courtroom scenes, tense and full of electricity, are undoubtedly the film's highlights and there are supporting actors to relish (Donald Sutherland, Allan Rich and in particular a slimy Dylan Baker). It's not a perfect film, but it is a reminder of the kind of solid, sensual thriller that got made during a sometimes forgotten decade of filmmaking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corporate Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays Tom Sanders, a successful computer specialist working for a big firm who is passed over for promotion in favor of an old flame named Meredith Johnson(played by Demi Moore). She is very ambitious, and seems to have undue influence over the CEO, which proves to be the case as Meredith tries to seduce Tom after hours in her office. Tom, a happily married man, is tempted by her beauty, but resists. He is later shocked to learn that she has reported him for sexual harassment, so he has no choice but to sue her, which endangers his future within the company, but Tom will discover that things are not as simple as they seem, and Meredith has another agenda at work... Based on Michael Crichton's novel, and well directed by Barry Levinson, this features fine acting by its stars, and a fascinating story with many twists and turns, that leads to a satisfying finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Naked Truth...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cronostitan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the specialist of the trendy thriller, this movie rather well pinned also speaks about the difficult square in the society that all those can occupy sometimes who do not enough sit - at least not endowed with varied and diverse protections. What it will be necessary to raise it is that Crichton dodges these long sequences of court with strong theatrical echo which we undergo very often among soaps in the TV (and also in John Grisham's books and in adventures of the TV show Ally Mc Beal), instead of it he joins in the life the office among this great number of "small" details that all those sometimes forget who do not work: another tour de force very rich in teaching... Because freedom is also a question of money although people are not globally more free than before in the old time, it is simply wrong!! Careful thus in "politically correct" falsified, in the traps, in the blackmail, in the propaganda, in the jealousy...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full disclosure: this movie stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suppose the idea of Michael Douglas being sexually harassed by Demi Moore could be intriguing. Could be. But in this movie it doesn't end up being intriguing at all. The story fizzles out before it ever really gets going. The movie goes on and on without ever really going anywhere. There's no spark, no sizzle. Attempts at humor fall horribly flat. The only laughs in this movie come from laughing at just how bad it is, most notably in the big climactic virtual reality scene. Wait, big climactic virtual reality scene? Yeah, it's just as stupid as it sounds, an awful idea executed so badly you can't help but laugh at how truly terrible it is. This is a movie which fails in pretty much every way possible. Douglas plays Tom Sanders, the head of production at some high-tech Seattle outfit. There's a big merger on the horizon, Tom expects a big promotion to go with it. But the job he covets goes to Meredith Johnson, a one-time girlfriend of his who celebrates their reunion by trying to rape him in her office. When Tom says no, not before having a little fun of course because the movie needs its obligatory sex scene, Meredith promises to ruin him. And the next day she duly accuses him of sexual harassment. He gets himself a lawyer, accuses her and it's a big he-said, she-said deal which only serves to bore those of us who are unfortunate enough to be watching. Drama and tension are in very short supply. Tedium is the order of the day. Moore's absolutely atrocious acting doesn't help matters. My goodness, she is terrible. The story slogs along, everyone ganging up on poor Tom in some horribly uninteresting conspiracy. It's not just Meredith out to get him, this goes all the way up to the big boss at the top. That character, played by Donald Sutherland, is I suppose meant to seem sinister but the way Sutherland mugs and overacts he just comes off as a buffoon. Just another example of the way this movie completely misses the mark. And just when you think it can't possibly get any worse along comes that absurd virtual reality scene which is simply one of the dumbest things ever seen in any movie. Even after that laughable "climax" the movie doesn't have the decency to just end. More pointless, boring twists to come. The whole thing is just interminable. Movies don't get much worse than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Douglas contends with business foe Demi Moore determined to oust him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Disclosure" is a smoothly done, pleasurable and suspenseful watch in which the action never flags. This is a good solid Hollywood product by all involved. Michael Douglas does his usual fine job -- he makes look easy what is not at all easy -- playing a Silicon Valley production specialist. For reasons unknown, the production line product is failing while the prototypes work. He is being made to look incompetent. Meanwhile, he has a new boss, Demi Moore, who was his old flame. And the big boss, Donald Sutherland, is negotiating a merger that will enrich everyone in the firm, stock options and all that. Preventing Douglas from tracking down the production line issues in Malaysia are this merger and Moore's plot to accuse Douglas of sexual harassment. Douglas fights back, without anger and bitterness, by mediation, accusing her correctly of harassing him. Meanwhile, he's trying to figure out how production has gone wrong. In the narrow world of an operations specialist, he doesn't suspect behind the scenes machinations. But he has a "friend" higher up (a guardian angel) who does, and who spurs him on via anonymous e-mails to dig deeper. As the merger pressures those around him, all of whom stand to gain handsomely by stock options, he finds his associates melting away and, more or less, siding with pressures brought by Sutherland to get Douglas to paper over the production issues. Sutherland absolutely looks the part and steals every scene he is in. His part in all this is ambiguous enough that he can bob and weave and land on his feet. He's a slick one. He didn't get to head the company without this skill. And so we enter the world of Silicon Valley too, and that's part of the movie's charm. The interior sets of the business itself bring this to life, and complement the business rivalries and machinations. The 128m running time passes quickly. Douglas learns a thing or two. The supporting roles are well cast and played. The movie is a business thriller, with the emphasis on emotional pressures, calculation, and psychological conflicts that bring out the varying personalities and motivations of those involved. Dramatic elements are present but not over-emphasized.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demi Moore As A Femme Fatale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is a thriller directed by Barry Levinson that stars Michael Douglas and Demi Moore. It is based on Michael Crichton's novel of the same title.The cast also includes Donald Sutherland, Rosemary Forsyth and Dennis Miller.The film is a combination mystery and thriller about office politics and intrigue in the computer industry in the mid-1990s. Also,it includes the issue of sexual harassment. Tom Sanders is an executive at DigiCom, a leading computer software firm. The company is about to launch a new virtual reality-based data storage system that is expected to revolutionize the industry, and Bob Garvin, the owner of the company, is in the midst of negotiating a merger that could bring $100 million into the firm. However, while Tom is expecting a promotion, he discovers the position has been given instead to a new hire, Meredith Johnson, with whom Tom had an affair years ago, before he was married. After her first day of work, Meredith invites Tom up to her office and makes a concerted attempt to seduce him; while Tom doesn't fight off her advances with very much gusto at first, eventually he decides things have gone too far and leaves in a huff. The next morning, Meredith accuses Tom of sexual harassment, and he realizes this was merely a power ploy to get him out of DigiCom for good; Tom, determined to fight, files a counter-suit, which makes him no friends at the company, since rocking the boat too hard could very well scotch the merger. The story takes some clever twists and turns as it develops into a full- fledged psychological thriller that is effective and gripping, if occasionally contrived as a result of over-plotting.The film is genuinely gripping and well-written.As for the performances,Moore makes an awesome femme fatale while Douglas triumps over evil in a big way.But it is a watchable film as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Crichton winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) not only finds himself passed over for an expected promotion, but his new boss turns out to be an old flame, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). When Meredith makes strong overtures to him, Tom initially goes along, only to refuse her. Furious at his rejection, Meredith accuses him of sexual harassment, so he makes a counter-accusation. Set against the corporate and executive positioning of a complex business deal, Michael Crichton's story (oh how we miss that man's creative output) strikes an interesting balance between techno-thriller, sexual politics commentary, courtroom drama, and urban paranoia thriller. The story is terrific - complex but always followable, gripping and involving, and with emotional ramifications as the essentially decent and blameless Sanders finds himself in an impossible situation. This is a good film, with one of the best payoffs ever, and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the book. No good comes from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everybody's out to get Michael Douglas. Marketed as a controversial examination of a man's charge of sexual harassment against a female co-worker, "Disclosure" is really about paranoia. The reverse discrimination angle is a (albeit large) plot point, but it isn't the crux of the movie. Which is where the movie takes a sharp turn off a cliff. Douglas is a software engineer for a large corporation, and he's been turned down for the big promotion - in favor of a man-eating former lover (Demi Moore). Moore, the new V.P. invites Douglas to her office for a catch-up session, and things get downright steamy. But Douglas is a family man, and he walks away from an enraged (rebuffed) Moore. The next day, Douglas walks into the office to the accusation that he was the one doing the harassing. A very large chunk of the movie is devoted to the harassment charge, with Douglas calling in the help of a media-hungry lawyer (Roma Maffia) to help him with his case. Sordid details emerge, cracks appear in the Douglas household, and and it's not a pretty skirmish. But Moore is just a cog in a larger scheme to eventually make Douglas look incompetent and throw him out on the street. That's what this movie is really about: Douglas is worried about his job. It's all a very conspiratorial and manipulative oppression of the poor white family man, complete with hushed voices in the office. Throw in some deliciously early '90s CGI and a ridiculously lame virtual reality subplot, and you've got the market fresh makings of an overly- long film that never rises above goofy. 3/10; a real chore
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Office Politics, Paranoia & The Abuse Of Power
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the 1990s when an increasing number of women were filling top jobs in the corporate world, a story about a woman sexually harassing a man became a plausible scenario and the topical and controversial nature of the subject resonated strongly enough with the public at that time to make "Disclosure" a great box office success. Whilst the sexual harassment element of the story was shocking and attention grabbing, it soon became apparent that this was just part of a far larger and more pervasive issue i.e. the abuse of power. In the workplace, where social conventions, various legal constraints and political correctness all come into play, there is still no escape from the kind of management conspiracies, office politics and duplicity which are depicted so effectively in "Disclosure" or the kinds of distrust and paranoia that they can so easily generate. Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) heads one of the divisions of a Seattle computer company and is engaged in the development of a product which is vitally important to the success of a planned and very lucrative merger with another company. There are some problems with the product which Tom and his team are currently dealing with and are under considerable pressure to resolve. As a result of some changes which are taking place within the company, Tom's confident that he'll be promoted but it soon transpires that he's been passed over and the job has been given to one of his ex-girlfriends, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). On her first day in the job, Meredith arranges a late meeting with Tom to discuss his division's work but during their meeting she aggressively tries to seduce him and is furious when, after a considerable struggle, she's unsuccessful. Meredith responds to Tom's rejection by accusing him of sexual harassment and asserting that in the circumstances, there's no way that she'd be able to work with him again. The company want to avoid any publicity that could have an adverse impact on the upcoming merger and so try to get Tom to take a transfer to another job in their Austin branch. He can't countenance this idea because of the negative effect it would have on his career and is in a very tight spot. Help unexpectedly arrives in the form of an anonymous e-mail which recommends that he consult an attorney called Catherine Alvarez (Roma Maffia) who's a specialist in sexual harassment cases. Tom decides to fight back and files a counter-suit. The process he has to go through to achieve justice is difficult and painful but irrefutable proof of his innocence is produced and the company agrees to retain him and give him a pay rise. The relief that Tom feels after being cleared of the charges against him is short lived as it quickly becomes apparent that efforts which were originally initiated by Meredith to make him look incompetent have now drawn wider support and he's being set up to be publicly humiliated and undermined at a high profile shareholders' meeting. The way in which Tom copes with this threat then provides the story with its intriguing conclusion. The events in "Disclosure" all take place within the space of one intense week in which Tom's normally affluent and comfortable lifestyle is disrupted as his disappointment at being passed over for promotion turns into discomfort when he discovers the identity of his new boss and then horror as he's threatened with the loss of his job, his wife, his family and his stock options. The false accusation made against him, the plots to make him look incompetent and a workplace where no one can be trusted, create a climate of paranoia which is reinforced when some of his previous innocent actions are characterised as something more sinister and the support of his colleagues is systematically eroded by those high up in the company structure. Michael Douglas gives a good solid performance as the beleaguered Tom and Demi Moore is marvellous as the cold and cruel villain of the piece. Donald Sutherland and Roma Maffia also stand out in their supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexual harassment is about power. When did I have the power? When?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is directed by Barry Levinson and co-adapted to screenplay by Paul Attanasio and Michael Crichton from Crichton's own novel of the same name. It stars Michael Douglas, Demi Moore, Donald Sutherland, Roma Maffia, Dylan Baker, Caroline Goodall and Rosemary Forsyth. Music is scored by Ennio Morricone. Tom Sanders (Douglas) is an executive at DigiCom, a high-tech computer company, who hopes that now it's finally his time to get promotion. Passed over for an outsider, he's further irked when it turns out to be Meredith Johnson (Moore), an old passionate flame of his from years previously. When Meredith arranges for a meeting between the two later that evening, Tom finds himself sexually harassed by her. Spurning her aggressive overtures, Tom is shocked to learn the next day that she has filed a charge of sexual harassment against him. He naturally counters the charge, but this opens up a can of worms for both him and the future of DigiCom. The 1990s practically belonged to Michael Crichton, it seemed for a time that everything he wrote was adapted to the big screen for some form of entertainment. With Jurassic Park still warm and still garnering bucket loads of cash, two other Crichton adaptations worked their way into theatres; both of which were a world away from the family friendly extravaganza of Jurassic Park. One was Rising Sun, a messy wasted potential of a movie, the other was Disclosure, a zeitgeist snatcher that seized the moment. The topic, and the novelty of flipping the gender aggressor, was always going to make Disclosure of much interest, thus the film and the novel made big money: aided still further by the hot casting of Douglas and Moore, who were still draw cards in the early 90s. Crichton, after being displeased with other adaptations of his work, got big say on the screenplay as a written project. So with director Levinson in tow, he set about pushing the buttons of his audience, attempting to continue the heated debates that were brought about previously from Douglas' Fatal Attraction and Basic Instinct. If it's Crichton's or Levinson's fault that it didn't work out that way? I'm not sure, but fact is, is that Disclosure really wasn't that potent back then, and certainly now it's not even lukewarm. There's too much techno babble going on, and an over keenness to stick the nose up at the big business vultures picking the flesh off of the lesser minions. Entering the last half hour of the film, it's easy to forget there has actually been a sexual harassment case! Here's the crux of the matter, if going in to it for a first time viewing expecting this to be a powder-keg of sexual harassment muckiness and legal intrigue, then you are in for a big disappointment. I know, because I was one of the paying patrons at the theatre back in 94! You sense that one of the makers got a bit carried away Yet the film still has much going for it if stripped of that expectation, not least that it packs a pile of tension in that last half hour and the finale is rather rewarding. I'd go as far to say I'm a fan of the film, but it's not the film I originally went to see! There's a trio of interesting and differing female characters at the front of the narrative, even if Moore's stair-master vixen isn't exactly developed beyond being a bitch, and the virtual reality sequences have an appealing charm about them. The cast are turning in good ones, with a notable shout out to Caroline Goodall who wisely underplays it as the wife. While the interior set design (Gary Lewis/Joseph Hodges) for the DigiCom HQ is wonderful with its 90s excess of glass meeting mirrors and open spaces. Which leaves us with what? A film that is not what you expect! Which in this case is both disappointing and a surprise. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stand-alone thriller with a mish-mash of intriguing themes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tale of sexual harassment in the office with a twist  this time, the guy is the victim and the woman the pursuer. Yes, it's another thriller that builds on Michael Douglas's typecasting as a victim of powerful women (following FATAL ATTRACTION and BASIC INSTINCT) but this one plays all the right cards. Part workplace drama, part courtroom thriller, and all the time invested with now-dated-but-then-cutting-edge technology (email, virtual reality) I found Disclosure to be never less than intriguing and well made. The Crichton source material helps, of course; I haven't yet seen a Crichton film that hasn't been thought-provoking and entertaining (even the worst, CONGO, isn't entirely without merit, although the book is loads better). I've been seeing a lot of Douglas in recent months and my opinion of him has steadily improved to the degree that I can't remember him giving a bad performance. He's fine here, providing a key likable anchor for the film to revolve around, and playing opposite him Demi Moore is also a surprise: she oozes sexuality and selfishness in equal measure, proving a powerful enemy at all times. Moore isn't the world's greatest actress but this might well be her best performance in a film. The courtroom scenes, tense and full of electricity, are undoubtedly the film's highlights and there are supporting actors to relish (Donald Sutherland, Allan Rich and in particular a slimy Dylan Baker). It's not a perfect film, but it is a reminder of the kind of solid, sensual thriller that got made during a sometimes forgotten decade of filmmaking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corporate Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays Tom Sanders, a successful computer specialist working for a big firm who is passed over for promotion in favor of an old flame named Meredith Johnson(played by Demi Moore). She is very ambitious, and seems to have undue influence over the CEO, which proves to be the case as Meredith tries to seduce Tom after hours in her office. Tom, a happily married man, is tempted by her beauty, but resists. He is later shocked to learn that she has reported him for sexual harassment, so he has no choice but to sue her, which endangers his future within the company, but Tom will discover that things are not as simple as they seem, and Meredith has another agenda at work... Based on Michael Crichton's novel, and well directed by Barry Levinson, this features fine acting by its stars, and a fascinating story with many twists and turns, that leads to a satisfying finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Naked Truth...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cronostitan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the specialist of the trendy thriller, this movie rather well pinned also speaks about the difficult square in the society that all those can occupy sometimes who do not enough sit - at least not endowed with varied and diverse protections. What it will be necessary to raise it is that Crichton dodges these long sequences of court with strong theatrical echo which we undergo very often among soaps in the TV (and also in John Grisham's books and in adventures of the TV show Ally Mc Beal), instead of it he joins in the life the office among this great number of "small" details that all those sometimes forget who do not work: another tour de force very rich in teaching... Because freedom is also a question of money although people are not globally more free than before in the old time, it is simply wrong!! Careful thus in "politically correct" falsified, in the traps, in the blackmail, in the propaganda, in the jealousy...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full disclosure: this movie stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suppose the idea of Michael Douglas being sexually harassed by Demi Moore could be intriguing. Could be. But in this movie it doesn't end up being intriguing at all. The story fizzles out before it ever really gets going. The movie goes on and on without ever really going anywhere. There's no spark, no sizzle. Attempts at humor fall horribly flat. The only laughs in this movie come from laughing at just how bad it is, most notably in the big climactic virtual reality scene. Wait, big climactic virtual reality scene? Yeah, it's just as stupid as it sounds, an awful idea executed so badly you can't help but laugh at how truly terrible it is. This is a movie which fails in pretty much every way possible. Douglas plays Tom Sanders, the head of production at some high-tech Seattle outfit. There's a big merger on the horizon, Tom expects a big promotion to go with it. But the job he covets goes to Meredith Johnson, a one-time girlfriend of his who celebrates their reunion by trying to rape him in her office. When Tom says no, not before having a little fun of course because the movie needs its obligatory sex scene, Meredith promises to ruin him. And the next day she duly accuses him of sexual harassment. He gets himself a lawyer, accuses her and it's a big he-said, she-said deal which only serves to bore those of us who are unfortunate enough to be watching. Drama and tension are in very short supply. Tedium is the order of the day. Moore's absolutely atrocious acting doesn't help matters. My goodness, she is terrible. The story slogs along, everyone ganging up on poor Tom in some horribly uninteresting conspiracy. It's not just Meredith out to get him, this goes all the way up to the big boss at the top. That character, played by Donald Sutherland, is I suppose meant to seem sinister but the way Sutherland mugs and overacts he just comes off as a buffoon. Just another example of the way this movie completely misses the mark. And just when you think it can't possibly get any worse along comes that absurd virtual reality scene which is simply one of the dumbest things ever seen in any movie. Even after that laughable "climax" the movie doesn't have the decency to just end. More pointless, boring twists to come. The whole thing is just interminable. Movies don't get much worse than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Douglas contends with business foe Demi Moore determined to oust him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Disclosure" is a smoothly done, pleasurable and suspenseful watch in which the action never flags. This is a good solid Hollywood product by all involved. Michael Douglas does his usual fine job -- he makes look easy what is not at all easy -- playing a Silicon Valley production specialist. For reasons unknown, the production line product is failing while the prototypes work. He is being made to look incompetent. Meanwhile, he has a new boss, Demi Moore, who was his old flame. And the big boss, Donald Sutherland, is negotiating a merger that will enrich everyone in the firm, stock options and all that. Preventing Douglas from tracking down the production line issues in Malaysia are this merger and Moore's plot to accuse Douglas of sexual harassment. Douglas fights back, without anger and bitterness, by mediation, accusing her correctly of harassing him. Meanwhile, he's trying to figure out how production has gone wrong. In the narrow world of an operations specialist, he doesn't suspect behind the scenes machinations. But he has a "friend" higher up (a guardian angel) who does, and who spurs him on via anonymous e-mails to dig deeper. As the merger pressures those around him, all of whom stand to gain handsomely by stock options, he finds his associates melting away and, more or less, siding with pressures brought by Sutherland to get Douglas to paper over the production issues. Sutherland absolutely looks the part and steals every scene he is in. His part in all this is ambiguous enough that he can bob and weave and land on his feet. He's a slick one. He didn't get to head the company without this skill. And so we enter the world of Silicon Valley too, and that's part of the movie's charm. The interior sets of the business itself bring this to life, and complement the business rivalries and machinations. The 128m running time passes quickly. Douglas learns a thing or two. The supporting roles are well cast and played. The movie is a business thriller, with the emphasis on emotional pressures, calculation, and psychological conflicts that bring out the varying personalities and motivations of those involved. Dramatic elements are present but not over-emphasized.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demi Moore As A Femme Fatale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is a thriller directed by Barry Levinson that stars Michael Douglas and Demi Moore. It is based on Michael Crichton's novel of the same title.The cast also includes Donald Sutherland, Rosemary Forsyth and Dennis Miller.The film is a combination mystery and thriller about office politics and intrigue in the computer industry in the mid-1990s. Also,it includes the issue of sexual harassment. Tom Sanders is an executive at DigiCom, a leading computer software firm. The company is about to launch a new virtual reality-based data storage system that is expected to revolutionize the industry, and Bob Garvin, the owner of the company, is in the midst of negotiating a merger that could bring $100 million into the firm. However, while Tom is expecting a promotion, he discovers the position has been given instead to a new hire, Meredith Johnson, with whom Tom had an affair years ago, before he was married. After her first day of work, Meredith invites Tom up to her office and makes a concerted attempt to seduce him; while Tom doesn't fight off her advances with very much gusto at first, eventually he decides things have gone too far and leaves in a huff. The next morning, Meredith accuses Tom of sexual harassment, and he realizes this was merely a power ploy to get him out of DigiCom for good; Tom, determined to fight, files a counter-suit, which makes him no friends at the company, since rocking the boat too hard could very well scotch the merger. The story takes some clever twists and turns as it develops into a full- fledged psychological thriller that is effective and gripping, if occasionally contrived as a result of over-plotting.The film is genuinely gripping and well-written.As for the performances,Moore makes an awesome femme fatale while Douglas triumps over evil in a big way.But it is a watchable film as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Crichton winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) not only finds himself passed over for an expected promotion, but his new boss turns out to be an old flame, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). When Meredith makes strong overtures to him, Tom initially goes along, only to refuse her. Furious at his rejection, Meredith accuses him of sexual harassment, so he makes a counter-accusation. Set against the corporate and executive positioning of a complex business deal, Michael Crichton's story (oh how we miss that man's creative output) strikes an interesting balance between techno-thriller, sexual politics commentary, courtroom drama, and urban paranoia thriller. The story is terrific - complex but always followable, gripping and involving, and with emotional ramifications as the essentially decent and blameless Sanders finds himself in an impossible situation. This is a good film, with one of the best payoffs ever, and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the book. No good comes from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everybody's out to get Michael Douglas. Marketed as a controversial examination of a man's charge of sexual harassment against a female co-worker, "Disclosure" is really about paranoia. The reverse discrimination angle is a (albeit large) plot point, but it isn't the crux of the movie. Which is where the movie takes a sharp turn off a cliff. Douglas is a software engineer for a large corporation, and he's been turned down for the big promotion - in favor of a man-eating former lover (Demi Moore). Moore, the new V.P. invites Douglas to her office for a catch-up session, and things get downright steamy. But Douglas is a family man, and he walks away from an enraged (rebuffed) Moore. The next day, Douglas walks into the office to the accusation that he was the one doing the harassing. A very large chunk of the movie is devoted to the harassment charge, with Douglas calling in the help of a media-hungry lawyer (Roma Maffia) to help him with his case. Sordid details emerge, cracks appear in the Douglas household, and and it's not a pretty skirmish. But Moore is just a cog in a larger scheme to eventually make Douglas look incompetent and throw him out on the street. That's what this movie is really about: Douglas is worried about his job. It's all a very conspiratorial and manipulative oppression of the poor white family man, complete with hushed voices in the office. Throw in some deliciously early '90s CGI and a ridiculously lame virtual reality subplot, and you've got the market fresh makings of an overly- long film that never rises above goofy. 3/10; a real chore
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Office Politics, Paranoia & The Abuse Of Power
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the 1990s when an increasing number of women were filling top jobs in the corporate world, a story about a woman sexually harassing a man became a plausible scenario and the topical and controversial nature of the subject resonated strongly enough with the public at that time to make "Disclosure" a great box office success. Whilst the sexual harassment element of the story was shocking and attention grabbing, it soon became apparent that this was just part of a far larger and more pervasive issue i.e. the abuse of power. In the workplace, where social conventions, various legal constraints and political correctness all come into play, there is still no escape from the kind of management conspiracies, office politics and duplicity which are depicted so effectively in "Disclosure" or the kinds of distrust and paranoia that they can so easily generate. Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) heads one of the divisions of a Seattle computer company and is engaged in the development of a product which is vitally important to the success of a planned and very lucrative merger with another company. There are some problems with the product which Tom and his team are currently dealing with and are under considerable pressure to resolve. As a result of some changes which are taking place within the company, Tom's confident that he'll be promoted but it soon transpires that he's been passed over and the job has been given to one of his ex-girlfriends, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). On her first day in the job, Meredith arranges a late meeting with Tom to discuss his division's work but during their meeting she aggressively tries to seduce him and is furious when, after a considerable struggle, she's unsuccessful. Meredith responds to Tom's rejection by accusing him of sexual harassment and asserting that in the circumstances, there's no way that she'd be able to work with him again. The company want to avoid any publicity that could have an adverse impact on the upcoming merger and so try to get Tom to take a transfer to another job in their Austin branch. He can't countenance this idea because of the negative effect it would have on his career and is in a very tight spot. Help unexpectedly arrives in the form of an anonymous e-mail which recommends that he consult an attorney called Catherine Alvarez (Roma Maffia) who's a specialist in sexual harassment cases. Tom decides to fight back and files a counter-suit. The process he has to go through to achieve justice is difficult and painful but irrefutable proof of his innocence is produced and the company agrees to retain him and give him a pay rise. The relief that Tom feels after being cleared of the charges against him is short lived as it quickly becomes apparent that efforts which were originally initiated by Meredith to make him look incompetent have now drawn wider support and he's being set up to be publicly humiliated and undermined at a high profile shareholders' meeting. The way in which Tom copes with this threat then provides the story with its intriguing conclusion. The events in "Disclosure" all take place within the space of one intense week in which Tom's normally affluent and comfortable lifestyle is disrupted as his disappointment at being passed over for promotion turns into discomfort when he discovers the identity of his new boss and then horror as he's threatened with the loss of his job, his wife, his family and his stock options. The false accusation made against him, the plots to make him look incompetent and a workplace where no one can be trusted, create a climate of paranoia which is reinforced when some of his previous innocent actions are characterised as something more sinister and the support of his colleagues is systematically eroded by those high up in the company structure. Michael Douglas gives a good solid performance as the beleaguered Tom and Demi Moore is marvellous as the cold and cruel villain of the piece. Donald Sutherland and Roma Maffia also stand out in their supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexual harassment is about power. When did I have the power? When?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is directed by Barry Levinson and co-adapted to screenplay by Paul Attanasio and Michael Crichton from Crichton's own novel of the same name. It stars Michael Douglas, Demi Moore, Donald Sutherland, Roma Maffia, Dylan Baker, Caroline Goodall and Rosemary Forsyth. Music is scored by Ennio Morricone. Tom Sanders (Douglas) is an executive at DigiCom, a high-tech computer company, who hopes that now it's finally his time to get promotion. Passed over for an outsider, he's further irked when it turns out to be Meredith Johnson (Moore), an old passionate flame of his from years previously. When Meredith arranges for a meeting between the two later that evening, Tom finds himself sexually harassed by her. Spurning her aggressive overtures, Tom is shocked to learn the next day that she has filed a charge of sexual harassment against him. He naturally counters the charge, but this opens up a can of worms for both him and the future of DigiCom. The 1990s practically belonged to Michael Crichton, it seemed for a time that everything he wrote was adapted to the big screen for some form of entertainment. With Jurassic Park still warm and still garnering bucket loads of cash, two other Crichton adaptations worked their way into theatres; both of which were a world away from the family friendly extravaganza of Jurassic Park. One was Rising Sun, a messy wasted potential of a movie, the other was Disclosure, a zeitgeist snatcher that seized the moment. The topic, and the novelty of flipping the gender aggressor, was always going to make Disclosure of much interest, thus the film and the novel made big money: aided still further by the hot casting of Douglas and Moore, who were still draw cards in the early 90s. Crichton, after being displeased with other adaptations of his work, got big say on the screenplay as a written project. So with director Levinson in tow, he set about pushing the buttons of his audience, attempting to continue the heated debates that were brought about previously from Douglas' Fatal Attraction and Basic Instinct. If it's Crichton's or Levinson's fault that it didn't work out that way? I'm not sure, but fact is, is that Disclosure really wasn't that potent back then, and certainly now it's not even lukewarm. There's too much techno babble going on, and an over keenness to stick the nose up at the big business vultures picking the flesh off of the lesser minions. Entering the last half hour of the film, it's easy to forget there has actually been a sexual harassment case! Here's the crux of the matter, if going in to it for a first time viewing expecting this to be a powder-keg of sexual harassment muckiness and legal intrigue, then you are in for a big disappointment. I know, because I was one of the paying patrons at the theatre back in 94! You sense that one of the makers got a bit carried away Yet the film still has much going for it if stripped of that expectation, not least that it packs a pile of tension in that last half hour and the finale is rather rewarding. I'd go as far to say I'm a fan of the film, but it's not the film I originally went to see! There's a trio of interesting and differing female characters at the front of the narrative, even if Moore's stair-master vixen isn't exactly developed beyond being a bitch, and the virtual reality sequences have an appealing charm about them. The cast are turning in good ones, with a notable shout out to Caroline Goodall who wisely underplays it as the wife. While the interior set design (Gary Lewis/Joseph Hodges) for the DigiCom HQ is wonderful with its 90s excess of glass meeting mirrors and open spaces. Which leaves us with what? A film that is not what you expect! Which in this case is both disappointing and a surprise. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stand-alone thriller with a mish-mash of intriguing themes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tale of sexual harassment in the office with a twist  this time, the guy is the victim and the woman the pursuer. Yes, it's another thriller that builds on Michael Douglas's typecasting as a victim of powerful women (following FATAL ATTRACTION and BASIC INSTINCT) but this one plays all the right cards. Part workplace drama, part courtroom thriller, and all the time invested with now-dated-but-then-cutting-edge technology (email, virtual reality) I found Disclosure to be never less than intriguing and well made. The Crichton source material helps, of course; I haven't yet seen a Crichton film that hasn't been thought-provoking and entertaining (even the worst, CONGO, isn't entirely without merit, although the book is loads better). I've been seeing a lot of Douglas in recent months and my opinion of him has steadily improved to the degree that I can't remember him giving a bad performance. He's fine here, providing a key likable anchor for the film to revolve around, and playing opposite him Demi Moore is also a surprise: she oozes sexuality and selfishness in equal measure, proving a powerful enemy at all times. Moore isn't the world's greatest actress but this might well be her best performance in a film. The courtroom scenes, tense and full of electricity, are undoubtedly the film's highlights and there are supporting actors to relish (Donald Sutherland, Allan Rich and in particular a slimy Dylan Baker). It's not a perfect film, but it is a reminder of the kind of solid, sensual thriller that got made during a sometimes forgotten decade of filmmaking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corporate Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays Tom Sanders, a successful computer specialist working for a big firm who is passed over for promotion in favor of an old flame named Meredith Johnson(played by Demi Moore). She is very ambitious, and seems to have undue influence over the CEO, which proves to be the case as Meredith tries to seduce Tom after hours in her office. Tom, a happily married man, is tempted by her beauty, but resists. He is later shocked to learn that she has reported him for sexual harassment, so he has no choice but to sue her, which endangers his future within the company, but Tom will discover that things are not as simple as they seem, and Meredith has another agenda at work... Based on Michael Crichton's novel, and well directed by Barry Levinson, this features fine acting by its stars, and a fascinating story with many twists and turns, that leads to a satisfying finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Naked Truth...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cronostitan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the specialist of the trendy thriller, this movie rather well pinned also speaks about the difficult square in the society that all those can occupy sometimes who do not enough sit - at least not endowed with varied and diverse protections. What it will be necessary to raise it is that Crichton dodges these long sequences of court with strong theatrical echo which we undergo very often among soaps in the TV (and also in John Grisham's books and in adventures of the TV show Ally Mc Beal), instead of it he joins in the life the office among this great number of "small" details that all those sometimes forget who do not work: another tour de force very rich in teaching... Because freedom is also a question of money although people are not globally more free than before in the old time, it is simply wrong!! Careful thus in "politically correct" falsified, in the traps, in the blackmail, in the propaganda, in the jealousy...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full disclosure: this movie stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suppose the idea of Michael Douglas being sexually harassed by Demi Moore could be intriguing. Could be. But in this movie it doesn't end up being intriguing at all. The story fizzles out before it ever really gets going. The movie goes on and on without ever really going anywhere. There's no spark, no sizzle. Attempts at humor fall horribly flat. The only laughs in this movie come from laughing at just how bad it is, most notably in the big climactic virtual reality scene. Wait, big climactic virtual reality scene? Yeah, it's just as stupid as it sounds, an awful idea executed so badly you can't help but laugh at how truly terrible it is. This is a movie which fails in pretty much every way possible. Douglas plays Tom Sanders, the head of production at some high-tech Seattle outfit. There's a big merger on the horizon, Tom expects a big promotion to go with it. But the job he covets goes to Meredith Johnson, a one-time girlfriend of his who celebrates their reunion by trying to rape him in her office. When Tom says no, not before having a little fun of course because the movie needs its obligatory sex scene, Meredith promises to ruin him. And the next day she duly accuses him of sexual harassment. He gets himself a lawyer, accuses her and it's a big he-said, she-said deal which only serves to bore those of us who are unfortunate enough to be watching. Drama and tension are in very short supply. Tedium is the order of the day. Moore's absolutely atrocious acting doesn't help matters. My goodness, she is terrible. The story slogs along, everyone ganging up on poor Tom in some horribly uninteresting conspiracy. It's not just Meredith out to get him, this goes all the way up to the big boss at the top. That character, played by Donald Sutherland, is I suppose meant to seem sinister but the way Sutherland mugs and overacts he just comes off as a buffoon. Just another example of the way this movie completely misses the mark. And just when you think it can't possibly get any worse along comes that absurd virtual reality scene which is simply one of the dumbest things ever seen in any movie. Even after that laughable "climax" the movie doesn't have the decency to just end. More pointless, boring twists to come. The whole thing is just interminable. Movies don't get much worse than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Douglas contends with business foe Demi Moore determined to oust him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Disclosure" is a smoothly done, pleasurable and suspenseful watch in which the action never flags. This is a good solid Hollywood product by all involved. Michael Douglas does his usual fine job -- he makes look easy what is not at all easy -- playing a Silicon Valley production specialist. For reasons unknown, the production line product is failing while the prototypes work. He is being made to look incompetent. Meanwhile, he has a new boss, Demi Moore, who was his old flame. And the big boss, Donald Sutherland, is negotiating a merger that will enrich everyone in the firm, stock options and all that. Preventing Douglas from tracking down the production line issues in Malaysia are this merger and Moore's plot to accuse Douglas of sexual harassment. Douglas fights back, without anger and bitterness, by mediation, accusing her correctly of harassing him. Meanwhile, he's trying to figure out how production has gone wrong. In the narrow world of an operations specialist, he doesn't suspect behind the scenes machinations. But he has a "friend" higher up (a guardian angel) who does, and who spurs him on via anonymous e-mails to dig deeper. As the merger pressures those around him, all of whom stand to gain handsomely by stock options, he finds his associates melting away and, more or less, siding with pressures brought by Sutherland to get Douglas to paper over the production issues. Sutherland absolutely looks the part and steals every scene he is in. His part in all this is ambiguous enough that he can bob and weave and land on his feet. He's a slick one. He didn't get to head the company without this skill. And so we enter the world of Silicon Valley too, and that's part of the movie's charm. The interior sets of the business itself bring this to life, and complement the business rivalries and machinations. The 128m running time passes quickly. Douglas learns a thing or two. The supporting roles are well cast and played. The movie is a business thriller, with the emphasis on emotional pressures, calculation, and psychological conflicts that bring out the varying personalities and motivations of those involved. Dramatic elements are present but not over-emphasized.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demi Moore As A Femme Fatale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is a thriller directed by Barry Levinson that stars Michael Douglas and Demi Moore. It is based on Michael Crichton's novel of the same title.The cast also includes Donald Sutherland, Rosemary Forsyth and Dennis Miller.The film is a combination mystery and thriller about office politics and intrigue in the computer industry in the mid-1990s. Also,it includes the issue of sexual harassment. Tom Sanders is an executive at DigiCom, a leading computer software firm. The company is about to launch a new virtual reality-based data storage system that is expected to revolutionize the industry, and Bob Garvin, the owner of the company, is in the midst of negotiating a merger that could bring $100 million into the firm. However, while Tom is expecting a promotion, he discovers the position has been given instead to a new hire, Meredith Johnson, with whom Tom had an affair years ago, before he was married. After her first day of work, Meredith invites Tom up to her office and makes a concerted attempt to seduce him; while Tom doesn't fight off her advances with very much gusto at first, eventually he decides things have gone too far and leaves in a huff. The next morning, Meredith accuses Tom of sexual harassment, and he realizes this was merely a power ploy to get him out of DigiCom for good; Tom, determined to fight, files a counter-suit, which makes him no friends at the company, since rocking the boat too hard could very well scotch the merger. The story takes some clever twists and turns as it develops into a full- fledged psychological thriller that is effective and gripping, if occasionally contrived as a result of over-plotting.The film is genuinely gripping and well-written.As for the performances,Moore makes an awesome femme fatale while Douglas triumps over evil in a big way.But it is a watchable film as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Crichton winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) not only finds himself passed over for an expected promotion, but his new boss turns out to be an old flame, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). When Meredith makes strong overtures to him, Tom initially goes along, only to refuse her. Furious at his rejection, Meredith accuses him of sexual harassment, so he makes a counter-accusation. Set against the corporate and executive positioning of a complex business deal, Michael Crichton's story (oh how we miss that man's creative output) strikes an interesting balance between techno-thriller, sexual politics commentary, courtroom drama, and urban paranoia thriller. The story is terrific - complex but always followable, gripping and involving, and with emotional ramifications as the essentially decent and blameless Sanders finds himself in an impossible situation. This is a good film, with one of the best payoffs ever, and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the book. No good comes from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everybody's out to get Michael Douglas. Marketed as a controversial examination of a man's charge of sexual harassment against a female co-worker, "Disclosure" is really about paranoia. The reverse discrimination angle is a (albeit large) plot point, but it isn't the crux of the movie. Which is where the movie takes a sharp turn off a cliff. Douglas is a software engineer for a large corporation, and he's been turned down for the big promotion - in favor of a man-eating former lover (Demi Moore). Moore, the new V.P. invites Douglas to her office for a catch-up session, and things get downright steamy. But Douglas is a family man, and he walks away from an enraged (rebuffed) Moore. The next day, Douglas walks into the office to the accusation that he was the one doing the harassing. A very large chunk of the movie is devoted to the harassment charge, with Douglas calling in the help of a media-hungry lawyer (Roma Maffia) to help him with his case. Sordid details emerge, cracks appear in the Douglas household, and and it's not a pretty skirmish. But Moore is just a cog in a larger scheme to eventually make Douglas look incompetent and throw him out on the street. That's what this movie is really about: Douglas is worried about his job. It's all a very conspiratorial and manipulative oppression of the poor white family man, complete with hushed voices in the office. Throw in some deliciously early '90s CGI and a ridiculously lame virtual reality subplot, and you've got the market fresh makings of an overly- long film that never rises above goofy. 3/10; a real chore
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Office Politics, Paranoia & The Abuse Of Power
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the 1990s when an increasing number of women were filling top jobs in the corporate world, a story about a woman sexually harassing a man became a plausible scenario and the topical and controversial nature of the subject resonated strongly enough with the public at that time to make "Disclosure" a great box office success. Whilst the sexual harassment element of the story was shocking and attention grabbing, it soon became apparent that this was just part of a far larger and more pervasive issue i.e. the abuse of power. In the workplace, where social conventions, various legal constraints and political correctness all come into play, there is still no escape from the kind of management conspiracies, office politics and duplicity which are depicted so effectively in "Disclosure" or the kinds of distrust and paranoia that they can so easily generate. Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) heads one of the divisions of a Seattle computer company and is engaged in the development of a product which is vitally important to the success of a planned and very lucrative merger with another company. There are some problems with the product which Tom and his team are currently dealing with and are under considerable pressure to resolve. As a result of some changes which are taking place within the company, Tom's confident that he'll be promoted but it soon transpires that he's been passed over and the job has been given to one of his ex-girlfriends, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). On her first day in the job, Meredith arranges a late meeting with Tom to discuss his division's work but during their meeting she aggressively tries to seduce him and is furious when, after a considerable struggle, she's unsuccessful. Meredith responds to Tom's rejection by accusing him of sexual harassment and asserting that in the circumstances, there's no way that she'd be able to work with him again. The company want to avoid any publicity that could have an adverse impact on the upcoming merger and so try to get Tom to take a transfer to another job in their Austin branch. He can't countenance this idea because of the negative effect it would have on his career and is in a very tight spot. Help unexpectedly arrives in the form of an anonymous e-mail which recommends that he consult an attorney called Catherine Alvarez (Roma Maffia) who's a specialist in sexual harassment cases. Tom decides to fight back and files a counter-suit. The process he has to go through to achieve justice is difficult and painful but irrefutable proof of his innocence is produced and the company agrees to retain him and give him a pay rise. The relief that Tom feels after being cleared of the charges against him is short lived as it quickly becomes apparent that efforts which were originally initiated by Meredith to make him look incompetent have now drawn wider support and he's being set up to be publicly humiliated and undermined at a high profile shareholders' meeting. The way in which Tom copes with this threat then provides the story with its intriguing conclusion. The events in "Disclosure" all take place within the space of one intense week in which Tom's normally affluent and comfortable lifestyle is disrupted as his disappointment at being passed over for promotion turns into discomfort when he discovers the identity of his new boss and then horror as he's threatened with the loss of his job, his wife, his family and his stock options. The false accusation made against him, the plots to make him look incompetent and a workplace where no one can be trusted, create a climate of paranoia which is reinforced when some of his previous innocent actions are characterised as something more sinister and the support of his colleagues is systematically eroded by those high up in the company structure. Michael Douglas gives a good solid performance as the beleaguered Tom and Demi Moore is marvellous as the cold and cruel villain of the piece. Donald Sutherland and Roma Maffia also stand out in their supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexual harassment is about power. When did I have the power? When?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is directed by Barry Levinson and co-adapted to screenplay by Paul Attanasio and Michael Crichton from Crichton's own novel of the same name. It stars Michael Douglas, Demi Moore, Donald Sutherland, Roma Maffia, Dylan Baker, Caroline Goodall and Rosemary Forsyth. Music is scored by Ennio Morricone. Tom Sanders (Douglas) is an executive at DigiCom, a high-tech computer company, who hopes that now it's finally his time to get promotion. Passed over for an outsider, he's further irked when it turns out to be Meredith Johnson (Moore), an old passionate flame of his from years previously. When Meredith arranges for a meeting between the two later that evening, Tom finds himself sexually harassed by her. Spurning her aggressive overtures, Tom is shocked to learn the next day that she has filed a charge of sexual harassment against him. He naturally counters the charge, but this opens up a can of worms for both him and the future of DigiCom. The 1990s practically belonged to Michael Crichton, it seemed for a time that everything he wrote was adapted to the big screen for some form of entertainment. With Jurassic Park still warm and still garnering bucket loads of cash, two other Crichton adaptations worked their way into theatres; both of which were a world away from the family friendly extravaganza of Jurassic Park. One was Rising Sun, a messy wasted potential of a movie, the other was Disclosure, a zeitgeist snatcher that seized the moment. The topic, and the novelty of flipping the gender aggressor, was always going to make Disclosure of much interest, thus the film and the novel made big money: aided still further by the hot casting of Douglas and Moore, who were still draw cards in the early 90s. Crichton, after being displeased with other adaptations of his work, got big say on the screenplay as a written project. So with director Levinson in tow, he set about pushing the buttons of his audience, attempting to continue the heated debates that were brought about previously from Douglas' Fatal Attraction and Basic Instinct. If it's Crichton's or Levinson's fault that it didn't work out that way? I'm not sure, but fact is, is that Disclosure really wasn't that potent back then, and certainly now it's not even lukewarm. There's too much techno babble going on, and an over keenness to stick the nose up at the big business vultures picking the flesh off of the lesser minions. Entering the last half hour of the film, it's easy to forget there has actually been a sexual harassment case! Here's the crux of the matter, if going in to it for a first time viewing expecting this to be a powder-keg of sexual harassment muckiness and legal intrigue, then you are in for a big disappointment. I know, because I was one of the paying patrons at the theatre back in 94! You sense that one of the makers got a bit carried away Yet the film still has much going for it if stripped of that expectation, not least that it packs a pile of tension in that last half hour and the finale is rather rewarding. I'd go as far to say I'm a fan of the film, but it's not the film I originally went to see! There's a trio of interesting and differing female characters at the front of the narrative, even if Moore's stair-master vixen isn't exactly developed beyond being a bitch, and the virtual reality sequences have an appealing charm about them. The cast are turning in good ones, with a notable shout out to Caroline Goodall who wisely underplays it as the wife. While the interior set design (Gary Lewis/Joseph Hodges) for the DigiCom HQ is wonderful with its 90s excess of glass meeting mirrors and open spaces. Which leaves us with what? A film that is not what you expect! Which in this case is both disappointing and a surprise. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stand-alone thriller with a mish-mash of intriguing themes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tale of sexual harassment in the office with a twist  this time, the guy is the victim and the woman the pursuer. Yes, it's another thriller that builds on Michael Douglas's typecasting as a victim of powerful women (following FATAL ATTRACTION and BASIC INSTINCT) but this one plays all the right cards. Part workplace drama, part courtroom thriller, and all the time invested with now-dated-but-then-cutting-edge technology (email, virtual reality) I found Disclosure to be never less than intriguing and well made. The Crichton source material helps, of course; I haven't yet seen a Crichton film that hasn't been thought-provoking and entertaining (even the worst, CONGO, isn't entirely without merit, although the book is loads better). I've been seeing a lot of Douglas in recent months and my opinion of him has steadily improved to the degree that I can't remember him giving a bad performance. He's fine here, providing a key likable anchor for the film to revolve around, and playing opposite him Demi Moore is also a surprise: she oozes sexuality and selfishness in equal measure, proving a powerful enemy at all times. Moore isn't the world's greatest actress but this might well be her best performance in a film. The courtroom scenes, tense and full of electricity, are undoubtedly the film's highlights and there are supporting actors to relish (Donald Sutherland, Allan Rich and in particular a slimy Dylan Baker). It's not a perfect film, but it is a reminder of the kind of solid, sensual thriller that got made during a sometimes forgotten decade of filmmaking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corporate Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays Tom Sanders, a successful computer specialist working for a big firm who is passed over for promotion in favor of an old flame named Meredith Johnson(played by Demi Moore). She is very ambitious, and seems to have undue influence over the CEO, which proves to be the case as Meredith tries to seduce Tom after hours in her office. Tom, a happily married man, is tempted by her beauty, but resists. He is later shocked to learn that she has reported him for sexual harassment, so he has no choice but to sue her, which endangers his future within the company, but Tom will discover that things are not as simple as they seem, and Meredith has another agenda at work... Based on Michael Crichton's novel, and well directed by Barry Levinson, this features fine acting by its stars, and a fascinating story with many twists and turns, that leads to a satisfying finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Naked Truth...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cronostitan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the specialist of the trendy thriller, this movie rather well pinned also speaks about the difficult square in the society that all those can occupy sometimes who do not enough sit - at least not endowed with varied and diverse protections. What it will be necessary to raise it is that Crichton dodges these long sequences of court with strong theatrical echo which we undergo very often among soaps in the TV (and also in John Grisham's books and in adventures of the TV show Ally Mc Beal), instead of it he joins in the life the office among this great number of "small" details that all those sometimes forget who do not work: another tour de force very rich in teaching... Because freedom is also a question of money although people are not globally more free than before in the old time, it is simply wrong!! Careful thus in "politically correct" falsified, in the traps, in the blackmail, in the propaganda, in the jealousy...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full disclosure: this movie stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suppose the idea of Michael Douglas being sexually harassed by Demi Moore could be intriguing. Could be. But in this movie it doesn't end up being intriguing at all. The story fizzles out before it ever really gets going. The movie goes on and on without ever really going anywhere. There's no spark, no sizzle. Attempts at humor fall horribly flat. The only laughs in this movie come from laughing at just how bad it is, most notably in the big climactic virtual reality scene. Wait, big climactic virtual reality scene? Yeah, it's just as stupid as it sounds, an awful idea executed so badly you can't help but laugh at how truly terrible it is. This is a movie which fails in pretty much every way possible. Douglas plays Tom Sanders, the head of production at some high-tech Seattle outfit. There's a big merger on the horizon, Tom expects a big promotion to go with it. But the job he covets goes to Meredith Johnson, a one-time girlfriend of his who celebrates their reunion by trying to rape him in her office. When Tom says no, not before having a little fun of course because the movie needs its obligatory sex scene, Meredith promises to ruin him. And the next day she duly accuses him of sexual harassment. He gets himself a lawyer, accuses her and it's a big he-said, she-said deal which only serves to bore those of us who are unfortunate enough to be watching. Drama and tension are in very short supply. Tedium is the order of the day. Moore's absolutely atrocious acting doesn't help matters. My goodness, she is terrible. The story slogs along, everyone ganging up on poor Tom in some horribly uninteresting conspiracy. It's not just Meredith out to get him, this goes all the way up to the big boss at the top. That character, played by Donald Sutherland, is I suppose meant to seem sinister but the way Sutherland mugs and overacts he just comes off as a buffoon. Just another example of the way this movie completely misses the mark. And just when you think it can't possibly get any worse along comes that absurd virtual reality scene which is simply one of the dumbest things ever seen in any movie. Even after that laughable "climax" the movie doesn't have the decency to just end. More pointless, boring twists to come. The whole thing is just interminable. Movies don't get much worse than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Douglas contends with business foe Demi Moore determined to oust him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Disclosure" is a smoothly done, pleasurable and suspenseful watch in which the action never flags. This is a good solid Hollywood product by all involved. Michael Douglas does his usual fine job -- he makes look easy what is not at all easy -- playing a Silicon Valley production specialist. For reasons unknown, the production line product is failing while the prototypes work. He is being made to look incompetent. Meanwhile, he has a new boss, Demi Moore, who was his old flame. And the big boss, Donald Sutherland, is negotiating a merger that will enrich everyone in the firm, stock options and all that. Preventing Douglas from tracking down the production line issues in Malaysia are this merger and Moore's plot to accuse Douglas of sexual harassment. Douglas fights back, without anger and bitterness, by mediation, accusing her correctly of harassing him. Meanwhile, he's trying to figure out how production has gone wrong. In the narrow world of an operations specialist, he doesn't suspect behind the scenes machinations. But he has a "friend" higher up (a guardian angel) who does, and who spurs him on via anonymous e-mails to dig deeper. As the merger pressures those around him, all of whom stand to gain handsomely by stock options, he finds his associates melting away and, more or less, siding with pressures brought by Sutherland to get Douglas to paper over the production issues. Sutherland absolutely looks the part and steals every scene he is in. His part in all this is ambiguous enough that he can bob and weave and land on his feet. He's a slick one. He didn't get to head the company without this skill. And so we enter the world of Silicon Valley too, and that's part of the movie's charm. The interior sets of the business itself bring this to life, and complement the business rivalries and machinations. The 128m running time passes quickly. Douglas learns a thing or two. The supporting roles are well cast and played. The movie is a business thriller, with the emphasis on emotional pressures, calculation, and psychological conflicts that bring out the varying personalities and motivations of those involved. Dramatic elements are present but not over-emphasized.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demi Moore As A Femme Fatale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is a thriller directed by Barry Levinson that stars Michael Douglas and Demi Moore. It is based on Michael Crichton's novel of the same title.The cast also includes Donald Sutherland, Rosemary Forsyth and Dennis Miller.The film is a combination mystery and thriller about office politics and intrigue in the computer industry in the mid-1990s. Also,it includes the issue of sexual harassment. Tom Sanders is an executive at DigiCom, a leading computer software firm. The company is about to launch a new virtual reality-based data storage system that is expected to revolutionize the industry, and Bob Garvin, the owner of the company, is in the midst of negotiating a merger that could bring $100 million into the firm. However, while Tom is expecting a promotion, he discovers the position has been given instead to a new hire, Meredith Johnson, with whom Tom had an affair years ago, before he was married. After her first day of work, Meredith invites Tom up to her office and makes a concerted attempt to seduce him; while Tom doesn't fight off her advances with very much gusto at first, eventually he decides things have gone too far and leaves in a huff. The next morning, Meredith accuses Tom of sexual harassment, and he realizes this was merely a power ploy to get him out of DigiCom for good; Tom, determined to fight, files a counter-suit, which makes him no friends at the company, since rocking the boat too hard could very well scotch the merger. The story takes some clever twists and turns as it develops into a full- fledged psychological thriller that is effective and gripping, if occasionally contrived as a result of over-plotting.The film is genuinely gripping and well-written.As for the performances,Moore makes an awesome femme fatale while Douglas triumps over evil in a big way.But it is a watchable film as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Crichton winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) not only finds himself passed over for an expected promotion, but his new boss turns out to be an old flame, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). When Meredith makes strong overtures to him, Tom initially goes along, only to refuse her. Furious at his rejection, Meredith accuses him of sexual harassment, so he makes a counter-accusation. Set against the corporate and executive positioning of a complex business deal, Michael Crichton's story (oh how we miss that man's creative output) strikes an interesting balance between techno-thriller, sexual politics commentary, courtroom drama, and urban paranoia thriller. The story is terrific - complex but always followable, gripping and involving, and with emotional ramifications as the essentially decent and blameless Sanders finds himself in an impossible situation. This is a good film, with one of the best payoffs ever, and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the book. No good comes from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everybody's out to get Michael Douglas. Marketed as a controversial examination of a man's charge of sexual harassment against a female co-worker, "Disclosure" is really about paranoia. The reverse discrimination angle is a (albeit large) plot point, but it isn't the crux of the movie. Which is where the movie takes a sharp turn off a cliff. Douglas is a software engineer for a large corporation, and he's been turned down for the big promotion - in favor of a man-eating former lover (Demi Moore). Moore, the new V.P. invites Douglas to her office for a catch-up session, and things get downright steamy. But Douglas is a family man, and he walks away from an enraged (rebuffed) Moore. The next day, Douglas walks into the office to the accusation that he was the one doing the harassing. A very large chunk of the movie is devoted to the harassment charge, with Douglas calling in the help of a media-hungry lawyer (Roma Maffia) to help him with his case. Sordid details emerge, cracks appear in the Douglas household, and and it's not a pretty skirmish. But Moore is just a cog in a larger scheme to eventually make Douglas look incompetent and throw him out on the street. That's what this movie is really about: Douglas is worried about his job. It's all a very conspiratorial and manipulative oppression of the poor white family man, complete with hushed voices in the office. Throw in some deliciously early '90s CGI and a ridiculously lame virtual reality subplot, and you've got the market fresh makings of an overly- long film that never rises above goofy. 3/10; a real chore
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Office Politics, Paranoia & The Abuse Of Power
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the 1990s when an increasing number of women were filling top jobs in the corporate world, a story about a woman sexually harassing a man became a plausible scenario and the topical and controversial nature of the subject resonated strongly enough with the public at that time to make "Disclosure" a great box office success. Whilst the sexual harassment element of the story was shocking and attention grabbing, it soon became apparent that this was just part of a far larger and more pervasive issue i.e. the abuse of power. In the workplace, where social conventions, various legal constraints and political correctness all come into play, there is still no escape from the kind of management conspiracies, office politics and duplicity which are depicted so effectively in "Disclosure" or the kinds of distrust and paranoia that they can so easily generate. Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) heads one of the divisions of a Seattle computer company and is engaged in the development of a product which is vitally important to the success of a planned and very lucrative merger with another company. There are some problems with the product which Tom and his team are currently dealing with and are under considerable pressure to resolve. As a result of some changes which are taking place within the company, Tom's confident that he'll be promoted but it soon transpires that he's been passed over and the job has been given to one of his ex-girlfriends, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). On her first day in the job, Meredith arranges a late meeting with Tom to discuss his division's work but during their meeting she aggressively tries to seduce him and is furious when, after a considerable struggle, she's unsuccessful. Meredith responds to Tom's rejection by accusing him of sexual harassment and asserting that in the circumstances, there's no way that she'd be able to work with him again. The company want to avoid any publicity that could have an adverse impact on the upcoming merger and so try to get Tom to take a transfer to another job in their Austin branch. He can't countenance this idea because of the negative effect it would have on his career and is in a very tight spot. Help unexpectedly arrives in the form of an anonymous e-mail which recommends that he consult an attorney called Catherine Alvarez (Roma Maffia) who's a specialist in sexual harassment cases. Tom decides to fight back and files a counter-suit. The process he has to go through to achieve justice is difficult and painful but irrefutable proof of his innocence is produced and the company agrees to retain him and give him a pay rise. The relief that Tom feels after being cleared of the charges against him is short lived as it quickly becomes apparent that efforts which were originally initiated by Meredith to make him look incompetent have now drawn wider support and he's being set up to be publicly humiliated and undermined at a high profile shareholders' meeting. The way in which Tom copes with this threat then provides the story with its intriguing conclusion. The events in "Disclosure" all take place within the space of one intense week in which Tom's normally affluent and comfortable lifestyle is disrupted as his disappointment at being passed over for promotion turns into discomfort when he discovers the identity of his new boss and then horror as he's threatened with the loss of his job, his wife, his family and his stock options. The false accusation made against him, the plots to make him look incompetent and a workplace where no one can be trusted, create a climate of paranoia which is reinforced when some of his previous innocent actions are characterised as something more sinister and the support of his colleagues is systematically eroded by those high up in the company structure. Michael Douglas gives a good solid performance as the beleaguered Tom and Demi Moore is marvellous as the cold and cruel villain of the piece. Donald Sutherland and Roma Maffia also stand out in their supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexual harassment is about power. When did I have the power? When?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is directed by Barry Levinson and co-adapted to screenplay by Paul Attanasio and Michael Crichton from Crichton's own novel of the same name. It stars Michael Douglas, Demi Moore, Donald Sutherland, Roma Maffia, Dylan Baker, Caroline Goodall and Rosemary Forsyth. Music is scored by Ennio Morricone. Tom Sanders (Douglas) is an executive at DigiCom, a high-tech computer company, who hopes that now it's finally his time to get promotion. Passed over for an outsider, he's further irked when it turns out to be Meredith Johnson (Moore), an old passionate flame of his from years previously. When Meredith arranges for a meeting between the two later that evening, Tom finds himself sexually harassed by her. Spurning her aggressive overtures, Tom is shocked to learn the next day that she has filed a charge of sexual harassment against him. He naturally counters the charge, but this opens up a can of worms for both him and the future of DigiCom. The 1990s practically belonged to Michael Crichton, it seemed for a time that everything he wrote was adapted to the big screen for some form of entertainment. With Jurassic Park still warm and still garnering bucket loads of cash, two other Crichton adaptations worked their way into theatres; both of which were a world away from the family friendly extravaganza of Jurassic Park. One was Rising Sun, a messy wasted potential of a movie, the other was Disclosure, a zeitgeist snatcher that seized the moment. The topic, and the novelty of flipping the gender aggressor, was always going to make Disclosure of much interest, thus the film and the novel made big money: aided still further by the hot casting of Douglas and Moore, who were still draw cards in the early 90s. Crichton, after being displeased with other adaptations of his work, got big say on the screenplay as a written project. So with director Levinson in tow, he set about pushing the buttons of his audience, attempting to continue the heated debates that were brought about previously from Douglas' Fatal Attraction and Basic Instinct. If it's Crichton's or Levinson's fault that it didn't work out that way? I'm not sure, but fact is, is that Disclosure really wasn't that potent back then, and certainly now it's not even lukewarm. There's too much techno babble going on, and an over keenness to stick the nose up at the big business vultures picking the flesh off of the lesser minions. Entering the last half hour of the film, it's easy to forget there has actually been a sexual harassment case! Here's the crux of the matter, if going in to it for a first time viewing expecting this to be a powder-keg of sexual harassment muckiness and legal intrigue, then you are in for a big disappointment. I know, because I was one of the paying patrons at the theatre back in 94! You sense that one of the makers got a bit carried away Yet the film still has much going for it if stripped of that expectation, not least that it packs a pile of tension in that last half hour and the finale is rather rewarding. I'd go as far to say I'm a fan of the film, but it's not the film I originally went to see! There's a trio of interesting and differing female characters at the front of the narrative, even if Moore's stair-master vixen isn't exactly developed beyond being a bitch, and the virtual reality sequences have an appealing charm about them. The cast are turning in good ones, with a notable shout out to Caroline Goodall who wisely underplays it as the wife. While the interior set design (Gary Lewis/Joseph Hodges) for the DigiCom HQ is wonderful with its 90s excess of glass meeting mirrors and open spaces. Which leaves us with what? A film that is not what you expect! Which in this case is both disappointing and a surprise. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stand-alone thriller with a mish-mash of intriguing themes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tale of sexual harassment in the office with a twist  this time, the guy is the victim and the woman the pursuer. Yes, it's another thriller that builds on Michael Douglas's typecasting as a victim of powerful women (following FATAL ATTRACTION and BASIC INSTINCT) but this one plays all the right cards. Part workplace drama, part courtroom thriller, and all the time invested with now-dated-but-then-cutting-edge technology (email, virtual reality) I found Disclosure to be never less than intriguing and well made. The Crichton source material helps, of course; I haven't yet seen a Crichton film that hasn't been thought-provoking and entertaining (even the worst, CONGO, isn't entirely without merit, although the book is loads better). I've been seeing a lot of Douglas in recent months and my opinion of him has steadily improved to the degree that I can't remember him giving a bad performance. He's fine here, providing a key likable anchor for the film to revolve around, and playing opposite him Demi Moore is also a surprise: she oozes sexuality and selfishness in equal measure, proving a powerful enemy at all times. Moore isn't the world's greatest actress but this might well be her best performance in a film. The courtroom scenes, tense and full of electricity, are undoubtedly the film's highlights and there are supporting actors to relish (Donald Sutherland, Allan Rich and in particular a slimy Dylan Baker). It's not a perfect film, but it is a reminder of the kind of solid, sensual thriller that got made during a sometimes forgotten decade of filmmaking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corporate Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays Tom Sanders, a successful computer specialist working for a big firm who is passed over for promotion in favor of an old flame named Meredith Johnson(played by Demi Moore). She is very ambitious, and seems to have undue influence over the CEO, which proves to be the case as Meredith tries to seduce Tom after hours in her office. Tom, a happily married man, is tempted by her beauty, but resists. He is later shocked to learn that she has reported him for sexual harassment, so he has no choice but to sue her, which endangers his future within the company, but Tom will discover that things are not as simple as they seem, and Meredith has another agenda at work... Based on Michael Crichton's novel, and well directed by Barry Levinson, this features fine acting by its stars, and a fascinating story with many twists and turns, that leads to a satisfying finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Naked Truth...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cronostitan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the specialist of the trendy thriller, this movie rather well pinned also speaks about the difficult square in the society that all those can occupy sometimes who do not enough sit - at least not endowed with varied and diverse protections. What it will be necessary to raise it is that Crichton dodges these long sequences of court with strong theatrical echo which we undergo very often among soaps in the TV (and also in John Grisham's books and in adventures of the TV show Ally Mc Beal), instead of it he joins in the life the office among this great number of "small" details that all those sometimes forget who do not work: another tour de force very rich in teaching... Because freedom is also a question of money although people are not globally more free than before in the old time, it is simply wrong!! Careful thus in "politically correct" falsified, in the traps, in the blackmail, in the propaganda, in the jealousy...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Full disclosure: this movie stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suppose the idea of Michael Douglas being sexually harassed by Demi Moore could be intriguing. Could be. But in this movie it doesn't end up being intriguing at all. The story fizzles out before it ever really gets going. The movie goes on and on without ever really going anywhere. There's no spark, no sizzle. Attempts at humor fall horribly flat. The only laughs in this movie come from laughing at just how bad it is, most notably in the big climactic virtual reality scene. Wait, big climactic virtual reality scene? Yeah, it's just as stupid as it sounds, an awful idea executed so badly you can't help but laugh at how truly terrible it is. This is a movie which fails in pretty much every way possible. Douglas plays Tom Sanders, the head of production at some high-tech Seattle outfit. There's a big merger on the horizon, Tom expects a big promotion to go with it. But the job he covets goes to Meredith Johnson, a one-time girlfriend of his who celebrates their reunion by trying to rape him in her office. When Tom says no, not before having a little fun of course because the movie needs its obligatory sex scene, Meredith promises to ruin him. And the next day she duly accuses him of sexual harassment. He gets himself a lawyer, accuses her and it's a big he-said, she-said deal which only serves to bore those of us who are unfortunate enough to be watching. Drama and tension are in very short supply. Tedium is the order of the day. Moore's absolutely atrocious acting doesn't help matters. My goodness, she is terrible. The story slogs along, everyone ganging up on poor Tom in some horribly uninteresting conspiracy. It's not just Meredith out to get him, this goes all the way up to the big boss at the top. That character, played by Donald Sutherland, is I suppose meant to seem sinister but the way Sutherland mugs and overacts he just comes off as a buffoon. Just another example of the way this movie completely misses the mark. And just when you think it can't possibly get any worse along comes that absurd virtual reality scene which is simply one of the dumbest things ever seen in any movie. Even after that laughable "climax" the movie doesn't have the decency to just end. More pointless, boring twists to come. The whole thing is just interminable. Movies don't get much worse than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Douglas contends with business foe Demi Moore determined to oust him
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Disclosure" is a smoothly done, pleasurable and suspenseful watch in which the action never flags. This is a good solid Hollywood product by all involved. Michael Douglas does his usual fine job -- he makes look easy what is not at all easy -- playing a Silicon Valley production specialist. For reasons unknown, the production line product is failing while the prototypes work. He is being made to look incompetent. Meanwhile, he has a new boss, Demi Moore, who was his old flame. And the big boss, Donald Sutherland, is negotiating a merger that will enrich everyone in the firm, stock options and all that. Preventing Douglas from tracking down the production line issues in Malaysia are this merger and Moore's plot to accuse Douglas of sexual harassment. Douglas fights back, without anger and bitterness, by mediation, accusing her correctly of harassing him. Meanwhile, he's trying to figure out how production has gone wrong. In the narrow world of an operations specialist, he doesn't suspect behind the scenes machinations. But he has a "friend" higher up (a guardian angel) who does, and who spurs him on via anonymous e-mails to dig deeper. As the merger pressures those around him, all of whom stand to gain handsomely by stock options, he finds his associates melting away and, more or less, siding with pressures brought by Sutherland to get Douglas to paper over the production issues. Sutherland absolutely looks the part and steals every scene he is in. His part in all this is ambiguous enough that he can bob and weave and land on his feet. He's a slick one. He didn't get to head the company without this skill. And so we enter the world of Silicon Valley too, and that's part of the movie's charm. The interior sets of the business itself bring this to life, and complement the business rivalries and machinations. The 128m running time passes quickly. Douglas learns a thing or two. The supporting roles are well cast and played. The movie is a business thriller, with the emphasis on emotional pressures, calculation, and psychological conflicts that bring out the varying personalities and motivations of those involved. Dramatic elements are present but not over-emphasized.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Demi Moore As A Femme Fatale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is a thriller directed by Barry Levinson that stars Michael Douglas and Demi Moore. It is based on Michael Crichton's novel of the same title.The cast also includes Donald Sutherland, Rosemary Forsyth and Dennis Miller.The film is a combination mystery and thriller about office politics and intrigue in the computer industry in the mid-1990s. Also,it includes the issue of sexual harassment. Tom Sanders is an executive at DigiCom, a leading computer software firm. The company is about to launch a new virtual reality-based data storage system that is expected to revolutionize the industry, and Bob Garvin, the owner of the company, is in the midst of negotiating a merger that could bring $100 million into the firm. However, while Tom is expecting a promotion, he discovers the position has been given instead to a new hire, Meredith Johnson, with whom Tom had an affair years ago, before he was married. After her first day of work, Meredith invites Tom up to her office and makes a concerted attempt to seduce him; while Tom doesn't fight off her advances with very much gusto at first, eventually he decides things have gone too far and leaves in a huff. The next morning, Meredith accuses Tom of sexual harassment, and he realizes this was merely a power ploy to get him out of DigiCom for good; Tom, determined to fight, files a counter-suit, which makes him no friends at the company, since rocking the boat too hard could very well scotch the merger. The story takes some clever twists and turns as it develops into a full- fledged psychological thriller that is effective and gripping, if occasionally contrived as a result of over-plotting.The film is genuinely gripping and well-written.As for the performances,Moore makes an awesome femme fatale while Douglas triumps over evil in a big way.But it is a watchable film as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Crichton winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) not only finds himself passed over for an expected promotion, but his new boss turns out to be an old flame, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). When Meredith makes strong overtures to him, Tom initially goes along, only to refuse her. Furious at his rejection, Meredith accuses him of sexual harassment, so he makes a counter-accusation. Set against the corporate and executive positioning of a complex business deal, Michael Crichton's story (oh how we miss that man's creative output) strikes an interesting balance between techno-thriller, sexual politics commentary, courtroom drama, and urban paranoia thriller. The story is terrific - complex but always followable, gripping and involving, and with emotional ramifications as the essentially decent and blameless Sanders finds himself in an impossible situation. This is a good film, with one of the best payoffs ever, and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the book. No good comes from this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everybody's out to get Michael Douglas. Marketed as a controversial examination of a man's charge of sexual harassment against a female co-worker, "Disclosure" is really about paranoia. The reverse discrimination angle is a (albeit large) plot point, but it isn't the crux of the movie. Which is where the movie takes a sharp turn off a cliff. Douglas is a software engineer for a large corporation, and he's been turned down for the big promotion - in favor of a man-eating former lover (Demi Moore). Moore, the new V.P. invites Douglas to her office for a catch-up session, and things get downright steamy. But Douglas is a family man, and he walks away from an enraged (rebuffed) Moore. The next day, Douglas walks into the office to the accusation that he was the one doing the harassing. A very large chunk of the movie is devoted to the harassment charge, with Douglas calling in the help of a media-hungry lawyer (Roma Maffia) to help him with his case. Sordid details emerge, cracks appear in the Douglas household, and and it's not a pretty skirmish. But Moore is just a cog in a larger scheme to eventually make Douglas look incompetent and throw him out on the street. That's what this movie is really about: Douglas is worried about his job. It's all a very conspiratorial and manipulative oppression of the poor white family man, complete with hushed voices in the office. Throw in some deliciously early '90s CGI and a ridiculously lame virtual reality subplot, and you've got the market fresh makings of an overly- long film that never rises above goofy. 3/10; a real chore
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Office Politics, Paranoia & The Abuse Of Power
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By the 1990s when an increasing number of women were filling top jobs in the corporate world, a story about a woman sexually harassing a man became a plausible scenario and the topical and controversial nature of the subject resonated strongly enough with the public at that time to make "Disclosure" a great box office success. Whilst the sexual harassment element of the story was shocking and attention grabbing, it soon became apparent that this was just part of a far larger and more pervasive issue i.e. the abuse of power. In the workplace, where social conventions, various legal constraints and political correctness all come into play, there is still no escape from the kind of management conspiracies, office politics and duplicity which are depicted so effectively in "Disclosure" or the kinds of distrust and paranoia that they can so easily generate. Tom Sanders (Michael Douglas) heads one of the divisions of a Seattle computer company and is engaged in the development of a product which is vitally important to the success of a planned and very lucrative merger with another company. There are some problems with the product which Tom and his team are currently dealing with and are under considerable pressure to resolve. As a result of some changes which are taking place within the company, Tom's confident that he'll be promoted but it soon transpires that he's been passed over and the job has been given to one of his ex-girlfriends, Meredith Johnson (Demi Moore). On her first day in the job, Meredith arranges a late meeting with Tom to discuss his division's work but during their meeting she aggressively tries to seduce him and is furious when, after a considerable struggle, she's unsuccessful. Meredith responds to Tom's rejection by accusing him of sexual harassment and asserting that in the circumstances, there's no way that she'd be able to work with him again. The company want to avoid any publicity that could have an adverse impact on the upcoming merger and so try to get Tom to take a transfer to another job in their Austin branch. He can't countenance this idea because of the negative effect it would have on his career and is in a very tight spot. Help unexpectedly arrives in the form of an anonymous e-mail which recommends that he consult an attorney called Catherine Alvarez (Roma Maffia) who's a specialist in sexual harassment cases. Tom decides to fight back and files a counter-suit. The process he has to go through to achieve justice is difficult and painful but irrefutable proof of his innocence is produced and the company agrees to retain him and give him a pay rise. The relief that Tom feels after being cleared of the charges against him is short lived as it quickly becomes apparent that efforts which were originally initiated by Meredith to make him look incompetent have now drawn wider support and he's being set up to be publicly humiliated and undermined at a high profile shareholders' meeting. The way in which Tom copes with this threat then provides the story with its intriguing conclusion. The events in "Disclosure" all take place within the space of one intense week in which Tom's normally affluent and comfortable lifestyle is disrupted as his disappointment at being passed over for promotion turns into discomfort when he discovers the identity of his new boss and then horror as he's threatened with the loss of his job, his wife, his family and his stock options. The false accusation made against him, the plots to make him look incompetent and a workplace where no one can be trusted, create a climate of paranoia which is reinforced when some of his previous innocent actions are characterised as something more sinister and the support of his colleagues is systematically eroded by those high up in the company structure. Michael Douglas gives a good solid performance as the beleaguered Tom and Demi Moore is marvellous as the cold and cruel villain of the piece. Donald Sutherland and Roma Maffia also stand out in their supporting roles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexual harassment is about power. When did I have the power? When?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disclosure is directed by Barry Levinson and co-adapted to screenplay by Paul Attanasio and Michael Crichton from Crichton's own novel of the same name. It stars Michael Douglas, Demi Moore, Donald Sutherland, Roma Maffia, Dylan Baker, Caroline Goodall and Rosemary Forsyth. Music is scored by Ennio Morricone. Tom Sanders (Douglas) is an executive at DigiCom, a high-tech computer company, who hopes that now it's finally his time to get promotion. Passed over for an outsider, he's further irked when it turns out to be Meredith Johnson (Moore), an old passionate flame of his from years previously. When Meredith arranges for a meeting between the two later that evening, Tom finds himself sexually harassed by her. Spurning her aggressive overtures, Tom is shocked to learn the next day that she has filed a charge of sexual harassment against him. He naturally counters the charge, but this opens up a can of worms for both him and the future of DigiCom. The 1990s practically belonged to Michael Crichton, it seemed for a time that everything he wrote was adapted to the big screen for some form of entertainment. With Jurassic Park still warm and still garnering bucket loads of cash, two other Crichton adaptations worked their way into theatres; both of which were a world away from the family friendly extravaganza of Jurassic Park. One was Rising Sun, a messy wasted potential of a movie, the other was Disclosure, a zeitgeist snatcher that seized the moment. The topic, and the novelty of flipping the gender aggressor, was always going to make Disclosure of much interest, thus the film and the novel made big money: aided still further by the hot casting of Douglas and Moore, who were still draw cards in the early 90s. Crichton, after being displeased with other adaptations of his work, got big say on the screenplay as a written project. So with director Levinson in tow, he set about pushing the buttons of his audience, attempting to continue the heated debates that were brought about previously from Douglas' Fatal Attraction and Basic Instinct. If it's Crichton's or Levinson's fault that it didn't work out that way? I'm not sure, but fact is, is that Disclosure really wasn't that potent back then, and certainly now it's not even lukewarm. There's too much techno babble going on, and an over keenness to stick the nose up at the big business vultures picking the flesh off of the lesser minions. Entering the last half hour of the film, it's easy to forget there has actually been a sexual harassment case! Here's the crux of the matter, if going in to it for a first time viewing expecting this to be a powder-keg of sexual harassment muckiness and legal intrigue, then you are in for a big disappointment. I know, because I was one of the paying patrons at the theatre back in 94! You sense that one of the makers got a bit carried away Yet the film still has much going for it if stripped of that expectation, not least that it packs a pile of tension in that last half hour and the finale is rather rewarding. I'd go as far to say I'm a fan of the film, but it's not the film I originally went to see! There's a trio of interesting and differing female characters at the front of the narrative, even if Moore's stair-master vixen isn't exactly developed beyond being a bitch, and the virtual reality sequences have an appealing charm about them. The cast are turning in good ones, with a notable shout out to Caroline Goodall who wisely underplays it as the wife. While the interior set design (Gary Lewis/Joseph Hodges) for the DigiCom HQ is wonderful with its 90s excess of glass meeting mirrors and open spaces. Which leaves us with what? A film that is not what you expect! Which in this case is both disappointing and a surprise. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stand-alone thriller with a mish-mash of intriguing themes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tale of sexual harassment in the office with a twist  this time, the guy is the victim and the woman the pursuer. Yes, it's another thriller that builds on Michael Douglas's typecasting as a victim of powerful women (following FATAL ATTRACTION and BASIC INSTINCT) but this one plays all the right cards. Part workplace drama, part courtroom thriller, and all the time invested with now-dated-but-then-cutting-edge technology (email, virtual reality) I found Disclosure to be never less than intriguing and well made. The Crichton source material helps, of course; I haven't yet seen a Crichton film that hasn't been thought-provoking and entertaining (even the worst, CONGO, isn't entirely without merit, although the book is loads better). I've been seeing a lot of Douglas in recent months and my opinion of him has steadily improved to the degree that I can't remember him giving a bad performance. He's fine here, providing a key likable anchor for the film to revolve around, and playing opposite him Demi Moore is also a surprise: she oozes sexuality and selfishness in equal measure, proving a powerful enemy at all times. Moore isn't the world's greatest actress but this might well be her best performance in a film. The courtroom scenes, tense and full of electricity, are undoubtedly the film's highlights and there are supporting actors to relish (Donald Sutherland, Allan Rich and in particular a slimy Dylan Baker). It's not a perfect film, but it is a reminder of the kind of solid, sensual thriller that got made during a sometimes forgotten decade of filmmaking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
