<filme>
 <id>
  432
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0032455
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1940
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Fantasia
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A collection of animated interpretations of great works of Western classical music.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Disney animators set pictures to Western classical music as Leopold Stokowski conducts the Philadelphia Orchestra. "The Sorcerer's Apprentice" features Mickey Mouse as an aspiring magician who oversteps his limits. "The Rite of Spring" tells the story of evolution, from single-celled animals to the death of the dinosaurs. "Dance of the Hours" is a comic ballet performed by ostriches, hippos, elephants, and alligators. "Night on Bald Mountain" and "Ave Maria" set the forces of darkness and light against each other as a devilish revel is interrupted by the coming of a new day.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Animation
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   classical music
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   elephant
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   apprentice
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dance
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mountain
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   James Algar
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Samuel Armstrong
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Joe Grant
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Dick Huemer
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Leopold Stokowski
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Deems Taylor
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Corey Burton
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different, Not Meaningful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reuben Barbosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my life I've attempted to watch Fantasia at least 8 times, and every time I've always turned it off 30 to 40 minutes in. Does that warrant the film to get a 1/10? No, it has great animation but I still think the movie is a boring bunch of tar. The people who like Fantasia tend to say the film is good for it's emotional simplicity, creativity, and darker tone (when compared to other Disney films). I feel these reasons are somewhat ridiculous since even though I know when the film wants be to feel happy or sad, it still doesn't detract from the fact that's all the film has going for it: emotion. As someone who loves symbolism in film, I have never seen Fantasia show any images that would allow the viewer to think. Fantasia is like therapy, if you want to feel happy you can and if you want to feel sad you can. It's a movie where you just turn off your brain and enjoy the colours and music. Is there anything wrong with that? No. But, I still hate the fact that everyone treats this like 2001. The main difference between 2001 and Fantasia is that 2001 had an actual message it wanted to tell. Granted, that message is not entirely known by people but it is still a thought provoking film. Fantasia was an exercise in how the plot of a film can be told like 2001, but it feels like in the end it just had nothing to say. That's the main thing I find boring about the film, the fact that I have nothing to think about since it has nothing to say. I wouldn't call the film pretentious but I feel that fans of the film are pretentious for thinking a film that merely gives us emotions is the most revolutionary thing ever since it's just with animation and music. Any film can give you emotion with characters, plot, and meaning. Was Fantasia different? Yes. Does it have meaning? I don't think so but that's my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disney's most ambitious feature to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like DW Griffith's silent epic Intolerance (1916), Disney's most ambitious work Fantasia (1940) is a film more respected than loved. It is an experimental work, lacking the warmth of the most popular Disney films but beating out nearly all of them in terms of artistry and animation (its only rival being Pinocchio (1940)). Indeed, this might be the one Disney film created for an adult audience alone, even though more thoughtful children will be able to enjoy it. The Disney studio would never do something so bold as this ever again. Oh sure, they made Fantasia 2000 (1999) during the final years of the Disney Renaissance, but let's face it, that was made with toddlers in mind. It doesn't run nearly as long, insults the audience's intelligence with those dreadful celebrity introductions, and the new segments never measure up to the maturity and sublime artistry of the original. The Disney name is too closely linked with "children's entertainment" for them to boldly experiment at this point. That Fantasia was made at all is a miracle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fantasia" is truly a film ahead of its time and it needs to be seen in able for one to understand its importance in film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there is one thing that Walt Disney knew about better than anyone else, it was that the combination of music and animation is one of the most important combinations since bread and butter. This can best explain why most of Disney's animated features are all musicals. It's because Walt Disney strongly believed that music and sound were essential keys towards great animated features and shorts. One could make a good argument that his 3rd full-length animated feature, Fantasia (1940), was created as further proof regarding why he believed music was so essential to the world of animation. Fantasia is a unique animated feature in terms of its narrative. It starts out with an orchestra taking their places as if they were preparing for a concert. Then, the main narrator of this picture by the name of Deems Taylor emerges and introduces us to a new form of entertainment called Fantasia. We are told that during this new form of entertainment, we will see the images that classical music had inspired in the minds of Walt Disney's massive staff of artists. In other words, we are seeing pieces of famous classical music being brought to life visually based on what Disney's artists think these pieces are about. We are also told that there are three types of musical pieces in this program: music that tells a definite story, music that paints a series of pictures, and "absolute music" that exists simply for its own sake. This animated feature basically consists of eight separate segments which all are devoted to one of the three types of music. Sometimes, one could make an argument that some segments have more than one of the three types of music, since some segments are more clearly cut in the type of music they're going for than other segments. For instance, the first segment "Toccata and Fugue in D Minor" is clearly an example of absolute music that exists simply for its own sake. All this segment composes of is visuals that one might think of whenever this classical music is being played. But then there are segments like "The Rite of Spring" which could easily count as music that paints a series of pictures as well as music that tells a definite story. The reason I believe this segment could apply to both is because while it tells us the history of the dinosaurs, you aren't exactly sure what to make of the overall main vision Disney was going for with this segment in the end. This is precisely why Fantasia is such a fascinating piece of filmmaking, because what it shows its audience is so unconventional and diverse that it's hard not to admire the fact that it's so unique with its story structure. After seeing this picture a couple times, I truly have a better understanding of why Fantasia was immensely influential in the film industry, particularly with the medium of music videos. If you think more about it, this film is basically a series of silent animated short films perfectly synchronized to famous pieces of classical music. Fantasia would easily qualify as one of the films I would be most interested in learning more about the making behind. I would be more than eager to learn what Walt Disney's animators thought when he wanted to pursue executing this specific project so soon after the ambitious production of Snow White. I would also be interested in learning the process behind the animation for these segments and how the animators synchronized the animation and music as well as they did, since I know the animation process was probably painstaking to say the least. Is this a film that will please everyone's tastes? I don't think so, since it's definitely an acquired taste for some. After all, Fantasia is considered a big step for Disney fans to take since it is so different from anything Disney ever did that it could throw them for a loop. Are there some slow moments? I'd say that this film gets off to a little bit of a slow start, but by the time the film's most famous segment "The Sorcerer's Apprentice" with Mickey Mouse comes around, it only gets better. Was the intermission involving the soundtrack corny and unnecessary? While I certainly can say it is by modern standards, I'll be fair by stating that this came out at a time when some audiences had trouble getting used to the then-new Technicolor process and their eyes had to take a break from the bright colors on screen. In short, Fantasia is truly a film that was way ahead of its time in almost every aspect imaginable. From outstanding segments like "The Rite of Spring" and "Night on Bald Mountain", to the excellent orchestration of the classical music by Leopold Stokowski and his orchestra, to the tremendous craft of the animation. It's one of those rare films in which the only way you can understand its importance in the history of cinema is to see for yourself. So what are you waiting for?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The epitome of the animated musical genre!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KadrianBlackwolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back when this film was made there were two broad schools of thought on animated films. One school believed that the animated action was the main point of an animated film and that the music should fit the animation. Sadly, this is how almost all animation is done today. The other school believed that the music should be the main focus and that the animation should enhance the music by providing an artistic visual representation. This is the school that "Fantasia" represents. I love this film and have watched it (or at least listened to it) countless times. The musical selections are among the best that classical music has to offer, and the animation and styling of the characters are classical Disney at its best. The scenes depicted vary from the hilarious to the terrifying to the awe-inspiring. Most satisfying are those that take your breath away and hold you in fascination with their beauty and elegance. My only complaint about the film is Disney's choice of Leopold Stokowski as conductor. Stokowski arrogantly took it upon himself to "improve" Mussorgsky's "Night on Bare Mountain," and effectively ruined the best parts of the score. Compare Stokowski's version with the original and you'll see what I mean. But with the exception of Stokowski's occasional interference, "Fantasia" is the best animated musical film ever produced.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Tenth Favorite Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1940's Fantasia Is My Tenth Favorite Film Of All Time, I Like It Because It's Has Great Animation Set To Classical Music, I Do Like The Live-Action Parts With Deems Taylor Where He Tells About Each Segment, My Favorite Segments I Like In This Are, Toccata And Fugue In D Minor, The Sorcerer's Apprentice, Rite Of Spring, A Night On Bald Mountain And Ave Maria, This Is My Favorite Animated Film And Also My Favorite Disney Film, I Really Don't Want To Get This Film On DVD Because My DVD Collection Is Done With And It's Full And Done With, The Only Version Of 1940's Fantasia That I Like The 2000 60th Anniversary Version With Corey Burton Doing The Voice Of Deems Taylor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike-duffy-486-49185
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fanatasia is not a film, it is an experience. Fantasia took a big risk back in 1940 when Walt Disney decided that he wanted to try something new. Fantasia has left a mark on history as one of the most unique and beautiful films ever created. Fantasia does not have a narrative story, it is shown through multiple 20-25 minute stories that do not have dialogue. The stories are told through music conducted by the great Leopold Stokowski. The music matches the visuals perfectly. The film opens with us listening to the orchestra play Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, accompanied by good visuals. The film then carries on to the six story lines which use classical music by some of the greats such as Beethoven and Tchaikovsky. All of these story lines are magnificently animated. Picking my favourite segment was not easy because they were all perfect. The segments include the creation of earth, The change of seasons on the envoirment and the devil vs God. My personal favourite is probably the mythology segment where we listen to Beethoven's Pastoral Symphony with animation of centaurs, fairies, gods and fawns. What really surprised me about Fantasia was the messages that were delivered in each segment that was up to the interpretation of the audience. For example, The Sorceror's Apprentice deals with a situation displaying what could happen if we had all the power in the world. The Dance of the Hours sequence deals with the innocence of the animal kingdom. These are just some examples of the power of visuals and music. What really makes Fantasia a masterpiece is how it ends. The final sequence which many people know of is the Night on Bald Mountain where we see the full power of the devil. Even if you are not religious(such as myself) the power in this sequence can touch anybody. The segment shows the devil awakening on a mountain and he begins to call spirits, ghost, demons, etc to the mountain where he proceeds to destroy them even in death with fire. The devil is stopped by God who puts him back to rest. After this we hear the Ave Maria and see monks with torches walking to a cathedral. The messages in this scene show probably the most powerful messages Disney has ever produced. Fanastia is a masterpiece plain and simple. Everything about this film works. The sequences are in the right order, the music is beautiful and the animation is breathtaking. As I commented earlier, Fantasia is not a movie it is an experience. The film is not really meant for kid. This is not because of the content but I only question how kids will handle a movie with no dialogue. I speak from experience. This film serves as Walt Disney's masterpiece and very much deserves that title. This is not just Disney at its best, it is probably one of the greatest films ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3rd out of 5 in the Golden Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantasia was released in the same year as Pinocchio (1940), but this film was released 9 months later in November. This film has he perfect amount of classical music, breathtaking animation, and memorable shorts to make the best package film ever made. Even though this film is 2 hours long, it does not feel that way, as you are just enjoying the shorts, which will go by so quickly. The best and the most iconic short in the film was "The Sorcerer's Apprentice". This is the one where Mickey tests out his master's tricks. The other shorts like "Rite of Spring", "Nutcracker Suite" and the others hold up as well. The children will enjoy the pretty animation and colours, while the adults will like the music and substance. Give it a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles_Hardy
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fantasia" is a wonderful blend of live action and animation, but not like the latter Disney films of "Mary Poppins" and "Petes Dragon." The live action sequences are that of Deems Taylor narrating the film as well as setting up the stories. Leopold Stowkowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra give us the music to fit to the beautiful pictures. The film was originally intended to be released each year (as a roadshow film) thereafter with different scenes intact as well as some old ones. This was not the case when WWII broke out and the US got involved. Walt Disney's vision would not be complete until "Fantasia 2000" was released in 1999. Probably the most important and proclaimed piece of "Fantasia" would be The Sorcerer's Apprentice starring Mickey Mouse. In fact, this sequence was reused in the sequel film in 1999 to achieve the roadshow feel that Disney wanted. It was also this sequence in the film that spawned another film in 2010 starring Nicolas Cage, "The Sorcerer's Apprentice." A wonderful film and one that will delve into your imagination and take you places you thought you may never see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Adult Fantasy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psychocosmic-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a person who consider Art, or rich Art, being able to elevate our minds and from which we are able to draw huge amount of information. Fantasia is not only a unique film, its also the only film which with musical pieces illustrates evolution at work and prehistoric scenes pretty scary and violent with the last groups of dinosaurs parading towards doom. Development and Extermination. Also, here you have sceneries of the Hellenian mythological world portraying the mating ritual and the Bacchus celebration, "sex, drugs and party!", and the battle between the light and the shadow world - the world of death and decay and that of light and peace. We get the living Nature in its transgressions through the different seasons, comical portraits of animals and veggies impersonating humans, and a moral tale of a young who forgot that he is not the tutor yet, etc. The basic thread of the movie is the music of course! To begin the film with J S Bach's Toccata and Fuge in d minor, is not only supercool, but is the perfect upwarming piece. As the music itself is pretty impossible to create a simple visual story with characters from, the visuals we see are closer to abstract and expressionism in form, with natural elements to illustrate Bach's famous cosmic flow of his fugues! Walt Disney was so serious with this project, that a psychological consult with experience of peyote, was hired to give guide lines to the different segments, not to mention all the ideas which came from the big crowd of artists that was working with the pictures and the translation of the music into pictures. Just like other Disney films of the period, like Three Caballeros 1946 and certain scenes in Dumbo and others, could easily be placed side by side with Yellow Submarine and experimental underground shorts in the late 60's, in a period when LSD, Psilocybin mushrooms and cannabis was the inspiration, for both young hippies and soul searching intellectuals. Disney was really psychedelic! The imagination at work in this film is so rich, that one can view it over and over again, to find details as well as new interpretations to the different segments. When viewing this multi artwork from beginning to end, through the music to the visuals and its themes, it seems to encompass the human and natural world on Earth,in a trancendental way, so it seems to be the perfect movie to send with a probe out into outer space, hoping to encounter an alien species, who might be able to watch it! They would not only consider it a colorful gem, but would find the film be a treasure for understanding Humans from the planet Earth. Of course, I am exaggerating, but still, if NASA could pack a satellite with chosen music, which I know they had, why not a movie? Anyways, this is a way for me to say, that Fantasia, as the film looks, could not have been made today, as the most powerful film companies would not bet a huge some of money on a project like this. Also, a feature film, all drawn and painted by hand, gives a decidedly more impressive look than one that is made in a computer. The fact is, that around 1939 - 1940, in the midst of Second World War, some of the most popular, hailed by critics and audience alike, greatest films were made. If the time consuming, painstaking efforts behind Pinoccio, Wizard of Oz, The Thief of Bagdad and Fantasia all are made to be true fantasy films, they seem to tell us that during war time it better works to make "timeless" films. In other words, films which not occupy themselves with the ever changing societies of Humanity and the issues of the times in which they were made. Instead, and this is what make them work as true art, they seem to speak to us, in matter of symbols, archetypes and themes which have been with us through the history of time. It could be seen as a work of a great shaman, who wants to remind us about the most important and utterly most sublimely beautiful things we have on this Earth. The Greatest Movie Achievement Ever In History! I only give full points (10/10) to films that are more than a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michelle Palmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I must say that my son and I were very, very impressed with the art work in this. Considering this movie was made in the 1940's and how they did the animated features back then, it took a lot of hard work, dedication, and talent for all involved to do this. I was amazed!!! My favorite scene is the Nutcracker piece. My second favorite was mickey mouse :-) We didn't really care for the others (though the Soundtrack part was pretty cute. We skipped about three chapters simply because we were not interested... We'll watch the parts we like in the future, but skip over the rest...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different, Not Meaningful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reuben Barbosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my life I've attempted to watch Fantasia at least 8 times, and every time I've always turned it off 30 to 40 minutes in. Does that warrant the film to get a 1/10? No, it has great animation but I still think the movie is a boring bunch of tar. The people who like Fantasia tend to say the film is good for it's emotional simplicity, creativity, and darker tone (when compared to other Disney films). I feel these reasons are somewhat ridiculous since even though I know when the film wants be to feel happy or sad, it still doesn't detract from the fact that's all the film has going for it: emotion. As someone who loves symbolism in film, I have never seen Fantasia show any images that would allow the viewer to think. Fantasia is like therapy, if you want to feel happy you can and if you want to feel sad you can. It's a movie where you just turn off your brain and enjoy the colours and music. Is there anything wrong with that? No. But, I still hate the fact that everyone treats this like 2001. The main difference between 2001 and Fantasia is that 2001 had an actual message it wanted to tell. Granted, that message is not entirely known by people but it is still a thought provoking film. Fantasia was an exercise in how the plot of a film can be told like 2001, but it feels like in the end it just had nothing to say. That's the main thing I find boring about the film, the fact that I have nothing to think about since it has nothing to say. I wouldn't call the film pretentious but I feel that fans of the film are pretentious for thinking a film that merely gives us emotions is the most revolutionary thing ever since it's just with animation and music. Any film can give you emotion with characters, plot, and meaning. Was Fantasia different? Yes. Does it have meaning? I don't think so but that's my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disney's most ambitious feature to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like DW Griffith's silent epic Intolerance (1916), Disney's most ambitious work Fantasia (1940) is a film more respected than loved. It is an experimental work, lacking the warmth of the most popular Disney films but beating out nearly all of them in terms of artistry and animation (its only rival being Pinocchio (1940)). Indeed, this might be the one Disney film created for an adult audience alone, even though more thoughtful children will be able to enjoy it. The Disney studio would never do something so bold as this ever again. Oh sure, they made Fantasia 2000 (1999) during the final years of the Disney Renaissance, but let's face it, that was made with toddlers in mind. It doesn't run nearly as long, insults the audience's intelligence with those dreadful celebrity introductions, and the new segments never measure up to the maturity and sublime artistry of the original. The Disney name is too closely linked with "children's entertainment" for them to boldly experiment at this point. That Fantasia was made at all is a miracle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fantasia" is truly a film ahead of its time and it needs to be seen in able for one to understand its importance in film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there is one thing that Walt Disney knew about better than anyone else, it was that the combination of music and animation is one of the most important combinations since bread and butter. This can best explain why most of Disney's animated features are all musicals. It's because Walt Disney strongly believed that music and sound were essential keys towards great animated features and shorts. One could make a good argument that his 3rd full-length animated feature, Fantasia (1940), was created as further proof regarding why he believed music was so essential to the world of animation. Fantasia is a unique animated feature in terms of its narrative. It starts out with an orchestra taking their places as if they were preparing for a concert. Then, the main narrator of this picture by the name of Deems Taylor emerges and introduces us to a new form of entertainment called Fantasia. We are told that during this new form of entertainment, we will see the images that classical music had inspired in the minds of Walt Disney's massive staff of artists. In other words, we are seeing pieces of famous classical music being brought to life visually based on what Disney's artists think these pieces are about. We are also told that there are three types of musical pieces in this program: music that tells a definite story, music that paints a series of pictures, and "absolute music" that exists simply for its own sake. This animated feature basically consists of eight separate segments which all are devoted to one of the three types of music. Sometimes, one could make an argument that some segments have more than one of the three types of music, since some segments are more clearly cut in the type of music they're going for than other segments. For instance, the first segment "Toccata and Fugue in D Minor" is clearly an example of absolute music that exists simply for its own sake. All this segment composes of is visuals that one might think of whenever this classical music is being played. But then there are segments like "The Rite of Spring" which could easily count as music that paints a series of pictures as well as music that tells a definite story. The reason I believe this segment could apply to both is because while it tells us the history of the dinosaurs, you aren't exactly sure what to make of the overall main vision Disney was going for with this segment in the end. This is precisely why Fantasia is such a fascinating piece of filmmaking, because what it shows its audience is so unconventional and diverse that it's hard not to admire the fact that it's so unique with its story structure. After seeing this picture a couple times, I truly have a better understanding of why Fantasia was immensely influential in the film industry, particularly with the medium of music videos. If you think more about it, this film is basically a series of silent animated short films perfectly synchronized to famous pieces of classical music. Fantasia would easily qualify as one of the films I would be most interested in learning more about the making behind. I would be more than eager to learn what Walt Disney's animators thought when he wanted to pursue executing this specific project so soon after the ambitious production of Snow White. I would also be interested in learning the process behind the animation for these segments and how the animators synchronized the animation and music as well as they did, since I know the animation process was probably painstaking to say the least. Is this a film that will please everyone's tastes? I don't think so, since it's definitely an acquired taste for some. After all, Fantasia is considered a big step for Disney fans to take since it is so different from anything Disney ever did that it could throw them for a loop. Are there some slow moments? I'd say that this film gets off to a little bit of a slow start, but by the time the film's most famous segment "The Sorcerer's Apprentice" with Mickey Mouse comes around, it only gets better. Was the intermission involving the soundtrack corny and unnecessary? While I certainly can say it is by modern standards, I'll be fair by stating that this came out at a time when some audiences had trouble getting used to the then-new Technicolor process and their eyes had to take a break from the bright colors on screen. In short, Fantasia is truly a film that was way ahead of its time in almost every aspect imaginable. From outstanding segments like "The Rite of Spring" and "Night on Bald Mountain", to the excellent orchestration of the classical music by Leopold Stokowski and his orchestra, to the tremendous craft of the animation. It's one of those rare films in which the only way you can understand its importance in the history of cinema is to see for yourself. So what are you waiting for?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The epitome of the animated musical genre!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KadrianBlackwolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back when this film was made there were two broad schools of thought on animated films. One school believed that the animated action was the main point of an animated film and that the music should fit the animation. Sadly, this is how almost all animation is done today. The other school believed that the music should be the main focus and that the animation should enhance the music by providing an artistic visual representation. This is the school that "Fantasia" represents. I love this film and have watched it (or at least listened to it) countless times. The musical selections are among the best that classical music has to offer, and the animation and styling of the characters are classical Disney at its best. The scenes depicted vary from the hilarious to the terrifying to the awe-inspiring. Most satisfying are those that take your breath away and hold you in fascination with their beauty and elegance. My only complaint about the film is Disney's choice of Leopold Stokowski as conductor. Stokowski arrogantly took it upon himself to "improve" Mussorgsky's "Night on Bare Mountain," and effectively ruined the best parts of the score. Compare Stokowski's version with the original and you'll see what I mean. But with the exception of Stokowski's occasional interference, "Fantasia" is the best animated musical film ever produced.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Tenth Favorite Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1940's Fantasia Is My Tenth Favorite Film Of All Time, I Like It Because It's Has Great Animation Set To Classical Music, I Do Like The Live-Action Parts With Deems Taylor Where He Tells About Each Segment, My Favorite Segments I Like In This Are, Toccata And Fugue In D Minor, The Sorcerer's Apprentice, Rite Of Spring, A Night On Bald Mountain And Ave Maria, This Is My Favorite Animated Film And Also My Favorite Disney Film, I Really Don't Want To Get This Film On DVD Because My DVD Collection Is Done With And It's Full And Done With, The Only Version Of 1940's Fantasia That I Like The 2000 60th Anniversary Version With Corey Burton Doing The Voice Of Deems Taylor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike-duffy-486-49185
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fanatasia is not a film, it is an experience. Fantasia took a big risk back in 1940 when Walt Disney decided that he wanted to try something new. Fantasia has left a mark on history as one of the most unique and beautiful films ever created. Fantasia does not have a narrative story, it is shown through multiple 20-25 minute stories that do not have dialogue. The stories are told through music conducted by the great Leopold Stokowski. The music matches the visuals perfectly. The film opens with us listening to the orchestra play Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, accompanied by good visuals. The film then carries on to the six story lines which use classical music by some of the greats such as Beethoven and Tchaikovsky. All of these story lines are magnificently animated. Picking my favourite segment was not easy because they were all perfect. The segments include the creation of earth, The change of seasons on the envoirment and the devil vs God. My personal favourite is probably the mythology segment where we listen to Beethoven's Pastoral Symphony with animation of centaurs, fairies, gods and fawns. What really surprised me about Fantasia was the messages that were delivered in each segment that was up to the interpretation of the audience. For example, The Sorceror's Apprentice deals with a situation displaying what could happen if we had all the power in the world. The Dance of the Hours sequence deals with the innocence of the animal kingdom. These are just some examples of the power of visuals and music. What really makes Fantasia a masterpiece is how it ends. The final sequence which many people know of is the Night on Bald Mountain where we see the full power of the devil. Even if you are not religious(such as myself) the power in this sequence can touch anybody. The segment shows the devil awakening on a mountain and he begins to call spirits, ghost, demons, etc to the mountain where he proceeds to destroy them even in death with fire. The devil is stopped by God who puts him back to rest. After this we hear the Ave Maria and see monks with torches walking to a cathedral. The messages in this scene show probably the most powerful messages Disney has ever produced. Fanastia is a masterpiece plain and simple. Everything about this film works. The sequences are in the right order, the music is beautiful and the animation is breathtaking. As I commented earlier, Fantasia is not a movie it is an experience. The film is not really meant for kid. This is not because of the content but I only question how kids will handle a movie with no dialogue. I speak from experience. This film serves as Walt Disney's masterpiece and very much deserves that title. This is not just Disney at its best, it is probably one of the greatest films ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3rd out of 5 in the Golden Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantasia was released in the same year as Pinocchio (1940), but this film was released 9 months later in November. This film has he perfect amount of classical music, breathtaking animation, and memorable shorts to make the best package film ever made. Even though this film is 2 hours long, it does not feel that way, as you are just enjoying the shorts, which will go by so quickly. The best and the most iconic short in the film was "The Sorcerer's Apprentice". This is the one where Mickey tests out his master's tricks. The other shorts like "Rite of Spring", "Nutcracker Suite" and the others hold up as well. The children will enjoy the pretty animation and colours, while the adults will like the music and substance. Give it a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles_Hardy
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fantasia" is a wonderful blend of live action and animation, but not like the latter Disney films of "Mary Poppins" and "Petes Dragon." The live action sequences are that of Deems Taylor narrating the film as well as setting up the stories. Leopold Stowkowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra give us the music to fit to the beautiful pictures. The film was originally intended to be released each year (as a roadshow film) thereafter with different scenes intact as well as some old ones. This was not the case when WWII broke out and the US got involved. Walt Disney's vision would not be complete until "Fantasia 2000" was released in 1999. Probably the most important and proclaimed piece of "Fantasia" would be The Sorcerer's Apprentice starring Mickey Mouse. In fact, this sequence was reused in the sequel film in 1999 to achieve the roadshow feel that Disney wanted. It was also this sequence in the film that spawned another film in 2010 starring Nicolas Cage, "The Sorcerer's Apprentice." A wonderful film and one that will delve into your imagination and take you places you thought you may never see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Adult Fantasy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psychocosmic-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a person who consider Art, or rich Art, being able to elevate our minds and from which we are able to draw huge amount of information. Fantasia is not only a unique film, its also the only film which with musical pieces illustrates evolution at work and prehistoric scenes pretty scary and violent with the last groups of dinosaurs parading towards doom. Development and Extermination. Also, here you have sceneries of the Hellenian mythological world portraying the mating ritual and the Bacchus celebration, "sex, drugs and party!", and the battle between the light and the shadow world - the world of death and decay and that of light and peace. We get the living Nature in its transgressions through the different seasons, comical portraits of animals and veggies impersonating humans, and a moral tale of a young who forgot that he is not the tutor yet, etc. The basic thread of the movie is the music of course! To begin the film with J S Bach's Toccata and Fuge in d minor, is not only supercool, but is the perfect upwarming piece. As the music itself is pretty impossible to create a simple visual story with characters from, the visuals we see are closer to abstract and expressionism in form, with natural elements to illustrate Bach's famous cosmic flow of his fugues! Walt Disney was so serious with this project, that a psychological consult with experience of peyote, was hired to give guide lines to the different segments, not to mention all the ideas which came from the big crowd of artists that was working with the pictures and the translation of the music into pictures. Just like other Disney films of the period, like Three Caballeros 1946 and certain scenes in Dumbo and others, could easily be placed side by side with Yellow Submarine and experimental underground shorts in the late 60's, in a period when LSD, Psilocybin mushrooms and cannabis was the inspiration, for both young hippies and soul searching intellectuals. Disney was really psychedelic! The imagination at work in this film is so rich, that one can view it over and over again, to find details as well as new interpretations to the different segments. When viewing this multi artwork from beginning to end, through the music to the visuals and its themes, it seems to encompass the human and natural world on Earth,in a trancendental way, so it seems to be the perfect movie to send with a probe out into outer space, hoping to encounter an alien species, who might be able to watch it! They would not only consider it a colorful gem, but would find the film be a treasure for understanding Humans from the planet Earth. Of course, I am exaggerating, but still, if NASA could pack a satellite with chosen music, which I know they had, why not a movie? Anyways, this is a way for me to say, that Fantasia, as the film looks, could not have been made today, as the most powerful film companies would not bet a huge some of money on a project like this. Also, a feature film, all drawn and painted by hand, gives a decidedly more impressive look than one that is made in a computer. The fact is, that around 1939 - 1940, in the midst of Second World War, some of the most popular, hailed by critics and audience alike, greatest films were made. If the time consuming, painstaking efforts behind Pinoccio, Wizard of Oz, The Thief of Bagdad and Fantasia all are made to be true fantasy films, they seem to tell us that during war time it better works to make "timeless" films. In other words, films which not occupy themselves with the ever changing societies of Humanity and the issues of the times in which they were made. Instead, and this is what make them work as true art, they seem to speak to us, in matter of symbols, archetypes and themes which have been with us through the history of time. It could be seen as a work of a great shaman, who wants to remind us about the most important and utterly most sublimely beautiful things we have on this Earth. The Greatest Movie Achievement Ever In History! I only give full points (10/10) to films that are more than a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michelle Palmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I must say that my son and I were very, very impressed with the art work in this. Considering this movie was made in the 1940's and how they did the animated features back then, it took a lot of hard work, dedication, and talent for all involved to do this. I was amazed!!! My favorite scene is the Nutcracker piece. My second favorite was mickey mouse :-) We didn't really care for the others (though the Soundtrack part was pretty cute. We skipped about three chapters simply because we were not interested... We'll watch the parts we like in the future, but skip over the rest...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different, Not Meaningful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reuben Barbosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my life I've attempted to watch Fantasia at least 8 times, and every time I've always turned it off 30 to 40 minutes in. Does that warrant the film to get a 1/10? No, it has great animation but I still think the movie is a boring bunch of tar. The people who like Fantasia tend to say the film is good for it's emotional simplicity, creativity, and darker tone (when compared to other Disney films). I feel these reasons are somewhat ridiculous since even though I know when the film wants be to feel happy or sad, it still doesn't detract from the fact that's all the film has going for it: emotion. As someone who loves symbolism in film, I have never seen Fantasia show any images that would allow the viewer to think. Fantasia is like therapy, if you want to feel happy you can and if you want to feel sad you can. It's a movie where you just turn off your brain and enjoy the colours and music. Is there anything wrong with that? No. But, I still hate the fact that everyone treats this like 2001. The main difference between 2001 and Fantasia is that 2001 had an actual message it wanted to tell. Granted, that message is not entirely known by people but it is still a thought provoking film. Fantasia was an exercise in how the plot of a film can be told like 2001, but it feels like in the end it just had nothing to say. That's the main thing I find boring about the film, the fact that I have nothing to think about since it has nothing to say. I wouldn't call the film pretentious but I feel that fans of the film are pretentious for thinking a film that merely gives us emotions is the most revolutionary thing ever since it's just with animation and music. Any film can give you emotion with characters, plot, and meaning. Was Fantasia different? Yes. Does it have meaning? I don't think so but that's my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disney's most ambitious feature to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like DW Griffith's silent epic Intolerance (1916), Disney's most ambitious work Fantasia (1940) is a film more respected than loved. It is an experimental work, lacking the warmth of the most popular Disney films but beating out nearly all of them in terms of artistry and animation (its only rival being Pinocchio (1940)). Indeed, this might be the one Disney film created for an adult audience alone, even though more thoughtful children will be able to enjoy it. The Disney studio would never do something so bold as this ever again. Oh sure, they made Fantasia 2000 (1999) during the final years of the Disney Renaissance, but let's face it, that was made with toddlers in mind. It doesn't run nearly as long, insults the audience's intelligence with those dreadful celebrity introductions, and the new segments never measure up to the maturity and sublime artistry of the original. The Disney name is too closely linked with "children's entertainment" for them to boldly experiment at this point. That Fantasia was made at all is a miracle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fantasia" is truly a film ahead of its time and it needs to be seen in able for one to understand its importance in film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there is one thing that Walt Disney knew about better than anyone else, it was that the combination of music and animation is one of the most important combinations since bread and butter. This can best explain why most of Disney's animated features are all musicals. It's because Walt Disney strongly believed that music and sound were essential keys towards great animated features and shorts. One could make a good argument that his 3rd full-length animated feature, Fantasia (1940), was created as further proof regarding why he believed music was so essential to the world of animation. Fantasia is a unique animated feature in terms of its narrative. It starts out with an orchestra taking their places as if they were preparing for a concert. Then, the main narrator of this picture by the name of Deems Taylor emerges and introduces us to a new form of entertainment called Fantasia. We are told that during this new form of entertainment, we will see the images that classical music had inspired in the minds of Walt Disney's massive staff of artists. In other words, we are seeing pieces of famous classical music being brought to life visually based on what Disney's artists think these pieces are about. We are also told that there are three types of musical pieces in this program: music that tells a definite story, music that paints a series of pictures, and "absolute music" that exists simply for its own sake. This animated feature basically consists of eight separate segments which all are devoted to one of the three types of music. Sometimes, one could make an argument that some segments have more than one of the three types of music, since some segments are more clearly cut in the type of music they're going for than other segments. For instance, the first segment "Toccata and Fugue in D Minor" is clearly an example of absolute music that exists simply for its own sake. All this segment composes of is visuals that one might think of whenever this classical music is being played. But then there are segments like "The Rite of Spring" which could easily count as music that paints a series of pictures as well as music that tells a definite story. The reason I believe this segment could apply to both is because while it tells us the history of the dinosaurs, you aren't exactly sure what to make of the overall main vision Disney was going for with this segment in the end. This is precisely why Fantasia is such a fascinating piece of filmmaking, because what it shows its audience is so unconventional and diverse that it's hard not to admire the fact that it's so unique with its story structure. After seeing this picture a couple times, I truly have a better understanding of why Fantasia was immensely influential in the film industry, particularly with the medium of music videos. If you think more about it, this film is basically a series of silent animated short films perfectly synchronized to famous pieces of classical music. Fantasia would easily qualify as one of the films I would be most interested in learning more about the making behind. I would be more than eager to learn what Walt Disney's animators thought when he wanted to pursue executing this specific project so soon after the ambitious production of Snow White. I would also be interested in learning the process behind the animation for these segments and how the animators synchronized the animation and music as well as they did, since I know the animation process was probably painstaking to say the least. Is this a film that will please everyone's tastes? I don't think so, since it's definitely an acquired taste for some. After all, Fantasia is considered a big step for Disney fans to take since it is so different from anything Disney ever did that it could throw them for a loop. Are there some slow moments? I'd say that this film gets off to a little bit of a slow start, but by the time the film's most famous segment "The Sorcerer's Apprentice" with Mickey Mouse comes around, it only gets better. Was the intermission involving the soundtrack corny and unnecessary? While I certainly can say it is by modern standards, I'll be fair by stating that this came out at a time when some audiences had trouble getting used to the then-new Technicolor process and their eyes had to take a break from the bright colors on screen. In short, Fantasia is truly a film that was way ahead of its time in almost every aspect imaginable. From outstanding segments like "The Rite of Spring" and "Night on Bald Mountain", to the excellent orchestration of the classical music by Leopold Stokowski and his orchestra, to the tremendous craft of the animation. It's one of those rare films in which the only way you can understand its importance in the history of cinema is to see for yourself. So what are you waiting for?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The epitome of the animated musical genre!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KadrianBlackwolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back when this film was made there were two broad schools of thought on animated films. One school believed that the animated action was the main point of an animated film and that the music should fit the animation. Sadly, this is how almost all animation is done today. The other school believed that the music should be the main focus and that the animation should enhance the music by providing an artistic visual representation. This is the school that "Fantasia" represents. I love this film and have watched it (or at least listened to it) countless times. The musical selections are among the best that classical music has to offer, and the animation and styling of the characters are classical Disney at its best. The scenes depicted vary from the hilarious to the terrifying to the awe-inspiring. Most satisfying are those that take your breath away and hold you in fascination with their beauty and elegance. My only complaint about the film is Disney's choice of Leopold Stokowski as conductor. Stokowski arrogantly took it upon himself to "improve" Mussorgsky's "Night on Bare Mountain," and effectively ruined the best parts of the score. Compare Stokowski's version with the original and you'll see what I mean. But with the exception of Stokowski's occasional interference, "Fantasia" is the best animated musical film ever produced.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Tenth Favorite Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1940's Fantasia Is My Tenth Favorite Film Of All Time, I Like It Because It's Has Great Animation Set To Classical Music, I Do Like The Live-Action Parts With Deems Taylor Where He Tells About Each Segment, My Favorite Segments I Like In This Are, Toccata And Fugue In D Minor, The Sorcerer's Apprentice, Rite Of Spring, A Night On Bald Mountain And Ave Maria, This Is My Favorite Animated Film And Also My Favorite Disney Film, I Really Don't Want To Get This Film On DVD Because My DVD Collection Is Done With And It's Full And Done With, The Only Version Of 1940's Fantasia That I Like The 2000 60th Anniversary Version With Corey Burton Doing The Voice Of Deems Taylor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike-duffy-486-49185
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fanatasia is not a film, it is an experience. Fantasia took a big risk back in 1940 when Walt Disney decided that he wanted to try something new. Fantasia has left a mark on history as one of the most unique and beautiful films ever created. Fantasia does not have a narrative story, it is shown through multiple 20-25 minute stories that do not have dialogue. The stories are told through music conducted by the great Leopold Stokowski. The music matches the visuals perfectly. The film opens with us listening to the orchestra play Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, accompanied by good visuals. The film then carries on to the six story lines which use classical music by some of the greats such as Beethoven and Tchaikovsky. All of these story lines are magnificently animated. Picking my favourite segment was not easy because they were all perfect. The segments include the creation of earth, The change of seasons on the envoirment and the devil vs God. My personal favourite is probably the mythology segment where we listen to Beethoven's Pastoral Symphony with animation of centaurs, fairies, gods and fawns. What really surprised me about Fantasia was the messages that were delivered in each segment that was up to the interpretation of the audience. For example, The Sorceror's Apprentice deals with a situation displaying what could happen if we had all the power in the world. The Dance of the Hours sequence deals with the innocence of the animal kingdom. These are just some examples of the power of visuals and music. What really makes Fantasia a masterpiece is how it ends. The final sequence which many people know of is the Night on Bald Mountain where we see the full power of the devil. Even if you are not religious(such as myself) the power in this sequence can touch anybody. The segment shows the devil awakening on a mountain and he begins to call spirits, ghost, demons, etc to the mountain where he proceeds to destroy them even in death with fire. The devil is stopped by God who puts him back to rest. After this we hear the Ave Maria and see monks with torches walking to a cathedral. The messages in this scene show probably the most powerful messages Disney has ever produced. Fanastia is a masterpiece plain and simple. Everything about this film works. The sequences are in the right order, the music is beautiful and the animation is breathtaking. As I commented earlier, Fantasia is not a movie it is an experience. The film is not really meant for kid. This is not because of the content but I only question how kids will handle a movie with no dialogue. I speak from experience. This film serves as Walt Disney's masterpiece and very much deserves that title. This is not just Disney at its best, it is probably one of the greatest films ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3rd out of 5 in the Golden Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantasia was released in the same year as Pinocchio (1940), but this film was released 9 months later in November. This film has he perfect amount of classical music, breathtaking animation, and memorable shorts to make the best package film ever made. Even though this film is 2 hours long, it does not feel that way, as you are just enjoying the shorts, which will go by so quickly. The best and the most iconic short in the film was "The Sorcerer's Apprentice". This is the one where Mickey tests out his master's tricks. The other shorts like "Rite of Spring", "Nutcracker Suite" and the others hold up as well. The children will enjoy the pretty animation and colours, while the adults will like the music and substance. Give it a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles_Hardy
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fantasia" is a wonderful blend of live action and animation, but not like the latter Disney films of "Mary Poppins" and "Petes Dragon." The live action sequences are that of Deems Taylor narrating the film as well as setting up the stories. Leopold Stowkowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra give us the music to fit to the beautiful pictures. The film was originally intended to be released each year (as a roadshow film) thereafter with different scenes intact as well as some old ones. This was not the case when WWII broke out and the US got involved. Walt Disney's vision would not be complete until "Fantasia 2000" was released in 1999. Probably the most important and proclaimed piece of "Fantasia" would be The Sorcerer's Apprentice starring Mickey Mouse. In fact, this sequence was reused in the sequel film in 1999 to achieve the roadshow feel that Disney wanted. It was also this sequence in the film that spawned another film in 2010 starring Nicolas Cage, "The Sorcerer's Apprentice." A wonderful film and one that will delve into your imagination and take you places you thought you may never see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Adult Fantasy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psychocosmic-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a person who consider Art, or rich Art, being able to elevate our minds and from which we are able to draw huge amount of information. Fantasia is not only a unique film, its also the only film which with musical pieces illustrates evolution at work and prehistoric scenes pretty scary and violent with the last groups of dinosaurs parading towards doom. Development and Extermination. Also, here you have sceneries of the Hellenian mythological world portraying the mating ritual and the Bacchus celebration, "sex, drugs and party!", and the battle between the light and the shadow world - the world of death and decay and that of light and peace. We get the living Nature in its transgressions through the different seasons, comical portraits of animals and veggies impersonating humans, and a moral tale of a young who forgot that he is not the tutor yet, etc. The basic thread of the movie is the music of course! To begin the film with J S Bach's Toccata and Fuge in d minor, is not only supercool, but is the perfect upwarming piece. As the music itself is pretty impossible to create a simple visual story with characters from, the visuals we see are closer to abstract and expressionism in form, with natural elements to illustrate Bach's famous cosmic flow of his fugues! Walt Disney was so serious with this project, that a psychological consult with experience of peyote, was hired to give guide lines to the different segments, not to mention all the ideas which came from the big crowd of artists that was working with the pictures and the translation of the music into pictures. Just like other Disney films of the period, like Three Caballeros 1946 and certain scenes in Dumbo and others, could easily be placed side by side with Yellow Submarine and experimental underground shorts in the late 60's, in a period when LSD, Psilocybin mushrooms and cannabis was the inspiration, for both young hippies and soul searching intellectuals. Disney was really psychedelic! The imagination at work in this film is so rich, that one can view it over and over again, to find details as well as new interpretations to the different segments. When viewing this multi artwork from beginning to end, through the music to the visuals and its themes, it seems to encompass the human and natural world on Earth,in a trancendental way, so it seems to be the perfect movie to send with a probe out into outer space, hoping to encounter an alien species, who might be able to watch it! They would not only consider it a colorful gem, but would find the film be a treasure for understanding Humans from the planet Earth. Of course, I am exaggerating, but still, if NASA could pack a satellite with chosen music, which I know they had, why not a movie? Anyways, this is a way for me to say, that Fantasia, as the film looks, could not have been made today, as the most powerful film companies would not bet a huge some of money on a project like this. Also, a feature film, all drawn and painted by hand, gives a decidedly more impressive look than one that is made in a computer. The fact is, that around 1939 - 1940, in the midst of Second World War, some of the most popular, hailed by critics and audience alike, greatest films were made. If the time consuming, painstaking efforts behind Pinoccio, Wizard of Oz, The Thief of Bagdad and Fantasia all are made to be true fantasy films, they seem to tell us that during war time it better works to make "timeless" films. In other words, films which not occupy themselves with the ever changing societies of Humanity and the issues of the times in which they were made. Instead, and this is what make them work as true art, they seem to speak to us, in matter of symbols, archetypes and themes which have been with us through the history of time. It could be seen as a work of a great shaman, who wants to remind us about the most important and utterly most sublimely beautiful things we have on this Earth. The Greatest Movie Achievement Ever In History! I only give full points (10/10) to films that are more than a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michelle Palmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I must say that my son and I were very, very impressed with the art work in this. Considering this movie was made in the 1940's and how they did the animated features back then, it took a lot of hard work, dedication, and talent for all involved to do this. I was amazed!!! My favorite scene is the Nutcracker piece. My second favorite was mickey mouse :-) We didn't really care for the others (though the Soundtrack part was pretty cute. We skipped about three chapters simply because we were not interested... We'll watch the parts we like in the future, but skip over the rest...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different, Not Meaningful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reuben Barbosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my life I've attempted to watch Fantasia at least 8 times, and every time I've always turned it off 30 to 40 minutes in. Does that warrant the film to get a 1/10? No, it has great animation but I still think the movie is a boring bunch of tar. The people who like Fantasia tend to say the film is good for it's emotional simplicity, creativity, and darker tone (when compared to other Disney films). I feel these reasons are somewhat ridiculous since even though I know when the film wants be to feel happy or sad, it still doesn't detract from the fact that's all the film has going for it: emotion. As someone who loves symbolism in film, I have never seen Fantasia show any images that would allow the viewer to think. Fantasia is like therapy, if you want to feel happy you can and if you want to feel sad you can. It's a movie where you just turn off your brain and enjoy the colours and music. Is there anything wrong with that? No. But, I still hate the fact that everyone treats this like 2001. The main difference between 2001 and Fantasia is that 2001 had an actual message it wanted to tell. Granted, that message is not entirely known by people but it is still a thought provoking film. Fantasia was an exercise in how the plot of a film can be told like 2001, but it feels like in the end it just had nothing to say. That's the main thing I find boring about the film, the fact that I have nothing to think about since it has nothing to say. I wouldn't call the film pretentious but I feel that fans of the film are pretentious for thinking a film that merely gives us emotions is the most revolutionary thing ever since it's just with animation and music. Any film can give you emotion with characters, plot, and meaning. Was Fantasia different? Yes. Does it have meaning? I don't think so but that's my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disney's most ambitious feature to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like DW Griffith's silent epic Intolerance (1916), Disney's most ambitious work Fantasia (1940) is a film more respected than loved. It is an experimental work, lacking the warmth of the most popular Disney films but beating out nearly all of them in terms of artistry and animation (its only rival being Pinocchio (1940)). Indeed, this might be the one Disney film created for an adult audience alone, even though more thoughtful children will be able to enjoy it. The Disney studio would never do something so bold as this ever again. Oh sure, they made Fantasia 2000 (1999) during the final years of the Disney Renaissance, but let's face it, that was made with toddlers in mind. It doesn't run nearly as long, insults the audience's intelligence with those dreadful celebrity introductions, and the new segments never measure up to the maturity and sublime artistry of the original. The Disney name is too closely linked with "children's entertainment" for them to boldly experiment at this point. That Fantasia was made at all is a miracle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fantasia" is truly a film ahead of its time and it needs to be seen in able for one to understand its importance in film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there is one thing that Walt Disney knew about better than anyone else, it was that the combination of music and animation is one of the most important combinations since bread and butter. This can best explain why most of Disney's animated features are all musicals. It's because Walt Disney strongly believed that music and sound were essential keys towards great animated features and shorts. One could make a good argument that his 3rd full-length animated feature, Fantasia (1940), was created as further proof regarding why he believed music was so essential to the world of animation. Fantasia is a unique animated feature in terms of its narrative. It starts out with an orchestra taking their places as if they were preparing for a concert. Then, the main narrator of this picture by the name of Deems Taylor emerges and introduces us to a new form of entertainment called Fantasia. We are told that during this new form of entertainment, we will see the images that classical music had inspired in the minds of Walt Disney's massive staff of artists. In other words, we are seeing pieces of famous classical music being brought to life visually based on what Disney's artists think these pieces are about. We are also told that there are three types of musical pieces in this program: music that tells a definite story, music that paints a series of pictures, and "absolute music" that exists simply for its own sake. This animated feature basically consists of eight separate segments which all are devoted to one of the three types of music. Sometimes, one could make an argument that some segments have more than one of the three types of music, since some segments are more clearly cut in the type of music they're going for than other segments. For instance, the first segment "Toccata and Fugue in D Minor" is clearly an example of absolute music that exists simply for its own sake. All this segment composes of is visuals that one might think of whenever this classical music is being played. But then there are segments like "The Rite of Spring" which could easily count as music that paints a series of pictures as well as music that tells a definite story. The reason I believe this segment could apply to both is because while it tells us the history of the dinosaurs, you aren't exactly sure what to make of the overall main vision Disney was going for with this segment in the end. This is precisely why Fantasia is such a fascinating piece of filmmaking, because what it shows its audience is so unconventional and diverse that it's hard not to admire the fact that it's so unique with its story structure. After seeing this picture a couple times, I truly have a better understanding of why Fantasia was immensely influential in the film industry, particularly with the medium of music videos. If you think more about it, this film is basically a series of silent animated short films perfectly synchronized to famous pieces of classical music. Fantasia would easily qualify as one of the films I would be most interested in learning more about the making behind. I would be more than eager to learn what Walt Disney's animators thought when he wanted to pursue executing this specific project so soon after the ambitious production of Snow White. I would also be interested in learning the process behind the animation for these segments and how the animators synchronized the animation and music as well as they did, since I know the animation process was probably painstaking to say the least. Is this a film that will please everyone's tastes? I don't think so, since it's definitely an acquired taste for some. After all, Fantasia is considered a big step for Disney fans to take since it is so different from anything Disney ever did that it could throw them for a loop. Are there some slow moments? I'd say that this film gets off to a little bit of a slow start, but by the time the film's most famous segment "The Sorcerer's Apprentice" with Mickey Mouse comes around, it only gets better. Was the intermission involving the soundtrack corny and unnecessary? While I certainly can say it is by modern standards, I'll be fair by stating that this came out at a time when some audiences had trouble getting used to the then-new Technicolor process and their eyes had to take a break from the bright colors on screen. In short, Fantasia is truly a film that was way ahead of its time in almost every aspect imaginable. From outstanding segments like "The Rite of Spring" and "Night on Bald Mountain", to the excellent orchestration of the classical music by Leopold Stokowski and his orchestra, to the tremendous craft of the animation. It's one of those rare films in which the only way you can understand its importance in the history of cinema is to see for yourself. So what are you waiting for?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The epitome of the animated musical genre!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KadrianBlackwolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back when this film was made there were two broad schools of thought on animated films. One school believed that the animated action was the main point of an animated film and that the music should fit the animation. Sadly, this is how almost all animation is done today. The other school believed that the music should be the main focus and that the animation should enhance the music by providing an artistic visual representation. This is the school that "Fantasia" represents. I love this film and have watched it (or at least listened to it) countless times. The musical selections are among the best that classical music has to offer, and the animation and styling of the characters are classical Disney at its best. The scenes depicted vary from the hilarious to the terrifying to the awe-inspiring. Most satisfying are those that take your breath away and hold you in fascination with their beauty and elegance. My only complaint about the film is Disney's choice of Leopold Stokowski as conductor. Stokowski arrogantly took it upon himself to "improve" Mussorgsky's "Night on Bare Mountain," and effectively ruined the best parts of the score. Compare Stokowski's version with the original and you'll see what I mean. But with the exception of Stokowski's occasional interference, "Fantasia" is the best animated musical film ever produced.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Tenth Favorite Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1940's Fantasia Is My Tenth Favorite Film Of All Time, I Like It Because It's Has Great Animation Set To Classical Music, I Do Like The Live-Action Parts With Deems Taylor Where He Tells About Each Segment, My Favorite Segments I Like In This Are, Toccata And Fugue In D Minor, The Sorcerer's Apprentice, Rite Of Spring, A Night On Bald Mountain And Ave Maria, This Is My Favorite Animated Film And Also My Favorite Disney Film, I Really Don't Want To Get This Film On DVD Because My DVD Collection Is Done With And It's Full And Done With, The Only Version Of 1940's Fantasia That I Like The 2000 60th Anniversary Version With Corey Burton Doing The Voice Of Deems Taylor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike-duffy-486-49185
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fanatasia is not a film, it is an experience. Fantasia took a big risk back in 1940 when Walt Disney decided that he wanted to try something new. Fantasia has left a mark on history as one of the most unique and beautiful films ever created. Fantasia does not have a narrative story, it is shown through multiple 20-25 minute stories that do not have dialogue. The stories are told through music conducted by the great Leopold Stokowski. The music matches the visuals perfectly. The film opens with us listening to the orchestra play Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, accompanied by good visuals. The film then carries on to the six story lines which use classical music by some of the greats such as Beethoven and Tchaikovsky. All of these story lines are magnificently animated. Picking my favourite segment was not easy because they were all perfect. The segments include the creation of earth, The change of seasons on the envoirment and the devil vs God. My personal favourite is probably the mythology segment where we listen to Beethoven's Pastoral Symphony with animation of centaurs, fairies, gods and fawns. What really surprised me about Fantasia was the messages that were delivered in each segment that was up to the interpretation of the audience. For example, The Sorceror's Apprentice deals with a situation displaying what could happen if we had all the power in the world. The Dance of the Hours sequence deals with the innocence of the animal kingdom. These are just some examples of the power of visuals and music. What really makes Fantasia a masterpiece is how it ends. The final sequence which many people know of is the Night on Bald Mountain where we see the full power of the devil. Even if you are not religious(such as myself) the power in this sequence can touch anybody. The segment shows the devil awakening on a mountain and he begins to call spirits, ghost, demons, etc to the mountain where he proceeds to destroy them even in death with fire. The devil is stopped by God who puts him back to rest. After this we hear the Ave Maria and see monks with torches walking to a cathedral. The messages in this scene show probably the most powerful messages Disney has ever produced. Fanastia is a masterpiece plain and simple. Everything about this film works. The sequences are in the right order, the music is beautiful and the animation is breathtaking. As I commented earlier, Fantasia is not a movie it is an experience. The film is not really meant for kid. This is not because of the content but I only question how kids will handle a movie with no dialogue. I speak from experience. This film serves as Walt Disney's masterpiece and very much deserves that title. This is not just Disney at its best, it is probably one of the greatest films ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3rd out of 5 in the Golden Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantasia was released in the same year as Pinocchio (1940), but this film was released 9 months later in November. This film has he perfect amount of classical music, breathtaking animation, and memorable shorts to make the best package film ever made. Even though this film is 2 hours long, it does not feel that way, as you are just enjoying the shorts, which will go by so quickly. The best and the most iconic short in the film was "The Sorcerer's Apprentice". This is the one where Mickey tests out his master's tricks. The other shorts like "Rite of Spring", "Nutcracker Suite" and the others hold up as well. The children will enjoy the pretty animation and colours, while the adults will like the music and substance. Give it a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles_Hardy
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fantasia" is a wonderful blend of live action and animation, but not like the latter Disney films of "Mary Poppins" and "Petes Dragon." The live action sequences are that of Deems Taylor narrating the film as well as setting up the stories. Leopold Stowkowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra give us the music to fit to the beautiful pictures. The film was originally intended to be released each year (as a roadshow film) thereafter with different scenes intact as well as some old ones. This was not the case when WWII broke out and the US got involved. Walt Disney's vision would not be complete until "Fantasia 2000" was released in 1999. Probably the most important and proclaimed piece of "Fantasia" would be The Sorcerer's Apprentice starring Mickey Mouse. In fact, this sequence was reused in the sequel film in 1999 to achieve the roadshow feel that Disney wanted. It was also this sequence in the film that spawned another film in 2010 starring Nicolas Cage, "The Sorcerer's Apprentice." A wonderful film and one that will delve into your imagination and take you places you thought you may never see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Adult Fantasy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psychocosmic-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a person who consider Art, or rich Art, being able to elevate our minds and from which we are able to draw huge amount of information. Fantasia is not only a unique film, its also the only film which with musical pieces illustrates evolution at work and prehistoric scenes pretty scary and violent with the last groups of dinosaurs parading towards doom. Development and Extermination. Also, here you have sceneries of the Hellenian mythological world portraying the mating ritual and the Bacchus celebration, "sex, drugs and party!", and the battle between the light and the shadow world - the world of death and decay and that of light and peace. We get the living Nature in its transgressions through the different seasons, comical portraits of animals and veggies impersonating humans, and a moral tale of a young who forgot that he is not the tutor yet, etc. The basic thread of the movie is the music of course! To begin the film with J S Bach's Toccata and Fuge in d minor, is not only supercool, but is the perfect upwarming piece. As the music itself is pretty impossible to create a simple visual story with characters from, the visuals we see are closer to abstract and expressionism in form, with natural elements to illustrate Bach's famous cosmic flow of his fugues! Walt Disney was so serious with this project, that a psychological consult with experience of peyote, was hired to give guide lines to the different segments, not to mention all the ideas which came from the big crowd of artists that was working with the pictures and the translation of the music into pictures. Just like other Disney films of the period, like Three Caballeros 1946 and certain scenes in Dumbo and others, could easily be placed side by side with Yellow Submarine and experimental underground shorts in the late 60's, in a period when LSD, Psilocybin mushrooms and cannabis was the inspiration, for both young hippies and soul searching intellectuals. Disney was really psychedelic! The imagination at work in this film is so rich, that one can view it over and over again, to find details as well as new interpretations to the different segments. When viewing this multi artwork from beginning to end, through the music to the visuals and its themes, it seems to encompass the human and natural world on Earth,in a trancendental way, so it seems to be the perfect movie to send with a probe out into outer space, hoping to encounter an alien species, who might be able to watch it! They would not only consider it a colorful gem, but would find the film be a treasure for understanding Humans from the planet Earth. Of course, I am exaggerating, but still, if NASA could pack a satellite with chosen music, which I know they had, why not a movie? Anyways, this is a way for me to say, that Fantasia, as the film looks, could not have been made today, as the most powerful film companies would not bet a huge some of money on a project like this. Also, a feature film, all drawn and painted by hand, gives a decidedly more impressive look than one that is made in a computer. The fact is, that around 1939 - 1940, in the midst of Second World War, some of the most popular, hailed by critics and audience alike, greatest films were made. If the time consuming, painstaking efforts behind Pinoccio, Wizard of Oz, The Thief of Bagdad and Fantasia all are made to be true fantasy films, they seem to tell us that during war time it better works to make "timeless" films. In other words, films which not occupy themselves with the ever changing societies of Humanity and the issues of the times in which they were made. Instead, and this is what make them work as true art, they seem to speak to us, in matter of symbols, archetypes and themes which have been with us through the history of time. It could be seen as a work of a great shaman, who wants to remind us about the most important and utterly most sublimely beautiful things we have on this Earth. The Greatest Movie Achievement Ever In History! I only give full points (10/10) to films that are more than a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michelle Palmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I must say that my son and I were very, very impressed with the art work in this. Considering this movie was made in the 1940's and how they did the animated features back then, it took a lot of hard work, dedication, and talent for all involved to do this. I was amazed!!! My favorite scene is the Nutcracker piece. My second favorite was mickey mouse :-) We didn't really care for the others (though the Soundtrack part was pretty cute. We skipped about three chapters simply because we were not interested... We'll watch the parts we like in the future, but skip over the rest...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different, Not Meaningful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reuben Barbosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my life I've attempted to watch Fantasia at least 8 times, and every time I've always turned it off 30 to 40 minutes in. Does that warrant the film to get a 1/10? No, it has great animation but I still think the movie is a boring bunch of tar. The people who like Fantasia tend to say the film is good for it's emotional simplicity, creativity, and darker tone (when compared to other Disney films). I feel these reasons are somewhat ridiculous since even though I know when the film wants be to feel happy or sad, it still doesn't detract from the fact that's all the film has going for it: emotion. As someone who loves symbolism in film, I have never seen Fantasia show any images that would allow the viewer to think. Fantasia is like therapy, if you want to feel happy you can and if you want to feel sad you can. It's a movie where you just turn off your brain and enjoy the colours and music. Is there anything wrong with that? No. But, I still hate the fact that everyone treats this like 2001. The main difference between 2001 and Fantasia is that 2001 had an actual message it wanted to tell. Granted, that message is not entirely known by people but it is still a thought provoking film. Fantasia was an exercise in how the plot of a film can be told like 2001, but it feels like in the end it just had nothing to say. That's the main thing I find boring about the film, the fact that I have nothing to think about since it has nothing to say. I wouldn't call the film pretentious but I feel that fans of the film are pretentious for thinking a film that merely gives us emotions is the most revolutionary thing ever since it's just with animation and music. Any film can give you emotion with characters, plot, and meaning. Was Fantasia different? Yes. Does it have meaning? I don't think so but that's my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disney's most ambitious feature to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like DW Griffith's silent epic Intolerance (1916), Disney's most ambitious work Fantasia (1940) is a film more respected than loved. It is an experimental work, lacking the warmth of the most popular Disney films but beating out nearly all of them in terms of artistry and animation (its only rival being Pinocchio (1940)). Indeed, this might be the one Disney film created for an adult audience alone, even though more thoughtful children will be able to enjoy it. The Disney studio would never do something so bold as this ever again. Oh sure, they made Fantasia 2000 (1999) during the final years of the Disney Renaissance, but let's face it, that was made with toddlers in mind. It doesn't run nearly as long, insults the audience's intelligence with those dreadful celebrity introductions, and the new segments never measure up to the maturity and sublime artistry of the original. The Disney name is too closely linked with "children's entertainment" for them to boldly experiment at this point. That Fantasia was made at all is a miracle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fantasia" is truly a film ahead of its time and it needs to be seen in able for one to understand its importance in film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there is one thing that Walt Disney knew about better than anyone else, it was that the combination of music and animation is one of the most important combinations since bread and butter. This can best explain why most of Disney's animated features are all musicals. It's because Walt Disney strongly believed that music and sound were essential keys towards great animated features and shorts. One could make a good argument that his 3rd full-length animated feature, Fantasia (1940), was created as further proof regarding why he believed music was so essential to the world of animation. Fantasia is a unique animated feature in terms of its narrative. It starts out with an orchestra taking their places as if they were preparing for a concert. Then, the main narrator of this picture by the name of Deems Taylor emerges and introduces us to a new form of entertainment called Fantasia. We are told that during this new form of entertainment, we will see the images that classical music had inspired in the minds of Walt Disney's massive staff of artists. In other words, we are seeing pieces of famous classical music being brought to life visually based on what Disney's artists think these pieces are about. We are also told that there are three types of musical pieces in this program: music that tells a definite story, music that paints a series of pictures, and "absolute music" that exists simply for its own sake. This animated feature basically consists of eight separate segments which all are devoted to one of the three types of music. Sometimes, one could make an argument that some segments have more than one of the three types of music, since some segments are more clearly cut in the type of music they're going for than other segments. For instance, the first segment "Toccata and Fugue in D Minor" is clearly an example of absolute music that exists simply for its own sake. All this segment composes of is visuals that one might think of whenever this classical music is being played. But then there are segments like "The Rite of Spring" which could easily count as music that paints a series of pictures as well as music that tells a definite story. The reason I believe this segment could apply to both is because while it tells us the history of the dinosaurs, you aren't exactly sure what to make of the overall main vision Disney was going for with this segment in the end. This is precisely why Fantasia is such a fascinating piece of filmmaking, because what it shows its audience is so unconventional and diverse that it's hard not to admire the fact that it's so unique with its story structure. After seeing this picture a couple times, I truly have a better understanding of why Fantasia was immensely influential in the film industry, particularly with the medium of music videos. If you think more about it, this film is basically a series of silent animated short films perfectly synchronized to famous pieces of classical music. Fantasia would easily qualify as one of the films I would be most interested in learning more about the making behind. I would be more than eager to learn what Walt Disney's animators thought when he wanted to pursue executing this specific project so soon after the ambitious production of Snow White. I would also be interested in learning the process behind the animation for these segments and how the animators synchronized the animation and music as well as they did, since I know the animation process was probably painstaking to say the least. Is this a film that will please everyone's tastes? I don't think so, since it's definitely an acquired taste for some. After all, Fantasia is considered a big step for Disney fans to take since it is so different from anything Disney ever did that it could throw them for a loop. Are there some slow moments? I'd say that this film gets off to a little bit of a slow start, but by the time the film's most famous segment "The Sorcerer's Apprentice" with Mickey Mouse comes around, it only gets better. Was the intermission involving the soundtrack corny and unnecessary? While I certainly can say it is by modern standards, I'll be fair by stating that this came out at a time when some audiences had trouble getting used to the then-new Technicolor process and their eyes had to take a break from the bright colors on screen. In short, Fantasia is truly a film that was way ahead of its time in almost every aspect imaginable. From outstanding segments like "The Rite of Spring" and "Night on Bald Mountain", to the excellent orchestration of the classical music by Leopold Stokowski and his orchestra, to the tremendous craft of the animation. It's one of those rare films in which the only way you can understand its importance in the history of cinema is to see for yourself. So what are you waiting for?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The epitome of the animated musical genre!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KadrianBlackwolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back when this film was made there were two broad schools of thought on animated films. One school believed that the animated action was the main point of an animated film and that the music should fit the animation. Sadly, this is how almost all animation is done today. The other school believed that the music should be the main focus and that the animation should enhance the music by providing an artistic visual representation. This is the school that "Fantasia" represents. I love this film and have watched it (or at least listened to it) countless times. The musical selections are among the best that classical music has to offer, and the animation and styling of the characters are classical Disney at its best. The scenes depicted vary from the hilarious to the terrifying to the awe-inspiring. Most satisfying are those that take your breath away and hold you in fascination with their beauty and elegance. My only complaint about the film is Disney's choice of Leopold Stokowski as conductor. Stokowski arrogantly took it upon himself to "improve" Mussorgsky's "Night on Bare Mountain," and effectively ruined the best parts of the score. Compare Stokowski's version with the original and you'll see what I mean. But with the exception of Stokowski's occasional interference, "Fantasia" is the best animated musical film ever produced.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Tenth Favorite Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1940's Fantasia Is My Tenth Favorite Film Of All Time, I Like It Because It's Has Great Animation Set To Classical Music, I Do Like The Live-Action Parts With Deems Taylor Where He Tells About Each Segment, My Favorite Segments I Like In This Are, Toccata And Fugue In D Minor, The Sorcerer's Apprentice, Rite Of Spring, A Night On Bald Mountain And Ave Maria, This Is My Favorite Animated Film And Also My Favorite Disney Film, I Really Don't Want To Get This Film On DVD Because My DVD Collection Is Done With And It's Full And Done With, The Only Version Of 1940's Fantasia That I Like The 2000 60th Anniversary Version With Corey Burton Doing The Voice Of Deems Taylor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike-duffy-486-49185
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fanatasia is not a film, it is an experience. Fantasia took a big risk back in 1940 when Walt Disney decided that he wanted to try something new. Fantasia has left a mark on history as one of the most unique and beautiful films ever created. Fantasia does not have a narrative story, it is shown through multiple 20-25 minute stories that do not have dialogue. The stories are told through music conducted by the great Leopold Stokowski. The music matches the visuals perfectly. The film opens with us listening to the orchestra play Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, accompanied by good visuals. The film then carries on to the six story lines which use classical music by some of the greats such as Beethoven and Tchaikovsky. All of these story lines are magnificently animated. Picking my favourite segment was not easy because they were all perfect. The segments include the creation of earth, The change of seasons on the envoirment and the devil vs God. My personal favourite is probably the mythology segment where we listen to Beethoven's Pastoral Symphony with animation of centaurs, fairies, gods and fawns. What really surprised me about Fantasia was the messages that were delivered in each segment that was up to the interpretation of the audience. For example, The Sorceror's Apprentice deals with a situation displaying what could happen if we had all the power in the world. The Dance of the Hours sequence deals with the innocence of the animal kingdom. These are just some examples of the power of visuals and music. What really makes Fantasia a masterpiece is how it ends. The final sequence which many people know of is the Night on Bald Mountain where we see the full power of the devil. Even if you are not religious(such as myself) the power in this sequence can touch anybody. The segment shows the devil awakening on a mountain and he begins to call spirits, ghost, demons, etc to the mountain where he proceeds to destroy them even in death with fire. The devil is stopped by God who puts him back to rest. After this we hear the Ave Maria and see monks with torches walking to a cathedral. The messages in this scene show probably the most powerful messages Disney has ever produced. Fanastia is a masterpiece plain and simple. Everything about this film works. The sequences are in the right order, the music is beautiful and the animation is breathtaking. As I commented earlier, Fantasia is not a movie it is an experience. The film is not really meant for kid. This is not because of the content but I only question how kids will handle a movie with no dialogue. I speak from experience. This film serves as Walt Disney's masterpiece and very much deserves that title. This is not just Disney at its best, it is probably one of the greatest films ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3rd out of 5 in the Golden Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantasia was released in the same year as Pinocchio (1940), but this film was released 9 months later in November. This film has he perfect amount of classical music, breathtaking animation, and memorable shorts to make the best package film ever made. Even though this film is 2 hours long, it does not feel that way, as you are just enjoying the shorts, which will go by so quickly. The best and the most iconic short in the film was "The Sorcerer's Apprentice". This is the one where Mickey tests out his master's tricks. The other shorts like "Rite of Spring", "Nutcracker Suite" and the others hold up as well. The children will enjoy the pretty animation and colours, while the adults will like the music and substance. Give it a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles_Hardy
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fantasia" is a wonderful blend of live action and animation, but not like the latter Disney films of "Mary Poppins" and "Petes Dragon." The live action sequences are that of Deems Taylor narrating the film as well as setting up the stories. Leopold Stowkowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra give us the music to fit to the beautiful pictures. The film was originally intended to be released each year (as a roadshow film) thereafter with different scenes intact as well as some old ones. This was not the case when WWII broke out and the US got involved. Walt Disney's vision would not be complete until "Fantasia 2000" was released in 1999. Probably the most important and proclaimed piece of "Fantasia" would be The Sorcerer's Apprentice starring Mickey Mouse. In fact, this sequence was reused in the sequel film in 1999 to achieve the roadshow feel that Disney wanted. It was also this sequence in the film that spawned another film in 2010 starring Nicolas Cage, "The Sorcerer's Apprentice." A wonderful film and one that will delve into your imagination and take you places you thought you may never see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Adult Fantasy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psychocosmic-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a person who consider Art, or rich Art, being able to elevate our minds and from which we are able to draw huge amount of information. Fantasia is not only a unique film, its also the only film which with musical pieces illustrates evolution at work and prehistoric scenes pretty scary and violent with the last groups of dinosaurs parading towards doom. Development and Extermination. Also, here you have sceneries of the Hellenian mythological world portraying the mating ritual and the Bacchus celebration, "sex, drugs and party!", and the battle between the light and the shadow world - the world of death and decay and that of light and peace. We get the living Nature in its transgressions through the different seasons, comical portraits of animals and veggies impersonating humans, and a moral tale of a young who forgot that he is not the tutor yet, etc. The basic thread of the movie is the music of course! To begin the film with J S Bach's Toccata and Fuge in d minor, is not only supercool, but is the perfect upwarming piece. As the music itself is pretty impossible to create a simple visual story with characters from, the visuals we see are closer to abstract and expressionism in form, with natural elements to illustrate Bach's famous cosmic flow of his fugues! Walt Disney was so serious with this project, that a psychological consult with experience of peyote, was hired to give guide lines to the different segments, not to mention all the ideas which came from the big crowd of artists that was working with the pictures and the translation of the music into pictures. Just like other Disney films of the period, like Three Caballeros 1946 and certain scenes in Dumbo and others, could easily be placed side by side with Yellow Submarine and experimental underground shorts in the late 60's, in a period when LSD, Psilocybin mushrooms and cannabis was the inspiration, for both young hippies and soul searching intellectuals. Disney was really psychedelic! The imagination at work in this film is so rich, that one can view it over and over again, to find details as well as new interpretations to the different segments. When viewing this multi artwork from beginning to end, through the music to the visuals and its themes, it seems to encompass the human and natural world on Earth,in a trancendental way, so it seems to be the perfect movie to send with a probe out into outer space, hoping to encounter an alien species, who might be able to watch it! They would not only consider it a colorful gem, but would find the film be a treasure for understanding Humans from the planet Earth. Of course, I am exaggerating, but still, if NASA could pack a satellite with chosen music, which I know they had, why not a movie? Anyways, this is a way for me to say, that Fantasia, as the film looks, could not have been made today, as the most powerful film companies would not bet a huge some of money on a project like this. Also, a feature film, all drawn and painted by hand, gives a decidedly more impressive look than one that is made in a computer. The fact is, that around 1939 - 1940, in the midst of Second World War, some of the most popular, hailed by critics and audience alike, greatest films were made. If the time consuming, painstaking efforts behind Pinoccio, Wizard of Oz, The Thief of Bagdad and Fantasia all are made to be true fantasy films, they seem to tell us that during war time it better works to make "timeless" films. In other words, films which not occupy themselves with the ever changing societies of Humanity and the issues of the times in which they were made. Instead, and this is what make them work as true art, they seem to speak to us, in matter of symbols, archetypes and themes which have been with us through the history of time. It could be seen as a work of a great shaman, who wants to remind us about the most important and utterly most sublimely beautiful things we have on this Earth. The Greatest Movie Achievement Ever In History! I only give full points (10/10) to films that are more than a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michelle Palmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I must say that my son and I were very, very impressed with the art work in this. Considering this movie was made in the 1940's and how they did the animated features back then, it took a lot of hard work, dedication, and talent for all involved to do this. I was amazed!!! My favorite scene is the Nutcracker piece. My second favorite was mickey mouse :-) We didn't really care for the others (though the Soundtrack part was pretty cute. We skipped about three chapters simply because we were not interested... We'll watch the parts we like in the future, but skip over the rest...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different, Not Meaningful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reuben Barbosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my life I've attempted to watch Fantasia at least 8 times, and every time I've always turned it off 30 to 40 minutes in. Does that warrant the film to get a 1/10? No, it has great animation but I still think the movie is a boring bunch of tar. The people who like Fantasia tend to say the film is good for it's emotional simplicity, creativity, and darker tone (when compared to other Disney films). I feel these reasons are somewhat ridiculous since even though I know when the film wants be to feel happy or sad, it still doesn't detract from the fact that's all the film has going for it: emotion. As someone who loves symbolism in film, I have never seen Fantasia show any images that would allow the viewer to think. Fantasia is like therapy, if you want to feel happy you can and if you want to feel sad you can. It's a movie where you just turn off your brain and enjoy the colours and music. Is there anything wrong with that? No. But, I still hate the fact that everyone treats this like 2001. The main difference between 2001 and Fantasia is that 2001 had an actual message it wanted to tell. Granted, that message is not entirely known by people but it is still a thought provoking film. Fantasia was an exercise in how the plot of a film can be told like 2001, but it feels like in the end it just had nothing to say. That's the main thing I find boring about the film, the fact that I have nothing to think about since it has nothing to say. I wouldn't call the film pretentious but I feel that fans of the film are pretentious for thinking a film that merely gives us emotions is the most revolutionary thing ever since it's just with animation and music. Any film can give you emotion with characters, plot, and meaning. Was Fantasia different? Yes. Does it have meaning? I don't think so but that's my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disney's most ambitious feature to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like DW Griffith's silent epic Intolerance (1916), Disney's most ambitious work Fantasia (1940) is a film more respected than loved. It is an experimental work, lacking the warmth of the most popular Disney films but beating out nearly all of them in terms of artistry and animation (its only rival being Pinocchio (1940)). Indeed, this might be the one Disney film created for an adult audience alone, even though more thoughtful children will be able to enjoy it. The Disney studio would never do something so bold as this ever again. Oh sure, they made Fantasia 2000 (1999) during the final years of the Disney Renaissance, but let's face it, that was made with toddlers in mind. It doesn't run nearly as long, insults the audience's intelligence with those dreadful celebrity introductions, and the new segments never measure up to the maturity and sublime artistry of the original. The Disney name is too closely linked with "children's entertainment" for them to boldly experiment at this point. That Fantasia was made at all is a miracle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fantasia" is truly a film ahead of its time and it needs to be seen in able for one to understand its importance in film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there is one thing that Walt Disney knew about better than anyone else, it was that the combination of music and animation is one of the most important combinations since bread and butter. This can best explain why most of Disney's animated features are all musicals. It's because Walt Disney strongly believed that music and sound were essential keys towards great animated features and shorts. One could make a good argument that his 3rd full-length animated feature, Fantasia (1940), was created as further proof regarding why he believed music was so essential to the world of animation. Fantasia is a unique animated feature in terms of its narrative. It starts out with an orchestra taking their places as if they were preparing for a concert. Then, the main narrator of this picture by the name of Deems Taylor emerges and introduces us to a new form of entertainment called Fantasia. We are told that during this new form of entertainment, we will see the images that classical music had inspired in the minds of Walt Disney's massive staff of artists. In other words, we are seeing pieces of famous classical music being brought to life visually based on what Disney's artists think these pieces are about. We are also told that there are three types of musical pieces in this program: music that tells a definite story, music that paints a series of pictures, and "absolute music" that exists simply for its own sake. This animated feature basically consists of eight separate segments which all are devoted to one of the three types of music. Sometimes, one could make an argument that some segments have more than one of the three types of music, since some segments are more clearly cut in the type of music they're going for than other segments. For instance, the first segment "Toccata and Fugue in D Minor" is clearly an example of absolute music that exists simply for its own sake. All this segment composes of is visuals that one might think of whenever this classical music is being played. But then there are segments like "The Rite of Spring" which could easily count as music that paints a series of pictures as well as music that tells a definite story. The reason I believe this segment could apply to both is because while it tells us the history of the dinosaurs, you aren't exactly sure what to make of the overall main vision Disney was going for with this segment in the end. This is precisely why Fantasia is such a fascinating piece of filmmaking, because what it shows its audience is so unconventional and diverse that it's hard not to admire the fact that it's so unique with its story structure. After seeing this picture a couple times, I truly have a better understanding of why Fantasia was immensely influential in the film industry, particularly with the medium of music videos. If you think more about it, this film is basically a series of silent animated short films perfectly synchronized to famous pieces of classical music. Fantasia would easily qualify as one of the films I would be most interested in learning more about the making behind. I would be more than eager to learn what Walt Disney's animators thought when he wanted to pursue executing this specific project so soon after the ambitious production of Snow White. I would also be interested in learning the process behind the animation for these segments and how the animators synchronized the animation and music as well as they did, since I know the animation process was probably painstaking to say the least. Is this a film that will please everyone's tastes? I don't think so, since it's definitely an acquired taste for some. After all, Fantasia is considered a big step for Disney fans to take since it is so different from anything Disney ever did that it could throw them for a loop. Are there some slow moments? I'd say that this film gets off to a little bit of a slow start, but by the time the film's most famous segment "The Sorcerer's Apprentice" with Mickey Mouse comes around, it only gets better. Was the intermission involving the soundtrack corny and unnecessary? While I certainly can say it is by modern standards, I'll be fair by stating that this came out at a time when some audiences had trouble getting used to the then-new Technicolor process and their eyes had to take a break from the bright colors on screen. In short, Fantasia is truly a film that was way ahead of its time in almost every aspect imaginable. From outstanding segments like "The Rite of Spring" and "Night on Bald Mountain", to the excellent orchestration of the classical music by Leopold Stokowski and his orchestra, to the tremendous craft of the animation. It's one of those rare films in which the only way you can understand its importance in the history of cinema is to see for yourself. So what are you waiting for?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The epitome of the animated musical genre!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KadrianBlackwolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back when this film was made there were two broad schools of thought on animated films. One school believed that the animated action was the main point of an animated film and that the music should fit the animation. Sadly, this is how almost all animation is done today. The other school believed that the music should be the main focus and that the animation should enhance the music by providing an artistic visual representation. This is the school that "Fantasia" represents. I love this film and have watched it (or at least listened to it) countless times. The musical selections are among the best that classical music has to offer, and the animation and styling of the characters are classical Disney at its best. The scenes depicted vary from the hilarious to the terrifying to the awe-inspiring. Most satisfying are those that take your breath away and hold you in fascination with their beauty and elegance. My only complaint about the film is Disney's choice of Leopold Stokowski as conductor. Stokowski arrogantly took it upon himself to "improve" Mussorgsky's "Night on Bare Mountain," and effectively ruined the best parts of the score. Compare Stokowski's version with the original and you'll see what I mean. But with the exception of Stokowski's occasional interference, "Fantasia" is the best animated musical film ever produced.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Tenth Favorite Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1940's Fantasia Is My Tenth Favorite Film Of All Time, I Like It Because It's Has Great Animation Set To Classical Music, I Do Like The Live-Action Parts With Deems Taylor Where He Tells About Each Segment, My Favorite Segments I Like In This Are, Toccata And Fugue In D Minor, The Sorcerer's Apprentice, Rite Of Spring, A Night On Bald Mountain And Ave Maria, This Is My Favorite Animated Film And Also My Favorite Disney Film, I Really Don't Want To Get This Film On DVD Because My DVD Collection Is Done With And It's Full And Done With, The Only Version Of 1940's Fantasia That I Like The 2000 60th Anniversary Version With Corey Burton Doing The Voice Of Deems Taylor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike-duffy-486-49185
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fanatasia is not a film, it is an experience. Fantasia took a big risk back in 1940 when Walt Disney decided that he wanted to try something new. Fantasia has left a mark on history as one of the most unique and beautiful films ever created. Fantasia does not have a narrative story, it is shown through multiple 20-25 minute stories that do not have dialogue. The stories are told through music conducted by the great Leopold Stokowski. The music matches the visuals perfectly. The film opens with us listening to the orchestra play Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, accompanied by good visuals. The film then carries on to the six story lines which use classical music by some of the greats such as Beethoven and Tchaikovsky. All of these story lines are magnificently animated. Picking my favourite segment was not easy because they were all perfect. The segments include the creation of earth, The change of seasons on the envoirment and the devil vs God. My personal favourite is probably the mythology segment where we listen to Beethoven's Pastoral Symphony with animation of centaurs, fairies, gods and fawns. What really surprised me about Fantasia was the messages that were delivered in each segment that was up to the interpretation of the audience. For example, The Sorceror's Apprentice deals with a situation displaying what could happen if we had all the power in the world. The Dance of the Hours sequence deals with the innocence of the animal kingdom. These are just some examples of the power of visuals and music. What really makes Fantasia a masterpiece is how it ends. The final sequence which many people know of is the Night on Bald Mountain where we see the full power of the devil. Even if you are not religious(such as myself) the power in this sequence can touch anybody. The segment shows the devil awakening on a mountain and he begins to call spirits, ghost, demons, etc to the mountain where he proceeds to destroy them even in death with fire. The devil is stopped by God who puts him back to rest. After this we hear the Ave Maria and see monks with torches walking to a cathedral. The messages in this scene show probably the most powerful messages Disney has ever produced. Fanastia is a masterpiece plain and simple. Everything about this film works. The sequences are in the right order, the music is beautiful and the animation is breathtaking. As I commented earlier, Fantasia is not a movie it is an experience. The film is not really meant for kid. This is not because of the content but I only question how kids will handle a movie with no dialogue. I speak from experience. This film serves as Walt Disney's masterpiece and very much deserves that title. This is not just Disney at its best, it is probably one of the greatest films ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3rd out of 5 in the Golden Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantasia was released in the same year as Pinocchio (1940), but this film was released 9 months later in November. This film has he perfect amount of classical music, breathtaking animation, and memorable shorts to make the best package film ever made. Even though this film is 2 hours long, it does not feel that way, as you are just enjoying the shorts, which will go by so quickly. The best and the most iconic short in the film was "The Sorcerer's Apprentice". This is the one where Mickey tests out his master's tricks. The other shorts like "Rite of Spring", "Nutcracker Suite" and the others hold up as well. The children will enjoy the pretty animation and colours, while the adults will like the music and substance. Give it a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles_Hardy
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fantasia" is a wonderful blend of live action and animation, but not like the latter Disney films of "Mary Poppins" and "Petes Dragon." The live action sequences are that of Deems Taylor narrating the film as well as setting up the stories. Leopold Stowkowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra give us the music to fit to the beautiful pictures. The film was originally intended to be released each year (as a roadshow film) thereafter with different scenes intact as well as some old ones. This was not the case when WWII broke out and the US got involved. Walt Disney's vision would not be complete until "Fantasia 2000" was released in 1999. Probably the most important and proclaimed piece of "Fantasia" would be The Sorcerer's Apprentice starring Mickey Mouse. In fact, this sequence was reused in the sequel film in 1999 to achieve the roadshow feel that Disney wanted. It was also this sequence in the film that spawned another film in 2010 starring Nicolas Cage, "The Sorcerer's Apprentice." A wonderful film and one that will delve into your imagination and take you places you thought you may never see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Adult Fantasy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psychocosmic-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a person who consider Art, or rich Art, being able to elevate our minds and from which we are able to draw huge amount of information. Fantasia is not only a unique film, its also the only film which with musical pieces illustrates evolution at work and prehistoric scenes pretty scary and violent with the last groups of dinosaurs parading towards doom. Development and Extermination. Also, here you have sceneries of the Hellenian mythological world portraying the mating ritual and the Bacchus celebration, "sex, drugs and party!", and the battle between the light and the shadow world - the world of death and decay and that of light and peace. We get the living Nature in its transgressions through the different seasons, comical portraits of animals and veggies impersonating humans, and a moral tale of a young who forgot that he is not the tutor yet, etc. The basic thread of the movie is the music of course! To begin the film with J S Bach's Toccata and Fuge in d minor, is not only supercool, but is the perfect upwarming piece. As the music itself is pretty impossible to create a simple visual story with characters from, the visuals we see are closer to abstract and expressionism in form, with natural elements to illustrate Bach's famous cosmic flow of his fugues! Walt Disney was so serious with this project, that a psychological consult with experience of peyote, was hired to give guide lines to the different segments, not to mention all the ideas which came from the big crowd of artists that was working with the pictures and the translation of the music into pictures. Just like other Disney films of the period, like Three Caballeros 1946 and certain scenes in Dumbo and others, could easily be placed side by side with Yellow Submarine and experimental underground shorts in the late 60's, in a period when LSD, Psilocybin mushrooms and cannabis was the inspiration, for both young hippies and soul searching intellectuals. Disney was really psychedelic! The imagination at work in this film is so rich, that one can view it over and over again, to find details as well as new interpretations to the different segments. When viewing this multi artwork from beginning to end, through the music to the visuals and its themes, it seems to encompass the human and natural world on Earth,in a trancendental way, so it seems to be the perfect movie to send with a probe out into outer space, hoping to encounter an alien species, who might be able to watch it! They would not only consider it a colorful gem, but would find the film be a treasure for understanding Humans from the planet Earth. Of course, I am exaggerating, but still, if NASA could pack a satellite with chosen music, which I know they had, why not a movie? Anyways, this is a way for me to say, that Fantasia, as the film looks, could not have been made today, as the most powerful film companies would not bet a huge some of money on a project like this. Also, a feature film, all drawn and painted by hand, gives a decidedly more impressive look than one that is made in a computer. The fact is, that around 1939 - 1940, in the midst of Second World War, some of the most popular, hailed by critics and audience alike, greatest films were made. If the time consuming, painstaking efforts behind Pinoccio, Wizard of Oz, The Thief of Bagdad and Fantasia all are made to be true fantasy films, they seem to tell us that during war time it better works to make "timeless" films. In other words, films which not occupy themselves with the ever changing societies of Humanity and the issues of the times in which they were made. Instead, and this is what make them work as true art, they seem to speak to us, in matter of symbols, archetypes and themes which have been with us through the history of time. It could be seen as a work of a great shaman, who wants to remind us about the most important and utterly most sublimely beautiful things we have on this Earth. The Greatest Movie Achievement Ever In History! I only give full points (10/10) to films that are more than a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michelle Palmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I must say that my son and I were very, very impressed with the art work in this. Considering this movie was made in the 1940's and how they did the animated features back then, it took a lot of hard work, dedication, and talent for all involved to do this. I was amazed!!! My favorite scene is the Nutcracker piece. My second favorite was mickey mouse :-) We didn't really care for the others (though the Soundtrack part was pretty cute. We skipped about three chapters simply because we were not interested... We'll watch the parts we like in the future, but skip over the rest...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different, Not Meaningful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reuben Barbosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my life I've attempted to watch Fantasia at least 8 times, and every time I've always turned it off 30 to 40 minutes in. Does that warrant the film to get a 1/10? No, it has great animation but I still think the movie is a boring bunch of tar. The people who like Fantasia tend to say the film is good for it's emotional simplicity, creativity, and darker tone (when compared to other Disney films). I feel these reasons are somewhat ridiculous since even though I know when the film wants be to feel happy or sad, it still doesn't detract from the fact that's all the film has going for it: emotion. As someone who loves symbolism in film, I have never seen Fantasia show any images that would allow the viewer to think. Fantasia is like therapy, if you want to feel happy you can and if you want to feel sad you can. It's a movie where you just turn off your brain and enjoy the colours and music. Is there anything wrong with that? No. But, I still hate the fact that everyone treats this like 2001. The main difference between 2001 and Fantasia is that 2001 had an actual message it wanted to tell. Granted, that message is not entirely known by people but it is still a thought provoking film. Fantasia was an exercise in how the plot of a film can be told like 2001, but it feels like in the end it just had nothing to say. That's the main thing I find boring about the film, the fact that I have nothing to think about since it has nothing to say. I wouldn't call the film pretentious but I feel that fans of the film are pretentious for thinking a film that merely gives us emotions is the most revolutionary thing ever since it's just with animation and music. Any film can give you emotion with characters, plot, and meaning. Was Fantasia different? Yes. Does it have meaning? I don't think so but that's my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disney's most ambitious feature to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like DW Griffith's silent epic Intolerance (1916), Disney's most ambitious work Fantasia (1940) is a film more respected than loved. It is an experimental work, lacking the warmth of the most popular Disney films but beating out nearly all of them in terms of artistry and animation (its only rival being Pinocchio (1940)). Indeed, this might be the one Disney film created for an adult audience alone, even though more thoughtful children will be able to enjoy it. The Disney studio would never do something so bold as this ever again. Oh sure, they made Fantasia 2000 (1999) during the final years of the Disney Renaissance, but let's face it, that was made with toddlers in mind. It doesn't run nearly as long, insults the audience's intelligence with those dreadful celebrity introductions, and the new segments never measure up to the maturity and sublime artistry of the original. The Disney name is too closely linked with "children's entertainment" for them to boldly experiment at this point. That Fantasia was made at all is a miracle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fantasia" is truly a film ahead of its time and it needs to be seen in able for one to understand its importance in film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there is one thing that Walt Disney knew about better than anyone else, it was that the combination of music and animation is one of the most important combinations since bread and butter. This can best explain why most of Disney's animated features are all musicals. It's because Walt Disney strongly believed that music and sound were essential keys towards great animated features and shorts. One could make a good argument that his 3rd full-length animated feature, Fantasia (1940), was created as further proof regarding why he believed music was so essential to the world of animation. Fantasia is a unique animated feature in terms of its narrative. It starts out with an orchestra taking their places as if they were preparing for a concert. Then, the main narrator of this picture by the name of Deems Taylor emerges and introduces us to a new form of entertainment called Fantasia. We are told that during this new form of entertainment, we will see the images that classical music had inspired in the minds of Walt Disney's massive staff of artists. In other words, we are seeing pieces of famous classical music being brought to life visually based on what Disney's artists think these pieces are about. We are also told that there are three types of musical pieces in this program: music that tells a definite story, music that paints a series of pictures, and "absolute music" that exists simply for its own sake. This animated feature basically consists of eight separate segments which all are devoted to one of the three types of music. Sometimes, one could make an argument that some segments have more than one of the three types of music, since some segments are more clearly cut in the type of music they're going for than other segments. For instance, the first segment "Toccata and Fugue in D Minor" is clearly an example of absolute music that exists simply for its own sake. All this segment composes of is visuals that one might think of whenever this classical music is being played. But then there are segments like "The Rite of Spring" which could easily count as music that paints a series of pictures as well as music that tells a definite story. The reason I believe this segment could apply to both is because while it tells us the history of the dinosaurs, you aren't exactly sure what to make of the overall main vision Disney was going for with this segment in the end. This is precisely why Fantasia is such a fascinating piece of filmmaking, because what it shows its audience is so unconventional and diverse that it's hard not to admire the fact that it's so unique with its story structure. After seeing this picture a couple times, I truly have a better understanding of why Fantasia was immensely influential in the film industry, particularly with the medium of music videos. If you think more about it, this film is basically a series of silent animated short films perfectly synchronized to famous pieces of classical music. Fantasia would easily qualify as one of the films I would be most interested in learning more about the making behind. I would be more than eager to learn what Walt Disney's animators thought when he wanted to pursue executing this specific project so soon after the ambitious production of Snow White. I would also be interested in learning the process behind the animation for these segments and how the animators synchronized the animation and music as well as they did, since I know the animation process was probably painstaking to say the least. Is this a film that will please everyone's tastes? I don't think so, since it's definitely an acquired taste for some. After all, Fantasia is considered a big step for Disney fans to take since it is so different from anything Disney ever did that it could throw them for a loop. Are there some slow moments? I'd say that this film gets off to a little bit of a slow start, but by the time the film's most famous segment "The Sorcerer's Apprentice" with Mickey Mouse comes around, it only gets better. Was the intermission involving the soundtrack corny and unnecessary? While I certainly can say it is by modern standards, I'll be fair by stating that this came out at a time when some audiences had trouble getting used to the then-new Technicolor process and their eyes had to take a break from the bright colors on screen. In short, Fantasia is truly a film that was way ahead of its time in almost every aspect imaginable. From outstanding segments like "The Rite of Spring" and "Night on Bald Mountain", to the excellent orchestration of the classical music by Leopold Stokowski and his orchestra, to the tremendous craft of the animation. It's one of those rare films in which the only way you can understand its importance in the history of cinema is to see for yourself. So what are you waiting for?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The epitome of the animated musical genre!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KadrianBlackwolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back when this film was made there were two broad schools of thought on animated films. One school believed that the animated action was the main point of an animated film and that the music should fit the animation. Sadly, this is how almost all animation is done today. The other school believed that the music should be the main focus and that the animation should enhance the music by providing an artistic visual representation. This is the school that "Fantasia" represents. I love this film and have watched it (or at least listened to it) countless times. The musical selections are among the best that classical music has to offer, and the animation and styling of the characters are classical Disney at its best. The scenes depicted vary from the hilarious to the terrifying to the awe-inspiring. Most satisfying are those that take your breath away and hold you in fascination with their beauty and elegance. My only complaint about the film is Disney's choice of Leopold Stokowski as conductor. Stokowski arrogantly took it upon himself to "improve" Mussorgsky's "Night on Bare Mountain," and effectively ruined the best parts of the score. Compare Stokowski's version with the original and you'll see what I mean. But with the exception of Stokowski's occasional interference, "Fantasia" is the best animated musical film ever produced.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Tenth Favorite Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1940's Fantasia Is My Tenth Favorite Film Of All Time, I Like It Because It's Has Great Animation Set To Classical Music, I Do Like The Live-Action Parts With Deems Taylor Where He Tells About Each Segment, My Favorite Segments I Like In This Are, Toccata And Fugue In D Minor, The Sorcerer's Apprentice, Rite Of Spring, A Night On Bald Mountain And Ave Maria, This Is My Favorite Animated Film And Also My Favorite Disney Film, I Really Don't Want To Get This Film On DVD Because My DVD Collection Is Done With And It's Full And Done With, The Only Version Of 1940's Fantasia That I Like The 2000 60th Anniversary Version With Corey Burton Doing The Voice Of Deems Taylor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike-duffy-486-49185
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fanatasia is not a film, it is an experience. Fantasia took a big risk back in 1940 when Walt Disney decided that he wanted to try something new. Fantasia has left a mark on history as one of the most unique and beautiful films ever created. Fantasia does not have a narrative story, it is shown through multiple 20-25 minute stories that do not have dialogue. The stories are told through music conducted by the great Leopold Stokowski. The music matches the visuals perfectly. The film opens with us listening to the orchestra play Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, accompanied by good visuals. The film then carries on to the six story lines which use classical music by some of the greats such as Beethoven and Tchaikovsky. All of these story lines are magnificently animated. Picking my favourite segment was not easy because they were all perfect. The segments include the creation of earth, The change of seasons on the envoirment and the devil vs God. My personal favourite is probably the mythology segment where we listen to Beethoven's Pastoral Symphony with animation of centaurs, fairies, gods and fawns. What really surprised me about Fantasia was the messages that were delivered in each segment that was up to the interpretation of the audience. For example, The Sorceror's Apprentice deals with a situation displaying what could happen if we had all the power in the world. The Dance of the Hours sequence deals with the innocence of the animal kingdom. These are just some examples of the power of visuals and music. What really makes Fantasia a masterpiece is how it ends. The final sequence which many people know of is the Night on Bald Mountain where we see the full power of the devil. Even if you are not religious(such as myself) the power in this sequence can touch anybody. The segment shows the devil awakening on a mountain and he begins to call spirits, ghost, demons, etc to the mountain where he proceeds to destroy them even in death with fire. The devil is stopped by God who puts him back to rest. After this we hear the Ave Maria and see monks with torches walking to a cathedral. The messages in this scene show probably the most powerful messages Disney has ever produced. Fanastia is a masterpiece plain and simple. Everything about this film works. The sequences are in the right order, the music is beautiful and the animation is breathtaking. As I commented earlier, Fantasia is not a movie it is an experience. The film is not really meant for kid. This is not because of the content but I only question how kids will handle a movie with no dialogue. I speak from experience. This film serves as Walt Disney's masterpiece and very much deserves that title. This is not just Disney at its best, it is probably one of the greatest films ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3rd out of 5 in the Golden Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantasia was released in the same year as Pinocchio (1940), but this film was released 9 months later in November. This film has he perfect amount of classical music, breathtaking animation, and memorable shorts to make the best package film ever made. Even though this film is 2 hours long, it does not feel that way, as you are just enjoying the shorts, which will go by so quickly. The best and the most iconic short in the film was "The Sorcerer's Apprentice". This is the one where Mickey tests out his master's tricks. The other shorts like "Rite of Spring", "Nutcracker Suite" and the others hold up as well. The children will enjoy the pretty animation and colours, while the adults will like the music and substance. Give it a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles_Hardy
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fantasia" is a wonderful blend of live action and animation, but not like the latter Disney films of "Mary Poppins" and "Petes Dragon." The live action sequences are that of Deems Taylor narrating the film as well as setting up the stories. Leopold Stowkowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra give us the music to fit to the beautiful pictures. The film was originally intended to be released each year (as a roadshow film) thereafter with different scenes intact as well as some old ones. This was not the case when WWII broke out and the US got involved. Walt Disney's vision would not be complete until "Fantasia 2000" was released in 1999. Probably the most important and proclaimed piece of "Fantasia" would be The Sorcerer's Apprentice starring Mickey Mouse. In fact, this sequence was reused in the sequel film in 1999 to achieve the roadshow feel that Disney wanted. It was also this sequence in the film that spawned another film in 2010 starring Nicolas Cage, "The Sorcerer's Apprentice." A wonderful film and one that will delve into your imagination and take you places you thought you may never see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Adult Fantasy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psychocosmic-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a person who consider Art, or rich Art, being able to elevate our minds and from which we are able to draw huge amount of information. Fantasia is not only a unique film, its also the only film which with musical pieces illustrates evolution at work and prehistoric scenes pretty scary and violent with the last groups of dinosaurs parading towards doom. Development and Extermination. Also, here you have sceneries of the Hellenian mythological world portraying the mating ritual and the Bacchus celebration, "sex, drugs and party!", and the battle between the light and the shadow world - the world of death and decay and that of light and peace. We get the living Nature in its transgressions through the different seasons, comical portraits of animals and veggies impersonating humans, and a moral tale of a young who forgot that he is not the tutor yet, etc. The basic thread of the movie is the music of course! To begin the film with J S Bach's Toccata and Fuge in d minor, is not only supercool, but is the perfect upwarming piece. As the music itself is pretty impossible to create a simple visual story with characters from, the visuals we see are closer to abstract and expressionism in form, with natural elements to illustrate Bach's famous cosmic flow of his fugues! Walt Disney was so serious with this project, that a psychological consult with experience of peyote, was hired to give guide lines to the different segments, not to mention all the ideas which came from the big crowd of artists that was working with the pictures and the translation of the music into pictures. Just like other Disney films of the period, like Three Caballeros 1946 and certain scenes in Dumbo and others, could easily be placed side by side with Yellow Submarine and experimental underground shorts in the late 60's, in a period when LSD, Psilocybin mushrooms and cannabis was the inspiration, for both young hippies and soul searching intellectuals. Disney was really psychedelic! The imagination at work in this film is so rich, that one can view it over and over again, to find details as well as new interpretations to the different segments. When viewing this multi artwork from beginning to end, through the music to the visuals and its themes, it seems to encompass the human and natural world on Earth,in a trancendental way, so it seems to be the perfect movie to send with a probe out into outer space, hoping to encounter an alien species, who might be able to watch it! They would not only consider it a colorful gem, but would find the film be a treasure for understanding Humans from the planet Earth. Of course, I am exaggerating, but still, if NASA could pack a satellite with chosen music, which I know they had, why not a movie? Anyways, this is a way for me to say, that Fantasia, as the film looks, could not have been made today, as the most powerful film companies would not bet a huge some of money on a project like this. Also, a feature film, all drawn and painted by hand, gives a decidedly more impressive look than one that is made in a computer. The fact is, that around 1939 - 1940, in the midst of Second World War, some of the most popular, hailed by critics and audience alike, greatest films were made. If the time consuming, painstaking efforts behind Pinoccio, Wizard of Oz, The Thief of Bagdad and Fantasia all are made to be true fantasy films, they seem to tell us that during war time it better works to make "timeless" films. In other words, films which not occupy themselves with the ever changing societies of Humanity and the issues of the times in which they were made. Instead, and this is what make them work as true art, they seem to speak to us, in matter of symbols, archetypes and themes which have been with us through the history of time. It could be seen as a work of a great shaman, who wants to remind us about the most important and utterly most sublimely beautiful things we have on this Earth. The Greatest Movie Achievement Ever In History! I only give full points (10/10) to films that are more than a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michelle Palmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I must say that my son and I were very, very impressed with the art work in this. Considering this movie was made in the 1940's and how they did the animated features back then, it took a lot of hard work, dedication, and talent for all involved to do this. I was amazed!!! My favorite scene is the Nutcracker piece. My second favorite was mickey mouse :-) We didn't really care for the others (though the Soundtrack part was pretty cute. We skipped about three chapters simply because we were not interested... We'll watch the parts we like in the future, but skip over the rest...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different, Not Meaningful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reuben Barbosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my life I've attempted to watch Fantasia at least 8 times, and every time I've always turned it off 30 to 40 minutes in. Does that warrant the film to get a 1/10? No, it has great animation but I still think the movie is a boring bunch of tar. The people who like Fantasia tend to say the film is good for it's emotional simplicity, creativity, and darker tone (when compared to other Disney films). I feel these reasons are somewhat ridiculous since even though I know when the film wants be to feel happy or sad, it still doesn't detract from the fact that's all the film has going for it: emotion. As someone who loves symbolism in film, I have never seen Fantasia show any images that would allow the viewer to think. Fantasia is like therapy, if you want to feel happy you can and if you want to feel sad you can. It's a movie where you just turn off your brain and enjoy the colours and music. Is there anything wrong with that? No. But, I still hate the fact that everyone treats this like 2001. The main difference between 2001 and Fantasia is that 2001 had an actual message it wanted to tell. Granted, that message is not entirely known by people but it is still a thought provoking film. Fantasia was an exercise in how the plot of a film can be told like 2001, but it feels like in the end it just had nothing to say. That's the main thing I find boring about the film, the fact that I have nothing to think about since it has nothing to say. I wouldn't call the film pretentious but I feel that fans of the film are pretentious for thinking a film that merely gives us emotions is the most revolutionary thing ever since it's just with animation and music. Any film can give you emotion with characters, plot, and meaning. Was Fantasia different? Yes. Does it have meaning? I don't think so but that's my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disney's most ambitious feature to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like DW Griffith's silent epic Intolerance (1916), Disney's most ambitious work Fantasia (1940) is a film more respected than loved. It is an experimental work, lacking the warmth of the most popular Disney films but beating out nearly all of them in terms of artistry and animation (its only rival being Pinocchio (1940)). Indeed, this might be the one Disney film created for an adult audience alone, even though more thoughtful children will be able to enjoy it. The Disney studio would never do something so bold as this ever again. Oh sure, they made Fantasia 2000 (1999) during the final years of the Disney Renaissance, but let's face it, that was made with toddlers in mind. It doesn't run nearly as long, insults the audience's intelligence with those dreadful celebrity introductions, and the new segments never measure up to the maturity and sublime artistry of the original. The Disney name is too closely linked with "children's entertainment" for them to boldly experiment at this point. That Fantasia was made at all is a miracle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fantasia" is truly a film ahead of its time and it needs to be seen in able for one to understand its importance in film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there is one thing that Walt Disney knew about better than anyone else, it was that the combination of music and animation is one of the most important combinations since bread and butter. This can best explain why most of Disney's animated features are all musicals. It's because Walt Disney strongly believed that music and sound were essential keys towards great animated features and shorts. One could make a good argument that his 3rd full-length animated feature, Fantasia (1940), was created as further proof regarding why he believed music was so essential to the world of animation. Fantasia is a unique animated feature in terms of its narrative. It starts out with an orchestra taking their places as if they were preparing for a concert. Then, the main narrator of this picture by the name of Deems Taylor emerges and introduces us to a new form of entertainment called Fantasia. We are told that during this new form of entertainment, we will see the images that classical music had inspired in the minds of Walt Disney's massive staff of artists. In other words, we are seeing pieces of famous classical music being brought to life visually based on what Disney's artists think these pieces are about. We are also told that there are three types of musical pieces in this program: music that tells a definite story, music that paints a series of pictures, and "absolute music" that exists simply for its own sake. This animated feature basically consists of eight separate segments which all are devoted to one of the three types of music. Sometimes, one could make an argument that some segments have more than one of the three types of music, since some segments are more clearly cut in the type of music they're going for than other segments. For instance, the first segment "Toccata and Fugue in D Minor" is clearly an example of absolute music that exists simply for its own sake. All this segment composes of is visuals that one might think of whenever this classical music is being played. But then there are segments like "The Rite of Spring" which could easily count as music that paints a series of pictures as well as music that tells a definite story. The reason I believe this segment could apply to both is because while it tells us the history of the dinosaurs, you aren't exactly sure what to make of the overall main vision Disney was going for with this segment in the end. This is precisely why Fantasia is such a fascinating piece of filmmaking, because what it shows its audience is so unconventional and diverse that it's hard not to admire the fact that it's so unique with its story structure. After seeing this picture a couple times, I truly have a better understanding of why Fantasia was immensely influential in the film industry, particularly with the medium of music videos. If you think more about it, this film is basically a series of silent animated short films perfectly synchronized to famous pieces of classical music. Fantasia would easily qualify as one of the films I would be most interested in learning more about the making behind. I would be more than eager to learn what Walt Disney's animators thought when he wanted to pursue executing this specific project so soon after the ambitious production of Snow White. I would also be interested in learning the process behind the animation for these segments and how the animators synchronized the animation and music as well as they did, since I know the animation process was probably painstaking to say the least. Is this a film that will please everyone's tastes? I don't think so, since it's definitely an acquired taste for some. After all, Fantasia is considered a big step for Disney fans to take since it is so different from anything Disney ever did that it could throw them for a loop. Are there some slow moments? I'd say that this film gets off to a little bit of a slow start, but by the time the film's most famous segment "The Sorcerer's Apprentice" with Mickey Mouse comes around, it only gets better. Was the intermission involving the soundtrack corny and unnecessary? While I certainly can say it is by modern standards, I'll be fair by stating that this came out at a time when some audiences had trouble getting used to the then-new Technicolor process and their eyes had to take a break from the bright colors on screen. In short, Fantasia is truly a film that was way ahead of its time in almost every aspect imaginable. From outstanding segments like "The Rite of Spring" and "Night on Bald Mountain", to the excellent orchestration of the classical music by Leopold Stokowski and his orchestra, to the tremendous craft of the animation. It's one of those rare films in which the only way you can understand its importance in the history of cinema is to see for yourself. So what are you waiting for?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The epitome of the animated musical genre!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KadrianBlackwolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back when this film was made there were two broad schools of thought on animated films. One school believed that the animated action was the main point of an animated film and that the music should fit the animation. Sadly, this is how almost all animation is done today. The other school believed that the music should be the main focus and that the animation should enhance the music by providing an artistic visual representation. This is the school that "Fantasia" represents. I love this film and have watched it (or at least listened to it) countless times. The musical selections are among the best that classical music has to offer, and the animation and styling of the characters are classical Disney at its best. The scenes depicted vary from the hilarious to the terrifying to the awe-inspiring. Most satisfying are those that take your breath away and hold you in fascination with their beauty and elegance. My only complaint about the film is Disney's choice of Leopold Stokowski as conductor. Stokowski arrogantly took it upon himself to "improve" Mussorgsky's "Night on Bare Mountain," and effectively ruined the best parts of the score. Compare Stokowski's version with the original and you'll see what I mean. But with the exception of Stokowski's occasional interference, "Fantasia" is the best animated musical film ever produced.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Tenth Favorite Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1940's Fantasia Is My Tenth Favorite Film Of All Time, I Like It Because It's Has Great Animation Set To Classical Music, I Do Like The Live-Action Parts With Deems Taylor Where He Tells About Each Segment, My Favorite Segments I Like In This Are, Toccata And Fugue In D Minor, The Sorcerer's Apprentice, Rite Of Spring, A Night On Bald Mountain And Ave Maria, This Is My Favorite Animated Film And Also My Favorite Disney Film, I Really Don't Want To Get This Film On DVD Because My DVD Collection Is Done With And It's Full And Done With, The Only Version Of 1940's Fantasia That I Like The 2000 60th Anniversary Version With Corey Burton Doing The Voice Of Deems Taylor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike-duffy-486-49185
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fanatasia is not a film, it is an experience. Fantasia took a big risk back in 1940 when Walt Disney decided that he wanted to try something new. Fantasia has left a mark on history as one of the most unique and beautiful films ever created. Fantasia does not have a narrative story, it is shown through multiple 20-25 minute stories that do not have dialogue. The stories are told through music conducted by the great Leopold Stokowski. The music matches the visuals perfectly. The film opens with us listening to the orchestra play Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, accompanied by good visuals. The film then carries on to the six story lines which use classical music by some of the greats such as Beethoven and Tchaikovsky. All of these story lines are magnificently animated. Picking my favourite segment was not easy because they were all perfect. The segments include the creation of earth, The change of seasons on the envoirment and the devil vs God. My personal favourite is probably the mythology segment where we listen to Beethoven's Pastoral Symphony with animation of centaurs, fairies, gods and fawns. What really surprised me about Fantasia was the messages that were delivered in each segment that was up to the interpretation of the audience. For example, The Sorceror's Apprentice deals with a situation displaying what could happen if we had all the power in the world. The Dance of the Hours sequence deals with the innocence of the animal kingdom. These are just some examples of the power of visuals and music. What really makes Fantasia a masterpiece is how it ends. The final sequence which many people know of is the Night on Bald Mountain where we see the full power of the devil. Even if you are not religious(such as myself) the power in this sequence can touch anybody. The segment shows the devil awakening on a mountain and he begins to call spirits, ghost, demons, etc to the mountain where he proceeds to destroy them even in death with fire. The devil is stopped by God who puts him back to rest. After this we hear the Ave Maria and see monks with torches walking to a cathedral. The messages in this scene show probably the most powerful messages Disney has ever produced. Fanastia is a masterpiece plain and simple. Everything about this film works. The sequences are in the right order, the music is beautiful and the animation is breathtaking. As I commented earlier, Fantasia is not a movie it is an experience. The film is not really meant for kid. This is not because of the content but I only question how kids will handle a movie with no dialogue. I speak from experience. This film serves as Walt Disney's masterpiece and very much deserves that title. This is not just Disney at its best, it is probably one of the greatest films ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3rd out of 5 in the Golden Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantasia was released in the same year as Pinocchio (1940), but this film was released 9 months later in November. This film has he perfect amount of classical music, breathtaking animation, and memorable shorts to make the best package film ever made. Even though this film is 2 hours long, it does not feel that way, as you are just enjoying the shorts, which will go by so quickly. The best and the most iconic short in the film was "The Sorcerer's Apprentice". This is the one where Mickey tests out his master's tricks. The other shorts like "Rite of Spring", "Nutcracker Suite" and the others hold up as well. The children will enjoy the pretty animation and colours, while the adults will like the music and substance. Give it a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles_Hardy
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fantasia" is a wonderful blend of live action and animation, but not like the latter Disney films of "Mary Poppins" and "Petes Dragon." The live action sequences are that of Deems Taylor narrating the film as well as setting up the stories. Leopold Stowkowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra give us the music to fit to the beautiful pictures. The film was originally intended to be released each year (as a roadshow film) thereafter with different scenes intact as well as some old ones. This was not the case when WWII broke out and the US got involved. Walt Disney's vision would not be complete until "Fantasia 2000" was released in 1999. Probably the most important and proclaimed piece of "Fantasia" would be The Sorcerer's Apprentice starring Mickey Mouse. In fact, this sequence was reused in the sequel film in 1999 to achieve the roadshow feel that Disney wanted. It was also this sequence in the film that spawned another film in 2010 starring Nicolas Cage, "The Sorcerer's Apprentice." A wonderful film and one that will delve into your imagination and take you places you thought you may never see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Adult Fantasy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psychocosmic-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a person who consider Art, or rich Art, being able to elevate our minds and from which we are able to draw huge amount of information. Fantasia is not only a unique film, its also the only film which with musical pieces illustrates evolution at work and prehistoric scenes pretty scary and violent with the last groups of dinosaurs parading towards doom. Development and Extermination. Also, here you have sceneries of the Hellenian mythological world portraying the mating ritual and the Bacchus celebration, "sex, drugs and party!", and the battle between the light and the shadow world - the world of death and decay and that of light and peace. We get the living Nature in its transgressions through the different seasons, comical portraits of animals and veggies impersonating humans, and a moral tale of a young who forgot that he is not the tutor yet, etc. The basic thread of the movie is the music of course! To begin the film with J S Bach's Toccata and Fuge in d minor, is not only supercool, but is the perfect upwarming piece. As the music itself is pretty impossible to create a simple visual story with characters from, the visuals we see are closer to abstract and expressionism in form, with natural elements to illustrate Bach's famous cosmic flow of his fugues! Walt Disney was so serious with this project, that a psychological consult with experience of peyote, was hired to give guide lines to the different segments, not to mention all the ideas which came from the big crowd of artists that was working with the pictures and the translation of the music into pictures. Just like other Disney films of the period, like Three Caballeros 1946 and certain scenes in Dumbo and others, could easily be placed side by side with Yellow Submarine and experimental underground shorts in the late 60's, in a period when LSD, Psilocybin mushrooms and cannabis was the inspiration, for both young hippies and soul searching intellectuals. Disney was really psychedelic! The imagination at work in this film is so rich, that one can view it over and over again, to find details as well as new interpretations to the different segments. When viewing this multi artwork from beginning to end, through the music to the visuals and its themes, it seems to encompass the human and natural world on Earth,in a trancendental way, so it seems to be the perfect movie to send with a probe out into outer space, hoping to encounter an alien species, who might be able to watch it! They would not only consider it a colorful gem, but would find the film be a treasure for understanding Humans from the planet Earth. Of course, I am exaggerating, but still, if NASA could pack a satellite with chosen music, which I know they had, why not a movie? Anyways, this is a way for me to say, that Fantasia, as the film looks, could not have been made today, as the most powerful film companies would not bet a huge some of money on a project like this. Also, a feature film, all drawn and painted by hand, gives a decidedly more impressive look than one that is made in a computer. The fact is, that around 1939 - 1940, in the midst of Second World War, some of the most popular, hailed by critics and audience alike, greatest films were made. If the time consuming, painstaking efforts behind Pinoccio, Wizard of Oz, The Thief of Bagdad and Fantasia all are made to be true fantasy films, they seem to tell us that during war time it better works to make "timeless" films. In other words, films which not occupy themselves with the ever changing societies of Humanity and the issues of the times in which they were made. Instead, and this is what make them work as true art, they seem to speak to us, in matter of symbols, archetypes and themes which have been with us through the history of time. It could be seen as a work of a great shaman, who wants to remind us about the most important and utterly most sublimely beautiful things we have on this Earth. The Greatest Movie Achievement Ever In History! I only give full points (10/10) to films that are more than a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michelle Palmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I must say that my son and I were very, very impressed with the art work in this. Considering this movie was made in the 1940's and how they did the animated features back then, it took a lot of hard work, dedication, and talent for all involved to do this. I was amazed!!! My favorite scene is the Nutcracker piece. My second favorite was mickey mouse :-) We didn't really care for the others (though the Soundtrack part was pretty cute. We skipped about three chapters simply because we were not interested... We'll watch the parts we like in the future, but skip over the rest...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different, Not Meaningful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reuben Barbosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my life I've attempted to watch Fantasia at least 8 times, and every time I've always turned it off 30 to 40 minutes in. Does that warrant the film to get a 1/10? No, it has great animation but I still think the movie is a boring bunch of tar. The people who like Fantasia tend to say the film is good for it's emotional simplicity, creativity, and darker tone (when compared to other Disney films). I feel these reasons are somewhat ridiculous since even though I know when the film wants be to feel happy or sad, it still doesn't detract from the fact that's all the film has going for it: emotion. As someone who loves symbolism in film, I have never seen Fantasia show any images that would allow the viewer to think. Fantasia is like therapy, if you want to feel happy you can and if you want to feel sad you can. It's a movie where you just turn off your brain and enjoy the colours and music. Is there anything wrong with that? No. But, I still hate the fact that everyone treats this like 2001. The main difference between 2001 and Fantasia is that 2001 had an actual message it wanted to tell. Granted, that message is not entirely known by people but it is still a thought provoking film. Fantasia was an exercise in how the plot of a film can be told like 2001, but it feels like in the end it just had nothing to say. That's the main thing I find boring about the film, the fact that I have nothing to think about since it has nothing to say. I wouldn't call the film pretentious but I feel that fans of the film are pretentious for thinking a film that merely gives us emotions is the most revolutionary thing ever since it's just with animation and music. Any film can give you emotion with characters, plot, and meaning. Was Fantasia different? Yes. Does it have meaning? I don't think so but that's my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disney's most ambitious feature to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like DW Griffith's silent epic Intolerance (1916), Disney's most ambitious work Fantasia (1940) is a film more respected than loved. It is an experimental work, lacking the warmth of the most popular Disney films but beating out nearly all of them in terms of artistry and animation (its only rival being Pinocchio (1940)). Indeed, this might be the one Disney film created for an adult audience alone, even though more thoughtful children will be able to enjoy it. The Disney studio would never do something so bold as this ever again. Oh sure, they made Fantasia 2000 (1999) during the final years of the Disney Renaissance, but let's face it, that was made with toddlers in mind. It doesn't run nearly as long, insults the audience's intelligence with those dreadful celebrity introductions, and the new segments never measure up to the maturity and sublime artistry of the original. The Disney name is too closely linked with "children's entertainment" for them to boldly experiment at this point. That Fantasia was made at all is a miracle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fantasia" is truly a film ahead of its time and it needs to be seen in able for one to understand its importance in film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there is one thing that Walt Disney knew about better than anyone else, it was that the combination of music and animation is one of the most important combinations since bread and butter. This can best explain why most of Disney's animated features are all musicals. It's because Walt Disney strongly believed that music and sound were essential keys towards great animated features and shorts. One could make a good argument that his 3rd full-length animated feature, Fantasia (1940), was created as further proof regarding why he believed music was so essential to the world of animation. Fantasia is a unique animated feature in terms of its narrative. It starts out with an orchestra taking their places as if they were preparing for a concert. Then, the main narrator of this picture by the name of Deems Taylor emerges and introduces us to a new form of entertainment called Fantasia. We are told that during this new form of entertainment, we will see the images that classical music had inspired in the minds of Walt Disney's massive staff of artists. In other words, we are seeing pieces of famous classical music being brought to life visually based on what Disney's artists think these pieces are about. We are also told that there are three types of musical pieces in this program: music that tells a definite story, music that paints a series of pictures, and "absolute music" that exists simply for its own sake. This animated feature basically consists of eight separate segments which all are devoted to one of the three types of music. Sometimes, one could make an argument that some segments have more than one of the three types of music, since some segments are more clearly cut in the type of music they're going for than other segments. For instance, the first segment "Toccata and Fugue in D Minor" is clearly an example of absolute music that exists simply for its own sake. All this segment composes of is visuals that one might think of whenever this classical music is being played. But then there are segments like "The Rite of Spring" which could easily count as music that paints a series of pictures as well as music that tells a definite story. The reason I believe this segment could apply to both is because while it tells us the history of the dinosaurs, you aren't exactly sure what to make of the overall main vision Disney was going for with this segment in the end. This is precisely why Fantasia is such a fascinating piece of filmmaking, because what it shows its audience is so unconventional and diverse that it's hard not to admire the fact that it's so unique with its story structure. After seeing this picture a couple times, I truly have a better understanding of why Fantasia was immensely influential in the film industry, particularly with the medium of music videos. If you think more about it, this film is basically a series of silent animated short films perfectly synchronized to famous pieces of classical music. Fantasia would easily qualify as one of the films I would be most interested in learning more about the making behind. I would be more than eager to learn what Walt Disney's animators thought when he wanted to pursue executing this specific project so soon after the ambitious production of Snow White. I would also be interested in learning the process behind the animation for these segments and how the animators synchronized the animation and music as well as they did, since I know the animation process was probably painstaking to say the least. Is this a film that will please everyone's tastes? I don't think so, since it's definitely an acquired taste for some. After all, Fantasia is considered a big step for Disney fans to take since it is so different from anything Disney ever did that it could throw them for a loop. Are there some slow moments? I'd say that this film gets off to a little bit of a slow start, but by the time the film's most famous segment "The Sorcerer's Apprentice" with Mickey Mouse comes around, it only gets better. Was the intermission involving the soundtrack corny and unnecessary? While I certainly can say it is by modern standards, I'll be fair by stating that this came out at a time when some audiences had trouble getting used to the then-new Technicolor process and their eyes had to take a break from the bright colors on screen. In short, Fantasia is truly a film that was way ahead of its time in almost every aspect imaginable. From outstanding segments like "The Rite of Spring" and "Night on Bald Mountain", to the excellent orchestration of the classical music by Leopold Stokowski and his orchestra, to the tremendous craft of the animation. It's one of those rare films in which the only way you can understand its importance in the history of cinema is to see for yourself. So what are you waiting for?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The epitome of the animated musical genre!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KadrianBlackwolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back when this film was made there were two broad schools of thought on animated films. One school believed that the animated action was the main point of an animated film and that the music should fit the animation. Sadly, this is how almost all animation is done today. The other school believed that the music should be the main focus and that the animation should enhance the music by providing an artistic visual representation. This is the school that "Fantasia" represents. I love this film and have watched it (or at least listened to it) countless times. The musical selections are among the best that classical music has to offer, and the animation and styling of the characters are classical Disney at its best. The scenes depicted vary from the hilarious to the terrifying to the awe-inspiring. Most satisfying are those that take your breath away and hold you in fascination with their beauty and elegance. My only complaint about the film is Disney's choice of Leopold Stokowski as conductor. Stokowski arrogantly took it upon himself to "improve" Mussorgsky's "Night on Bare Mountain," and effectively ruined the best parts of the score. Compare Stokowski's version with the original and you'll see what I mean. But with the exception of Stokowski's occasional interference, "Fantasia" is the best animated musical film ever produced.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Tenth Favorite Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1940's Fantasia Is My Tenth Favorite Film Of All Time, I Like It Because It's Has Great Animation Set To Classical Music, I Do Like The Live-Action Parts With Deems Taylor Where He Tells About Each Segment, My Favorite Segments I Like In This Are, Toccata And Fugue In D Minor, The Sorcerer's Apprentice, Rite Of Spring, A Night On Bald Mountain And Ave Maria, This Is My Favorite Animated Film And Also My Favorite Disney Film, I Really Don't Want To Get This Film On DVD Because My DVD Collection Is Done With And It's Full And Done With, The Only Version Of 1940's Fantasia That I Like The 2000 60th Anniversary Version With Corey Burton Doing The Voice Of Deems Taylor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike-duffy-486-49185
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fanatasia is not a film, it is an experience. Fantasia took a big risk back in 1940 when Walt Disney decided that he wanted to try something new. Fantasia has left a mark on history as one of the most unique and beautiful films ever created. Fantasia does not have a narrative story, it is shown through multiple 20-25 minute stories that do not have dialogue. The stories are told through music conducted by the great Leopold Stokowski. The music matches the visuals perfectly. The film opens with us listening to the orchestra play Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, accompanied by good visuals. The film then carries on to the six story lines which use classical music by some of the greats such as Beethoven and Tchaikovsky. All of these story lines are magnificently animated. Picking my favourite segment was not easy because they were all perfect. The segments include the creation of earth, The change of seasons on the envoirment and the devil vs God. My personal favourite is probably the mythology segment where we listen to Beethoven's Pastoral Symphony with animation of centaurs, fairies, gods and fawns. What really surprised me about Fantasia was the messages that were delivered in each segment that was up to the interpretation of the audience. For example, The Sorceror's Apprentice deals with a situation displaying what could happen if we had all the power in the world. The Dance of the Hours sequence deals with the innocence of the animal kingdom. These are just some examples of the power of visuals and music. What really makes Fantasia a masterpiece is how it ends. The final sequence which many people know of is the Night on Bald Mountain where we see the full power of the devil. Even if you are not religious(such as myself) the power in this sequence can touch anybody. The segment shows the devil awakening on a mountain and he begins to call spirits, ghost, demons, etc to the mountain where he proceeds to destroy them even in death with fire. The devil is stopped by God who puts him back to rest. After this we hear the Ave Maria and see monks with torches walking to a cathedral. The messages in this scene show probably the most powerful messages Disney has ever produced. Fanastia is a masterpiece plain and simple. Everything about this film works. The sequences are in the right order, the music is beautiful and the animation is breathtaking. As I commented earlier, Fantasia is not a movie it is an experience. The film is not really meant for kid. This is not because of the content but I only question how kids will handle a movie with no dialogue. I speak from experience. This film serves as Walt Disney's masterpiece and very much deserves that title. This is not just Disney at its best, it is probably one of the greatest films ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3rd out of 5 in the Golden Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantasia was released in the same year as Pinocchio (1940), but this film was released 9 months later in November. This film has he perfect amount of classical music, breathtaking animation, and memorable shorts to make the best package film ever made. Even though this film is 2 hours long, it does not feel that way, as you are just enjoying the shorts, which will go by so quickly. The best and the most iconic short in the film was "The Sorcerer's Apprentice". This is the one where Mickey tests out his master's tricks. The other shorts like "Rite of Spring", "Nutcracker Suite" and the others hold up as well. The children will enjoy the pretty animation and colours, while the adults will like the music and substance. Give it a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles_Hardy
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fantasia" is a wonderful blend of live action and animation, but not like the latter Disney films of "Mary Poppins" and "Petes Dragon." The live action sequences are that of Deems Taylor narrating the film as well as setting up the stories. Leopold Stowkowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra give us the music to fit to the beautiful pictures. The film was originally intended to be released each year (as a roadshow film) thereafter with different scenes intact as well as some old ones. This was not the case when WWII broke out and the US got involved. Walt Disney's vision would not be complete until "Fantasia 2000" was released in 1999. Probably the most important and proclaimed piece of "Fantasia" would be The Sorcerer's Apprentice starring Mickey Mouse. In fact, this sequence was reused in the sequel film in 1999 to achieve the roadshow feel that Disney wanted. It was also this sequence in the film that spawned another film in 2010 starring Nicolas Cage, "The Sorcerer's Apprentice." A wonderful film and one that will delve into your imagination and take you places you thought you may never see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Adult Fantasy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psychocosmic-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a person who consider Art, or rich Art, being able to elevate our minds and from which we are able to draw huge amount of information. Fantasia is not only a unique film, its also the only film which with musical pieces illustrates evolution at work and prehistoric scenes pretty scary and violent with the last groups of dinosaurs parading towards doom. Development and Extermination. Also, here you have sceneries of the Hellenian mythological world portraying the mating ritual and the Bacchus celebration, "sex, drugs and party!", and the battle between the light and the shadow world - the world of death and decay and that of light and peace. We get the living Nature in its transgressions through the different seasons, comical portraits of animals and veggies impersonating humans, and a moral tale of a young who forgot that he is not the tutor yet, etc. The basic thread of the movie is the music of course! To begin the film with J S Bach's Toccata and Fuge in d minor, is not only supercool, but is the perfect upwarming piece. As the music itself is pretty impossible to create a simple visual story with characters from, the visuals we see are closer to abstract and expressionism in form, with natural elements to illustrate Bach's famous cosmic flow of his fugues! Walt Disney was so serious with this project, that a psychological consult with experience of peyote, was hired to give guide lines to the different segments, not to mention all the ideas which came from the big crowd of artists that was working with the pictures and the translation of the music into pictures. Just like other Disney films of the period, like Three Caballeros 1946 and certain scenes in Dumbo and others, could easily be placed side by side with Yellow Submarine and experimental underground shorts in the late 60's, in a period when LSD, Psilocybin mushrooms and cannabis was the inspiration, for both young hippies and soul searching intellectuals. Disney was really psychedelic! The imagination at work in this film is so rich, that one can view it over and over again, to find details as well as new interpretations to the different segments. When viewing this multi artwork from beginning to end, through the music to the visuals and its themes, it seems to encompass the human and natural world on Earth,in a trancendental way, so it seems to be the perfect movie to send with a probe out into outer space, hoping to encounter an alien species, who might be able to watch it! They would not only consider it a colorful gem, but would find the film be a treasure for understanding Humans from the planet Earth. Of course, I am exaggerating, but still, if NASA could pack a satellite with chosen music, which I know they had, why not a movie? Anyways, this is a way for me to say, that Fantasia, as the film looks, could not have been made today, as the most powerful film companies would not bet a huge some of money on a project like this. Also, a feature film, all drawn and painted by hand, gives a decidedly more impressive look than one that is made in a computer. The fact is, that around 1939 - 1940, in the midst of Second World War, some of the most popular, hailed by critics and audience alike, greatest films were made. If the time consuming, painstaking efforts behind Pinoccio, Wizard of Oz, The Thief of Bagdad and Fantasia all are made to be true fantasy films, they seem to tell us that during war time it better works to make "timeless" films. In other words, films which not occupy themselves with the ever changing societies of Humanity and the issues of the times in which they were made. Instead, and this is what make them work as true art, they seem to speak to us, in matter of symbols, archetypes and themes which have been with us through the history of time. It could be seen as a work of a great shaman, who wants to remind us about the most important and utterly most sublimely beautiful things we have on this Earth. The Greatest Movie Achievement Ever In History! I only give full points (10/10) to films that are more than a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michelle Palmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I must say that my son and I were very, very impressed with the art work in this. Considering this movie was made in the 1940's and how they did the animated features back then, it took a lot of hard work, dedication, and talent for all involved to do this. I was amazed!!! My favorite scene is the Nutcracker piece. My second favorite was mickey mouse :-) We didn't really care for the others (though the Soundtrack part was pretty cute. We skipped about three chapters simply because we were not interested... We'll watch the parts we like in the future, but skip over the rest...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different, Not Meaningful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reuben Barbosa
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my life I've attempted to watch Fantasia at least 8 times, and every time I've always turned it off 30 to 40 minutes in. Does that warrant the film to get a 1/10? No, it has great animation but I still think the movie is a boring bunch of tar. The people who like Fantasia tend to say the film is good for it's emotional simplicity, creativity, and darker tone (when compared to other Disney films). I feel these reasons are somewhat ridiculous since even though I know when the film wants be to feel happy or sad, it still doesn't detract from the fact that's all the film has going for it: emotion. As someone who loves symbolism in film, I have never seen Fantasia show any images that would allow the viewer to think. Fantasia is like therapy, if you want to feel happy you can and if you want to feel sad you can. It's a movie where you just turn off your brain and enjoy the colours and music. Is there anything wrong with that? No. But, I still hate the fact that everyone treats this like 2001. The main difference between 2001 and Fantasia is that 2001 had an actual message it wanted to tell. Granted, that message is not entirely known by people but it is still a thought provoking film. Fantasia was an exercise in how the plot of a film can be told like 2001, but it feels like in the end it just had nothing to say. That's the main thing I find boring about the film, the fact that I have nothing to think about since it has nothing to say. I wouldn't call the film pretentious but I feel that fans of the film are pretentious for thinking a film that merely gives us emotions is the most revolutionary thing ever since it's just with animation and music. Any film can give you emotion with characters, plot, and meaning. Was Fantasia different? Yes. Does it have meaning? I don't think so but that's my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disney's most ambitious feature to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like DW Griffith's silent epic Intolerance (1916), Disney's most ambitious work Fantasia (1940) is a film more respected than loved. It is an experimental work, lacking the warmth of the most popular Disney films but beating out nearly all of them in terms of artistry and animation (its only rival being Pinocchio (1940)). Indeed, this might be the one Disney film created for an adult audience alone, even though more thoughtful children will be able to enjoy it. The Disney studio would never do something so bold as this ever again. Oh sure, they made Fantasia 2000 (1999) during the final years of the Disney Renaissance, but let's face it, that was made with toddlers in mind. It doesn't run nearly as long, insults the audience's intelligence with those dreadful celebrity introductions, and the new segments never measure up to the maturity and sublime artistry of the original. The Disney name is too closely linked with "children's entertainment" for them to boldly experiment at this point. That Fantasia was made at all is a miracle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Fantasia" is truly a film ahead of its time and it needs to be seen in able for one to understand its importance in film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there is one thing that Walt Disney knew about better than anyone else, it was that the combination of music and animation is one of the most important combinations since bread and butter. This can best explain why most of Disney's animated features are all musicals. It's because Walt Disney strongly believed that music and sound were essential keys towards great animated features and shorts. One could make a good argument that his 3rd full-length animated feature, Fantasia (1940), was created as further proof regarding why he believed music was so essential to the world of animation. Fantasia is a unique animated feature in terms of its narrative. It starts out with an orchestra taking their places as if they were preparing for a concert. Then, the main narrator of this picture by the name of Deems Taylor emerges and introduces us to a new form of entertainment called Fantasia. We are told that during this new form of entertainment, we will see the images that classical music had inspired in the minds of Walt Disney's massive staff of artists. In other words, we are seeing pieces of famous classical music being brought to life visually based on what Disney's artists think these pieces are about. We are also told that there are three types of musical pieces in this program: music that tells a definite story, music that paints a series of pictures, and "absolute music" that exists simply for its own sake. This animated feature basically consists of eight separate segments which all are devoted to one of the three types of music. Sometimes, one could make an argument that some segments have more than one of the three types of music, since some segments are more clearly cut in the type of music they're going for than other segments. For instance, the first segment "Toccata and Fugue in D Minor" is clearly an example of absolute music that exists simply for its own sake. All this segment composes of is visuals that one might think of whenever this classical music is being played. But then there are segments like "The Rite of Spring" which could easily count as music that paints a series of pictures as well as music that tells a definite story. The reason I believe this segment could apply to both is because while it tells us the history of the dinosaurs, you aren't exactly sure what to make of the overall main vision Disney was going for with this segment in the end. This is precisely why Fantasia is such a fascinating piece of filmmaking, because what it shows its audience is so unconventional and diverse that it's hard not to admire the fact that it's so unique with its story structure. After seeing this picture a couple times, I truly have a better understanding of why Fantasia was immensely influential in the film industry, particularly with the medium of music videos. If you think more about it, this film is basically a series of silent animated short films perfectly synchronized to famous pieces of classical music. Fantasia would easily qualify as one of the films I would be most interested in learning more about the making behind. I would be more than eager to learn what Walt Disney's animators thought when he wanted to pursue executing this specific project so soon after the ambitious production of Snow White. I would also be interested in learning the process behind the animation for these segments and how the animators synchronized the animation and music as well as they did, since I know the animation process was probably painstaking to say the least. Is this a film that will please everyone's tastes? I don't think so, since it's definitely an acquired taste for some. After all, Fantasia is considered a big step for Disney fans to take since it is so different from anything Disney ever did that it could throw them for a loop. Are there some slow moments? I'd say that this film gets off to a little bit of a slow start, but by the time the film's most famous segment "The Sorcerer's Apprentice" with Mickey Mouse comes around, it only gets better. Was the intermission involving the soundtrack corny and unnecessary? While I certainly can say it is by modern standards, I'll be fair by stating that this came out at a time when some audiences had trouble getting used to the then-new Technicolor process and their eyes had to take a break from the bright colors on screen. In short, Fantasia is truly a film that was way ahead of its time in almost every aspect imaginable. From outstanding segments like "The Rite of Spring" and "Night on Bald Mountain", to the excellent orchestration of the classical music by Leopold Stokowski and his orchestra, to the tremendous craft of the animation. It's one of those rare films in which the only way you can understand its importance in the history of cinema is to see for yourself. So what are you waiting for?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The epitome of the animated musical genre!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KadrianBlackwolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back when this film was made there were two broad schools of thought on animated films. One school believed that the animated action was the main point of an animated film and that the music should fit the animation. Sadly, this is how almost all animation is done today. The other school believed that the music should be the main focus and that the animation should enhance the music by providing an artistic visual representation. This is the school that "Fantasia" represents. I love this film and have watched it (or at least listened to it) countless times. The musical selections are among the best that classical music has to offer, and the animation and styling of the characters are classical Disney at its best. The scenes depicted vary from the hilarious to the terrifying to the awe-inspiring. Most satisfying are those that take your breath away and hold you in fascination with their beauty and elegance. My only complaint about the film is Disney's choice of Leopold Stokowski as conductor. Stokowski arrogantly took it upon himself to "improve" Mussorgsky's "Night on Bare Mountain," and effectively ruined the best parts of the score. Compare Stokowski's version with the original and you'll see what I mean. But with the exception of Stokowski's occasional interference, "Fantasia" is the best animated musical film ever produced.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Tenth Favorite Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1940's Fantasia Is My Tenth Favorite Film Of All Time, I Like It Because It's Has Great Animation Set To Classical Music, I Do Like The Live-Action Parts With Deems Taylor Where He Tells About Each Segment, My Favorite Segments I Like In This Are, Toccata And Fugue In D Minor, The Sorcerer's Apprentice, Rite Of Spring, A Night On Bald Mountain And Ave Maria, This Is My Favorite Animated Film And Also My Favorite Disney Film, I Really Don't Want To Get This Film On DVD Because My DVD Collection Is Done With And It's Full And Done With, The Only Version Of 1940's Fantasia That I Like The 2000 60th Anniversary Version With Corey Burton Doing The Voice Of Deems Taylor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike-duffy-486-49185
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fanatasia is not a film, it is an experience. Fantasia took a big risk back in 1940 when Walt Disney decided that he wanted to try something new. Fantasia has left a mark on history as one of the most unique and beautiful films ever created. Fantasia does not have a narrative story, it is shown through multiple 20-25 minute stories that do not have dialogue. The stories are told through music conducted by the great Leopold Stokowski. The music matches the visuals perfectly. The film opens with us listening to the orchestra play Toccata and Fugue in D Minor, accompanied by good visuals. The film then carries on to the six story lines which use classical music by some of the greats such as Beethoven and Tchaikovsky. All of these story lines are magnificently animated. Picking my favourite segment was not easy because they were all perfect. The segments include the creation of earth, The change of seasons on the envoirment and the devil vs God. My personal favourite is probably the mythology segment where we listen to Beethoven's Pastoral Symphony with animation of centaurs, fairies, gods and fawns. What really surprised me about Fantasia was the messages that were delivered in each segment that was up to the interpretation of the audience. For example, The Sorceror's Apprentice deals with a situation displaying what could happen if we had all the power in the world. The Dance of the Hours sequence deals with the innocence of the animal kingdom. These are just some examples of the power of visuals and music. What really makes Fantasia a masterpiece is how it ends. The final sequence which many people know of is the Night on Bald Mountain where we see the full power of the devil. Even if you are not religious(such as myself) the power in this sequence can touch anybody. The segment shows the devil awakening on a mountain and he begins to call spirits, ghost, demons, etc to the mountain where he proceeds to destroy them even in death with fire. The devil is stopped by God who puts him back to rest. After this we hear the Ave Maria and see monks with torches walking to a cathedral. The messages in this scene show probably the most powerful messages Disney has ever produced. Fanastia is a masterpiece plain and simple. Everything about this film works. The sequences are in the right order, the music is beautiful and the animation is breathtaking. As I commented earlier, Fantasia is not a movie it is an experience. The film is not really meant for kid. This is not because of the content but I only question how kids will handle a movie with no dialogue. I speak from experience. This film serves as Walt Disney's masterpiece and very much deserves that title. This is not just Disney at its best, it is probably one of the greatest films ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3rd out of 5 in the Golden Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantasia was released in the same year as Pinocchio (1940), but this film was released 9 months later in November. This film has he perfect amount of classical music, breathtaking animation, and memorable shorts to make the best package film ever made. Even though this film is 2 hours long, it does not feel that way, as you are just enjoying the shorts, which will go by so quickly. The best and the most iconic short in the film was "The Sorcerer's Apprentice". This is the one where Mickey tests out his master's tricks. The other shorts like "Rite of Spring", "Nutcracker Suite" and the others hold up as well. The children will enjoy the pretty animation and colours, while the adults will like the music and substance. Give it a watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walt Disney's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles_Hardy
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fantasia" is a wonderful blend of live action and animation, but not like the latter Disney films of "Mary Poppins" and "Petes Dragon." The live action sequences are that of Deems Taylor narrating the film as well as setting up the stories. Leopold Stowkowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra give us the music to fit to the beautiful pictures. The film was originally intended to be released each year (as a roadshow film) thereafter with different scenes intact as well as some old ones. This was not the case when WWII broke out and the US got involved. Walt Disney's vision would not be complete until "Fantasia 2000" was released in 1999. Probably the most important and proclaimed piece of "Fantasia" would be The Sorcerer's Apprentice starring Mickey Mouse. In fact, this sequence was reused in the sequel film in 1999 to achieve the roadshow feel that Disney wanted. It was also this sequence in the film that spawned another film in 2010 starring Nicolas Cage, "The Sorcerer's Apprentice." A wonderful film and one that will delve into your imagination and take you places you thought you may never see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Adult Fantasy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psychocosmic-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a person who consider Art, or rich Art, being able to elevate our minds and from which we are able to draw huge amount of information. Fantasia is not only a unique film, its also the only film which with musical pieces illustrates evolution at work and prehistoric scenes pretty scary and violent with the last groups of dinosaurs parading towards doom. Development and Extermination. Also, here you have sceneries of the Hellenian mythological world portraying the mating ritual and the Bacchus celebration, "sex, drugs and party!", and the battle between the light and the shadow world - the world of death and decay and that of light and peace. We get the living Nature in its transgressions through the different seasons, comical portraits of animals and veggies impersonating humans, and a moral tale of a young who forgot that he is not the tutor yet, etc. The basic thread of the movie is the music of course! To begin the film with J S Bach's Toccata and Fuge in d minor, is not only supercool, but is the perfect upwarming piece. As the music itself is pretty impossible to create a simple visual story with characters from, the visuals we see are closer to abstract and expressionism in form, with natural elements to illustrate Bach's famous cosmic flow of his fugues! Walt Disney was so serious with this project, that a psychological consult with experience of peyote, was hired to give guide lines to the different segments, not to mention all the ideas which came from the big crowd of artists that was working with the pictures and the translation of the music into pictures. Just like other Disney films of the period, like Three Caballeros 1946 and certain scenes in Dumbo and others, could easily be placed side by side with Yellow Submarine and experimental underground shorts in the late 60's, in a period when LSD, Psilocybin mushrooms and cannabis was the inspiration, for both young hippies and soul searching intellectuals. Disney was really psychedelic! The imagination at work in this film is so rich, that one can view it over and over again, to find details as well as new interpretations to the different segments. When viewing this multi artwork from beginning to end, through the music to the visuals and its themes, it seems to encompass the human and natural world on Earth,in a trancendental way, so it seems to be the perfect movie to send with a probe out into outer space, hoping to encounter an alien species, who might be able to watch it! They would not only consider it a colorful gem, but would find the film be a treasure for understanding Humans from the planet Earth. Of course, I am exaggerating, but still, if NASA could pack a satellite with chosen music, which I know they had, why not a movie? Anyways, this is a way for me to say, that Fantasia, as the film looks, could not have been made today, as the most powerful film companies would not bet a huge some of money on a project like this. Also, a feature film, all drawn and painted by hand, gives a decidedly more impressive look than one that is made in a computer. The fact is, that around 1939 - 1940, in the midst of Second World War, some of the most popular, hailed by critics and audience alike, greatest films were made. If the time consuming, painstaking efforts behind Pinoccio, Wizard of Oz, The Thief of Bagdad and Fantasia all are made to be true fantasy films, they seem to tell us that during war time it better works to make "timeless" films. In other words, films which not occupy themselves with the ever changing societies of Humanity and the issues of the times in which they were made. Instead, and this is what make them work as true art, they seem to speak to us, in matter of symbols, archetypes and themes which have been with us through the history of time. It could be seen as a work of a great shaman, who wants to remind us about the most important and utterly most sublimely beautiful things we have on this Earth. The Greatest Movie Achievement Ever In History! I only give full points (10/10) to films that are more than a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michelle Palmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I must say that my son and I were very, very impressed with the art work in this. Considering this movie was made in the 1940's and how they did the animated features back then, it took a lot of hard work, dedication, and talent for all involved to do this. I was amazed!!! My favorite scene is the Nutcracker piece. My second favorite was mickey mouse :-) We didn't really care for the others (though the Soundtrack part was pretty cute. We skipped about three chapters simply because we were not interested... We'll watch the parts we like in the future, but skip over the rest...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
