<filme>
 <id>
  445
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0037549
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1945
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O T&uacute;mulo Vazio
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A ruthless doctor and his young prize student find themselves continually harassed by their murderous supplier of illegal cadavers.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In Edinburgh in 1831, Dr. Wolfe MacFarlane runs a medical school where Donald Fettes is a student. Fettes is interested in helping a young girl who has lost the use of her legs. He is certain that MacFarlane's surgical skills could be put to great use but he is reluctant to do so. The good Dr. MacFarlane has a secret that soon becomes all too obvious to young Fettes, who has only recently been promoted as his assistant: he has been paying a local cabbie, John Gray, to supply him with dead bodies for anatomical research. Gray constantly harasses MacFarlane and clearly has a hold over him dating to a famous trial many years before where Gray refused to identify the man for whom he was robbing graves. Fettes isn't aware of any of this but soon realizes exactly how Gray obtains the bodies they use in their anatomy classes.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   medical
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   doctor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cemetery
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   medical student
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Robert Wise
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Robert Louis Stevenson
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Philip MacDonald
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Boris Karloff
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bela Lugosi
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Henry Daniell
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant film with Karloff in one of his finest ever performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film directed by Robert Wise, starring Boris Karloff and Bela Lugosi and based on a story by Robert Louis Stevenson, The Body Snatcher had all the ingredients to be great. And it was. It is very well-made, the attention to detail is authentic and very striking and it is shot in a way that really enhances the atmosphere, the use of shadows, gloomy cobbled streets and the lighting also add much. The music score is softly suspenseful with the ability to be chilling and emotional when called for. The dialogue has a fair bit of talk but is very literate and intelligent and develops its two main characters to the extent that they're much more complex than they seem to be. The supporting characters are not as interesting but are written better than other films of the same genre, whether before, during or after. The story is pitch-perfect in pace, it's very sedate but it complimented brilliantly with the atmosphere and I actually think any other type of pacing would not have worked anywhere near as effectively. People may say that there isn't much horror, while billed as a horror in some way I saw it more of a film that relied more on atmosphere and suspense than all else; this worked wonders because the scene with Karloff following the girl(I don't think I have seen that type of scene done so chillingly on film) and the ending are genuinely creepy and the atmosphere is ominous but in a restrained way. The subplot with the crippled girl didn't bother me at all, I for one found it touching and the girl was played with real sincerity. Robert Wise's imaginative direction really does help, as do the performances. Russell Wade is a little too much of a drip for my tastes but the supporting roles are played well on the believe, and Bela Lugosi still gives a sinister turn despite limited screen time. The two leads dominate though, Henry Daniell has a juicy role which he plays with intensity and sympathy but it's the magnificently evil performance of Boris Karloff that really does it for me, one of his finest ever performances easily. All in all, brilliant. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A More Complex Horror Movie Than Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A mid-series movie from that master of horror, Val Lewton. It's not quite front-rank, like The Seventh Victim (1943) or The Cat People (1942), but it's close. The horror, of course, is subdued, allowing the imagination to fill in the blanks, both of which amount to Lewton's brilliant trademark. Perhaps the most unsettling instance here is the lovely little street singer as she lullabies pitch-perfect down a darkened byway, only to be cut short by the maddened cabman (Karloff) who follows her. Now her heavenly aire is lost forever, even as her corporeal body is delivered to medical school for vivisection. In fact, the movie raises a knotty ethical question amidst the ghoulish goings-on. Namely, what in fact are the ethical limits on the advancement of medical science. Dr. MacFarlane (Daniell) needs cadavers to teach his classes and especially to heal the paralyzed little girl (Moffett). So he relies on grave-robber Gray (Karloff) to supply him with the freshly dead. Of course, it's clearly wrong to kill someone for cadaver purposes, as Gray does to the street singer. But is it clearly wrong to rob graves so that the living may benefit. It's an interesting question to raise, as the movie does, and one that thankfully medical science no longer must struggle with. Karloff delivers an outstanding turn as the wickedly jolly grave robber John Gray. Excellent also are Daniell and Lugosi in unusually restrained roles. In fact, Daniell's doctor amounts to an interesting character, a man who can neither accept nor reject his other halfhis cadaver supplier, Gray. At the same time, the movie's ostensible hero Fettes (Wade), the young handsome medical student, can neither wholly accept nor reject the methods of his mentor MacFarlane. Thus the narrative's character development is much more complex than expected for a 70-minute, horror movie. But then that too was part of the brilliance of cult producer Val Lewton. I can't help noting that the lighting bill for this exceptionally shadowy movie could not have exceeded five bucks. There's not a ray of sunshine or high-key lighting anywhere in the narrative. But then the whole thing is being shot on an RKO sound stage for minimal bucks. Amazing, however, what can be achieved in the face of such constraints. No doubt about it, the world of Val Lewton is like that of no other moviemaker, then or now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where a doctor's zeal for medical science goes off the rails.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is interesting for a couple of reasons. First, it's from a short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, one of the 19th century greats. Second, it stars the two bad guys of horror  Karloff and Lugosi  together for the second time (the other was Son of Frankenstein in 1939). And a third reason, perhaps, is the presence of Henry Daniell, as Toddy MacFarlane, who is usually in a supporting role to other bigger stars. In this effort, he's on screen most of the time, and a pleasure it was to watch him relish in the role of a doctor who's willing to bend even his Hippocratic oath to further his scientific and medical discoveries. As a foil to those efforts, there is his medical assistant, Donald (Russell Wade), a young man who is initially dazzled by the genius of his mentor  but who eventually realizes that the end never justifies the means. Which, in this plot, comes down and dirty to stealing bodies from grave yards for medical research. It's a fairly predictable plot; but it's enlivened by the gusto with which Karloff, Lugosi and Daniell perform  although, Lugosi's performance is quite low key, as befits the man servant, Joseph. Throughout, the acting is uniformly precise and consistent for each character. The Scottish setting is realistic; although the lack of Scots accents is noticeable, particularly in the main characters. The photography, editing and direction are simply excellent as one would expect from Robert Wise, famous for so many award winning movies. This effort is worth seeing for that alone, if not for the three main players. As to viewing, I'd suggest getting a DVD of the movie instead of watching a TV broadcast as I did: even in digital format, the TV imagery suffers in transmission so that many of the truly darkened scenes are just too dark to appreciate fully. And there are many dark scenes in this movie. Recommended for all except for the very young. Give this eight out of ten. February 12, 2013
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    never get rid of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a classic this is and what a great performance by Boris Karloff as Gray the grave robber or the body snatcher. Also what a great directing by Robert Wise also known for West Side Story (1961). excellent editing and perfect way of lighting and camera angles. Don't think to see blood or whatsoever, this is made in the forties remember. Bela Lugosi is also to see in a very small part as Joseph but it is really Boris that carries this horror story. It all starts when a woman needs help for her disabled girl. She goes to Dr. Wolfe 'Toddy' MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) for help. The doctor himself got help from a student, Donald Fettes (Russell Wade). Both need bodies to help study them how to solve the girls problem. Therefore they got help from Gray (Boris Karloff). But Gray and the doctor have a backstory. They find themselves continually harassed by their murderous supplier of illegal cadavers. From there the movie turns into a horror with a creepy final. It still works nowadays, and you just keep watching due Gray. Even as it is low on everything the final also delivers the horror in this well known short story by Robert Louis Stevenson. There's a small message in this story. A must have in all horror collections. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 0/5 Story 4/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superbly atmospheric, well written and directed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aandmbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As has been said in previous reviews Karloff and Daniell are excellent in the central roles and the atmosphere generated on the low budget provides a perfect backdrop to a story of moral corruption. I think some other reviewers have missed the point of the subplot of the little girl, which is to provide the ambiguity of the death (or should that be sacrifice) of the street singer against this being the only way the little girl can have her progressive condition cured. Unfortunately the sequences with the girl and her mother do suffer as the performance of Russell Wade as Fettes is rather sentimental and anaemic, although this does have its advantages in portraying the character's moral weakness in falling in with McFarlane despite his reservations. The film works in that although Karloff's character (Gray)is undeniably evil, the other characters are all morally ambiguous and it would have been interesting to see whether Fettes would have carried on McFarlane's work as McFarlane carried on Knox's work before him. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsettling Chiller Of Graverobbing And Retribution With Classic Karloff Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Donald Fettes is a medical student in Edinburgh in 1831, who meets the sinister John Gray and realises that the cadavers supplied to the medical school are being stolen from fresh graves. What should he do, and what powerful influence does Gray have over the eminent Dr MacFarlane ... This beautifully creepy little morality tale, loosely based on an 1884 short story by the great Robert Louis Stevenson, is one of the best of RKO's forties horror classics, and one of Karloff's most assured and memorable performances. He is hypnotising as the seedy, ingratiating, cruel and malevolent cabman, the worst acquaintance you could possibly make, but plays it with such a light touch, smiling and mannered, that the contradiction is almost unbearable. Daniell is also terrific, in a rare role which allows him to move past his standard stock villain part, but still retains his trademark icy stare and hard-as-nails character. The scene in the bar where they debate the mechanics of anatomy versus the indefinable qualities of humanity is one of the best in the movie, and nicely sums up the theme of the advancement of science versus the sanctity and dignity of life. For extra points we also get the inimitable Mr Blasko (in the last of eight films he appeared in with Karloff) in an unusual part, and a scary fight scene between these two legends of cinema. Look out too for the always lovable Gordon (Mrs Hudson in the old Sherlock Holmes flicks) as the bereaved mother in the Greyfriars cemetery scenes. This was Wise's third film in a long and successful career, and his direction is excellent; he paints the tragedy with simple strokes and stages many great horrible moments, such as when Karloff brings Lugosi's body back to the laboratory and the camera closes in on the curtain, leaving our fevered imaginations to guess at his macabre movements. Whilst it may seem difficult now to imagine Georgian moral or religious attitudes to autopsy, it remains a fascinating theme in the modern era of cloning and stem-cell research. Whilst this is a fictional story, it makes several allusions to the infamous Burke and Hare murders - for more on them, there are several good movies, notably The Flesh And The Fiends, The Doctor And The Devils and the recent John Landis biopic. A great little chiller, and a must for Karloff and black-and-white horror fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such A Great Movie! **********/**********
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people know Boris Karloff for his role as Frankenstein's Monster in three movies, but a lot of people probably are unfamiliar with his roles in other movies that he made, such as the masterpiece, The Body Snatcher. I first heard of this movie when I watched on TCM a documentary on Val Lewton, and when they mentioned this movie, I took a very huge interest in it. Now I have seen it, and I am now going to say what I thought of this movie. In my honest to goodness point of view, this movie is a total and completely masterpiece, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton ever produced, and it is one of Boris Karloff's best movies! This movie is another one of those movies that once you watch it, you will want to watch it over and over again, it is a movie that stays in your memory for as long as you live. This is also another movie that I am going to add to my list of great movies, because I certainly think that it is a great movie, once it was over, I just stood up and applauded, it really was that great! I thought that it was so nice to see Boris Karloff in a role other than Frankenstein, because outside of all of that horror stuff that he was doing, he truly was a very talented actor. This movie is probably one of the best movies that he has ever made, and it is also one of the best movies that Val Lewton ever produced. However, while I love this movie, I don't live it as much as my sister. I mean that my sister is obsessed with this movie, after it was over, she wanted to watch it again because she loved it so much. Now I have nothing against that, but while I could watch this movie over and over again, I could not watch it as often as her. But anyway, this movie is incredible, it is a masterpiece starring Boris Karloff. I will award this masterpiece another perfect rating of ten stars out of ten for doing what a masterpiece of a movie should do, entertain you to the highest degree, and that is what this movie did, it entertained me to the highest degree. Well all in all, this is one of the greatest movies ever made, and it is one of the best movies with Boris Karloff, but that's not all, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton has ever produced. Val Lewton was quite an interesting man, being able to produce a lot of interesting material. Val Lewton just might become to my sister what Martin Scorsese is to me, she is really impressed with the former, and I am really impressed with the latter. You've got to watch The Body Snatcher if you haven't done so already, because when you start watching it, you will not want to stop watching it until it is over, because it is one of those movies that will absorb you! Get ready to see a great movie, that movie is The Body Snatcher, and indeed, it is great movie, a splendid time is guaranteed for all of those who watch it! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Val Lewton Gives You the Creeps
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1831 Edinburgh, idealistic medical student Russell Wade (as Donald Fettes) considers quitting due to lack of funds and disillusionment with the profession's deadly reality. However, he is persuaded to stay on as assistant to doctor Henry Daniell (as Wolfe "Toddy" MacFarlane), who has given up his practice for teaching. For important research and dissection purposes, Mr. Daniell needs fresh cadavers. Providing the dead bodies is "The Body Snatcher" Boris Karloff (as John Gray), a poor cab driver moonlighting as a grave robber. When Mr. Wade and Mr. Daniell become interested in the case of an irresistibly cute paraplegic girl, Mr. Karloff is put to work overtime... With great help director Robert Wise, photographer Robert De Grasse and the RKO team, producer Val Lewton's "The Body Snatcher" has one of his smoothest and most satisfying psychological, horror-tinged thrillers. Many of these films were promoted (and still are) as all-out horror movies, but they are mostly atmosphere. The stories were sometimes cobbled together and the budget less than monstrous, but it could all coalesce on occasion. This is one example. Karloff and Daniell are at their best; every scene between the two physically unique actors sizzles. Handyman Bela Lugosi is thrown in for good measure - he and Karloff have a classic termination scene. ********* The Body Snatcher (5/25/45) Val Lewton : Robert Wise ~ Henry Daniell, Boris Karloff, Russell Wade, Bela Lugosi
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding performance by Karloff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    udar55
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Noble young doctor-in-training Donald Fettes (Russell Wade) gets a dark lesson in the profession when he finds out instructor Dr. MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) is paying cabbie Mr. Gray (Boris Karloff) to procure fresh specimens for him from the local graveyard. Fettes is disturbed by the arrangement, but turns to Mr. Gray for a body when a little girl's surgery depends on it. What he doesn't expect is Gray opting to deliver even fresher specimens. Based on the short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, this has some solid drama balanced with some moody chills. This was Robert Wise's third feature film as director and he already shows a great handle of the craft (the abduction of the town singer is a great bit). By far the best thing about the film is the performance of Karloff in the title role. Man, he is just awesome. There is a great scene where he is confronted by an extortionist (played by Bela Lugosi) and Karloff's charm as the works in closer to kill the man is fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Karloff picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Karloff at his very finest. He was masterful as the monster in the Frankenstein roles, but really didn't impress me in much else, until I saw this movie. He was the most evil, dastardly, conniving and disgustingly depraved villain as ever seen in pictures up until this movie was made. I'm sure the character, and Karloff's performance, both, shocked audiences. It was a dramatic role in a somewhat horror, more of a thriller, type movie. His screen presence is so profound in this movie, that you just can't take your eyes off of him. He literally steals the show. Frankly, I never knew he had it in him to do this kind of work. This was a superb performance by Karloff. Worthy of a best supporting actor nod.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant film with Karloff in one of his finest ever performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film directed by Robert Wise, starring Boris Karloff and Bela Lugosi and based on a story by Robert Louis Stevenson, The Body Snatcher had all the ingredients to be great. And it was. It is very well-made, the attention to detail is authentic and very striking and it is shot in a way that really enhances the atmosphere, the use of shadows, gloomy cobbled streets and the lighting also add much. The music score is softly suspenseful with the ability to be chilling and emotional when called for. The dialogue has a fair bit of talk but is very literate and intelligent and develops its two main characters to the extent that they're much more complex than they seem to be. The supporting characters are not as interesting but are written better than other films of the same genre, whether before, during or after. The story is pitch-perfect in pace, it's very sedate but it complimented brilliantly with the atmosphere and I actually think any other type of pacing would not have worked anywhere near as effectively. People may say that there isn't much horror, while billed as a horror in some way I saw it more of a film that relied more on atmosphere and suspense than all else; this worked wonders because the scene with Karloff following the girl(I don't think I have seen that type of scene done so chillingly on film) and the ending are genuinely creepy and the atmosphere is ominous but in a restrained way. The subplot with the crippled girl didn't bother me at all, I for one found it touching and the girl was played with real sincerity. Robert Wise's imaginative direction really does help, as do the performances. Russell Wade is a little too much of a drip for my tastes but the supporting roles are played well on the believe, and Bela Lugosi still gives a sinister turn despite limited screen time. The two leads dominate though, Henry Daniell has a juicy role which he plays with intensity and sympathy but it's the magnificently evil performance of Boris Karloff that really does it for me, one of his finest ever performances easily. All in all, brilliant. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A More Complex Horror Movie Than Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A mid-series movie from that master of horror, Val Lewton. It's not quite front-rank, like The Seventh Victim (1943) or The Cat People (1942), but it's close. The horror, of course, is subdued, allowing the imagination to fill in the blanks, both of which amount to Lewton's brilliant trademark. Perhaps the most unsettling instance here is the lovely little street singer as she lullabies pitch-perfect down a darkened byway, only to be cut short by the maddened cabman (Karloff) who follows her. Now her heavenly aire is lost forever, even as her corporeal body is delivered to medical school for vivisection. In fact, the movie raises a knotty ethical question amidst the ghoulish goings-on. Namely, what in fact are the ethical limits on the advancement of medical science. Dr. MacFarlane (Daniell) needs cadavers to teach his classes and especially to heal the paralyzed little girl (Moffett). So he relies on grave-robber Gray (Karloff) to supply him with the freshly dead. Of course, it's clearly wrong to kill someone for cadaver purposes, as Gray does to the street singer. But is it clearly wrong to rob graves so that the living may benefit. It's an interesting question to raise, as the movie does, and one that thankfully medical science no longer must struggle with. Karloff delivers an outstanding turn as the wickedly jolly grave robber John Gray. Excellent also are Daniell and Lugosi in unusually restrained roles. In fact, Daniell's doctor amounts to an interesting character, a man who can neither accept nor reject his other halfhis cadaver supplier, Gray. At the same time, the movie's ostensible hero Fettes (Wade), the young handsome medical student, can neither wholly accept nor reject the methods of his mentor MacFarlane. Thus the narrative's character development is much more complex than expected for a 70-minute, horror movie. But then that too was part of the brilliance of cult producer Val Lewton. I can't help noting that the lighting bill for this exceptionally shadowy movie could not have exceeded five bucks. There's not a ray of sunshine or high-key lighting anywhere in the narrative. But then the whole thing is being shot on an RKO sound stage for minimal bucks. Amazing, however, what can be achieved in the face of such constraints. No doubt about it, the world of Val Lewton is like that of no other moviemaker, then or now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where a doctor's zeal for medical science goes off the rails.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is interesting for a couple of reasons. First, it's from a short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, one of the 19th century greats. Second, it stars the two bad guys of horror  Karloff and Lugosi  together for the second time (the other was Son of Frankenstein in 1939). And a third reason, perhaps, is the presence of Henry Daniell, as Toddy MacFarlane, who is usually in a supporting role to other bigger stars. In this effort, he's on screen most of the time, and a pleasure it was to watch him relish in the role of a doctor who's willing to bend even his Hippocratic oath to further his scientific and medical discoveries. As a foil to those efforts, there is his medical assistant, Donald (Russell Wade), a young man who is initially dazzled by the genius of his mentor  but who eventually realizes that the end never justifies the means. Which, in this plot, comes down and dirty to stealing bodies from grave yards for medical research. It's a fairly predictable plot; but it's enlivened by the gusto with which Karloff, Lugosi and Daniell perform  although, Lugosi's performance is quite low key, as befits the man servant, Joseph. Throughout, the acting is uniformly precise and consistent for each character. The Scottish setting is realistic; although the lack of Scots accents is noticeable, particularly in the main characters. The photography, editing and direction are simply excellent as one would expect from Robert Wise, famous for so many award winning movies. This effort is worth seeing for that alone, if not for the three main players. As to viewing, I'd suggest getting a DVD of the movie instead of watching a TV broadcast as I did: even in digital format, the TV imagery suffers in transmission so that many of the truly darkened scenes are just too dark to appreciate fully. And there are many dark scenes in this movie. Recommended for all except for the very young. Give this eight out of ten. February 12, 2013
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    never get rid of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a classic this is and what a great performance by Boris Karloff as Gray the grave robber or the body snatcher. Also what a great directing by Robert Wise also known for West Side Story (1961). excellent editing and perfect way of lighting and camera angles. Don't think to see blood or whatsoever, this is made in the forties remember. Bela Lugosi is also to see in a very small part as Joseph but it is really Boris that carries this horror story. It all starts when a woman needs help for her disabled girl. She goes to Dr. Wolfe 'Toddy' MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) for help. The doctor himself got help from a student, Donald Fettes (Russell Wade). Both need bodies to help study them how to solve the girls problem. Therefore they got help from Gray (Boris Karloff). But Gray and the doctor have a backstory. They find themselves continually harassed by their murderous supplier of illegal cadavers. From there the movie turns into a horror with a creepy final. It still works nowadays, and you just keep watching due Gray. Even as it is low on everything the final also delivers the horror in this well known short story by Robert Louis Stevenson. There's a small message in this story. A must have in all horror collections. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 0/5 Story 4/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superbly atmospheric, well written and directed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aandmbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As has been said in previous reviews Karloff and Daniell are excellent in the central roles and the atmosphere generated on the low budget provides a perfect backdrop to a story of moral corruption. I think some other reviewers have missed the point of the subplot of the little girl, which is to provide the ambiguity of the death (or should that be sacrifice) of the street singer against this being the only way the little girl can have her progressive condition cured. Unfortunately the sequences with the girl and her mother do suffer as the performance of Russell Wade as Fettes is rather sentimental and anaemic, although this does have its advantages in portraying the character's moral weakness in falling in with McFarlane despite his reservations. The film works in that although Karloff's character (Gray)is undeniably evil, the other characters are all morally ambiguous and it would have been interesting to see whether Fettes would have carried on McFarlane's work as McFarlane carried on Knox's work before him. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsettling Chiller Of Graverobbing And Retribution With Classic Karloff Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Donald Fettes is a medical student in Edinburgh in 1831, who meets the sinister John Gray and realises that the cadavers supplied to the medical school are being stolen from fresh graves. What should he do, and what powerful influence does Gray have over the eminent Dr MacFarlane ... This beautifully creepy little morality tale, loosely based on an 1884 short story by the great Robert Louis Stevenson, is one of the best of RKO's forties horror classics, and one of Karloff's most assured and memorable performances. He is hypnotising as the seedy, ingratiating, cruel and malevolent cabman, the worst acquaintance you could possibly make, but plays it with such a light touch, smiling and mannered, that the contradiction is almost unbearable. Daniell is also terrific, in a rare role which allows him to move past his standard stock villain part, but still retains his trademark icy stare and hard-as-nails character. The scene in the bar where they debate the mechanics of anatomy versus the indefinable qualities of humanity is one of the best in the movie, and nicely sums up the theme of the advancement of science versus the sanctity and dignity of life. For extra points we also get the inimitable Mr Blasko (in the last of eight films he appeared in with Karloff) in an unusual part, and a scary fight scene between these two legends of cinema. Look out too for the always lovable Gordon (Mrs Hudson in the old Sherlock Holmes flicks) as the bereaved mother in the Greyfriars cemetery scenes. This was Wise's third film in a long and successful career, and his direction is excellent; he paints the tragedy with simple strokes and stages many great horrible moments, such as when Karloff brings Lugosi's body back to the laboratory and the camera closes in on the curtain, leaving our fevered imaginations to guess at his macabre movements. Whilst it may seem difficult now to imagine Georgian moral or religious attitudes to autopsy, it remains a fascinating theme in the modern era of cloning and stem-cell research. Whilst this is a fictional story, it makes several allusions to the infamous Burke and Hare murders - for more on them, there are several good movies, notably The Flesh And The Fiends, The Doctor And The Devils and the recent John Landis biopic. A great little chiller, and a must for Karloff and black-and-white horror fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such A Great Movie! **********/**********
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people know Boris Karloff for his role as Frankenstein's Monster in three movies, but a lot of people probably are unfamiliar with his roles in other movies that he made, such as the masterpiece, The Body Snatcher. I first heard of this movie when I watched on TCM a documentary on Val Lewton, and when they mentioned this movie, I took a very huge interest in it. Now I have seen it, and I am now going to say what I thought of this movie. In my honest to goodness point of view, this movie is a total and completely masterpiece, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton ever produced, and it is one of Boris Karloff's best movies! This movie is another one of those movies that once you watch it, you will want to watch it over and over again, it is a movie that stays in your memory for as long as you live. This is also another movie that I am going to add to my list of great movies, because I certainly think that it is a great movie, once it was over, I just stood up and applauded, it really was that great! I thought that it was so nice to see Boris Karloff in a role other than Frankenstein, because outside of all of that horror stuff that he was doing, he truly was a very talented actor. This movie is probably one of the best movies that he has ever made, and it is also one of the best movies that Val Lewton ever produced. However, while I love this movie, I don't live it as much as my sister. I mean that my sister is obsessed with this movie, after it was over, she wanted to watch it again because she loved it so much. Now I have nothing against that, but while I could watch this movie over and over again, I could not watch it as often as her. But anyway, this movie is incredible, it is a masterpiece starring Boris Karloff. I will award this masterpiece another perfect rating of ten stars out of ten for doing what a masterpiece of a movie should do, entertain you to the highest degree, and that is what this movie did, it entertained me to the highest degree. Well all in all, this is one of the greatest movies ever made, and it is one of the best movies with Boris Karloff, but that's not all, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton has ever produced. Val Lewton was quite an interesting man, being able to produce a lot of interesting material. Val Lewton just might become to my sister what Martin Scorsese is to me, she is really impressed with the former, and I am really impressed with the latter. You've got to watch The Body Snatcher if you haven't done so already, because when you start watching it, you will not want to stop watching it until it is over, because it is one of those movies that will absorb you! Get ready to see a great movie, that movie is The Body Snatcher, and indeed, it is great movie, a splendid time is guaranteed for all of those who watch it! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Val Lewton Gives You the Creeps
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1831 Edinburgh, idealistic medical student Russell Wade (as Donald Fettes) considers quitting due to lack of funds and disillusionment with the profession's deadly reality. However, he is persuaded to stay on as assistant to doctor Henry Daniell (as Wolfe "Toddy" MacFarlane), who has given up his practice for teaching. For important research and dissection purposes, Mr. Daniell needs fresh cadavers. Providing the dead bodies is "The Body Snatcher" Boris Karloff (as John Gray), a poor cab driver moonlighting as a grave robber. When Mr. Wade and Mr. Daniell become interested in the case of an irresistibly cute paraplegic girl, Mr. Karloff is put to work overtime... With great help director Robert Wise, photographer Robert De Grasse and the RKO team, producer Val Lewton's "The Body Snatcher" has one of his smoothest and most satisfying psychological, horror-tinged thrillers. Many of these films were promoted (and still are) as all-out horror movies, but they are mostly atmosphere. The stories were sometimes cobbled together and the budget less than monstrous, but it could all coalesce on occasion. This is one example. Karloff and Daniell are at their best; every scene between the two physically unique actors sizzles. Handyman Bela Lugosi is thrown in for good measure - he and Karloff have a classic termination scene. ********* The Body Snatcher (5/25/45) Val Lewton : Robert Wise ~ Henry Daniell, Boris Karloff, Russell Wade, Bela Lugosi
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding performance by Karloff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    udar55
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Noble young doctor-in-training Donald Fettes (Russell Wade) gets a dark lesson in the profession when he finds out instructor Dr. MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) is paying cabbie Mr. Gray (Boris Karloff) to procure fresh specimens for him from the local graveyard. Fettes is disturbed by the arrangement, but turns to Mr. Gray for a body when a little girl's surgery depends on it. What he doesn't expect is Gray opting to deliver even fresher specimens. Based on the short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, this has some solid drama balanced with some moody chills. This was Robert Wise's third feature film as director and he already shows a great handle of the craft (the abduction of the town singer is a great bit). By far the best thing about the film is the performance of Karloff in the title role. Man, he is just awesome. There is a great scene where he is confronted by an extortionist (played by Bela Lugosi) and Karloff's charm as the works in closer to kill the man is fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Karloff picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Karloff at his very finest. He was masterful as the monster in the Frankenstein roles, but really didn't impress me in much else, until I saw this movie. He was the most evil, dastardly, conniving and disgustingly depraved villain as ever seen in pictures up until this movie was made. I'm sure the character, and Karloff's performance, both, shocked audiences. It was a dramatic role in a somewhat horror, more of a thriller, type movie. His screen presence is so profound in this movie, that you just can't take your eyes off of him. He literally steals the show. Frankly, I never knew he had it in him to do this kind of work. This was a superb performance by Karloff. Worthy of a best supporting actor nod.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant film with Karloff in one of his finest ever performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film directed by Robert Wise, starring Boris Karloff and Bela Lugosi and based on a story by Robert Louis Stevenson, The Body Snatcher had all the ingredients to be great. And it was. It is very well-made, the attention to detail is authentic and very striking and it is shot in a way that really enhances the atmosphere, the use of shadows, gloomy cobbled streets and the lighting also add much. The music score is softly suspenseful with the ability to be chilling and emotional when called for. The dialogue has a fair bit of talk but is very literate and intelligent and develops its two main characters to the extent that they're much more complex than they seem to be. The supporting characters are not as interesting but are written better than other films of the same genre, whether before, during or after. The story is pitch-perfect in pace, it's very sedate but it complimented brilliantly with the atmosphere and I actually think any other type of pacing would not have worked anywhere near as effectively. People may say that there isn't much horror, while billed as a horror in some way I saw it more of a film that relied more on atmosphere and suspense than all else; this worked wonders because the scene with Karloff following the girl(I don't think I have seen that type of scene done so chillingly on film) and the ending are genuinely creepy and the atmosphere is ominous but in a restrained way. The subplot with the crippled girl didn't bother me at all, I for one found it touching and the girl was played with real sincerity. Robert Wise's imaginative direction really does help, as do the performances. Russell Wade is a little too much of a drip for my tastes but the supporting roles are played well on the believe, and Bela Lugosi still gives a sinister turn despite limited screen time. The two leads dominate though, Henry Daniell has a juicy role which he plays with intensity and sympathy but it's the magnificently evil performance of Boris Karloff that really does it for me, one of his finest ever performances easily. All in all, brilliant. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A More Complex Horror Movie Than Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A mid-series movie from that master of horror, Val Lewton. It's not quite front-rank, like The Seventh Victim (1943) or The Cat People (1942), but it's close. The horror, of course, is subdued, allowing the imagination to fill in the blanks, both of which amount to Lewton's brilliant trademark. Perhaps the most unsettling instance here is the lovely little street singer as she lullabies pitch-perfect down a darkened byway, only to be cut short by the maddened cabman (Karloff) who follows her. Now her heavenly aire is lost forever, even as her corporeal body is delivered to medical school for vivisection. In fact, the movie raises a knotty ethical question amidst the ghoulish goings-on. Namely, what in fact are the ethical limits on the advancement of medical science. Dr. MacFarlane (Daniell) needs cadavers to teach his classes and especially to heal the paralyzed little girl (Moffett). So he relies on grave-robber Gray (Karloff) to supply him with the freshly dead. Of course, it's clearly wrong to kill someone for cadaver purposes, as Gray does to the street singer. But is it clearly wrong to rob graves so that the living may benefit. It's an interesting question to raise, as the movie does, and one that thankfully medical science no longer must struggle with. Karloff delivers an outstanding turn as the wickedly jolly grave robber John Gray. Excellent also are Daniell and Lugosi in unusually restrained roles. In fact, Daniell's doctor amounts to an interesting character, a man who can neither accept nor reject his other halfhis cadaver supplier, Gray. At the same time, the movie's ostensible hero Fettes (Wade), the young handsome medical student, can neither wholly accept nor reject the methods of his mentor MacFarlane. Thus the narrative's character development is much more complex than expected for a 70-minute, horror movie. But then that too was part of the brilliance of cult producer Val Lewton. I can't help noting that the lighting bill for this exceptionally shadowy movie could not have exceeded five bucks. There's not a ray of sunshine or high-key lighting anywhere in the narrative. But then the whole thing is being shot on an RKO sound stage for minimal bucks. Amazing, however, what can be achieved in the face of such constraints. No doubt about it, the world of Val Lewton is like that of no other moviemaker, then or now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where a doctor's zeal for medical science goes off the rails.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is interesting for a couple of reasons. First, it's from a short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, one of the 19th century greats. Second, it stars the two bad guys of horror  Karloff and Lugosi  together for the second time (the other was Son of Frankenstein in 1939). And a third reason, perhaps, is the presence of Henry Daniell, as Toddy MacFarlane, who is usually in a supporting role to other bigger stars. In this effort, he's on screen most of the time, and a pleasure it was to watch him relish in the role of a doctor who's willing to bend even his Hippocratic oath to further his scientific and medical discoveries. As a foil to those efforts, there is his medical assistant, Donald (Russell Wade), a young man who is initially dazzled by the genius of his mentor  but who eventually realizes that the end never justifies the means. Which, in this plot, comes down and dirty to stealing bodies from grave yards for medical research. It's a fairly predictable plot; but it's enlivened by the gusto with which Karloff, Lugosi and Daniell perform  although, Lugosi's performance is quite low key, as befits the man servant, Joseph. Throughout, the acting is uniformly precise and consistent for each character. The Scottish setting is realistic; although the lack of Scots accents is noticeable, particularly in the main characters. The photography, editing and direction are simply excellent as one would expect from Robert Wise, famous for so many award winning movies. This effort is worth seeing for that alone, if not for the three main players. As to viewing, I'd suggest getting a DVD of the movie instead of watching a TV broadcast as I did: even in digital format, the TV imagery suffers in transmission so that many of the truly darkened scenes are just too dark to appreciate fully. And there are many dark scenes in this movie. Recommended for all except for the very young. Give this eight out of ten. February 12, 2013
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    never get rid of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a classic this is and what a great performance by Boris Karloff as Gray the grave robber or the body snatcher. Also what a great directing by Robert Wise also known for West Side Story (1961). excellent editing and perfect way of lighting and camera angles. Don't think to see blood or whatsoever, this is made in the forties remember. Bela Lugosi is also to see in a very small part as Joseph but it is really Boris that carries this horror story. It all starts when a woman needs help for her disabled girl. She goes to Dr. Wolfe 'Toddy' MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) for help. The doctor himself got help from a student, Donald Fettes (Russell Wade). Both need bodies to help study them how to solve the girls problem. Therefore they got help from Gray (Boris Karloff). But Gray and the doctor have a backstory. They find themselves continually harassed by their murderous supplier of illegal cadavers. From there the movie turns into a horror with a creepy final. It still works nowadays, and you just keep watching due Gray. Even as it is low on everything the final also delivers the horror in this well known short story by Robert Louis Stevenson. There's a small message in this story. A must have in all horror collections. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 0/5 Story 4/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superbly atmospheric, well written and directed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aandmbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As has been said in previous reviews Karloff and Daniell are excellent in the central roles and the atmosphere generated on the low budget provides a perfect backdrop to a story of moral corruption. I think some other reviewers have missed the point of the subplot of the little girl, which is to provide the ambiguity of the death (or should that be sacrifice) of the street singer against this being the only way the little girl can have her progressive condition cured. Unfortunately the sequences with the girl and her mother do suffer as the performance of Russell Wade as Fettes is rather sentimental and anaemic, although this does have its advantages in portraying the character's moral weakness in falling in with McFarlane despite his reservations. The film works in that although Karloff's character (Gray)is undeniably evil, the other characters are all morally ambiguous and it would have been interesting to see whether Fettes would have carried on McFarlane's work as McFarlane carried on Knox's work before him. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsettling Chiller Of Graverobbing And Retribution With Classic Karloff Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Donald Fettes is a medical student in Edinburgh in 1831, who meets the sinister John Gray and realises that the cadavers supplied to the medical school are being stolen from fresh graves. What should he do, and what powerful influence does Gray have over the eminent Dr MacFarlane ... This beautifully creepy little morality tale, loosely based on an 1884 short story by the great Robert Louis Stevenson, is one of the best of RKO's forties horror classics, and one of Karloff's most assured and memorable performances. He is hypnotising as the seedy, ingratiating, cruel and malevolent cabman, the worst acquaintance you could possibly make, but plays it with such a light touch, smiling and mannered, that the contradiction is almost unbearable. Daniell is also terrific, in a rare role which allows him to move past his standard stock villain part, but still retains his trademark icy stare and hard-as-nails character. The scene in the bar where they debate the mechanics of anatomy versus the indefinable qualities of humanity is one of the best in the movie, and nicely sums up the theme of the advancement of science versus the sanctity and dignity of life. For extra points we also get the inimitable Mr Blasko (in the last of eight films he appeared in with Karloff) in an unusual part, and a scary fight scene between these two legends of cinema. Look out too for the always lovable Gordon (Mrs Hudson in the old Sherlock Holmes flicks) as the bereaved mother in the Greyfriars cemetery scenes. This was Wise's third film in a long and successful career, and his direction is excellent; he paints the tragedy with simple strokes and stages many great horrible moments, such as when Karloff brings Lugosi's body back to the laboratory and the camera closes in on the curtain, leaving our fevered imaginations to guess at his macabre movements. Whilst it may seem difficult now to imagine Georgian moral or religious attitudes to autopsy, it remains a fascinating theme in the modern era of cloning and stem-cell research. Whilst this is a fictional story, it makes several allusions to the infamous Burke and Hare murders - for more on them, there are several good movies, notably The Flesh And The Fiends, The Doctor And The Devils and the recent John Landis biopic. A great little chiller, and a must for Karloff and black-and-white horror fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such A Great Movie! **********/**********
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people know Boris Karloff for his role as Frankenstein's Monster in three movies, but a lot of people probably are unfamiliar with his roles in other movies that he made, such as the masterpiece, The Body Snatcher. I first heard of this movie when I watched on TCM a documentary on Val Lewton, and when they mentioned this movie, I took a very huge interest in it. Now I have seen it, and I am now going to say what I thought of this movie. In my honest to goodness point of view, this movie is a total and completely masterpiece, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton ever produced, and it is one of Boris Karloff's best movies! This movie is another one of those movies that once you watch it, you will want to watch it over and over again, it is a movie that stays in your memory for as long as you live. This is also another movie that I am going to add to my list of great movies, because I certainly think that it is a great movie, once it was over, I just stood up and applauded, it really was that great! I thought that it was so nice to see Boris Karloff in a role other than Frankenstein, because outside of all of that horror stuff that he was doing, he truly was a very talented actor. This movie is probably one of the best movies that he has ever made, and it is also one of the best movies that Val Lewton ever produced. However, while I love this movie, I don't live it as much as my sister. I mean that my sister is obsessed with this movie, after it was over, she wanted to watch it again because she loved it so much. Now I have nothing against that, but while I could watch this movie over and over again, I could not watch it as often as her. But anyway, this movie is incredible, it is a masterpiece starring Boris Karloff. I will award this masterpiece another perfect rating of ten stars out of ten for doing what a masterpiece of a movie should do, entertain you to the highest degree, and that is what this movie did, it entertained me to the highest degree. Well all in all, this is one of the greatest movies ever made, and it is one of the best movies with Boris Karloff, but that's not all, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton has ever produced. Val Lewton was quite an interesting man, being able to produce a lot of interesting material. Val Lewton just might become to my sister what Martin Scorsese is to me, she is really impressed with the former, and I am really impressed with the latter. You've got to watch The Body Snatcher if you haven't done so already, because when you start watching it, you will not want to stop watching it until it is over, because it is one of those movies that will absorb you! Get ready to see a great movie, that movie is The Body Snatcher, and indeed, it is great movie, a splendid time is guaranteed for all of those who watch it! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Val Lewton Gives You the Creeps
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1831 Edinburgh, idealistic medical student Russell Wade (as Donald Fettes) considers quitting due to lack of funds and disillusionment with the profession's deadly reality. However, he is persuaded to stay on as assistant to doctor Henry Daniell (as Wolfe "Toddy" MacFarlane), who has given up his practice for teaching. For important research and dissection purposes, Mr. Daniell needs fresh cadavers. Providing the dead bodies is "The Body Snatcher" Boris Karloff (as John Gray), a poor cab driver moonlighting as a grave robber. When Mr. Wade and Mr. Daniell become interested in the case of an irresistibly cute paraplegic girl, Mr. Karloff is put to work overtime... With great help director Robert Wise, photographer Robert De Grasse and the RKO team, producer Val Lewton's "The Body Snatcher" has one of his smoothest and most satisfying psychological, horror-tinged thrillers. Many of these films were promoted (and still are) as all-out horror movies, but they are mostly atmosphere. The stories were sometimes cobbled together and the budget less than monstrous, but it could all coalesce on occasion. This is one example. Karloff and Daniell are at their best; every scene between the two physically unique actors sizzles. Handyman Bela Lugosi is thrown in for good measure - he and Karloff have a classic termination scene. ********* The Body Snatcher (5/25/45) Val Lewton : Robert Wise ~ Henry Daniell, Boris Karloff, Russell Wade, Bela Lugosi
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding performance by Karloff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    udar55
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Noble young doctor-in-training Donald Fettes (Russell Wade) gets a dark lesson in the profession when he finds out instructor Dr. MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) is paying cabbie Mr. Gray (Boris Karloff) to procure fresh specimens for him from the local graveyard. Fettes is disturbed by the arrangement, but turns to Mr. Gray for a body when a little girl's surgery depends on it. What he doesn't expect is Gray opting to deliver even fresher specimens. Based on the short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, this has some solid drama balanced with some moody chills. This was Robert Wise's third feature film as director and he already shows a great handle of the craft (the abduction of the town singer is a great bit). By far the best thing about the film is the performance of Karloff in the title role. Man, he is just awesome. There is a great scene where he is confronted by an extortionist (played by Bela Lugosi) and Karloff's charm as the works in closer to kill the man is fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Karloff picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Karloff at his very finest. He was masterful as the monster in the Frankenstein roles, but really didn't impress me in much else, until I saw this movie. He was the most evil, dastardly, conniving and disgustingly depraved villain as ever seen in pictures up until this movie was made. I'm sure the character, and Karloff's performance, both, shocked audiences. It was a dramatic role in a somewhat horror, more of a thriller, type movie. His screen presence is so profound in this movie, that you just can't take your eyes off of him. He literally steals the show. Frankly, I never knew he had it in him to do this kind of work. This was a superb performance by Karloff. Worthy of a best supporting actor nod.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant film with Karloff in one of his finest ever performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film directed by Robert Wise, starring Boris Karloff and Bela Lugosi and based on a story by Robert Louis Stevenson, The Body Snatcher had all the ingredients to be great. And it was. It is very well-made, the attention to detail is authentic and very striking and it is shot in a way that really enhances the atmosphere, the use of shadows, gloomy cobbled streets and the lighting also add much. The music score is softly suspenseful with the ability to be chilling and emotional when called for. The dialogue has a fair bit of talk but is very literate and intelligent and develops its two main characters to the extent that they're much more complex than they seem to be. The supporting characters are not as interesting but are written better than other films of the same genre, whether before, during or after. The story is pitch-perfect in pace, it's very sedate but it complimented brilliantly with the atmosphere and I actually think any other type of pacing would not have worked anywhere near as effectively. People may say that there isn't much horror, while billed as a horror in some way I saw it more of a film that relied more on atmosphere and suspense than all else; this worked wonders because the scene with Karloff following the girl(I don't think I have seen that type of scene done so chillingly on film) and the ending are genuinely creepy and the atmosphere is ominous but in a restrained way. The subplot with the crippled girl didn't bother me at all, I for one found it touching and the girl was played with real sincerity. Robert Wise's imaginative direction really does help, as do the performances. Russell Wade is a little too much of a drip for my tastes but the supporting roles are played well on the believe, and Bela Lugosi still gives a sinister turn despite limited screen time. The two leads dominate though, Henry Daniell has a juicy role which he plays with intensity and sympathy but it's the magnificently evil performance of Boris Karloff that really does it for me, one of his finest ever performances easily. All in all, brilliant. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A More Complex Horror Movie Than Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A mid-series movie from that master of horror, Val Lewton. It's not quite front-rank, like The Seventh Victim (1943) or The Cat People (1942), but it's close. The horror, of course, is subdued, allowing the imagination to fill in the blanks, both of which amount to Lewton's brilliant trademark. Perhaps the most unsettling instance here is the lovely little street singer as she lullabies pitch-perfect down a darkened byway, only to be cut short by the maddened cabman (Karloff) who follows her. Now her heavenly aire is lost forever, even as her corporeal body is delivered to medical school for vivisection. In fact, the movie raises a knotty ethical question amidst the ghoulish goings-on. Namely, what in fact are the ethical limits on the advancement of medical science. Dr. MacFarlane (Daniell) needs cadavers to teach his classes and especially to heal the paralyzed little girl (Moffett). So he relies on grave-robber Gray (Karloff) to supply him with the freshly dead. Of course, it's clearly wrong to kill someone for cadaver purposes, as Gray does to the street singer. But is it clearly wrong to rob graves so that the living may benefit. It's an interesting question to raise, as the movie does, and one that thankfully medical science no longer must struggle with. Karloff delivers an outstanding turn as the wickedly jolly grave robber John Gray. Excellent also are Daniell and Lugosi in unusually restrained roles. In fact, Daniell's doctor amounts to an interesting character, a man who can neither accept nor reject his other halfhis cadaver supplier, Gray. At the same time, the movie's ostensible hero Fettes (Wade), the young handsome medical student, can neither wholly accept nor reject the methods of his mentor MacFarlane. Thus the narrative's character development is much more complex than expected for a 70-minute, horror movie. But then that too was part of the brilliance of cult producer Val Lewton. I can't help noting that the lighting bill for this exceptionally shadowy movie could not have exceeded five bucks. There's not a ray of sunshine or high-key lighting anywhere in the narrative. But then the whole thing is being shot on an RKO sound stage for minimal bucks. Amazing, however, what can be achieved in the face of such constraints. No doubt about it, the world of Val Lewton is like that of no other moviemaker, then or now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where a doctor's zeal for medical science goes off the rails.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is interesting for a couple of reasons. First, it's from a short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, one of the 19th century greats. Second, it stars the two bad guys of horror  Karloff and Lugosi  together for the second time (the other was Son of Frankenstein in 1939). And a third reason, perhaps, is the presence of Henry Daniell, as Toddy MacFarlane, who is usually in a supporting role to other bigger stars. In this effort, he's on screen most of the time, and a pleasure it was to watch him relish in the role of a doctor who's willing to bend even his Hippocratic oath to further his scientific and medical discoveries. As a foil to those efforts, there is his medical assistant, Donald (Russell Wade), a young man who is initially dazzled by the genius of his mentor  but who eventually realizes that the end never justifies the means. Which, in this plot, comes down and dirty to stealing bodies from grave yards for medical research. It's a fairly predictable plot; but it's enlivened by the gusto with which Karloff, Lugosi and Daniell perform  although, Lugosi's performance is quite low key, as befits the man servant, Joseph. Throughout, the acting is uniformly precise and consistent for each character. The Scottish setting is realistic; although the lack of Scots accents is noticeable, particularly in the main characters. The photography, editing and direction are simply excellent as one would expect from Robert Wise, famous for so many award winning movies. This effort is worth seeing for that alone, if not for the three main players. As to viewing, I'd suggest getting a DVD of the movie instead of watching a TV broadcast as I did: even in digital format, the TV imagery suffers in transmission so that many of the truly darkened scenes are just too dark to appreciate fully. And there are many dark scenes in this movie. Recommended for all except for the very young. Give this eight out of ten. February 12, 2013
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    never get rid of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a classic this is and what a great performance by Boris Karloff as Gray the grave robber or the body snatcher. Also what a great directing by Robert Wise also known for West Side Story (1961). excellent editing and perfect way of lighting and camera angles. Don't think to see blood or whatsoever, this is made in the forties remember. Bela Lugosi is also to see in a very small part as Joseph but it is really Boris that carries this horror story. It all starts when a woman needs help for her disabled girl. She goes to Dr. Wolfe 'Toddy' MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) for help. The doctor himself got help from a student, Donald Fettes (Russell Wade). Both need bodies to help study them how to solve the girls problem. Therefore they got help from Gray (Boris Karloff). But Gray and the doctor have a backstory. They find themselves continually harassed by their murderous supplier of illegal cadavers. From there the movie turns into a horror with a creepy final. It still works nowadays, and you just keep watching due Gray. Even as it is low on everything the final also delivers the horror in this well known short story by Robert Louis Stevenson. There's a small message in this story. A must have in all horror collections. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 0/5 Story 4/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superbly atmospheric, well written and directed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aandmbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As has been said in previous reviews Karloff and Daniell are excellent in the central roles and the atmosphere generated on the low budget provides a perfect backdrop to a story of moral corruption. I think some other reviewers have missed the point of the subplot of the little girl, which is to provide the ambiguity of the death (or should that be sacrifice) of the street singer against this being the only way the little girl can have her progressive condition cured. Unfortunately the sequences with the girl and her mother do suffer as the performance of Russell Wade as Fettes is rather sentimental and anaemic, although this does have its advantages in portraying the character's moral weakness in falling in with McFarlane despite his reservations. The film works in that although Karloff's character (Gray)is undeniably evil, the other characters are all morally ambiguous and it would have been interesting to see whether Fettes would have carried on McFarlane's work as McFarlane carried on Knox's work before him. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsettling Chiller Of Graverobbing And Retribution With Classic Karloff Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Donald Fettes is a medical student in Edinburgh in 1831, who meets the sinister John Gray and realises that the cadavers supplied to the medical school are being stolen from fresh graves. What should he do, and what powerful influence does Gray have over the eminent Dr MacFarlane ... This beautifully creepy little morality tale, loosely based on an 1884 short story by the great Robert Louis Stevenson, is one of the best of RKO's forties horror classics, and one of Karloff's most assured and memorable performances. He is hypnotising as the seedy, ingratiating, cruel and malevolent cabman, the worst acquaintance you could possibly make, but plays it with such a light touch, smiling and mannered, that the contradiction is almost unbearable. Daniell is also terrific, in a rare role which allows him to move past his standard stock villain part, but still retains his trademark icy stare and hard-as-nails character. The scene in the bar where they debate the mechanics of anatomy versus the indefinable qualities of humanity is one of the best in the movie, and nicely sums up the theme of the advancement of science versus the sanctity and dignity of life. For extra points we also get the inimitable Mr Blasko (in the last of eight films he appeared in with Karloff) in an unusual part, and a scary fight scene between these two legends of cinema. Look out too for the always lovable Gordon (Mrs Hudson in the old Sherlock Holmes flicks) as the bereaved mother in the Greyfriars cemetery scenes. This was Wise's third film in a long and successful career, and his direction is excellent; he paints the tragedy with simple strokes and stages many great horrible moments, such as when Karloff brings Lugosi's body back to the laboratory and the camera closes in on the curtain, leaving our fevered imaginations to guess at his macabre movements. Whilst it may seem difficult now to imagine Georgian moral or religious attitudes to autopsy, it remains a fascinating theme in the modern era of cloning and stem-cell research. Whilst this is a fictional story, it makes several allusions to the infamous Burke and Hare murders - for more on them, there are several good movies, notably The Flesh And The Fiends, The Doctor And The Devils and the recent John Landis biopic. A great little chiller, and a must for Karloff and black-and-white horror fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such A Great Movie! **********/**********
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people know Boris Karloff for his role as Frankenstein's Monster in three movies, but a lot of people probably are unfamiliar with his roles in other movies that he made, such as the masterpiece, The Body Snatcher. I first heard of this movie when I watched on TCM a documentary on Val Lewton, and when they mentioned this movie, I took a very huge interest in it. Now I have seen it, and I am now going to say what I thought of this movie. In my honest to goodness point of view, this movie is a total and completely masterpiece, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton ever produced, and it is one of Boris Karloff's best movies! This movie is another one of those movies that once you watch it, you will want to watch it over and over again, it is a movie that stays in your memory for as long as you live. This is also another movie that I am going to add to my list of great movies, because I certainly think that it is a great movie, once it was over, I just stood up and applauded, it really was that great! I thought that it was so nice to see Boris Karloff in a role other than Frankenstein, because outside of all of that horror stuff that he was doing, he truly was a very talented actor. This movie is probably one of the best movies that he has ever made, and it is also one of the best movies that Val Lewton ever produced. However, while I love this movie, I don't live it as much as my sister. I mean that my sister is obsessed with this movie, after it was over, she wanted to watch it again because she loved it so much. Now I have nothing against that, but while I could watch this movie over and over again, I could not watch it as often as her. But anyway, this movie is incredible, it is a masterpiece starring Boris Karloff. I will award this masterpiece another perfect rating of ten stars out of ten for doing what a masterpiece of a movie should do, entertain you to the highest degree, and that is what this movie did, it entertained me to the highest degree. Well all in all, this is one of the greatest movies ever made, and it is one of the best movies with Boris Karloff, but that's not all, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton has ever produced. Val Lewton was quite an interesting man, being able to produce a lot of interesting material. Val Lewton just might become to my sister what Martin Scorsese is to me, she is really impressed with the former, and I am really impressed with the latter. You've got to watch The Body Snatcher if you haven't done so already, because when you start watching it, you will not want to stop watching it until it is over, because it is one of those movies that will absorb you! Get ready to see a great movie, that movie is The Body Snatcher, and indeed, it is great movie, a splendid time is guaranteed for all of those who watch it! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Val Lewton Gives You the Creeps
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1831 Edinburgh, idealistic medical student Russell Wade (as Donald Fettes) considers quitting due to lack of funds and disillusionment with the profession's deadly reality. However, he is persuaded to stay on as assistant to doctor Henry Daniell (as Wolfe "Toddy" MacFarlane), who has given up his practice for teaching. For important research and dissection purposes, Mr. Daniell needs fresh cadavers. Providing the dead bodies is "The Body Snatcher" Boris Karloff (as John Gray), a poor cab driver moonlighting as a grave robber. When Mr. Wade and Mr. Daniell become interested in the case of an irresistibly cute paraplegic girl, Mr. Karloff is put to work overtime... With great help director Robert Wise, photographer Robert De Grasse and the RKO team, producer Val Lewton's "The Body Snatcher" has one of his smoothest and most satisfying psychological, horror-tinged thrillers. Many of these films were promoted (and still are) as all-out horror movies, but they are mostly atmosphere. The stories were sometimes cobbled together and the budget less than monstrous, but it could all coalesce on occasion. This is one example. Karloff and Daniell are at their best; every scene between the two physically unique actors sizzles. Handyman Bela Lugosi is thrown in for good measure - he and Karloff have a classic termination scene. ********* The Body Snatcher (5/25/45) Val Lewton : Robert Wise ~ Henry Daniell, Boris Karloff, Russell Wade, Bela Lugosi
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding performance by Karloff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    udar55
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Noble young doctor-in-training Donald Fettes (Russell Wade) gets a dark lesson in the profession when he finds out instructor Dr. MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) is paying cabbie Mr. Gray (Boris Karloff) to procure fresh specimens for him from the local graveyard. Fettes is disturbed by the arrangement, but turns to Mr. Gray for a body when a little girl's surgery depends on it. What he doesn't expect is Gray opting to deliver even fresher specimens. Based on the short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, this has some solid drama balanced with some moody chills. This was Robert Wise's third feature film as director and he already shows a great handle of the craft (the abduction of the town singer is a great bit). By far the best thing about the film is the performance of Karloff in the title role. Man, he is just awesome. There is a great scene where he is confronted by an extortionist (played by Bela Lugosi) and Karloff's charm as the works in closer to kill the man is fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Karloff picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Karloff at his very finest. He was masterful as the monster in the Frankenstein roles, but really didn't impress me in much else, until I saw this movie. He was the most evil, dastardly, conniving and disgustingly depraved villain as ever seen in pictures up until this movie was made. I'm sure the character, and Karloff's performance, both, shocked audiences. It was a dramatic role in a somewhat horror, more of a thriller, type movie. His screen presence is so profound in this movie, that you just can't take your eyes off of him. He literally steals the show. Frankly, I never knew he had it in him to do this kind of work. This was a superb performance by Karloff. Worthy of a best supporting actor nod.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant film with Karloff in one of his finest ever performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film directed by Robert Wise, starring Boris Karloff and Bela Lugosi and based on a story by Robert Louis Stevenson, The Body Snatcher had all the ingredients to be great. And it was. It is very well-made, the attention to detail is authentic and very striking and it is shot in a way that really enhances the atmosphere, the use of shadows, gloomy cobbled streets and the lighting also add much. The music score is softly suspenseful with the ability to be chilling and emotional when called for. The dialogue has a fair bit of talk but is very literate and intelligent and develops its two main characters to the extent that they're much more complex than they seem to be. The supporting characters are not as interesting but are written better than other films of the same genre, whether before, during or after. The story is pitch-perfect in pace, it's very sedate but it complimented brilliantly with the atmosphere and I actually think any other type of pacing would not have worked anywhere near as effectively. People may say that there isn't much horror, while billed as a horror in some way I saw it more of a film that relied more on atmosphere and suspense than all else; this worked wonders because the scene with Karloff following the girl(I don't think I have seen that type of scene done so chillingly on film) and the ending are genuinely creepy and the atmosphere is ominous but in a restrained way. The subplot with the crippled girl didn't bother me at all, I for one found it touching and the girl was played with real sincerity. Robert Wise's imaginative direction really does help, as do the performances. Russell Wade is a little too much of a drip for my tastes but the supporting roles are played well on the believe, and Bela Lugosi still gives a sinister turn despite limited screen time. The two leads dominate though, Henry Daniell has a juicy role which he plays with intensity and sympathy but it's the magnificently evil performance of Boris Karloff that really does it for me, one of his finest ever performances easily. All in all, brilliant. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A More Complex Horror Movie Than Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A mid-series movie from that master of horror, Val Lewton. It's not quite front-rank, like The Seventh Victim (1943) or The Cat People (1942), but it's close. The horror, of course, is subdued, allowing the imagination to fill in the blanks, both of which amount to Lewton's brilliant trademark. Perhaps the most unsettling instance here is the lovely little street singer as she lullabies pitch-perfect down a darkened byway, only to be cut short by the maddened cabman (Karloff) who follows her. Now her heavenly aire is lost forever, even as her corporeal body is delivered to medical school for vivisection. In fact, the movie raises a knotty ethical question amidst the ghoulish goings-on. Namely, what in fact are the ethical limits on the advancement of medical science. Dr. MacFarlane (Daniell) needs cadavers to teach his classes and especially to heal the paralyzed little girl (Moffett). So he relies on grave-robber Gray (Karloff) to supply him with the freshly dead. Of course, it's clearly wrong to kill someone for cadaver purposes, as Gray does to the street singer. But is it clearly wrong to rob graves so that the living may benefit. It's an interesting question to raise, as the movie does, and one that thankfully medical science no longer must struggle with. Karloff delivers an outstanding turn as the wickedly jolly grave robber John Gray. Excellent also are Daniell and Lugosi in unusually restrained roles. In fact, Daniell's doctor amounts to an interesting character, a man who can neither accept nor reject his other halfhis cadaver supplier, Gray. At the same time, the movie's ostensible hero Fettes (Wade), the young handsome medical student, can neither wholly accept nor reject the methods of his mentor MacFarlane. Thus the narrative's character development is much more complex than expected for a 70-minute, horror movie. But then that too was part of the brilliance of cult producer Val Lewton. I can't help noting that the lighting bill for this exceptionally shadowy movie could not have exceeded five bucks. There's not a ray of sunshine or high-key lighting anywhere in the narrative. But then the whole thing is being shot on an RKO sound stage for minimal bucks. Amazing, however, what can be achieved in the face of such constraints. No doubt about it, the world of Val Lewton is like that of no other moviemaker, then or now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where a doctor's zeal for medical science goes off the rails.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is interesting for a couple of reasons. First, it's from a short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, one of the 19th century greats. Second, it stars the two bad guys of horror  Karloff and Lugosi  together for the second time (the other was Son of Frankenstein in 1939). And a third reason, perhaps, is the presence of Henry Daniell, as Toddy MacFarlane, who is usually in a supporting role to other bigger stars. In this effort, he's on screen most of the time, and a pleasure it was to watch him relish in the role of a doctor who's willing to bend even his Hippocratic oath to further his scientific and medical discoveries. As a foil to those efforts, there is his medical assistant, Donald (Russell Wade), a young man who is initially dazzled by the genius of his mentor  but who eventually realizes that the end never justifies the means. Which, in this plot, comes down and dirty to stealing bodies from grave yards for medical research. It's a fairly predictable plot; but it's enlivened by the gusto with which Karloff, Lugosi and Daniell perform  although, Lugosi's performance is quite low key, as befits the man servant, Joseph. Throughout, the acting is uniformly precise and consistent for each character. The Scottish setting is realistic; although the lack of Scots accents is noticeable, particularly in the main characters. The photography, editing and direction are simply excellent as one would expect from Robert Wise, famous for so many award winning movies. This effort is worth seeing for that alone, if not for the three main players. As to viewing, I'd suggest getting a DVD of the movie instead of watching a TV broadcast as I did: even in digital format, the TV imagery suffers in transmission so that many of the truly darkened scenes are just too dark to appreciate fully. And there are many dark scenes in this movie. Recommended for all except for the very young. Give this eight out of ten. February 12, 2013
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    never get rid of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a classic this is and what a great performance by Boris Karloff as Gray the grave robber or the body snatcher. Also what a great directing by Robert Wise also known for West Side Story (1961). excellent editing and perfect way of lighting and camera angles. Don't think to see blood or whatsoever, this is made in the forties remember. Bela Lugosi is also to see in a very small part as Joseph but it is really Boris that carries this horror story. It all starts when a woman needs help for her disabled girl. She goes to Dr. Wolfe 'Toddy' MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) for help. The doctor himself got help from a student, Donald Fettes (Russell Wade). Both need bodies to help study them how to solve the girls problem. Therefore they got help from Gray (Boris Karloff). But Gray and the doctor have a backstory. They find themselves continually harassed by their murderous supplier of illegal cadavers. From there the movie turns into a horror with a creepy final. It still works nowadays, and you just keep watching due Gray. Even as it is low on everything the final also delivers the horror in this well known short story by Robert Louis Stevenson. There's a small message in this story. A must have in all horror collections. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 0/5 Story 4/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superbly atmospheric, well written and directed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aandmbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As has been said in previous reviews Karloff and Daniell are excellent in the central roles and the atmosphere generated on the low budget provides a perfect backdrop to a story of moral corruption. I think some other reviewers have missed the point of the subplot of the little girl, which is to provide the ambiguity of the death (or should that be sacrifice) of the street singer against this being the only way the little girl can have her progressive condition cured. Unfortunately the sequences with the girl and her mother do suffer as the performance of Russell Wade as Fettes is rather sentimental and anaemic, although this does have its advantages in portraying the character's moral weakness in falling in with McFarlane despite his reservations. The film works in that although Karloff's character (Gray)is undeniably evil, the other characters are all morally ambiguous and it would have been interesting to see whether Fettes would have carried on McFarlane's work as McFarlane carried on Knox's work before him. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsettling Chiller Of Graverobbing And Retribution With Classic Karloff Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Donald Fettes is a medical student in Edinburgh in 1831, who meets the sinister John Gray and realises that the cadavers supplied to the medical school are being stolen from fresh graves. What should he do, and what powerful influence does Gray have over the eminent Dr MacFarlane ... This beautifully creepy little morality tale, loosely based on an 1884 short story by the great Robert Louis Stevenson, is one of the best of RKO's forties horror classics, and one of Karloff's most assured and memorable performances. He is hypnotising as the seedy, ingratiating, cruel and malevolent cabman, the worst acquaintance you could possibly make, but plays it with such a light touch, smiling and mannered, that the contradiction is almost unbearable. Daniell is also terrific, in a rare role which allows him to move past his standard stock villain part, but still retains his trademark icy stare and hard-as-nails character. The scene in the bar where they debate the mechanics of anatomy versus the indefinable qualities of humanity is one of the best in the movie, and nicely sums up the theme of the advancement of science versus the sanctity and dignity of life. For extra points we also get the inimitable Mr Blasko (in the last of eight films he appeared in with Karloff) in an unusual part, and a scary fight scene between these two legends of cinema. Look out too for the always lovable Gordon (Mrs Hudson in the old Sherlock Holmes flicks) as the bereaved mother in the Greyfriars cemetery scenes. This was Wise's third film in a long and successful career, and his direction is excellent; he paints the tragedy with simple strokes and stages many great horrible moments, such as when Karloff brings Lugosi's body back to the laboratory and the camera closes in on the curtain, leaving our fevered imaginations to guess at his macabre movements. Whilst it may seem difficult now to imagine Georgian moral or religious attitudes to autopsy, it remains a fascinating theme in the modern era of cloning and stem-cell research. Whilst this is a fictional story, it makes several allusions to the infamous Burke and Hare murders - for more on them, there are several good movies, notably The Flesh And The Fiends, The Doctor And The Devils and the recent John Landis biopic. A great little chiller, and a must for Karloff and black-and-white horror fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such A Great Movie! **********/**********
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people know Boris Karloff for his role as Frankenstein's Monster in three movies, but a lot of people probably are unfamiliar with his roles in other movies that he made, such as the masterpiece, The Body Snatcher. I first heard of this movie when I watched on TCM a documentary on Val Lewton, and when they mentioned this movie, I took a very huge interest in it. Now I have seen it, and I am now going to say what I thought of this movie. In my honest to goodness point of view, this movie is a total and completely masterpiece, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton ever produced, and it is one of Boris Karloff's best movies! This movie is another one of those movies that once you watch it, you will want to watch it over and over again, it is a movie that stays in your memory for as long as you live. This is also another movie that I am going to add to my list of great movies, because I certainly think that it is a great movie, once it was over, I just stood up and applauded, it really was that great! I thought that it was so nice to see Boris Karloff in a role other than Frankenstein, because outside of all of that horror stuff that he was doing, he truly was a very talented actor. This movie is probably one of the best movies that he has ever made, and it is also one of the best movies that Val Lewton ever produced. However, while I love this movie, I don't live it as much as my sister. I mean that my sister is obsessed with this movie, after it was over, she wanted to watch it again because she loved it so much. Now I have nothing against that, but while I could watch this movie over and over again, I could not watch it as often as her. But anyway, this movie is incredible, it is a masterpiece starring Boris Karloff. I will award this masterpiece another perfect rating of ten stars out of ten for doing what a masterpiece of a movie should do, entertain you to the highest degree, and that is what this movie did, it entertained me to the highest degree. Well all in all, this is one of the greatest movies ever made, and it is one of the best movies with Boris Karloff, but that's not all, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton has ever produced. Val Lewton was quite an interesting man, being able to produce a lot of interesting material. Val Lewton just might become to my sister what Martin Scorsese is to me, she is really impressed with the former, and I am really impressed with the latter. You've got to watch The Body Snatcher if you haven't done so already, because when you start watching it, you will not want to stop watching it until it is over, because it is one of those movies that will absorb you! Get ready to see a great movie, that movie is The Body Snatcher, and indeed, it is great movie, a splendid time is guaranteed for all of those who watch it! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Val Lewton Gives You the Creeps
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1831 Edinburgh, idealistic medical student Russell Wade (as Donald Fettes) considers quitting due to lack of funds and disillusionment with the profession's deadly reality. However, he is persuaded to stay on as assistant to doctor Henry Daniell (as Wolfe "Toddy" MacFarlane), who has given up his practice for teaching. For important research and dissection purposes, Mr. Daniell needs fresh cadavers. Providing the dead bodies is "The Body Snatcher" Boris Karloff (as John Gray), a poor cab driver moonlighting as a grave robber. When Mr. Wade and Mr. Daniell become interested in the case of an irresistibly cute paraplegic girl, Mr. Karloff is put to work overtime... With great help director Robert Wise, photographer Robert De Grasse and the RKO team, producer Val Lewton's "The Body Snatcher" has one of his smoothest and most satisfying psychological, horror-tinged thrillers. Many of these films were promoted (and still are) as all-out horror movies, but they are mostly atmosphere. The stories were sometimes cobbled together and the budget less than monstrous, but it could all coalesce on occasion. This is one example. Karloff and Daniell are at their best; every scene between the two physically unique actors sizzles. Handyman Bela Lugosi is thrown in for good measure - he and Karloff have a classic termination scene. ********* The Body Snatcher (5/25/45) Val Lewton : Robert Wise ~ Henry Daniell, Boris Karloff, Russell Wade, Bela Lugosi
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding performance by Karloff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    udar55
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Noble young doctor-in-training Donald Fettes (Russell Wade) gets a dark lesson in the profession when he finds out instructor Dr. MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) is paying cabbie Mr. Gray (Boris Karloff) to procure fresh specimens for him from the local graveyard. Fettes is disturbed by the arrangement, but turns to Mr. Gray for a body when a little girl's surgery depends on it. What he doesn't expect is Gray opting to deliver even fresher specimens. Based on the short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, this has some solid drama balanced with some moody chills. This was Robert Wise's third feature film as director and he already shows a great handle of the craft (the abduction of the town singer is a great bit). By far the best thing about the film is the performance of Karloff in the title role. Man, he is just awesome. There is a great scene where he is confronted by an extortionist (played by Bela Lugosi) and Karloff's charm as the works in closer to kill the man is fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Karloff picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Karloff at his very finest. He was masterful as the monster in the Frankenstein roles, but really didn't impress me in much else, until I saw this movie. He was the most evil, dastardly, conniving and disgustingly depraved villain as ever seen in pictures up until this movie was made. I'm sure the character, and Karloff's performance, both, shocked audiences. It was a dramatic role in a somewhat horror, more of a thriller, type movie. His screen presence is so profound in this movie, that you just can't take your eyes off of him. He literally steals the show. Frankly, I never knew he had it in him to do this kind of work. This was a superb performance by Karloff. Worthy of a best supporting actor nod.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant film with Karloff in one of his finest ever performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film directed by Robert Wise, starring Boris Karloff and Bela Lugosi and based on a story by Robert Louis Stevenson, The Body Snatcher had all the ingredients to be great. And it was. It is very well-made, the attention to detail is authentic and very striking and it is shot in a way that really enhances the atmosphere, the use of shadows, gloomy cobbled streets and the lighting also add much. The music score is softly suspenseful with the ability to be chilling and emotional when called for. The dialogue has a fair bit of talk but is very literate and intelligent and develops its two main characters to the extent that they're much more complex than they seem to be. The supporting characters are not as interesting but are written better than other films of the same genre, whether before, during or after. The story is pitch-perfect in pace, it's very sedate but it complimented brilliantly with the atmosphere and I actually think any other type of pacing would not have worked anywhere near as effectively. People may say that there isn't much horror, while billed as a horror in some way I saw it more of a film that relied more on atmosphere and suspense than all else; this worked wonders because the scene with Karloff following the girl(I don't think I have seen that type of scene done so chillingly on film) and the ending are genuinely creepy and the atmosphere is ominous but in a restrained way. The subplot with the crippled girl didn't bother me at all, I for one found it touching and the girl was played with real sincerity. Robert Wise's imaginative direction really does help, as do the performances. Russell Wade is a little too much of a drip for my tastes but the supporting roles are played well on the believe, and Bela Lugosi still gives a sinister turn despite limited screen time. The two leads dominate though, Henry Daniell has a juicy role which he plays with intensity and sympathy but it's the magnificently evil performance of Boris Karloff that really does it for me, one of his finest ever performances easily. All in all, brilliant. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A More Complex Horror Movie Than Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A mid-series movie from that master of horror, Val Lewton. It's not quite front-rank, like The Seventh Victim (1943) or The Cat People (1942), but it's close. The horror, of course, is subdued, allowing the imagination to fill in the blanks, both of which amount to Lewton's brilliant trademark. Perhaps the most unsettling instance here is the lovely little street singer as she lullabies pitch-perfect down a darkened byway, only to be cut short by the maddened cabman (Karloff) who follows her. Now her heavenly aire is lost forever, even as her corporeal body is delivered to medical school for vivisection. In fact, the movie raises a knotty ethical question amidst the ghoulish goings-on. Namely, what in fact are the ethical limits on the advancement of medical science. Dr. MacFarlane (Daniell) needs cadavers to teach his classes and especially to heal the paralyzed little girl (Moffett). So he relies on grave-robber Gray (Karloff) to supply him with the freshly dead. Of course, it's clearly wrong to kill someone for cadaver purposes, as Gray does to the street singer. But is it clearly wrong to rob graves so that the living may benefit. It's an interesting question to raise, as the movie does, and one that thankfully medical science no longer must struggle with. Karloff delivers an outstanding turn as the wickedly jolly grave robber John Gray. Excellent also are Daniell and Lugosi in unusually restrained roles. In fact, Daniell's doctor amounts to an interesting character, a man who can neither accept nor reject his other halfhis cadaver supplier, Gray. At the same time, the movie's ostensible hero Fettes (Wade), the young handsome medical student, can neither wholly accept nor reject the methods of his mentor MacFarlane. Thus the narrative's character development is much more complex than expected for a 70-minute, horror movie. But then that too was part of the brilliance of cult producer Val Lewton. I can't help noting that the lighting bill for this exceptionally shadowy movie could not have exceeded five bucks. There's not a ray of sunshine or high-key lighting anywhere in the narrative. But then the whole thing is being shot on an RKO sound stage for minimal bucks. Amazing, however, what can be achieved in the face of such constraints. No doubt about it, the world of Val Lewton is like that of no other moviemaker, then or now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where a doctor's zeal for medical science goes off the rails.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is interesting for a couple of reasons. First, it's from a short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, one of the 19th century greats. Second, it stars the two bad guys of horror  Karloff and Lugosi  together for the second time (the other was Son of Frankenstein in 1939). And a third reason, perhaps, is the presence of Henry Daniell, as Toddy MacFarlane, who is usually in a supporting role to other bigger stars. In this effort, he's on screen most of the time, and a pleasure it was to watch him relish in the role of a doctor who's willing to bend even his Hippocratic oath to further his scientific and medical discoveries. As a foil to those efforts, there is his medical assistant, Donald (Russell Wade), a young man who is initially dazzled by the genius of his mentor  but who eventually realizes that the end never justifies the means. Which, in this plot, comes down and dirty to stealing bodies from grave yards for medical research. It's a fairly predictable plot; but it's enlivened by the gusto with which Karloff, Lugosi and Daniell perform  although, Lugosi's performance is quite low key, as befits the man servant, Joseph. Throughout, the acting is uniformly precise and consistent for each character. The Scottish setting is realistic; although the lack of Scots accents is noticeable, particularly in the main characters. The photography, editing and direction are simply excellent as one would expect from Robert Wise, famous for so many award winning movies. This effort is worth seeing for that alone, if not for the three main players. As to viewing, I'd suggest getting a DVD of the movie instead of watching a TV broadcast as I did: even in digital format, the TV imagery suffers in transmission so that many of the truly darkened scenes are just too dark to appreciate fully. And there are many dark scenes in this movie. Recommended for all except for the very young. Give this eight out of ten. February 12, 2013
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    never get rid of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a classic this is and what a great performance by Boris Karloff as Gray the grave robber or the body snatcher. Also what a great directing by Robert Wise also known for West Side Story (1961). excellent editing and perfect way of lighting and camera angles. Don't think to see blood or whatsoever, this is made in the forties remember. Bela Lugosi is also to see in a very small part as Joseph but it is really Boris that carries this horror story. It all starts when a woman needs help for her disabled girl. She goes to Dr. Wolfe 'Toddy' MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) for help. The doctor himself got help from a student, Donald Fettes (Russell Wade). Both need bodies to help study them how to solve the girls problem. Therefore they got help from Gray (Boris Karloff). But Gray and the doctor have a backstory. They find themselves continually harassed by their murderous supplier of illegal cadavers. From there the movie turns into a horror with a creepy final. It still works nowadays, and you just keep watching due Gray. Even as it is low on everything the final also delivers the horror in this well known short story by Robert Louis Stevenson. There's a small message in this story. A must have in all horror collections. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 0/5 Story 4/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superbly atmospheric, well written and directed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aandmbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As has been said in previous reviews Karloff and Daniell are excellent in the central roles and the atmosphere generated on the low budget provides a perfect backdrop to a story of moral corruption. I think some other reviewers have missed the point of the subplot of the little girl, which is to provide the ambiguity of the death (or should that be sacrifice) of the street singer against this being the only way the little girl can have her progressive condition cured. Unfortunately the sequences with the girl and her mother do suffer as the performance of Russell Wade as Fettes is rather sentimental and anaemic, although this does have its advantages in portraying the character's moral weakness in falling in with McFarlane despite his reservations. The film works in that although Karloff's character (Gray)is undeniably evil, the other characters are all morally ambiguous and it would have been interesting to see whether Fettes would have carried on McFarlane's work as McFarlane carried on Knox's work before him. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsettling Chiller Of Graverobbing And Retribution With Classic Karloff Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Donald Fettes is a medical student in Edinburgh in 1831, who meets the sinister John Gray and realises that the cadavers supplied to the medical school are being stolen from fresh graves. What should he do, and what powerful influence does Gray have over the eminent Dr MacFarlane ... This beautifully creepy little morality tale, loosely based on an 1884 short story by the great Robert Louis Stevenson, is one of the best of RKO's forties horror classics, and one of Karloff's most assured and memorable performances. He is hypnotising as the seedy, ingratiating, cruel and malevolent cabman, the worst acquaintance you could possibly make, but plays it with such a light touch, smiling and mannered, that the contradiction is almost unbearable. Daniell is also terrific, in a rare role which allows him to move past his standard stock villain part, but still retains his trademark icy stare and hard-as-nails character. The scene in the bar where they debate the mechanics of anatomy versus the indefinable qualities of humanity is one of the best in the movie, and nicely sums up the theme of the advancement of science versus the sanctity and dignity of life. For extra points we also get the inimitable Mr Blasko (in the last of eight films he appeared in with Karloff) in an unusual part, and a scary fight scene between these two legends of cinema. Look out too for the always lovable Gordon (Mrs Hudson in the old Sherlock Holmes flicks) as the bereaved mother in the Greyfriars cemetery scenes. This was Wise's third film in a long and successful career, and his direction is excellent; he paints the tragedy with simple strokes and stages many great horrible moments, such as when Karloff brings Lugosi's body back to the laboratory and the camera closes in on the curtain, leaving our fevered imaginations to guess at his macabre movements. Whilst it may seem difficult now to imagine Georgian moral or religious attitudes to autopsy, it remains a fascinating theme in the modern era of cloning and stem-cell research. Whilst this is a fictional story, it makes several allusions to the infamous Burke and Hare murders - for more on them, there are several good movies, notably The Flesh And The Fiends, The Doctor And The Devils and the recent John Landis biopic. A great little chiller, and a must for Karloff and black-and-white horror fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such A Great Movie! **********/**********
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people know Boris Karloff for his role as Frankenstein's Monster in three movies, but a lot of people probably are unfamiliar with his roles in other movies that he made, such as the masterpiece, The Body Snatcher. I first heard of this movie when I watched on TCM a documentary on Val Lewton, and when they mentioned this movie, I took a very huge interest in it. Now I have seen it, and I am now going to say what I thought of this movie. In my honest to goodness point of view, this movie is a total and completely masterpiece, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton ever produced, and it is one of Boris Karloff's best movies! This movie is another one of those movies that once you watch it, you will want to watch it over and over again, it is a movie that stays in your memory for as long as you live. This is also another movie that I am going to add to my list of great movies, because I certainly think that it is a great movie, once it was over, I just stood up and applauded, it really was that great! I thought that it was so nice to see Boris Karloff in a role other than Frankenstein, because outside of all of that horror stuff that he was doing, he truly was a very talented actor. This movie is probably one of the best movies that he has ever made, and it is also one of the best movies that Val Lewton ever produced. However, while I love this movie, I don't live it as much as my sister. I mean that my sister is obsessed with this movie, after it was over, she wanted to watch it again because she loved it so much. Now I have nothing against that, but while I could watch this movie over and over again, I could not watch it as often as her. But anyway, this movie is incredible, it is a masterpiece starring Boris Karloff. I will award this masterpiece another perfect rating of ten stars out of ten for doing what a masterpiece of a movie should do, entertain you to the highest degree, and that is what this movie did, it entertained me to the highest degree. Well all in all, this is one of the greatest movies ever made, and it is one of the best movies with Boris Karloff, but that's not all, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton has ever produced. Val Lewton was quite an interesting man, being able to produce a lot of interesting material. Val Lewton just might become to my sister what Martin Scorsese is to me, she is really impressed with the former, and I am really impressed with the latter. You've got to watch The Body Snatcher if you haven't done so already, because when you start watching it, you will not want to stop watching it until it is over, because it is one of those movies that will absorb you! Get ready to see a great movie, that movie is The Body Snatcher, and indeed, it is great movie, a splendid time is guaranteed for all of those who watch it! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Val Lewton Gives You the Creeps
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1831 Edinburgh, idealistic medical student Russell Wade (as Donald Fettes) considers quitting due to lack of funds and disillusionment with the profession's deadly reality. However, he is persuaded to stay on as assistant to doctor Henry Daniell (as Wolfe "Toddy" MacFarlane), who has given up his practice for teaching. For important research and dissection purposes, Mr. Daniell needs fresh cadavers. Providing the dead bodies is "The Body Snatcher" Boris Karloff (as John Gray), a poor cab driver moonlighting as a grave robber. When Mr. Wade and Mr. Daniell become interested in the case of an irresistibly cute paraplegic girl, Mr. Karloff is put to work overtime... With great help director Robert Wise, photographer Robert De Grasse and the RKO team, producer Val Lewton's "The Body Snatcher" has one of his smoothest and most satisfying psychological, horror-tinged thrillers. Many of these films were promoted (and still are) as all-out horror movies, but they are mostly atmosphere. The stories were sometimes cobbled together and the budget less than monstrous, but it could all coalesce on occasion. This is one example. Karloff and Daniell are at their best; every scene between the two physically unique actors sizzles. Handyman Bela Lugosi is thrown in for good measure - he and Karloff have a classic termination scene. ********* The Body Snatcher (5/25/45) Val Lewton : Robert Wise ~ Henry Daniell, Boris Karloff, Russell Wade, Bela Lugosi
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding performance by Karloff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    udar55
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Noble young doctor-in-training Donald Fettes (Russell Wade) gets a dark lesson in the profession when he finds out instructor Dr. MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) is paying cabbie Mr. Gray (Boris Karloff) to procure fresh specimens for him from the local graveyard. Fettes is disturbed by the arrangement, but turns to Mr. Gray for a body when a little girl's surgery depends on it. What he doesn't expect is Gray opting to deliver even fresher specimens. Based on the short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, this has some solid drama balanced with some moody chills. This was Robert Wise's third feature film as director and he already shows a great handle of the craft (the abduction of the town singer is a great bit). By far the best thing about the film is the performance of Karloff in the title role. Man, he is just awesome. There is a great scene where he is confronted by an extortionist (played by Bela Lugosi) and Karloff's charm as the works in closer to kill the man is fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Karloff picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Karloff at his very finest. He was masterful as the monster in the Frankenstein roles, but really didn't impress me in much else, until I saw this movie. He was the most evil, dastardly, conniving and disgustingly depraved villain as ever seen in pictures up until this movie was made. I'm sure the character, and Karloff's performance, both, shocked audiences. It was a dramatic role in a somewhat horror, more of a thriller, type movie. His screen presence is so profound in this movie, that you just can't take your eyes off of him. He literally steals the show. Frankly, I never knew he had it in him to do this kind of work. This was a superb performance by Karloff. Worthy of a best supporting actor nod.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant film with Karloff in one of his finest ever performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film directed by Robert Wise, starring Boris Karloff and Bela Lugosi and based on a story by Robert Louis Stevenson, The Body Snatcher had all the ingredients to be great. And it was. It is very well-made, the attention to detail is authentic and very striking and it is shot in a way that really enhances the atmosphere, the use of shadows, gloomy cobbled streets and the lighting also add much. The music score is softly suspenseful with the ability to be chilling and emotional when called for. The dialogue has a fair bit of talk but is very literate and intelligent and develops its two main characters to the extent that they're much more complex than they seem to be. The supporting characters are not as interesting but are written better than other films of the same genre, whether before, during or after. The story is pitch-perfect in pace, it's very sedate but it complimented brilliantly with the atmosphere and I actually think any other type of pacing would not have worked anywhere near as effectively. People may say that there isn't much horror, while billed as a horror in some way I saw it more of a film that relied more on atmosphere and suspense than all else; this worked wonders because the scene with Karloff following the girl(I don't think I have seen that type of scene done so chillingly on film) and the ending are genuinely creepy and the atmosphere is ominous but in a restrained way. The subplot with the crippled girl didn't bother me at all, I for one found it touching and the girl was played with real sincerity. Robert Wise's imaginative direction really does help, as do the performances. Russell Wade is a little too much of a drip for my tastes but the supporting roles are played well on the believe, and Bela Lugosi still gives a sinister turn despite limited screen time. The two leads dominate though, Henry Daniell has a juicy role which he plays with intensity and sympathy but it's the magnificently evil performance of Boris Karloff that really does it for me, one of his finest ever performances easily. All in all, brilliant. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A More Complex Horror Movie Than Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A mid-series movie from that master of horror, Val Lewton. It's not quite front-rank, like The Seventh Victim (1943) or The Cat People (1942), but it's close. The horror, of course, is subdued, allowing the imagination to fill in the blanks, both of which amount to Lewton's brilliant trademark. Perhaps the most unsettling instance here is the lovely little street singer as she lullabies pitch-perfect down a darkened byway, only to be cut short by the maddened cabman (Karloff) who follows her. Now her heavenly aire is lost forever, even as her corporeal body is delivered to medical school for vivisection. In fact, the movie raises a knotty ethical question amidst the ghoulish goings-on. Namely, what in fact are the ethical limits on the advancement of medical science. Dr. MacFarlane (Daniell) needs cadavers to teach his classes and especially to heal the paralyzed little girl (Moffett). So he relies on grave-robber Gray (Karloff) to supply him with the freshly dead. Of course, it's clearly wrong to kill someone for cadaver purposes, as Gray does to the street singer. But is it clearly wrong to rob graves so that the living may benefit. It's an interesting question to raise, as the movie does, and one that thankfully medical science no longer must struggle with. Karloff delivers an outstanding turn as the wickedly jolly grave robber John Gray. Excellent also are Daniell and Lugosi in unusually restrained roles. In fact, Daniell's doctor amounts to an interesting character, a man who can neither accept nor reject his other halfhis cadaver supplier, Gray. At the same time, the movie's ostensible hero Fettes (Wade), the young handsome medical student, can neither wholly accept nor reject the methods of his mentor MacFarlane. Thus the narrative's character development is much more complex than expected for a 70-minute, horror movie. But then that too was part of the brilliance of cult producer Val Lewton. I can't help noting that the lighting bill for this exceptionally shadowy movie could not have exceeded five bucks. There's not a ray of sunshine or high-key lighting anywhere in the narrative. But then the whole thing is being shot on an RKO sound stage for minimal bucks. Amazing, however, what can be achieved in the face of such constraints. No doubt about it, the world of Val Lewton is like that of no other moviemaker, then or now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where a doctor's zeal for medical science goes off the rails.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is interesting for a couple of reasons. First, it's from a short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, one of the 19th century greats. Second, it stars the two bad guys of horror  Karloff and Lugosi  together for the second time (the other was Son of Frankenstein in 1939). And a third reason, perhaps, is the presence of Henry Daniell, as Toddy MacFarlane, who is usually in a supporting role to other bigger stars. In this effort, he's on screen most of the time, and a pleasure it was to watch him relish in the role of a doctor who's willing to bend even his Hippocratic oath to further his scientific and medical discoveries. As a foil to those efforts, there is his medical assistant, Donald (Russell Wade), a young man who is initially dazzled by the genius of his mentor  but who eventually realizes that the end never justifies the means. Which, in this plot, comes down and dirty to stealing bodies from grave yards for medical research. It's a fairly predictable plot; but it's enlivened by the gusto with which Karloff, Lugosi and Daniell perform  although, Lugosi's performance is quite low key, as befits the man servant, Joseph. Throughout, the acting is uniformly precise and consistent for each character. The Scottish setting is realistic; although the lack of Scots accents is noticeable, particularly in the main characters. The photography, editing and direction are simply excellent as one would expect from Robert Wise, famous for so many award winning movies. This effort is worth seeing for that alone, if not for the three main players. As to viewing, I'd suggest getting a DVD of the movie instead of watching a TV broadcast as I did: even in digital format, the TV imagery suffers in transmission so that many of the truly darkened scenes are just too dark to appreciate fully. And there are many dark scenes in this movie. Recommended for all except for the very young. Give this eight out of ten. February 12, 2013
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    never get rid of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a classic this is and what a great performance by Boris Karloff as Gray the grave robber or the body snatcher. Also what a great directing by Robert Wise also known for West Side Story (1961). excellent editing and perfect way of lighting and camera angles. Don't think to see blood or whatsoever, this is made in the forties remember. Bela Lugosi is also to see in a very small part as Joseph but it is really Boris that carries this horror story. It all starts when a woman needs help for her disabled girl. She goes to Dr. Wolfe 'Toddy' MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) for help. The doctor himself got help from a student, Donald Fettes (Russell Wade). Both need bodies to help study them how to solve the girls problem. Therefore they got help from Gray (Boris Karloff). But Gray and the doctor have a backstory. They find themselves continually harassed by their murderous supplier of illegal cadavers. From there the movie turns into a horror with a creepy final. It still works nowadays, and you just keep watching due Gray. Even as it is low on everything the final also delivers the horror in this well known short story by Robert Louis Stevenson. There's a small message in this story. A must have in all horror collections. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 0/5 Story 4/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superbly atmospheric, well written and directed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aandmbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As has been said in previous reviews Karloff and Daniell are excellent in the central roles and the atmosphere generated on the low budget provides a perfect backdrop to a story of moral corruption. I think some other reviewers have missed the point of the subplot of the little girl, which is to provide the ambiguity of the death (or should that be sacrifice) of the street singer against this being the only way the little girl can have her progressive condition cured. Unfortunately the sequences with the girl and her mother do suffer as the performance of Russell Wade as Fettes is rather sentimental and anaemic, although this does have its advantages in portraying the character's moral weakness in falling in with McFarlane despite his reservations. The film works in that although Karloff's character (Gray)is undeniably evil, the other characters are all morally ambiguous and it would have been interesting to see whether Fettes would have carried on McFarlane's work as McFarlane carried on Knox's work before him. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsettling Chiller Of Graverobbing And Retribution With Classic Karloff Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Donald Fettes is a medical student in Edinburgh in 1831, who meets the sinister John Gray and realises that the cadavers supplied to the medical school are being stolen from fresh graves. What should he do, and what powerful influence does Gray have over the eminent Dr MacFarlane ... This beautifully creepy little morality tale, loosely based on an 1884 short story by the great Robert Louis Stevenson, is one of the best of RKO's forties horror classics, and one of Karloff's most assured and memorable performances. He is hypnotising as the seedy, ingratiating, cruel and malevolent cabman, the worst acquaintance you could possibly make, but plays it with such a light touch, smiling and mannered, that the contradiction is almost unbearable. Daniell is also terrific, in a rare role which allows him to move past his standard stock villain part, but still retains his trademark icy stare and hard-as-nails character. The scene in the bar where they debate the mechanics of anatomy versus the indefinable qualities of humanity is one of the best in the movie, and nicely sums up the theme of the advancement of science versus the sanctity and dignity of life. For extra points we also get the inimitable Mr Blasko (in the last of eight films he appeared in with Karloff) in an unusual part, and a scary fight scene between these two legends of cinema. Look out too for the always lovable Gordon (Mrs Hudson in the old Sherlock Holmes flicks) as the bereaved mother in the Greyfriars cemetery scenes. This was Wise's third film in a long and successful career, and his direction is excellent; he paints the tragedy with simple strokes and stages many great horrible moments, such as when Karloff brings Lugosi's body back to the laboratory and the camera closes in on the curtain, leaving our fevered imaginations to guess at his macabre movements. Whilst it may seem difficult now to imagine Georgian moral or religious attitudes to autopsy, it remains a fascinating theme in the modern era of cloning and stem-cell research. Whilst this is a fictional story, it makes several allusions to the infamous Burke and Hare murders - for more on them, there are several good movies, notably The Flesh And The Fiends, The Doctor And The Devils and the recent John Landis biopic. A great little chiller, and a must for Karloff and black-and-white horror fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such A Great Movie! **********/**********
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people know Boris Karloff for his role as Frankenstein's Monster in three movies, but a lot of people probably are unfamiliar with his roles in other movies that he made, such as the masterpiece, The Body Snatcher. I first heard of this movie when I watched on TCM a documentary on Val Lewton, and when they mentioned this movie, I took a very huge interest in it. Now I have seen it, and I am now going to say what I thought of this movie. In my honest to goodness point of view, this movie is a total and completely masterpiece, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton ever produced, and it is one of Boris Karloff's best movies! This movie is another one of those movies that once you watch it, you will want to watch it over and over again, it is a movie that stays in your memory for as long as you live. This is also another movie that I am going to add to my list of great movies, because I certainly think that it is a great movie, once it was over, I just stood up and applauded, it really was that great! I thought that it was so nice to see Boris Karloff in a role other than Frankenstein, because outside of all of that horror stuff that he was doing, he truly was a very talented actor. This movie is probably one of the best movies that he has ever made, and it is also one of the best movies that Val Lewton ever produced. However, while I love this movie, I don't live it as much as my sister. I mean that my sister is obsessed with this movie, after it was over, she wanted to watch it again because she loved it so much. Now I have nothing against that, but while I could watch this movie over and over again, I could not watch it as often as her. But anyway, this movie is incredible, it is a masterpiece starring Boris Karloff. I will award this masterpiece another perfect rating of ten stars out of ten for doing what a masterpiece of a movie should do, entertain you to the highest degree, and that is what this movie did, it entertained me to the highest degree. Well all in all, this is one of the greatest movies ever made, and it is one of the best movies with Boris Karloff, but that's not all, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton has ever produced. Val Lewton was quite an interesting man, being able to produce a lot of interesting material. Val Lewton just might become to my sister what Martin Scorsese is to me, she is really impressed with the former, and I am really impressed with the latter. You've got to watch The Body Snatcher if you haven't done so already, because when you start watching it, you will not want to stop watching it until it is over, because it is one of those movies that will absorb you! Get ready to see a great movie, that movie is The Body Snatcher, and indeed, it is great movie, a splendid time is guaranteed for all of those who watch it! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Val Lewton Gives You the Creeps
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1831 Edinburgh, idealistic medical student Russell Wade (as Donald Fettes) considers quitting due to lack of funds and disillusionment with the profession's deadly reality. However, he is persuaded to stay on as assistant to doctor Henry Daniell (as Wolfe "Toddy" MacFarlane), who has given up his practice for teaching. For important research and dissection purposes, Mr. Daniell needs fresh cadavers. Providing the dead bodies is "The Body Snatcher" Boris Karloff (as John Gray), a poor cab driver moonlighting as a grave robber. When Mr. Wade and Mr. Daniell become interested in the case of an irresistibly cute paraplegic girl, Mr. Karloff is put to work overtime... With great help director Robert Wise, photographer Robert De Grasse and the RKO team, producer Val Lewton's "The Body Snatcher" has one of his smoothest and most satisfying psychological, horror-tinged thrillers. Many of these films were promoted (and still are) as all-out horror movies, but they are mostly atmosphere. The stories were sometimes cobbled together and the budget less than monstrous, but it could all coalesce on occasion. This is one example. Karloff and Daniell are at their best; every scene between the two physically unique actors sizzles. Handyman Bela Lugosi is thrown in for good measure - he and Karloff have a classic termination scene. ********* The Body Snatcher (5/25/45) Val Lewton : Robert Wise ~ Henry Daniell, Boris Karloff, Russell Wade, Bela Lugosi
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding performance by Karloff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    udar55
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Noble young doctor-in-training Donald Fettes (Russell Wade) gets a dark lesson in the profession when he finds out instructor Dr. MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) is paying cabbie Mr. Gray (Boris Karloff) to procure fresh specimens for him from the local graveyard. Fettes is disturbed by the arrangement, but turns to Mr. Gray for a body when a little girl's surgery depends on it. What he doesn't expect is Gray opting to deliver even fresher specimens. Based on the short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, this has some solid drama balanced with some moody chills. This was Robert Wise's third feature film as director and he already shows a great handle of the craft (the abduction of the town singer is a great bit). By far the best thing about the film is the performance of Karloff in the title role. Man, he is just awesome. There is a great scene where he is confronted by an extortionist (played by Bela Lugosi) and Karloff's charm as the works in closer to kill the man is fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Karloff picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Karloff at his very finest. He was masterful as the monster in the Frankenstein roles, but really didn't impress me in much else, until I saw this movie. He was the most evil, dastardly, conniving and disgustingly depraved villain as ever seen in pictures up until this movie was made. I'm sure the character, and Karloff's performance, both, shocked audiences. It was a dramatic role in a somewhat horror, more of a thriller, type movie. His screen presence is so profound in this movie, that you just can't take your eyes off of him. He literally steals the show. Frankly, I never knew he had it in him to do this kind of work. This was a superb performance by Karloff. Worthy of a best supporting actor nod.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant film with Karloff in one of his finest ever performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film directed by Robert Wise, starring Boris Karloff and Bela Lugosi and based on a story by Robert Louis Stevenson, The Body Snatcher had all the ingredients to be great. And it was. It is very well-made, the attention to detail is authentic and very striking and it is shot in a way that really enhances the atmosphere, the use of shadows, gloomy cobbled streets and the lighting also add much. The music score is softly suspenseful with the ability to be chilling and emotional when called for. The dialogue has a fair bit of talk but is very literate and intelligent and develops its two main characters to the extent that they're much more complex than they seem to be. The supporting characters are not as interesting but are written better than other films of the same genre, whether before, during or after. The story is pitch-perfect in pace, it's very sedate but it complimented brilliantly with the atmosphere and I actually think any other type of pacing would not have worked anywhere near as effectively. People may say that there isn't much horror, while billed as a horror in some way I saw it more of a film that relied more on atmosphere and suspense than all else; this worked wonders because the scene with Karloff following the girl(I don't think I have seen that type of scene done so chillingly on film) and the ending are genuinely creepy and the atmosphere is ominous but in a restrained way. The subplot with the crippled girl didn't bother me at all, I for one found it touching and the girl was played with real sincerity. Robert Wise's imaginative direction really does help, as do the performances. Russell Wade is a little too much of a drip for my tastes but the supporting roles are played well on the believe, and Bela Lugosi still gives a sinister turn despite limited screen time. The two leads dominate though, Henry Daniell has a juicy role which he plays with intensity and sympathy but it's the magnificently evil performance of Boris Karloff that really does it for me, one of his finest ever performances easily. All in all, brilliant. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A More Complex Horror Movie Than Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A mid-series movie from that master of horror, Val Lewton. It's not quite front-rank, like The Seventh Victim (1943) or The Cat People (1942), but it's close. The horror, of course, is subdued, allowing the imagination to fill in the blanks, both of which amount to Lewton's brilliant trademark. Perhaps the most unsettling instance here is the lovely little street singer as she lullabies pitch-perfect down a darkened byway, only to be cut short by the maddened cabman (Karloff) who follows her. Now her heavenly aire is lost forever, even as her corporeal body is delivered to medical school for vivisection. In fact, the movie raises a knotty ethical question amidst the ghoulish goings-on. Namely, what in fact are the ethical limits on the advancement of medical science. Dr. MacFarlane (Daniell) needs cadavers to teach his classes and especially to heal the paralyzed little girl (Moffett). So he relies on grave-robber Gray (Karloff) to supply him with the freshly dead. Of course, it's clearly wrong to kill someone for cadaver purposes, as Gray does to the street singer. But is it clearly wrong to rob graves so that the living may benefit. It's an interesting question to raise, as the movie does, and one that thankfully medical science no longer must struggle with. Karloff delivers an outstanding turn as the wickedly jolly grave robber John Gray. Excellent also are Daniell and Lugosi in unusually restrained roles. In fact, Daniell's doctor amounts to an interesting character, a man who can neither accept nor reject his other halfhis cadaver supplier, Gray. At the same time, the movie's ostensible hero Fettes (Wade), the young handsome medical student, can neither wholly accept nor reject the methods of his mentor MacFarlane. Thus the narrative's character development is much more complex than expected for a 70-minute, horror movie. But then that too was part of the brilliance of cult producer Val Lewton. I can't help noting that the lighting bill for this exceptionally shadowy movie could not have exceeded five bucks. There's not a ray of sunshine or high-key lighting anywhere in the narrative. But then the whole thing is being shot on an RKO sound stage for minimal bucks. Amazing, however, what can be achieved in the face of such constraints. No doubt about it, the world of Val Lewton is like that of no other moviemaker, then or now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where a doctor's zeal for medical science goes off the rails.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is interesting for a couple of reasons. First, it's from a short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, one of the 19th century greats. Second, it stars the two bad guys of horror  Karloff and Lugosi  together for the second time (the other was Son of Frankenstein in 1939). And a third reason, perhaps, is the presence of Henry Daniell, as Toddy MacFarlane, who is usually in a supporting role to other bigger stars. In this effort, he's on screen most of the time, and a pleasure it was to watch him relish in the role of a doctor who's willing to bend even his Hippocratic oath to further his scientific and medical discoveries. As a foil to those efforts, there is his medical assistant, Donald (Russell Wade), a young man who is initially dazzled by the genius of his mentor  but who eventually realizes that the end never justifies the means. Which, in this plot, comes down and dirty to stealing bodies from grave yards for medical research. It's a fairly predictable plot; but it's enlivened by the gusto with which Karloff, Lugosi and Daniell perform  although, Lugosi's performance is quite low key, as befits the man servant, Joseph. Throughout, the acting is uniformly precise and consistent for each character. The Scottish setting is realistic; although the lack of Scots accents is noticeable, particularly in the main characters. The photography, editing and direction are simply excellent as one would expect from Robert Wise, famous for so many award winning movies. This effort is worth seeing for that alone, if not for the three main players. As to viewing, I'd suggest getting a DVD of the movie instead of watching a TV broadcast as I did: even in digital format, the TV imagery suffers in transmission so that many of the truly darkened scenes are just too dark to appreciate fully. And there are many dark scenes in this movie. Recommended for all except for the very young. Give this eight out of ten. February 12, 2013
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    never get rid of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a classic this is and what a great performance by Boris Karloff as Gray the grave robber or the body snatcher. Also what a great directing by Robert Wise also known for West Side Story (1961). excellent editing and perfect way of lighting and camera angles. Don't think to see blood or whatsoever, this is made in the forties remember. Bela Lugosi is also to see in a very small part as Joseph but it is really Boris that carries this horror story. It all starts when a woman needs help for her disabled girl. She goes to Dr. Wolfe 'Toddy' MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) for help. The doctor himself got help from a student, Donald Fettes (Russell Wade). Both need bodies to help study them how to solve the girls problem. Therefore they got help from Gray (Boris Karloff). But Gray and the doctor have a backstory. They find themselves continually harassed by their murderous supplier of illegal cadavers. From there the movie turns into a horror with a creepy final. It still works nowadays, and you just keep watching due Gray. Even as it is low on everything the final also delivers the horror in this well known short story by Robert Louis Stevenson. There's a small message in this story. A must have in all horror collections. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 0/5 Story 4/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superbly atmospheric, well written and directed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aandmbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As has been said in previous reviews Karloff and Daniell are excellent in the central roles and the atmosphere generated on the low budget provides a perfect backdrop to a story of moral corruption. I think some other reviewers have missed the point of the subplot of the little girl, which is to provide the ambiguity of the death (or should that be sacrifice) of the street singer against this being the only way the little girl can have her progressive condition cured. Unfortunately the sequences with the girl and her mother do suffer as the performance of Russell Wade as Fettes is rather sentimental and anaemic, although this does have its advantages in portraying the character's moral weakness in falling in with McFarlane despite his reservations. The film works in that although Karloff's character (Gray)is undeniably evil, the other characters are all morally ambiguous and it would have been interesting to see whether Fettes would have carried on McFarlane's work as McFarlane carried on Knox's work before him. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsettling Chiller Of Graverobbing And Retribution With Classic Karloff Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Donald Fettes is a medical student in Edinburgh in 1831, who meets the sinister John Gray and realises that the cadavers supplied to the medical school are being stolen from fresh graves. What should he do, and what powerful influence does Gray have over the eminent Dr MacFarlane ... This beautifully creepy little morality tale, loosely based on an 1884 short story by the great Robert Louis Stevenson, is one of the best of RKO's forties horror classics, and one of Karloff's most assured and memorable performances. He is hypnotising as the seedy, ingratiating, cruel and malevolent cabman, the worst acquaintance you could possibly make, but plays it with such a light touch, smiling and mannered, that the contradiction is almost unbearable. Daniell is also terrific, in a rare role which allows him to move past his standard stock villain part, but still retains his trademark icy stare and hard-as-nails character. The scene in the bar where they debate the mechanics of anatomy versus the indefinable qualities of humanity is one of the best in the movie, and nicely sums up the theme of the advancement of science versus the sanctity and dignity of life. For extra points we also get the inimitable Mr Blasko (in the last of eight films he appeared in with Karloff) in an unusual part, and a scary fight scene between these two legends of cinema. Look out too for the always lovable Gordon (Mrs Hudson in the old Sherlock Holmes flicks) as the bereaved mother in the Greyfriars cemetery scenes. This was Wise's third film in a long and successful career, and his direction is excellent; he paints the tragedy with simple strokes and stages many great horrible moments, such as when Karloff brings Lugosi's body back to the laboratory and the camera closes in on the curtain, leaving our fevered imaginations to guess at his macabre movements. Whilst it may seem difficult now to imagine Georgian moral or religious attitudes to autopsy, it remains a fascinating theme in the modern era of cloning and stem-cell research. Whilst this is a fictional story, it makes several allusions to the infamous Burke and Hare murders - for more on them, there are several good movies, notably The Flesh And The Fiends, The Doctor And The Devils and the recent John Landis biopic. A great little chiller, and a must for Karloff and black-and-white horror fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such A Great Movie! **********/**********
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people know Boris Karloff for his role as Frankenstein's Monster in three movies, but a lot of people probably are unfamiliar with his roles in other movies that he made, such as the masterpiece, The Body Snatcher. I first heard of this movie when I watched on TCM a documentary on Val Lewton, and when they mentioned this movie, I took a very huge interest in it. Now I have seen it, and I am now going to say what I thought of this movie. In my honest to goodness point of view, this movie is a total and completely masterpiece, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton ever produced, and it is one of Boris Karloff's best movies! This movie is another one of those movies that once you watch it, you will want to watch it over and over again, it is a movie that stays in your memory for as long as you live. This is also another movie that I am going to add to my list of great movies, because I certainly think that it is a great movie, once it was over, I just stood up and applauded, it really was that great! I thought that it was so nice to see Boris Karloff in a role other than Frankenstein, because outside of all of that horror stuff that he was doing, he truly was a very talented actor. This movie is probably one of the best movies that he has ever made, and it is also one of the best movies that Val Lewton ever produced. However, while I love this movie, I don't live it as much as my sister. I mean that my sister is obsessed with this movie, after it was over, she wanted to watch it again because she loved it so much. Now I have nothing against that, but while I could watch this movie over and over again, I could not watch it as often as her. But anyway, this movie is incredible, it is a masterpiece starring Boris Karloff. I will award this masterpiece another perfect rating of ten stars out of ten for doing what a masterpiece of a movie should do, entertain you to the highest degree, and that is what this movie did, it entertained me to the highest degree. Well all in all, this is one of the greatest movies ever made, and it is one of the best movies with Boris Karloff, but that's not all, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton has ever produced. Val Lewton was quite an interesting man, being able to produce a lot of interesting material. Val Lewton just might become to my sister what Martin Scorsese is to me, she is really impressed with the former, and I am really impressed with the latter. You've got to watch The Body Snatcher if you haven't done so already, because when you start watching it, you will not want to stop watching it until it is over, because it is one of those movies that will absorb you! Get ready to see a great movie, that movie is The Body Snatcher, and indeed, it is great movie, a splendid time is guaranteed for all of those who watch it! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Val Lewton Gives You the Creeps
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1831 Edinburgh, idealistic medical student Russell Wade (as Donald Fettes) considers quitting due to lack of funds and disillusionment with the profession's deadly reality. However, he is persuaded to stay on as assistant to doctor Henry Daniell (as Wolfe "Toddy" MacFarlane), who has given up his practice for teaching. For important research and dissection purposes, Mr. Daniell needs fresh cadavers. Providing the dead bodies is "The Body Snatcher" Boris Karloff (as John Gray), a poor cab driver moonlighting as a grave robber. When Mr. Wade and Mr. Daniell become interested in the case of an irresistibly cute paraplegic girl, Mr. Karloff is put to work overtime... With great help director Robert Wise, photographer Robert De Grasse and the RKO team, producer Val Lewton's "The Body Snatcher" has one of his smoothest and most satisfying psychological, horror-tinged thrillers. Many of these films were promoted (and still are) as all-out horror movies, but they are mostly atmosphere. The stories were sometimes cobbled together and the budget less than monstrous, but it could all coalesce on occasion. This is one example. Karloff and Daniell are at their best; every scene between the two physically unique actors sizzles. Handyman Bela Lugosi is thrown in for good measure - he and Karloff have a classic termination scene. ********* The Body Snatcher (5/25/45) Val Lewton : Robert Wise ~ Henry Daniell, Boris Karloff, Russell Wade, Bela Lugosi
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding performance by Karloff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    udar55
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Noble young doctor-in-training Donald Fettes (Russell Wade) gets a dark lesson in the profession when he finds out instructor Dr. MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) is paying cabbie Mr. Gray (Boris Karloff) to procure fresh specimens for him from the local graveyard. Fettes is disturbed by the arrangement, but turns to Mr. Gray for a body when a little girl's surgery depends on it. What he doesn't expect is Gray opting to deliver even fresher specimens. Based on the short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, this has some solid drama balanced with some moody chills. This was Robert Wise's third feature film as director and he already shows a great handle of the craft (the abduction of the town singer is a great bit). By far the best thing about the film is the performance of Karloff in the title role. Man, he is just awesome. There is a great scene where he is confronted by an extortionist (played by Bela Lugosi) and Karloff's charm as the works in closer to kill the man is fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Karloff picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Karloff at his very finest. He was masterful as the monster in the Frankenstein roles, but really didn't impress me in much else, until I saw this movie. He was the most evil, dastardly, conniving and disgustingly depraved villain as ever seen in pictures up until this movie was made. I'm sure the character, and Karloff's performance, both, shocked audiences. It was a dramatic role in a somewhat horror, more of a thriller, type movie. His screen presence is so profound in this movie, that you just can't take your eyes off of him. He literally steals the show. Frankly, I never knew he had it in him to do this kind of work. This was a superb performance by Karloff. Worthy of a best supporting actor nod.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant film with Karloff in one of his finest ever performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film directed by Robert Wise, starring Boris Karloff and Bela Lugosi and based on a story by Robert Louis Stevenson, The Body Snatcher had all the ingredients to be great. And it was. It is very well-made, the attention to detail is authentic and very striking and it is shot in a way that really enhances the atmosphere, the use of shadows, gloomy cobbled streets and the lighting also add much. The music score is softly suspenseful with the ability to be chilling and emotional when called for. The dialogue has a fair bit of talk but is very literate and intelligent and develops its two main characters to the extent that they're much more complex than they seem to be. The supporting characters are not as interesting but are written better than other films of the same genre, whether before, during or after. The story is pitch-perfect in pace, it's very sedate but it complimented brilliantly with the atmosphere and I actually think any other type of pacing would not have worked anywhere near as effectively. People may say that there isn't much horror, while billed as a horror in some way I saw it more of a film that relied more on atmosphere and suspense than all else; this worked wonders because the scene with Karloff following the girl(I don't think I have seen that type of scene done so chillingly on film) and the ending are genuinely creepy and the atmosphere is ominous but in a restrained way. The subplot with the crippled girl didn't bother me at all, I for one found it touching and the girl was played with real sincerity. Robert Wise's imaginative direction really does help, as do the performances. Russell Wade is a little too much of a drip for my tastes but the supporting roles are played well on the believe, and Bela Lugosi still gives a sinister turn despite limited screen time. The two leads dominate though, Henry Daniell has a juicy role which he plays with intensity and sympathy but it's the magnificently evil performance of Boris Karloff that really does it for me, one of his finest ever performances easily. All in all, brilliant. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A More Complex Horror Movie Than Expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A mid-series movie from that master of horror, Val Lewton. It's not quite front-rank, like The Seventh Victim (1943) or The Cat People (1942), but it's close. The horror, of course, is subdued, allowing the imagination to fill in the blanks, both of which amount to Lewton's brilliant trademark. Perhaps the most unsettling instance here is the lovely little street singer as she lullabies pitch-perfect down a darkened byway, only to be cut short by the maddened cabman (Karloff) who follows her. Now her heavenly aire is lost forever, even as her corporeal body is delivered to medical school for vivisection. In fact, the movie raises a knotty ethical question amidst the ghoulish goings-on. Namely, what in fact are the ethical limits on the advancement of medical science. Dr. MacFarlane (Daniell) needs cadavers to teach his classes and especially to heal the paralyzed little girl (Moffett). So he relies on grave-robber Gray (Karloff) to supply him with the freshly dead. Of course, it's clearly wrong to kill someone for cadaver purposes, as Gray does to the street singer. But is it clearly wrong to rob graves so that the living may benefit. It's an interesting question to raise, as the movie does, and one that thankfully medical science no longer must struggle with. Karloff delivers an outstanding turn as the wickedly jolly grave robber John Gray. Excellent also are Daniell and Lugosi in unusually restrained roles. In fact, Daniell's doctor amounts to an interesting character, a man who can neither accept nor reject his other halfhis cadaver supplier, Gray. At the same time, the movie's ostensible hero Fettes (Wade), the young handsome medical student, can neither wholly accept nor reject the methods of his mentor MacFarlane. Thus the narrative's character development is much more complex than expected for a 70-minute, horror movie. But then that too was part of the brilliance of cult producer Val Lewton. I can't help noting that the lighting bill for this exceptionally shadowy movie could not have exceeded five bucks. There's not a ray of sunshine or high-key lighting anywhere in the narrative. But then the whole thing is being shot on an RKO sound stage for minimal bucks. Amazing, however, what can be achieved in the face of such constraints. No doubt about it, the world of Val Lewton is like that of no other moviemaker, then or now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where a doctor's zeal for medical science goes off the rails.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is interesting for a couple of reasons. First, it's from a short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, one of the 19th century greats. Second, it stars the two bad guys of horror  Karloff and Lugosi  together for the second time (the other was Son of Frankenstein in 1939). And a third reason, perhaps, is the presence of Henry Daniell, as Toddy MacFarlane, who is usually in a supporting role to other bigger stars. In this effort, he's on screen most of the time, and a pleasure it was to watch him relish in the role of a doctor who's willing to bend even his Hippocratic oath to further his scientific and medical discoveries. As a foil to those efforts, there is his medical assistant, Donald (Russell Wade), a young man who is initially dazzled by the genius of his mentor  but who eventually realizes that the end never justifies the means. Which, in this plot, comes down and dirty to stealing bodies from grave yards for medical research. It's a fairly predictable plot; but it's enlivened by the gusto with which Karloff, Lugosi and Daniell perform  although, Lugosi's performance is quite low key, as befits the man servant, Joseph. Throughout, the acting is uniformly precise and consistent for each character. The Scottish setting is realistic; although the lack of Scots accents is noticeable, particularly in the main characters. The photography, editing and direction are simply excellent as one would expect from Robert Wise, famous for so many award winning movies. This effort is worth seeing for that alone, if not for the three main players. As to viewing, I'd suggest getting a DVD of the movie instead of watching a TV broadcast as I did: even in digital format, the TV imagery suffers in transmission so that many of the truly darkened scenes are just too dark to appreciate fully. And there are many dark scenes in this movie. Recommended for all except for the very young. Give this eight out of ten. February 12, 2013
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    never get rid of me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a classic this is and what a great performance by Boris Karloff as Gray the grave robber or the body snatcher. Also what a great directing by Robert Wise also known for West Side Story (1961). excellent editing and perfect way of lighting and camera angles. Don't think to see blood or whatsoever, this is made in the forties remember. Bela Lugosi is also to see in a very small part as Joseph but it is really Boris that carries this horror story. It all starts when a woman needs help for her disabled girl. She goes to Dr. Wolfe 'Toddy' MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) for help. The doctor himself got help from a student, Donald Fettes (Russell Wade). Both need bodies to help study them how to solve the girls problem. Therefore they got help from Gray (Boris Karloff). But Gray and the doctor have a backstory. They find themselves continually harassed by their murderous supplier of illegal cadavers. From there the movie turns into a horror with a creepy final. It still works nowadays, and you just keep watching due Gray. Even as it is low on everything the final also delivers the horror in this well known short story by Robert Louis Stevenson. There's a small message in this story. A must have in all horror collections. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 0/5 Story 4/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superbly atmospheric, well written and directed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aandmbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As has been said in previous reviews Karloff and Daniell are excellent in the central roles and the atmosphere generated on the low budget provides a perfect backdrop to a story of moral corruption. I think some other reviewers have missed the point of the subplot of the little girl, which is to provide the ambiguity of the death (or should that be sacrifice) of the street singer against this being the only way the little girl can have her progressive condition cured. Unfortunately the sequences with the girl and her mother do suffer as the performance of Russell Wade as Fettes is rather sentimental and anaemic, although this does have its advantages in portraying the character's moral weakness in falling in with McFarlane despite his reservations. The film works in that although Karloff's character (Gray)is undeniably evil, the other characters are all morally ambiguous and it would have been interesting to see whether Fettes would have carried on McFarlane's work as McFarlane carried on Knox's work before him. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsettling Chiller Of Graverobbing And Retribution With Classic Karloff Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Donald Fettes is a medical student in Edinburgh in 1831, who meets the sinister John Gray and realises that the cadavers supplied to the medical school are being stolen from fresh graves. What should he do, and what powerful influence does Gray have over the eminent Dr MacFarlane ... This beautifully creepy little morality tale, loosely based on an 1884 short story by the great Robert Louis Stevenson, is one of the best of RKO's forties horror classics, and one of Karloff's most assured and memorable performances. He is hypnotising as the seedy, ingratiating, cruel and malevolent cabman, the worst acquaintance you could possibly make, but plays it with such a light touch, smiling and mannered, that the contradiction is almost unbearable. Daniell is also terrific, in a rare role which allows him to move past his standard stock villain part, but still retains his trademark icy stare and hard-as-nails character. The scene in the bar where they debate the mechanics of anatomy versus the indefinable qualities of humanity is one of the best in the movie, and nicely sums up the theme of the advancement of science versus the sanctity and dignity of life. For extra points we also get the inimitable Mr Blasko (in the last of eight films he appeared in with Karloff) in an unusual part, and a scary fight scene between these two legends of cinema. Look out too for the always lovable Gordon (Mrs Hudson in the old Sherlock Holmes flicks) as the bereaved mother in the Greyfriars cemetery scenes. This was Wise's third film in a long and successful career, and his direction is excellent; he paints the tragedy with simple strokes and stages many great horrible moments, such as when Karloff brings Lugosi's body back to the laboratory and the camera closes in on the curtain, leaving our fevered imaginations to guess at his macabre movements. Whilst it may seem difficult now to imagine Georgian moral or religious attitudes to autopsy, it remains a fascinating theme in the modern era of cloning and stem-cell research. Whilst this is a fictional story, it makes several allusions to the infamous Burke and Hare murders - for more on them, there are several good movies, notably The Flesh And The Fiends, The Doctor And The Devils and the recent John Landis biopic. A great little chiller, and a must for Karloff and black-and-white horror fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such A Great Movie! **********/**********
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people know Boris Karloff for his role as Frankenstein's Monster in three movies, but a lot of people probably are unfamiliar with his roles in other movies that he made, such as the masterpiece, The Body Snatcher. I first heard of this movie when I watched on TCM a documentary on Val Lewton, and when they mentioned this movie, I took a very huge interest in it. Now I have seen it, and I am now going to say what I thought of this movie. In my honest to goodness point of view, this movie is a total and completely masterpiece, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton ever produced, and it is one of Boris Karloff's best movies! This movie is another one of those movies that once you watch it, you will want to watch it over and over again, it is a movie that stays in your memory for as long as you live. This is also another movie that I am going to add to my list of great movies, because I certainly think that it is a great movie, once it was over, I just stood up and applauded, it really was that great! I thought that it was so nice to see Boris Karloff in a role other than Frankenstein, because outside of all of that horror stuff that he was doing, he truly was a very talented actor. This movie is probably one of the best movies that he has ever made, and it is also one of the best movies that Val Lewton ever produced. However, while I love this movie, I don't live it as much as my sister. I mean that my sister is obsessed with this movie, after it was over, she wanted to watch it again because she loved it so much. Now I have nothing against that, but while I could watch this movie over and over again, I could not watch it as often as her. But anyway, this movie is incredible, it is a masterpiece starring Boris Karloff. I will award this masterpiece another perfect rating of ten stars out of ten for doing what a masterpiece of a movie should do, entertain you to the highest degree, and that is what this movie did, it entertained me to the highest degree. Well all in all, this is one of the greatest movies ever made, and it is one of the best movies with Boris Karloff, but that's not all, it is one of the best things that Val Lewton has ever produced. Val Lewton was quite an interesting man, being able to produce a lot of interesting material. Val Lewton just might become to my sister what Martin Scorsese is to me, she is really impressed with the former, and I am really impressed with the latter. You've got to watch The Body Snatcher if you haven't done so already, because when you start watching it, you will not want to stop watching it until it is over, because it is one of those movies that will absorb you! Get ready to see a great movie, that movie is The Body Snatcher, and indeed, it is great movie, a splendid time is guaranteed for all of those who watch it! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Val Lewton Gives You the Creeps
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1831 Edinburgh, idealistic medical student Russell Wade (as Donald Fettes) considers quitting due to lack of funds and disillusionment with the profession's deadly reality. However, he is persuaded to stay on as assistant to doctor Henry Daniell (as Wolfe "Toddy" MacFarlane), who has given up his practice for teaching. For important research and dissection purposes, Mr. Daniell needs fresh cadavers. Providing the dead bodies is "The Body Snatcher" Boris Karloff (as John Gray), a poor cab driver moonlighting as a grave robber. When Mr. Wade and Mr. Daniell become interested in the case of an irresistibly cute paraplegic girl, Mr. Karloff is put to work overtime... With great help director Robert Wise, photographer Robert De Grasse and the RKO team, producer Val Lewton's "The Body Snatcher" has one of his smoothest and most satisfying psychological, horror-tinged thrillers. Many of these films were promoted (and still are) as all-out horror movies, but they are mostly atmosphere. The stories were sometimes cobbled together and the budget less than monstrous, but it could all coalesce on occasion. This is one example. Karloff and Daniell are at their best; every scene between the two physically unique actors sizzles. Handyman Bela Lugosi is thrown in for good measure - he and Karloff have a classic termination scene. ********* The Body Snatcher (5/25/45) Val Lewton : Robert Wise ~ Henry Daniell, Boris Karloff, Russell Wade, Bela Lugosi
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding performance by Karloff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    udar55
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Noble young doctor-in-training Donald Fettes (Russell Wade) gets a dark lesson in the profession when he finds out instructor Dr. MacFarlane (Henry Daniell) is paying cabbie Mr. Gray (Boris Karloff) to procure fresh specimens for him from the local graveyard. Fettes is disturbed by the arrangement, but turns to Mr. Gray for a body when a little girl's surgery depends on it. What he doesn't expect is Gray opting to deliver even fresher specimens. Based on the short story by Robert Louis Stevenson, this has some solid drama balanced with some moody chills. This was Robert Wise's third feature film as director and he already shows a great handle of the craft (the abduction of the town singer is a great bit). By far the best thing about the film is the performance of Karloff in the title role. Man, he is just awesome. There is a great scene where he is confronted by an extortionist (played by Bela Lugosi) and Karloff's charm as the works in closer to kill the man is fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Karloff picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Karloff at his very finest. He was masterful as the monster in the Frankenstein roles, but really didn't impress me in much else, until I saw this movie. He was the most evil, dastardly, conniving and disgustingly depraved villain as ever seen in pictures up until this movie was made. I'm sure the character, and Karloff's performance, both, shocked audiences. It was a dramatic role in a somewhat horror, more of a thriller, type movie. His screen presence is so profound in this movie, that you just can't take your eyes off of him. He literally steals the show. Frankly, I never knew he had it in him to do this kind of work. This was a superb performance by Karloff. Worthy of a best supporting actor nod.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
