<filme>
 <id>
  447
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0074285
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1976
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Carrie, a Estranha
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young, abused and timid 17-year-old girl discovers she has telekinesis, and gets pushed to the limit on the night of her school's prom by a humiliating prank.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Carrie White is a shy young girl who doesn't make friends easily. After her class mates taunt her about her horrified reaction to her totally unexpected first period one of them takes pity on her and gets Tommy Ross, her boyfriend and class hunk to invite Carrie to the senior prom. Meanwhile another girl who has been banned from the prom for her continued aggressive behaviour is not as forgiving and plans a trick to embarrass Carrie in front of the whole school. What she doesn't realise is that Carrie is ... gifted, and you really don't want to get her angry.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   prom
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   school
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   telekinesis
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   student
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   teacher
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Brian De Palma
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Stephen King
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Lawrence D. Cohen
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Sissy Spacek
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Piper Laurie
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Amy Irving
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Milito
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1974, legendary horror writer Stephen King published his first novel, titled Carrie, which launched him into the fame that he has today. Even today, the story is recognized as one of the best Stephen King novels, but also as one of the greatest horror stories ever told. Two years after publication, director Brian De Palma would adapt this famous story for the big screen. The result was a fantastic horror movie with absolutely phenomenal acting performances and a chilling storyline that leaves an impact on everyone who witnesses it. Carrie White is a shy, socially awkward teenager who is subject to frequent bullying at Bates High School. Carrie is one of the girls who wears her hair down in order to cover her face. She lives at home with her mother Margaret, a mentally unstable Christian fundamentalist. Carrie is often subject to punishments from her mother, whether it's being forced into a closet to pray or repeating verses from the Bible over and over. Carrie is special though: she has the ability of telekinesis, meaning she can movie objects with her mind. After humiliating Carrie in the girls locker room, the more popular girls at the school, including Sue Snell, Chris Hargensen, and Norma Watson, are sentenced to a week long detention for their inappropriate behavior towards Carrie. Feeling bad for what she did, Sue decides to get her boyfriend, Tommy Ross, to ask Carrie to the senior prom in order to make up for the embarrassment. Reluctantly, Carrie accepts. However, when something goes down at the prom, the night turns from one of happiness and fun into one of pure horror. The story is chilling and unsettling without being a full-fledged slasher movie. What's great about the movie is the way takes the time to slow down and flesh out Carrie's story, giving a chance for viewers to realize just how terrible Carrie's life really is. As it progresses, Carrie becomes a more relatable and sympathetic character, which makes the climax all the more saddening and even understandable to a certain degree. The performances in Carrie are top-notch all around the board. Sissy Spacek, in an Oscar-nominated performance, plays Carrie extremely well. She plays all the emotions that Carrie faces in an extremely believable way, almost making it hard to tell if she's actually acting. Spacek also has a sort of physical appearance where she can match the qualities needed for the character of Carrie, but also where she is undeniably beautiful when she cleans herself up for the prom. Piper Laurie sort of revived her career with her performance as Margaret, garnering her an Oscar nomination also. She felt over-the-top at times, but Laurie's performance is undeniably unsettling, especially in the scenes where she physically abuses Carrie. Rounding out the supporting cast is Betty Buckley as Miss Collins, the gym teacher in charge of the detention and a comforting figure for Carrie, and John Travolta, in a breakthrough performance as Chris' boyfriend. There are a few aspects of Carrie that feel like they haven't aged well, such as the strange blurry lighting in some of the outdoor shots, but it's not enough to hinder it's greatness. The performances are solid, especially the Oscar-nominated performances from Spacek and Laurie. The story was well-written and well-executed, and offers some deep themes about bullying. Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Felt Bad For Poor Carrie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Stephen King's first novel, this film tells the story of a shy teenage girl named Carrie White(Sissy Spacek in an unforgettable performance) who is mocked and humiliated by her cruel schoolmates, though one of them takes pity on her, and has her popular boyfriend(William Katt) ask Carrie to the prom, which she accepts, but tragically Carrie's mother(Piper Laurie, quite good) is a psychopathic religious zealot who keeps Carrie locked in the closet as punishment for her "sins", but Carrie defies her, though two evil expelled classmates(played by Nancy Allen & John Travolta) plot a cruel prank on her at the prom, which pushes Carrie over the edge, and makes her use her latent telekinetic powers in merciless revenge... Fine performances and script compensate for some exploitive and obvious scare tactics in this memorable film, which elicits such sympathy for this unjustly put-upon girl that her rage at the end is understandable, though of course the poor girl is doomed...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A loose adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie was Stephen King's first novel and easily considered one of his best. When it became a hit a film adaptation was practically inevitable. Carrie is considered one of the most important horror films of the 70s. Carrie White (Sissy Spacek) is an isolated high school student with no friends and a fundamentalist Christian mum, Margaret (Piper Laurie). After being humiliated when she gets her first period in the school shower her telekinetic powers start to develop and heighten when under stress. Sue Snell (Amy Irving) feels guilty due to the incident in the shower where she joined in with mob and wants to make it up to Carrie by getting her boyfriend, Tommy (William Katt) to take Carrie to the prom. But the lead bully, Chris Hargensen (Nancy Allen) wants revenge against Carrie, blaming her for not letting her go to the prom and with her delinquent boyfriend, Billy (John Travolta) plan to humiliate Carrie in the most public and sadistic way possible. Carrie is an excellent novel, a short, taut little affair that is a breeze of a read. Some of the elements from the novel would have been hard to translate into because of the structure of the novel: mainly the extracts from the White Commission, The Shadow Exploded and Sue Snell's diary. Other scenes were cut because of expense, i.e. the explosion of the petrol station. But this is an adaptation that does make some big changes and cuts from the novel. Some include not getting to see Chris' father threatening to sue and ends up seeing what his daughter really is, cutting out Sue's pregnancy to small things like Carrie saying her father left her mother instead of dying in an industrial accident. Plus the sociological elements were cut out, looking at the impact of the aftermath of the Carrie incident which I thought was some of the most interesting stuff in the novel. The big positive with the film is the casting of Spacek: she was a terrific as Carrie, having the right look for seemingly being a little weird but have a unique beauty when she is at the prom. She was able to convey the shy, awkwardness of a character who is beaten emotionally at home and at school and shows a psychopathic rage with the look with her eyes when the pigs blood fell on her. The rest of the cast were solid, like Allen playing the bitchy, self-centred bully, Travolta as the abusive boyfriend, Katt and Irving as the high school students who want to do the right thing. Betty Buckley was excellent as the friendly teacher who wants to support and protect Carrie and Laurie did a good job as Carrie's fundamentalist mother. But Sydney Lassick was really hammy and out of place as an English teacher who wasn't even in the book. The big highlight of the film was the prom scene when the pig's blood felt on Carrie goes into a psychopathic rage, locking the doors with her mind and sets out killing everyone. Director Brian De Palma was able highlight the build-up and the tension and then the terror of Carrie's killing. De Palma was able to make the sequence with a unique style using split screens to show different actions happening at the same time and De Palma used silences, making us lip-read what people are saying (though it is very obvious). It is excellent sequence. During the film they are plenty of musical cues when Carrie using her powers, partly due to the limits of special effects, but sometimes the violin streaks from Psycho which was a distraction. Carrie is a very well-acted film that had some stand out sequences and excellent acting, but it is too loose of an adaptation for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Modern Tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nc-holdsworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Carrie again for the first time in years, having seen the trailer for the remake with Chloe thingybob from the god awful Kick Ass. Its a tragic tale about a shy girl called Carrie White who seems to get abuse and bullying by almost everyone she meets, her mother, classmates even annoying kids on bikes. Her mother is a religious nut case, therefore she has had no knowledge or understanding of the world and is left open to bullying from other kids due to the fact she is different. What no one knows is how different Carrie really is. She is already realising she can move things with her mind at the start of the movie, therefore its not dragged down with learning to use her 'powers' etc and instead concentrates on the story. For the story is not only about her ability, its an all too human tale of someone looking for acceptance, to be loved and its this that makes it so memorable. Its a very cruel movie for several reasons. First of all the bullying is quite nasty and humiliating, secondly then with help of one of the few sympathetic class mates Carrie gets her dream date for the prom (after initial scepticism) and during the prom she is genuinely happy for once in her life and these scenes are very touching. As a viewer we know its not going to end there however, we know the fall will come and DePalma expertly creates the ominous atmosphere before the bucket of blood comes crashing down all over her. What comes next is a split screen massacre as Carrie wipes out almost the entire Prom Night goers in a rage fuelled inferno. Carrie is a film that has that magic mix. DePalma's sure direction is excellent (even the quirky touches such as the fast forward work for me) Sissy Spacek, words are not enough to explain her shattering performance. It really is something. I've always been a fan of Pino Donnaggio and his work here is one, if not the best soundtrack he has ever done. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Magical Melodrama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zacharyduresky
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie is a film that makes you feel so many different emotions. Scenes like the infamous "period" scene will make you feel disgusted. The gym detention scene will make you laugh. The dance between Carrie and Tommy will touch you're heart. The climactic scene where Carrie unleashes her powers and kills everyone will have haunt your nightmares. There's drama, romance, suspense, comedy, eroticism and horror, everything you cold possibly want. But at its core, this film is a melodrama. This is a melodrama about an abused and taunted teenage girl who just wants love and acceptance. Then she discovers she can move things with her mind. At first she does nothing evil with it, and still tries to get accepted, and manages to do so. But then after a cruel prank involving pig blood, she's now out for human blood. Everyone dies, and this evil she finally unleashes leads to her demise, just like any other tragic character. This is easily my favorite film by director Brian De Palma, and my favorite film based on a Stephen King story. This melodramatic piece of genius never stops satisfying me, and just gets better and better every time I watch it. I highly recommend this to all who are unfortunate enough to have not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly the best horror movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I had not read the book before the film and I was only watching because I had seen the trailer for the upcoming remake. So I started it with no expectations at all and just had nothing better to do. Now down to the review. Right from the beginning this movie entices you in with a lovely period scene in a shower. I had no idea that this was going to happen and was quite surprised because it was handled very well and the actresses were not sexualised by Brian De Palma at all. Next was the entrance of Carrie's not so terrifying mother played by Piper Laurie. Maybe when this came out in 1974 she was scary, but now she's more....really really funny. This is really the only bad thing I can think of about the movie, with the exception of a pointless sex scene later. The next 40 minutes of the movie run pretty smoothly containing simple camera work and medium acting, with the occasional completely pointless sex scene. To make it even worse it has John Travolta in it! But then about 50 minutes in the prom scene arrives which I have already read about on Rotten Tomatoes and is in my opinion....actually not in my opinion IT'S A FACT! One of the most awesome movie scenes ever! Which is surprising because the special effects are a bit dodgy, but I won't deduct points for that because it was the best for the time. After Carrie has awesomely killed a gazabillion people at the prom she decides to go home and change into her pyjamas, which was bit weird considering she had just murdered loads of her classmates. But I won't deduct points for that because it's probably something to do with her telekinesis/puberty experience. Then her mum (who is one of my favourite unintentionally funny characters of all time) stabs her in the back LITERALLY! while they are praying, another reason why I'm atheist folks. Overall CARRIE is one of my favourite movies of all time. Possibly the best horror movie I have ever seen. Starting off at 10 (obviously) I minus 1 point for Piper Laurie being unintentionally hilarious. Then minus 0.3 points for a pointless sex scene. And finally minus 0.2 points for Carrie killing loads of people then going home as if nothing has happened. So I give Carrie- 8.5 out of 10 and 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Toronto85
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shy young girl gets back at her high school bullies using telekinetic powers in 'Carrie'. Carrie White is graduating high school, yet has no one to take her to the prom. She has no friends and all of the girls at school pick on her constantly. On top of all that, her mother is a religious nut who emotionally and physically abuses her at home. After picking on Carrie, fellow classmate Sue Snell decides to make it up to her by having her own boyfriend Tommy ask Carrie to the prom. After much reluctance, Tommy asks her out and they head off for the big night. The bullies fix it so that Tommy/Carrie are picked as king and queen in order for pig's blood to land right on the poor girl. That's when Carrie loses control and all HELL breaks loose at the high school. 'Carrie' is an amazing fantasy/horror film. Director Brian De Palma does such a good job with 'Carrie'. We get the flashes of the magical prom mixed in with Kris planning to dump the pig's blood over Carrie. The plot of the shy girl getting back at her bullies is a satisfying one, but with the added idea of telekinesis makes an even more exciting movie. The acting was really well done by everyone! Sissy Spacek puts in a good job as the lead Carrie, Piper Laurie is convincing as Carrie's crazed religious mother, and I REALLY thought Amy Irving was wonderful as Sue Snell. John Travolta, PJ Soles and Nancy Allen were great too as the villains. All around, a really good cast. It's always fun to see bullies get theirs in movies, but 'Carrie' takes it up a notch. I'd recommend this for sure to every horror fan. It's well acted, got a great cast and tells a pretty satisfying but sad story. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more than a film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    each adaptation of Stephen King novels is a delicate action. because , more than expectation of readers, important is the vision of director. and, sure, the cast. Carrie is out of this law. because it is not part of an genre or expectation in ordinary sense. it is a classic but not is its virtue. it is extraordinary expression of Sissy Spacek performance but not is the essential part. because, out of definitions, it is a mirror. the horror side is only trace of a profound tragedy who defines our world. the blood, the expression of Carrie face, the shadow of mother, the end, all represents images for ordinary state of each of us. it is so human, so cruel in manner to expose the deep truth about society than it is not, in time, only a good/extraordinary/admirable movie, it is a warning. and clear mirror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent horror mystery thriller! 8!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen many movies based on books written by Stephen King. In fact, I would consider myself a King's fan if I had read, at least, one of the numerous books he has written. "Carrie" is one of the best of them I saw. King's traits are very visible in this story: his sense of humour, horror, supernatural elements, mystery, drama, good performances, etc. The fact that John Travolta acted in the movie and that Brian de Palma directed it made me wish to watch "Carrie". Moreover, I am looking forward to seeing its remake. This movie is wonderfully directed with the right pace and duration. Brian de Palma did a very entertaining job with a very good script. The story is about a teenage girl who has telekinetic abilities and is bullied by her schoolmates. She lacks of a social life and is not like most teenagers. Moreover, she lives with her mother, who is a very possessive and mad women left by his husband. I prefer not to tell anything else about the plot not to spoil. The cast is mainly composed by Sissy Spacek, Piper Laurie and John Travolta. Sissy Spacek delivered a solid performance, maybe, a little bit overacted. The performances are very correct. The story is original and the capacity of entertainment is really high. The plot and the performances are the strongest points of this movie. There are several shocking scenes which are very amazing. In conclusion, this is a must-see for those like the stories from King. 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect cinema classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombiefan89
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't really even consider Carrie a horror movie. Sissy Spacek was just to adorable to find threatening, even when she went fully homicidal. Everything she did felt justified. However, if I had to say the biggest issue with the film was the ending. It made no sense at all. Why did they blame Carrie for the gym catching on fire? How did they know Carrie didn't die in the gym with everyone else? There were no survivors except the two antagonists, but they died shortly after. Let's say there were survivors, Did they all unanimously accept that Carrie had psychic powers and caused the fire? Why and how did they blame Carrie? It was like Light Yagami in Death Note, who could kill people by writing their name down and thinking of their face as they do it. They accepted that a notebook could kill people WAY too easily! No court on Earth would have convicted Light Yagami of being "Kira" because there was NO solid proof! I had a complete opposite reaction to the "surprise ending", I would have immediately started digging her out, trying to save her life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Milito
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1974, legendary horror writer Stephen King published his first novel, titled Carrie, which launched him into the fame that he has today. Even today, the story is recognized as one of the best Stephen King novels, but also as one of the greatest horror stories ever told. Two years after publication, director Brian De Palma would adapt this famous story for the big screen. The result was a fantastic horror movie with absolutely phenomenal acting performances and a chilling storyline that leaves an impact on everyone who witnesses it. Carrie White is a shy, socially awkward teenager who is subject to frequent bullying at Bates High School. Carrie is one of the girls who wears her hair down in order to cover her face. She lives at home with her mother Margaret, a mentally unstable Christian fundamentalist. Carrie is often subject to punishments from her mother, whether it's being forced into a closet to pray or repeating verses from the Bible over and over. Carrie is special though: she has the ability of telekinesis, meaning she can movie objects with her mind. After humiliating Carrie in the girls locker room, the more popular girls at the school, including Sue Snell, Chris Hargensen, and Norma Watson, are sentenced to a week long detention for their inappropriate behavior towards Carrie. Feeling bad for what she did, Sue decides to get her boyfriend, Tommy Ross, to ask Carrie to the senior prom in order to make up for the embarrassment. Reluctantly, Carrie accepts. However, when something goes down at the prom, the night turns from one of happiness and fun into one of pure horror. The story is chilling and unsettling without being a full-fledged slasher movie. What's great about the movie is the way takes the time to slow down and flesh out Carrie's story, giving a chance for viewers to realize just how terrible Carrie's life really is. As it progresses, Carrie becomes a more relatable and sympathetic character, which makes the climax all the more saddening and even understandable to a certain degree. The performances in Carrie are top-notch all around the board. Sissy Spacek, in an Oscar-nominated performance, plays Carrie extremely well. She plays all the emotions that Carrie faces in an extremely believable way, almost making it hard to tell if she's actually acting. Spacek also has a sort of physical appearance where she can match the qualities needed for the character of Carrie, but also where she is undeniably beautiful when she cleans herself up for the prom. Piper Laurie sort of revived her career with her performance as Margaret, garnering her an Oscar nomination also. She felt over-the-top at times, but Laurie's performance is undeniably unsettling, especially in the scenes where she physically abuses Carrie. Rounding out the supporting cast is Betty Buckley as Miss Collins, the gym teacher in charge of the detention and a comforting figure for Carrie, and John Travolta, in a breakthrough performance as Chris' boyfriend. There are a few aspects of Carrie that feel like they haven't aged well, such as the strange blurry lighting in some of the outdoor shots, but it's not enough to hinder it's greatness. The performances are solid, especially the Oscar-nominated performances from Spacek and Laurie. The story was well-written and well-executed, and offers some deep themes about bullying. Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Felt Bad For Poor Carrie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Stephen King's first novel, this film tells the story of a shy teenage girl named Carrie White(Sissy Spacek in an unforgettable performance) who is mocked and humiliated by her cruel schoolmates, though one of them takes pity on her, and has her popular boyfriend(William Katt) ask Carrie to the prom, which she accepts, but tragically Carrie's mother(Piper Laurie, quite good) is a psychopathic religious zealot who keeps Carrie locked in the closet as punishment for her "sins", but Carrie defies her, though two evil expelled classmates(played by Nancy Allen & John Travolta) plot a cruel prank on her at the prom, which pushes Carrie over the edge, and makes her use her latent telekinetic powers in merciless revenge... Fine performances and script compensate for some exploitive and obvious scare tactics in this memorable film, which elicits such sympathy for this unjustly put-upon girl that her rage at the end is understandable, though of course the poor girl is doomed...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A loose adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie was Stephen King's first novel and easily considered one of his best. When it became a hit a film adaptation was practically inevitable. Carrie is considered one of the most important horror films of the 70s. Carrie White (Sissy Spacek) is an isolated high school student with no friends and a fundamentalist Christian mum, Margaret (Piper Laurie). After being humiliated when she gets her first period in the school shower her telekinetic powers start to develop and heighten when under stress. Sue Snell (Amy Irving) feels guilty due to the incident in the shower where she joined in with mob and wants to make it up to Carrie by getting her boyfriend, Tommy (William Katt) to take Carrie to the prom. But the lead bully, Chris Hargensen (Nancy Allen) wants revenge against Carrie, blaming her for not letting her go to the prom and with her delinquent boyfriend, Billy (John Travolta) plan to humiliate Carrie in the most public and sadistic way possible. Carrie is an excellent novel, a short, taut little affair that is a breeze of a read. Some of the elements from the novel would have been hard to translate into because of the structure of the novel: mainly the extracts from the White Commission, The Shadow Exploded and Sue Snell's diary. Other scenes were cut because of expense, i.e. the explosion of the petrol station. But this is an adaptation that does make some big changes and cuts from the novel. Some include not getting to see Chris' father threatening to sue and ends up seeing what his daughter really is, cutting out Sue's pregnancy to small things like Carrie saying her father left her mother instead of dying in an industrial accident. Plus the sociological elements were cut out, looking at the impact of the aftermath of the Carrie incident which I thought was some of the most interesting stuff in the novel. The big positive with the film is the casting of Spacek: she was a terrific as Carrie, having the right look for seemingly being a little weird but have a unique beauty when she is at the prom. She was able to convey the shy, awkwardness of a character who is beaten emotionally at home and at school and shows a psychopathic rage with the look with her eyes when the pigs blood fell on her. The rest of the cast were solid, like Allen playing the bitchy, self-centred bully, Travolta as the abusive boyfriend, Katt and Irving as the high school students who want to do the right thing. Betty Buckley was excellent as the friendly teacher who wants to support and protect Carrie and Laurie did a good job as Carrie's fundamentalist mother. But Sydney Lassick was really hammy and out of place as an English teacher who wasn't even in the book. The big highlight of the film was the prom scene when the pig's blood felt on Carrie goes into a psychopathic rage, locking the doors with her mind and sets out killing everyone. Director Brian De Palma was able highlight the build-up and the tension and then the terror of Carrie's killing. De Palma was able to make the sequence with a unique style using split screens to show different actions happening at the same time and De Palma used silences, making us lip-read what people are saying (though it is very obvious). It is excellent sequence. During the film they are plenty of musical cues when Carrie using her powers, partly due to the limits of special effects, but sometimes the violin streaks from Psycho which was a distraction. Carrie is a very well-acted film that had some stand out sequences and excellent acting, but it is too loose of an adaptation for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Modern Tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nc-holdsworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Carrie again for the first time in years, having seen the trailer for the remake with Chloe thingybob from the god awful Kick Ass. Its a tragic tale about a shy girl called Carrie White who seems to get abuse and bullying by almost everyone she meets, her mother, classmates even annoying kids on bikes. Her mother is a religious nut case, therefore she has had no knowledge or understanding of the world and is left open to bullying from other kids due to the fact she is different. What no one knows is how different Carrie really is. She is already realising she can move things with her mind at the start of the movie, therefore its not dragged down with learning to use her 'powers' etc and instead concentrates on the story. For the story is not only about her ability, its an all too human tale of someone looking for acceptance, to be loved and its this that makes it so memorable. Its a very cruel movie for several reasons. First of all the bullying is quite nasty and humiliating, secondly then with help of one of the few sympathetic class mates Carrie gets her dream date for the prom (after initial scepticism) and during the prom she is genuinely happy for once in her life and these scenes are very touching. As a viewer we know its not going to end there however, we know the fall will come and DePalma expertly creates the ominous atmosphere before the bucket of blood comes crashing down all over her. What comes next is a split screen massacre as Carrie wipes out almost the entire Prom Night goers in a rage fuelled inferno. Carrie is a film that has that magic mix. DePalma's sure direction is excellent (even the quirky touches such as the fast forward work for me) Sissy Spacek, words are not enough to explain her shattering performance. It really is something. I've always been a fan of Pino Donnaggio and his work here is one, if not the best soundtrack he has ever done. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Magical Melodrama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zacharyduresky
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie is a film that makes you feel so many different emotions. Scenes like the infamous "period" scene will make you feel disgusted. The gym detention scene will make you laugh. The dance between Carrie and Tommy will touch you're heart. The climactic scene where Carrie unleashes her powers and kills everyone will have haunt your nightmares. There's drama, romance, suspense, comedy, eroticism and horror, everything you cold possibly want. But at its core, this film is a melodrama. This is a melodrama about an abused and taunted teenage girl who just wants love and acceptance. Then she discovers she can move things with her mind. At first she does nothing evil with it, and still tries to get accepted, and manages to do so. But then after a cruel prank involving pig blood, she's now out for human blood. Everyone dies, and this evil she finally unleashes leads to her demise, just like any other tragic character. This is easily my favorite film by director Brian De Palma, and my favorite film based on a Stephen King story. This melodramatic piece of genius never stops satisfying me, and just gets better and better every time I watch it. I highly recommend this to all who are unfortunate enough to have not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly the best horror movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I had not read the book before the film and I was only watching because I had seen the trailer for the upcoming remake. So I started it with no expectations at all and just had nothing better to do. Now down to the review. Right from the beginning this movie entices you in with a lovely period scene in a shower. I had no idea that this was going to happen and was quite surprised because it was handled very well and the actresses were not sexualised by Brian De Palma at all. Next was the entrance of Carrie's not so terrifying mother played by Piper Laurie. Maybe when this came out in 1974 she was scary, but now she's more....really really funny. This is really the only bad thing I can think of about the movie, with the exception of a pointless sex scene later. The next 40 minutes of the movie run pretty smoothly containing simple camera work and medium acting, with the occasional completely pointless sex scene. To make it even worse it has John Travolta in it! But then about 50 minutes in the prom scene arrives which I have already read about on Rotten Tomatoes and is in my opinion....actually not in my opinion IT'S A FACT! One of the most awesome movie scenes ever! Which is surprising because the special effects are a bit dodgy, but I won't deduct points for that because it was the best for the time. After Carrie has awesomely killed a gazabillion people at the prom she decides to go home and change into her pyjamas, which was bit weird considering she had just murdered loads of her classmates. But I won't deduct points for that because it's probably something to do with her telekinesis/puberty experience. Then her mum (who is one of my favourite unintentionally funny characters of all time) stabs her in the back LITERALLY! while they are praying, another reason why I'm atheist folks. Overall CARRIE is one of my favourite movies of all time. Possibly the best horror movie I have ever seen. Starting off at 10 (obviously) I minus 1 point for Piper Laurie being unintentionally hilarious. Then minus 0.3 points for a pointless sex scene. And finally minus 0.2 points for Carrie killing loads of people then going home as if nothing has happened. So I give Carrie- 8.5 out of 10 and 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Toronto85
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shy young girl gets back at her high school bullies using telekinetic powers in 'Carrie'. Carrie White is graduating high school, yet has no one to take her to the prom. She has no friends and all of the girls at school pick on her constantly. On top of all that, her mother is a religious nut who emotionally and physically abuses her at home. After picking on Carrie, fellow classmate Sue Snell decides to make it up to her by having her own boyfriend Tommy ask Carrie to the prom. After much reluctance, Tommy asks her out and they head off for the big night. The bullies fix it so that Tommy/Carrie are picked as king and queen in order for pig's blood to land right on the poor girl. That's when Carrie loses control and all HELL breaks loose at the high school. 'Carrie' is an amazing fantasy/horror film. Director Brian De Palma does such a good job with 'Carrie'. We get the flashes of the magical prom mixed in with Kris planning to dump the pig's blood over Carrie. The plot of the shy girl getting back at her bullies is a satisfying one, but with the added idea of telekinesis makes an even more exciting movie. The acting was really well done by everyone! Sissy Spacek puts in a good job as the lead Carrie, Piper Laurie is convincing as Carrie's crazed religious mother, and I REALLY thought Amy Irving was wonderful as Sue Snell. John Travolta, PJ Soles and Nancy Allen were great too as the villains. All around, a really good cast. It's always fun to see bullies get theirs in movies, but 'Carrie' takes it up a notch. I'd recommend this for sure to every horror fan. It's well acted, got a great cast and tells a pretty satisfying but sad story. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more than a film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    each adaptation of Stephen King novels is a delicate action. because , more than expectation of readers, important is the vision of director. and, sure, the cast. Carrie is out of this law. because it is not part of an genre or expectation in ordinary sense. it is a classic but not is its virtue. it is extraordinary expression of Sissy Spacek performance but not is the essential part. because, out of definitions, it is a mirror. the horror side is only trace of a profound tragedy who defines our world. the blood, the expression of Carrie face, the shadow of mother, the end, all represents images for ordinary state of each of us. it is so human, so cruel in manner to expose the deep truth about society than it is not, in time, only a good/extraordinary/admirable movie, it is a warning. and clear mirror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent horror mystery thriller! 8!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen many movies based on books written by Stephen King. In fact, I would consider myself a King's fan if I had read, at least, one of the numerous books he has written. "Carrie" is one of the best of them I saw. King's traits are very visible in this story: his sense of humour, horror, supernatural elements, mystery, drama, good performances, etc. The fact that John Travolta acted in the movie and that Brian de Palma directed it made me wish to watch "Carrie". Moreover, I am looking forward to seeing its remake. This movie is wonderfully directed with the right pace and duration. Brian de Palma did a very entertaining job with a very good script. The story is about a teenage girl who has telekinetic abilities and is bullied by her schoolmates. She lacks of a social life and is not like most teenagers. Moreover, she lives with her mother, who is a very possessive and mad women left by his husband. I prefer not to tell anything else about the plot not to spoil. The cast is mainly composed by Sissy Spacek, Piper Laurie and John Travolta. Sissy Spacek delivered a solid performance, maybe, a little bit overacted. The performances are very correct. The story is original and the capacity of entertainment is really high. The plot and the performances are the strongest points of this movie. There are several shocking scenes which are very amazing. In conclusion, this is a must-see for those like the stories from King. 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect cinema classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombiefan89
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't really even consider Carrie a horror movie. Sissy Spacek was just to adorable to find threatening, even when she went fully homicidal. Everything she did felt justified. However, if I had to say the biggest issue with the film was the ending. It made no sense at all. Why did they blame Carrie for the gym catching on fire? How did they know Carrie didn't die in the gym with everyone else? There were no survivors except the two antagonists, but they died shortly after. Let's say there were survivors, Did they all unanimously accept that Carrie had psychic powers and caused the fire? Why and how did they blame Carrie? It was like Light Yagami in Death Note, who could kill people by writing their name down and thinking of their face as they do it. They accepted that a notebook could kill people WAY too easily! No court on Earth would have convicted Light Yagami of being "Kira" because there was NO solid proof! I had a complete opposite reaction to the "surprise ending", I would have immediately started digging her out, trying to save her life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Milito
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1974, legendary horror writer Stephen King published his first novel, titled Carrie, which launched him into the fame that he has today. Even today, the story is recognized as one of the best Stephen King novels, but also as one of the greatest horror stories ever told. Two years after publication, director Brian De Palma would adapt this famous story for the big screen. The result was a fantastic horror movie with absolutely phenomenal acting performances and a chilling storyline that leaves an impact on everyone who witnesses it. Carrie White is a shy, socially awkward teenager who is subject to frequent bullying at Bates High School. Carrie is one of the girls who wears her hair down in order to cover her face. She lives at home with her mother Margaret, a mentally unstable Christian fundamentalist. Carrie is often subject to punishments from her mother, whether it's being forced into a closet to pray or repeating verses from the Bible over and over. Carrie is special though: she has the ability of telekinesis, meaning she can movie objects with her mind. After humiliating Carrie in the girls locker room, the more popular girls at the school, including Sue Snell, Chris Hargensen, and Norma Watson, are sentenced to a week long detention for their inappropriate behavior towards Carrie. Feeling bad for what she did, Sue decides to get her boyfriend, Tommy Ross, to ask Carrie to the senior prom in order to make up for the embarrassment. Reluctantly, Carrie accepts. However, when something goes down at the prom, the night turns from one of happiness and fun into one of pure horror. The story is chilling and unsettling without being a full-fledged slasher movie. What's great about the movie is the way takes the time to slow down and flesh out Carrie's story, giving a chance for viewers to realize just how terrible Carrie's life really is. As it progresses, Carrie becomes a more relatable and sympathetic character, which makes the climax all the more saddening and even understandable to a certain degree. The performances in Carrie are top-notch all around the board. Sissy Spacek, in an Oscar-nominated performance, plays Carrie extremely well. She plays all the emotions that Carrie faces in an extremely believable way, almost making it hard to tell if she's actually acting. Spacek also has a sort of physical appearance where she can match the qualities needed for the character of Carrie, but also where she is undeniably beautiful when she cleans herself up for the prom. Piper Laurie sort of revived her career with her performance as Margaret, garnering her an Oscar nomination also. She felt over-the-top at times, but Laurie's performance is undeniably unsettling, especially in the scenes where she physically abuses Carrie. Rounding out the supporting cast is Betty Buckley as Miss Collins, the gym teacher in charge of the detention and a comforting figure for Carrie, and John Travolta, in a breakthrough performance as Chris' boyfriend. There are a few aspects of Carrie that feel like they haven't aged well, such as the strange blurry lighting in some of the outdoor shots, but it's not enough to hinder it's greatness. The performances are solid, especially the Oscar-nominated performances from Spacek and Laurie. The story was well-written and well-executed, and offers some deep themes about bullying. Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Felt Bad For Poor Carrie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Stephen King's first novel, this film tells the story of a shy teenage girl named Carrie White(Sissy Spacek in an unforgettable performance) who is mocked and humiliated by her cruel schoolmates, though one of them takes pity on her, and has her popular boyfriend(William Katt) ask Carrie to the prom, which she accepts, but tragically Carrie's mother(Piper Laurie, quite good) is a psychopathic religious zealot who keeps Carrie locked in the closet as punishment for her "sins", but Carrie defies her, though two evil expelled classmates(played by Nancy Allen & John Travolta) plot a cruel prank on her at the prom, which pushes Carrie over the edge, and makes her use her latent telekinetic powers in merciless revenge... Fine performances and script compensate for some exploitive and obvious scare tactics in this memorable film, which elicits such sympathy for this unjustly put-upon girl that her rage at the end is understandable, though of course the poor girl is doomed...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A loose adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie was Stephen King's first novel and easily considered one of his best. When it became a hit a film adaptation was practically inevitable. Carrie is considered one of the most important horror films of the 70s. Carrie White (Sissy Spacek) is an isolated high school student with no friends and a fundamentalist Christian mum, Margaret (Piper Laurie). After being humiliated when she gets her first period in the school shower her telekinetic powers start to develop and heighten when under stress. Sue Snell (Amy Irving) feels guilty due to the incident in the shower where she joined in with mob and wants to make it up to Carrie by getting her boyfriend, Tommy (William Katt) to take Carrie to the prom. But the lead bully, Chris Hargensen (Nancy Allen) wants revenge against Carrie, blaming her for not letting her go to the prom and with her delinquent boyfriend, Billy (John Travolta) plan to humiliate Carrie in the most public and sadistic way possible. Carrie is an excellent novel, a short, taut little affair that is a breeze of a read. Some of the elements from the novel would have been hard to translate into because of the structure of the novel: mainly the extracts from the White Commission, The Shadow Exploded and Sue Snell's diary. Other scenes were cut because of expense, i.e. the explosion of the petrol station. But this is an adaptation that does make some big changes and cuts from the novel. Some include not getting to see Chris' father threatening to sue and ends up seeing what his daughter really is, cutting out Sue's pregnancy to small things like Carrie saying her father left her mother instead of dying in an industrial accident. Plus the sociological elements were cut out, looking at the impact of the aftermath of the Carrie incident which I thought was some of the most interesting stuff in the novel. The big positive with the film is the casting of Spacek: she was a terrific as Carrie, having the right look for seemingly being a little weird but have a unique beauty when she is at the prom. She was able to convey the shy, awkwardness of a character who is beaten emotionally at home and at school and shows a psychopathic rage with the look with her eyes when the pigs blood fell on her. The rest of the cast were solid, like Allen playing the bitchy, self-centred bully, Travolta as the abusive boyfriend, Katt and Irving as the high school students who want to do the right thing. Betty Buckley was excellent as the friendly teacher who wants to support and protect Carrie and Laurie did a good job as Carrie's fundamentalist mother. But Sydney Lassick was really hammy and out of place as an English teacher who wasn't even in the book. The big highlight of the film was the prom scene when the pig's blood felt on Carrie goes into a psychopathic rage, locking the doors with her mind and sets out killing everyone. Director Brian De Palma was able highlight the build-up and the tension and then the terror of Carrie's killing. De Palma was able to make the sequence with a unique style using split screens to show different actions happening at the same time and De Palma used silences, making us lip-read what people are saying (though it is very obvious). It is excellent sequence. During the film they are plenty of musical cues when Carrie using her powers, partly due to the limits of special effects, but sometimes the violin streaks from Psycho which was a distraction. Carrie is a very well-acted film that had some stand out sequences and excellent acting, but it is too loose of an adaptation for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Modern Tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nc-holdsworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Carrie again for the first time in years, having seen the trailer for the remake with Chloe thingybob from the god awful Kick Ass. Its a tragic tale about a shy girl called Carrie White who seems to get abuse and bullying by almost everyone she meets, her mother, classmates even annoying kids on bikes. Her mother is a religious nut case, therefore she has had no knowledge or understanding of the world and is left open to bullying from other kids due to the fact she is different. What no one knows is how different Carrie really is. She is already realising she can move things with her mind at the start of the movie, therefore its not dragged down with learning to use her 'powers' etc and instead concentrates on the story. For the story is not only about her ability, its an all too human tale of someone looking for acceptance, to be loved and its this that makes it so memorable. Its a very cruel movie for several reasons. First of all the bullying is quite nasty and humiliating, secondly then with help of one of the few sympathetic class mates Carrie gets her dream date for the prom (after initial scepticism) and during the prom she is genuinely happy for once in her life and these scenes are very touching. As a viewer we know its not going to end there however, we know the fall will come and DePalma expertly creates the ominous atmosphere before the bucket of blood comes crashing down all over her. What comes next is a split screen massacre as Carrie wipes out almost the entire Prom Night goers in a rage fuelled inferno. Carrie is a film that has that magic mix. DePalma's sure direction is excellent (even the quirky touches such as the fast forward work for me) Sissy Spacek, words are not enough to explain her shattering performance. It really is something. I've always been a fan of Pino Donnaggio and his work here is one, if not the best soundtrack he has ever done. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Magical Melodrama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zacharyduresky
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie is a film that makes you feel so many different emotions. Scenes like the infamous "period" scene will make you feel disgusted. The gym detention scene will make you laugh. The dance between Carrie and Tommy will touch you're heart. The climactic scene where Carrie unleashes her powers and kills everyone will have haunt your nightmares. There's drama, romance, suspense, comedy, eroticism and horror, everything you cold possibly want. But at its core, this film is a melodrama. This is a melodrama about an abused and taunted teenage girl who just wants love and acceptance. Then she discovers she can move things with her mind. At first she does nothing evil with it, and still tries to get accepted, and manages to do so. But then after a cruel prank involving pig blood, she's now out for human blood. Everyone dies, and this evil she finally unleashes leads to her demise, just like any other tragic character. This is easily my favorite film by director Brian De Palma, and my favorite film based on a Stephen King story. This melodramatic piece of genius never stops satisfying me, and just gets better and better every time I watch it. I highly recommend this to all who are unfortunate enough to have not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly the best horror movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I had not read the book before the film and I was only watching because I had seen the trailer for the upcoming remake. So I started it with no expectations at all and just had nothing better to do. Now down to the review. Right from the beginning this movie entices you in with a lovely period scene in a shower. I had no idea that this was going to happen and was quite surprised because it was handled very well and the actresses were not sexualised by Brian De Palma at all. Next was the entrance of Carrie's not so terrifying mother played by Piper Laurie. Maybe when this came out in 1974 she was scary, but now she's more....really really funny. This is really the only bad thing I can think of about the movie, with the exception of a pointless sex scene later. The next 40 minutes of the movie run pretty smoothly containing simple camera work and medium acting, with the occasional completely pointless sex scene. To make it even worse it has John Travolta in it! But then about 50 minutes in the prom scene arrives which I have already read about on Rotten Tomatoes and is in my opinion....actually not in my opinion IT'S A FACT! One of the most awesome movie scenes ever! Which is surprising because the special effects are a bit dodgy, but I won't deduct points for that because it was the best for the time. After Carrie has awesomely killed a gazabillion people at the prom she decides to go home and change into her pyjamas, which was bit weird considering she had just murdered loads of her classmates. But I won't deduct points for that because it's probably something to do with her telekinesis/puberty experience. Then her mum (who is one of my favourite unintentionally funny characters of all time) stabs her in the back LITERALLY! while they are praying, another reason why I'm atheist folks. Overall CARRIE is one of my favourite movies of all time. Possibly the best horror movie I have ever seen. Starting off at 10 (obviously) I minus 1 point for Piper Laurie being unintentionally hilarious. Then minus 0.3 points for a pointless sex scene. And finally minus 0.2 points for Carrie killing loads of people then going home as if nothing has happened. So I give Carrie- 8.5 out of 10 and 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Toronto85
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shy young girl gets back at her high school bullies using telekinetic powers in 'Carrie'. Carrie White is graduating high school, yet has no one to take her to the prom. She has no friends and all of the girls at school pick on her constantly. On top of all that, her mother is a religious nut who emotionally and physically abuses her at home. After picking on Carrie, fellow classmate Sue Snell decides to make it up to her by having her own boyfriend Tommy ask Carrie to the prom. After much reluctance, Tommy asks her out and they head off for the big night. The bullies fix it so that Tommy/Carrie are picked as king and queen in order for pig's blood to land right on the poor girl. That's when Carrie loses control and all HELL breaks loose at the high school. 'Carrie' is an amazing fantasy/horror film. Director Brian De Palma does such a good job with 'Carrie'. We get the flashes of the magical prom mixed in with Kris planning to dump the pig's blood over Carrie. The plot of the shy girl getting back at her bullies is a satisfying one, but with the added idea of telekinesis makes an even more exciting movie. The acting was really well done by everyone! Sissy Spacek puts in a good job as the lead Carrie, Piper Laurie is convincing as Carrie's crazed religious mother, and I REALLY thought Amy Irving was wonderful as Sue Snell. John Travolta, PJ Soles and Nancy Allen were great too as the villains. All around, a really good cast. It's always fun to see bullies get theirs in movies, but 'Carrie' takes it up a notch. I'd recommend this for sure to every horror fan. It's well acted, got a great cast and tells a pretty satisfying but sad story. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more than a film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    each adaptation of Stephen King novels is a delicate action. because , more than expectation of readers, important is the vision of director. and, sure, the cast. Carrie is out of this law. because it is not part of an genre or expectation in ordinary sense. it is a classic but not is its virtue. it is extraordinary expression of Sissy Spacek performance but not is the essential part. because, out of definitions, it is a mirror. the horror side is only trace of a profound tragedy who defines our world. the blood, the expression of Carrie face, the shadow of mother, the end, all represents images for ordinary state of each of us. it is so human, so cruel in manner to expose the deep truth about society than it is not, in time, only a good/extraordinary/admirable movie, it is a warning. and clear mirror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent horror mystery thriller! 8!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen many movies based on books written by Stephen King. In fact, I would consider myself a King's fan if I had read, at least, one of the numerous books he has written. "Carrie" is one of the best of them I saw. King's traits are very visible in this story: his sense of humour, horror, supernatural elements, mystery, drama, good performances, etc. The fact that John Travolta acted in the movie and that Brian de Palma directed it made me wish to watch "Carrie". Moreover, I am looking forward to seeing its remake. This movie is wonderfully directed with the right pace and duration. Brian de Palma did a very entertaining job with a very good script. The story is about a teenage girl who has telekinetic abilities and is bullied by her schoolmates. She lacks of a social life and is not like most teenagers. Moreover, she lives with her mother, who is a very possessive and mad women left by his husband. I prefer not to tell anything else about the plot not to spoil. The cast is mainly composed by Sissy Spacek, Piper Laurie and John Travolta. Sissy Spacek delivered a solid performance, maybe, a little bit overacted. The performances are very correct. The story is original and the capacity of entertainment is really high. The plot and the performances are the strongest points of this movie. There are several shocking scenes which are very amazing. In conclusion, this is a must-see for those like the stories from King. 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect cinema classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombiefan89
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't really even consider Carrie a horror movie. Sissy Spacek was just to adorable to find threatening, even when she went fully homicidal. Everything she did felt justified. However, if I had to say the biggest issue with the film was the ending. It made no sense at all. Why did they blame Carrie for the gym catching on fire? How did they know Carrie didn't die in the gym with everyone else? There were no survivors except the two antagonists, but they died shortly after. Let's say there were survivors, Did they all unanimously accept that Carrie had psychic powers and caused the fire? Why and how did they blame Carrie? It was like Light Yagami in Death Note, who could kill people by writing their name down and thinking of their face as they do it. They accepted that a notebook could kill people WAY too easily! No court on Earth would have convicted Light Yagami of being "Kira" because there was NO solid proof! I had a complete opposite reaction to the "surprise ending", I would have immediately started digging her out, trying to save her life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Milito
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1974, legendary horror writer Stephen King published his first novel, titled Carrie, which launched him into the fame that he has today. Even today, the story is recognized as one of the best Stephen King novels, but also as one of the greatest horror stories ever told. Two years after publication, director Brian De Palma would adapt this famous story for the big screen. The result was a fantastic horror movie with absolutely phenomenal acting performances and a chilling storyline that leaves an impact on everyone who witnesses it. Carrie White is a shy, socially awkward teenager who is subject to frequent bullying at Bates High School. Carrie is one of the girls who wears her hair down in order to cover her face. She lives at home with her mother Margaret, a mentally unstable Christian fundamentalist. Carrie is often subject to punishments from her mother, whether it's being forced into a closet to pray or repeating verses from the Bible over and over. Carrie is special though: she has the ability of telekinesis, meaning she can movie objects with her mind. After humiliating Carrie in the girls locker room, the more popular girls at the school, including Sue Snell, Chris Hargensen, and Norma Watson, are sentenced to a week long detention for their inappropriate behavior towards Carrie. Feeling bad for what she did, Sue decides to get her boyfriend, Tommy Ross, to ask Carrie to the senior prom in order to make up for the embarrassment. Reluctantly, Carrie accepts. However, when something goes down at the prom, the night turns from one of happiness and fun into one of pure horror. The story is chilling and unsettling without being a full-fledged slasher movie. What's great about the movie is the way takes the time to slow down and flesh out Carrie's story, giving a chance for viewers to realize just how terrible Carrie's life really is. As it progresses, Carrie becomes a more relatable and sympathetic character, which makes the climax all the more saddening and even understandable to a certain degree. The performances in Carrie are top-notch all around the board. Sissy Spacek, in an Oscar-nominated performance, plays Carrie extremely well. She plays all the emotions that Carrie faces in an extremely believable way, almost making it hard to tell if she's actually acting. Spacek also has a sort of physical appearance where she can match the qualities needed for the character of Carrie, but also where she is undeniably beautiful when she cleans herself up for the prom. Piper Laurie sort of revived her career with her performance as Margaret, garnering her an Oscar nomination also. She felt over-the-top at times, but Laurie's performance is undeniably unsettling, especially in the scenes where she physically abuses Carrie. Rounding out the supporting cast is Betty Buckley as Miss Collins, the gym teacher in charge of the detention and a comforting figure for Carrie, and John Travolta, in a breakthrough performance as Chris' boyfriend. There are a few aspects of Carrie that feel like they haven't aged well, such as the strange blurry lighting in some of the outdoor shots, but it's not enough to hinder it's greatness. The performances are solid, especially the Oscar-nominated performances from Spacek and Laurie. The story was well-written and well-executed, and offers some deep themes about bullying. Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Felt Bad For Poor Carrie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Stephen King's first novel, this film tells the story of a shy teenage girl named Carrie White(Sissy Spacek in an unforgettable performance) who is mocked and humiliated by her cruel schoolmates, though one of them takes pity on her, and has her popular boyfriend(William Katt) ask Carrie to the prom, which she accepts, but tragically Carrie's mother(Piper Laurie, quite good) is a psychopathic religious zealot who keeps Carrie locked in the closet as punishment for her "sins", but Carrie defies her, though two evil expelled classmates(played by Nancy Allen & John Travolta) plot a cruel prank on her at the prom, which pushes Carrie over the edge, and makes her use her latent telekinetic powers in merciless revenge... Fine performances and script compensate for some exploitive and obvious scare tactics in this memorable film, which elicits such sympathy for this unjustly put-upon girl that her rage at the end is understandable, though of course the poor girl is doomed...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A loose adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie was Stephen King's first novel and easily considered one of his best. When it became a hit a film adaptation was practically inevitable. Carrie is considered one of the most important horror films of the 70s. Carrie White (Sissy Spacek) is an isolated high school student with no friends and a fundamentalist Christian mum, Margaret (Piper Laurie). After being humiliated when she gets her first period in the school shower her telekinetic powers start to develop and heighten when under stress. Sue Snell (Amy Irving) feels guilty due to the incident in the shower where she joined in with mob and wants to make it up to Carrie by getting her boyfriend, Tommy (William Katt) to take Carrie to the prom. But the lead bully, Chris Hargensen (Nancy Allen) wants revenge against Carrie, blaming her for not letting her go to the prom and with her delinquent boyfriend, Billy (John Travolta) plan to humiliate Carrie in the most public and sadistic way possible. Carrie is an excellent novel, a short, taut little affair that is a breeze of a read. Some of the elements from the novel would have been hard to translate into because of the structure of the novel: mainly the extracts from the White Commission, The Shadow Exploded and Sue Snell's diary. Other scenes were cut because of expense, i.e. the explosion of the petrol station. But this is an adaptation that does make some big changes and cuts from the novel. Some include not getting to see Chris' father threatening to sue and ends up seeing what his daughter really is, cutting out Sue's pregnancy to small things like Carrie saying her father left her mother instead of dying in an industrial accident. Plus the sociological elements were cut out, looking at the impact of the aftermath of the Carrie incident which I thought was some of the most interesting stuff in the novel. The big positive with the film is the casting of Spacek: she was a terrific as Carrie, having the right look for seemingly being a little weird but have a unique beauty when she is at the prom. She was able to convey the shy, awkwardness of a character who is beaten emotionally at home and at school and shows a psychopathic rage with the look with her eyes when the pigs blood fell on her. The rest of the cast were solid, like Allen playing the bitchy, self-centred bully, Travolta as the abusive boyfriend, Katt and Irving as the high school students who want to do the right thing. Betty Buckley was excellent as the friendly teacher who wants to support and protect Carrie and Laurie did a good job as Carrie's fundamentalist mother. But Sydney Lassick was really hammy and out of place as an English teacher who wasn't even in the book. The big highlight of the film was the prom scene when the pig's blood felt on Carrie goes into a psychopathic rage, locking the doors with her mind and sets out killing everyone. Director Brian De Palma was able highlight the build-up and the tension and then the terror of Carrie's killing. De Palma was able to make the sequence with a unique style using split screens to show different actions happening at the same time and De Palma used silences, making us lip-read what people are saying (though it is very obvious). It is excellent sequence. During the film they are plenty of musical cues when Carrie using her powers, partly due to the limits of special effects, but sometimes the violin streaks from Psycho which was a distraction. Carrie is a very well-acted film that had some stand out sequences and excellent acting, but it is too loose of an adaptation for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Modern Tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nc-holdsworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Carrie again for the first time in years, having seen the trailer for the remake with Chloe thingybob from the god awful Kick Ass. Its a tragic tale about a shy girl called Carrie White who seems to get abuse and bullying by almost everyone she meets, her mother, classmates even annoying kids on bikes. Her mother is a religious nut case, therefore she has had no knowledge or understanding of the world and is left open to bullying from other kids due to the fact she is different. What no one knows is how different Carrie really is. She is already realising she can move things with her mind at the start of the movie, therefore its not dragged down with learning to use her 'powers' etc and instead concentrates on the story. For the story is not only about her ability, its an all too human tale of someone looking for acceptance, to be loved and its this that makes it so memorable. Its a very cruel movie for several reasons. First of all the bullying is quite nasty and humiliating, secondly then with help of one of the few sympathetic class mates Carrie gets her dream date for the prom (after initial scepticism) and during the prom she is genuinely happy for once in her life and these scenes are very touching. As a viewer we know its not going to end there however, we know the fall will come and DePalma expertly creates the ominous atmosphere before the bucket of blood comes crashing down all over her. What comes next is a split screen massacre as Carrie wipes out almost the entire Prom Night goers in a rage fuelled inferno. Carrie is a film that has that magic mix. DePalma's sure direction is excellent (even the quirky touches such as the fast forward work for me) Sissy Spacek, words are not enough to explain her shattering performance. It really is something. I've always been a fan of Pino Donnaggio and his work here is one, if not the best soundtrack he has ever done. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Magical Melodrama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zacharyduresky
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie is a film that makes you feel so many different emotions. Scenes like the infamous "period" scene will make you feel disgusted. The gym detention scene will make you laugh. The dance between Carrie and Tommy will touch you're heart. The climactic scene where Carrie unleashes her powers and kills everyone will have haunt your nightmares. There's drama, romance, suspense, comedy, eroticism and horror, everything you cold possibly want. But at its core, this film is a melodrama. This is a melodrama about an abused and taunted teenage girl who just wants love and acceptance. Then she discovers she can move things with her mind. At first she does nothing evil with it, and still tries to get accepted, and manages to do so. But then after a cruel prank involving pig blood, she's now out for human blood. Everyone dies, and this evil she finally unleashes leads to her demise, just like any other tragic character. This is easily my favorite film by director Brian De Palma, and my favorite film based on a Stephen King story. This melodramatic piece of genius never stops satisfying me, and just gets better and better every time I watch it. I highly recommend this to all who are unfortunate enough to have not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly the best horror movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I had not read the book before the film and I was only watching because I had seen the trailer for the upcoming remake. So I started it with no expectations at all and just had nothing better to do. Now down to the review. Right from the beginning this movie entices you in with a lovely period scene in a shower. I had no idea that this was going to happen and was quite surprised because it was handled very well and the actresses were not sexualised by Brian De Palma at all. Next was the entrance of Carrie's not so terrifying mother played by Piper Laurie. Maybe when this came out in 1974 she was scary, but now she's more....really really funny. This is really the only bad thing I can think of about the movie, with the exception of a pointless sex scene later. The next 40 minutes of the movie run pretty smoothly containing simple camera work and medium acting, with the occasional completely pointless sex scene. To make it even worse it has John Travolta in it! But then about 50 minutes in the prom scene arrives which I have already read about on Rotten Tomatoes and is in my opinion....actually not in my opinion IT'S A FACT! One of the most awesome movie scenes ever! Which is surprising because the special effects are a bit dodgy, but I won't deduct points for that because it was the best for the time. After Carrie has awesomely killed a gazabillion people at the prom she decides to go home and change into her pyjamas, which was bit weird considering she had just murdered loads of her classmates. But I won't deduct points for that because it's probably something to do with her telekinesis/puberty experience. Then her mum (who is one of my favourite unintentionally funny characters of all time) stabs her in the back LITERALLY! while they are praying, another reason why I'm atheist folks. Overall CARRIE is one of my favourite movies of all time. Possibly the best horror movie I have ever seen. Starting off at 10 (obviously) I minus 1 point for Piper Laurie being unintentionally hilarious. Then minus 0.3 points for a pointless sex scene. And finally minus 0.2 points for Carrie killing loads of people then going home as if nothing has happened. So I give Carrie- 8.5 out of 10 and 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Toronto85
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shy young girl gets back at her high school bullies using telekinetic powers in 'Carrie'. Carrie White is graduating high school, yet has no one to take her to the prom. She has no friends and all of the girls at school pick on her constantly. On top of all that, her mother is a religious nut who emotionally and physically abuses her at home. After picking on Carrie, fellow classmate Sue Snell decides to make it up to her by having her own boyfriend Tommy ask Carrie to the prom. After much reluctance, Tommy asks her out and they head off for the big night. The bullies fix it so that Tommy/Carrie are picked as king and queen in order for pig's blood to land right on the poor girl. That's when Carrie loses control and all HELL breaks loose at the high school. 'Carrie' is an amazing fantasy/horror film. Director Brian De Palma does such a good job with 'Carrie'. We get the flashes of the magical prom mixed in with Kris planning to dump the pig's blood over Carrie. The plot of the shy girl getting back at her bullies is a satisfying one, but with the added idea of telekinesis makes an even more exciting movie. The acting was really well done by everyone! Sissy Spacek puts in a good job as the lead Carrie, Piper Laurie is convincing as Carrie's crazed religious mother, and I REALLY thought Amy Irving was wonderful as Sue Snell. John Travolta, PJ Soles and Nancy Allen were great too as the villains. All around, a really good cast. It's always fun to see bullies get theirs in movies, but 'Carrie' takes it up a notch. I'd recommend this for sure to every horror fan. It's well acted, got a great cast and tells a pretty satisfying but sad story. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more than a film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    each adaptation of Stephen King novels is a delicate action. because , more than expectation of readers, important is the vision of director. and, sure, the cast. Carrie is out of this law. because it is not part of an genre or expectation in ordinary sense. it is a classic but not is its virtue. it is extraordinary expression of Sissy Spacek performance but not is the essential part. because, out of definitions, it is a mirror. the horror side is only trace of a profound tragedy who defines our world. the blood, the expression of Carrie face, the shadow of mother, the end, all represents images for ordinary state of each of us. it is so human, so cruel in manner to expose the deep truth about society than it is not, in time, only a good/extraordinary/admirable movie, it is a warning. and clear mirror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent horror mystery thriller! 8!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen many movies based on books written by Stephen King. In fact, I would consider myself a King's fan if I had read, at least, one of the numerous books he has written. "Carrie" is one of the best of them I saw. King's traits are very visible in this story: his sense of humour, horror, supernatural elements, mystery, drama, good performances, etc. The fact that John Travolta acted in the movie and that Brian de Palma directed it made me wish to watch "Carrie". Moreover, I am looking forward to seeing its remake. This movie is wonderfully directed with the right pace and duration. Brian de Palma did a very entertaining job with a very good script. The story is about a teenage girl who has telekinetic abilities and is bullied by her schoolmates. She lacks of a social life and is not like most teenagers. Moreover, she lives with her mother, who is a very possessive and mad women left by his husband. I prefer not to tell anything else about the plot not to spoil. The cast is mainly composed by Sissy Spacek, Piper Laurie and John Travolta. Sissy Spacek delivered a solid performance, maybe, a little bit overacted. The performances are very correct. The story is original and the capacity of entertainment is really high. The plot and the performances are the strongest points of this movie. There are several shocking scenes which are very amazing. In conclusion, this is a must-see for those like the stories from King. 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect cinema classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombiefan89
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't really even consider Carrie a horror movie. Sissy Spacek was just to adorable to find threatening, even when she went fully homicidal. Everything she did felt justified. However, if I had to say the biggest issue with the film was the ending. It made no sense at all. Why did they blame Carrie for the gym catching on fire? How did they know Carrie didn't die in the gym with everyone else? There were no survivors except the two antagonists, but they died shortly after. Let's say there were survivors, Did they all unanimously accept that Carrie had psychic powers and caused the fire? Why and how did they blame Carrie? It was like Light Yagami in Death Note, who could kill people by writing their name down and thinking of their face as they do it. They accepted that a notebook could kill people WAY too easily! No court on Earth would have convicted Light Yagami of being "Kira" because there was NO solid proof! I had a complete opposite reaction to the "surprise ending", I would have immediately started digging her out, trying to save her life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Milito
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1974, legendary horror writer Stephen King published his first novel, titled Carrie, which launched him into the fame that he has today. Even today, the story is recognized as one of the best Stephen King novels, but also as one of the greatest horror stories ever told. Two years after publication, director Brian De Palma would adapt this famous story for the big screen. The result was a fantastic horror movie with absolutely phenomenal acting performances and a chilling storyline that leaves an impact on everyone who witnesses it. Carrie White is a shy, socially awkward teenager who is subject to frequent bullying at Bates High School. Carrie is one of the girls who wears her hair down in order to cover her face. She lives at home with her mother Margaret, a mentally unstable Christian fundamentalist. Carrie is often subject to punishments from her mother, whether it's being forced into a closet to pray or repeating verses from the Bible over and over. Carrie is special though: she has the ability of telekinesis, meaning she can movie objects with her mind. After humiliating Carrie in the girls locker room, the more popular girls at the school, including Sue Snell, Chris Hargensen, and Norma Watson, are sentenced to a week long detention for their inappropriate behavior towards Carrie. Feeling bad for what she did, Sue decides to get her boyfriend, Tommy Ross, to ask Carrie to the senior prom in order to make up for the embarrassment. Reluctantly, Carrie accepts. However, when something goes down at the prom, the night turns from one of happiness and fun into one of pure horror. The story is chilling and unsettling without being a full-fledged slasher movie. What's great about the movie is the way takes the time to slow down and flesh out Carrie's story, giving a chance for viewers to realize just how terrible Carrie's life really is. As it progresses, Carrie becomes a more relatable and sympathetic character, which makes the climax all the more saddening and even understandable to a certain degree. The performances in Carrie are top-notch all around the board. Sissy Spacek, in an Oscar-nominated performance, plays Carrie extremely well. She plays all the emotions that Carrie faces in an extremely believable way, almost making it hard to tell if she's actually acting. Spacek also has a sort of physical appearance where she can match the qualities needed for the character of Carrie, but also where she is undeniably beautiful when she cleans herself up for the prom. Piper Laurie sort of revived her career with her performance as Margaret, garnering her an Oscar nomination also. She felt over-the-top at times, but Laurie's performance is undeniably unsettling, especially in the scenes where she physically abuses Carrie. Rounding out the supporting cast is Betty Buckley as Miss Collins, the gym teacher in charge of the detention and a comforting figure for Carrie, and John Travolta, in a breakthrough performance as Chris' boyfriend. There are a few aspects of Carrie that feel like they haven't aged well, such as the strange blurry lighting in some of the outdoor shots, but it's not enough to hinder it's greatness. The performances are solid, especially the Oscar-nominated performances from Spacek and Laurie. The story was well-written and well-executed, and offers some deep themes about bullying. Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Felt Bad For Poor Carrie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Stephen King's first novel, this film tells the story of a shy teenage girl named Carrie White(Sissy Spacek in an unforgettable performance) who is mocked and humiliated by her cruel schoolmates, though one of them takes pity on her, and has her popular boyfriend(William Katt) ask Carrie to the prom, which she accepts, but tragically Carrie's mother(Piper Laurie, quite good) is a psychopathic religious zealot who keeps Carrie locked in the closet as punishment for her "sins", but Carrie defies her, though two evil expelled classmates(played by Nancy Allen & John Travolta) plot a cruel prank on her at the prom, which pushes Carrie over the edge, and makes her use her latent telekinetic powers in merciless revenge... Fine performances and script compensate for some exploitive and obvious scare tactics in this memorable film, which elicits such sympathy for this unjustly put-upon girl that her rage at the end is understandable, though of course the poor girl is doomed...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A loose adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie was Stephen King's first novel and easily considered one of his best. When it became a hit a film adaptation was practically inevitable. Carrie is considered one of the most important horror films of the 70s. Carrie White (Sissy Spacek) is an isolated high school student with no friends and a fundamentalist Christian mum, Margaret (Piper Laurie). After being humiliated when she gets her first period in the school shower her telekinetic powers start to develop and heighten when under stress. Sue Snell (Amy Irving) feels guilty due to the incident in the shower where she joined in with mob and wants to make it up to Carrie by getting her boyfriend, Tommy (William Katt) to take Carrie to the prom. But the lead bully, Chris Hargensen (Nancy Allen) wants revenge against Carrie, blaming her for not letting her go to the prom and with her delinquent boyfriend, Billy (John Travolta) plan to humiliate Carrie in the most public and sadistic way possible. Carrie is an excellent novel, a short, taut little affair that is a breeze of a read. Some of the elements from the novel would have been hard to translate into because of the structure of the novel: mainly the extracts from the White Commission, The Shadow Exploded and Sue Snell's diary. Other scenes were cut because of expense, i.e. the explosion of the petrol station. But this is an adaptation that does make some big changes and cuts from the novel. Some include not getting to see Chris' father threatening to sue and ends up seeing what his daughter really is, cutting out Sue's pregnancy to small things like Carrie saying her father left her mother instead of dying in an industrial accident. Plus the sociological elements were cut out, looking at the impact of the aftermath of the Carrie incident which I thought was some of the most interesting stuff in the novel. The big positive with the film is the casting of Spacek: she was a terrific as Carrie, having the right look for seemingly being a little weird but have a unique beauty when she is at the prom. She was able to convey the shy, awkwardness of a character who is beaten emotionally at home and at school and shows a psychopathic rage with the look with her eyes when the pigs blood fell on her. The rest of the cast were solid, like Allen playing the bitchy, self-centred bully, Travolta as the abusive boyfriend, Katt and Irving as the high school students who want to do the right thing. Betty Buckley was excellent as the friendly teacher who wants to support and protect Carrie and Laurie did a good job as Carrie's fundamentalist mother. But Sydney Lassick was really hammy and out of place as an English teacher who wasn't even in the book. The big highlight of the film was the prom scene when the pig's blood felt on Carrie goes into a psychopathic rage, locking the doors with her mind and sets out killing everyone. Director Brian De Palma was able highlight the build-up and the tension and then the terror of Carrie's killing. De Palma was able to make the sequence with a unique style using split screens to show different actions happening at the same time and De Palma used silences, making us lip-read what people are saying (though it is very obvious). It is excellent sequence. During the film they are plenty of musical cues when Carrie using her powers, partly due to the limits of special effects, but sometimes the violin streaks from Psycho which was a distraction. Carrie is a very well-acted film that had some stand out sequences and excellent acting, but it is too loose of an adaptation for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Modern Tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nc-holdsworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Carrie again for the first time in years, having seen the trailer for the remake with Chloe thingybob from the god awful Kick Ass. Its a tragic tale about a shy girl called Carrie White who seems to get abuse and bullying by almost everyone she meets, her mother, classmates even annoying kids on bikes. Her mother is a religious nut case, therefore she has had no knowledge or understanding of the world and is left open to bullying from other kids due to the fact she is different. What no one knows is how different Carrie really is. She is already realising she can move things with her mind at the start of the movie, therefore its not dragged down with learning to use her 'powers' etc and instead concentrates on the story. For the story is not only about her ability, its an all too human tale of someone looking for acceptance, to be loved and its this that makes it so memorable. Its a very cruel movie for several reasons. First of all the bullying is quite nasty and humiliating, secondly then with help of one of the few sympathetic class mates Carrie gets her dream date for the prom (after initial scepticism) and during the prom she is genuinely happy for once in her life and these scenes are very touching. As a viewer we know its not going to end there however, we know the fall will come and DePalma expertly creates the ominous atmosphere before the bucket of blood comes crashing down all over her. What comes next is a split screen massacre as Carrie wipes out almost the entire Prom Night goers in a rage fuelled inferno. Carrie is a film that has that magic mix. DePalma's sure direction is excellent (even the quirky touches such as the fast forward work for me) Sissy Spacek, words are not enough to explain her shattering performance. It really is something. I've always been a fan of Pino Donnaggio and his work here is one, if not the best soundtrack he has ever done. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Magical Melodrama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zacharyduresky
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie is a film that makes you feel so many different emotions. Scenes like the infamous "period" scene will make you feel disgusted. The gym detention scene will make you laugh. The dance between Carrie and Tommy will touch you're heart. The climactic scene where Carrie unleashes her powers and kills everyone will have haunt your nightmares. There's drama, romance, suspense, comedy, eroticism and horror, everything you cold possibly want. But at its core, this film is a melodrama. This is a melodrama about an abused and taunted teenage girl who just wants love and acceptance. Then she discovers she can move things with her mind. At first she does nothing evil with it, and still tries to get accepted, and manages to do so. But then after a cruel prank involving pig blood, she's now out for human blood. Everyone dies, and this evil she finally unleashes leads to her demise, just like any other tragic character. This is easily my favorite film by director Brian De Palma, and my favorite film based on a Stephen King story. This melodramatic piece of genius never stops satisfying me, and just gets better and better every time I watch it. I highly recommend this to all who are unfortunate enough to have not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly the best horror movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I had not read the book before the film and I was only watching because I had seen the trailer for the upcoming remake. So I started it with no expectations at all and just had nothing better to do. Now down to the review. Right from the beginning this movie entices you in with a lovely period scene in a shower. I had no idea that this was going to happen and was quite surprised because it was handled very well and the actresses were not sexualised by Brian De Palma at all. Next was the entrance of Carrie's not so terrifying mother played by Piper Laurie. Maybe when this came out in 1974 she was scary, but now she's more....really really funny. This is really the only bad thing I can think of about the movie, with the exception of a pointless sex scene later. The next 40 minutes of the movie run pretty smoothly containing simple camera work and medium acting, with the occasional completely pointless sex scene. To make it even worse it has John Travolta in it! But then about 50 minutes in the prom scene arrives which I have already read about on Rotten Tomatoes and is in my opinion....actually not in my opinion IT'S A FACT! One of the most awesome movie scenes ever! Which is surprising because the special effects are a bit dodgy, but I won't deduct points for that because it was the best for the time. After Carrie has awesomely killed a gazabillion people at the prom she decides to go home and change into her pyjamas, which was bit weird considering she had just murdered loads of her classmates. But I won't deduct points for that because it's probably something to do with her telekinesis/puberty experience. Then her mum (who is one of my favourite unintentionally funny characters of all time) stabs her in the back LITERALLY! while they are praying, another reason why I'm atheist folks. Overall CARRIE is one of my favourite movies of all time. Possibly the best horror movie I have ever seen. Starting off at 10 (obviously) I minus 1 point for Piper Laurie being unintentionally hilarious. Then minus 0.3 points for a pointless sex scene. And finally minus 0.2 points for Carrie killing loads of people then going home as if nothing has happened. So I give Carrie- 8.5 out of 10 and 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Toronto85
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shy young girl gets back at her high school bullies using telekinetic powers in 'Carrie'. Carrie White is graduating high school, yet has no one to take her to the prom. She has no friends and all of the girls at school pick on her constantly. On top of all that, her mother is a religious nut who emotionally and physically abuses her at home. After picking on Carrie, fellow classmate Sue Snell decides to make it up to her by having her own boyfriend Tommy ask Carrie to the prom. After much reluctance, Tommy asks her out and they head off for the big night. The bullies fix it so that Tommy/Carrie are picked as king and queen in order for pig's blood to land right on the poor girl. That's when Carrie loses control and all HELL breaks loose at the high school. 'Carrie' is an amazing fantasy/horror film. Director Brian De Palma does such a good job with 'Carrie'. We get the flashes of the magical prom mixed in with Kris planning to dump the pig's blood over Carrie. The plot of the shy girl getting back at her bullies is a satisfying one, but with the added idea of telekinesis makes an even more exciting movie. The acting was really well done by everyone! Sissy Spacek puts in a good job as the lead Carrie, Piper Laurie is convincing as Carrie's crazed religious mother, and I REALLY thought Amy Irving was wonderful as Sue Snell. John Travolta, PJ Soles and Nancy Allen were great too as the villains. All around, a really good cast. It's always fun to see bullies get theirs in movies, but 'Carrie' takes it up a notch. I'd recommend this for sure to every horror fan. It's well acted, got a great cast and tells a pretty satisfying but sad story. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more than a film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    each adaptation of Stephen King novels is a delicate action. because , more than expectation of readers, important is the vision of director. and, sure, the cast. Carrie is out of this law. because it is not part of an genre or expectation in ordinary sense. it is a classic but not is its virtue. it is extraordinary expression of Sissy Spacek performance but not is the essential part. because, out of definitions, it is a mirror. the horror side is only trace of a profound tragedy who defines our world. the blood, the expression of Carrie face, the shadow of mother, the end, all represents images for ordinary state of each of us. it is so human, so cruel in manner to expose the deep truth about society than it is not, in time, only a good/extraordinary/admirable movie, it is a warning. and clear mirror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent horror mystery thriller! 8!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen many movies based on books written by Stephen King. In fact, I would consider myself a King's fan if I had read, at least, one of the numerous books he has written. "Carrie" is one of the best of them I saw. King's traits are very visible in this story: his sense of humour, horror, supernatural elements, mystery, drama, good performances, etc. The fact that John Travolta acted in the movie and that Brian de Palma directed it made me wish to watch "Carrie". Moreover, I am looking forward to seeing its remake. This movie is wonderfully directed with the right pace and duration. Brian de Palma did a very entertaining job with a very good script. The story is about a teenage girl who has telekinetic abilities and is bullied by her schoolmates. She lacks of a social life and is not like most teenagers. Moreover, she lives with her mother, who is a very possessive and mad women left by his husband. I prefer not to tell anything else about the plot not to spoil. The cast is mainly composed by Sissy Spacek, Piper Laurie and John Travolta. Sissy Spacek delivered a solid performance, maybe, a little bit overacted. The performances are very correct. The story is original and the capacity of entertainment is really high. The plot and the performances are the strongest points of this movie. There are several shocking scenes which are very amazing. In conclusion, this is a must-see for those like the stories from King. 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect cinema classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombiefan89
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't really even consider Carrie a horror movie. Sissy Spacek was just to adorable to find threatening, even when she went fully homicidal. Everything she did felt justified. However, if I had to say the biggest issue with the film was the ending. It made no sense at all. Why did they blame Carrie for the gym catching on fire? How did they know Carrie didn't die in the gym with everyone else? There were no survivors except the two antagonists, but they died shortly after. Let's say there were survivors, Did they all unanimously accept that Carrie had psychic powers and caused the fire? Why and how did they blame Carrie? It was like Light Yagami in Death Note, who could kill people by writing their name down and thinking of their face as they do it. They accepted that a notebook could kill people WAY too easily! No court on Earth would have convicted Light Yagami of being "Kira" because there was NO solid proof! I had a complete opposite reaction to the "surprise ending", I would have immediately started digging her out, trying to save her life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Milito
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1974, legendary horror writer Stephen King published his first novel, titled Carrie, which launched him into the fame that he has today. Even today, the story is recognized as one of the best Stephen King novels, but also as one of the greatest horror stories ever told. Two years after publication, director Brian De Palma would adapt this famous story for the big screen. The result was a fantastic horror movie with absolutely phenomenal acting performances and a chilling storyline that leaves an impact on everyone who witnesses it. Carrie White is a shy, socially awkward teenager who is subject to frequent bullying at Bates High School. Carrie is one of the girls who wears her hair down in order to cover her face. She lives at home with her mother Margaret, a mentally unstable Christian fundamentalist. Carrie is often subject to punishments from her mother, whether it's being forced into a closet to pray or repeating verses from the Bible over and over. Carrie is special though: she has the ability of telekinesis, meaning she can movie objects with her mind. After humiliating Carrie in the girls locker room, the more popular girls at the school, including Sue Snell, Chris Hargensen, and Norma Watson, are sentenced to a week long detention for their inappropriate behavior towards Carrie. Feeling bad for what she did, Sue decides to get her boyfriend, Tommy Ross, to ask Carrie to the senior prom in order to make up for the embarrassment. Reluctantly, Carrie accepts. However, when something goes down at the prom, the night turns from one of happiness and fun into one of pure horror. The story is chilling and unsettling without being a full-fledged slasher movie. What's great about the movie is the way takes the time to slow down and flesh out Carrie's story, giving a chance for viewers to realize just how terrible Carrie's life really is. As it progresses, Carrie becomes a more relatable and sympathetic character, which makes the climax all the more saddening and even understandable to a certain degree. The performances in Carrie are top-notch all around the board. Sissy Spacek, in an Oscar-nominated performance, plays Carrie extremely well. She plays all the emotions that Carrie faces in an extremely believable way, almost making it hard to tell if she's actually acting. Spacek also has a sort of physical appearance where she can match the qualities needed for the character of Carrie, but also where she is undeniably beautiful when she cleans herself up for the prom. Piper Laurie sort of revived her career with her performance as Margaret, garnering her an Oscar nomination also. She felt over-the-top at times, but Laurie's performance is undeniably unsettling, especially in the scenes where she physically abuses Carrie. Rounding out the supporting cast is Betty Buckley as Miss Collins, the gym teacher in charge of the detention and a comforting figure for Carrie, and John Travolta, in a breakthrough performance as Chris' boyfriend. There are a few aspects of Carrie that feel like they haven't aged well, such as the strange blurry lighting in some of the outdoor shots, but it's not enough to hinder it's greatness. The performances are solid, especially the Oscar-nominated performances from Spacek and Laurie. The story was well-written and well-executed, and offers some deep themes about bullying. Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Felt Bad For Poor Carrie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Stephen King's first novel, this film tells the story of a shy teenage girl named Carrie White(Sissy Spacek in an unforgettable performance) who is mocked and humiliated by her cruel schoolmates, though one of them takes pity on her, and has her popular boyfriend(William Katt) ask Carrie to the prom, which she accepts, but tragically Carrie's mother(Piper Laurie, quite good) is a psychopathic religious zealot who keeps Carrie locked in the closet as punishment for her "sins", but Carrie defies her, though two evil expelled classmates(played by Nancy Allen & John Travolta) plot a cruel prank on her at the prom, which pushes Carrie over the edge, and makes her use her latent telekinetic powers in merciless revenge... Fine performances and script compensate for some exploitive and obvious scare tactics in this memorable film, which elicits such sympathy for this unjustly put-upon girl that her rage at the end is understandable, though of course the poor girl is doomed...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A loose adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie was Stephen King's first novel and easily considered one of his best. When it became a hit a film adaptation was practically inevitable. Carrie is considered one of the most important horror films of the 70s. Carrie White (Sissy Spacek) is an isolated high school student with no friends and a fundamentalist Christian mum, Margaret (Piper Laurie). After being humiliated when she gets her first period in the school shower her telekinetic powers start to develop and heighten when under stress. Sue Snell (Amy Irving) feels guilty due to the incident in the shower where she joined in with mob and wants to make it up to Carrie by getting her boyfriend, Tommy (William Katt) to take Carrie to the prom. But the lead bully, Chris Hargensen (Nancy Allen) wants revenge against Carrie, blaming her for not letting her go to the prom and with her delinquent boyfriend, Billy (John Travolta) plan to humiliate Carrie in the most public and sadistic way possible. Carrie is an excellent novel, a short, taut little affair that is a breeze of a read. Some of the elements from the novel would have been hard to translate into because of the structure of the novel: mainly the extracts from the White Commission, The Shadow Exploded and Sue Snell's diary. Other scenes were cut because of expense, i.e. the explosion of the petrol station. But this is an adaptation that does make some big changes and cuts from the novel. Some include not getting to see Chris' father threatening to sue and ends up seeing what his daughter really is, cutting out Sue's pregnancy to small things like Carrie saying her father left her mother instead of dying in an industrial accident. Plus the sociological elements were cut out, looking at the impact of the aftermath of the Carrie incident which I thought was some of the most interesting stuff in the novel. The big positive with the film is the casting of Spacek: she was a terrific as Carrie, having the right look for seemingly being a little weird but have a unique beauty when she is at the prom. She was able to convey the shy, awkwardness of a character who is beaten emotionally at home and at school and shows a psychopathic rage with the look with her eyes when the pigs blood fell on her. The rest of the cast were solid, like Allen playing the bitchy, self-centred bully, Travolta as the abusive boyfriend, Katt and Irving as the high school students who want to do the right thing. Betty Buckley was excellent as the friendly teacher who wants to support and protect Carrie and Laurie did a good job as Carrie's fundamentalist mother. But Sydney Lassick was really hammy and out of place as an English teacher who wasn't even in the book. The big highlight of the film was the prom scene when the pig's blood felt on Carrie goes into a psychopathic rage, locking the doors with her mind and sets out killing everyone. Director Brian De Palma was able highlight the build-up and the tension and then the terror of Carrie's killing. De Palma was able to make the sequence with a unique style using split screens to show different actions happening at the same time and De Palma used silences, making us lip-read what people are saying (though it is very obvious). It is excellent sequence. During the film they are plenty of musical cues when Carrie using her powers, partly due to the limits of special effects, but sometimes the violin streaks from Psycho which was a distraction. Carrie is a very well-acted film that had some stand out sequences and excellent acting, but it is too loose of an adaptation for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Modern Tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nc-holdsworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Carrie again for the first time in years, having seen the trailer for the remake with Chloe thingybob from the god awful Kick Ass. Its a tragic tale about a shy girl called Carrie White who seems to get abuse and bullying by almost everyone she meets, her mother, classmates even annoying kids on bikes. Her mother is a religious nut case, therefore she has had no knowledge or understanding of the world and is left open to bullying from other kids due to the fact she is different. What no one knows is how different Carrie really is. She is already realising she can move things with her mind at the start of the movie, therefore its not dragged down with learning to use her 'powers' etc and instead concentrates on the story. For the story is not only about her ability, its an all too human tale of someone looking for acceptance, to be loved and its this that makes it so memorable. Its a very cruel movie for several reasons. First of all the bullying is quite nasty and humiliating, secondly then with help of one of the few sympathetic class mates Carrie gets her dream date for the prom (after initial scepticism) and during the prom she is genuinely happy for once in her life and these scenes are very touching. As a viewer we know its not going to end there however, we know the fall will come and DePalma expertly creates the ominous atmosphere before the bucket of blood comes crashing down all over her. What comes next is a split screen massacre as Carrie wipes out almost the entire Prom Night goers in a rage fuelled inferno. Carrie is a film that has that magic mix. DePalma's sure direction is excellent (even the quirky touches such as the fast forward work for me) Sissy Spacek, words are not enough to explain her shattering performance. It really is something. I've always been a fan of Pino Donnaggio and his work here is one, if not the best soundtrack he has ever done. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Magical Melodrama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zacharyduresky
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie is a film that makes you feel so many different emotions. Scenes like the infamous "period" scene will make you feel disgusted. The gym detention scene will make you laugh. The dance between Carrie and Tommy will touch you're heart. The climactic scene where Carrie unleashes her powers and kills everyone will have haunt your nightmares. There's drama, romance, suspense, comedy, eroticism and horror, everything you cold possibly want. But at its core, this film is a melodrama. This is a melodrama about an abused and taunted teenage girl who just wants love and acceptance. Then she discovers she can move things with her mind. At first she does nothing evil with it, and still tries to get accepted, and manages to do so. But then after a cruel prank involving pig blood, she's now out for human blood. Everyone dies, and this evil she finally unleashes leads to her demise, just like any other tragic character. This is easily my favorite film by director Brian De Palma, and my favorite film based on a Stephen King story. This melodramatic piece of genius never stops satisfying me, and just gets better and better every time I watch it. I highly recommend this to all who are unfortunate enough to have not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly the best horror movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I had not read the book before the film and I was only watching because I had seen the trailer for the upcoming remake. So I started it with no expectations at all and just had nothing better to do. Now down to the review. Right from the beginning this movie entices you in with a lovely period scene in a shower. I had no idea that this was going to happen and was quite surprised because it was handled very well and the actresses were not sexualised by Brian De Palma at all. Next was the entrance of Carrie's not so terrifying mother played by Piper Laurie. Maybe when this came out in 1974 she was scary, but now she's more....really really funny. This is really the only bad thing I can think of about the movie, with the exception of a pointless sex scene later. The next 40 minutes of the movie run pretty smoothly containing simple camera work and medium acting, with the occasional completely pointless sex scene. To make it even worse it has John Travolta in it! But then about 50 minutes in the prom scene arrives which I have already read about on Rotten Tomatoes and is in my opinion....actually not in my opinion IT'S A FACT! One of the most awesome movie scenes ever! Which is surprising because the special effects are a bit dodgy, but I won't deduct points for that because it was the best for the time. After Carrie has awesomely killed a gazabillion people at the prom she decides to go home and change into her pyjamas, which was bit weird considering she had just murdered loads of her classmates. But I won't deduct points for that because it's probably something to do with her telekinesis/puberty experience. Then her mum (who is one of my favourite unintentionally funny characters of all time) stabs her in the back LITERALLY! while they are praying, another reason why I'm atheist folks. Overall CARRIE is one of my favourite movies of all time. Possibly the best horror movie I have ever seen. Starting off at 10 (obviously) I minus 1 point for Piper Laurie being unintentionally hilarious. Then minus 0.3 points for a pointless sex scene. And finally minus 0.2 points for Carrie killing loads of people then going home as if nothing has happened. So I give Carrie- 8.5 out of 10 and 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Toronto85
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shy young girl gets back at her high school bullies using telekinetic powers in 'Carrie'. Carrie White is graduating high school, yet has no one to take her to the prom. She has no friends and all of the girls at school pick on her constantly. On top of all that, her mother is a religious nut who emotionally and physically abuses her at home. After picking on Carrie, fellow classmate Sue Snell decides to make it up to her by having her own boyfriend Tommy ask Carrie to the prom. After much reluctance, Tommy asks her out and they head off for the big night. The bullies fix it so that Tommy/Carrie are picked as king and queen in order for pig's blood to land right on the poor girl. That's when Carrie loses control and all HELL breaks loose at the high school. 'Carrie' is an amazing fantasy/horror film. Director Brian De Palma does such a good job with 'Carrie'. We get the flashes of the magical prom mixed in with Kris planning to dump the pig's blood over Carrie. The plot of the shy girl getting back at her bullies is a satisfying one, but with the added idea of telekinesis makes an even more exciting movie. The acting was really well done by everyone! Sissy Spacek puts in a good job as the lead Carrie, Piper Laurie is convincing as Carrie's crazed religious mother, and I REALLY thought Amy Irving was wonderful as Sue Snell. John Travolta, PJ Soles and Nancy Allen were great too as the villains. All around, a really good cast. It's always fun to see bullies get theirs in movies, but 'Carrie' takes it up a notch. I'd recommend this for sure to every horror fan. It's well acted, got a great cast and tells a pretty satisfying but sad story. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more than a film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    each adaptation of Stephen King novels is a delicate action. because , more than expectation of readers, important is the vision of director. and, sure, the cast. Carrie is out of this law. because it is not part of an genre or expectation in ordinary sense. it is a classic but not is its virtue. it is extraordinary expression of Sissy Spacek performance but not is the essential part. because, out of definitions, it is a mirror. the horror side is only trace of a profound tragedy who defines our world. the blood, the expression of Carrie face, the shadow of mother, the end, all represents images for ordinary state of each of us. it is so human, so cruel in manner to expose the deep truth about society than it is not, in time, only a good/extraordinary/admirable movie, it is a warning. and clear mirror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent horror mystery thriller! 8!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen many movies based on books written by Stephen King. In fact, I would consider myself a King's fan if I had read, at least, one of the numerous books he has written. "Carrie" is one of the best of them I saw. King's traits are very visible in this story: his sense of humour, horror, supernatural elements, mystery, drama, good performances, etc. The fact that John Travolta acted in the movie and that Brian de Palma directed it made me wish to watch "Carrie". Moreover, I am looking forward to seeing its remake. This movie is wonderfully directed with the right pace and duration. Brian de Palma did a very entertaining job with a very good script. The story is about a teenage girl who has telekinetic abilities and is bullied by her schoolmates. She lacks of a social life and is not like most teenagers. Moreover, she lives with her mother, who is a very possessive and mad women left by his husband. I prefer not to tell anything else about the plot not to spoil. The cast is mainly composed by Sissy Spacek, Piper Laurie and John Travolta. Sissy Spacek delivered a solid performance, maybe, a little bit overacted. The performances are very correct. The story is original and the capacity of entertainment is really high. The plot and the performances are the strongest points of this movie. There are several shocking scenes which are very amazing. In conclusion, this is a must-see for those like the stories from King. 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect cinema classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombiefan89
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't really even consider Carrie a horror movie. Sissy Spacek was just to adorable to find threatening, even when she went fully homicidal. Everything she did felt justified. However, if I had to say the biggest issue with the film was the ending. It made no sense at all. Why did they blame Carrie for the gym catching on fire? How did they know Carrie didn't die in the gym with everyone else? There were no survivors except the two antagonists, but they died shortly after. Let's say there were survivors, Did they all unanimously accept that Carrie had psychic powers and caused the fire? Why and how did they blame Carrie? It was like Light Yagami in Death Note, who could kill people by writing their name down and thinking of their face as they do it. They accepted that a notebook could kill people WAY too easily! No court on Earth would have convicted Light Yagami of being "Kira" because there was NO solid proof! I had a complete opposite reaction to the "surprise ending", I would have immediately started digging her out, trying to save her life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Milito
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1974, legendary horror writer Stephen King published his first novel, titled Carrie, which launched him into the fame that he has today. Even today, the story is recognized as one of the best Stephen King novels, but also as one of the greatest horror stories ever told. Two years after publication, director Brian De Palma would adapt this famous story for the big screen. The result was a fantastic horror movie with absolutely phenomenal acting performances and a chilling storyline that leaves an impact on everyone who witnesses it. Carrie White is a shy, socially awkward teenager who is subject to frequent bullying at Bates High School. Carrie is one of the girls who wears her hair down in order to cover her face. She lives at home with her mother Margaret, a mentally unstable Christian fundamentalist. Carrie is often subject to punishments from her mother, whether it's being forced into a closet to pray or repeating verses from the Bible over and over. Carrie is special though: she has the ability of telekinesis, meaning she can movie objects with her mind. After humiliating Carrie in the girls locker room, the more popular girls at the school, including Sue Snell, Chris Hargensen, and Norma Watson, are sentenced to a week long detention for their inappropriate behavior towards Carrie. Feeling bad for what she did, Sue decides to get her boyfriend, Tommy Ross, to ask Carrie to the senior prom in order to make up for the embarrassment. Reluctantly, Carrie accepts. However, when something goes down at the prom, the night turns from one of happiness and fun into one of pure horror. The story is chilling and unsettling without being a full-fledged slasher movie. What's great about the movie is the way takes the time to slow down and flesh out Carrie's story, giving a chance for viewers to realize just how terrible Carrie's life really is. As it progresses, Carrie becomes a more relatable and sympathetic character, which makes the climax all the more saddening and even understandable to a certain degree. The performances in Carrie are top-notch all around the board. Sissy Spacek, in an Oscar-nominated performance, plays Carrie extremely well. She plays all the emotions that Carrie faces in an extremely believable way, almost making it hard to tell if she's actually acting. Spacek also has a sort of physical appearance where she can match the qualities needed for the character of Carrie, but also where she is undeniably beautiful when she cleans herself up for the prom. Piper Laurie sort of revived her career with her performance as Margaret, garnering her an Oscar nomination also. She felt over-the-top at times, but Laurie's performance is undeniably unsettling, especially in the scenes where she physically abuses Carrie. Rounding out the supporting cast is Betty Buckley as Miss Collins, the gym teacher in charge of the detention and a comforting figure for Carrie, and John Travolta, in a breakthrough performance as Chris' boyfriend. There are a few aspects of Carrie that feel like they haven't aged well, such as the strange blurry lighting in some of the outdoor shots, but it's not enough to hinder it's greatness. The performances are solid, especially the Oscar-nominated performances from Spacek and Laurie. The story was well-written and well-executed, and offers some deep themes about bullying. Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Felt Bad For Poor Carrie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Stephen King's first novel, this film tells the story of a shy teenage girl named Carrie White(Sissy Spacek in an unforgettable performance) who is mocked and humiliated by her cruel schoolmates, though one of them takes pity on her, and has her popular boyfriend(William Katt) ask Carrie to the prom, which she accepts, but tragically Carrie's mother(Piper Laurie, quite good) is a psychopathic religious zealot who keeps Carrie locked in the closet as punishment for her "sins", but Carrie defies her, though two evil expelled classmates(played by Nancy Allen & John Travolta) plot a cruel prank on her at the prom, which pushes Carrie over the edge, and makes her use her latent telekinetic powers in merciless revenge... Fine performances and script compensate for some exploitive and obvious scare tactics in this memorable film, which elicits such sympathy for this unjustly put-upon girl that her rage at the end is understandable, though of course the poor girl is doomed...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A loose adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie was Stephen King's first novel and easily considered one of his best. When it became a hit a film adaptation was practically inevitable. Carrie is considered one of the most important horror films of the 70s. Carrie White (Sissy Spacek) is an isolated high school student with no friends and a fundamentalist Christian mum, Margaret (Piper Laurie). After being humiliated when she gets her first period in the school shower her telekinetic powers start to develop and heighten when under stress. Sue Snell (Amy Irving) feels guilty due to the incident in the shower where she joined in with mob and wants to make it up to Carrie by getting her boyfriend, Tommy (William Katt) to take Carrie to the prom. But the lead bully, Chris Hargensen (Nancy Allen) wants revenge against Carrie, blaming her for not letting her go to the prom and with her delinquent boyfriend, Billy (John Travolta) plan to humiliate Carrie in the most public and sadistic way possible. Carrie is an excellent novel, a short, taut little affair that is a breeze of a read. Some of the elements from the novel would have been hard to translate into because of the structure of the novel: mainly the extracts from the White Commission, The Shadow Exploded and Sue Snell's diary. Other scenes were cut because of expense, i.e. the explosion of the petrol station. But this is an adaptation that does make some big changes and cuts from the novel. Some include not getting to see Chris' father threatening to sue and ends up seeing what his daughter really is, cutting out Sue's pregnancy to small things like Carrie saying her father left her mother instead of dying in an industrial accident. Plus the sociological elements were cut out, looking at the impact of the aftermath of the Carrie incident which I thought was some of the most interesting stuff in the novel. The big positive with the film is the casting of Spacek: she was a terrific as Carrie, having the right look for seemingly being a little weird but have a unique beauty when she is at the prom. She was able to convey the shy, awkwardness of a character who is beaten emotionally at home and at school and shows a psychopathic rage with the look with her eyes when the pigs blood fell on her. The rest of the cast were solid, like Allen playing the bitchy, self-centred bully, Travolta as the abusive boyfriend, Katt and Irving as the high school students who want to do the right thing. Betty Buckley was excellent as the friendly teacher who wants to support and protect Carrie and Laurie did a good job as Carrie's fundamentalist mother. But Sydney Lassick was really hammy and out of place as an English teacher who wasn't even in the book. The big highlight of the film was the prom scene when the pig's blood felt on Carrie goes into a psychopathic rage, locking the doors with her mind and sets out killing everyone. Director Brian De Palma was able highlight the build-up and the tension and then the terror of Carrie's killing. De Palma was able to make the sequence with a unique style using split screens to show different actions happening at the same time and De Palma used silences, making us lip-read what people are saying (though it is very obvious). It is excellent sequence. During the film they are plenty of musical cues when Carrie using her powers, partly due to the limits of special effects, but sometimes the violin streaks from Psycho which was a distraction. Carrie is a very well-acted film that had some stand out sequences and excellent acting, but it is too loose of an adaptation for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Modern Tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nc-holdsworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Carrie again for the first time in years, having seen the trailer for the remake with Chloe thingybob from the god awful Kick Ass. Its a tragic tale about a shy girl called Carrie White who seems to get abuse and bullying by almost everyone she meets, her mother, classmates even annoying kids on bikes. Her mother is a religious nut case, therefore she has had no knowledge or understanding of the world and is left open to bullying from other kids due to the fact she is different. What no one knows is how different Carrie really is. She is already realising she can move things with her mind at the start of the movie, therefore its not dragged down with learning to use her 'powers' etc and instead concentrates on the story. For the story is not only about her ability, its an all too human tale of someone looking for acceptance, to be loved and its this that makes it so memorable. Its a very cruel movie for several reasons. First of all the bullying is quite nasty and humiliating, secondly then with help of one of the few sympathetic class mates Carrie gets her dream date for the prom (after initial scepticism) and during the prom she is genuinely happy for once in her life and these scenes are very touching. As a viewer we know its not going to end there however, we know the fall will come and DePalma expertly creates the ominous atmosphere before the bucket of blood comes crashing down all over her. What comes next is a split screen massacre as Carrie wipes out almost the entire Prom Night goers in a rage fuelled inferno. Carrie is a film that has that magic mix. DePalma's sure direction is excellent (even the quirky touches such as the fast forward work for me) Sissy Spacek, words are not enough to explain her shattering performance. It really is something. I've always been a fan of Pino Donnaggio and his work here is one, if not the best soundtrack he has ever done. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Magical Melodrama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zacharyduresky
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie is a film that makes you feel so many different emotions. Scenes like the infamous "period" scene will make you feel disgusted. The gym detention scene will make you laugh. The dance between Carrie and Tommy will touch you're heart. The climactic scene where Carrie unleashes her powers and kills everyone will have haunt your nightmares. There's drama, romance, suspense, comedy, eroticism and horror, everything you cold possibly want. But at its core, this film is a melodrama. This is a melodrama about an abused and taunted teenage girl who just wants love and acceptance. Then she discovers she can move things with her mind. At first she does nothing evil with it, and still tries to get accepted, and manages to do so. But then after a cruel prank involving pig blood, she's now out for human blood. Everyone dies, and this evil she finally unleashes leads to her demise, just like any other tragic character. This is easily my favorite film by director Brian De Palma, and my favorite film based on a Stephen King story. This melodramatic piece of genius never stops satisfying me, and just gets better and better every time I watch it. I highly recommend this to all who are unfortunate enough to have not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly the best horror movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I had not read the book before the film and I was only watching because I had seen the trailer for the upcoming remake. So I started it with no expectations at all and just had nothing better to do. Now down to the review. Right from the beginning this movie entices you in with a lovely period scene in a shower. I had no idea that this was going to happen and was quite surprised because it was handled very well and the actresses were not sexualised by Brian De Palma at all. Next was the entrance of Carrie's not so terrifying mother played by Piper Laurie. Maybe when this came out in 1974 she was scary, but now she's more....really really funny. This is really the only bad thing I can think of about the movie, with the exception of a pointless sex scene later. The next 40 minutes of the movie run pretty smoothly containing simple camera work and medium acting, with the occasional completely pointless sex scene. To make it even worse it has John Travolta in it! But then about 50 minutes in the prom scene arrives which I have already read about on Rotten Tomatoes and is in my opinion....actually not in my opinion IT'S A FACT! One of the most awesome movie scenes ever! Which is surprising because the special effects are a bit dodgy, but I won't deduct points for that because it was the best for the time. After Carrie has awesomely killed a gazabillion people at the prom she decides to go home and change into her pyjamas, which was bit weird considering she had just murdered loads of her classmates. But I won't deduct points for that because it's probably something to do with her telekinesis/puberty experience. Then her mum (who is one of my favourite unintentionally funny characters of all time) stabs her in the back LITERALLY! while they are praying, another reason why I'm atheist folks. Overall CARRIE is one of my favourite movies of all time. Possibly the best horror movie I have ever seen. Starting off at 10 (obviously) I minus 1 point for Piper Laurie being unintentionally hilarious. Then minus 0.3 points for a pointless sex scene. And finally minus 0.2 points for Carrie killing loads of people then going home as if nothing has happened. So I give Carrie- 8.5 out of 10 and 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Toronto85
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shy young girl gets back at her high school bullies using telekinetic powers in 'Carrie'. Carrie White is graduating high school, yet has no one to take her to the prom. She has no friends and all of the girls at school pick on her constantly. On top of all that, her mother is a religious nut who emotionally and physically abuses her at home. After picking on Carrie, fellow classmate Sue Snell decides to make it up to her by having her own boyfriend Tommy ask Carrie to the prom. After much reluctance, Tommy asks her out and they head off for the big night. The bullies fix it so that Tommy/Carrie are picked as king and queen in order for pig's blood to land right on the poor girl. That's when Carrie loses control and all HELL breaks loose at the high school. 'Carrie' is an amazing fantasy/horror film. Director Brian De Palma does such a good job with 'Carrie'. We get the flashes of the magical prom mixed in with Kris planning to dump the pig's blood over Carrie. The plot of the shy girl getting back at her bullies is a satisfying one, but with the added idea of telekinesis makes an even more exciting movie. The acting was really well done by everyone! Sissy Spacek puts in a good job as the lead Carrie, Piper Laurie is convincing as Carrie's crazed religious mother, and I REALLY thought Amy Irving was wonderful as Sue Snell. John Travolta, PJ Soles and Nancy Allen were great too as the villains. All around, a really good cast. It's always fun to see bullies get theirs in movies, but 'Carrie' takes it up a notch. I'd recommend this for sure to every horror fan. It's well acted, got a great cast and tells a pretty satisfying but sad story. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more than a film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    each adaptation of Stephen King novels is a delicate action. because , more than expectation of readers, important is the vision of director. and, sure, the cast. Carrie is out of this law. because it is not part of an genre or expectation in ordinary sense. it is a classic but not is its virtue. it is extraordinary expression of Sissy Spacek performance but not is the essential part. because, out of definitions, it is a mirror. the horror side is only trace of a profound tragedy who defines our world. the blood, the expression of Carrie face, the shadow of mother, the end, all represents images for ordinary state of each of us. it is so human, so cruel in manner to expose the deep truth about society than it is not, in time, only a good/extraordinary/admirable movie, it is a warning. and clear mirror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent horror mystery thriller! 8!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen many movies based on books written by Stephen King. In fact, I would consider myself a King's fan if I had read, at least, one of the numerous books he has written. "Carrie" is one of the best of them I saw. King's traits are very visible in this story: his sense of humour, horror, supernatural elements, mystery, drama, good performances, etc. The fact that John Travolta acted in the movie and that Brian de Palma directed it made me wish to watch "Carrie". Moreover, I am looking forward to seeing its remake. This movie is wonderfully directed with the right pace and duration. Brian de Palma did a very entertaining job with a very good script. The story is about a teenage girl who has telekinetic abilities and is bullied by her schoolmates. She lacks of a social life and is not like most teenagers. Moreover, she lives with her mother, who is a very possessive and mad women left by his husband. I prefer not to tell anything else about the plot not to spoil. The cast is mainly composed by Sissy Spacek, Piper Laurie and John Travolta. Sissy Spacek delivered a solid performance, maybe, a little bit overacted. The performances are very correct. The story is original and the capacity of entertainment is really high. The plot and the performances are the strongest points of this movie. There are several shocking scenes which are very amazing. In conclusion, this is a must-see for those like the stories from King. 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect cinema classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombiefan89
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't really even consider Carrie a horror movie. Sissy Spacek was just to adorable to find threatening, even when she went fully homicidal. Everything she did felt justified. However, if I had to say the biggest issue with the film was the ending. It made no sense at all. Why did they blame Carrie for the gym catching on fire? How did they know Carrie didn't die in the gym with everyone else? There were no survivors except the two antagonists, but they died shortly after. Let's say there were survivors, Did they all unanimously accept that Carrie had psychic powers and caused the fire? Why and how did they blame Carrie? It was like Light Yagami in Death Note, who could kill people by writing their name down and thinking of their face as they do it. They accepted that a notebook could kill people WAY too easily! No court on Earth would have convicted Light Yagami of being "Kira" because there was NO solid proof! I had a complete opposite reaction to the "surprise ending", I would have immediately started digging her out, trying to save her life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Milito
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1974, legendary horror writer Stephen King published his first novel, titled Carrie, which launched him into the fame that he has today. Even today, the story is recognized as one of the best Stephen King novels, but also as one of the greatest horror stories ever told. Two years after publication, director Brian De Palma would adapt this famous story for the big screen. The result was a fantastic horror movie with absolutely phenomenal acting performances and a chilling storyline that leaves an impact on everyone who witnesses it. Carrie White is a shy, socially awkward teenager who is subject to frequent bullying at Bates High School. Carrie is one of the girls who wears her hair down in order to cover her face. She lives at home with her mother Margaret, a mentally unstable Christian fundamentalist. Carrie is often subject to punishments from her mother, whether it's being forced into a closet to pray or repeating verses from the Bible over and over. Carrie is special though: she has the ability of telekinesis, meaning she can movie objects with her mind. After humiliating Carrie in the girls locker room, the more popular girls at the school, including Sue Snell, Chris Hargensen, and Norma Watson, are sentenced to a week long detention for their inappropriate behavior towards Carrie. Feeling bad for what she did, Sue decides to get her boyfriend, Tommy Ross, to ask Carrie to the senior prom in order to make up for the embarrassment. Reluctantly, Carrie accepts. However, when something goes down at the prom, the night turns from one of happiness and fun into one of pure horror. The story is chilling and unsettling without being a full-fledged slasher movie. What's great about the movie is the way takes the time to slow down and flesh out Carrie's story, giving a chance for viewers to realize just how terrible Carrie's life really is. As it progresses, Carrie becomes a more relatable and sympathetic character, which makes the climax all the more saddening and even understandable to a certain degree. The performances in Carrie are top-notch all around the board. Sissy Spacek, in an Oscar-nominated performance, plays Carrie extremely well. She plays all the emotions that Carrie faces in an extremely believable way, almost making it hard to tell if she's actually acting. Spacek also has a sort of physical appearance where she can match the qualities needed for the character of Carrie, but also where she is undeniably beautiful when she cleans herself up for the prom. Piper Laurie sort of revived her career with her performance as Margaret, garnering her an Oscar nomination also. She felt over-the-top at times, but Laurie's performance is undeniably unsettling, especially in the scenes where she physically abuses Carrie. Rounding out the supporting cast is Betty Buckley as Miss Collins, the gym teacher in charge of the detention and a comforting figure for Carrie, and John Travolta, in a breakthrough performance as Chris' boyfriend. There are a few aspects of Carrie that feel like they haven't aged well, such as the strange blurry lighting in some of the outdoor shots, but it's not enough to hinder it's greatness. The performances are solid, especially the Oscar-nominated performances from Spacek and Laurie. The story was well-written and well-executed, and offers some deep themes about bullying. Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Felt Bad For Poor Carrie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Stephen King's first novel, this film tells the story of a shy teenage girl named Carrie White(Sissy Spacek in an unforgettable performance) who is mocked and humiliated by her cruel schoolmates, though one of them takes pity on her, and has her popular boyfriend(William Katt) ask Carrie to the prom, which she accepts, but tragically Carrie's mother(Piper Laurie, quite good) is a psychopathic religious zealot who keeps Carrie locked in the closet as punishment for her "sins", but Carrie defies her, though two evil expelled classmates(played by Nancy Allen & John Travolta) plot a cruel prank on her at the prom, which pushes Carrie over the edge, and makes her use her latent telekinetic powers in merciless revenge... Fine performances and script compensate for some exploitive and obvious scare tactics in this memorable film, which elicits such sympathy for this unjustly put-upon girl that her rage at the end is understandable, though of course the poor girl is doomed...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A loose adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie was Stephen King's first novel and easily considered one of his best. When it became a hit a film adaptation was practically inevitable. Carrie is considered one of the most important horror films of the 70s. Carrie White (Sissy Spacek) is an isolated high school student with no friends and a fundamentalist Christian mum, Margaret (Piper Laurie). After being humiliated when she gets her first period in the school shower her telekinetic powers start to develop and heighten when under stress. Sue Snell (Amy Irving) feels guilty due to the incident in the shower where she joined in with mob and wants to make it up to Carrie by getting her boyfriend, Tommy (William Katt) to take Carrie to the prom. But the lead bully, Chris Hargensen (Nancy Allen) wants revenge against Carrie, blaming her for not letting her go to the prom and with her delinquent boyfriend, Billy (John Travolta) plan to humiliate Carrie in the most public and sadistic way possible. Carrie is an excellent novel, a short, taut little affair that is a breeze of a read. Some of the elements from the novel would have been hard to translate into because of the structure of the novel: mainly the extracts from the White Commission, The Shadow Exploded and Sue Snell's diary. Other scenes were cut because of expense, i.e. the explosion of the petrol station. But this is an adaptation that does make some big changes and cuts from the novel. Some include not getting to see Chris' father threatening to sue and ends up seeing what his daughter really is, cutting out Sue's pregnancy to small things like Carrie saying her father left her mother instead of dying in an industrial accident. Plus the sociological elements were cut out, looking at the impact of the aftermath of the Carrie incident which I thought was some of the most interesting stuff in the novel. The big positive with the film is the casting of Spacek: she was a terrific as Carrie, having the right look for seemingly being a little weird but have a unique beauty when she is at the prom. She was able to convey the shy, awkwardness of a character who is beaten emotionally at home and at school and shows a psychopathic rage with the look with her eyes when the pigs blood fell on her. The rest of the cast were solid, like Allen playing the bitchy, self-centred bully, Travolta as the abusive boyfriend, Katt and Irving as the high school students who want to do the right thing. Betty Buckley was excellent as the friendly teacher who wants to support and protect Carrie and Laurie did a good job as Carrie's fundamentalist mother. But Sydney Lassick was really hammy and out of place as an English teacher who wasn't even in the book. The big highlight of the film was the prom scene when the pig's blood felt on Carrie goes into a psychopathic rage, locking the doors with her mind and sets out killing everyone. Director Brian De Palma was able highlight the build-up and the tension and then the terror of Carrie's killing. De Palma was able to make the sequence with a unique style using split screens to show different actions happening at the same time and De Palma used silences, making us lip-read what people are saying (though it is very obvious). It is excellent sequence. During the film they are plenty of musical cues when Carrie using her powers, partly due to the limits of special effects, but sometimes the violin streaks from Psycho which was a distraction. Carrie is a very well-acted film that had some stand out sequences and excellent acting, but it is too loose of an adaptation for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Modern Tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nc-holdsworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Carrie again for the first time in years, having seen the trailer for the remake with Chloe thingybob from the god awful Kick Ass. Its a tragic tale about a shy girl called Carrie White who seems to get abuse and bullying by almost everyone she meets, her mother, classmates even annoying kids on bikes. Her mother is a religious nut case, therefore she has had no knowledge or understanding of the world and is left open to bullying from other kids due to the fact she is different. What no one knows is how different Carrie really is. She is already realising she can move things with her mind at the start of the movie, therefore its not dragged down with learning to use her 'powers' etc and instead concentrates on the story. For the story is not only about her ability, its an all too human tale of someone looking for acceptance, to be loved and its this that makes it so memorable. Its a very cruel movie for several reasons. First of all the bullying is quite nasty and humiliating, secondly then with help of one of the few sympathetic class mates Carrie gets her dream date for the prom (after initial scepticism) and during the prom she is genuinely happy for once in her life and these scenes are very touching. As a viewer we know its not going to end there however, we know the fall will come and DePalma expertly creates the ominous atmosphere before the bucket of blood comes crashing down all over her. What comes next is a split screen massacre as Carrie wipes out almost the entire Prom Night goers in a rage fuelled inferno. Carrie is a film that has that magic mix. DePalma's sure direction is excellent (even the quirky touches such as the fast forward work for me) Sissy Spacek, words are not enough to explain her shattering performance. It really is something. I've always been a fan of Pino Donnaggio and his work here is one, if not the best soundtrack he has ever done. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Magical Melodrama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zacharyduresky
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie is a film that makes you feel so many different emotions. Scenes like the infamous "period" scene will make you feel disgusted. The gym detention scene will make you laugh. The dance between Carrie and Tommy will touch you're heart. The climactic scene where Carrie unleashes her powers and kills everyone will have haunt your nightmares. There's drama, romance, suspense, comedy, eroticism and horror, everything you cold possibly want. But at its core, this film is a melodrama. This is a melodrama about an abused and taunted teenage girl who just wants love and acceptance. Then she discovers she can move things with her mind. At first she does nothing evil with it, and still tries to get accepted, and manages to do so. But then after a cruel prank involving pig blood, she's now out for human blood. Everyone dies, and this evil she finally unleashes leads to her demise, just like any other tragic character. This is easily my favorite film by director Brian De Palma, and my favorite film based on a Stephen King story. This melodramatic piece of genius never stops satisfying me, and just gets better and better every time I watch it. I highly recommend this to all who are unfortunate enough to have not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly the best horror movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I had not read the book before the film and I was only watching because I had seen the trailer for the upcoming remake. So I started it with no expectations at all and just had nothing better to do. Now down to the review. Right from the beginning this movie entices you in with a lovely period scene in a shower. I had no idea that this was going to happen and was quite surprised because it was handled very well and the actresses were not sexualised by Brian De Palma at all. Next was the entrance of Carrie's not so terrifying mother played by Piper Laurie. Maybe when this came out in 1974 she was scary, but now she's more....really really funny. This is really the only bad thing I can think of about the movie, with the exception of a pointless sex scene later. The next 40 minutes of the movie run pretty smoothly containing simple camera work and medium acting, with the occasional completely pointless sex scene. To make it even worse it has John Travolta in it! But then about 50 minutes in the prom scene arrives which I have already read about on Rotten Tomatoes and is in my opinion....actually not in my opinion IT'S A FACT! One of the most awesome movie scenes ever! Which is surprising because the special effects are a bit dodgy, but I won't deduct points for that because it was the best for the time. After Carrie has awesomely killed a gazabillion people at the prom she decides to go home and change into her pyjamas, which was bit weird considering she had just murdered loads of her classmates. But I won't deduct points for that because it's probably something to do with her telekinesis/puberty experience. Then her mum (who is one of my favourite unintentionally funny characters of all time) stabs her in the back LITERALLY! while they are praying, another reason why I'm atheist folks. Overall CARRIE is one of my favourite movies of all time. Possibly the best horror movie I have ever seen. Starting off at 10 (obviously) I minus 1 point for Piper Laurie being unintentionally hilarious. Then minus 0.3 points for a pointless sex scene. And finally minus 0.2 points for Carrie killing loads of people then going home as if nothing has happened. So I give Carrie- 8.5 out of 10 and 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Toronto85
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shy young girl gets back at her high school bullies using telekinetic powers in 'Carrie'. Carrie White is graduating high school, yet has no one to take her to the prom. She has no friends and all of the girls at school pick on her constantly. On top of all that, her mother is a religious nut who emotionally and physically abuses her at home. After picking on Carrie, fellow classmate Sue Snell decides to make it up to her by having her own boyfriend Tommy ask Carrie to the prom. After much reluctance, Tommy asks her out and they head off for the big night. The bullies fix it so that Tommy/Carrie are picked as king and queen in order for pig's blood to land right on the poor girl. That's when Carrie loses control and all HELL breaks loose at the high school. 'Carrie' is an amazing fantasy/horror film. Director Brian De Palma does such a good job with 'Carrie'. We get the flashes of the magical prom mixed in with Kris planning to dump the pig's blood over Carrie. The plot of the shy girl getting back at her bullies is a satisfying one, but with the added idea of telekinesis makes an even more exciting movie. The acting was really well done by everyone! Sissy Spacek puts in a good job as the lead Carrie, Piper Laurie is convincing as Carrie's crazed religious mother, and I REALLY thought Amy Irving was wonderful as Sue Snell. John Travolta, PJ Soles and Nancy Allen were great too as the villains. All around, a really good cast. It's always fun to see bullies get theirs in movies, but 'Carrie' takes it up a notch. I'd recommend this for sure to every horror fan. It's well acted, got a great cast and tells a pretty satisfying but sad story. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more than a film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    each adaptation of Stephen King novels is a delicate action. because , more than expectation of readers, important is the vision of director. and, sure, the cast. Carrie is out of this law. because it is not part of an genre or expectation in ordinary sense. it is a classic but not is its virtue. it is extraordinary expression of Sissy Spacek performance but not is the essential part. because, out of definitions, it is a mirror. the horror side is only trace of a profound tragedy who defines our world. the blood, the expression of Carrie face, the shadow of mother, the end, all represents images for ordinary state of each of us. it is so human, so cruel in manner to expose the deep truth about society than it is not, in time, only a good/extraordinary/admirable movie, it is a warning. and clear mirror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent horror mystery thriller! 8!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen many movies based on books written by Stephen King. In fact, I would consider myself a King's fan if I had read, at least, one of the numerous books he has written. "Carrie" is one of the best of them I saw. King's traits are very visible in this story: his sense of humour, horror, supernatural elements, mystery, drama, good performances, etc. The fact that John Travolta acted in the movie and that Brian de Palma directed it made me wish to watch "Carrie". Moreover, I am looking forward to seeing its remake. This movie is wonderfully directed with the right pace and duration. Brian de Palma did a very entertaining job with a very good script. The story is about a teenage girl who has telekinetic abilities and is bullied by her schoolmates. She lacks of a social life and is not like most teenagers. Moreover, she lives with her mother, who is a very possessive and mad women left by his husband. I prefer not to tell anything else about the plot not to spoil. The cast is mainly composed by Sissy Spacek, Piper Laurie and John Travolta. Sissy Spacek delivered a solid performance, maybe, a little bit overacted. The performances are very correct. The story is original and the capacity of entertainment is really high. The plot and the performances are the strongest points of this movie. There are several shocking scenes which are very amazing. In conclusion, this is a must-see for those like the stories from King. 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect cinema classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombiefan89
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't really even consider Carrie a horror movie. Sissy Spacek was just to adorable to find threatening, even when she went fully homicidal. Everything she did felt justified. However, if I had to say the biggest issue with the film was the ending. It made no sense at all. Why did they blame Carrie for the gym catching on fire? How did they know Carrie didn't die in the gym with everyone else? There were no survivors except the two antagonists, but they died shortly after. Let's say there were survivors, Did they all unanimously accept that Carrie had psychic powers and caused the fire? Why and how did they blame Carrie? It was like Light Yagami in Death Note, who could kill people by writing their name down and thinking of their face as they do it. They accepted that a notebook could kill people WAY too easily! No court on Earth would have convicted Light Yagami of being "Kira" because there was NO solid proof! I had a complete opposite reaction to the "surprise ending", I would have immediately started digging her out, trying to save her life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Milito
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1974, legendary horror writer Stephen King published his first novel, titled Carrie, which launched him into the fame that he has today. Even today, the story is recognized as one of the best Stephen King novels, but also as one of the greatest horror stories ever told. Two years after publication, director Brian De Palma would adapt this famous story for the big screen. The result was a fantastic horror movie with absolutely phenomenal acting performances and a chilling storyline that leaves an impact on everyone who witnesses it. Carrie White is a shy, socially awkward teenager who is subject to frequent bullying at Bates High School. Carrie is one of the girls who wears her hair down in order to cover her face. She lives at home with her mother Margaret, a mentally unstable Christian fundamentalist. Carrie is often subject to punishments from her mother, whether it's being forced into a closet to pray or repeating verses from the Bible over and over. Carrie is special though: she has the ability of telekinesis, meaning she can movie objects with her mind. After humiliating Carrie in the girls locker room, the more popular girls at the school, including Sue Snell, Chris Hargensen, and Norma Watson, are sentenced to a week long detention for their inappropriate behavior towards Carrie. Feeling bad for what she did, Sue decides to get her boyfriend, Tommy Ross, to ask Carrie to the senior prom in order to make up for the embarrassment. Reluctantly, Carrie accepts. However, when something goes down at the prom, the night turns from one of happiness and fun into one of pure horror. The story is chilling and unsettling without being a full-fledged slasher movie. What's great about the movie is the way takes the time to slow down and flesh out Carrie's story, giving a chance for viewers to realize just how terrible Carrie's life really is. As it progresses, Carrie becomes a more relatable and sympathetic character, which makes the climax all the more saddening and even understandable to a certain degree. The performances in Carrie are top-notch all around the board. Sissy Spacek, in an Oscar-nominated performance, plays Carrie extremely well. She plays all the emotions that Carrie faces in an extremely believable way, almost making it hard to tell if she's actually acting. Spacek also has a sort of physical appearance where she can match the qualities needed for the character of Carrie, but also where she is undeniably beautiful when she cleans herself up for the prom. Piper Laurie sort of revived her career with her performance as Margaret, garnering her an Oscar nomination also. She felt over-the-top at times, but Laurie's performance is undeniably unsettling, especially in the scenes where she physically abuses Carrie. Rounding out the supporting cast is Betty Buckley as Miss Collins, the gym teacher in charge of the detention and a comforting figure for Carrie, and John Travolta, in a breakthrough performance as Chris' boyfriend. There are a few aspects of Carrie that feel like they haven't aged well, such as the strange blurry lighting in some of the outdoor shots, but it's not enough to hinder it's greatness. The performances are solid, especially the Oscar-nominated performances from Spacek and Laurie. The story was well-written and well-executed, and offers some deep themes about bullying. Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Felt Bad For Poor Carrie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Stephen King's first novel, this film tells the story of a shy teenage girl named Carrie White(Sissy Spacek in an unforgettable performance) who is mocked and humiliated by her cruel schoolmates, though one of them takes pity on her, and has her popular boyfriend(William Katt) ask Carrie to the prom, which she accepts, but tragically Carrie's mother(Piper Laurie, quite good) is a psychopathic religious zealot who keeps Carrie locked in the closet as punishment for her "sins", but Carrie defies her, though two evil expelled classmates(played by Nancy Allen & John Travolta) plot a cruel prank on her at the prom, which pushes Carrie over the edge, and makes her use her latent telekinetic powers in merciless revenge... Fine performances and script compensate for some exploitive and obvious scare tactics in this memorable film, which elicits such sympathy for this unjustly put-upon girl that her rage at the end is understandable, though of course the poor girl is doomed...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A loose adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie was Stephen King's first novel and easily considered one of his best. When it became a hit a film adaptation was practically inevitable. Carrie is considered one of the most important horror films of the 70s. Carrie White (Sissy Spacek) is an isolated high school student with no friends and a fundamentalist Christian mum, Margaret (Piper Laurie). After being humiliated when she gets her first period in the school shower her telekinetic powers start to develop and heighten when under stress. Sue Snell (Amy Irving) feels guilty due to the incident in the shower where she joined in with mob and wants to make it up to Carrie by getting her boyfriend, Tommy (William Katt) to take Carrie to the prom. But the lead bully, Chris Hargensen (Nancy Allen) wants revenge against Carrie, blaming her for not letting her go to the prom and with her delinquent boyfriend, Billy (John Travolta) plan to humiliate Carrie in the most public and sadistic way possible. Carrie is an excellent novel, a short, taut little affair that is a breeze of a read. Some of the elements from the novel would have been hard to translate into because of the structure of the novel: mainly the extracts from the White Commission, The Shadow Exploded and Sue Snell's diary. Other scenes were cut because of expense, i.e. the explosion of the petrol station. But this is an adaptation that does make some big changes and cuts from the novel. Some include not getting to see Chris' father threatening to sue and ends up seeing what his daughter really is, cutting out Sue's pregnancy to small things like Carrie saying her father left her mother instead of dying in an industrial accident. Plus the sociological elements were cut out, looking at the impact of the aftermath of the Carrie incident which I thought was some of the most interesting stuff in the novel. The big positive with the film is the casting of Spacek: she was a terrific as Carrie, having the right look for seemingly being a little weird but have a unique beauty when she is at the prom. She was able to convey the shy, awkwardness of a character who is beaten emotionally at home and at school and shows a psychopathic rage with the look with her eyes when the pigs blood fell on her. The rest of the cast were solid, like Allen playing the bitchy, self-centred bully, Travolta as the abusive boyfriend, Katt and Irving as the high school students who want to do the right thing. Betty Buckley was excellent as the friendly teacher who wants to support and protect Carrie and Laurie did a good job as Carrie's fundamentalist mother. But Sydney Lassick was really hammy and out of place as an English teacher who wasn't even in the book. The big highlight of the film was the prom scene when the pig's blood felt on Carrie goes into a psychopathic rage, locking the doors with her mind and sets out killing everyone. Director Brian De Palma was able highlight the build-up and the tension and then the terror of Carrie's killing. De Palma was able to make the sequence with a unique style using split screens to show different actions happening at the same time and De Palma used silences, making us lip-read what people are saying (though it is very obvious). It is excellent sequence. During the film they are plenty of musical cues when Carrie using her powers, partly due to the limits of special effects, but sometimes the violin streaks from Psycho which was a distraction. Carrie is a very well-acted film that had some stand out sequences and excellent acting, but it is too loose of an adaptation for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Modern Tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nc-holdsworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Carrie again for the first time in years, having seen the trailer for the remake with Chloe thingybob from the god awful Kick Ass. Its a tragic tale about a shy girl called Carrie White who seems to get abuse and bullying by almost everyone she meets, her mother, classmates even annoying kids on bikes. Her mother is a religious nut case, therefore she has had no knowledge or understanding of the world and is left open to bullying from other kids due to the fact she is different. What no one knows is how different Carrie really is. She is already realising she can move things with her mind at the start of the movie, therefore its not dragged down with learning to use her 'powers' etc and instead concentrates on the story. For the story is not only about her ability, its an all too human tale of someone looking for acceptance, to be loved and its this that makes it so memorable. Its a very cruel movie for several reasons. First of all the bullying is quite nasty and humiliating, secondly then with help of one of the few sympathetic class mates Carrie gets her dream date for the prom (after initial scepticism) and during the prom she is genuinely happy for once in her life and these scenes are very touching. As a viewer we know its not going to end there however, we know the fall will come and DePalma expertly creates the ominous atmosphere before the bucket of blood comes crashing down all over her. What comes next is a split screen massacre as Carrie wipes out almost the entire Prom Night goers in a rage fuelled inferno. Carrie is a film that has that magic mix. DePalma's sure direction is excellent (even the quirky touches such as the fast forward work for me) Sissy Spacek, words are not enough to explain her shattering performance. It really is something. I've always been a fan of Pino Donnaggio and his work here is one, if not the best soundtrack he has ever done. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Magical Melodrama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zacharyduresky
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie is a film that makes you feel so many different emotions. Scenes like the infamous "period" scene will make you feel disgusted. The gym detention scene will make you laugh. The dance between Carrie and Tommy will touch you're heart. The climactic scene where Carrie unleashes her powers and kills everyone will have haunt your nightmares. There's drama, romance, suspense, comedy, eroticism and horror, everything you cold possibly want. But at its core, this film is a melodrama. This is a melodrama about an abused and taunted teenage girl who just wants love and acceptance. Then she discovers she can move things with her mind. At first she does nothing evil with it, and still tries to get accepted, and manages to do so. But then after a cruel prank involving pig blood, she's now out for human blood. Everyone dies, and this evil she finally unleashes leads to her demise, just like any other tragic character. This is easily my favorite film by director Brian De Palma, and my favorite film based on a Stephen King story. This melodramatic piece of genius never stops satisfying me, and just gets better and better every time I watch it. I highly recommend this to all who are unfortunate enough to have not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly the best horror movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I had not read the book before the film and I was only watching because I had seen the trailer for the upcoming remake. So I started it with no expectations at all and just had nothing better to do. Now down to the review. Right from the beginning this movie entices you in with a lovely period scene in a shower. I had no idea that this was going to happen and was quite surprised because it was handled very well and the actresses were not sexualised by Brian De Palma at all. Next was the entrance of Carrie's not so terrifying mother played by Piper Laurie. Maybe when this came out in 1974 she was scary, but now she's more....really really funny. This is really the only bad thing I can think of about the movie, with the exception of a pointless sex scene later. The next 40 minutes of the movie run pretty smoothly containing simple camera work and medium acting, with the occasional completely pointless sex scene. To make it even worse it has John Travolta in it! But then about 50 minutes in the prom scene arrives which I have already read about on Rotten Tomatoes and is in my opinion....actually not in my opinion IT'S A FACT! One of the most awesome movie scenes ever! Which is surprising because the special effects are a bit dodgy, but I won't deduct points for that because it was the best for the time. After Carrie has awesomely killed a gazabillion people at the prom she decides to go home and change into her pyjamas, which was bit weird considering she had just murdered loads of her classmates. But I won't deduct points for that because it's probably something to do with her telekinesis/puberty experience. Then her mum (who is one of my favourite unintentionally funny characters of all time) stabs her in the back LITERALLY! while they are praying, another reason why I'm atheist folks. Overall CARRIE is one of my favourite movies of all time. Possibly the best horror movie I have ever seen. Starting off at 10 (obviously) I minus 1 point for Piper Laurie being unintentionally hilarious. Then minus 0.3 points for a pointless sex scene. And finally minus 0.2 points for Carrie killing loads of people then going home as if nothing has happened. So I give Carrie- 8.5 out of 10 and 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Toronto85
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shy young girl gets back at her high school bullies using telekinetic powers in 'Carrie'. Carrie White is graduating high school, yet has no one to take her to the prom. She has no friends and all of the girls at school pick on her constantly. On top of all that, her mother is a religious nut who emotionally and physically abuses her at home. After picking on Carrie, fellow classmate Sue Snell decides to make it up to her by having her own boyfriend Tommy ask Carrie to the prom. After much reluctance, Tommy asks her out and they head off for the big night. The bullies fix it so that Tommy/Carrie are picked as king and queen in order for pig's blood to land right on the poor girl. That's when Carrie loses control and all HELL breaks loose at the high school. 'Carrie' is an amazing fantasy/horror film. Director Brian De Palma does such a good job with 'Carrie'. We get the flashes of the magical prom mixed in with Kris planning to dump the pig's blood over Carrie. The plot of the shy girl getting back at her bullies is a satisfying one, but with the added idea of telekinesis makes an even more exciting movie. The acting was really well done by everyone! Sissy Spacek puts in a good job as the lead Carrie, Piper Laurie is convincing as Carrie's crazed religious mother, and I REALLY thought Amy Irving was wonderful as Sue Snell. John Travolta, PJ Soles and Nancy Allen were great too as the villains. All around, a really good cast. It's always fun to see bullies get theirs in movies, but 'Carrie' takes it up a notch. I'd recommend this for sure to every horror fan. It's well acted, got a great cast and tells a pretty satisfying but sad story. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more than a film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    each adaptation of Stephen King novels is a delicate action. because , more than expectation of readers, important is the vision of director. and, sure, the cast. Carrie is out of this law. because it is not part of an genre or expectation in ordinary sense. it is a classic but not is its virtue. it is extraordinary expression of Sissy Spacek performance but not is the essential part. because, out of definitions, it is a mirror. the horror side is only trace of a profound tragedy who defines our world. the blood, the expression of Carrie face, the shadow of mother, the end, all represents images for ordinary state of each of us. it is so human, so cruel in manner to expose the deep truth about society than it is not, in time, only a good/extraordinary/admirable movie, it is a warning. and clear mirror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent horror mystery thriller! 8!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen many movies based on books written by Stephen King. In fact, I would consider myself a King's fan if I had read, at least, one of the numerous books he has written. "Carrie" is one of the best of them I saw. King's traits are very visible in this story: his sense of humour, horror, supernatural elements, mystery, drama, good performances, etc. The fact that John Travolta acted in the movie and that Brian de Palma directed it made me wish to watch "Carrie". Moreover, I am looking forward to seeing its remake. This movie is wonderfully directed with the right pace and duration. Brian de Palma did a very entertaining job with a very good script. The story is about a teenage girl who has telekinetic abilities and is bullied by her schoolmates. She lacks of a social life and is not like most teenagers. Moreover, she lives with her mother, who is a very possessive and mad women left by his husband. I prefer not to tell anything else about the plot not to spoil. The cast is mainly composed by Sissy Spacek, Piper Laurie and John Travolta. Sissy Spacek delivered a solid performance, maybe, a little bit overacted. The performances are very correct. The story is original and the capacity of entertainment is really high. The plot and the performances are the strongest points of this movie. There are several shocking scenes which are very amazing. In conclusion, this is a must-see for those like the stories from King. 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect cinema classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombiefan89
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't really even consider Carrie a horror movie. Sissy Spacek was just to adorable to find threatening, even when she went fully homicidal. Everything she did felt justified. However, if I had to say the biggest issue with the film was the ending. It made no sense at all. Why did they blame Carrie for the gym catching on fire? How did they know Carrie didn't die in the gym with everyone else? There were no survivors except the two antagonists, but they died shortly after. Let's say there were survivors, Did they all unanimously accept that Carrie had psychic powers and caused the fire? Why and how did they blame Carrie? It was like Light Yagami in Death Note, who could kill people by writing their name down and thinking of their face as they do it. They accepted that a notebook could kill people WAY too easily! No court on Earth would have convicted Light Yagami of being "Kira" because there was NO solid proof! I had a complete opposite reaction to the "surprise ending", I would have immediately started digging her out, trying to save her life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Milito
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1974, legendary horror writer Stephen King published his first novel, titled Carrie, which launched him into the fame that he has today. Even today, the story is recognized as one of the best Stephen King novels, but also as one of the greatest horror stories ever told. Two years after publication, director Brian De Palma would adapt this famous story for the big screen. The result was a fantastic horror movie with absolutely phenomenal acting performances and a chilling storyline that leaves an impact on everyone who witnesses it. Carrie White is a shy, socially awkward teenager who is subject to frequent bullying at Bates High School. Carrie is one of the girls who wears her hair down in order to cover her face. She lives at home with her mother Margaret, a mentally unstable Christian fundamentalist. Carrie is often subject to punishments from her mother, whether it's being forced into a closet to pray or repeating verses from the Bible over and over. Carrie is special though: she has the ability of telekinesis, meaning she can movie objects with her mind. After humiliating Carrie in the girls locker room, the more popular girls at the school, including Sue Snell, Chris Hargensen, and Norma Watson, are sentenced to a week long detention for their inappropriate behavior towards Carrie. Feeling bad for what she did, Sue decides to get her boyfriend, Tommy Ross, to ask Carrie to the senior prom in order to make up for the embarrassment. Reluctantly, Carrie accepts. However, when something goes down at the prom, the night turns from one of happiness and fun into one of pure horror. The story is chilling and unsettling without being a full-fledged slasher movie. What's great about the movie is the way takes the time to slow down and flesh out Carrie's story, giving a chance for viewers to realize just how terrible Carrie's life really is. As it progresses, Carrie becomes a more relatable and sympathetic character, which makes the climax all the more saddening and even understandable to a certain degree. The performances in Carrie are top-notch all around the board. Sissy Spacek, in an Oscar-nominated performance, plays Carrie extremely well. She plays all the emotions that Carrie faces in an extremely believable way, almost making it hard to tell if she's actually acting. Spacek also has a sort of physical appearance where she can match the qualities needed for the character of Carrie, but also where she is undeniably beautiful when she cleans herself up for the prom. Piper Laurie sort of revived her career with her performance as Margaret, garnering her an Oscar nomination also. She felt over-the-top at times, but Laurie's performance is undeniably unsettling, especially in the scenes where she physically abuses Carrie. Rounding out the supporting cast is Betty Buckley as Miss Collins, the gym teacher in charge of the detention and a comforting figure for Carrie, and John Travolta, in a breakthrough performance as Chris' boyfriend. There are a few aspects of Carrie that feel like they haven't aged well, such as the strange blurry lighting in some of the outdoor shots, but it's not enough to hinder it's greatness. The performances are solid, especially the Oscar-nominated performances from Spacek and Laurie. The story was well-written and well-executed, and offers some deep themes about bullying. Carrie still stands as one of the best Stephen King book-to-movie adaptations, and one of the greatest horror movies to ever grace the silver screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Felt Bad For Poor Carrie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on Stephen King's first novel, this film tells the story of a shy teenage girl named Carrie White(Sissy Spacek in an unforgettable performance) who is mocked and humiliated by her cruel schoolmates, though one of them takes pity on her, and has her popular boyfriend(William Katt) ask Carrie to the prom, which she accepts, but tragically Carrie's mother(Piper Laurie, quite good) is a psychopathic religious zealot who keeps Carrie locked in the closet as punishment for her "sins", but Carrie defies her, though two evil expelled classmates(played by Nancy Allen & John Travolta) plot a cruel prank on her at the prom, which pushes Carrie over the edge, and makes her use her latent telekinetic powers in merciless revenge... Fine performances and script compensate for some exploitive and obvious scare tactics in this memorable film, which elicits such sympathy for this unjustly put-upon girl that her rage at the end is understandable, though of course the poor girl is doomed...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A loose adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    freemantle_uk
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie was Stephen King's first novel and easily considered one of his best. When it became a hit a film adaptation was practically inevitable. Carrie is considered one of the most important horror films of the 70s. Carrie White (Sissy Spacek) is an isolated high school student with no friends and a fundamentalist Christian mum, Margaret (Piper Laurie). After being humiliated when she gets her first period in the school shower her telekinetic powers start to develop and heighten when under stress. Sue Snell (Amy Irving) feels guilty due to the incident in the shower where she joined in with mob and wants to make it up to Carrie by getting her boyfriend, Tommy (William Katt) to take Carrie to the prom. But the lead bully, Chris Hargensen (Nancy Allen) wants revenge against Carrie, blaming her for not letting her go to the prom and with her delinquent boyfriend, Billy (John Travolta) plan to humiliate Carrie in the most public and sadistic way possible. Carrie is an excellent novel, a short, taut little affair that is a breeze of a read. Some of the elements from the novel would have been hard to translate into because of the structure of the novel: mainly the extracts from the White Commission, The Shadow Exploded and Sue Snell's diary. Other scenes were cut because of expense, i.e. the explosion of the petrol station. But this is an adaptation that does make some big changes and cuts from the novel. Some include not getting to see Chris' father threatening to sue and ends up seeing what his daughter really is, cutting out Sue's pregnancy to small things like Carrie saying her father left her mother instead of dying in an industrial accident. Plus the sociological elements were cut out, looking at the impact of the aftermath of the Carrie incident which I thought was some of the most interesting stuff in the novel. The big positive with the film is the casting of Spacek: she was a terrific as Carrie, having the right look for seemingly being a little weird but have a unique beauty when she is at the prom. She was able to convey the shy, awkwardness of a character who is beaten emotionally at home and at school and shows a psychopathic rage with the look with her eyes when the pigs blood fell on her. The rest of the cast were solid, like Allen playing the bitchy, self-centred bully, Travolta as the abusive boyfriend, Katt and Irving as the high school students who want to do the right thing. Betty Buckley was excellent as the friendly teacher who wants to support and protect Carrie and Laurie did a good job as Carrie's fundamentalist mother. But Sydney Lassick was really hammy and out of place as an English teacher who wasn't even in the book. The big highlight of the film was the prom scene when the pig's blood felt on Carrie goes into a psychopathic rage, locking the doors with her mind and sets out killing everyone. Director Brian De Palma was able highlight the build-up and the tension and then the terror of Carrie's killing. De Palma was able to make the sequence with a unique style using split screens to show different actions happening at the same time and De Palma used silences, making us lip-read what people are saying (though it is very obvious). It is excellent sequence. During the film they are plenty of musical cues when Carrie using her powers, partly due to the limits of special effects, but sometimes the violin streaks from Psycho which was a distraction. Carrie is a very well-acted film that had some stand out sequences and excellent acting, but it is too loose of an adaptation for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Modern Tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nc-holdsworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched Carrie again for the first time in years, having seen the trailer for the remake with Chloe thingybob from the god awful Kick Ass. Its a tragic tale about a shy girl called Carrie White who seems to get abuse and bullying by almost everyone she meets, her mother, classmates even annoying kids on bikes. Her mother is a religious nut case, therefore she has had no knowledge or understanding of the world and is left open to bullying from other kids due to the fact she is different. What no one knows is how different Carrie really is. She is already realising she can move things with her mind at the start of the movie, therefore its not dragged down with learning to use her 'powers' etc and instead concentrates on the story. For the story is not only about her ability, its an all too human tale of someone looking for acceptance, to be loved and its this that makes it so memorable. Its a very cruel movie for several reasons. First of all the bullying is quite nasty and humiliating, secondly then with help of one of the few sympathetic class mates Carrie gets her dream date for the prom (after initial scepticism) and during the prom she is genuinely happy for once in her life and these scenes are very touching. As a viewer we know its not going to end there however, we know the fall will come and DePalma expertly creates the ominous atmosphere before the bucket of blood comes crashing down all over her. What comes next is a split screen massacre as Carrie wipes out almost the entire Prom Night goers in a rage fuelled inferno. Carrie is a film that has that magic mix. DePalma's sure direction is excellent (even the quirky touches such as the fast forward work for me) Sissy Spacek, words are not enough to explain her shattering performance. It really is something. I've always been a fan of Pino Donnaggio and his work here is one, if not the best soundtrack he has ever done. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Magical Melodrama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zacharyduresky
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carrie is a film that makes you feel so many different emotions. Scenes like the infamous "period" scene will make you feel disgusted. The gym detention scene will make you laugh. The dance between Carrie and Tommy will touch you're heart. The climactic scene where Carrie unleashes her powers and kills everyone will have haunt your nightmares. There's drama, romance, suspense, comedy, eroticism and horror, everything you cold possibly want. But at its core, this film is a melodrama. This is a melodrama about an abused and taunted teenage girl who just wants love and acceptance. Then she discovers she can move things with her mind. At first she does nothing evil with it, and still tries to get accepted, and manages to do so. But then after a cruel prank involving pig blood, she's now out for human blood. Everyone dies, and this evil she finally unleashes leads to her demise, just like any other tragic character. This is easily my favorite film by director Brian De Palma, and my favorite film based on a Stephen King story. This melodramatic piece of genius never stops satisfying me, and just gets better and better every time I watch it. I highly recommend this to all who are unfortunate enough to have not seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly the best horror movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying that I had not read the book before the film and I was only watching because I had seen the trailer for the upcoming remake. So I started it with no expectations at all and just had nothing better to do. Now down to the review. Right from the beginning this movie entices you in with a lovely period scene in a shower. I had no idea that this was going to happen and was quite surprised because it was handled very well and the actresses were not sexualised by Brian De Palma at all. Next was the entrance of Carrie's not so terrifying mother played by Piper Laurie. Maybe when this came out in 1974 she was scary, but now she's more....really really funny. This is really the only bad thing I can think of about the movie, with the exception of a pointless sex scene later. The next 40 minutes of the movie run pretty smoothly containing simple camera work and medium acting, with the occasional completely pointless sex scene. To make it even worse it has John Travolta in it! But then about 50 minutes in the prom scene arrives which I have already read about on Rotten Tomatoes and is in my opinion....actually not in my opinion IT'S A FACT! One of the most awesome movie scenes ever! Which is surprising because the special effects are a bit dodgy, but I won't deduct points for that because it was the best for the time. After Carrie has awesomely killed a gazabillion people at the prom she decides to go home and change into her pyjamas, which was bit weird considering she had just murdered loads of her classmates. But I won't deduct points for that because it's probably something to do with her telekinesis/puberty experience. Then her mum (who is one of my favourite unintentionally funny characters of all time) stabs her in the back LITERALLY! while they are praying, another reason why I'm atheist folks. Overall CARRIE is one of my favourite movies of all time. Possibly the best horror movie I have ever seen. Starting off at 10 (obviously) I minus 1 point for Piper Laurie being unintentionally hilarious. Then minus 0.3 points for a pointless sex scene. And finally minus 0.2 points for Carrie killing loads of people then going home as if nothing has happened. So I give Carrie- 8.5 out of 10 and 4 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carrie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Toronto85
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shy young girl gets back at her high school bullies using telekinetic powers in 'Carrie'. Carrie White is graduating high school, yet has no one to take her to the prom. She has no friends and all of the girls at school pick on her constantly. On top of all that, her mother is a religious nut who emotionally and physically abuses her at home. After picking on Carrie, fellow classmate Sue Snell decides to make it up to her by having her own boyfriend Tommy ask Carrie to the prom. After much reluctance, Tommy asks her out and they head off for the big night. The bullies fix it so that Tommy/Carrie are picked as king and queen in order for pig's blood to land right on the poor girl. That's when Carrie loses control and all HELL breaks loose at the high school. 'Carrie' is an amazing fantasy/horror film. Director Brian De Palma does such a good job with 'Carrie'. We get the flashes of the magical prom mixed in with Kris planning to dump the pig's blood over Carrie. The plot of the shy girl getting back at her bullies is a satisfying one, but with the added idea of telekinesis makes an even more exciting movie. The acting was really well done by everyone! Sissy Spacek puts in a good job as the lead Carrie, Piper Laurie is convincing as Carrie's crazed religious mother, and I REALLY thought Amy Irving was wonderful as Sue Snell. John Travolta, PJ Soles and Nancy Allen were great too as the villains. All around, a really good cast. It's always fun to see bullies get theirs in movies, but 'Carrie' takes it up a notch. I'd recommend this for sure to every horror fan. It's well acted, got a great cast and tells a pretty satisfying but sad story. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more than a film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    each adaptation of Stephen King novels is a delicate action. because , more than expectation of readers, important is the vision of director. and, sure, the cast. Carrie is out of this law. because it is not part of an genre or expectation in ordinary sense. it is a classic but not is its virtue. it is extraordinary expression of Sissy Spacek performance but not is the essential part. because, out of definitions, it is a mirror. the horror side is only trace of a profound tragedy who defines our world. the blood, the expression of Carrie face, the shadow of mother, the end, all represents images for ordinary state of each of us. it is so human, so cruel in manner to expose the deep truth about society than it is not, in time, only a good/extraordinary/admirable movie, it is a warning. and clear mirror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent horror mystery thriller! 8!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen many movies based on books written by Stephen King. In fact, I would consider myself a King's fan if I had read, at least, one of the numerous books he has written. "Carrie" is one of the best of them I saw. King's traits are very visible in this story: his sense of humour, horror, supernatural elements, mystery, drama, good performances, etc. The fact that John Travolta acted in the movie and that Brian de Palma directed it made me wish to watch "Carrie". Moreover, I am looking forward to seeing its remake. This movie is wonderfully directed with the right pace and duration. Brian de Palma did a very entertaining job with a very good script. The story is about a teenage girl who has telekinetic abilities and is bullied by her schoolmates. She lacks of a social life and is not like most teenagers. Moreover, she lives with her mother, who is a very possessive and mad women left by his husband. I prefer not to tell anything else about the plot not to spoil. The cast is mainly composed by Sissy Spacek, Piper Laurie and John Travolta. Sissy Spacek delivered a solid performance, maybe, a little bit overacted. The performances are very correct. The story is original and the capacity of entertainment is really high. The plot and the performances are the strongest points of this movie. There are several shocking scenes which are very amazing. In conclusion, this is a must-see for those like the stories from King. 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect cinema classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombiefan89
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't really even consider Carrie a horror movie. Sissy Spacek was just to adorable to find threatening, even when she went fully homicidal. Everything she did felt justified. However, if I had to say the biggest issue with the film was the ending. It made no sense at all. Why did they blame Carrie for the gym catching on fire? How did they know Carrie didn't die in the gym with everyone else? There were no survivors except the two antagonists, but they died shortly after. Let's say there were survivors, Did they all unanimously accept that Carrie had psychic powers and caused the fire? Why and how did they blame Carrie? It was like Light Yagami in Death Note, who could kill people by writing their name down and thinking of their face as they do it. They accepted that a notebook could kill people WAY too easily! No court on Earth would have convicted Light Yagami of being "Kira" because there was NO solid proof! I had a complete opposite reaction to the "surprise ending", I would have immediately started digging her out, trying to save her life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
