<filme>
 <id>
  451
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0077631
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1978
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Grease: Nos Tempos da Brilhantina
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Good girl Sandy and greaser Danny fell in love over the summer. But when they unexpectedly discover they're now in the same high school, will they be able to rekindle their romance?
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A musical about teens in love in the 50's! It's California, 1959 and greaser Danny Zuko and Australian Sandy Olsson are in love. They spend time at the beach, but when they go back to school, what either of them don't know is that they both now attend Rydell High. Danny's the leader of the T-Birds, a group of black-jacket greasers while Sandy hangs with the Pink Ladies, a group of pink-wearing girls led by Rizzo. When they clash at Rydell's first pep rally, Danny isn't the same Danny at the beach. They try to be like each other so they can be together.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Musical
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   school
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   beach
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   greaser
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   high school
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Randal Kleiser
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jim Jacobs
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Warren Casey
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   John Travolta
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Olivia Newton-John
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Stockard Channing
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite musicals that was a highlight of my youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw this film in its entirety (prior to this I saw the musical number clips on VH1) was at the cinema when it was re-released for its 20th anniversary when I was 11 and in my first year at secondary school. Re-visiting this film today brought back many memories, especially my Eisteddfod performance of 'Summer Nights (one of the best songs)' with my form. Before I saw the film in full, I'd listen to the film's soundtrack on tape on 'Wet Play' days (playtime in the classroom on rainy days) with my fellow classmates at primary school. There are plenty of positive aspects of this film such as the majority of musical numbers being memorable (with the exception of There Are Worse Things I Could Do,' Rizzo's second solo performance that I completely forgot about), especially 'Grease Is The Word,' 'Summer Nights,' 'Look At Me I'm Sandra Dee,' 'Hopelessly Devoted To You,' 'Greased Lightning (and the dance to go with it), 'Beauty School Dropout,' 'Sandy (my housemate does a brilliant rendition of this one),' You're The One That I Want (which I also remember from a Shape yoghurt advert from my childhood) and 'We Go Together (which sounds a little like all versions of 'The Tide Is High') as well as a version of 'La Bamba' being played in the background in the first Frosty Palace scene; the costumes and vehicles that were true to the 1950s setting; the impressive choreography (especially the school dance scene) and the odd funny moment, especially the scene where Jan imitates the beaver in the toothpaste commercial at the slumber party at Frenchy's house - I couldn't help myself laughing at that today! I also liked the animated segments consisting of the title sequence, toothpaste commercial and the promotional refreshment animations at the drive-in. After having watched the Nostalgia Chick's review of this film, she helped me notice things I hadn't on previous viewings such as Rizzo feeling like a defective typewriter and her pregnancy rumours, although one thing I noticed for the first time today was product placement (a Reese's Peanut Butter Cups billboard ad in the opening sequence and Jan eating a Twinkie at Frenchy's slumber party). The songs made the film go quickly and they were broken up by the various antics of the T-Birds and the Pink Ladies whether they were hanging out at Frosty Palace or partaking in a car chase. I also remember the up-and-down relationship between the two protagonists very fondly. Overall this is a thoroughly enjoyable musical that has sheer nostalgic value and I'd undoubtedly like to see it time and time again. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Simply Critic-Proof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_rawjalaurence
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are quite simply critic-proof: GREASE is one of these. Forget the flat filming style (by Randal Kleiser) and the fact that the Rydale High students seem way too mature - we should just sit back and enjoy the songs, color, movement and sheer energy of the film. John Travolta's Danny is both arrogant yet touching; someone willing to show bravado in front of his male buddies, yet extremely weak when it comes to showing off his emotions. His body movements are a joy to watch - especially during the sequence where he presents Sandy (Olivia Newton- John) with a cheap ring and asks her to marry him. Newton-John is especially good as a Doris Day/ Sandra Dee-type figure who cannot quite understand why Danny should behave so differently in front of his buddies. Stockard Channing's Rizzo quite simply steals the show; she cultivates a hard-boiled exterior (her real name in the film is Betty), yet cannot cover up an essential vulnerability, especially when she thinks that she is pregnant. GREASE also contains a clutch of memorable cameos from television and film old-timers, from Sid Caesar's Coach Calhoun to Eve Arden's Principal McGee, to Joan Blondell's Vi. In short, there is something in this film for absolutely everyone, regardless of their age and/or cinematic tastes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is the word that you Heard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Samantha Rios
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease is the word. There are many musicals in the world but not one compare to the musical that is Grease. You have the T-birds and the Pink Ladies and new incomer Sandy Olsson, who overall take the story through twists and turns. Good girl Sandy and Greaser Danny must make life-changing decisions on whether being who they are now is worth loosing the one they most care about. Like most musicals, Grease tells their audience the story through song engaging the audience. With the song "Summer Nights" we are introduced into the background information on how exactly Sandy and Danny met during the summer. With the two stories not adding up we get a feel on the personalities of bad boy Danny and sweet and innocent Sandy. After running into each other at a pep rally for the football team, Sandy runs off crying after being humiliated by the bad boy Danny in front of his fellow T-birds and Pink Ladies. Throughout the story we see the numerous attempts by both Danny and Sandy to show one another whether it be changing from a leather jacket to a letterman jacket or dating a jock in attempts to make him jealous. Through "Hopelessly Devoted to You" and " Sandy" the couple show that no matter what they are going through now they cant and wont stop loving each other. While the Danny and Sandy are trying to make things work, Danny's second in command Kenickie is out to beat T-birds rival gang The Scorpions in a race were they will be racing for ownership papers of the cars or what they call "Pinks". Though a series of unfortunate events and Kenickie is incapable of racing he asks his friend Danny to take his place. After winning the race and defeating their rivals we see that Sandy has been watching the race from afar. Asking Pink Ladies' Frenchy for a makeover we see that not only did Danny make the transition from leather jacket to letterman but also Sandy went from innocent to Pink Lady newcomer. In the final scene Rydell High School has rewarded the graduating class with a senior carnival. Here we get the first look at new and improved Danny Zuko who has indeed traded in his T-bird jacket, but he isn't the only one who made a drastic change. After reassuring his fellow boys that this change in jackets didn't mean the end to their friendship, Danny is soon interrupted by the new Sandy Olsson. "You're The One That I Want" is the final song number the couple sing showing that they both changed their ways to be with each other and in the end it worked out for the best. The final number the T-birds and the Pink Ladies perform is the song, " We Go Together". This number gives the audience the final feel for the movie and the two groups of friends as they part ways. Yes the movie isn't the most relevant and up to date movie, but it still has what it takes to be a classic. With the love story that Grease takes us on, we take a trip when not just the girl has to change for the guy but also the guy goes through endless activities to be with his one true love. This movie is one you can't get tired of. The more you watch the more the songs stick with you and with the songs it just adds in to the affect that comes with watching Grease. Grease really and truly is the word. And it's a movie that is worthy enough to be considered a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless and epic musical from my childhood!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a brief note, I have never heard of this film before and I'm only a 90s kind of guy at the time I was a little kid until one day, my father got it on video. Being interested, I watched it and after the first time after my viewing, I became amazed by how epic this film is. I mean, of all the musicals I've seen in every high school production along with cinema, this really takes the cake as one of the best ones yet. Sure, it is a little long and some of the dialog is pretty corny, but hey, those two problems are just nitpicks. Everything else is perfect and holds up well even as a young adult. THe story is amazing with lots of charm and romance that would make you fall in love. The direction from Randal Kleiser is fine and the 1950s setting along with the costumes are brilliant. The characters are pretty good too and the acting is great. John Travolta is a charming Danny Zuko and Olivia Newton-John is a cute and beautiful Sandy. The best part, however, would have to go to the musical song sequences helped by excellent choreography. The songs, "Grease Is The Word", "Summer Nights", "Hopelessly Devoted", "Greased Lightning", "You're The One That I Want", "We'll Be Together" and such are, and always will be, memorable on their own right you will end up humming them for a few hours. Overall, Grease is an epic musical that would always remain in my memory for all time and is recommended to those who haven't seen it yet! It is that good, guys. I'm not gonna lie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wafer thin plot, but still a blast thanks to energy, exuberance and toe-tapping musical numbers.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathon Dabell (barnaby.rudge@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease, like a fine wine, has grown with age. It was a phenomenally successful film in its time but its commercial popularity was not equalled by its critical reception. Not that contemporary critics were especially negative towards it, more that they approved it with blandly above average reviews. To be sure, the plot of Grease is wafer thin and its narrative borders on non-existent between the musical set pieces.. However, it is a film which transcends the basic requirements of strong plot and narrative. It's about joyous set pieces. It's about goofy characters, interacting via goofy dialogue. It's about nostalgia. It's about awkward teen courtship. It's about those last days of high school where the joy of being young is ever-so-slightly tarnished by the encroaching end of one's educational era. The final scene of John Travolta and Olivia Newton John driving off into the sky in a flying car roots the film in a dreamy nostalgic/retrospective landscape, reminding us that we've been watching a fun musical fantasy, nothing more. In terms of achieving its goals  entertaining the audience, rocking us out, and putting a smile on our face  Grease does exactly what it says on the tin. It's the start of a new school year at Rydell High, and T-Bird gang member Danny Zuko (John Travolta) enthusiastically tells his friends about a summer romance that he has enjoyed during the holidays. Unbeknown to him, his summer sweetheart Sandy (Olivia Newton John), has not returned to Australia as expected but, in fact, has enrolled at the same high school, where she relates her amazing summer of love with Danny to her new classmates. When they eventually run into each other, Danny can't bring himself to be his true self in front of his friends. Embarrassed by his gushing sentiments, his genuine feelings for Sandy, he treats her off-handedly, cruelly even, and it seems impossible that they will ever rediscover their magical connection. Throughout the continuing story of Danny and Sandy's difficult on/off romance, we also follow the exploits of the other characters in their circle  the risqu&eacute; relationship between Kenickie (Jeff Conaway) and Rizzo (Stockard Channing); the rivalry between the T-Birds and another gang, the Scorpions, culminating in a classic car race; an impending dance contest at Rydell; and the final graduation (and goodbyes) of each of the gang. What makes Grease work above everything else is the charm, enthusiasm and energy with which it is presented. There's a sense of everyone pulling in the same direction, entering into the spirit of things in a manner that becomes immediately infectious. The characters are at once lovable and identifiable; their actions and reactions cleverly tuned into real people and real feelings, but dressed up in a joyous musical approach. The musical set pieces are very well done indeed  all the songs pretty much deliver, getting the audience toe-tapping in spite of themselves. Best of all is the sensational closing number, You're The One That I Want, brilliantly choreographed against a fairground backdrop, and featuring Newton John shedding her bookish image and wooing Danny in cinema's most infamous tight leather pants. Performance-wise the film is generally pretty good. Travolta and Newton John have a lovely chemistry, even if their characters are a mite too broadly painted at times. Channing is fabulous as the scene-stealing Rizzo, and Eve Arden has some moments of pure comedic gold as the disapproving school principal Miss McGee. Enduringly popular, always fresh and fun to watch, and a real sing-along favourite, Grease is vastly entertaining if nothing else. Yes, its narrative meanders without much direction at times, but Grease is still a blast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Get Ready To Laugh And Have A Great Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Step right up ladies and gentleman! Get ready to laugh and have a great time! Get ready to watch a delight that you will never forget! Okay, I know that I sound like a game show host, but you'll understand it. From director Randal Kleiser comes a musical comedy that just about anybody is bound to enjoy! That film is the 1978 musical masterpiece that we all know as Grease! That's right people! Grease is a wonderful movie, I repeat, a wonderful movie, an absolutely wonderful movie that is! Why is the movie great? Well step right up to find out why! This movie is funny for one thing, and when I say funny, I mean funny. Funny scenes in this film include any scene in which John Travolta sings in his falsetto, and the restaurant scene, not to mention the recurring school chimes gag. The music is outstanding, no really, it was, about 100% of the time, I was tapping my feet and clapping my hands to the beat of the music. The music in this movie is the type of music that makes you want to get up and dance. And you'll see what I mean! Just watch the film, you'll love it! John Travolta shines in his role as Danny Zuko, a high school senior who finds out that his girlfriend, Sandy Olsen (played fabulously by Olivia Newton-John), is going to the same school as he is (however, his relationship with her is a bit strained). Can these two lovers rekindle the flame for each other? The answer to that question lies in this wonderful musical comedy filled with laughs, passions, great music, great acting, great singing, and just about everything else that you would expect to see from a musical classic. Like musical classics like Singin' In The Rain, My Fair Lady, Seven Brides For Seven Brothers, and 42nd Street among others, most musical films don't get any better than this! This is one of the best movies of 1978, and one of the best musical films that you'll ever see! I am not kidding about that, this film is a classic, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean by that statement! Do you want to see a musical film that you will definitely have fun viewing? Then you have got absolutely nothing to worry about, because the movie known as Grease is just the film for you, it's wonderful, it's marvelous, it's...well, you'll probably understand it when you watch it, which is what you should precisely do! If I was given the chance to watch this fabulous film as second time, I would definitely take that chance and do it, as I loved this film, I loved it all the way through from start to finish! This is a definite must see as far as musical films go, and possibly even as far as films in general go, it's a whole lot of fun, and when I say fun, I mean super fun! Anyway, if you haven't seen this movie, then all I can say is that you have got to see it, because you are missing out on something grand. Ladies and gentlemen, I am proud to present to you a musical classic that's enjoyable for just about everyone, that's the 1978 marvel, Grease. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbewnylorac
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My high school drama teacher pointed out something that a lot of this viewers don't get -- it's a satire! People who hate Grease actually think it's supposed to be a true reflection of early 1960s America, but it's a comedy, a spoof, and it's meant to be fun entertainment. The songs are the best thing, from the pounding opening song, Grease, to the lovely Travolta showpiece ballad, Sandy to the dance spectacular, Hand Jive. There are quite a few silly bits, such as Jan singing the toothbrush song and most of Frenchy's dialogue, but you've got to remember that this is a movie about teenagers, for teenagers, although most of the cast were aged in their 20s and 30s. Highlights for me included Beauty School Dropout by Frankie Avalon, There are Worse Things I Could Do by Stockard Channing and Hopelessly Devoted to You by Olivia Newton-John. Grease was a musical we did at my high school, and it'sjust a quality production that's hugely enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Masturbation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen7272
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    However much sugar you coat this with, Grease is a movie about teenagers expectations for future sex. The film is essentially split into two components. The first is the pre- puberty story of boy loves girl with sugar coated candy floss. The second, the post-puberty, part of the film only takes up the last 15 minutes, is about boys and girls doing the stuff they do prior to back-seat copulation. As a musical the songs essentially come from the pages of a girlie magazine for 13 year old wannabee love hearts. But as adults we view this with nostalgia, for those days before we had to go to work, take out mortgages and bring up families of our own. It reflects that short period of exciting sexual frustration and freedom that society soon inoculates us against until we rediscover it somewhere around our mid-50's. More socially importantly, this is a movie about the beginnings of the Baby Boomer generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease (1978).
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_manRedux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's basically no story structure, the film is episodic and really kind of plot less. Most of these characters are paper thin and the words on the page basically just introduce situations into the screen with no breathing room. The film is so borderline campy it edges on the ridiculous, there's not enough scenes between Sandy and Danny, and don't even get me started on Sandy's late act switch from naive schoolgirl to sultry bombshell (although Jim Jacobs' explanation for this change is very interesting, it doesn't come off in a convincing way on screen). And yet...it works. There's an infusing energy in this film that can only be chalked up to its pitch-perfect cast, who breathe life into these caricatures, and to Randal Kleiser's underrated direction. As far as musicals go (a genre that, I'll admit, I'm not a fan of), this is one of the most entertaining offerings, particularly because it doesn't take itself so seriously like so many modern musicals do. Jeff Conaway and Stockard Channing are scene-stealers, Olivia Newton-John is a charming presence, but it's Travolta's spirited and hilarious performance that takes the cake as MVP.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes Grease girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ronnyk-0101
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm twenty three. My girlfriends and I have real conversations like this. We're poor, fresh out of college, and headed toward grad school (hopefully.) What I'm getting at is this show is relevant to our lives, it's realistic and actually funny. Not all women were like Sex and the City and it's been said that Carrie's extravagant lifestyle was not realistic, this show is. I hate to compare the two but Girls blows SATC out of the water. This show is fresh, funny, and so true that it hurts. Lena Dunham is not only a phenomenal actress but the entire premise is so new and amazing that it's hard to believe she writes and directs each episode. Love is so far and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite musicals that was a highlight of my youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw this film in its entirety (prior to this I saw the musical number clips on VH1) was at the cinema when it was re-released for its 20th anniversary when I was 11 and in my first year at secondary school. Re-visiting this film today brought back many memories, especially my Eisteddfod performance of 'Summer Nights (one of the best songs)' with my form. Before I saw the film in full, I'd listen to the film's soundtrack on tape on 'Wet Play' days (playtime in the classroom on rainy days) with my fellow classmates at primary school. There are plenty of positive aspects of this film such as the majority of musical numbers being memorable (with the exception of There Are Worse Things I Could Do,' Rizzo's second solo performance that I completely forgot about), especially 'Grease Is The Word,' 'Summer Nights,' 'Look At Me I'm Sandra Dee,' 'Hopelessly Devoted To You,' 'Greased Lightning (and the dance to go with it), 'Beauty School Dropout,' 'Sandy (my housemate does a brilliant rendition of this one),' You're The One That I Want (which I also remember from a Shape yoghurt advert from my childhood) and 'We Go Together (which sounds a little like all versions of 'The Tide Is High') as well as a version of 'La Bamba' being played in the background in the first Frosty Palace scene; the costumes and vehicles that were true to the 1950s setting; the impressive choreography (especially the school dance scene) and the odd funny moment, especially the scene where Jan imitates the beaver in the toothpaste commercial at the slumber party at Frenchy's house - I couldn't help myself laughing at that today! I also liked the animated segments consisting of the title sequence, toothpaste commercial and the promotional refreshment animations at the drive-in. After having watched the Nostalgia Chick's review of this film, she helped me notice things I hadn't on previous viewings such as Rizzo feeling like a defective typewriter and her pregnancy rumours, although one thing I noticed for the first time today was product placement (a Reese's Peanut Butter Cups billboard ad in the opening sequence and Jan eating a Twinkie at Frenchy's slumber party). The songs made the film go quickly and they were broken up by the various antics of the T-Birds and the Pink Ladies whether they were hanging out at Frosty Palace or partaking in a car chase. I also remember the up-and-down relationship between the two protagonists very fondly. Overall this is a thoroughly enjoyable musical that has sheer nostalgic value and I'd undoubtedly like to see it time and time again. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Simply Critic-Proof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_rawjalaurence
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are quite simply critic-proof: GREASE is one of these. Forget the flat filming style (by Randal Kleiser) and the fact that the Rydale High students seem way too mature - we should just sit back and enjoy the songs, color, movement and sheer energy of the film. John Travolta's Danny is both arrogant yet touching; someone willing to show bravado in front of his male buddies, yet extremely weak when it comes to showing off his emotions. His body movements are a joy to watch - especially during the sequence where he presents Sandy (Olivia Newton- John) with a cheap ring and asks her to marry him. Newton-John is especially good as a Doris Day/ Sandra Dee-type figure who cannot quite understand why Danny should behave so differently in front of his buddies. Stockard Channing's Rizzo quite simply steals the show; she cultivates a hard-boiled exterior (her real name in the film is Betty), yet cannot cover up an essential vulnerability, especially when she thinks that she is pregnant. GREASE also contains a clutch of memorable cameos from television and film old-timers, from Sid Caesar's Coach Calhoun to Eve Arden's Principal McGee, to Joan Blondell's Vi. In short, there is something in this film for absolutely everyone, regardless of their age and/or cinematic tastes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is the word that you Heard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Samantha Rios
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease is the word. There are many musicals in the world but not one compare to the musical that is Grease. You have the T-birds and the Pink Ladies and new incomer Sandy Olsson, who overall take the story through twists and turns. Good girl Sandy and Greaser Danny must make life-changing decisions on whether being who they are now is worth loosing the one they most care about. Like most musicals, Grease tells their audience the story through song engaging the audience. With the song "Summer Nights" we are introduced into the background information on how exactly Sandy and Danny met during the summer. With the two stories not adding up we get a feel on the personalities of bad boy Danny and sweet and innocent Sandy. After running into each other at a pep rally for the football team, Sandy runs off crying after being humiliated by the bad boy Danny in front of his fellow T-birds and Pink Ladies. Throughout the story we see the numerous attempts by both Danny and Sandy to show one another whether it be changing from a leather jacket to a letterman jacket or dating a jock in attempts to make him jealous. Through "Hopelessly Devoted to You" and " Sandy" the couple show that no matter what they are going through now they cant and wont stop loving each other. While the Danny and Sandy are trying to make things work, Danny's second in command Kenickie is out to beat T-birds rival gang The Scorpions in a race were they will be racing for ownership papers of the cars or what they call "Pinks". Though a series of unfortunate events and Kenickie is incapable of racing he asks his friend Danny to take his place. After winning the race and defeating their rivals we see that Sandy has been watching the race from afar. Asking Pink Ladies' Frenchy for a makeover we see that not only did Danny make the transition from leather jacket to letterman but also Sandy went from innocent to Pink Lady newcomer. In the final scene Rydell High School has rewarded the graduating class with a senior carnival. Here we get the first look at new and improved Danny Zuko who has indeed traded in his T-bird jacket, but he isn't the only one who made a drastic change. After reassuring his fellow boys that this change in jackets didn't mean the end to their friendship, Danny is soon interrupted by the new Sandy Olsson. "You're The One That I Want" is the final song number the couple sing showing that they both changed their ways to be with each other and in the end it worked out for the best. The final number the T-birds and the Pink Ladies perform is the song, " We Go Together". This number gives the audience the final feel for the movie and the two groups of friends as they part ways. Yes the movie isn't the most relevant and up to date movie, but it still has what it takes to be a classic. With the love story that Grease takes us on, we take a trip when not just the girl has to change for the guy but also the guy goes through endless activities to be with his one true love. This movie is one you can't get tired of. The more you watch the more the songs stick with you and with the songs it just adds in to the affect that comes with watching Grease. Grease really and truly is the word. And it's a movie that is worthy enough to be considered a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless and epic musical from my childhood!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a brief note, I have never heard of this film before and I'm only a 90s kind of guy at the time I was a little kid until one day, my father got it on video. Being interested, I watched it and after the first time after my viewing, I became amazed by how epic this film is. I mean, of all the musicals I've seen in every high school production along with cinema, this really takes the cake as one of the best ones yet. Sure, it is a little long and some of the dialog is pretty corny, but hey, those two problems are just nitpicks. Everything else is perfect and holds up well even as a young adult. THe story is amazing with lots of charm and romance that would make you fall in love. The direction from Randal Kleiser is fine and the 1950s setting along with the costumes are brilliant. The characters are pretty good too and the acting is great. John Travolta is a charming Danny Zuko and Olivia Newton-John is a cute and beautiful Sandy. The best part, however, would have to go to the musical song sequences helped by excellent choreography. The songs, "Grease Is The Word", "Summer Nights", "Hopelessly Devoted", "Greased Lightning", "You're The One That I Want", "We'll Be Together" and such are, and always will be, memorable on their own right you will end up humming them for a few hours. Overall, Grease is an epic musical that would always remain in my memory for all time and is recommended to those who haven't seen it yet! It is that good, guys. I'm not gonna lie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wafer thin plot, but still a blast thanks to energy, exuberance and toe-tapping musical numbers.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathon Dabell (barnaby.rudge@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease, like a fine wine, has grown with age. It was a phenomenally successful film in its time but its commercial popularity was not equalled by its critical reception. Not that contemporary critics were especially negative towards it, more that they approved it with blandly above average reviews. To be sure, the plot of Grease is wafer thin and its narrative borders on non-existent between the musical set pieces.. However, it is a film which transcends the basic requirements of strong plot and narrative. It's about joyous set pieces. It's about goofy characters, interacting via goofy dialogue. It's about nostalgia. It's about awkward teen courtship. It's about those last days of high school where the joy of being young is ever-so-slightly tarnished by the encroaching end of one's educational era. The final scene of John Travolta and Olivia Newton John driving off into the sky in a flying car roots the film in a dreamy nostalgic/retrospective landscape, reminding us that we've been watching a fun musical fantasy, nothing more. In terms of achieving its goals  entertaining the audience, rocking us out, and putting a smile on our face  Grease does exactly what it says on the tin. It's the start of a new school year at Rydell High, and T-Bird gang member Danny Zuko (John Travolta) enthusiastically tells his friends about a summer romance that he has enjoyed during the holidays. Unbeknown to him, his summer sweetheart Sandy (Olivia Newton John), has not returned to Australia as expected but, in fact, has enrolled at the same high school, where she relates her amazing summer of love with Danny to her new classmates. When they eventually run into each other, Danny can't bring himself to be his true self in front of his friends. Embarrassed by his gushing sentiments, his genuine feelings for Sandy, he treats her off-handedly, cruelly even, and it seems impossible that they will ever rediscover their magical connection. Throughout the continuing story of Danny and Sandy's difficult on/off romance, we also follow the exploits of the other characters in their circle  the risqu&eacute; relationship between Kenickie (Jeff Conaway) and Rizzo (Stockard Channing); the rivalry between the T-Birds and another gang, the Scorpions, culminating in a classic car race; an impending dance contest at Rydell; and the final graduation (and goodbyes) of each of the gang. What makes Grease work above everything else is the charm, enthusiasm and energy with which it is presented. There's a sense of everyone pulling in the same direction, entering into the spirit of things in a manner that becomes immediately infectious. The characters are at once lovable and identifiable; their actions and reactions cleverly tuned into real people and real feelings, but dressed up in a joyous musical approach. The musical set pieces are very well done indeed  all the songs pretty much deliver, getting the audience toe-tapping in spite of themselves. Best of all is the sensational closing number, You're The One That I Want, brilliantly choreographed against a fairground backdrop, and featuring Newton John shedding her bookish image and wooing Danny in cinema's most infamous tight leather pants. Performance-wise the film is generally pretty good. Travolta and Newton John have a lovely chemistry, even if their characters are a mite too broadly painted at times. Channing is fabulous as the scene-stealing Rizzo, and Eve Arden has some moments of pure comedic gold as the disapproving school principal Miss McGee. Enduringly popular, always fresh and fun to watch, and a real sing-along favourite, Grease is vastly entertaining if nothing else. Yes, its narrative meanders without much direction at times, but Grease is still a blast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Get Ready To Laugh And Have A Great Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Step right up ladies and gentleman! Get ready to laugh and have a great time! Get ready to watch a delight that you will never forget! Okay, I know that I sound like a game show host, but you'll understand it. From director Randal Kleiser comes a musical comedy that just about anybody is bound to enjoy! That film is the 1978 musical masterpiece that we all know as Grease! That's right people! Grease is a wonderful movie, I repeat, a wonderful movie, an absolutely wonderful movie that is! Why is the movie great? Well step right up to find out why! This movie is funny for one thing, and when I say funny, I mean funny. Funny scenes in this film include any scene in which John Travolta sings in his falsetto, and the restaurant scene, not to mention the recurring school chimes gag. The music is outstanding, no really, it was, about 100% of the time, I was tapping my feet and clapping my hands to the beat of the music. The music in this movie is the type of music that makes you want to get up and dance. And you'll see what I mean! Just watch the film, you'll love it! John Travolta shines in his role as Danny Zuko, a high school senior who finds out that his girlfriend, Sandy Olsen (played fabulously by Olivia Newton-John), is going to the same school as he is (however, his relationship with her is a bit strained). Can these two lovers rekindle the flame for each other? The answer to that question lies in this wonderful musical comedy filled with laughs, passions, great music, great acting, great singing, and just about everything else that you would expect to see from a musical classic. Like musical classics like Singin' In The Rain, My Fair Lady, Seven Brides For Seven Brothers, and 42nd Street among others, most musical films don't get any better than this! This is one of the best movies of 1978, and one of the best musical films that you'll ever see! I am not kidding about that, this film is a classic, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean by that statement! Do you want to see a musical film that you will definitely have fun viewing? Then you have got absolutely nothing to worry about, because the movie known as Grease is just the film for you, it's wonderful, it's marvelous, it's...well, you'll probably understand it when you watch it, which is what you should precisely do! If I was given the chance to watch this fabulous film as second time, I would definitely take that chance and do it, as I loved this film, I loved it all the way through from start to finish! This is a definite must see as far as musical films go, and possibly even as far as films in general go, it's a whole lot of fun, and when I say fun, I mean super fun! Anyway, if you haven't seen this movie, then all I can say is that you have got to see it, because you are missing out on something grand. Ladies and gentlemen, I am proud to present to you a musical classic that's enjoyable for just about everyone, that's the 1978 marvel, Grease. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbewnylorac
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My high school drama teacher pointed out something that a lot of this viewers don't get -- it's a satire! People who hate Grease actually think it's supposed to be a true reflection of early 1960s America, but it's a comedy, a spoof, and it's meant to be fun entertainment. The songs are the best thing, from the pounding opening song, Grease, to the lovely Travolta showpiece ballad, Sandy to the dance spectacular, Hand Jive. There are quite a few silly bits, such as Jan singing the toothbrush song and most of Frenchy's dialogue, but you've got to remember that this is a movie about teenagers, for teenagers, although most of the cast were aged in their 20s and 30s. Highlights for me included Beauty School Dropout by Frankie Avalon, There are Worse Things I Could Do by Stockard Channing and Hopelessly Devoted to You by Olivia Newton-John. Grease was a musical we did at my high school, and it'sjust a quality production that's hugely enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Masturbation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen7272
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    However much sugar you coat this with, Grease is a movie about teenagers expectations for future sex. The film is essentially split into two components. The first is the pre- puberty story of boy loves girl with sugar coated candy floss. The second, the post-puberty, part of the film only takes up the last 15 minutes, is about boys and girls doing the stuff they do prior to back-seat copulation. As a musical the songs essentially come from the pages of a girlie magazine for 13 year old wannabee love hearts. But as adults we view this with nostalgia, for those days before we had to go to work, take out mortgages and bring up families of our own. It reflects that short period of exciting sexual frustration and freedom that society soon inoculates us against until we rediscover it somewhere around our mid-50's. More socially importantly, this is a movie about the beginnings of the Baby Boomer generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease (1978).
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_manRedux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's basically no story structure, the film is episodic and really kind of plot less. Most of these characters are paper thin and the words on the page basically just introduce situations into the screen with no breathing room. The film is so borderline campy it edges on the ridiculous, there's not enough scenes between Sandy and Danny, and don't even get me started on Sandy's late act switch from naive schoolgirl to sultry bombshell (although Jim Jacobs' explanation for this change is very interesting, it doesn't come off in a convincing way on screen). And yet...it works. There's an infusing energy in this film that can only be chalked up to its pitch-perfect cast, who breathe life into these caricatures, and to Randal Kleiser's underrated direction. As far as musicals go (a genre that, I'll admit, I'm not a fan of), this is one of the most entertaining offerings, particularly because it doesn't take itself so seriously like so many modern musicals do. Jeff Conaway and Stockard Channing are scene-stealers, Olivia Newton-John is a charming presence, but it's Travolta's spirited and hilarious performance that takes the cake as MVP.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes Grease girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ronnyk-0101
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm twenty three. My girlfriends and I have real conversations like this. We're poor, fresh out of college, and headed toward grad school (hopefully.) What I'm getting at is this show is relevant to our lives, it's realistic and actually funny. Not all women were like Sex and the City and it's been said that Carrie's extravagant lifestyle was not realistic, this show is. I hate to compare the two but Girls blows SATC out of the water. This show is fresh, funny, and so true that it hurts. Lena Dunham is not only a phenomenal actress but the entire premise is so new and amazing that it's hard to believe she writes and directs each episode. Love is so far and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite musicals that was a highlight of my youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw this film in its entirety (prior to this I saw the musical number clips on VH1) was at the cinema when it was re-released for its 20th anniversary when I was 11 and in my first year at secondary school. Re-visiting this film today brought back many memories, especially my Eisteddfod performance of 'Summer Nights (one of the best songs)' with my form. Before I saw the film in full, I'd listen to the film's soundtrack on tape on 'Wet Play' days (playtime in the classroom on rainy days) with my fellow classmates at primary school. There are plenty of positive aspects of this film such as the majority of musical numbers being memorable (with the exception of There Are Worse Things I Could Do,' Rizzo's second solo performance that I completely forgot about), especially 'Grease Is The Word,' 'Summer Nights,' 'Look At Me I'm Sandra Dee,' 'Hopelessly Devoted To You,' 'Greased Lightning (and the dance to go with it), 'Beauty School Dropout,' 'Sandy (my housemate does a brilliant rendition of this one),' You're The One That I Want (which I also remember from a Shape yoghurt advert from my childhood) and 'We Go Together (which sounds a little like all versions of 'The Tide Is High') as well as a version of 'La Bamba' being played in the background in the first Frosty Palace scene; the costumes and vehicles that were true to the 1950s setting; the impressive choreography (especially the school dance scene) and the odd funny moment, especially the scene where Jan imitates the beaver in the toothpaste commercial at the slumber party at Frenchy's house - I couldn't help myself laughing at that today! I also liked the animated segments consisting of the title sequence, toothpaste commercial and the promotional refreshment animations at the drive-in. After having watched the Nostalgia Chick's review of this film, she helped me notice things I hadn't on previous viewings such as Rizzo feeling like a defective typewriter and her pregnancy rumours, although one thing I noticed for the first time today was product placement (a Reese's Peanut Butter Cups billboard ad in the opening sequence and Jan eating a Twinkie at Frenchy's slumber party). The songs made the film go quickly and they were broken up by the various antics of the T-Birds and the Pink Ladies whether they were hanging out at Frosty Palace or partaking in a car chase. I also remember the up-and-down relationship between the two protagonists very fondly. Overall this is a thoroughly enjoyable musical that has sheer nostalgic value and I'd undoubtedly like to see it time and time again. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Simply Critic-Proof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_rawjalaurence
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are quite simply critic-proof: GREASE is one of these. Forget the flat filming style (by Randal Kleiser) and the fact that the Rydale High students seem way too mature - we should just sit back and enjoy the songs, color, movement and sheer energy of the film. John Travolta's Danny is both arrogant yet touching; someone willing to show bravado in front of his male buddies, yet extremely weak when it comes to showing off his emotions. His body movements are a joy to watch - especially during the sequence where he presents Sandy (Olivia Newton- John) with a cheap ring and asks her to marry him. Newton-John is especially good as a Doris Day/ Sandra Dee-type figure who cannot quite understand why Danny should behave so differently in front of his buddies. Stockard Channing's Rizzo quite simply steals the show; she cultivates a hard-boiled exterior (her real name in the film is Betty), yet cannot cover up an essential vulnerability, especially when she thinks that she is pregnant. GREASE also contains a clutch of memorable cameos from television and film old-timers, from Sid Caesar's Coach Calhoun to Eve Arden's Principal McGee, to Joan Blondell's Vi. In short, there is something in this film for absolutely everyone, regardless of their age and/or cinematic tastes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is the word that you Heard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Samantha Rios
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease is the word. There are many musicals in the world but not one compare to the musical that is Grease. You have the T-birds and the Pink Ladies and new incomer Sandy Olsson, who overall take the story through twists and turns. Good girl Sandy and Greaser Danny must make life-changing decisions on whether being who they are now is worth loosing the one they most care about. Like most musicals, Grease tells their audience the story through song engaging the audience. With the song "Summer Nights" we are introduced into the background information on how exactly Sandy and Danny met during the summer. With the two stories not adding up we get a feel on the personalities of bad boy Danny and sweet and innocent Sandy. After running into each other at a pep rally for the football team, Sandy runs off crying after being humiliated by the bad boy Danny in front of his fellow T-birds and Pink Ladies. Throughout the story we see the numerous attempts by both Danny and Sandy to show one another whether it be changing from a leather jacket to a letterman jacket or dating a jock in attempts to make him jealous. Through "Hopelessly Devoted to You" and " Sandy" the couple show that no matter what they are going through now they cant and wont stop loving each other. While the Danny and Sandy are trying to make things work, Danny's second in command Kenickie is out to beat T-birds rival gang The Scorpions in a race were they will be racing for ownership papers of the cars or what they call "Pinks". Though a series of unfortunate events and Kenickie is incapable of racing he asks his friend Danny to take his place. After winning the race and defeating their rivals we see that Sandy has been watching the race from afar. Asking Pink Ladies' Frenchy for a makeover we see that not only did Danny make the transition from leather jacket to letterman but also Sandy went from innocent to Pink Lady newcomer. In the final scene Rydell High School has rewarded the graduating class with a senior carnival. Here we get the first look at new and improved Danny Zuko who has indeed traded in his T-bird jacket, but he isn't the only one who made a drastic change. After reassuring his fellow boys that this change in jackets didn't mean the end to their friendship, Danny is soon interrupted by the new Sandy Olsson. "You're The One That I Want" is the final song number the couple sing showing that they both changed their ways to be with each other and in the end it worked out for the best. The final number the T-birds and the Pink Ladies perform is the song, " We Go Together". This number gives the audience the final feel for the movie and the two groups of friends as they part ways. Yes the movie isn't the most relevant and up to date movie, but it still has what it takes to be a classic. With the love story that Grease takes us on, we take a trip when not just the girl has to change for the guy but also the guy goes through endless activities to be with his one true love. This movie is one you can't get tired of. The more you watch the more the songs stick with you and with the songs it just adds in to the affect that comes with watching Grease. Grease really and truly is the word. And it's a movie that is worthy enough to be considered a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless and epic musical from my childhood!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a brief note, I have never heard of this film before and I'm only a 90s kind of guy at the time I was a little kid until one day, my father got it on video. Being interested, I watched it and after the first time after my viewing, I became amazed by how epic this film is. I mean, of all the musicals I've seen in every high school production along with cinema, this really takes the cake as one of the best ones yet. Sure, it is a little long and some of the dialog is pretty corny, but hey, those two problems are just nitpicks. Everything else is perfect and holds up well even as a young adult. THe story is amazing with lots of charm and romance that would make you fall in love. The direction from Randal Kleiser is fine and the 1950s setting along with the costumes are brilliant. The characters are pretty good too and the acting is great. John Travolta is a charming Danny Zuko and Olivia Newton-John is a cute and beautiful Sandy. The best part, however, would have to go to the musical song sequences helped by excellent choreography. The songs, "Grease Is The Word", "Summer Nights", "Hopelessly Devoted", "Greased Lightning", "You're The One That I Want", "We'll Be Together" and such are, and always will be, memorable on their own right you will end up humming them for a few hours. Overall, Grease is an epic musical that would always remain in my memory for all time and is recommended to those who haven't seen it yet! It is that good, guys. I'm not gonna lie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wafer thin plot, but still a blast thanks to energy, exuberance and toe-tapping musical numbers.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathon Dabell (barnaby.rudge@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease, like a fine wine, has grown with age. It was a phenomenally successful film in its time but its commercial popularity was not equalled by its critical reception. Not that contemporary critics were especially negative towards it, more that they approved it with blandly above average reviews. To be sure, the plot of Grease is wafer thin and its narrative borders on non-existent between the musical set pieces.. However, it is a film which transcends the basic requirements of strong plot and narrative. It's about joyous set pieces. It's about goofy characters, interacting via goofy dialogue. It's about nostalgia. It's about awkward teen courtship. It's about those last days of high school where the joy of being young is ever-so-slightly tarnished by the encroaching end of one's educational era. The final scene of John Travolta and Olivia Newton John driving off into the sky in a flying car roots the film in a dreamy nostalgic/retrospective landscape, reminding us that we've been watching a fun musical fantasy, nothing more. In terms of achieving its goals  entertaining the audience, rocking us out, and putting a smile on our face  Grease does exactly what it says on the tin. It's the start of a new school year at Rydell High, and T-Bird gang member Danny Zuko (John Travolta) enthusiastically tells his friends about a summer romance that he has enjoyed during the holidays. Unbeknown to him, his summer sweetheart Sandy (Olivia Newton John), has not returned to Australia as expected but, in fact, has enrolled at the same high school, where she relates her amazing summer of love with Danny to her new classmates. When they eventually run into each other, Danny can't bring himself to be his true self in front of his friends. Embarrassed by his gushing sentiments, his genuine feelings for Sandy, he treats her off-handedly, cruelly even, and it seems impossible that they will ever rediscover their magical connection. Throughout the continuing story of Danny and Sandy's difficult on/off romance, we also follow the exploits of the other characters in their circle  the risqu&eacute; relationship between Kenickie (Jeff Conaway) and Rizzo (Stockard Channing); the rivalry between the T-Birds and another gang, the Scorpions, culminating in a classic car race; an impending dance contest at Rydell; and the final graduation (and goodbyes) of each of the gang. What makes Grease work above everything else is the charm, enthusiasm and energy with which it is presented. There's a sense of everyone pulling in the same direction, entering into the spirit of things in a manner that becomes immediately infectious. The characters are at once lovable and identifiable; their actions and reactions cleverly tuned into real people and real feelings, but dressed up in a joyous musical approach. The musical set pieces are very well done indeed  all the songs pretty much deliver, getting the audience toe-tapping in spite of themselves. Best of all is the sensational closing number, You're The One That I Want, brilliantly choreographed against a fairground backdrop, and featuring Newton John shedding her bookish image and wooing Danny in cinema's most infamous tight leather pants. Performance-wise the film is generally pretty good. Travolta and Newton John have a lovely chemistry, even if their characters are a mite too broadly painted at times. Channing is fabulous as the scene-stealing Rizzo, and Eve Arden has some moments of pure comedic gold as the disapproving school principal Miss McGee. Enduringly popular, always fresh and fun to watch, and a real sing-along favourite, Grease is vastly entertaining if nothing else. Yes, its narrative meanders without much direction at times, but Grease is still a blast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Get Ready To Laugh And Have A Great Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Step right up ladies and gentleman! Get ready to laugh and have a great time! Get ready to watch a delight that you will never forget! Okay, I know that I sound like a game show host, but you'll understand it. From director Randal Kleiser comes a musical comedy that just about anybody is bound to enjoy! That film is the 1978 musical masterpiece that we all know as Grease! That's right people! Grease is a wonderful movie, I repeat, a wonderful movie, an absolutely wonderful movie that is! Why is the movie great? Well step right up to find out why! This movie is funny for one thing, and when I say funny, I mean funny. Funny scenes in this film include any scene in which John Travolta sings in his falsetto, and the restaurant scene, not to mention the recurring school chimes gag. The music is outstanding, no really, it was, about 100% of the time, I was tapping my feet and clapping my hands to the beat of the music. The music in this movie is the type of music that makes you want to get up and dance. And you'll see what I mean! Just watch the film, you'll love it! John Travolta shines in his role as Danny Zuko, a high school senior who finds out that his girlfriend, Sandy Olsen (played fabulously by Olivia Newton-John), is going to the same school as he is (however, his relationship with her is a bit strained). Can these two lovers rekindle the flame for each other? The answer to that question lies in this wonderful musical comedy filled with laughs, passions, great music, great acting, great singing, and just about everything else that you would expect to see from a musical classic. Like musical classics like Singin' In The Rain, My Fair Lady, Seven Brides For Seven Brothers, and 42nd Street among others, most musical films don't get any better than this! This is one of the best movies of 1978, and one of the best musical films that you'll ever see! I am not kidding about that, this film is a classic, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean by that statement! Do you want to see a musical film that you will definitely have fun viewing? Then you have got absolutely nothing to worry about, because the movie known as Grease is just the film for you, it's wonderful, it's marvelous, it's...well, you'll probably understand it when you watch it, which is what you should precisely do! If I was given the chance to watch this fabulous film as second time, I would definitely take that chance and do it, as I loved this film, I loved it all the way through from start to finish! This is a definite must see as far as musical films go, and possibly even as far as films in general go, it's a whole lot of fun, and when I say fun, I mean super fun! Anyway, if you haven't seen this movie, then all I can say is that you have got to see it, because you are missing out on something grand. Ladies and gentlemen, I am proud to present to you a musical classic that's enjoyable for just about everyone, that's the 1978 marvel, Grease. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbewnylorac
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My high school drama teacher pointed out something that a lot of this viewers don't get -- it's a satire! People who hate Grease actually think it's supposed to be a true reflection of early 1960s America, but it's a comedy, a spoof, and it's meant to be fun entertainment. The songs are the best thing, from the pounding opening song, Grease, to the lovely Travolta showpiece ballad, Sandy to the dance spectacular, Hand Jive. There are quite a few silly bits, such as Jan singing the toothbrush song and most of Frenchy's dialogue, but you've got to remember that this is a movie about teenagers, for teenagers, although most of the cast were aged in their 20s and 30s. Highlights for me included Beauty School Dropout by Frankie Avalon, There are Worse Things I Could Do by Stockard Channing and Hopelessly Devoted to You by Olivia Newton-John. Grease was a musical we did at my high school, and it'sjust a quality production that's hugely enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Masturbation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen7272
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    However much sugar you coat this with, Grease is a movie about teenagers expectations for future sex. The film is essentially split into two components. The first is the pre- puberty story of boy loves girl with sugar coated candy floss. The second, the post-puberty, part of the film only takes up the last 15 minutes, is about boys and girls doing the stuff they do prior to back-seat copulation. As a musical the songs essentially come from the pages of a girlie magazine for 13 year old wannabee love hearts. But as adults we view this with nostalgia, for those days before we had to go to work, take out mortgages and bring up families of our own. It reflects that short period of exciting sexual frustration and freedom that society soon inoculates us against until we rediscover it somewhere around our mid-50's. More socially importantly, this is a movie about the beginnings of the Baby Boomer generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease (1978).
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_manRedux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's basically no story structure, the film is episodic and really kind of plot less. Most of these characters are paper thin and the words on the page basically just introduce situations into the screen with no breathing room. The film is so borderline campy it edges on the ridiculous, there's not enough scenes between Sandy and Danny, and don't even get me started on Sandy's late act switch from naive schoolgirl to sultry bombshell (although Jim Jacobs' explanation for this change is very interesting, it doesn't come off in a convincing way on screen). And yet...it works. There's an infusing energy in this film that can only be chalked up to its pitch-perfect cast, who breathe life into these caricatures, and to Randal Kleiser's underrated direction. As far as musicals go (a genre that, I'll admit, I'm not a fan of), this is one of the most entertaining offerings, particularly because it doesn't take itself so seriously like so many modern musicals do. Jeff Conaway and Stockard Channing are scene-stealers, Olivia Newton-John is a charming presence, but it's Travolta's spirited and hilarious performance that takes the cake as MVP.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes Grease girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ronnyk-0101
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm twenty three. My girlfriends and I have real conversations like this. We're poor, fresh out of college, and headed toward grad school (hopefully.) What I'm getting at is this show is relevant to our lives, it's realistic and actually funny. Not all women were like Sex and the City and it's been said that Carrie's extravagant lifestyle was not realistic, this show is. I hate to compare the two but Girls blows SATC out of the water. This show is fresh, funny, and so true that it hurts. Lena Dunham is not only a phenomenal actress but the entire premise is so new and amazing that it's hard to believe she writes and directs each episode. Love is so far and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite musicals that was a highlight of my youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw this film in its entirety (prior to this I saw the musical number clips on VH1) was at the cinema when it was re-released for its 20th anniversary when I was 11 and in my first year at secondary school. Re-visiting this film today brought back many memories, especially my Eisteddfod performance of 'Summer Nights (one of the best songs)' with my form. Before I saw the film in full, I'd listen to the film's soundtrack on tape on 'Wet Play' days (playtime in the classroom on rainy days) with my fellow classmates at primary school. There are plenty of positive aspects of this film such as the majority of musical numbers being memorable (with the exception of There Are Worse Things I Could Do,' Rizzo's second solo performance that I completely forgot about), especially 'Grease Is The Word,' 'Summer Nights,' 'Look At Me I'm Sandra Dee,' 'Hopelessly Devoted To You,' 'Greased Lightning (and the dance to go with it), 'Beauty School Dropout,' 'Sandy (my housemate does a brilliant rendition of this one),' You're The One That I Want (which I also remember from a Shape yoghurt advert from my childhood) and 'We Go Together (which sounds a little like all versions of 'The Tide Is High') as well as a version of 'La Bamba' being played in the background in the first Frosty Palace scene; the costumes and vehicles that were true to the 1950s setting; the impressive choreography (especially the school dance scene) and the odd funny moment, especially the scene where Jan imitates the beaver in the toothpaste commercial at the slumber party at Frenchy's house - I couldn't help myself laughing at that today! I also liked the animated segments consisting of the title sequence, toothpaste commercial and the promotional refreshment animations at the drive-in. After having watched the Nostalgia Chick's review of this film, she helped me notice things I hadn't on previous viewings such as Rizzo feeling like a defective typewriter and her pregnancy rumours, although one thing I noticed for the first time today was product placement (a Reese's Peanut Butter Cups billboard ad in the opening sequence and Jan eating a Twinkie at Frenchy's slumber party). The songs made the film go quickly and they were broken up by the various antics of the T-Birds and the Pink Ladies whether they were hanging out at Frosty Palace or partaking in a car chase. I also remember the up-and-down relationship between the two protagonists very fondly. Overall this is a thoroughly enjoyable musical that has sheer nostalgic value and I'd undoubtedly like to see it time and time again. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Simply Critic-Proof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_rawjalaurence
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are quite simply critic-proof: GREASE is one of these. Forget the flat filming style (by Randal Kleiser) and the fact that the Rydale High students seem way too mature - we should just sit back and enjoy the songs, color, movement and sheer energy of the film. John Travolta's Danny is both arrogant yet touching; someone willing to show bravado in front of his male buddies, yet extremely weak when it comes to showing off his emotions. His body movements are a joy to watch - especially during the sequence where he presents Sandy (Olivia Newton- John) with a cheap ring and asks her to marry him. Newton-John is especially good as a Doris Day/ Sandra Dee-type figure who cannot quite understand why Danny should behave so differently in front of his buddies. Stockard Channing's Rizzo quite simply steals the show; she cultivates a hard-boiled exterior (her real name in the film is Betty), yet cannot cover up an essential vulnerability, especially when she thinks that she is pregnant. GREASE also contains a clutch of memorable cameos from television and film old-timers, from Sid Caesar's Coach Calhoun to Eve Arden's Principal McGee, to Joan Blondell's Vi. In short, there is something in this film for absolutely everyone, regardless of their age and/or cinematic tastes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is the word that you Heard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Samantha Rios
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease is the word. There are many musicals in the world but not one compare to the musical that is Grease. You have the T-birds and the Pink Ladies and new incomer Sandy Olsson, who overall take the story through twists and turns. Good girl Sandy and Greaser Danny must make life-changing decisions on whether being who they are now is worth loosing the one they most care about. Like most musicals, Grease tells their audience the story through song engaging the audience. With the song "Summer Nights" we are introduced into the background information on how exactly Sandy and Danny met during the summer. With the two stories not adding up we get a feel on the personalities of bad boy Danny and sweet and innocent Sandy. After running into each other at a pep rally for the football team, Sandy runs off crying after being humiliated by the bad boy Danny in front of his fellow T-birds and Pink Ladies. Throughout the story we see the numerous attempts by both Danny and Sandy to show one another whether it be changing from a leather jacket to a letterman jacket or dating a jock in attempts to make him jealous. Through "Hopelessly Devoted to You" and " Sandy" the couple show that no matter what they are going through now they cant and wont stop loving each other. While the Danny and Sandy are trying to make things work, Danny's second in command Kenickie is out to beat T-birds rival gang The Scorpions in a race were they will be racing for ownership papers of the cars or what they call "Pinks". Though a series of unfortunate events and Kenickie is incapable of racing he asks his friend Danny to take his place. After winning the race and defeating their rivals we see that Sandy has been watching the race from afar. Asking Pink Ladies' Frenchy for a makeover we see that not only did Danny make the transition from leather jacket to letterman but also Sandy went from innocent to Pink Lady newcomer. In the final scene Rydell High School has rewarded the graduating class with a senior carnival. Here we get the first look at new and improved Danny Zuko who has indeed traded in his T-bird jacket, but he isn't the only one who made a drastic change. After reassuring his fellow boys that this change in jackets didn't mean the end to their friendship, Danny is soon interrupted by the new Sandy Olsson. "You're The One That I Want" is the final song number the couple sing showing that they both changed their ways to be with each other and in the end it worked out for the best. The final number the T-birds and the Pink Ladies perform is the song, " We Go Together". This number gives the audience the final feel for the movie and the two groups of friends as they part ways. Yes the movie isn't the most relevant and up to date movie, but it still has what it takes to be a classic. With the love story that Grease takes us on, we take a trip when not just the girl has to change for the guy but also the guy goes through endless activities to be with his one true love. This movie is one you can't get tired of. The more you watch the more the songs stick with you and with the songs it just adds in to the affect that comes with watching Grease. Grease really and truly is the word. And it's a movie that is worthy enough to be considered a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless and epic musical from my childhood!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a brief note, I have never heard of this film before and I'm only a 90s kind of guy at the time I was a little kid until one day, my father got it on video. Being interested, I watched it and after the first time after my viewing, I became amazed by how epic this film is. I mean, of all the musicals I've seen in every high school production along with cinema, this really takes the cake as one of the best ones yet. Sure, it is a little long and some of the dialog is pretty corny, but hey, those two problems are just nitpicks. Everything else is perfect and holds up well even as a young adult. THe story is amazing with lots of charm and romance that would make you fall in love. The direction from Randal Kleiser is fine and the 1950s setting along with the costumes are brilliant. The characters are pretty good too and the acting is great. John Travolta is a charming Danny Zuko and Olivia Newton-John is a cute and beautiful Sandy. The best part, however, would have to go to the musical song sequences helped by excellent choreography. The songs, "Grease Is The Word", "Summer Nights", "Hopelessly Devoted", "Greased Lightning", "You're The One That I Want", "We'll Be Together" and such are, and always will be, memorable on their own right you will end up humming them for a few hours. Overall, Grease is an epic musical that would always remain in my memory for all time and is recommended to those who haven't seen it yet! It is that good, guys. I'm not gonna lie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wafer thin plot, but still a blast thanks to energy, exuberance and toe-tapping musical numbers.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathon Dabell (barnaby.rudge@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease, like a fine wine, has grown with age. It was a phenomenally successful film in its time but its commercial popularity was not equalled by its critical reception. Not that contemporary critics were especially negative towards it, more that they approved it with blandly above average reviews. To be sure, the plot of Grease is wafer thin and its narrative borders on non-existent between the musical set pieces.. However, it is a film which transcends the basic requirements of strong plot and narrative. It's about joyous set pieces. It's about goofy characters, interacting via goofy dialogue. It's about nostalgia. It's about awkward teen courtship. It's about those last days of high school where the joy of being young is ever-so-slightly tarnished by the encroaching end of one's educational era. The final scene of John Travolta and Olivia Newton John driving off into the sky in a flying car roots the film in a dreamy nostalgic/retrospective landscape, reminding us that we've been watching a fun musical fantasy, nothing more. In terms of achieving its goals  entertaining the audience, rocking us out, and putting a smile on our face  Grease does exactly what it says on the tin. It's the start of a new school year at Rydell High, and T-Bird gang member Danny Zuko (John Travolta) enthusiastically tells his friends about a summer romance that he has enjoyed during the holidays. Unbeknown to him, his summer sweetheart Sandy (Olivia Newton John), has not returned to Australia as expected but, in fact, has enrolled at the same high school, where she relates her amazing summer of love with Danny to her new classmates. When they eventually run into each other, Danny can't bring himself to be his true self in front of his friends. Embarrassed by his gushing sentiments, his genuine feelings for Sandy, he treats her off-handedly, cruelly even, and it seems impossible that they will ever rediscover their magical connection. Throughout the continuing story of Danny and Sandy's difficult on/off romance, we also follow the exploits of the other characters in their circle  the risqu&eacute; relationship between Kenickie (Jeff Conaway) and Rizzo (Stockard Channing); the rivalry between the T-Birds and another gang, the Scorpions, culminating in a classic car race; an impending dance contest at Rydell; and the final graduation (and goodbyes) of each of the gang. What makes Grease work above everything else is the charm, enthusiasm and energy with which it is presented. There's a sense of everyone pulling in the same direction, entering into the spirit of things in a manner that becomes immediately infectious. The characters are at once lovable and identifiable; their actions and reactions cleverly tuned into real people and real feelings, but dressed up in a joyous musical approach. The musical set pieces are very well done indeed  all the songs pretty much deliver, getting the audience toe-tapping in spite of themselves. Best of all is the sensational closing number, You're The One That I Want, brilliantly choreographed against a fairground backdrop, and featuring Newton John shedding her bookish image and wooing Danny in cinema's most infamous tight leather pants. Performance-wise the film is generally pretty good. Travolta and Newton John have a lovely chemistry, even if their characters are a mite too broadly painted at times. Channing is fabulous as the scene-stealing Rizzo, and Eve Arden has some moments of pure comedic gold as the disapproving school principal Miss McGee. Enduringly popular, always fresh and fun to watch, and a real sing-along favourite, Grease is vastly entertaining if nothing else. Yes, its narrative meanders without much direction at times, but Grease is still a blast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Get Ready To Laugh And Have A Great Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Step right up ladies and gentleman! Get ready to laugh and have a great time! Get ready to watch a delight that you will never forget! Okay, I know that I sound like a game show host, but you'll understand it. From director Randal Kleiser comes a musical comedy that just about anybody is bound to enjoy! That film is the 1978 musical masterpiece that we all know as Grease! That's right people! Grease is a wonderful movie, I repeat, a wonderful movie, an absolutely wonderful movie that is! Why is the movie great? Well step right up to find out why! This movie is funny for one thing, and when I say funny, I mean funny. Funny scenes in this film include any scene in which John Travolta sings in his falsetto, and the restaurant scene, not to mention the recurring school chimes gag. The music is outstanding, no really, it was, about 100% of the time, I was tapping my feet and clapping my hands to the beat of the music. The music in this movie is the type of music that makes you want to get up and dance. And you'll see what I mean! Just watch the film, you'll love it! John Travolta shines in his role as Danny Zuko, a high school senior who finds out that his girlfriend, Sandy Olsen (played fabulously by Olivia Newton-John), is going to the same school as he is (however, his relationship with her is a bit strained). Can these two lovers rekindle the flame for each other? The answer to that question lies in this wonderful musical comedy filled with laughs, passions, great music, great acting, great singing, and just about everything else that you would expect to see from a musical classic. Like musical classics like Singin' In The Rain, My Fair Lady, Seven Brides For Seven Brothers, and 42nd Street among others, most musical films don't get any better than this! This is one of the best movies of 1978, and one of the best musical films that you'll ever see! I am not kidding about that, this film is a classic, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean by that statement! Do you want to see a musical film that you will definitely have fun viewing? Then you have got absolutely nothing to worry about, because the movie known as Grease is just the film for you, it's wonderful, it's marvelous, it's...well, you'll probably understand it when you watch it, which is what you should precisely do! If I was given the chance to watch this fabulous film as second time, I would definitely take that chance and do it, as I loved this film, I loved it all the way through from start to finish! This is a definite must see as far as musical films go, and possibly even as far as films in general go, it's a whole lot of fun, and when I say fun, I mean super fun! Anyway, if you haven't seen this movie, then all I can say is that you have got to see it, because you are missing out on something grand. Ladies and gentlemen, I am proud to present to you a musical classic that's enjoyable for just about everyone, that's the 1978 marvel, Grease. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbewnylorac
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My high school drama teacher pointed out something that a lot of this viewers don't get -- it's a satire! People who hate Grease actually think it's supposed to be a true reflection of early 1960s America, but it's a comedy, a spoof, and it's meant to be fun entertainment. The songs are the best thing, from the pounding opening song, Grease, to the lovely Travolta showpiece ballad, Sandy to the dance spectacular, Hand Jive. There are quite a few silly bits, such as Jan singing the toothbrush song and most of Frenchy's dialogue, but you've got to remember that this is a movie about teenagers, for teenagers, although most of the cast were aged in their 20s and 30s. Highlights for me included Beauty School Dropout by Frankie Avalon, There are Worse Things I Could Do by Stockard Channing and Hopelessly Devoted to You by Olivia Newton-John. Grease was a musical we did at my high school, and it'sjust a quality production that's hugely enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Masturbation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen7272
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    However much sugar you coat this with, Grease is a movie about teenagers expectations for future sex. The film is essentially split into two components. The first is the pre- puberty story of boy loves girl with sugar coated candy floss. The second, the post-puberty, part of the film only takes up the last 15 minutes, is about boys and girls doing the stuff they do prior to back-seat copulation. As a musical the songs essentially come from the pages of a girlie magazine for 13 year old wannabee love hearts. But as adults we view this with nostalgia, for those days before we had to go to work, take out mortgages and bring up families of our own. It reflects that short period of exciting sexual frustration and freedom that society soon inoculates us against until we rediscover it somewhere around our mid-50's. More socially importantly, this is a movie about the beginnings of the Baby Boomer generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease (1978).
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_manRedux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's basically no story structure, the film is episodic and really kind of plot less. Most of these characters are paper thin and the words on the page basically just introduce situations into the screen with no breathing room. The film is so borderline campy it edges on the ridiculous, there's not enough scenes between Sandy and Danny, and don't even get me started on Sandy's late act switch from naive schoolgirl to sultry bombshell (although Jim Jacobs' explanation for this change is very interesting, it doesn't come off in a convincing way on screen). And yet...it works. There's an infusing energy in this film that can only be chalked up to its pitch-perfect cast, who breathe life into these caricatures, and to Randal Kleiser's underrated direction. As far as musicals go (a genre that, I'll admit, I'm not a fan of), this is one of the most entertaining offerings, particularly because it doesn't take itself so seriously like so many modern musicals do. Jeff Conaway and Stockard Channing are scene-stealers, Olivia Newton-John is a charming presence, but it's Travolta's spirited and hilarious performance that takes the cake as MVP.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes Grease girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ronnyk-0101
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm twenty three. My girlfriends and I have real conversations like this. We're poor, fresh out of college, and headed toward grad school (hopefully.) What I'm getting at is this show is relevant to our lives, it's realistic and actually funny. Not all women were like Sex and the City and it's been said that Carrie's extravagant lifestyle was not realistic, this show is. I hate to compare the two but Girls blows SATC out of the water. This show is fresh, funny, and so true that it hurts. Lena Dunham is not only a phenomenal actress but the entire premise is so new and amazing that it's hard to believe she writes and directs each episode. Love is so far and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite musicals that was a highlight of my youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw this film in its entirety (prior to this I saw the musical number clips on VH1) was at the cinema when it was re-released for its 20th anniversary when I was 11 and in my first year at secondary school. Re-visiting this film today brought back many memories, especially my Eisteddfod performance of 'Summer Nights (one of the best songs)' with my form. Before I saw the film in full, I'd listen to the film's soundtrack on tape on 'Wet Play' days (playtime in the classroom on rainy days) with my fellow classmates at primary school. There are plenty of positive aspects of this film such as the majority of musical numbers being memorable (with the exception of There Are Worse Things I Could Do,' Rizzo's second solo performance that I completely forgot about), especially 'Grease Is The Word,' 'Summer Nights,' 'Look At Me I'm Sandra Dee,' 'Hopelessly Devoted To You,' 'Greased Lightning (and the dance to go with it), 'Beauty School Dropout,' 'Sandy (my housemate does a brilliant rendition of this one),' You're The One That I Want (which I also remember from a Shape yoghurt advert from my childhood) and 'We Go Together (which sounds a little like all versions of 'The Tide Is High') as well as a version of 'La Bamba' being played in the background in the first Frosty Palace scene; the costumes and vehicles that were true to the 1950s setting; the impressive choreography (especially the school dance scene) and the odd funny moment, especially the scene where Jan imitates the beaver in the toothpaste commercial at the slumber party at Frenchy's house - I couldn't help myself laughing at that today! I also liked the animated segments consisting of the title sequence, toothpaste commercial and the promotional refreshment animations at the drive-in. After having watched the Nostalgia Chick's review of this film, she helped me notice things I hadn't on previous viewings such as Rizzo feeling like a defective typewriter and her pregnancy rumours, although one thing I noticed for the first time today was product placement (a Reese's Peanut Butter Cups billboard ad in the opening sequence and Jan eating a Twinkie at Frenchy's slumber party). The songs made the film go quickly and they were broken up by the various antics of the T-Birds and the Pink Ladies whether they were hanging out at Frosty Palace or partaking in a car chase. I also remember the up-and-down relationship between the two protagonists very fondly. Overall this is a thoroughly enjoyable musical that has sheer nostalgic value and I'd undoubtedly like to see it time and time again. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Simply Critic-Proof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_rawjalaurence
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are quite simply critic-proof: GREASE is one of these. Forget the flat filming style (by Randal Kleiser) and the fact that the Rydale High students seem way too mature - we should just sit back and enjoy the songs, color, movement and sheer energy of the film. John Travolta's Danny is both arrogant yet touching; someone willing to show bravado in front of his male buddies, yet extremely weak when it comes to showing off his emotions. His body movements are a joy to watch - especially during the sequence where he presents Sandy (Olivia Newton- John) with a cheap ring and asks her to marry him. Newton-John is especially good as a Doris Day/ Sandra Dee-type figure who cannot quite understand why Danny should behave so differently in front of his buddies. Stockard Channing's Rizzo quite simply steals the show; she cultivates a hard-boiled exterior (her real name in the film is Betty), yet cannot cover up an essential vulnerability, especially when she thinks that she is pregnant. GREASE also contains a clutch of memorable cameos from television and film old-timers, from Sid Caesar's Coach Calhoun to Eve Arden's Principal McGee, to Joan Blondell's Vi. In short, there is something in this film for absolutely everyone, regardless of their age and/or cinematic tastes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is the word that you Heard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Samantha Rios
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease is the word. There are many musicals in the world but not one compare to the musical that is Grease. You have the T-birds and the Pink Ladies and new incomer Sandy Olsson, who overall take the story through twists and turns. Good girl Sandy and Greaser Danny must make life-changing decisions on whether being who they are now is worth loosing the one they most care about. Like most musicals, Grease tells their audience the story through song engaging the audience. With the song "Summer Nights" we are introduced into the background information on how exactly Sandy and Danny met during the summer. With the two stories not adding up we get a feel on the personalities of bad boy Danny and sweet and innocent Sandy. After running into each other at a pep rally for the football team, Sandy runs off crying after being humiliated by the bad boy Danny in front of his fellow T-birds and Pink Ladies. Throughout the story we see the numerous attempts by both Danny and Sandy to show one another whether it be changing from a leather jacket to a letterman jacket or dating a jock in attempts to make him jealous. Through "Hopelessly Devoted to You" and " Sandy" the couple show that no matter what they are going through now they cant and wont stop loving each other. While the Danny and Sandy are trying to make things work, Danny's second in command Kenickie is out to beat T-birds rival gang The Scorpions in a race were they will be racing for ownership papers of the cars or what they call "Pinks". Though a series of unfortunate events and Kenickie is incapable of racing he asks his friend Danny to take his place. After winning the race and defeating their rivals we see that Sandy has been watching the race from afar. Asking Pink Ladies' Frenchy for a makeover we see that not only did Danny make the transition from leather jacket to letterman but also Sandy went from innocent to Pink Lady newcomer. In the final scene Rydell High School has rewarded the graduating class with a senior carnival. Here we get the first look at new and improved Danny Zuko who has indeed traded in his T-bird jacket, but he isn't the only one who made a drastic change. After reassuring his fellow boys that this change in jackets didn't mean the end to their friendship, Danny is soon interrupted by the new Sandy Olsson. "You're The One That I Want" is the final song number the couple sing showing that they both changed their ways to be with each other and in the end it worked out for the best. The final number the T-birds and the Pink Ladies perform is the song, " We Go Together". This number gives the audience the final feel for the movie and the two groups of friends as they part ways. Yes the movie isn't the most relevant and up to date movie, but it still has what it takes to be a classic. With the love story that Grease takes us on, we take a trip when not just the girl has to change for the guy but also the guy goes through endless activities to be with his one true love. This movie is one you can't get tired of. The more you watch the more the songs stick with you and with the songs it just adds in to the affect that comes with watching Grease. Grease really and truly is the word. And it's a movie that is worthy enough to be considered a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless and epic musical from my childhood!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a brief note, I have never heard of this film before and I'm only a 90s kind of guy at the time I was a little kid until one day, my father got it on video. Being interested, I watched it and after the first time after my viewing, I became amazed by how epic this film is. I mean, of all the musicals I've seen in every high school production along with cinema, this really takes the cake as one of the best ones yet. Sure, it is a little long and some of the dialog is pretty corny, but hey, those two problems are just nitpicks. Everything else is perfect and holds up well even as a young adult. THe story is amazing with lots of charm and romance that would make you fall in love. The direction from Randal Kleiser is fine and the 1950s setting along with the costumes are brilliant. The characters are pretty good too and the acting is great. John Travolta is a charming Danny Zuko and Olivia Newton-John is a cute and beautiful Sandy. The best part, however, would have to go to the musical song sequences helped by excellent choreography. The songs, "Grease Is The Word", "Summer Nights", "Hopelessly Devoted", "Greased Lightning", "You're The One That I Want", "We'll Be Together" and such are, and always will be, memorable on their own right you will end up humming them for a few hours. Overall, Grease is an epic musical that would always remain in my memory for all time and is recommended to those who haven't seen it yet! It is that good, guys. I'm not gonna lie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wafer thin plot, but still a blast thanks to energy, exuberance and toe-tapping musical numbers.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathon Dabell (barnaby.rudge@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease, like a fine wine, has grown with age. It was a phenomenally successful film in its time but its commercial popularity was not equalled by its critical reception. Not that contemporary critics were especially negative towards it, more that they approved it with blandly above average reviews. To be sure, the plot of Grease is wafer thin and its narrative borders on non-existent between the musical set pieces.. However, it is a film which transcends the basic requirements of strong plot and narrative. It's about joyous set pieces. It's about goofy characters, interacting via goofy dialogue. It's about nostalgia. It's about awkward teen courtship. It's about those last days of high school where the joy of being young is ever-so-slightly tarnished by the encroaching end of one's educational era. The final scene of John Travolta and Olivia Newton John driving off into the sky in a flying car roots the film in a dreamy nostalgic/retrospective landscape, reminding us that we've been watching a fun musical fantasy, nothing more. In terms of achieving its goals  entertaining the audience, rocking us out, and putting a smile on our face  Grease does exactly what it says on the tin. It's the start of a new school year at Rydell High, and T-Bird gang member Danny Zuko (John Travolta) enthusiastically tells his friends about a summer romance that he has enjoyed during the holidays. Unbeknown to him, his summer sweetheart Sandy (Olivia Newton John), has not returned to Australia as expected but, in fact, has enrolled at the same high school, where she relates her amazing summer of love with Danny to her new classmates. When they eventually run into each other, Danny can't bring himself to be his true self in front of his friends. Embarrassed by his gushing sentiments, his genuine feelings for Sandy, he treats her off-handedly, cruelly even, and it seems impossible that they will ever rediscover their magical connection. Throughout the continuing story of Danny and Sandy's difficult on/off romance, we also follow the exploits of the other characters in their circle  the risqu&eacute; relationship between Kenickie (Jeff Conaway) and Rizzo (Stockard Channing); the rivalry between the T-Birds and another gang, the Scorpions, culminating in a classic car race; an impending dance contest at Rydell; and the final graduation (and goodbyes) of each of the gang. What makes Grease work above everything else is the charm, enthusiasm and energy with which it is presented. There's a sense of everyone pulling in the same direction, entering into the spirit of things in a manner that becomes immediately infectious. The characters are at once lovable and identifiable; their actions and reactions cleverly tuned into real people and real feelings, but dressed up in a joyous musical approach. The musical set pieces are very well done indeed  all the songs pretty much deliver, getting the audience toe-tapping in spite of themselves. Best of all is the sensational closing number, You're The One That I Want, brilliantly choreographed against a fairground backdrop, and featuring Newton John shedding her bookish image and wooing Danny in cinema's most infamous tight leather pants. Performance-wise the film is generally pretty good. Travolta and Newton John have a lovely chemistry, even if their characters are a mite too broadly painted at times. Channing is fabulous as the scene-stealing Rizzo, and Eve Arden has some moments of pure comedic gold as the disapproving school principal Miss McGee. Enduringly popular, always fresh and fun to watch, and a real sing-along favourite, Grease is vastly entertaining if nothing else. Yes, its narrative meanders without much direction at times, but Grease is still a blast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Get Ready To Laugh And Have A Great Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Step right up ladies and gentleman! Get ready to laugh and have a great time! Get ready to watch a delight that you will never forget! Okay, I know that I sound like a game show host, but you'll understand it. From director Randal Kleiser comes a musical comedy that just about anybody is bound to enjoy! That film is the 1978 musical masterpiece that we all know as Grease! That's right people! Grease is a wonderful movie, I repeat, a wonderful movie, an absolutely wonderful movie that is! Why is the movie great? Well step right up to find out why! This movie is funny for one thing, and when I say funny, I mean funny. Funny scenes in this film include any scene in which John Travolta sings in his falsetto, and the restaurant scene, not to mention the recurring school chimes gag. The music is outstanding, no really, it was, about 100% of the time, I was tapping my feet and clapping my hands to the beat of the music. The music in this movie is the type of music that makes you want to get up and dance. And you'll see what I mean! Just watch the film, you'll love it! John Travolta shines in his role as Danny Zuko, a high school senior who finds out that his girlfriend, Sandy Olsen (played fabulously by Olivia Newton-John), is going to the same school as he is (however, his relationship with her is a bit strained). Can these two lovers rekindle the flame for each other? The answer to that question lies in this wonderful musical comedy filled with laughs, passions, great music, great acting, great singing, and just about everything else that you would expect to see from a musical classic. Like musical classics like Singin' In The Rain, My Fair Lady, Seven Brides For Seven Brothers, and 42nd Street among others, most musical films don't get any better than this! This is one of the best movies of 1978, and one of the best musical films that you'll ever see! I am not kidding about that, this film is a classic, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean by that statement! Do you want to see a musical film that you will definitely have fun viewing? Then you have got absolutely nothing to worry about, because the movie known as Grease is just the film for you, it's wonderful, it's marvelous, it's...well, you'll probably understand it when you watch it, which is what you should precisely do! If I was given the chance to watch this fabulous film as second time, I would definitely take that chance and do it, as I loved this film, I loved it all the way through from start to finish! This is a definite must see as far as musical films go, and possibly even as far as films in general go, it's a whole lot of fun, and when I say fun, I mean super fun! Anyway, if you haven't seen this movie, then all I can say is that you have got to see it, because you are missing out on something grand. Ladies and gentlemen, I am proud to present to you a musical classic that's enjoyable for just about everyone, that's the 1978 marvel, Grease. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbewnylorac
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My high school drama teacher pointed out something that a lot of this viewers don't get -- it's a satire! People who hate Grease actually think it's supposed to be a true reflection of early 1960s America, but it's a comedy, a spoof, and it's meant to be fun entertainment. The songs are the best thing, from the pounding opening song, Grease, to the lovely Travolta showpiece ballad, Sandy to the dance spectacular, Hand Jive. There are quite a few silly bits, such as Jan singing the toothbrush song and most of Frenchy's dialogue, but you've got to remember that this is a movie about teenagers, for teenagers, although most of the cast were aged in their 20s and 30s. Highlights for me included Beauty School Dropout by Frankie Avalon, There are Worse Things I Could Do by Stockard Channing and Hopelessly Devoted to You by Olivia Newton-John. Grease was a musical we did at my high school, and it'sjust a quality production that's hugely enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Masturbation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen7272
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    However much sugar you coat this with, Grease is a movie about teenagers expectations for future sex. The film is essentially split into two components. The first is the pre- puberty story of boy loves girl with sugar coated candy floss. The second, the post-puberty, part of the film only takes up the last 15 minutes, is about boys and girls doing the stuff they do prior to back-seat copulation. As a musical the songs essentially come from the pages of a girlie magazine for 13 year old wannabee love hearts. But as adults we view this with nostalgia, for those days before we had to go to work, take out mortgages and bring up families of our own. It reflects that short period of exciting sexual frustration and freedom that society soon inoculates us against until we rediscover it somewhere around our mid-50's. More socially importantly, this is a movie about the beginnings of the Baby Boomer generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease (1978).
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_manRedux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's basically no story structure, the film is episodic and really kind of plot less. Most of these characters are paper thin and the words on the page basically just introduce situations into the screen with no breathing room. The film is so borderline campy it edges on the ridiculous, there's not enough scenes between Sandy and Danny, and don't even get me started on Sandy's late act switch from naive schoolgirl to sultry bombshell (although Jim Jacobs' explanation for this change is very interesting, it doesn't come off in a convincing way on screen). And yet...it works. There's an infusing energy in this film that can only be chalked up to its pitch-perfect cast, who breathe life into these caricatures, and to Randal Kleiser's underrated direction. As far as musicals go (a genre that, I'll admit, I'm not a fan of), this is one of the most entertaining offerings, particularly because it doesn't take itself so seriously like so many modern musicals do. Jeff Conaway and Stockard Channing are scene-stealers, Olivia Newton-John is a charming presence, but it's Travolta's spirited and hilarious performance that takes the cake as MVP.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes Grease girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ronnyk-0101
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm twenty three. My girlfriends and I have real conversations like this. We're poor, fresh out of college, and headed toward grad school (hopefully.) What I'm getting at is this show is relevant to our lives, it's realistic and actually funny. Not all women were like Sex and the City and it's been said that Carrie's extravagant lifestyle was not realistic, this show is. I hate to compare the two but Girls blows SATC out of the water. This show is fresh, funny, and so true that it hurts. Lena Dunham is not only a phenomenal actress but the entire premise is so new and amazing that it's hard to believe she writes and directs each episode. Love is so far and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite musicals that was a highlight of my youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw this film in its entirety (prior to this I saw the musical number clips on VH1) was at the cinema when it was re-released for its 20th anniversary when I was 11 and in my first year at secondary school. Re-visiting this film today brought back many memories, especially my Eisteddfod performance of 'Summer Nights (one of the best songs)' with my form. Before I saw the film in full, I'd listen to the film's soundtrack on tape on 'Wet Play' days (playtime in the classroom on rainy days) with my fellow classmates at primary school. There are plenty of positive aspects of this film such as the majority of musical numbers being memorable (with the exception of There Are Worse Things I Could Do,' Rizzo's second solo performance that I completely forgot about), especially 'Grease Is The Word,' 'Summer Nights,' 'Look At Me I'm Sandra Dee,' 'Hopelessly Devoted To You,' 'Greased Lightning (and the dance to go with it), 'Beauty School Dropout,' 'Sandy (my housemate does a brilliant rendition of this one),' You're The One That I Want (which I also remember from a Shape yoghurt advert from my childhood) and 'We Go Together (which sounds a little like all versions of 'The Tide Is High') as well as a version of 'La Bamba' being played in the background in the first Frosty Palace scene; the costumes and vehicles that were true to the 1950s setting; the impressive choreography (especially the school dance scene) and the odd funny moment, especially the scene where Jan imitates the beaver in the toothpaste commercial at the slumber party at Frenchy's house - I couldn't help myself laughing at that today! I also liked the animated segments consisting of the title sequence, toothpaste commercial and the promotional refreshment animations at the drive-in. After having watched the Nostalgia Chick's review of this film, she helped me notice things I hadn't on previous viewings such as Rizzo feeling like a defective typewriter and her pregnancy rumours, although one thing I noticed for the first time today was product placement (a Reese's Peanut Butter Cups billboard ad in the opening sequence and Jan eating a Twinkie at Frenchy's slumber party). The songs made the film go quickly and they were broken up by the various antics of the T-Birds and the Pink Ladies whether they were hanging out at Frosty Palace or partaking in a car chase. I also remember the up-and-down relationship between the two protagonists very fondly. Overall this is a thoroughly enjoyable musical that has sheer nostalgic value and I'd undoubtedly like to see it time and time again. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Simply Critic-Proof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_rawjalaurence
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are quite simply critic-proof: GREASE is one of these. Forget the flat filming style (by Randal Kleiser) and the fact that the Rydale High students seem way too mature - we should just sit back and enjoy the songs, color, movement and sheer energy of the film. John Travolta's Danny is both arrogant yet touching; someone willing to show bravado in front of his male buddies, yet extremely weak when it comes to showing off his emotions. His body movements are a joy to watch - especially during the sequence where he presents Sandy (Olivia Newton- John) with a cheap ring and asks her to marry him. Newton-John is especially good as a Doris Day/ Sandra Dee-type figure who cannot quite understand why Danny should behave so differently in front of his buddies. Stockard Channing's Rizzo quite simply steals the show; she cultivates a hard-boiled exterior (her real name in the film is Betty), yet cannot cover up an essential vulnerability, especially when she thinks that she is pregnant. GREASE also contains a clutch of memorable cameos from television and film old-timers, from Sid Caesar's Coach Calhoun to Eve Arden's Principal McGee, to Joan Blondell's Vi. In short, there is something in this film for absolutely everyone, regardless of their age and/or cinematic tastes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is the word that you Heard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Samantha Rios
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease is the word. There are many musicals in the world but not one compare to the musical that is Grease. You have the T-birds and the Pink Ladies and new incomer Sandy Olsson, who overall take the story through twists and turns. Good girl Sandy and Greaser Danny must make life-changing decisions on whether being who they are now is worth loosing the one they most care about. Like most musicals, Grease tells their audience the story through song engaging the audience. With the song "Summer Nights" we are introduced into the background information on how exactly Sandy and Danny met during the summer. With the two stories not adding up we get a feel on the personalities of bad boy Danny and sweet and innocent Sandy. After running into each other at a pep rally for the football team, Sandy runs off crying after being humiliated by the bad boy Danny in front of his fellow T-birds and Pink Ladies. Throughout the story we see the numerous attempts by both Danny and Sandy to show one another whether it be changing from a leather jacket to a letterman jacket or dating a jock in attempts to make him jealous. Through "Hopelessly Devoted to You" and " Sandy" the couple show that no matter what they are going through now they cant and wont stop loving each other. While the Danny and Sandy are trying to make things work, Danny's second in command Kenickie is out to beat T-birds rival gang The Scorpions in a race were they will be racing for ownership papers of the cars or what they call "Pinks". Though a series of unfortunate events and Kenickie is incapable of racing he asks his friend Danny to take his place. After winning the race and defeating their rivals we see that Sandy has been watching the race from afar. Asking Pink Ladies' Frenchy for a makeover we see that not only did Danny make the transition from leather jacket to letterman but also Sandy went from innocent to Pink Lady newcomer. In the final scene Rydell High School has rewarded the graduating class with a senior carnival. Here we get the first look at new and improved Danny Zuko who has indeed traded in his T-bird jacket, but he isn't the only one who made a drastic change. After reassuring his fellow boys that this change in jackets didn't mean the end to their friendship, Danny is soon interrupted by the new Sandy Olsson. "You're The One That I Want" is the final song number the couple sing showing that they both changed their ways to be with each other and in the end it worked out for the best. The final number the T-birds and the Pink Ladies perform is the song, " We Go Together". This number gives the audience the final feel for the movie and the two groups of friends as they part ways. Yes the movie isn't the most relevant and up to date movie, but it still has what it takes to be a classic. With the love story that Grease takes us on, we take a trip when not just the girl has to change for the guy but also the guy goes through endless activities to be with his one true love. This movie is one you can't get tired of. The more you watch the more the songs stick with you and with the songs it just adds in to the affect that comes with watching Grease. Grease really and truly is the word. And it's a movie that is worthy enough to be considered a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless and epic musical from my childhood!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a brief note, I have never heard of this film before and I'm only a 90s kind of guy at the time I was a little kid until one day, my father got it on video. Being interested, I watched it and after the first time after my viewing, I became amazed by how epic this film is. I mean, of all the musicals I've seen in every high school production along with cinema, this really takes the cake as one of the best ones yet. Sure, it is a little long and some of the dialog is pretty corny, but hey, those two problems are just nitpicks. Everything else is perfect and holds up well even as a young adult. THe story is amazing with lots of charm and romance that would make you fall in love. The direction from Randal Kleiser is fine and the 1950s setting along with the costumes are brilliant. The characters are pretty good too and the acting is great. John Travolta is a charming Danny Zuko and Olivia Newton-John is a cute and beautiful Sandy. The best part, however, would have to go to the musical song sequences helped by excellent choreography. The songs, "Grease Is The Word", "Summer Nights", "Hopelessly Devoted", "Greased Lightning", "You're The One That I Want", "We'll Be Together" and such are, and always will be, memorable on their own right you will end up humming them for a few hours. Overall, Grease is an epic musical that would always remain in my memory for all time and is recommended to those who haven't seen it yet! It is that good, guys. I'm not gonna lie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wafer thin plot, but still a blast thanks to energy, exuberance and toe-tapping musical numbers.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathon Dabell (barnaby.rudge@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease, like a fine wine, has grown with age. It was a phenomenally successful film in its time but its commercial popularity was not equalled by its critical reception. Not that contemporary critics were especially negative towards it, more that they approved it with blandly above average reviews. To be sure, the plot of Grease is wafer thin and its narrative borders on non-existent between the musical set pieces.. However, it is a film which transcends the basic requirements of strong plot and narrative. It's about joyous set pieces. It's about goofy characters, interacting via goofy dialogue. It's about nostalgia. It's about awkward teen courtship. It's about those last days of high school where the joy of being young is ever-so-slightly tarnished by the encroaching end of one's educational era. The final scene of John Travolta and Olivia Newton John driving off into the sky in a flying car roots the film in a dreamy nostalgic/retrospective landscape, reminding us that we've been watching a fun musical fantasy, nothing more. In terms of achieving its goals  entertaining the audience, rocking us out, and putting a smile on our face  Grease does exactly what it says on the tin. It's the start of a new school year at Rydell High, and T-Bird gang member Danny Zuko (John Travolta) enthusiastically tells his friends about a summer romance that he has enjoyed during the holidays. Unbeknown to him, his summer sweetheart Sandy (Olivia Newton John), has not returned to Australia as expected but, in fact, has enrolled at the same high school, where she relates her amazing summer of love with Danny to her new classmates. When they eventually run into each other, Danny can't bring himself to be his true self in front of his friends. Embarrassed by his gushing sentiments, his genuine feelings for Sandy, he treats her off-handedly, cruelly even, and it seems impossible that they will ever rediscover their magical connection. Throughout the continuing story of Danny and Sandy's difficult on/off romance, we also follow the exploits of the other characters in their circle  the risqu&eacute; relationship between Kenickie (Jeff Conaway) and Rizzo (Stockard Channing); the rivalry between the T-Birds and another gang, the Scorpions, culminating in a classic car race; an impending dance contest at Rydell; and the final graduation (and goodbyes) of each of the gang. What makes Grease work above everything else is the charm, enthusiasm and energy with which it is presented. There's a sense of everyone pulling in the same direction, entering into the spirit of things in a manner that becomes immediately infectious. The characters are at once lovable and identifiable; their actions and reactions cleverly tuned into real people and real feelings, but dressed up in a joyous musical approach. The musical set pieces are very well done indeed  all the songs pretty much deliver, getting the audience toe-tapping in spite of themselves. Best of all is the sensational closing number, You're The One That I Want, brilliantly choreographed against a fairground backdrop, and featuring Newton John shedding her bookish image and wooing Danny in cinema's most infamous tight leather pants. Performance-wise the film is generally pretty good. Travolta and Newton John have a lovely chemistry, even if their characters are a mite too broadly painted at times. Channing is fabulous as the scene-stealing Rizzo, and Eve Arden has some moments of pure comedic gold as the disapproving school principal Miss McGee. Enduringly popular, always fresh and fun to watch, and a real sing-along favourite, Grease is vastly entertaining if nothing else. Yes, its narrative meanders without much direction at times, but Grease is still a blast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Get Ready To Laugh And Have A Great Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Step right up ladies and gentleman! Get ready to laugh and have a great time! Get ready to watch a delight that you will never forget! Okay, I know that I sound like a game show host, but you'll understand it. From director Randal Kleiser comes a musical comedy that just about anybody is bound to enjoy! That film is the 1978 musical masterpiece that we all know as Grease! That's right people! Grease is a wonderful movie, I repeat, a wonderful movie, an absolutely wonderful movie that is! Why is the movie great? Well step right up to find out why! This movie is funny for one thing, and when I say funny, I mean funny. Funny scenes in this film include any scene in which John Travolta sings in his falsetto, and the restaurant scene, not to mention the recurring school chimes gag. The music is outstanding, no really, it was, about 100% of the time, I was tapping my feet and clapping my hands to the beat of the music. The music in this movie is the type of music that makes you want to get up and dance. And you'll see what I mean! Just watch the film, you'll love it! John Travolta shines in his role as Danny Zuko, a high school senior who finds out that his girlfriend, Sandy Olsen (played fabulously by Olivia Newton-John), is going to the same school as he is (however, his relationship with her is a bit strained). Can these two lovers rekindle the flame for each other? The answer to that question lies in this wonderful musical comedy filled with laughs, passions, great music, great acting, great singing, and just about everything else that you would expect to see from a musical classic. Like musical classics like Singin' In The Rain, My Fair Lady, Seven Brides For Seven Brothers, and 42nd Street among others, most musical films don't get any better than this! This is one of the best movies of 1978, and one of the best musical films that you'll ever see! I am not kidding about that, this film is a classic, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean by that statement! Do you want to see a musical film that you will definitely have fun viewing? Then you have got absolutely nothing to worry about, because the movie known as Grease is just the film for you, it's wonderful, it's marvelous, it's...well, you'll probably understand it when you watch it, which is what you should precisely do! If I was given the chance to watch this fabulous film as second time, I would definitely take that chance and do it, as I loved this film, I loved it all the way through from start to finish! This is a definite must see as far as musical films go, and possibly even as far as films in general go, it's a whole lot of fun, and when I say fun, I mean super fun! Anyway, if you haven't seen this movie, then all I can say is that you have got to see it, because you are missing out on something grand. Ladies and gentlemen, I am proud to present to you a musical classic that's enjoyable for just about everyone, that's the 1978 marvel, Grease. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbewnylorac
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My high school drama teacher pointed out something that a lot of this viewers don't get -- it's a satire! People who hate Grease actually think it's supposed to be a true reflection of early 1960s America, but it's a comedy, a spoof, and it's meant to be fun entertainment. The songs are the best thing, from the pounding opening song, Grease, to the lovely Travolta showpiece ballad, Sandy to the dance spectacular, Hand Jive. There are quite a few silly bits, such as Jan singing the toothbrush song and most of Frenchy's dialogue, but you've got to remember that this is a movie about teenagers, for teenagers, although most of the cast were aged in their 20s and 30s. Highlights for me included Beauty School Dropout by Frankie Avalon, There are Worse Things I Could Do by Stockard Channing and Hopelessly Devoted to You by Olivia Newton-John. Grease was a musical we did at my high school, and it'sjust a quality production that's hugely enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Masturbation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen7272
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    However much sugar you coat this with, Grease is a movie about teenagers expectations for future sex. The film is essentially split into two components. The first is the pre- puberty story of boy loves girl with sugar coated candy floss. The second, the post-puberty, part of the film only takes up the last 15 minutes, is about boys and girls doing the stuff they do prior to back-seat copulation. As a musical the songs essentially come from the pages of a girlie magazine for 13 year old wannabee love hearts. But as adults we view this with nostalgia, for those days before we had to go to work, take out mortgages and bring up families of our own. It reflects that short period of exciting sexual frustration and freedom that society soon inoculates us against until we rediscover it somewhere around our mid-50's. More socially importantly, this is a movie about the beginnings of the Baby Boomer generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease (1978).
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_manRedux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's basically no story structure, the film is episodic and really kind of plot less. Most of these characters are paper thin and the words on the page basically just introduce situations into the screen with no breathing room. The film is so borderline campy it edges on the ridiculous, there's not enough scenes between Sandy and Danny, and don't even get me started on Sandy's late act switch from naive schoolgirl to sultry bombshell (although Jim Jacobs' explanation for this change is very interesting, it doesn't come off in a convincing way on screen). And yet...it works. There's an infusing energy in this film that can only be chalked up to its pitch-perfect cast, who breathe life into these caricatures, and to Randal Kleiser's underrated direction. As far as musicals go (a genre that, I'll admit, I'm not a fan of), this is one of the most entertaining offerings, particularly because it doesn't take itself so seriously like so many modern musicals do. Jeff Conaway and Stockard Channing are scene-stealers, Olivia Newton-John is a charming presence, but it's Travolta's spirited and hilarious performance that takes the cake as MVP.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes Grease girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ronnyk-0101
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm twenty three. My girlfriends and I have real conversations like this. We're poor, fresh out of college, and headed toward grad school (hopefully.) What I'm getting at is this show is relevant to our lives, it's realistic and actually funny. Not all women were like Sex and the City and it's been said that Carrie's extravagant lifestyle was not realistic, this show is. I hate to compare the two but Girls blows SATC out of the water. This show is fresh, funny, and so true that it hurts. Lena Dunham is not only a phenomenal actress but the entire premise is so new and amazing that it's hard to believe she writes and directs each episode. Love is so far and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite musicals that was a highlight of my youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw this film in its entirety (prior to this I saw the musical number clips on VH1) was at the cinema when it was re-released for its 20th anniversary when I was 11 and in my first year at secondary school. Re-visiting this film today brought back many memories, especially my Eisteddfod performance of 'Summer Nights (one of the best songs)' with my form. Before I saw the film in full, I'd listen to the film's soundtrack on tape on 'Wet Play' days (playtime in the classroom on rainy days) with my fellow classmates at primary school. There are plenty of positive aspects of this film such as the majority of musical numbers being memorable (with the exception of There Are Worse Things I Could Do,' Rizzo's second solo performance that I completely forgot about), especially 'Grease Is The Word,' 'Summer Nights,' 'Look At Me I'm Sandra Dee,' 'Hopelessly Devoted To You,' 'Greased Lightning (and the dance to go with it), 'Beauty School Dropout,' 'Sandy (my housemate does a brilliant rendition of this one),' You're The One That I Want (which I also remember from a Shape yoghurt advert from my childhood) and 'We Go Together (which sounds a little like all versions of 'The Tide Is High') as well as a version of 'La Bamba' being played in the background in the first Frosty Palace scene; the costumes and vehicles that were true to the 1950s setting; the impressive choreography (especially the school dance scene) and the odd funny moment, especially the scene where Jan imitates the beaver in the toothpaste commercial at the slumber party at Frenchy's house - I couldn't help myself laughing at that today! I also liked the animated segments consisting of the title sequence, toothpaste commercial and the promotional refreshment animations at the drive-in. After having watched the Nostalgia Chick's review of this film, she helped me notice things I hadn't on previous viewings such as Rizzo feeling like a defective typewriter and her pregnancy rumours, although one thing I noticed for the first time today was product placement (a Reese's Peanut Butter Cups billboard ad in the opening sequence and Jan eating a Twinkie at Frenchy's slumber party). The songs made the film go quickly and they were broken up by the various antics of the T-Birds and the Pink Ladies whether they were hanging out at Frosty Palace or partaking in a car chase. I also remember the up-and-down relationship between the two protagonists very fondly. Overall this is a thoroughly enjoyable musical that has sheer nostalgic value and I'd undoubtedly like to see it time and time again. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Simply Critic-Proof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_rawjalaurence
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are quite simply critic-proof: GREASE is one of these. Forget the flat filming style (by Randal Kleiser) and the fact that the Rydale High students seem way too mature - we should just sit back and enjoy the songs, color, movement and sheer energy of the film. John Travolta's Danny is both arrogant yet touching; someone willing to show bravado in front of his male buddies, yet extremely weak when it comes to showing off his emotions. His body movements are a joy to watch - especially during the sequence where he presents Sandy (Olivia Newton- John) with a cheap ring and asks her to marry him. Newton-John is especially good as a Doris Day/ Sandra Dee-type figure who cannot quite understand why Danny should behave so differently in front of his buddies. Stockard Channing's Rizzo quite simply steals the show; she cultivates a hard-boiled exterior (her real name in the film is Betty), yet cannot cover up an essential vulnerability, especially when she thinks that she is pregnant. GREASE also contains a clutch of memorable cameos from television and film old-timers, from Sid Caesar's Coach Calhoun to Eve Arden's Principal McGee, to Joan Blondell's Vi. In short, there is something in this film for absolutely everyone, regardless of their age and/or cinematic tastes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is the word that you Heard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Samantha Rios
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease is the word. There are many musicals in the world but not one compare to the musical that is Grease. You have the T-birds and the Pink Ladies and new incomer Sandy Olsson, who overall take the story through twists and turns. Good girl Sandy and Greaser Danny must make life-changing decisions on whether being who they are now is worth loosing the one they most care about. Like most musicals, Grease tells their audience the story through song engaging the audience. With the song "Summer Nights" we are introduced into the background information on how exactly Sandy and Danny met during the summer. With the two stories not adding up we get a feel on the personalities of bad boy Danny and sweet and innocent Sandy. After running into each other at a pep rally for the football team, Sandy runs off crying after being humiliated by the bad boy Danny in front of his fellow T-birds and Pink Ladies. Throughout the story we see the numerous attempts by both Danny and Sandy to show one another whether it be changing from a leather jacket to a letterman jacket or dating a jock in attempts to make him jealous. Through "Hopelessly Devoted to You" and " Sandy" the couple show that no matter what they are going through now they cant and wont stop loving each other. While the Danny and Sandy are trying to make things work, Danny's second in command Kenickie is out to beat T-birds rival gang The Scorpions in a race were they will be racing for ownership papers of the cars or what they call "Pinks". Though a series of unfortunate events and Kenickie is incapable of racing he asks his friend Danny to take his place. After winning the race and defeating their rivals we see that Sandy has been watching the race from afar. Asking Pink Ladies' Frenchy for a makeover we see that not only did Danny make the transition from leather jacket to letterman but also Sandy went from innocent to Pink Lady newcomer. In the final scene Rydell High School has rewarded the graduating class with a senior carnival. Here we get the first look at new and improved Danny Zuko who has indeed traded in his T-bird jacket, but he isn't the only one who made a drastic change. After reassuring his fellow boys that this change in jackets didn't mean the end to their friendship, Danny is soon interrupted by the new Sandy Olsson. "You're The One That I Want" is the final song number the couple sing showing that they both changed their ways to be with each other and in the end it worked out for the best. The final number the T-birds and the Pink Ladies perform is the song, " We Go Together". This number gives the audience the final feel for the movie and the two groups of friends as they part ways. Yes the movie isn't the most relevant and up to date movie, but it still has what it takes to be a classic. With the love story that Grease takes us on, we take a trip when not just the girl has to change for the guy but also the guy goes through endless activities to be with his one true love. This movie is one you can't get tired of. The more you watch the more the songs stick with you and with the songs it just adds in to the affect that comes with watching Grease. Grease really and truly is the word. And it's a movie that is worthy enough to be considered a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless and epic musical from my childhood!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a brief note, I have never heard of this film before and I'm only a 90s kind of guy at the time I was a little kid until one day, my father got it on video. Being interested, I watched it and after the first time after my viewing, I became amazed by how epic this film is. I mean, of all the musicals I've seen in every high school production along with cinema, this really takes the cake as one of the best ones yet. Sure, it is a little long and some of the dialog is pretty corny, but hey, those two problems are just nitpicks. Everything else is perfect and holds up well even as a young adult. THe story is amazing with lots of charm and romance that would make you fall in love. The direction from Randal Kleiser is fine and the 1950s setting along with the costumes are brilliant. The characters are pretty good too and the acting is great. John Travolta is a charming Danny Zuko and Olivia Newton-John is a cute and beautiful Sandy. The best part, however, would have to go to the musical song sequences helped by excellent choreography. The songs, "Grease Is The Word", "Summer Nights", "Hopelessly Devoted", "Greased Lightning", "You're The One That I Want", "We'll Be Together" and such are, and always will be, memorable on their own right you will end up humming them for a few hours. Overall, Grease is an epic musical that would always remain in my memory for all time and is recommended to those who haven't seen it yet! It is that good, guys. I'm not gonna lie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wafer thin plot, but still a blast thanks to energy, exuberance and toe-tapping musical numbers.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathon Dabell (barnaby.rudge@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease, like a fine wine, has grown with age. It was a phenomenally successful film in its time but its commercial popularity was not equalled by its critical reception. Not that contemporary critics were especially negative towards it, more that they approved it with blandly above average reviews. To be sure, the plot of Grease is wafer thin and its narrative borders on non-existent between the musical set pieces.. However, it is a film which transcends the basic requirements of strong plot and narrative. It's about joyous set pieces. It's about goofy characters, interacting via goofy dialogue. It's about nostalgia. It's about awkward teen courtship. It's about those last days of high school where the joy of being young is ever-so-slightly tarnished by the encroaching end of one's educational era. The final scene of John Travolta and Olivia Newton John driving off into the sky in a flying car roots the film in a dreamy nostalgic/retrospective landscape, reminding us that we've been watching a fun musical fantasy, nothing more. In terms of achieving its goals  entertaining the audience, rocking us out, and putting a smile on our face  Grease does exactly what it says on the tin. It's the start of a new school year at Rydell High, and T-Bird gang member Danny Zuko (John Travolta) enthusiastically tells his friends about a summer romance that he has enjoyed during the holidays. Unbeknown to him, his summer sweetheart Sandy (Olivia Newton John), has not returned to Australia as expected but, in fact, has enrolled at the same high school, where she relates her amazing summer of love with Danny to her new classmates. When they eventually run into each other, Danny can't bring himself to be his true self in front of his friends. Embarrassed by his gushing sentiments, his genuine feelings for Sandy, he treats her off-handedly, cruelly even, and it seems impossible that they will ever rediscover their magical connection. Throughout the continuing story of Danny and Sandy's difficult on/off romance, we also follow the exploits of the other characters in their circle  the risqu&eacute; relationship between Kenickie (Jeff Conaway) and Rizzo (Stockard Channing); the rivalry between the T-Birds and another gang, the Scorpions, culminating in a classic car race; an impending dance contest at Rydell; and the final graduation (and goodbyes) of each of the gang. What makes Grease work above everything else is the charm, enthusiasm and energy with which it is presented. There's a sense of everyone pulling in the same direction, entering into the spirit of things in a manner that becomes immediately infectious. The characters are at once lovable and identifiable; their actions and reactions cleverly tuned into real people and real feelings, but dressed up in a joyous musical approach. The musical set pieces are very well done indeed  all the songs pretty much deliver, getting the audience toe-tapping in spite of themselves. Best of all is the sensational closing number, You're The One That I Want, brilliantly choreographed against a fairground backdrop, and featuring Newton John shedding her bookish image and wooing Danny in cinema's most infamous tight leather pants. Performance-wise the film is generally pretty good. Travolta and Newton John have a lovely chemistry, even if their characters are a mite too broadly painted at times. Channing is fabulous as the scene-stealing Rizzo, and Eve Arden has some moments of pure comedic gold as the disapproving school principal Miss McGee. Enduringly popular, always fresh and fun to watch, and a real sing-along favourite, Grease is vastly entertaining if nothing else. Yes, its narrative meanders without much direction at times, but Grease is still a blast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Get Ready To Laugh And Have A Great Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Step right up ladies and gentleman! Get ready to laugh and have a great time! Get ready to watch a delight that you will never forget! Okay, I know that I sound like a game show host, but you'll understand it. From director Randal Kleiser comes a musical comedy that just about anybody is bound to enjoy! That film is the 1978 musical masterpiece that we all know as Grease! That's right people! Grease is a wonderful movie, I repeat, a wonderful movie, an absolutely wonderful movie that is! Why is the movie great? Well step right up to find out why! This movie is funny for one thing, and when I say funny, I mean funny. Funny scenes in this film include any scene in which John Travolta sings in his falsetto, and the restaurant scene, not to mention the recurring school chimes gag. The music is outstanding, no really, it was, about 100% of the time, I was tapping my feet and clapping my hands to the beat of the music. The music in this movie is the type of music that makes you want to get up and dance. And you'll see what I mean! Just watch the film, you'll love it! John Travolta shines in his role as Danny Zuko, a high school senior who finds out that his girlfriend, Sandy Olsen (played fabulously by Olivia Newton-John), is going to the same school as he is (however, his relationship with her is a bit strained). Can these two lovers rekindle the flame for each other? The answer to that question lies in this wonderful musical comedy filled with laughs, passions, great music, great acting, great singing, and just about everything else that you would expect to see from a musical classic. Like musical classics like Singin' In The Rain, My Fair Lady, Seven Brides For Seven Brothers, and 42nd Street among others, most musical films don't get any better than this! This is one of the best movies of 1978, and one of the best musical films that you'll ever see! I am not kidding about that, this film is a classic, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean by that statement! Do you want to see a musical film that you will definitely have fun viewing? Then you have got absolutely nothing to worry about, because the movie known as Grease is just the film for you, it's wonderful, it's marvelous, it's...well, you'll probably understand it when you watch it, which is what you should precisely do! If I was given the chance to watch this fabulous film as second time, I would definitely take that chance and do it, as I loved this film, I loved it all the way through from start to finish! This is a definite must see as far as musical films go, and possibly even as far as films in general go, it's a whole lot of fun, and when I say fun, I mean super fun! Anyway, if you haven't seen this movie, then all I can say is that you have got to see it, because you are missing out on something grand. Ladies and gentlemen, I am proud to present to you a musical classic that's enjoyable for just about everyone, that's the 1978 marvel, Grease. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbewnylorac
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My high school drama teacher pointed out something that a lot of this viewers don't get -- it's a satire! People who hate Grease actually think it's supposed to be a true reflection of early 1960s America, but it's a comedy, a spoof, and it's meant to be fun entertainment. The songs are the best thing, from the pounding opening song, Grease, to the lovely Travolta showpiece ballad, Sandy to the dance spectacular, Hand Jive. There are quite a few silly bits, such as Jan singing the toothbrush song and most of Frenchy's dialogue, but you've got to remember that this is a movie about teenagers, for teenagers, although most of the cast were aged in their 20s and 30s. Highlights for me included Beauty School Dropout by Frankie Avalon, There are Worse Things I Could Do by Stockard Channing and Hopelessly Devoted to You by Olivia Newton-John. Grease was a musical we did at my high school, and it'sjust a quality production that's hugely enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Masturbation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen7272
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    However much sugar you coat this with, Grease is a movie about teenagers expectations for future sex. The film is essentially split into two components. The first is the pre- puberty story of boy loves girl with sugar coated candy floss. The second, the post-puberty, part of the film only takes up the last 15 minutes, is about boys and girls doing the stuff they do prior to back-seat copulation. As a musical the songs essentially come from the pages of a girlie magazine for 13 year old wannabee love hearts. But as adults we view this with nostalgia, for those days before we had to go to work, take out mortgages and bring up families of our own. It reflects that short period of exciting sexual frustration and freedom that society soon inoculates us against until we rediscover it somewhere around our mid-50's. More socially importantly, this is a movie about the beginnings of the Baby Boomer generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease (1978).
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_manRedux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's basically no story structure, the film is episodic and really kind of plot less. Most of these characters are paper thin and the words on the page basically just introduce situations into the screen with no breathing room. The film is so borderline campy it edges on the ridiculous, there's not enough scenes between Sandy and Danny, and don't even get me started on Sandy's late act switch from naive schoolgirl to sultry bombshell (although Jim Jacobs' explanation for this change is very interesting, it doesn't come off in a convincing way on screen). And yet...it works. There's an infusing energy in this film that can only be chalked up to its pitch-perfect cast, who breathe life into these caricatures, and to Randal Kleiser's underrated direction. As far as musicals go (a genre that, I'll admit, I'm not a fan of), this is one of the most entertaining offerings, particularly because it doesn't take itself so seriously like so many modern musicals do. Jeff Conaway and Stockard Channing are scene-stealers, Olivia Newton-John is a charming presence, but it's Travolta's spirited and hilarious performance that takes the cake as MVP.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes Grease girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ronnyk-0101
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm twenty three. My girlfriends and I have real conversations like this. We're poor, fresh out of college, and headed toward grad school (hopefully.) What I'm getting at is this show is relevant to our lives, it's realistic and actually funny. Not all women were like Sex and the City and it's been said that Carrie's extravagant lifestyle was not realistic, this show is. I hate to compare the two but Girls blows SATC out of the water. This show is fresh, funny, and so true that it hurts. Lena Dunham is not only a phenomenal actress but the entire premise is so new and amazing that it's hard to believe she writes and directs each episode. Love is so far and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite musicals that was a highlight of my youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw this film in its entirety (prior to this I saw the musical number clips on VH1) was at the cinema when it was re-released for its 20th anniversary when I was 11 and in my first year at secondary school. Re-visiting this film today brought back many memories, especially my Eisteddfod performance of 'Summer Nights (one of the best songs)' with my form. Before I saw the film in full, I'd listen to the film's soundtrack on tape on 'Wet Play' days (playtime in the classroom on rainy days) with my fellow classmates at primary school. There are plenty of positive aspects of this film such as the majority of musical numbers being memorable (with the exception of There Are Worse Things I Could Do,' Rizzo's second solo performance that I completely forgot about), especially 'Grease Is The Word,' 'Summer Nights,' 'Look At Me I'm Sandra Dee,' 'Hopelessly Devoted To You,' 'Greased Lightning (and the dance to go with it), 'Beauty School Dropout,' 'Sandy (my housemate does a brilliant rendition of this one),' You're The One That I Want (which I also remember from a Shape yoghurt advert from my childhood) and 'We Go Together (which sounds a little like all versions of 'The Tide Is High') as well as a version of 'La Bamba' being played in the background in the first Frosty Palace scene; the costumes and vehicles that were true to the 1950s setting; the impressive choreography (especially the school dance scene) and the odd funny moment, especially the scene where Jan imitates the beaver in the toothpaste commercial at the slumber party at Frenchy's house - I couldn't help myself laughing at that today! I also liked the animated segments consisting of the title sequence, toothpaste commercial and the promotional refreshment animations at the drive-in. After having watched the Nostalgia Chick's review of this film, she helped me notice things I hadn't on previous viewings such as Rizzo feeling like a defective typewriter and her pregnancy rumours, although one thing I noticed for the first time today was product placement (a Reese's Peanut Butter Cups billboard ad in the opening sequence and Jan eating a Twinkie at Frenchy's slumber party). The songs made the film go quickly and they were broken up by the various antics of the T-Birds and the Pink Ladies whether they were hanging out at Frosty Palace or partaking in a car chase. I also remember the up-and-down relationship between the two protagonists very fondly. Overall this is a thoroughly enjoyable musical that has sheer nostalgic value and I'd undoubtedly like to see it time and time again. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Simply Critic-Proof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_rawjalaurence
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are quite simply critic-proof: GREASE is one of these. Forget the flat filming style (by Randal Kleiser) and the fact that the Rydale High students seem way too mature - we should just sit back and enjoy the songs, color, movement and sheer energy of the film. John Travolta's Danny is both arrogant yet touching; someone willing to show bravado in front of his male buddies, yet extremely weak when it comes to showing off his emotions. His body movements are a joy to watch - especially during the sequence where he presents Sandy (Olivia Newton- John) with a cheap ring and asks her to marry him. Newton-John is especially good as a Doris Day/ Sandra Dee-type figure who cannot quite understand why Danny should behave so differently in front of his buddies. Stockard Channing's Rizzo quite simply steals the show; she cultivates a hard-boiled exterior (her real name in the film is Betty), yet cannot cover up an essential vulnerability, especially when she thinks that she is pregnant. GREASE also contains a clutch of memorable cameos from television and film old-timers, from Sid Caesar's Coach Calhoun to Eve Arden's Principal McGee, to Joan Blondell's Vi. In short, there is something in this film for absolutely everyone, regardless of their age and/or cinematic tastes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is the word that you Heard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Samantha Rios
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease is the word. There are many musicals in the world but not one compare to the musical that is Grease. You have the T-birds and the Pink Ladies and new incomer Sandy Olsson, who overall take the story through twists and turns. Good girl Sandy and Greaser Danny must make life-changing decisions on whether being who they are now is worth loosing the one they most care about. Like most musicals, Grease tells their audience the story through song engaging the audience. With the song "Summer Nights" we are introduced into the background information on how exactly Sandy and Danny met during the summer. With the two stories not adding up we get a feel on the personalities of bad boy Danny and sweet and innocent Sandy. After running into each other at a pep rally for the football team, Sandy runs off crying after being humiliated by the bad boy Danny in front of his fellow T-birds and Pink Ladies. Throughout the story we see the numerous attempts by both Danny and Sandy to show one another whether it be changing from a leather jacket to a letterman jacket or dating a jock in attempts to make him jealous. Through "Hopelessly Devoted to You" and " Sandy" the couple show that no matter what they are going through now they cant and wont stop loving each other. While the Danny and Sandy are trying to make things work, Danny's second in command Kenickie is out to beat T-birds rival gang The Scorpions in a race were they will be racing for ownership papers of the cars or what they call "Pinks". Though a series of unfortunate events and Kenickie is incapable of racing he asks his friend Danny to take his place. After winning the race and defeating their rivals we see that Sandy has been watching the race from afar. Asking Pink Ladies' Frenchy for a makeover we see that not only did Danny make the transition from leather jacket to letterman but also Sandy went from innocent to Pink Lady newcomer. In the final scene Rydell High School has rewarded the graduating class with a senior carnival. Here we get the first look at new and improved Danny Zuko who has indeed traded in his T-bird jacket, but he isn't the only one who made a drastic change. After reassuring his fellow boys that this change in jackets didn't mean the end to their friendship, Danny is soon interrupted by the new Sandy Olsson. "You're The One That I Want" is the final song number the couple sing showing that they both changed their ways to be with each other and in the end it worked out for the best. The final number the T-birds and the Pink Ladies perform is the song, " We Go Together". This number gives the audience the final feel for the movie and the two groups of friends as they part ways. Yes the movie isn't the most relevant and up to date movie, but it still has what it takes to be a classic. With the love story that Grease takes us on, we take a trip when not just the girl has to change for the guy but also the guy goes through endless activities to be with his one true love. This movie is one you can't get tired of. The more you watch the more the songs stick with you and with the songs it just adds in to the affect that comes with watching Grease. Grease really and truly is the word. And it's a movie that is worthy enough to be considered a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless and epic musical from my childhood!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a brief note, I have never heard of this film before and I'm only a 90s kind of guy at the time I was a little kid until one day, my father got it on video. Being interested, I watched it and after the first time after my viewing, I became amazed by how epic this film is. I mean, of all the musicals I've seen in every high school production along with cinema, this really takes the cake as one of the best ones yet. Sure, it is a little long and some of the dialog is pretty corny, but hey, those two problems are just nitpicks. Everything else is perfect and holds up well even as a young adult. THe story is amazing with lots of charm and romance that would make you fall in love. The direction from Randal Kleiser is fine and the 1950s setting along with the costumes are brilliant. The characters are pretty good too and the acting is great. John Travolta is a charming Danny Zuko and Olivia Newton-John is a cute and beautiful Sandy. The best part, however, would have to go to the musical song sequences helped by excellent choreography. The songs, "Grease Is The Word", "Summer Nights", "Hopelessly Devoted", "Greased Lightning", "You're The One That I Want", "We'll Be Together" and such are, and always will be, memorable on their own right you will end up humming them for a few hours. Overall, Grease is an epic musical that would always remain in my memory for all time and is recommended to those who haven't seen it yet! It is that good, guys. I'm not gonna lie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wafer thin plot, but still a blast thanks to energy, exuberance and toe-tapping musical numbers.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathon Dabell (barnaby.rudge@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease, like a fine wine, has grown with age. It was a phenomenally successful film in its time but its commercial popularity was not equalled by its critical reception. Not that contemporary critics were especially negative towards it, more that they approved it with blandly above average reviews. To be sure, the plot of Grease is wafer thin and its narrative borders on non-existent between the musical set pieces.. However, it is a film which transcends the basic requirements of strong plot and narrative. It's about joyous set pieces. It's about goofy characters, interacting via goofy dialogue. It's about nostalgia. It's about awkward teen courtship. It's about those last days of high school where the joy of being young is ever-so-slightly tarnished by the encroaching end of one's educational era. The final scene of John Travolta and Olivia Newton John driving off into the sky in a flying car roots the film in a dreamy nostalgic/retrospective landscape, reminding us that we've been watching a fun musical fantasy, nothing more. In terms of achieving its goals  entertaining the audience, rocking us out, and putting a smile on our face  Grease does exactly what it says on the tin. It's the start of a new school year at Rydell High, and T-Bird gang member Danny Zuko (John Travolta) enthusiastically tells his friends about a summer romance that he has enjoyed during the holidays. Unbeknown to him, his summer sweetheart Sandy (Olivia Newton John), has not returned to Australia as expected but, in fact, has enrolled at the same high school, where she relates her amazing summer of love with Danny to her new classmates. When they eventually run into each other, Danny can't bring himself to be his true self in front of his friends. Embarrassed by his gushing sentiments, his genuine feelings for Sandy, he treats her off-handedly, cruelly even, and it seems impossible that they will ever rediscover their magical connection. Throughout the continuing story of Danny and Sandy's difficult on/off romance, we also follow the exploits of the other characters in their circle  the risqu&eacute; relationship between Kenickie (Jeff Conaway) and Rizzo (Stockard Channing); the rivalry between the T-Birds and another gang, the Scorpions, culminating in a classic car race; an impending dance contest at Rydell; and the final graduation (and goodbyes) of each of the gang. What makes Grease work above everything else is the charm, enthusiasm and energy with which it is presented. There's a sense of everyone pulling in the same direction, entering into the spirit of things in a manner that becomes immediately infectious. The characters are at once lovable and identifiable; their actions and reactions cleverly tuned into real people and real feelings, but dressed up in a joyous musical approach. The musical set pieces are very well done indeed  all the songs pretty much deliver, getting the audience toe-tapping in spite of themselves. Best of all is the sensational closing number, You're The One That I Want, brilliantly choreographed against a fairground backdrop, and featuring Newton John shedding her bookish image and wooing Danny in cinema's most infamous tight leather pants. Performance-wise the film is generally pretty good. Travolta and Newton John have a lovely chemistry, even if their characters are a mite too broadly painted at times. Channing is fabulous as the scene-stealing Rizzo, and Eve Arden has some moments of pure comedic gold as the disapproving school principal Miss McGee. Enduringly popular, always fresh and fun to watch, and a real sing-along favourite, Grease is vastly entertaining if nothing else. Yes, its narrative meanders without much direction at times, but Grease is still a blast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Get Ready To Laugh And Have A Great Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Step right up ladies and gentleman! Get ready to laugh and have a great time! Get ready to watch a delight that you will never forget! Okay, I know that I sound like a game show host, but you'll understand it. From director Randal Kleiser comes a musical comedy that just about anybody is bound to enjoy! That film is the 1978 musical masterpiece that we all know as Grease! That's right people! Grease is a wonderful movie, I repeat, a wonderful movie, an absolutely wonderful movie that is! Why is the movie great? Well step right up to find out why! This movie is funny for one thing, and when I say funny, I mean funny. Funny scenes in this film include any scene in which John Travolta sings in his falsetto, and the restaurant scene, not to mention the recurring school chimes gag. The music is outstanding, no really, it was, about 100% of the time, I was tapping my feet and clapping my hands to the beat of the music. The music in this movie is the type of music that makes you want to get up and dance. And you'll see what I mean! Just watch the film, you'll love it! John Travolta shines in his role as Danny Zuko, a high school senior who finds out that his girlfriend, Sandy Olsen (played fabulously by Olivia Newton-John), is going to the same school as he is (however, his relationship with her is a bit strained). Can these two lovers rekindle the flame for each other? The answer to that question lies in this wonderful musical comedy filled with laughs, passions, great music, great acting, great singing, and just about everything else that you would expect to see from a musical classic. Like musical classics like Singin' In The Rain, My Fair Lady, Seven Brides For Seven Brothers, and 42nd Street among others, most musical films don't get any better than this! This is one of the best movies of 1978, and one of the best musical films that you'll ever see! I am not kidding about that, this film is a classic, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean by that statement! Do you want to see a musical film that you will definitely have fun viewing? Then you have got absolutely nothing to worry about, because the movie known as Grease is just the film for you, it's wonderful, it's marvelous, it's...well, you'll probably understand it when you watch it, which is what you should precisely do! If I was given the chance to watch this fabulous film as second time, I would definitely take that chance and do it, as I loved this film, I loved it all the way through from start to finish! This is a definite must see as far as musical films go, and possibly even as far as films in general go, it's a whole lot of fun, and when I say fun, I mean super fun! Anyway, if you haven't seen this movie, then all I can say is that you have got to see it, because you are missing out on something grand. Ladies and gentlemen, I am proud to present to you a musical classic that's enjoyable for just about everyone, that's the 1978 marvel, Grease. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbewnylorac
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My high school drama teacher pointed out something that a lot of this viewers don't get -- it's a satire! People who hate Grease actually think it's supposed to be a true reflection of early 1960s America, but it's a comedy, a spoof, and it's meant to be fun entertainment. The songs are the best thing, from the pounding opening song, Grease, to the lovely Travolta showpiece ballad, Sandy to the dance spectacular, Hand Jive. There are quite a few silly bits, such as Jan singing the toothbrush song and most of Frenchy's dialogue, but you've got to remember that this is a movie about teenagers, for teenagers, although most of the cast were aged in their 20s and 30s. Highlights for me included Beauty School Dropout by Frankie Avalon, There are Worse Things I Could Do by Stockard Channing and Hopelessly Devoted to You by Olivia Newton-John. Grease was a musical we did at my high school, and it'sjust a quality production that's hugely enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Masturbation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen7272
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    However much sugar you coat this with, Grease is a movie about teenagers expectations for future sex. The film is essentially split into two components. The first is the pre- puberty story of boy loves girl with sugar coated candy floss. The second, the post-puberty, part of the film only takes up the last 15 minutes, is about boys and girls doing the stuff they do prior to back-seat copulation. As a musical the songs essentially come from the pages of a girlie magazine for 13 year old wannabee love hearts. But as adults we view this with nostalgia, for those days before we had to go to work, take out mortgages and bring up families of our own. It reflects that short period of exciting sexual frustration and freedom that society soon inoculates us against until we rediscover it somewhere around our mid-50's. More socially importantly, this is a movie about the beginnings of the Baby Boomer generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease (1978).
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_manRedux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's basically no story structure, the film is episodic and really kind of plot less. Most of these characters are paper thin and the words on the page basically just introduce situations into the screen with no breathing room. The film is so borderline campy it edges on the ridiculous, there's not enough scenes between Sandy and Danny, and don't even get me started on Sandy's late act switch from naive schoolgirl to sultry bombshell (although Jim Jacobs' explanation for this change is very interesting, it doesn't come off in a convincing way on screen). And yet...it works. There's an infusing energy in this film that can only be chalked up to its pitch-perfect cast, who breathe life into these caricatures, and to Randal Kleiser's underrated direction. As far as musicals go (a genre that, I'll admit, I'm not a fan of), this is one of the most entertaining offerings, particularly because it doesn't take itself so seriously like so many modern musicals do. Jeff Conaway and Stockard Channing are scene-stealers, Olivia Newton-John is a charming presence, but it's Travolta's spirited and hilarious performance that takes the cake as MVP.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes Grease girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ronnyk-0101
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm twenty three. My girlfriends and I have real conversations like this. We're poor, fresh out of college, and headed toward grad school (hopefully.) What I'm getting at is this show is relevant to our lives, it's realistic and actually funny. Not all women were like Sex and the City and it's been said that Carrie's extravagant lifestyle was not realistic, this show is. I hate to compare the two but Girls blows SATC out of the water. This show is fresh, funny, and so true that it hurts. Lena Dunham is not only a phenomenal actress but the entire premise is so new and amazing that it's hard to believe she writes and directs each episode. Love is so far and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite musicals that was a highlight of my youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw this film in its entirety (prior to this I saw the musical number clips on VH1) was at the cinema when it was re-released for its 20th anniversary when I was 11 and in my first year at secondary school. Re-visiting this film today brought back many memories, especially my Eisteddfod performance of 'Summer Nights (one of the best songs)' with my form. Before I saw the film in full, I'd listen to the film's soundtrack on tape on 'Wet Play' days (playtime in the classroom on rainy days) with my fellow classmates at primary school. There are plenty of positive aspects of this film such as the majority of musical numbers being memorable (with the exception of There Are Worse Things I Could Do,' Rizzo's second solo performance that I completely forgot about), especially 'Grease Is The Word,' 'Summer Nights,' 'Look At Me I'm Sandra Dee,' 'Hopelessly Devoted To You,' 'Greased Lightning (and the dance to go with it), 'Beauty School Dropout,' 'Sandy (my housemate does a brilliant rendition of this one),' You're The One That I Want (which I also remember from a Shape yoghurt advert from my childhood) and 'We Go Together (which sounds a little like all versions of 'The Tide Is High') as well as a version of 'La Bamba' being played in the background in the first Frosty Palace scene; the costumes and vehicles that were true to the 1950s setting; the impressive choreography (especially the school dance scene) and the odd funny moment, especially the scene where Jan imitates the beaver in the toothpaste commercial at the slumber party at Frenchy's house - I couldn't help myself laughing at that today! I also liked the animated segments consisting of the title sequence, toothpaste commercial and the promotional refreshment animations at the drive-in. After having watched the Nostalgia Chick's review of this film, she helped me notice things I hadn't on previous viewings such as Rizzo feeling like a defective typewriter and her pregnancy rumours, although one thing I noticed for the first time today was product placement (a Reese's Peanut Butter Cups billboard ad in the opening sequence and Jan eating a Twinkie at Frenchy's slumber party). The songs made the film go quickly and they were broken up by the various antics of the T-Birds and the Pink Ladies whether they were hanging out at Frosty Palace or partaking in a car chase. I also remember the up-and-down relationship between the two protagonists very fondly. Overall this is a thoroughly enjoyable musical that has sheer nostalgic value and I'd undoubtedly like to see it time and time again. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Simply Critic-Proof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_rawjalaurence
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are quite simply critic-proof: GREASE is one of these. Forget the flat filming style (by Randal Kleiser) and the fact that the Rydale High students seem way too mature - we should just sit back and enjoy the songs, color, movement and sheer energy of the film. John Travolta's Danny is both arrogant yet touching; someone willing to show bravado in front of his male buddies, yet extremely weak when it comes to showing off his emotions. His body movements are a joy to watch - especially during the sequence where he presents Sandy (Olivia Newton- John) with a cheap ring and asks her to marry him. Newton-John is especially good as a Doris Day/ Sandra Dee-type figure who cannot quite understand why Danny should behave so differently in front of his buddies. Stockard Channing's Rizzo quite simply steals the show; she cultivates a hard-boiled exterior (her real name in the film is Betty), yet cannot cover up an essential vulnerability, especially when she thinks that she is pregnant. GREASE also contains a clutch of memorable cameos from television and film old-timers, from Sid Caesar's Coach Calhoun to Eve Arden's Principal McGee, to Joan Blondell's Vi. In short, there is something in this film for absolutely everyone, regardless of their age and/or cinematic tastes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is the word that you Heard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Samantha Rios
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease is the word. There are many musicals in the world but not one compare to the musical that is Grease. You have the T-birds and the Pink Ladies and new incomer Sandy Olsson, who overall take the story through twists and turns. Good girl Sandy and Greaser Danny must make life-changing decisions on whether being who they are now is worth loosing the one they most care about. Like most musicals, Grease tells their audience the story through song engaging the audience. With the song "Summer Nights" we are introduced into the background information on how exactly Sandy and Danny met during the summer. With the two stories not adding up we get a feel on the personalities of bad boy Danny and sweet and innocent Sandy. After running into each other at a pep rally for the football team, Sandy runs off crying after being humiliated by the bad boy Danny in front of his fellow T-birds and Pink Ladies. Throughout the story we see the numerous attempts by both Danny and Sandy to show one another whether it be changing from a leather jacket to a letterman jacket or dating a jock in attempts to make him jealous. Through "Hopelessly Devoted to You" and " Sandy" the couple show that no matter what they are going through now they cant and wont stop loving each other. While the Danny and Sandy are trying to make things work, Danny's second in command Kenickie is out to beat T-birds rival gang The Scorpions in a race were they will be racing for ownership papers of the cars or what they call "Pinks". Though a series of unfortunate events and Kenickie is incapable of racing he asks his friend Danny to take his place. After winning the race and defeating their rivals we see that Sandy has been watching the race from afar. Asking Pink Ladies' Frenchy for a makeover we see that not only did Danny make the transition from leather jacket to letterman but also Sandy went from innocent to Pink Lady newcomer. In the final scene Rydell High School has rewarded the graduating class with a senior carnival. Here we get the first look at new and improved Danny Zuko who has indeed traded in his T-bird jacket, but he isn't the only one who made a drastic change. After reassuring his fellow boys that this change in jackets didn't mean the end to their friendship, Danny is soon interrupted by the new Sandy Olsson. "You're The One That I Want" is the final song number the couple sing showing that they both changed their ways to be with each other and in the end it worked out for the best. The final number the T-birds and the Pink Ladies perform is the song, " We Go Together". This number gives the audience the final feel for the movie and the two groups of friends as they part ways. Yes the movie isn't the most relevant and up to date movie, but it still has what it takes to be a classic. With the love story that Grease takes us on, we take a trip when not just the girl has to change for the guy but also the guy goes through endless activities to be with his one true love. This movie is one you can't get tired of. The more you watch the more the songs stick with you and with the songs it just adds in to the affect that comes with watching Grease. Grease really and truly is the word. And it's a movie that is worthy enough to be considered a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless and epic musical from my childhood!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a brief note, I have never heard of this film before and I'm only a 90s kind of guy at the time I was a little kid until one day, my father got it on video. Being interested, I watched it and after the first time after my viewing, I became amazed by how epic this film is. I mean, of all the musicals I've seen in every high school production along with cinema, this really takes the cake as one of the best ones yet. Sure, it is a little long and some of the dialog is pretty corny, but hey, those two problems are just nitpicks. Everything else is perfect and holds up well even as a young adult. THe story is amazing with lots of charm and romance that would make you fall in love. The direction from Randal Kleiser is fine and the 1950s setting along with the costumes are brilliant. The characters are pretty good too and the acting is great. John Travolta is a charming Danny Zuko and Olivia Newton-John is a cute and beautiful Sandy. The best part, however, would have to go to the musical song sequences helped by excellent choreography. The songs, "Grease Is The Word", "Summer Nights", "Hopelessly Devoted", "Greased Lightning", "You're The One That I Want", "We'll Be Together" and such are, and always will be, memorable on their own right you will end up humming them for a few hours. Overall, Grease is an epic musical that would always remain in my memory for all time and is recommended to those who haven't seen it yet! It is that good, guys. I'm not gonna lie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wafer thin plot, but still a blast thanks to energy, exuberance and toe-tapping musical numbers.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathon Dabell (barnaby.rudge@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease, like a fine wine, has grown with age. It was a phenomenally successful film in its time but its commercial popularity was not equalled by its critical reception. Not that contemporary critics were especially negative towards it, more that they approved it with blandly above average reviews. To be sure, the plot of Grease is wafer thin and its narrative borders on non-existent between the musical set pieces.. However, it is a film which transcends the basic requirements of strong plot and narrative. It's about joyous set pieces. It's about goofy characters, interacting via goofy dialogue. It's about nostalgia. It's about awkward teen courtship. It's about those last days of high school where the joy of being young is ever-so-slightly tarnished by the encroaching end of one's educational era. The final scene of John Travolta and Olivia Newton John driving off into the sky in a flying car roots the film in a dreamy nostalgic/retrospective landscape, reminding us that we've been watching a fun musical fantasy, nothing more. In terms of achieving its goals  entertaining the audience, rocking us out, and putting a smile on our face  Grease does exactly what it says on the tin. It's the start of a new school year at Rydell High, and T-Bird gang member Danny Zuko (John Travolta) enthusiastically tells his friends about a summer romance that he has enjoyed during the holidays. Unbeknown to him, his summer sweetheart Sandy (Olivia Newton John), has not returned to Australia as expected but, in fact, has enrolled at the same high school, where she relates her amazing summer of love with Danny to her new classmates. When they eventually run into each other, Danny can't bring himself to be his true self in front of his friends. Embarrassed by his gushing sentiments, his genuine feelings for Sandy, he treats her off-handedly, cruelly even, and it seems impossible that they will ever rediscover their magical connection. Throughout the continuing story of Danny and Sandy's difficult on/off romance, we also follow the exploits of the other characters in their circle  the risqu&eacute; relationship between Kenickie (Jeff Conaway) and Rizzo (Stockard Channing); the rivalry between the T-Birds and another gang, the Scorpions, culminating in a classic car race; an impending dance contest at Rydell; and the final graduation (and goodbyes) of each of the gang. What makes Grease work above everything else is the charm, enthusiasm and energy with which it is presented. There's a sense of everyone pulling in the same direction, entering into the spirit of things in a manner that becomes immediately infectious. The characters are at once lovable and identifiable; their actions and reactions cleverly tuned into real people and real feelings, but dressed up in a joyous musical approach. The musical set pieces are very well done indeed  all the songs pretty much deliver, getting the audience toe-tapping in spite of themselves. Best of all is the sensational closing number, You're The One That I Want, brilliantly choreographed against a fairground backdrop, and featuring Newton John shedding her bookish image and wooing Danny in cinema's most infamous tight leather pants. Performance-wise the film is generally pretty good. Travolta and Newton John have a lovely chemistry, even if their characters are a mite too broadly painted at times. Channing is fabulous as the scene-stealing Rizzo, and Eve Arden has some moments of pure comedic gold as the disapproving school principal Miss McGee. Enduringly popular, always fresh and fun to watch, and a real sing-along favourite, Grease is vastly entertaining if nothing else. Yes, its narrative meanders without much direction at times, but Grease is still a blast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Get Ready To Laugh And Have A Great Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Step right up ladies and gentleman! Get ready to laugh and have a great time! Get ready to watch a delight that you will never forget! Okay, I know that I sound like a game show host, but you'll understand it. From director Randal Kleiser comes a musical comedy that just about anybody is bound to enjoy! That film is the 1978 musical masterpiece that we all know as Grease! That's right people! Grease is a wonderful movie, I repeat, a wonderful movie, an absolutely wonderful movie that is! Why is the movie great? Well step right up to find out why! This movie is funny for one thing, and when I say funny, I mean funny. Funny scenes in this film include any scene in which John Travolta sings in his falsetto, and the restaurant scene, not to mention the recurring school chimes gag. The music is outstanding, no really, it was, about 100% of the time, I was tapping my feet and clapping my hands to the beat of the music. The music in this movie is the type of music that makes you want to get up and dance. And you'll see what I mean! Just watch the film, you'll love it! John Travolta shines in his role as Danny Zuko, a high school senior who finds out that his girlfriend, Sandy Olsen (played fabulously by Olivia Newton-John), is going to the same school as he is (however, his relationship with her is a bit strained). Can these two lovers rekindle the flame for each other? The answer to that question lies in this wonderful musical comedy filled with laughs, passions, great music, great acting, great singing, and just about everything else that you would expect to see from a musical classic. Like musical classics like Singin' In The Rain, My Fair Lady, Seven Brides For Seven Brothers, and 42nd Street among others, most musical films don't get any better than this! This is one of the best movies of 1978, and one of the best musical films that you'll ever see! I am not kidding about that, this film is a classic, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean by that statement! Do you want to see a musical film that you will definitely have fun viewing? Then you have got absolutely nothing to worry about, because the movie known as Grease is just the film for you, it's wonderful, it's marvelous, it's...well, you'll probably understand it when you watch it, which is what you should precisely do! If I was given the chance to watch this fabulous film as second time, I would definitely take that chance and do it, as I loved this film, I loved it all the way through from start to finish! This is a definite must see as far as musical films go, and possibly even as far as films in general go, it's a whole lot of fun, and when I say fun, I mean super fun! Anyway, if you haven't seen this movie, then all I can say is that you have got to see it, because you are missing out on something grand. Ladies and gentlemen, I am proud to present to you a musical classic that's enjoyable for just about everyone, that's the 1978 marvel, Grease. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbewnylorac
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My high school drama teacher pointed out something that a lot of this viewers don't get -- it's a satire! People who hate Grease actually think it's supposed to be a true reflection of early 1960s America, but it's a comedy, a spoof, and it's meant to be fun entertainment. The songs are the best thing, from the pounding opening song, Grease, to the lovely Travolta showpiece ballad, Sandy to the dance spectacular, Hand Jive. There are quite a few silly bits, such as Jan singing the toothbrush song and most of Frenchy's dialogue, but you've got to remember that this is a movie about teenagers, for teenagers, although most of the cast were aged in their 20s and 30s. Highlights for me included Beauty School Dropout by Frankie Avalon, There are Worse Things I Could Do by Stockard Channing and Hopelessly Devoted to You by Olivia Newton-John. Grease was a musical we did at my high school, and it'sjust a quality production that's hugely enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Masturbation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen7272
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    However much sugar you coat this with, Grease is a movie about teenagers expectations for future sex. The film is essentially split into two components. The first is the pre- puberty story of boy loves girl with sugar coated candy floss. The second, the post-puberty, part of the film only takes up the last 15 minutes, is about boys and girls doing the stuff they do prior to back-seat copulation. As a musical the songs essentially come from the pages of a girlie magazine for 13 year old wannabee love hearts. But as adults we view this with nostalgia, for those days before we had to go to work, take out mortgages and bring up families of our own. It reflects that short period of exciting sexual frustration and freedom that society soon inoculates us against until we rediscover it somewhere around our mid-50's. More socially importantly, this is a movie about the beginnings of the Baby Boomer generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease (1978).
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_manRedux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's basically no story structure, the film is episodic and really kind of plot less. Most of these characters are paper thin and the words on the page basically just introduce situations into the screen with no breathing room. The film is so borderline campy it edges on the ridiculous, there's not enough scenes between Sandy and Danny, and don't even get me started on Sandy's late act switch from naive schoolgirl to sultry bombshell (although Jim Jacobs' explanation for this change is very interesting, it doesn't come off in a convincing way on screen). And yet...it works. There's an infusing energy in this film that can only be chalked up to its pitch-perfect cast, who breathe life into these caricatures, and to Randal Kleiser's underrated direction. As far as musicals go (a genre that, I'll admit, I'm not a fan of), this is one of the most entertaining offerings, particularly because it doesn't take itself so seriously like so many modern musicals do. Jeff Conaway and Stockard Channing are scene-stealers, Olivia Newton-John is a charming presence, but it's Travolta's spirited and hilarious performance that takes the cake as MVP.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes Grease girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ronnyk-0101
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm twenty three. My girlfriends and I have real conversations like this. We're poor, fresh out of college, and headed toward grad school (hopefully.) What I'm getting at is this show is relevant to our lives, it's realistic and actually funny. Not all women were like Sex and the City and it's been said that Carrie's extravagant lifestyle was not realistic, this show is. I hate to compare the two but Girls blows SATC out of the water. This show is fresh, funny, and so true that it hurts. Lena Dunham is not only a phenomenal actress but the entire premise is so new and amazing that it's hard to believe she writes and directs each episode. Love is so far and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favourite musicals that was a highlight of my youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stompgal_87
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw this film in its entirety (prior to this I saw the musical number clips on VH1) was at the cinema when it was re-released for its 20th anniversary when I was 11 and in my first year at secondary school. Re-visiting this film today brought back many memories, especially my Eisteddfod performance of 'Summer Nights (one of the best songs)' with my form. Before I saw the film in full, I'd listen to the film's soundtrack on tape on 'Wet Play' days (playtime in the classroom on rainy days) with my fellow classmates at primary school. There are plenty of positive aspects of this film such as the majority of musical numbers being memorable (with the exception of There Are Worse Things I Could Do,' Rizzo's second solo performance that I completely forgot about), especially 'Grease Is The Word,' 'Summer Nights,' 'Look At Me I'm Sandra Dee,' 'Hopelessly Devoted To You,' 'Greased Lightning (and the dance to go with it), 'Beauty School Dropout,' 'Sandy (my housemate does a brilliant rendition of this one),' You're The One That I Want (which I also remember from a Shape yoghurt advert from my childhood) and 'We Go Together (which sounds a little like all versions of 'The Tide Is High') as well as a version of 'La Bamba' being played in the background in the first Frosty Palace scene; the costumes and vehicles that were true to the 1950s setting; the impressive choreography (especially the school dance scene) and the odd funny moment, especially the scene where Jan imitates the beaver in the toothpaste commercial at the slumber party at Frenchy's house - I couldn't help myself laughing at that today! I also liked the animated segments consisting of the title sequence, toothpaste commercial and the promotional refreshment animations at the drive-in. After having watched the Nostalgia Chick's review of this film, she helped me notice things I hadn't on previous viewings such as Rizzo feeling like a defective typewriter and her pregnancy rumours, although one thing I noticed for the first time today was product placement (a Reese's Peanut Butter Cups billboard ad in the opening sequence and Jan eating a Twinkie at Frenchy's slumber party). The songs made the film go quickly and they were broken up by the various antics of the T-Birds and the Pink Ladies whether they were hanging out at Frosty Palace or partaking in a car chase. I also remember the up-and-down relationship between the two protagonists very fondly. Overall this is a thoroughly enjoyable musical that has sheer nostalgic value and I'd undoubtedly like to see it time and time again. 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Simply Critic-Proof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    l_rawjalaurence
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some films that are quite simply critic-proof: GREASE is one of these. Forget the flat filming style (by Randal Kleiser) and the fact that the Rydale High students seem way too mature - we should just sit back and enjoy the songs, color, movement and sheer energy of the film. John Travolta's Danny is both arrogant yet touching; someone willing to show bravado in front of his male buddies, yet extremely weak when it comes to showing off his emotions. His body movements are a joy to watch - especially during the sequence where he presents Sandy (Olivia Newton- John) with a cheap ring and asks her to marry him. Newton-John is especially good as a Doris Day/ Sandra Dee-type figure who cannot quite understand why Danny should behave so differently in front of his buddies. Stockard Channing's Rizzo quite simply steals the show; she cultivates a hard-boiled exterior (her real name in the film is Betty), yet cannot cover up an essential vulnerability, especially when she thinks that she is pregnant. GREASE also contains a clutch of memorable cameos from television and film old-timers, from Sid Caesar's Coach Calhoun to Eve Arden's Principal McGee, to Joan Blondell's Vi. In short, there is something in this film for absolutely everyone, regardless of their age and/or cinematic tastes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is the word that you Heard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Samantha Rios
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease is the word. There are many musicals in the world but not one compare to the musical that is Grease. You have the T-birds and the Pink Ladies and new incomer Sandy Olsson, who overall take the story through twists and turns. Good girl Sandy and Greaser Danny must make life-changing decisions on whether being who they are now is worth loosing the one they most care about. Like most musicals, Grease tells their audience the story through song engaging the audience. With the song "Summer Nights" we are introduced into the background information on how exactly Sandy and Danny met during the summer. With the two stories not adding up we get a feel on the personalities of bad boy Danny and sweet and innocent Sandy. After running into each other at a pep rally for the football team, Sandy runs off crying after being humiliated by the bad boy Danny in front of his fellow T-birds and Pink Ladies. Throughout the story we see the numerous attempts by both Danny and Sandy to show one another whether it be changing from a leather jacket to a letterman jacket or dating a jock in attempts to make him jealous. Through "Hopelessly Devoted to You" and " Sandy" the couple show that no matter what they are going through now they cant and wont stop loving each other. While the Danny and Sandy are trying to make things work, Danny's second in command Kenickie is out to beat T-birds rival gang The Scorpions in a race were they will be racing for ownership papers of the cars or what they call "Pinks". Though a series of unfortunate events and Kenickie is incapable of racing he asks his friend Danny to take his place. After winning the race and defeating their rivals we see that Sandy has been watching the race from afar. Asking Pink Ladies' Frenchy for a makeover we see that not only did Danny make the transition from leather jacket to letterman but also Sandy went from innocent to Pink Lady newcomer. In the final scene Rydell High School has rewarded the graduating class with a senior carnival. Here we get the first look at new and improved Danny Zuko who has indeed traded in his T-bird jacket, but he isn't the only one who made a drastic change. After reassuring his fellow boys that this change in jackets didn't mean the end to their friendship, Danny is soon interrupted by the new Sandy Olsson. "You're The One That I Want" is the final song number the couple sing showing that they both changed their ways to be with each other and in the end it worked out for the best. The final number the T-birds and the Pink Ladies perform is the song, " We Go Together". This number gives the audience the final feel for the movie and the two groups of friends as they part ways. Yes the movie isn't the most relevant and up to date movie, but it still has what it takes to be a classic. With the love story that Grease takes us on, we take a trip when not just the girl has to change for the guy but also the guy goes through endless activities to be with his one true love. This movie is one you can't get tired of. The more you watch the more the songs stick with you and with the songs it just adds in to the affect that comes with watching Grease. Grease really and truly is the word. And it's a movie that is worthy enough to be considered a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless and epic musical from my childhood!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a brief note, I have never heard of this film before and I'm only a 90s kind of guy at the time I was a little kid until one day, my father got it on video. Being interested, I watched it and after the first time after my viewing, I became amazed by how epic this film is. I mean, of all the musicals I've seen in every high school production along with cinema, this really takes the cake as one of the best ones yet. Sure, it is a little long and some of the dialog is pretty corny, but hey, those two problems are just nitpicks. Everything else is perfect and holds up well even as a young adult. THe story is amazing with lots of charm and romance that would make you fall in love. The direction from Randal Kleiser is fine and the 1950s setting along with the costumes are brilliant. The characters are pretty good too and the acting is great. John Travolta is a charming Danny Zuko and Olivia Newton-John is a cute and beautiful Sandy. The best part, however, would have to go to the musical song sequences helped by excellent choreography. The songs, "Grease Is The Word", "Summer Nights", "Hopelessly Devoted", "Greased Lightning", "You're The One That I Want", "We'll Be Together" and such are, and always will be, memorable on their own right you will end up humming them for a few hours. Overall, Grease is an epic musical that would always remain in my memory for all time and is recommended to those who haven't seen it yet! It is that good, guys. I'm not gonna lie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wafer thin plot, but still a blast thanks to energy, exuberance and toe-tapping musical numbers.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathon Dabell (barnaby.rudge@hotmail.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grease, like a fine wine, has grown with age. It was a phenomenally successful film in its time but its commercial popularity was not equalled by its critical reception. Not that contemporary critics were especially negative towards it, more that they approved it with blandly above average reviews. To be sure, the plot of Grease is wafer thin and its narrative borders on non-existent between the musical set pieces.. However, it is a film which transcends the basic requirements of strong plot and narrative. It's about joyous set pieces. It's about goofy characters, interacting via goofy dialogue. It's about nostalgia. It's about awkward teen courtship. It's about those last days of high school where the joy of being young is ever-so-slightly tarnished by the encroaching end of one's educational era. The final scene of John Travolta and Olivia Newton John driving off into the sky in a flying car roots the film in a dreamy nostalgic/retrospective landscape, reminding us that we've been watching a fun musical fantasy, nothing more. In terms of achieving its goals  entertaining the audience, rocking us out, and putting a smile on our face  Grease does exactly what it says on the tin. It's the start of a new school year at Rydell High, and T-Bird gang member Danny Zuko (John Travolta) enthusiastically tells his friends about a summer romance that he has enjoyed during the holidays. Unbeknown to him, his summer sweetheart Sandy (Olivia Newton John), has not returned to Australia as expected but, in fact, has enrolled at the same high school, where she relates her amazing summer of love with Danny to her new classmates. When they eventually run into each other, Danny can't bring himself to be his true self in front of his friends. Embarrassed by his gushing sentiments, his genuine feelings for Sandy, he treats her off-handedly, cruelly even, and it seems impossible that they will ever rediscover their magical connection. Throughout the continuing story of Danny and Sandy's difficult on/off romance, we also follow the exploits of the other characters in their circle  the risqu&eacute; relationship between Kenickie (Jeff Conaway) and Rizzo (Stockard Channing); the rivalry between the T-Birds and another gang, the Scorpions, culminating in a classic car race; an impending dance contest at Rydell; and the final graduation (and goodbyes) of each of the gang. What makes Grease work above everything else is the charm, enthusiasm and energy with which it is presented. There's a sense of everyone pulling in the same direction, entering into the spirit of things in a manner that becomes immediately infectious. The characters are at once lovable and identifiable; their actions and reactions cleverly tuned into real people and real feelings, but dressed up in a joyous musical approach. The musical set pieces are very well done indeed  all the songs pretty much deliver, getting the audience toe-tapping in spite of themselves. Best of all is the sensational closing number, You're The One That I Want, brilliantly choreographed against a fairground backdrop, and featuring Newton John shedding her bookish image and wooing Danny in cinema's most infamous tight leather pants. Performance-wise the film is generally pretty good. Travolta and Newton John have a lovely chemistry, even if their characters are a mite too broadly painted at times. Channing is fabulous as the scene-stealing Rizzo, and Eve Arden has some moments of pure comedic gold as the disapproving school principal Miss McGee. Enduringly popular, always fresh and fun to watch, and a real sing-along favourite, Grease is vastly entertaining if nothing else. Yes, its narrative meanders without much direction at times, but Grease is still a blast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Get Ready To Laugh And Have A Great Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Step right up ladies and gentleman! Get ready to laugh and have a great time! Get ready to watch a delight that you will never forget! Okay, I know that I sound like a game show host, but you'll understand it. From director Randal Kleiser comes a musical comedy that just about anybody is bound to enjoy! That film is the 1978 musical masterpiece that we all know as Grease! That's right people! Grease is a wonderful movie, I repeat, a wonderful movie, an absolutely wonderful movie that is! Why is the movie great? Well step right up to find out why! This movie is funny for one thing, and when I say funny, I mean funny. Funny scenes in this film include any scene in which John Travolta sings in his falsetto, and the restaurant scene, not to mention the recurring school chimes gag. The music is outstanding, no really, it was, about 100% of the time, I was tapping my feet and clapping my hands to the beat of the music. The music in this movie is the type of music that makes you want to get up and dance. And you'll see what I mean! Just watch the film, you'll love it! John Travolta shines in his role as Danny Zuko, a high school senior who finds out that his girlfriend, Sandy Olsen (played fabulously by Olivia Newton-John), is going to the same school as he is (however, his relationship with her is a bit strained). Can these two lovers rekindle the flame for each other? The answer to that question lies in this wonderful musical comedy filled with laughs, passions, great music, great acting, great singing, and just about everything else that you would expect to see from a musical classic. Like musical classics like Singin' In The Rain, My Fair Lady, Seven Brides For Seven Brothers, and 42nd Street among others, most musical films don't get any better than this! This is one of the best movies of 1978, and one of the best musical films that you'll ever see! I am not kidding about that, this film is a classic, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean by that statement! Do you want to see a musical film that you will definitely have fun viewing? Then you have got absolutely nothing to worry about, because the movie known as Grease is just the film for you, it's wonderful, it's marvelous, it's...well, you'll probably understand it when you watch it, which is what you should precisely do! If I was given the chance to watch this fabulous film as second time, I would definitely take that chance and do it, as I loved this film, I loved it all the way through from start to finish! This is a definite must see as far as musical films go, and possibly even as far as films in general go, it's a whole lot of fun, and when I say fun, I mean super fun! Anyway, if you haven't seen this movie, then all I can say is that you have got to see it, because you are missing out on something grand. Ladies and gentlemen, I am proud to present to you a musical classic that's enjoyable for just about everyone, that's the 1978 marvel, Grease. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease is great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbewnylorac
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My high school drama teacher pointed out something that a lot of this viewers don't get -- it's a satire! People who hate Grease actually think it's supposed to be a true reflection of early 1960s America, but it's a comedy, a spoof, and it's meant to be fun entertainment. The songs are the best thing, from the pounding opening song, Grease, to the lovely Travolta showpiece ballad, Sandy to the dance spectacular, Hand Jive. There are quite a few silly bits, such as Jan singing the toothbrush song and most of Frenchy's dialogue, but you've got to remember that this is a movie about teenagers, for teenagers, although most of the cast were aged in their 20s and 30s. Highlights for me included Beauty School Dropout by Frankie Avalon, There are Worse Things I Could Do by Stockard Channing and Hopelessly Devoted to You by Olivia Newton-John. Grease was a musical we did at my high school, and it'sjust a quality production that's hugely enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Masturbation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen7272
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    However much sugar you coat this with, Grease is a movie about teenagers expectations for future sex. The film is essentially split into two components. The first is the pre- puberty story of boy loves girl with sugar coated candy floss. The second, the post-puberty, part of the film only takes up the last 15 minutes, is about boys and girls doing the stuff they do prior to back-seat copulation. As a musical the songs essentially come from the pages of a girlie magazine for 13 year old wannabee love hearts. But as adults we view this with nostalgia, for those days before we had to go to work, take out mortgages and bring up families of our own. It reflects that short period of exciting sexual frustration and freedom that society soon inoculates us against until we rediscover it somewhere around our mid-50's. More socially importantly, this is a movie about the beginnings of the Baby Boomer generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grease (1978).
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_manRedux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's basically no story structure, the film is episodic and really kind of plot less. Most of these characters are paper thin and the words on the page basically just introduce situations into the screen with no breathing room. The film is so borderline campy it edges on the ridiculous, there's not enough scenes between Sandy and Danny, and don't even get me started on Sandy's late act switch from naive schoolgirl to sultry bombshell (although Jim Jacobs' explanation for this change is very interesting, it doesn't come off in a convincing way on screen). And yet...it works. There's an infusing energy in this film that can only be chalked up to its pitch-perfect cast, who breathe life into these caricatures, and to Randal Kleiser's underrated direction. As far as musicals go (a genre that, I'll admit, I'm not a fan of), this is one of the most entertaining offerings, particularly because it doesn't take itself so seriously like so many modern musicals do. Jeff Conaway and Stockard Channing are scene-stealers, Olivia Newton-John is a charming presence, but it's Travolta's spirited and hilarious performance that takes the cake as MVP.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes Grease girls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ronnyk-0101
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm twenty three. My girlfriends and I have real conversations like this. We're poor, fresh out of college, and headed toward grad school (hopefully.) What I'm getting at is this show is relevant to our lives, it's realistic and actually funny. Not all women were like Sex and the City and it's been said that Carrie's extravagant lifestyle was not realistic, this show is. I hate to compare the two but Girls blows SATC out of the water. This show is fresh, funny, and so true that it hurts. Lena Dunham is not only a phenomenal actress but the entire premise is so new and amazing that it's hard to believe she writes and directs each episode. Love is so far and I recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
