<filme>
 <id>
  453
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0085750
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1983
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Tubar&atilde;o III
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  3.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The sons of police chief Brody must protect civilians at a Sea World theme park after a 35-foot shark becomes trapped in the park with them.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Michael Brody and Sean Brody, the sons of former Amity police chief Martin Brody, work at Florida's Sea World, a seaside park run by Calvin Bouchard. Sean befriends Kelly Ann Bukowski, and Michael's girlfriend Kathryn Morgan is Sea World's head scientist who always works with Sea World's dolphins Cindy and Sandy. In its man-made lagoon, about 40 feet under the water, Sea World opens the Undersea Kingdom, a new set of underwater glass tunnels that have their own control room, and Calvin's friend Philip FitzRoyce is there to do some filming. When Sea World diver Shelby Overman vanishes, everyone is worried. Michael and Kathryn head into the water, where they find a baby great white shark and decide to bring it to Sea World to put it on display, but at Sea World, the baby shark dies. When Overman's body is found, Michael vomits when he sees it. Kathryn looks at the body and knows that the baby shark could not have been the shark that killed Overman, because the baby shark's bite radius ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   shark
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sea
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sea world
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   florida
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   theme park
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Joe Alves
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Peter Benchley
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Richard Matheson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dennis Quaid
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bess Armstrong
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Simon MacCorkindale
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3-D This Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set several years after the events of Part II, Chief Brody's sons Mike & Sean(Roy Scheider did not return) are now young adults at Sea World in Florida, where yet another killer great white shark emerges, trying to track down its baby, who is being kept there and studied. Scientists and hunters must team up to defeat this menace before it kills the incoming tourists... Now in(shoddy) 3-D, this film is just inept, with a ridiculous, uninspired plot, poor science regarding sharks, and no story involvement whatsoever. Utterly devoid of a point, just a blatant cash-in on the title and resurgent popularity of 3-D(Third Jaws film in 3-D, clever no?) A bust.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Mockery To The 'Jaws' Name
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movieman
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3 has to be the worst movie I've ever seen in my whole life. If I could rate it 0 stars then I would. I didn't believe one bit that there was a shark in the waters, even though I did i Jaws 1 and 2. Firstly, the special effects were so out of date. In the dolphin scene, were they first saw the shark, when you see the Great White for the first time, I found that they just stole the footage from an old National Geographic Documentary. Secondly, this movie was full of sexual references. For example, Sean Brody says to his older brother Michael Brody, "I was so close to doing it in the water last night." after doing something inappropriate at the beach the previous night. Finally, the amount of shark facts they got wrong was just tremendous. I completely lost count. Overall, if you want to watch all of the 'Jaws' movies, I advise you skip this to 'Jaws: The Revenge' for nothing important happens in this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great idea, not done right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Dalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3-D had so much potential and it could have been the best in the series if they had done it right. The story is pure gold but unfortunately the scenes didn't go that far or break any rules. Not to mention that the 3D was awful. Another problem with this movie is that the dialogue was bad and the acting was horrible for the most part. If you want to see this movie, keep your expectations very low because you will likely be disappointed. Jaws 3-D as a whole was just mediocre as a whole but it does have some redeeming features. The things that are good about this movie are that the shark attack scenes were pretty cool and scarier than the first two and that the story is wildly original compared to the first two.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really isn't all that bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alienator Donut
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D was a satisfactory sequel with only very few flaws. The 3D visual effects were quite laughable. The plot was promising enough, it is set at Sea World, where a group of people set up an aquarium, It IS different to the other Jaws films, because Chief Brody does not make an appearance, (Even though he is often mentioned, and his sons are main characters in this film.) My personal favourite scene was the scene involving the very slow moving shark swimming to the screen with crashing into the glass window, it is later blown up! With laughable CGI special effects, and a soundtrack with a melody sounding like the Christmas song: "Joy to the world!" Jaws 3D is an entertaining enough second sequel! However, it looks like Citizen Kane, compared to its so bad it's hilarious follow up: "Jaws: The Revenge!" 6/10 Written By Alienator Donut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What, Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    suckmeoffflemwad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now Jaws 2 was a totally unnecessary sequel as I have said, however this film, Jaws 3-D is even more foul and pestilent, for starters, it lacks, and I mean it lacks, the signature shark theme from all the other films, this is what made Jaws so powerful and startling, that iconic theme. They have removed the power of the monster by replacing its theme with some bullshit merry melody, and here we barely even get to see the shark at all, I mean not like in the first, I mean in a bad way, and it kills very few people, it poses barely any threat at all, and for Christ's sake, its baby dies, and it wants revenge, sharks will eat their babies if they don't mature and scamper off quick enough, I mean seriously those idiots got even more dumb. Sharks don't have bonds, sharks are cold and emotionless, they don't take mates, and they don't care for their children a whole awful lot, they are just brainless instinctual fish, that must keep moving or they will die, this is why the geniuses in the movie put the baby in a cramped little tank, and shocked it shitless with a whole crowd of gawking people. Now this movie is very pointless, and very bad, and the way they kill the shark is pathetic, it can't swallow a guy whole for some reason when it can all those other times, and somehow he doesn't let go of his grenade, and they are able to pull the pin, I mean it just sounds utterly ridiculous. This film is horrifying and stupid in every single way, and I want to never defile my eyes by viewing it again, oh wait I just did, and saw that they used the shark theme, but still.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D The best thing about seeing a Great White Shark in 3D is that you'll look so stupid wearing those 3D glasses that it'll be too busy laughing at you to attack. However, no comical-looking headgear could keep the aquatic killer in this horror movie from ravaging you. A juvenile shark infiltrates the gates separating SeaWorld from the sea. Inside the underwater attraction, the finned-intruder begins preying on the animals and their trainers. When employees (Dennis Quaid, Bess Armstrong) go to the park manager (Louis Gossett, Jr.) with this news, he decides to profit off it. But when the mother comes looking for her pup, visitors trapped in the park's submerged tunnel system become its victims. The second sequel to Jaws, Jaws 3D is a lackluster contribution to the seafaring series that jumps the shark with this installment. Besides, SeaWorld doesn't need any outside help in killing their captive animal population. (Red Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just okay, no matter how many dimensions you see it in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even aside from the timely numerical designation of this sequel, the Jaws franchise seems like a natural for the realm of 3-D. The requisite underwater terrain alone is a perfect medium for textured dimensional rendering, and the idea of a terrifying, relentless killing machine swimming off-screen into audiences' laps is inherently awesome in and of itself. Sadly, this uneven offering never takes full advantage of its technology or its subject matter, and while it's nowhere near as bad as the truly abysmal Jaws: The Revenge (few things are), it's also nowhere near as good as the flawless original or the excellent and unfairly dismissed follow-up. Even without its potentially interesting visual ploy, Jaws 3-D has all of the ingredients to be a great sequel on paper: a stellar cast, a fresh concept, and, of course, a toothy behemoth that had already generated some of the scariest moments in screen history. These assets are ultimately squandered however. The seasoned ensemble is given very little to do, so the character studies at the heart of Jaws and Jaws 2 are bypassed entirely. The Sea World setting is woefully underused, and instead of giving our beast a novel killing ground, the park mostly functions as merely another mass of water for the action to unfold in. Worse, the shark itself isn't ever used in a suspenseful fashion, and the handful of deaths attributed to the monster are blatantly telegraphed and largely ineffective. Like many 3-D films that are stripped of their visual device for the home market, this one contains multiple scenes that may have been fun to behold on theater screens, but become utterly silly here. Floating fish heads and severed limbs bobbing with the tide might have provided cheap thrills for the opening weekend audience, but in a flat DVD representation, they simply function as camera shots that linger for far too long. The shark effects range from serviceable to downright awful, and since footage of actual sharks is utilized rather extensively, the titular titan more clearly resembles a synthetic puppet when we're seeing it at work. A couple of scenes of the creature slamming into gates and boats seem to have been created by using a plastic mock-up instead the sophisticated robotic construct that populated the first two Jaws outings, and since little effort is made to sell these moments, you can actually see the rubber shark bounce off its targets upon collision. When these flashes are integrated alongside the graceful maneuvering of real great whites, there is little symmetry between the two versions and the complete suspension of disbelief required to make a scenario like this pay off is rarely achieved. Apart from its obviousness as a prop, the shark in Jaws 3-D just isn't all that frightening because the meager body count doesn't allow it to prove itself as an insatiable murder machine. A couple of random victims are thrown in early on, but when the shark finally makes its way into the water park, where a virtual sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord of flailing legs awaits, every single person the shark pursues easily escapes its titular Jaws. Only one of the major characters gets bit during this extended sequence, and she gets away with little more than a few scratches on her leg. There are a few solid jump scares peppered throughout the film, but while the tension seems to be mounting every step of the way, the movie invariably pulls back before anything all that spectacular or horrifying occurs. Even the promising climax goes flaccid when the absolute dumbest false 3-D moment occurs, and any menace our finned antagonist has generated along the way is readily diffused by a protracted shot of her slowly floating toward the camera and breaking through a plainly animated sheet of glass. The way the shark is dispatched is particularly hard to swallow (this is actually a pretty good pun if you've seen the film), and yet another silly extended "in your face" moment caps off a tremendously underwhelming resolution. Savvy collectors will easily be able to track down readily available bootleg DVDs that retain the original 3-D presentation, but even the cleanest transfer available on the secondary market is still high-generation and extremely murky, a state which naturally strips away the potency of the visual effects. Watching my copy gave me a headache, and I had to stop about every thirty minutes or so to take off the glasses and give my eyes a rest. I eventually made it through, but when I did, all I discovered was that Jaws 3-D isn't much more impressive in its original form. The obsessive collector in me knows that if this offering ever gets a proper Blu-Ray release I will have to add it to my collection and give the film at least one more go, but the realist in me is guessing that even digitized 3-D effects won't make up for the numerous other weaknesses on hand here. There are a few effective moments here that will hold the attention of admirers of the series, but the film as a whole is a missed opportunity that can only be rightfully recommended to the most forgiving killer fish fans. An even better recommendation for those who have digested every frame of the unmatchable original and simply must have more is to skip this one entirely and give Jaws 2 another look instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Third Dimension is Terrible!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It used to be so simple to point out the bad shark movies. There was "Jaws 3" and "Jaws 4: The Revenge", and that was it pretty much! But then, as per the late nineties approximately, we literally received an overflow of inferior and quite often downright retarded killer shark flicks. And now all of a sudden, the aforementioned Jaws sequels actually don't look too terrible anymore. It started in the late 90's with the still traditional but totally inept "Deep Blue Sea" and "Shark Attack", but then since the new Millennium things really got out of control with murderous sharks popping up in the most illogical of places (like the rivers in Venice, in Tsunami infested areas, swamps, etc) and  worse even  all kinds of ridiculous hybrids and genetically altered species, like dinosaur sharks, octopus-sharks and two-headed sharks. Sigh  whatever happened to good-old fashioned massively over-sized Great Whites, like in our classic early 80's stinker "Jaws 3-D"? Now, please don't misunderstand me, the third installment in the Jaws franchise is still a very lousy film, but at least it's not bad in a frustrating or annoying way. The underdeveloped screenplay, the laughable attempt to bring depth to the main characters, the hilarious 3D effects and all the totally irrelevant padding footage  It almost feels cheesy and charming in a positive sort of way now. Interesting detail here is that Universal Studios, the mastodon production company behind the Jaws franchise, sued the creators of an obscure Italian imitation for being too reminiscent, but then they were hypocrite enough to steal ideas from the movie they accused of stealing from them! That's Hollywood for you, I guess. The script attempts, poorly I may add, to build a bridge between the previous two movies by depicting the Brody boys (the sons of Roy Scheider) as pivot characters in the grand opening of a brand new Florida Ocean theme park. Mike, the oldest one, works there as the head engineer and his younger brother Sean  supposedly still suffering from his childhood trauma even though he blindly follows the first cute girl he meets straight in the water for a nightly swimming session  comes to visit him for the ceremony. Due to malfunctioning underwater fences and unreliable technical staff, the park quickly receives unforeseen visitors in the shape of a great white shark and its offspring. Also in good old Jaws tradition, the park's senior executive initially hopes to exploit the baby shark as a unique special attraction without realizing he puts the lives of hundreds of guests and personnel in danger. When Junior White dies in front of many spectators, mommy goes on a relentless killing and destruction spree. The body count is intolerably low for a shark movie, but that's probably because all the action is concentrated in the last twenty minutes of the film. Throughout more than an hour, we're only exposed to uninteresting relationship issues, dull family conversations and a whole lot of random waterskiing footage. Most of the supportive characters are embarrassing stereotypes (an Australian outback hunter?) and the effects are hysterical even by early 80's standards. Especially the shark's ultimate attack is legendary, as he approaches the underwater control room in slow motion while the people inside just pull stupid faces.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sea World with a difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris.
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    35 feet of white teeth-gnashing terror finds itself on the wrong side of marine gates established to keep the sea from the lagoon of a Sea World resort in Florida. This third instalment in the "Jaws" family is entertaining, if somewhat tripe in its handling of the subject matter. Despite being an absurd looking shark imitation, the sight of the great dorsal fin breaking water beside oblivious skiers, together with the signature pulsating rhythm of the theme music, still manages to send shivers down the spine. The young Brody kids (Dennis Quaid and John Putch) from the first two episodes have returned, now adults enjoying some catch-up at the recently revamped Sea World Resort, where the older brother (Quaid) works alongside his love interest (Armstrong). However their merry reunion is short-lived when a young Great White shark is discovered in the waterpark's lagoon. After an attempt to catch and conserve the shark in captivity fails, they soon discover that mother is also in the park, and not at all pleased at the exploitation of junior. Despite some amateurish-looking performances in the minor roles, and the occasional inane dialogue, this remains a mostly suspenseful and exciting third entry in the quartet, still capable of invoking a primal fear of the water. And in case you were wondering, there's a particularly graphic attack scene and aftermath (check out the inventive make-up effects employed) that should impress.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please Tap on This Glass. Repeatedly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oy vey. I actually defended Jaws 2. Did that come back to bite me on the ass for the horror Jaws 3D was? And just to clear up my last statement: I meant horror as in HORRIBLE MOVIE and not a suspenseful scarefest. At any rate, Jaws 3D is so bad, so full of its gimmick of "3D"  which was NO WHERE NEAR new in 1983, by the way  that they actually turned the one-hit-wonder (the original, 1975's Jaws) into a jokefest. Sad. The one positive thing I can say about it, is that they really paved the way for Piranha 3DTWENTY-SEVEN YEARS LATER in 2010as there's a lot here that they held back on  it was Rated PG for some strange reason  that Piranha 3D took to the next level, or twenty. Seaworld's under attack by not one, but TWO sharks this time. Way to step it up from the previous "wimpy" films in the franchise that only involved one shark each. Somehow, without any investigation, its deemed the two sharks are parent and child. But, that's neither here, nor there. It's all about the fake 3D carnage. Really, I don't want to waste too much more time on this mess. I can even safely say, the Director and Writer feels the same way: they made a mess of poo and continuously wrote themselves into corners. There is no redeemable reasons to see this movie. Nothing that stands out, such as the "Okay, it's bad, but you gotta see this" scene. Of course, that makes me conclude with: You think this is bad? Wait until the next installment  I mean, who the *BLEEP* believed so deeply in this series, by this point, that they green lit the abomination that was to follow?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3-D This Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set several years after the events of Part II, Chief Brody's sons Mike & Sean(Roy Scheider did not return) are now young adults at Sea World in Florida, where yet another killer great white shark emerges, trying to track down its baby, who is being kept there and studied. Scientists and hunters must team up to defeat this menace before it kills the incoming tourists... Now in(shoddy) 3-D, this film is just inept, with a ridiculous, uninspired plot, poor science regarding sharks, and no story involvement whatsoever. Utterly devoid of a point, just a blatant cash-in on the title and resurgent popularity of 3-D(Third Jaws film in 3-D, clever no?) A bust.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Mockery To The 'Jaws' Name
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movieman
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3 has to be the worst movie I've ever seen in my whole life. If I could rate it 0 stars then I would. I didn't believe one bit that there was a shark in the waters, even though I did i Jaws 1 and 2. Firstly, the special effects were so out of date. In the dolphin scene, were they first saw the shark, when you see the Great White for the first time, I found that they just stole the footage from an old National Geographic Documentary. Secondly, this movie was full of sexual references. For example, Sean Brody says to his older brother Michael Brody, "I was so close to doing it in the water last night." after doing something inappropriate at the beach the previous night. Finally, the amount of shark facts they got wrong was just tremendous. I completely lost count. Overall, if you want to watch all of the 'Jaws' movies, I advise you skip this to 'Jaws: The Revenge' for nothing important happens in this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great idea, not done right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Dalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3-D had so much potential and it could have been the best in the series if they had done it right. The story is pure gold but unfortunately the scenes didn't go that far or break any rules. Not to mention that the 3D was awful. Another problem with this movie is that the dialogue was bad and the acting was horrible for the most part. If you want to see this movie, keep your expectations very low because you will likely be disappointed. Jaws 3-D as a whole was just mediocre as a whole but it does have some redeeming features. The things that are good about this movie are that the shark attack scenes were pretty cool and scarier than the first two and that the story is wildly original compared to the first two.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really isn't all that bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alienator Donut
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D was a satisfactory sequel with only very few flaws. The 3D visual effects were quite laughable. The plot was promising enough, it is set at Sea World, where a group of people set up an aquarium, It IS different to the other Jaws films, because Chief Brody does not make an appearance, (Even though he is often mentioned, and his sons are main characters in this film.) My personal favourite scene was the scene involving the very slow moving shark swimming to the screen with crashing into the glass window, it is later blown up! With laughable CGI special effects, and a soundtrack with a melody sounding like the Christmas song: "Joy to the world!" Jaws 3D is an entertaining enough second sequel! However, it looks like Citizen Kane, compared to its so bad it's hilarious follow up: "Jaws: The Revenge!" 6/10 Written By Alienator Donut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What, Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    suckmeoffflemwad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now Jaws 2 was a totally unnecessary sequel as I have said, however this film, Jaws 3-D is even more foul and pestilent, for starters, it lacks, and I mean it lacks, the signature shark theme from all the other films, this is what made Jaws so powerful and startling, that iconic theme. They have removed the power of the monster by replacing its theme with some bullshit merry melody, and here we barely even get to see the shark at all, I mean not like in the first, I mean in a bad way, and it kills very few people, it poses barely any threat at all, and for Christ's sake, its baby dies, and it wants revenge, sharks will eat their babies if they don't mature and scamper off quick enough, I mean seriously those idiots got even more dumb. Sharks don't have bonds, sharks are cold and emotionless, they don't take mates, and they don't care for their children a whole awful lot, they are just brainless instinctual fish, that must keep moving or they will die, this is why the geniuses in the movie put the baby in a cramped little tank, and shocked it shitless with a whole crowd of gawking people. Now this movie is very pointless, and very bad, and the way they kill the shark is pathetic, it can't swallow a guy whole for some reason when it can all those other times, and somehow he doesn't let go of his grenade, and they are able to pull the pin, I mean it just sounds utterly ridiculous. This film is horrifying and stupid in every single way, and I want to never defile my eyes by viewing it again, oh wait I just did, and saw that they used the shark theme, but still.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D The best thing about seeing a Great White Shark in 3D is that you'll look so stupid wearing those 3D glasses that it'll be too busy laughing at you to attack. However, no comical-looking headgear could keep the aquatic killer in this horror movie from ravaging you. A juvenile shark infiltrates the gates separating SeaWorld from the sea. Inside the underwater attraction, the finned-intruder begins preying on the animals and their trainers. When employees (Dennis Quaid, Bess Armstrong) go to the park manager (Louis Gossett, Jr.) with this news, he decides to profit off it. But when the mother comes looking for her pup, visitors trapped in the park's submerged tunnel system become its victims. The second sequel to Jaws, Jaws 3D is a lackluster contribution to the seafaring series that jumps the shark with this installment. Besides, SeaWorld doesn't need any outside help in killing their captive animal population. (Red Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just okay, no matter how many dimensions you see it in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even aside from the timely numerical designation of this sequel, the Jaws franchise seems like a natural for the realm of 3-D. The requisite underwater terrain alone is a perfect medium for textured dimensional rendering, and the idea of a terrifying, relentless killing machine swimming off-screen into audiences' laps is inherently awesome in and of itself. Sadly, this uneven offering never takes full advantage of its technology or its subject matter, and while it's nowhere near as bad as the truly abysmal Jaws: The Revenge (few things are), it's also nowhere near as good as the flawless original or the excellent and unfairly dismissed follow-up. Even without its potentially interesting visual ploy, Jaws 3-D has all of the ingredients to be a great sequel on paper: a stellar cast, a fresh concept, and, of course, a toothy behemoth that had already generated some of the scariest moments in screen history. These assets are ultimately squandered however. The seasoned ensemble is given very little to do, so the character studies at the heart of Jaws and Jaws 2 are bypassed entirely. The Sea World setting is woefully underused, and instead of giving our beast a novel killing ground, the park mostly functions as merely another mass of water for the action to unfold in. Worse, the shark itself isn't ever used in a suspenseful fashion, and the handful of deaths attributed to the monster are blatantly telegraphed and largely ineffective. Like many 3-D films that are stripped of their visual device for the home market, this one contains multiple scenes that may have been fun to behold on theater screens, but become utterly silly here. Floating fish heads and severed limbs bobbing with the tide might have provided cheap thrills for the opening weekend audience, but in a flat DVD representation, they simply function as camera shots that linger for far too long. The shark effects range from serviceable to downright awful, and since footage of actual sharks is utilized rather extensively, the titular titan more clearly resembles a synthetic puppet when we're seeing it at work. A couple of scenes of the creature slamming into gates and boats seem to have been created by using a plastic mock-up instead the sophisticated robotic construct that populated the first two Jaws outings, and since little effort is made to sell these moments, you can actually see the rubber shark bounce off its targets upon collision. When these flashes are integrated alongside the graceful maneuvering of real great whites, there is little symmetry between the two versions and the complete suspension of disbelief required to make a scenario like this pay off is rarely achieved. Apart from its obviousness as a prop, the shark in Jaws 3-D just isn't all that frightening because the meager body count doesn't allow it to prove itself as an insatiable murder machine. A couple of random victims are thrown in early on, but when the shark finally makes its way into the water park, where a virtual sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord of flailing legs awaits, every single person the shark pursues easily escapes its titular Jaws. Only one of the major characters gets bit during this extended sequence, and she gets away with little more than a few scratches on her leg. There are a few solid jump scares peppered throughout the film, but while the tension seems to be mounting every step of the way, the movie invariably pulls back before anything all that spectacular or horrifying occurs. Even the promising climax goes flaccid when the absolute dumbest false 3-D moment occurs, and any menace our finned antagonist has generated along the way is readily diffused by a protracted shot of her slowly floating toward the camera and breaking through a plainly animated sheet of glass. The way the shark is dispatched is particularly hard to swallow (this is actually a pretty good pun if you've seen the film), and yet another silly extended "in your face" moment caps off a tremendously underwhelming resolution. Savvy collectors will easily be able to track down readily available bootleg DVDs that retain the original 3-D presentation, but even the cleanest transfer available on the secondary market is still high-generation and extremely murky, a state which naturally strips away the potency of the visual effects. Watching my copy gave me a headache, and I had to stop about every thirty minutes or so to take off the glasses and give my eyes a rest. I eventually made it through, but when I did, all I discovered was that Jaws 3-D isn't much more impressive in its original form. The obsessive collector in me knows that if this offering ever gets a proper Blu-Ray release I will have to add it to my collection and give the film at least one more go, but the realist in me is guessing that even digitized 3-D effects won't make up for the numerous other weaknesses on hand here. There are a few effective moments here that will hold the attention of admirers of the series, but the film as a whole is a missed opportunity that can only be rightfully recommended to the most forgiving killer fish fans. An even better recommendation for those who have digested every frame of the unmatchable original and simply must have more is to skip this one entirely and give Jaws 2 another look instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Third Dimension is Terrible!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It used to be so simple to point out the bad shark movies. There was "Jaws 3" and "Jaws 4: The Revenge", and that was it pretty much! But then, as per the late nineties approximately, we literally received an overflow of inferior and quite often downright retarded killer shark flicks. And now all of a sudden, the aforementioned Jaws sequels actually don't look too terrible anymore. It started in the late 90's with the still traditional but totally inept "Deep Blue Sea" and "Shark Attack", but then since the new Millennium things really got out of control with murderous sharks popping up in the most illogical of places (like the rivers in Venice, in Tsunami infested areas, swamps, etc) and  worse even  all kinds of ridiculous hybrids and genetically altered species, like dinosaur sharks, octopus-sharks and two-headed sharks. Sigh  whatever happened to good-old fashioned massively over-sized Great Whites, like in our classic early 80's stinker "Jaws 3-D"? Now, please don't misunderstand me, the third installment in the Jaws franchise is still a very lousy film, but at least it's not bad in a frustrating or annoying way. The underdeveloped screenplay, the laughable attempt to bring depth to the main characters, the hilarious 3D effects and all the totally irrelevant padding footage  It almost feels cheesy and charming in a positive sort of way now. Interesting detail here is that Universal Studios, the mastodon production company behind the Jaws franchise, sued the creators of an obscure Italian imitation for being too reminiscent, but then they were hypocrite enough to steal ideas from the movie they accused of stealing from them! That's Hollywood for you, I guess. The script attempts, poorly I may add, to build a bridge between the previous two movies by depicting the Brody boys (the sons of Roy Scheider) as pivot characters in the grand opening of a brand new Florida Ocean theme park. Mike, the oldest one, works there as the head engineer and his younger brother Sean  supposedly still suffering from his childhood trauma even though he blindly follows the first cute girl he meets straight in the water for a nightly swimming session  comes to visit him for the ceremony. Due to malfunctioning underwater fences and unreliable technical staff, the park quickly receives unforeseen visitors in the shape of a great white shark and its offspring. Also in good old Jaws tradition, the park's senior executive initially hopes to exploit the baby shark as a unique special attraction without realizing he puts the lives of hundreds of guests and personnel in danger. When Junior White dies in front of many spectators, mommy goes on a relentless killing and destruction spree. The body count is intolerably low for a shark movie, but that's probably because all the action is concentrated in the last twenty minutes of the film. Throughout more than an hour, we're only exposed to uninteresting relationship issues, dull family conversations and a whole lot of random waterskiing footage. Most of the supportive characters are embarrassing stereotypes (an Australian outback hunter?) and the effects are hysterical even by early 80's standards. Especially the shark's ultimate attack is legendary, as he approaches the underwater control room in slow motion while the people inside just pull stupid faces.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sea World with a difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris.
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    35 feet of white teeth-gnashing terror finds itself on the wrong side of marine gates established to keep the sea from the lagoon of a Sea World resort in Florida. This third instalment in the "Jaws" family is entertaining, if somewhat tripe in its handling of the subject matter. Despite being an absurd looking shark imitation, the sight of the great dorsal fin breaking water beside oblivious skiers, together with the signature pulsating rhythm of the theme music, still manages to send shivers down the spine. The young Brody kids (Dennis Quaid and John Putch) from the first two episodes have returned, now adults enjoying some catch-up at the recently revamped Sea World Resort, where the older brother (Quaid) works alongside his love interest (Armstrong). However their merry reunion is short-lived when a young Great White shark is discovered in the waterpark's lagoon. After an attempt to catch and conserve the shark in captivity fails, they soon discover that mother is also in the park, and not at all pleased at the exploitation of junior. Despite some amateurish-looking performances in the minor roles, and the occasional inane dialogue, this remains a mostly suspenseful and exciting third entry in the quartet, still capable of invoking a primal fear of the water. And in case you were wondering, there's a particularly graphic attack scene and aftermath (check out the inventive make-up effects employed) that should impress.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please Tap on This Glass. Repeatedly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oy vey. I actually defended Jaws 2. Did that come back to bite me on the ass for the horror Jaws 3D was? And just to clear up my last statement: I meant horror as in HORRIBLE MOVIE and not a suspenseful scarefest. At any rate, Jaws 3D is so bad, so full of its gimmick of "3D"  which was NO WHERE NEAR new in 1983, by the way  that they actually turned the one-hit-wonder (the original, 1975's Jaws) into a jokefest. Sad. The one positive thing I can say about it, is that they really paved the way for Piranha 3DTWENTY-SEVEN YEARS LATER in 2010as there's a lot here that they held back on  it was Rated PG for some strange reason  that Piranha 3D took to the next level, or twenty. Seaworld's under attack by not one, but TWO sharks this time. Way to step it up from the previous "wimpy" films in the franchise that only involved one shark each. Somehow, without any investigation, its deemed the two sharks are parent and child. But, that's neither here, nor there. It's all about the fake 3D carnage. Really, I don't want to waste too much more time on this mess. I can even safely say, the Director and Writer feels the same way: they made a mess of poo and continuously wrote themselves into corners. There is no redeemable reasons to see this movie. Nothing that stands out, such as the "Okay, it's bad, but you gotta see this" scene. Of course, that makes me conclude with: You think this is bad? Wait until the next installment  I mean, who the *BLEEP* believed so deeply in this series, by this point, that they green lit the abomination that was to follow?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3-D This Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set several years after the events of Part II, Chief Brody's sons Mike & Sean(Roy Scheider did not return) are now young adults at Sea World in Florida, where yet another killer great white shark emerges, trying to track down its baby, who is being kept there and studied. Scientists and hunters must team up to defeat this menace before it kills the incoming tourists... Now in(shoddy) 3-D, this film is just inept, with a ridiculous, uninspired plot, poor science regarding sharks, and no story involvement whatsoever. Utterly devoid of a point, just a blatant cash-in on the title and resurgent popularity of 3-D(Third Jaws film in 3-D, clever no?) A bust.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Mockery To The 'Jaws' Name
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movieman
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3 has to be the worst movie I've ever seen in my whole life. If I could rate it 0 stars then I would. I didn't believe one bit that there was a shark in the waters, even though I did i Jaws 1 and 2. Firstly, the special effects were so out of date. In the dolphin scene, were they first saw the shark, when you see the Great White for the first time, I found that they just stole the footage from an old National Geographic Documentary. Secondly, this movie was full of sexual references. For example, Sean Brody says to his older brother Michael Brody, "I was so close to doing it in the water last night." after doing something inappropriate at the beach the previous night. Finally, the amount of shark facts they got wrong was just tremendous. I completely lost count. Overall, if you want to watch all of the 'Jaws' movies, I advise you skip this to 'Jaws: The Revenge' for nothing important happens in this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great idea, not done right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Dalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3-D had so much potential and it could have been the best in the series if they had done it right. The story is pure gold but unfortunately the scenes didn't go that far or break any rules. Not to mention that the 3D was awful. Another problem with this movie is that the dialogue was bad and the acting was horrible for the most part. If you want to see this movie, keep your expectations very low because you will likely be disappointed. Jaws 3-D as a whole was just mediocre as a whole but it does have some redeeming features. The things that are good about this movie are that the shark attack scenes were pretty cool and scarier than the first two and that the story is wildly original compared to the first two.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really isn't all that bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alienator Donut
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D was a satisfactory sequel with only very few flaws. The 3D visual effects were quite laughable. The plot was promising enough, it is set at Sea World, where a group of people set up an aquarium, It IS different to the other Jaws films, because Chief Brody does not make an appearance, (Even though he is often mentioned, and his sons are main characters in this film.) My personal favourite scene was the scene involving the very slow moving shark swimming to the screen with crashing into the glass window, it is later blown up! With laughable CGI special effects, and a soundtrack with a melody sounding like the Christmas song: "Joy to the world!" Jaws 3D is an entertaining enough second sequel! However, it looks like Citizen Kane, compared to its so bad it's hilarious follow up: "Jaws: The Revenge!" 6/10 Written By Alienator Donut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What, Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    suckmeoffflemwad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now Jaws 2 was a totally unnecessary sequel as I have said, however this film, Jaws 3-D is even more foul and pestilent, for starters, it lacks, and I mean it lacks, the signature shark theme from all the other films, this is what made Jaws so powerful and startling, that iconic theme. They have removed the power of the monster by replacing its theme with some bullshit merry melody, and here we barely even get to see the shark at all, I mean not like in the first, I mean in a bad way, and it kills very few people, it poses barely any threat at all, and for Christ's sake, its baby dies, and it wants revenge, sharks will eat their babies if they don't mature and scamper off quick enough, I mean seriously those idiots got even more dumb. Sharks don't have bonds, sharks are cold and emotionless, they don't take mates, and they don't care for their children a whole awful lot, they are just brainless instinctual fish, that must keep moving or they will die, this is why the geniuses in the movie put the baby in a cramped little tank, and shocked it shitless with a whole crowd of gawking people. Now this movie is very pointless, and very bad, and the way they kill the shark is pathetic, it can't swallow a guy whole for some reason when it can all those other times, and somehow he doesn't let go of his grenade, and they are able to pull the pin, I mean it just sounds utterly ridiculous. This film is horrifying and stupid in every single way, and I want to never defile my eyes by viewing it again, oh wait I just did, and saw that they used the shark theme, but still.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D The best thing about seeing a Great White Shark in 3D is that you'll look so stupid wearing those 3D glasses that it'll be too busy laughing at you to attack. However, no comical-looking headgear could keep the aquatic killer in this horror movie from ravaging you. A juvenile shark infiltrates the gates separating SeaWorld from the sea. Inside the underwater attraction, the finned-intruder begins preying on the animals and their trainers. When employees (Dennis Quaid, Bess Armstrong) go to the park manager (Louis Gossett, Jr.) with this news, he decides to profit off it. But when the mother comes looking for her pup, visitors trapped in the park's submerged tunnel system become its victims. The second sequel to Jaws, Jaws 3D is a lackluster contribution to the seafaring series that jumps the shark with this installment. Besides, SeaWorld doesn't need any outside help in killing their captive animal population. (Red Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just okay, no matter how many dimensions you see it in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even aside from the timely numerical designation of this sequel, the Jaws franchise seems like a natural for the realm of 3-D. The requisite underwater terrain alone is a perfect medium for textured dimensional rendering, and the idea of a terrifying, relentless killing machine swimming off-screen into audiences' laps is inherently awesome in and of itself. Sadly, this uneven offering never takes full advantage of its technology or its subject matter, and while it's nowhere near as bad as the truly abysmal Jaws: The Revenge (few things are), it's also nowhere near as good as the flawless original or the excellent and unfairly dismissed follow-up. Even without its potentially interesting visual ploy, Jaws 3-D has all of the ingredients to be a great sequel on paper: a stellar cast, a fresh concept, and, of course, a toothy behemoth that had already generated some of the scariest moments in screen history. These assets are ultimately squandered however. The seasoned ensemble is given very little to do, so the character studies at the heart of Jaws and Jaws 2 are bypassed entirely. The Sea World setting is woefully underused, and instead of giving our beast a novel killing ground, the park mostly functions as merely another mass of water for the action to unfold in. Worse, the shark itself isn't ever used in a suspenseful fashion, and the handful of deaths attributed to the monster are blatantly telegraphed and largely ineffective. Like many 3-D films that are stripped of their visual device for the home market, this one contains multiple scenes that may have been fun to behold on theater screens, but become utterly silly here. Floating fish heads and severed limbs bobbing with the tide might have provided cheap thrills for the opening weekend audience, but in a flat DVD representation, they simply function as camera shots that linger for far too long. The shark effects range from serviceable to downright awful, and since footage of actual sharks is utilized rather extensively, the titular titan more clearly resembles a synthetic puppet when we're seeing it at work. A couple of scenes of the creature slamming into gates and boats seem to have been created by using a plastic mock-up instead the sophisticated robotic construct that populated the first two Jaws outings, and since little effort is made to sell these moments, you can actually see the rubber shark bounce off its targets upon collision. When these flashes are integrated alongside the graceful maneuvering of real great whites, there is little symmetry between the two versions and the complete suspension of disbelief required to make a scenario like this pay off is rarely achieved. Apart from its obviousness as a prop, the shark in Jaws 3-D just isn't all that frightening because the meager body count doesn't allow it to prove itself as an insatiable murder machine. A couple of random victims are thrown in early on, but when the shark finally makes its way into the water park, where a virtual sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord of flailing legs awaits, every single person the shark pursues easily escapes its titular Jaws. Only one of the major characters gets bit during this extended sequence, and she gets away with little more than a few scratches on her leg. There are a few solid jump scares peppered throughout the film, but while the tension seems to be mounting every step of the way, the movie invariably pulls back before anything all that spectacular or horrifying occurs. Even the promising climax goes flaccid when the absolute dumbest false 3-D moment occurs, and any menace our finned antagonist has generated along the way is readily diffused by a protracted shot of her slowly floating toward the camera and breaking through a plainly animated sheet of glass. The way the shark is dispatched is particularly hard to swallow (this is actually a pretty good pun if you've seen the film), and yet another silly extended "in your face" moment caps off a tremendously underwhelming resolution. Savvy collectors will easily be able to track down readily available bootleg DVDs that retain the original 3-D presentation, but even the cleanest transfer available on the secondary market is still high-generation and extremely murky, a state which naturally strips away the potency of the visual effects. Watching my copy gave me a headache, and I had to stop about every thirty minutes or so to take off the glasses and give my eyes a rest. I eventually made it through, but when I did, all I discovered was that Jaws 3-D isn't much more impressive in its original form. The obsessive collector in me knows that if this offering ever gets a proper Blu-Ray release I will have to add it to my collection and give the film at least one more go, but the realist in me is guessing that even digitized 3-D effects won't make up for the numerous other weaknesses on hand here. There are a few effective moments here that will hold the attention of admirers of the series, but the film as a whole is a missed opportunity that can only be rightfully recommended to the most forgiving killer fish fans. An even better recommendation for those who have digested every frame of the unmatchable original and simply must have more is to skip this one entirely and give Jaws 2 another look instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Third Dimension is Terrible!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It used to be so simple to point out the bad shark movies. There was "Jaws 3" and "Jaws 4: The Revenge", and that was it pretty much! But then, as per the late nineties approximately, we literally received an overflow of inferior and quite often downright retarded killer shark flicks. And now all of a sudden, the aforementioned Jaws sequels actually don't look too terrible anymore. It started in the late 90's with the still traditional but totally inept "Deep Blue Sea" and "Shark Attack", but then since the new Millennium things really got out of control with murderous sharks popping up in the most illogical of places (like the rivers in Venice, in Tsunami infested areas, swamps, etc) and  worse even  all kinds of ridiculous hybrids and genetically altered species, like dinosaur sharks, octopus-sharks and two-headed sharks. Sigh  whatever happened to good-old fashioned massively over-sized Great Whites, like in our classic early 80's stinker "Jaws 3-D"? Now, please don't misunderstand me, the third installment in the Jaws franchise is still a very lousy film, but at least it's not bad in a frustrating or annoying way. The underdeveloped screenplay, the laughable attempt to bring depth to the main characters, the hilarious 3D effects and all the totally irrelevant padding footage  It almost feels cheesy and charming in a positive sort of way now. Interesting detail here is that Universal Studios, the mastodon production company behind the Jaws franchise, sued the creators of an obscure Italian imitation for being too reminiscent, but then they were hypocrite enough to steal ideas from the movie they accused of stealing from them! That's Hollywood for you, I guess. The script attempts, poorly I may add, to build a bridge between the previous two movies by depicting the Brody boys (the sons of Roy Scheider) as pivot characters in the grand opening of a brand new Florida Ocean theme park. Mike, the oldest one, works there as the head engineer and his younger brother Sean  supposedly still suffering from his childhood trauma even though he blindly follows the first cute girl he meets straight in the water for a nightly swimming session  comes to visit him for the ceremony. Due to malfunctioning underwater fences and unreliable technical staff, the park quickly receives unforeseen visitors in the shape of a great white shark and its offspring. Also in good old Jaws tradition, the park's senior executive initially hopes to exploit the baby shark as a unique special attraction without realizing he puts the lives of hundreds of guests and personnel in danger. When Junior White dies in front of many spectators, mommy goes on a relentless killing and destruction spree. The body count is intolerably low for a shark movie, but that's probably because all the action is concentrated in the last twenty minutes of the film. Throughout more than an hour, we're only exposed to uninteresting relationship issues, dull family conversations and a whole lot of random waterskiing footage. Most of the supportive characters are embarrassing stereotypes (an Australian outback hunter?) and the effects are hysterical even by early 80's standards. Especially the shark's ultimate attack is legendary, as he approaches the underwater control room in slow motion while the people inside just pull stupid faces.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sea World with a difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris.
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    35 feet of white teeth-gnashing terror finds itself on the wrong side of marine gates established to keep the sea from the lagoon of a Sea World resort in Florida. This third instalment in the "Jaws" family is entertaining, if somewhat tripe in its handling of the subject matter. Despite being an absurd looking shark imitation, the sight of the great dorsal fin breaking water beside oblivious skiers, together with the signature pulsating rhythm of the theme music, still manages to send shivers down the spine. The young Brody kids (Dennis Quaid and John Putch) from the first two episodes have returned, now adults enjoying some catch-up at the recently revamped Sea World Resort, where the older brother (Quaid) works alongside his love interest (Armstrong). However their merry reunion is short-lived when a young Great White shark is discovered in the waterpark's lagoon. After an attempt to catch and conserve the shark in captivity fails, they soon discover that mother is also in the park, and not at all pleased at the exploitation of junior. Despite some amateurish-looking performances in the minor roles, and the occasional inane dialogue, this remains a mostly suspenseful and exciting third entry in the quartet, still capable of invoking a primal fear of the water. And in case you were wondering, there's a particularly graphic attack scene and aftermath (check out the inventive make-up effects employed) that should impress.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please Tap on This Glass. Repeatedly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oy vey. I actually defended Jaws 2. Did that come back to bite me on the ass for the horror Jaws 3D was? And just to clear up my last statement: I meant horror as in HORRIBLE MOVIE and not a suspenseful scarefest. At any rate, Jaws 3D is so bad, so full of its gimmick of "3D"  which was NO WHERE NEAR new in 1983, by the way  that they actually turned the one-hit-wonder (the original, 1975's Jaws) into a jokefest. Sad. The one positive thing I can say about it, is that they really paved the way for Piranha 3DTWENTY-SEVEN YEARS LATER in 2010as there's a lot here that they held back on  it was Rated PG for some strange reason  that Piranha 3D took to the next level, or twenty. Seaworld's under attack by not one, but TWO sharks this time. Way to step it up from the previous "wimpy" films in the franchise that only involved one shark each. Somehow, without any investigation, its deemed the two sharks are parent and child. But, that's neither here, nor there. It's all about the fake 3D carnage. Really, I don't want to waste too much more time on this mess. I can even safely say, the Director and Writer feels the same way: they made a mess of poo and continuously wrote themselves into corners. There is no redeemable reasons to see this movie. Nothing that stands out, such as the "Okay, it's bad, but you gotta see this" scene. Of course, that makes me conclude with: You think this is bad? Wait until the next installment  I mean, who the *BLEEP* believed so deeply in this series, by this point, that they green lit the abomination that was to follow?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3-D This Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set several years after the events of Part II, Chief Brody's sons Mike & Sean(Roy Scheider did not return) are now young adults at Sea World in Florida, where yet another killer great white shark emerges, trying to track down its baby, who is being kept there and studied. Scientists and hunters must team up to defeat this menace before it kills the incoming tourists... Now in(shoddy) 3-D, this film is just inept, with a ridiculous, uninspired plot, poor science regarding sharks, and no story involvement whatsoever. Utterly devoid of a point, just a blatant cash-in on the title and resurgent popularity of 3-D(Third Jaws film in 3-D, clever no?) A bust.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Mockery To The 'Jaws' Name
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movieman
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3 has to be the worst movie I've ever seen in my whole life. If I could rate it 0 stars then I would. I didn't believe one bit that there was a shark in the waters, even though I did i Jaws 1 and 2. Firstly, the special effects were so out of date. In the dolphin scene, were they first saw the shark, when you see the Great White for the first time, I found that they just stole the footage from an old National Geographic Documentary. Secondly, this movie was full of sexual references. For example, Sean Brody says to his older brother Michael Brody, "I was so close to doing it in the water last night." after doing something inappropriate at the beach the previous night. Finally, the amount of shark facts they got wrong was just tremendous. I completely lost count. Overall, if you want to watch all of the 'Jaws' movies, I advise you skip this to 'Jaws: The Revenge' for nothing important happens in this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great idea, not done right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Dalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3-D had so much potential and it could have been the best in the series if they had done it right. The story is pure gold but unfortunately the scenes didn't go that far or break any rules. Not to mention that the 3D was awful. Another problem with this movie is that the dialogue was bad and the acting was horrible for the most part. If you want to see this movie, keep your expectations very low because you will likely be disappointed. Jaws 3-D as a whole was just mediocre as a whole but it does have some redeeming features. The things that are good about this movie are that the shark attack scenes were pretty cool and scarier than the first two and that the story is wildly original compared to the first two.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really isn't all that bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alienator Donut
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D was a satisfactory sequel with only very few flaws. The 3D visual effects were quite laughable. The plot was promising enough, it is set at Sea World, where a group of people set up an aquarium, It IS different to the other Jaws films, because Chief Brody does not make an appearance, (Even though he is often mentioned, and his sons are main characters in this film.) My personal favourite scene was the scene involving the very slow moving shark swimming to the screen with crashing into the glass window, it is later blown up! With laughable CGI special effects, and a soundtrack with a melody sounding like the Christmas song: "Joy to the world!" Jaws 3D is an entertaining enough second sequel! However, it looks like Citizen Kane, compared to its so bad it's hilarious follow up: "Jaws: The Revenge!" 6/10 Written By Alienator Donut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What, Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    suckmeoffflemwad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now Jaws 2 was a totally unnecessary sequel as I have said, however this film, Jaws 3-D is even more foul and pestilent, for starters, it lacks, and I mean it lacks, the signature shark theme from all the other films, this is what made Jaws so powerful and startling, that iconic theme. They have removed the power of the monster by replacing its theme with some bullshit merry melody, and here we barely even get to see the shark at all, I mean not like in the first, I mean in a bad way, and it kills very few people, it poses barely any threat at all, and for Christ's sake, its baby dies, and it wants revenge, sharks will eat their babies if they don't mature and scamper off quick enough, I mean seriously those idiots got even more dumb. Sharks don't have bonds, sharks are cold and emotionless, they don't take mates, and they don't care for their children a whole awful lot, they are just brainless instinctual fish, that must keep moving or they will die, this is why the geniuses in the movie put the baby in a cramped little tank, and shocked it shitless with a whole crowd of gawking people. Now this movie is very pointless, and very bad, and the way they kill the shark is pathetic, it can't swallow a guy whole for some reason when it can all those other times, and somehow he doesn't let go of his grenade, and they are able to pull the pin, I mean it just sounds utterly ridiculous. This film is horrifying and stupid in every single way, and I want to never defile my eyes by viewing it again, oh wait I just did, and saw that they used the shark theme, but still.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D The best thing about seeing a Great White Shark in 3D is that you'll look so stupid wearing those 3D glasses that it'll be too busy laughing at you to attack. However, no comical-looking headgear could keep the aquatic killer in this horror movie from ravaging you. A juvenile shark infiltrates the gates separating SeaWorld from the sea. Inside the underwater attraction, the finned-intruder begins preying on the animals and their trainers. When employees (Dennis Quaid, Bess Armstrong) go to the park manager (Louis Gossett, Jr.) with this news, he decides to profit off it. But when the mother comes looking for her pup, visitors trapped in the park's submerged tunnel system become its victims. The second sequel to Jaws, Jaws 3D is a lackluster contribution to the seafaring series that jumps the shark with this installment. Besides, SeaWorld doesn't need any outside help in killing their captive animal population. (Red Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just okay, no matter how many dimensions you see it in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even aside from the timely numerical designation of this sequel, the Jaws franchise seems like a natural for the realm of 3-D. The requisite underwater terrain alone is a perfect medium for textured dimensional rendering, and the idea of a terrifying, relentless killing machine swimming off-screen into audiences' laps is inherently awesome in and of itself. Sadly, this uneven offering never takes full advantage of its technology or its subject matter, and while it's nowhere near as bad as the truly abysmal Jaws: The Revenge (few things are), it's also nowhere near as good as the flawless original or the excellent and unfairly dismissed follow-up. Even without its potentially interesting visual ploy, Jaws 3-D has all of the ingredients to be a great sequel on paper: a stellar cast, a fresh concept, and, of course, a toothy behemoth that had already generated some of the scariest moments in screen history. These assets are ultimately squandered however. The seasoned ensemble is given very little to do, so the character studies at the heart of Jaws and Jaws 2 are bypassed entirely. The Sea World setting is woefully underused, and instead of giving our beast a novel killing ground, the park mostly functions as merely another mass of water for the action to unfold in. Worse, the shark itself isn't ever used in a suspenseful fashion, and the handful of deaths attributed to the monster are blatantly telegraphed and largely ineffective. Like many 3-D films that are stripped of their visual device for the home market, this one contains multiple scenes that may have been fun to behold on theater screens, but become utterly silly here. Floating fish heads and severed limbs bobbing with the tide might have provided cheap thrills for the opening weekend audience, but in a flat DVD representation, they simply function as camera shots that linger for far too long. The shark effects range from serviceable to downright awful, and since footage of actual sharks is utilized rather extensively, the titular titan more clearly resembles a synthetic puppet when we're seeing it at work. A couple of scenes of the creature slamming into gates and boats seem to have been created by using a plastic mock-up instead the sophisticated robotic construct that populated the first two Jaws outings, and since little effort is made to sell these moments, you can actually see the rubber shark bounce off its targets upon collision. When these flashes are integrated alongside the graceful maneuvering of real great whites, there is little symmetry between the two versions and the complete suspension of disbelief required to make a scenario like this pay off is rarely achieved. Apart from its obviousness as a prop, the shark in Jaws 3-D just isn't all that frightening because the meager body count doesn't allow it to prove itself as an insatiable murder machine. A couple of random victims are thrown in early on, but when the shark finally makes its way into the water park, where a virtual sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord of flailing legs awaits, every single person the shark pursues easily escapes its titular Jaws. Only one of the major characters gets bit during this extended sequence, and she gets away with little more than a few scratches on her leg. There are a few solid jump scares peppered throughout the film, but while the tension seems to be mounting every step of the way, the movie invariably pulls back before anything all that spectacular or horrifying occurs. Even the promising climax goes flaccid when the absolute dumbest false 3-D moment occurs, and any menace our finned antagonist has generated along the way is readily diffused by a protracted shot of her slowly floating toward the camera and breaking through a plainly animated sheet of glass. The way the shark is dispatched is particularly hard to swallow (this is actually a pretty good pun if you've seen the film), and yet another silly extended "in your face" moment caps off a tremendously underwhelming resolution. Savvy collectors will easily be able to track down readily available bootleg DVDs that retain the original 3-D presentation, but even the cleanest transfer available on the secondary market is still high-generation and extremely murky, a state which naturally strips away the potency of the visual effects. Watching my copy gave me a headache, and I had to stop about every thirty minutes or so to take off the glasses and give my eyes a rest. I eventually made it through, but when I did, all I discovered was that Jaws 3-D isn't much more impressive in its original form. The obsessive collector in me knows that if this offering ever gets a proper Blu-Ray release I will have to add it to my collection and give the film at least one more go, but the realist in me is guessing that even digitized 3-D effects won't make up for the numerous other weaknesses on hand here. There are a few effective moments here that will hold the attention of admirers of the series, but the film as a whole is a missed opportunity that can only be rightfully recommended to the most forgiving killer fish fans. An even better recommendation for those who have digested every frame of the unmatchable original and simply must have more is to skip this one entirely and give Jaws 2 another look instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Third Dimension is Terrible!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It used to be so simple to point out the bad shark movies. There was "Jaws 3" and "Jaws 4: The Revenge", and that was it pretty much! But then, as per the late nineties approximately, we literally received an overflow of inferior and quite often downright retarded killer shark flicks. And now all of a sudden, the aforementioned Jaws sequels actually don't look too terrible anymore. It started in the late 90's with the still traditional but totally inept "Deep Blue Sea" and "Shark Attack", but then since the new Millennium things really got out of control with murderous sharks popping up in the most illogical of places (like the rivers in Venice, in Tsunami infested areas, swamps, etc) and  worse even  all kinds of ridiculous hybrids and genetically altered species, like dinosaur sharks, octopus-sharks and two-headed sharks. Sigh  whatever happened to good-old fashioned massively over-sized Great Whites, like in our classic early 80's stinker "Jaws 3-D"? Now, please don't misunderstand me, the third installment in the Jaws franchise is still a very lousy film, but at least it's not bad in a frustrating or annoying way. The underdeveloped screenplay, the laughable attempt to bring depth to the main characters, the hilarious 3D effects and all the totally irrelevant padding footage  It almost feels cheesy and charming in a positive sort of way now. Interesting detail here is that Universal Studios, the mastodon production company behind the Jaws franchise, sued the creators of an obscure Italian imitation for being too reminiscent, but then they were hypocrite enough to steal ideas from the movie they accused of stealing from them! That's Hollywood for you, I guess. The script attempts, poorly I may add, to build a bridge between the previous two movies by depicting the Brody boys (the sons of Roy Scheider) as pivot characters in the grand opening of a brand new Florida Ocean theme park. Mike, the oldest one, works there as the head engineer and his younger brother Sean  supposedly still suffering from his childhood trauma even though he blindly follows the first cute girl he meets straight in the water for a nightly swimming session  comes to visit him for the ceremony. Due to malfunctioning underwater fences and unreliable technical staff, the park quickly receives unforeseen visitors in the shape of a great white shark and its offspring. Also in good old Jaws tradition, the park's senior executive initially hopes to exploit the baby shark as a unique special attraction without realizing he puts the lives of hundreds of guests and personnel in danger. When Junior White dies in front of many spectators, mommy goes on a relentless killing and destruction spree. The body count is intolerably low for a shark movie, but that's probably because all the action is concentrated in the last twenty minutes of the film. Throughout more than an hour, we're only exposed to uninteresting relationship issues, dull family conversations and a whole lot of random waterskiing footage. Most of the supportive characters are embarrassing stereotypes (an Australian outback hunter?) and the effects are hysterical even by early 80's standards. Especially the shark's ultimate attack is legendary, as he approaches the underwater control room in slow motion while the people inside just pull stupid faces.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sea World with a difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris.
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    35 feet of white teeth-gnashing terror finds itself on the wrong side of marine gates established to keep the sea from the lagoon of a Sea World resort in Florida. This third instalment in the "Jaws" family is entertaining, if somewhat tripe in its handling of the subject matter. Despite being an absurd looking shark imitation, the sight of the great dorsal fin breaking water beside oblivious skiers, together with the signature pulsating rhythm of the theme music, still manages to send shivers down the spine. The young Brody kids (Dennis Quaid and John Putch) from the first two episodes have returned, now adults enjoying some catch-up at the recently revamped Sea World Resort, where the older brother (Quaid) works alongside his love interest (Armstrong). However their merry reunion is short-lived when a young Great White shark is discovered in the waterpark's lagoon. After an attempt to catch and conserve the shark in captivity fails, they soon discover that mother is also in the park, and not at all pleased at the exploitation of junior. Despite some amateurish-looking performances in the minor roles, and the occasional inane dialogue, this remains a mostly suspenseful and exciting third entry in the quartet, still capable of invoking a primal fear of the water. And in case you were wondering, there's a particularly graphic attack scene and aftermath (check out the inventive make-up effects employed) that should impress.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please Tap on This Glass. Repeatedly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oy vey. I actually defended Jaws 2. Did that come back to bite me on the ass for the horror Jaws 3D was? And just to clear up my last statement: I meant horror as in HORRIBLE MOVIE and not a suspenseful scarefest. At any rate, Jaws 3D is so bad, so full of its gimmick of "3D"  which was NO WHERE NEAR new in 1983, by the way  that they actually turned the one-hit-wonder (the original, 1975's Jaws) into a jokefest. Sad. The one positive thing I can say about it, is that they really paved the way for Piranha 3DTWENTY-SEVEN YEARS LATER in 2010as there's a lot here that they held back on  it was Rated PG for some strange reason  that Piranha 3D took to the next level, or twenty. Seaworld's under attack by not one, but TWO sharks this time. Way to step it up from the previous "wimpy" films in the franchise that only involved one shark each. Somehow, without any investigation, its deemed the two sharks are parent and child. But, that's neither here, nor there. It's all about the fake 3D carnage. Really, I don't want to waste too much more time on this mess. I can even safely say, the Director and Writer feels the same way: they made a mess of poo and continuously wrote themselves into corners. There is no redeemable reasons to see this movie. Nothing that stands out, such as the "Okay, it's bad, but you gotta see this" scene. Of course, that makes me conclude with: You think this is bad? Wait until the next installment  I mean, who the *BLEEP* believed so deeply in this series, by this point, that they green lit the abomination that was to follow?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3-D This Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set several years after the events of Part II, Chief Brody's sons Mike & Sean(Roy Scheider did not return) are now young adults at Sea World in Florida, where yet another killer great white shark emerges, trying to track down its baby, who is being kept there and studied. Scientists and hunters must team up to defeat this menace before it kills the incoming tourists... Now in(shoddy) 3-D, this film is just inept, with a ridiculous, uninspired plot, poor science regarding sharks, and no story involvement whatsoever. Utterly devoid of a point, just a blatant cash-in on the title and resurgent popularity of 3-D(Third Jaws film in 3-D, clever no?) A bust.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Mockery To The 'Jaws' Name
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movieman
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3 has to be the worst movie I've ever seen in my whole life. If I could rate it 0 stars then I would. I didn't believe one bit that there was a shark in the waters, even though I did i Jaws 1 and 2. Firstly, the special effects were so out of date. In the dolphin scene, were they first saw the shark, when you see the Great White for the first time, I found that they just stole the footage from an old National Geographic Documentary. Secondly, this movie was full of sexual references. For example, Sean Brody says to his older brother Michael Brody, "I was so close to doing it in the water last night." after doing something inappropriate at the beach the previous night. Finally, the amount of shark facts they got wrong was just tremendous. I completely lost count. Overall, if you want to watch all of the 'Jaws' movies, I advise you skip this to 'Jaws: The Revenge' for nothing important happens in this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great idea, not done right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Dalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3-D had so much potential and it could have been the best in the series if they had done it right. The story is pure gold but unfortunately the scenes didn't go that far or break any rules. Not to mention that the 3D was awful. Another problem with this movie is that the dialogue was bad and the acting was horrible for the most part. If you want to see this movie, keep your expectations very low because you will likely be disappointed. Jaws 3-D as a whole was just mediocre as a whole but it does have some redeeming features. The things that are good about this movie are that the shark attack scenes were pretty cool and scarier than the first two and that the story is wildly original compared to the first two.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really isn't all that bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alienator Donut
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D was a satisfactory sequel with only very few flaws. The 3D visual effects were quite laughable. The plot was promising enough, it is set at Sea World, where a group of people set up an aquarium, It IS different to the other Jaws films, because Chief Brody does not make an appearance, (Even though he is often mentioned, and his sons are main characters in this film.) My personal favourite scene was the scene involving the very slow moving shark swimming to the screen with crashing into the glass window, it is later blown up! With laughable CGI special effects, and a soundtrack with a melody sounding like the Christmas song: "Joy to the world!" Jaws 3D is an entertaining enough second sequel! However, it looks like Citizen Kane, compared to its so bad it's hilarious follow up: "Jaws: The Revenge!" 6/10 Written By Alienator Donut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What, Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    suckmeoffflemwad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now Jaws 2 was a totally unnecessary sequel as I have said, however this film, Jaws 3-D is even more foul and pestilent, for starters, it lacks, and I mean it lacks, the signature shark theme from all the other films, this is what made Jaws so powerful and startling, that iconic theme. They have removed the power of the monster by replacing its theme with some bullshit merry melody, and here we barely even get to see the shark at all, I mean not like in the first, I mean in a bad way, and it kills very few people, it poses barely any threat at all, and for Christ's sake, its baby dies, and it wants revenge, sharks will eat their babies if they don't mature and scamper off quick enough, I mean seriously those idiots got even more dumb. Sharks don't have bonds, sharks are cold and emotionless, they don't take mates, and they don't care for their children a whole awful lot, they are just brainless instinctual fish, that must keep moving or they will die, this is why the geniuses in the movie put the baby in a cramped little tank, and shocked it shitless with a whole crowd of gawking people. Now this movie is very pointless, and very bad, and the way they kill the shark is pathetic, it can't swallow a guy whole for some reason when it can all those other times, and somehow he doesn't let go of his grenade, and they are able to pull the pin, I mean it just sounds utterly ridiculous. This film is horrifying and stupid in every single way, and I want to never defile my eyes by viewing it again, oh wait I just did, and saw that they used the shark theme, but still.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D The best thing about seeing a Great White Shark in 3D is that you'll look so stupid wearing those 3D glasses that it'll be too busy laughing at you to attack. However, no comical-looking headgear could keep the aquatic killer in this horror movie from ravaging you. A juvenile shark infiltrates the gates separating SeaWorld from the sea. Inside the underwater attraction, the finned-intruder begins preying on the animals and their trainers. When employees (Dennis Quaid, Bess Armstrong) go to the park manager (Louis Gossett, Jr.) with this news, he decides to profit off it. But when the mother comes looking for her pup, visitors trapped in the park's submerged tunnel system become its victims. The second sequel to Jaws, Jaws 3D is a lackluster contribution to the seafaring series that jumps the shark with this installment. Besides, SeaWorld doesn't need any outside help in killing their captive animal population. (Red Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just okay, no matter how many dimensions you see it in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even aside from the timely numerical designation of this sequel, the Jaws franchise seems like a natural for the realm of 3-D. The requisite underwater terrain alone is a perfect medium for textured dimensional rendering, and the idea of a terrifying, relentless killing machine swimming off-screen into audiences' laps is inherently awesome in and of itself. Sadly, this uneven offering never takes full advantage of its technology or its subject matter, and while it's nowhere near as bad as the truly abysmal Jaws: The Revenge (few things are), it's also nowhere near as good as the flawless original or the excellent and unfairly dismissed follow-up. Even without its potentially interesting visual ploy, Jaws 3-D has all of the ingredients to be a great sequel on paper: a stellar cast, a fresh concept, and, of course, a toothy behemoth that had already generated some of the scariest moments in screen history. These assets are ultimately squandered however. The seasoned ensemble is given very little to do, so the character studies at the heart of Jaws and Jaws 2 are bypassed entirely. The Sea World setting is woefully underused, and instead of giving our beast a novel killing ground, the park mostly functions as merely another mass of water for the action to unfold in. Worse, the shark itself isn't ever used in a suspenseful fashion, and the handful of deaths attributed to the monster are blatantly telegraphed and largely ineffective. Like many 3-D films that are stripped of their visual device for the home market, this one contains multiple scenes that may have been fun to behold on theater screens, but become utterly silly here. Floating fish heads and severed limbs bobbing with the tide might have provided cheap thrills for the opening weekend audience, but in a flat DVD representation, they simply function as camera shots that linger for far too long. The shark effects range from serviceable to downright awful, and since footage of actual sharks is utilized rather extensively, the titular titan more clearly resembles a synthetic puppet when we're seeing it at work. A couple of scenes of the creature slamming into gates and boats seem to have been created by using a plastic mock-up instead the sophisticated robotic construct that populated the first two Jaws outings, and since little effort is made to sell these moments, you can actually see the rubber shark bounce off its targets upon collision. When these flashes are integrated alongside the graceful maneuvering of real great whites, there is little symmetry between the two versions and the complete suspension of disbelief required to make a scenario like this pay off is rarely achieved. Apart from its obviousness as a prop, the shark in Jaws 3-D just isn't all that frightening because the meager body count doesn't allow it to prove itself as an insatiable murder machine. A couple of random victims are thrown in early on, but when the shark finally makes its way into the water park, where a virtual sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord of flailing legs awaits, every single person the shark pursues easily escapes its titular Jaws. Only one of the major characters gets bit during this extended sequence, and she gets away with little more than a few scratches on her leg. There are a few solid jump scares peppered throughout the film, but while the tension seems to be mounting every step of the way, the movie invariably pulls back before anything all that spectacular or horrifying occurs. Even the promising climax goes flaccid when the absolute dumbest false 3-D moment occurs, and any menace our finned antagonist has generated along the way is readily diffused by a protracted shot of her slowly floating toward the camera and breaking through a plainly animated sheet of glass. The way the shark is dispatched is particularly hard to swallow (this is actually a pretty good pun if you've seen the film), and yet another silly extended "in your face" moment caps off a tremendously underwhelming resolution. Savvy collectors will easily be able to track down readily available bootleg DVDs that retain the original 3-D presentation, but even the cleanest transfer available on the secondary market is still high-generation and extremely murky, a state which naturally strips away the potency of the visual effects. Watching my copy gave me a headache, and I had to stop about every thirty minutes or so to take off the glasses and give my eyes a rest. I eventually made it through, but when I did, all I discovered was that Jaws 3-D isn't much more impressive in its original form. The obsessive collector in me knows that if this offering ever gets a proper Blu-Ray release I will have to add it to my collection and give the film at least one more go, but the realist in me is guessing that even digitized 3-D effects won't make up for the numerous other weaknesses on hand here. There are a few effective moments here that will hold the attention of admirers of the series, but the film as a whole is a missed opportunity that can only be rightfully recommended to the most forgiving killer fish fans. An even better recommendation for those who have digested every frame of the unmatchable original and simply must have more is to skip this one entirely and give Jaws 2 another look instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Third Dimension is Terrible!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It used to be so simple to point out the bad shark movies. There was "Jaws 3" and "Jaws 4: The Revenge", and that was it pretty much! But then, as per the late nineties approximately, we literally received an overflow of inferior and quite often downright retarded killer shark flicks. And now all of a sudden, the aforementioned Jaws sequels actually don't look too terrible anymore. It started in the late 90's with the still traditional but totally inept "Deep Blue Sea" and "Shark Attack", but then since the new Millennium things really got out of control with murderous sharks popping up in the most illogical of places (like the rivers in Venice, in Tsunami infested areas, swamps, etc) and  worse even  all kinds of ridiculous hybrids and genetically altered species, like dinosaur sharks, octopus-sharks and two-headed sharks. Sigh  whatever happened to good-old fashioned massively over-sized Great Whites, like in our classic early 80's stinker "Jaws 3-D"? Now, please don't misunderstand me, the third installment in the Jaws franchise is still a very lousy film, but at least it's not bad in a frustrating or annoying way. The underdeveloped screenplay, the laughable attempt to bring depth to the main characters, the hilarious 3D effects and all the totally irrelevant padding footage  It almost feels cheesy and charming in a positive sort of way now. Interesting detail here is that Universal Studios, the mastodon production company behind the Jaws franchise, sued the creators of an obscure Italian imitation for being too reminiscent, but then they were hypocrite enough to steal ideas from the movie they accused of stealing from them! That's Hollywood for you, I guess. The script attempts, poorly I may add, to build a bridge between the previous two movies by depicting the Brody boys (the sons of Roy Scheider) as pivot characters in the grand opening of a brand new Florida Ocean theme park. Mike, the oldest one, works there as the head engineer and his younger brother Sean  supposedly still suffering from his childhood trauma even though he blindly follows the first cute girl he meets straight in the water for a nightly swimming session  comes to visit him for the ceremony. Due to malfunctioning underwater fences and unreliable technical staff, the park quickly receives unforeseen visitors in the shape of a great white shark and its offspring. Also in good old Jaws tradition, the park's senior executive initially hopes to exploit the baby shark as a unique special attraction without realizing he puts the lives of hundreds of guests and personnel in danger. When Junior White dies in front of many spectators, mommy goes on a relentless killing and destruction spree. The body count is intolerably low for a shark movie, but that's probably because all the action is concentrated in the last twenty minutes of the film. Throughout more than an hour, we're only exposed to uninteresting relationship issues, dull family conversations and a whole lot of random waterskiing footage. Most of the supportive characters are embarrassing stereotypes (an Australian outback hunter?) and the effects are hysterical even by early 80's standards. Especially the shark's ultimate attack is legendary, as he approaches the underwater control room in slow motion while the people inside just pull stupid faces.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sea World with a difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris.
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    35 feet of white teeth-gnashing terror finds itself on the wrong side of marine gates established to keep the sea from the lagoon of a Sea World resort in Florida. This third instalment in the "Jaws" family is entertaining, if somewhat tripe in its handling of the subject matter. Despite being an absurd looking shark imitation, the sight of the great dorsal fin breaking water beside oblivious skiers, together with the signature pulsating rhythm of the theme music, still manages to send shivers down the spine. The young Brody kids (Dennis Quaid and John Putch) from the first two episodes have returned, now adults enjoying some catch-up at the recently revamped Sea World Resort, where the older brother (Quaid) works alongside his love interest (Armstrong). However their merry reunion is short-lived when a young Great White shark is discovered in the waterpark's lagoon. After an attempt to catch and conserve the shark in captivity fails, they soon discover that mother is also in the park, and not at all pleased at the exploitation of junior. Despite some amateurish-looking performances in the minor roles, and the occasional inane dialogue, this remains a mostly suspenseful and exciting third entry in the quartet, still capable of invoking a primal fear of the water. And in case you were wondering, there's a particularly graphic attack scene and aftermath (check out the inventive make-up effects employed) that should impress.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please Tap on This Glass. Repeatedly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oy vey. I actually defended Jaws 2. Did that come back to bite me on the ass for the horror Jaws 3D was? And just to clear up my last statement: I meant horror as in HORRIBLE MOVIE and not a suspenseful scarefest. At any rate, Jaws 3D is so bad, so full of its gimmick of "3D"  which was NO WHERE NEAR new in 1983, by the way  that they actually turned the one-hit-wonder (the original, 1975's Jaws) into a jokefest. Sad. The one positive thing I can say about it, is that they really paved the way for Piranha 3DTWENTY-SEVEN YEARS LATER in 2010as there's a lot here that they held back on  it was Rated PG for some strange reason  that Piranha 3D took to the next level, or twenty. Seaworld's under attack by not one, but TWO sharks this time. Way to step it up from the previous "wimpy" films in the franchise that only involved one shark each. Somehow, without any investigation, its deemed the two sharks are parent and child. But, that's neither here, nor there. It's all about the fake 3D carnage. Really, I don't want to waste too much more time on this mess. I can even safely say, the Director and Writer feels the same way: they made a mess of poo and continuously wrote themselves into corners. There is no redeemable reasons to see this movie. Nothing that stands out, such as the "Okay, it's bad, but you gotta see this" scene. Of course, that makes me conclude with: You think this is bad? Wait until the next installment  I mean, who the *BLEEP* believed so deeply in this series, by this point, that they green lit the abomination that was to follow?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3-D This Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set several years after the events of Part II, Chief Brody's sons Mike & Sean(Roy Scheider did not return) are now young adults at Sea World in Florida, where yet another killer great white shark emerges, trying to track down its baby, who is being kept there and studied. Scientists and hunters must team up to defeat this menace before it kills the incoming tourists... Now in(shoddy) 3-D, this film is just inept, with a ridiculous, uninspired plot, poor science regarding sharks, and no story involvement whatsoever. Utterly devoid of a point, just a blatant cash-in on the title and resurgent popularity of 3-D(Third Jaws film in 3-D, clever no?) A bust.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Mockery To The 'Jaws' Name
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movieman
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3 has to be the worst movie I've ever seen in my whole life. If I could rate it 0 stars then I would. I didn't believe one bit that there was a shark in the waters, even though I did i Jaws 1 and 2. Firstly, the special effects were so out of date. In the dolphin scene, were they first saw the shark, when you see the Great White for the first time, I found that they just stole the footage from an old National Geographic Documentary. Secondly, this movie was full of sexual references. For example, Sean Brody says to his older brother Michael Brody, "I was so close to doing it in the water last night." after doing something inappropriate at the beach the previous night. Finally, the amount of shark facts they got wrong was just tremendous. I completely lost count. Overall, if you want to watch all of the 'Jaws' movies, I advise you skip this to 'Jaws: The Revenge' for nothing important happens in this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great idea, not done right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Dalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3-D had so much potential and it could have been the best in the series if they had done it right. The story is pure gold but unfortunately the scenes didn't go that far or break any rules. Not to mention that the 3D was awful. Another problem with this movie is that the dialogue was bad and the acting was horrible for the most part. If you want to see this movie, keep your expectations very low because you will likely be disappointed. Jaws 3-D as a whole was just mediocre as a whole but it does have some redeeming features. The things that are good about this movie are that the shark attack scenes were pretty cool and scarier than the first two and that the story is wildly original compared to the first two.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really isn't all that bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alienator Donut
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D was a satisfactory sequel with only very few flaws. The 3D visual effects were quite laughable. The plot was promising enough, it is set at Sea World, where a group of people set up an aquarium, It IS different to the other Jaws films, because Chief Brody does not make an appearance, (Even though he is often mentioned, and his sons are main characters in this film.) My personal favourite scene was the scene involving the very slow moving shark swimming to the screen with crashing into the glass window, it is later blown up! With laughable CGI special effects, and a soundtrack with a melody sounding like the Christmas song: "Joy to the world!" Jaws 3D is an entertaining enough second sequel! However, it looks like Citizen Kane, compared to its so bad it's hilarious follow up: "Jaws: The Revenge!" 6/10 Written By Alienator Donut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What, Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    suckmeoffflemwad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now Jaws 2 was a totally unnecessary sequel as I have said, however this film, Jaws 3-D is even more foul and pestilent, for starters, it lacks, and I mean it lacks, the signature shark theme from all the other films, this is what made Jaws so powerful and startling, that iconic theme. They have removed the power of the monster by replacing its theme with some bullshit merry melody, and here we barely even get to see the shark at all, I mean not like in the first, I mean in a bad way, and it kills very few people, it poses barely any threat at all, and for Christ's sake, its baby dies, and it wants revenge, sharks will eat their babies if they don't mature and scamper off quick enough, I mean seriously those idiots got even more dumb. Sharks don't have bonds, sharks are cold and emotionless, they don't take mates, and they don't care for their children a whole awful lot, they are just brainless instinctual fish, that must keep moving or they will die, this is why the geniuses in the movie put the baby in a cramped little tank, and shocked it shitless with a whole crowd of gawking people. Now this movie is very pointless, and very bad, and the way they kill the shark is pathetic, it can't swallow a guy whole for some reason when it can all those other times, and somehow he doesn't let go of his grenade, and they are able to pull the pin, I mean it just sounds utterly ridiculous. This film is horrifying and stupid in every single way, and I want to never defile my eyes by viewing it again, oh wait I just did, and saw that they used the shark theme, but still.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D The best thing about seeing a Great White Shark in 3D is that you'll look so stupid wearing those 3D glasses that it'll be too busy laughing at you to attack. However, no comical-looking headgear could keep the aquatic killer in this horror movie from ravaging you. A juvenile shark infiltrates the gates separating SeaWorld from the sea. Inside the underwater attraction, the finned-intruder begins preying on the animals and their trainers. When employees (Dennis Quaid, Bess Armstrong) go to the park manager (Louis Gossett, Jr.) with this news, he decides to profit off it. But when the mother comes looking for her pup, visitors trapped in the park's submerged tunnel system become its victims. The second sequel to Jaws, Jaws 3D is a lackluster contribution to the seafaring series that jumps the shark with this installment. Besides, SeaWorld doesn't need any outside help in killing their captive animal population. (Red Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just okay, no matter how many dimensions you see it in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even aside from the timely numerical designation of this sequel, the Jaws franchise seems like a natural for the realm of 3-D. The requisite underwater terrain alone is a perfect medium for textured dimensional rendering, and the idea of a terrifying, relentless killing machine swimming off-screen into audiences' laps is inherently awesome in and of itself. Sadly, this uneven offering never takes full advantage of its technology or its subject matter, and while it's nowhere near as bad as the truly abysmal Jaws: The Revenge (few things are), it's also nowhere near as good as the flawless original or the excellent and unfairly dismissed follow-up. Even without its potentially interesting visual ploy, Jaws 3-D has all of the ingredients to be a great sequel on paper: a stellar cast, a fresh concept, and, of course, a toothy behemoth that had already generated some of the scariest moments in screen history. These assets are ultimately squandered however. The seasoned ensemble is given very little to do, so the character studies at the heart of Jaws and Jaws 2 are bypassed entirely. The Sea World setting is woefully underused, and instead of giving our beast a novel killing ground, the park mostly functions as merely another mass of water for the action to unfold in. Worse, the shark itself isn't ever used in a suspenseful fashion, and the handful of deaths attributed to the monster are blatantly telegraphed and largely ineffective. Like many 3-D films that are stripped of their visual device for the home market, this one contains multiple scenes that may have been fun to behold on theater screens, but become utterly silly here. Floating fish heads and severed limbs bobbing with the tide might have provided cheap thrills for the opening weekend audience, but in a flat DVD representation, they simply function as camera shots that linger for far too long. The shark effects range from serviceable to downright awful, and since footage of actual sharks is utilized rather extensively, the titular titan more clearly resembles a synthetic puppet when we're seeing it at work. A couple of scenes of the creature slamming into gates and boats seem to have been created by using a plastic mock-up instead the sophisticated robotic construct that populated the first two Jaws outings, and since little effort is made to sell these moments, you can actually see the rubber shark bounce off its targets upon collision. When these flashes are integrated alongside the graceful maneuvering of real great whites, there is little symmetry between the two versions and the complete suspension of disbelief required to make a scenario like this pay off is rarely achieved. Apart from its obviousness as a prop, the shark in Jaws 3-D just isn't all that frightening because the meager body count doesn't allow it to prove itself as an insatiable murder machine. A couple of random victims are thrown in early on, but when the shark finally makes its way into the water park, where a virtual sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord of flailing legs awaits, every single person the shark pursues easily escapes its titular Jaws. Only one of the major characters gets bit during this extended sequence, and she gets away with little more than a few scratches on her leg. There are a few solid jump scares peppered throughout the film, but while the tension seems to be mounting every step of the way, the movie invariably pulls back before anything all that spectacular or horrifying occurs. Even the promising climax goes flaccid when the absolute dumbest false 3-D moment occurs, and any menace our finned antagonist has generated along the way is readily diffused by a protracted shot of her slowly floating toward the camera and breaking through a plainly animated sheet of glass. The way the shark is dispatched is particularly hard to swallow (this is actually a pretty good pun if you've seen the film), and yet another silly extended "in your face" moment caps off a tremendously underwhelming resolution. Savvy collectors will easily be able to track down readily available bootleg DVDs that retain the original 3-D presentation, but even the cleanest transfer available on the secondary market is still high-generation and extremely murky, a state which naturally strips away the potency of the visual effects. Watching my copy gave me a headache, and I had to stop about every thirty minutes or so to take off the glasses and give my eyes a rest. I eventually made it through, but when I did, all I discovered was that Jaws 3-D isn't much more impressive in its original form. The obsessive collector in me knows that if this offering ever gets a proper Blu-Ray release I will have to add it to my collection and give the film at least one more go, but the realist in me is guessing that even digitized 3-D effects won't make up for the numerous other weaknesses on hand here. There are a few effective moments here that will hold the attention of admirers of the series, but the film as a whole is a missed opportunity that can only be rightfully recommended to the most forgiving killer fish fans. An even better recommendation for those who have digested every frame of the unmatchable original and simply must have more is to skip this one entirely and give Jaws 2 another look instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Third Dimension is Terrible!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It used to be so simple to point out the bad shark movies. There was "Jaws 3" and "Jaws 4: The Revenge", and that was it pretty much! But then, as per the late nineties approximately, we literally received an overflow of inferior and quite often downright retarded killer shark flicks. And now all of a sudden, the aforementioned Jaws sequels actually don't look too terrible anymore. It started in the late 90's with the still traditional but totally inept "Deep Blue Sea" and "Shark Attack", but then since the new Millennium things really got out of control with murderous sharks popping up in the most illogical of places (like the rivers in Venice, in Tsunami infested areas, swamps, etc) and  worse even  all kinds of ridiculous hybrids and genetically altered species, like dinosaur sharks, octopus-sharks and two-headed sharks. Sigh  whatever happened to good-old fashioned massively over-sized Great Whites, like in our classic early 80's stinker "Jaws 3-D"? Now, please don't misunderstand me, the third installment in the Jaws franchise is still a very lousy film, but at least it's not bad in a frustrating or annoying way. The underdeveloped screenplay, the laughable attempt to bring depth to the main characters, the hilarious 3D effects and all the totally irrelevant padding footage  It almost feels cheesy and charming in a positive sort of way now. Interesting detail here is that Universal Studios, the mastodon production company behind the Jaws franchise, sued the creators of an obscure Italian imitation for being too reminiscent, but then they were hypocrite enough to steal ideas from the movie they accused of stealing from them! That's Hollywood for you, I guess. The script attempts, poorly I may add, to build a bridge between the previous two movies by depicting the Brody boys (the sons of Roy Scheider) as pivot characters in the grand opening of a brand new Florida Ocean theme park. Mike, the oldest one, works there as the head engineer and his younger brother Sean  supposedly still suffering from his childhood trauma even though he blindly follows the first cute girl he meets straight in the water for a nightly swimming session  comes to visit him for the ceremony. Due to malfunctioning underwater fences and unreliable technical staff, the park quickly receives unforeseen visitors in the shape of a great white shark and its offspring. Also in good old Jaws tradition, the park's senior executive initially hopes to exploit the baby shark as a unique special attraction without realizing he puts the lives of hundreds of guests and personnel in danger. When Junior White dies in front of many spectators, mommy goes on a relentless killing and destruction spree. The body count is intolerably low for a shark movie, but that's probably because all the action is concentrated in the last twenty minutes of the film. Throughout more than an hour, we're only exposed to uninteresting relationship issues, dull family conversations and a whole lot of random waterskiing footage. Most of the supportive characters are embarrassing stereotypes (an Australian outback hunter?) and the effects are hysterical even by early 80's standards. Especially the shark's ultimate attack is legendary, as he approaches the underwater control room in slow motion while the people inside just pull stupid faces.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sea World with a difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris.
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    35 feet of white teeth-gnashing terror finds itself on the wrong side of marine gates established to keep the sea from the lagoon of a Sea World resort in Florida. This third instalment in the "Jaws" family is entertaining, if somewhat tripe in its handling of the subject matter. Despite being an absurd looking shark imitation, the sight of the great dorsal fin breaking water beside oblivious skiers, together with the signature pulsating rhythm of the theme music, still manages to send shivers down the spine. The young Brody kids (Dennis Quaid and John Putch) from the first two episodes have returned, now adults enjoying some catch-up at the recently revamped Sea World Resort, where the older brother (Quaid) works alongside his love interest (Armstrong). However their merry reunion is short-lived when a young Great White shark is discovered in the waterpark's lagoon. After an attempt to catch and conserve the shark in captivity fails, they soon discover that mother is also in the park, and not at all pleased at the exploitation of junior. Despite some amateurish-looking performances in the minor roles, and the occasional inane dialogue, this remains a mostly suspenseful and exciting third entry in the quartet, still capable of invoking a primal fear of the water. And in case you were wondering, there's a particularly graphic attack scene and aftermath (check out the inventive make-up effects employed) that should impress.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please Tap on This Glass. Repeatedly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oy vey. I actually defended Jaws 2. Did that come back to bite me on the ass for the horror Jaws 3D was? And just to clear up my last statement: I meant horror as in HORRIBLE MOVIE and not a suspenseful scarefest. At any rate, Jaws 3D is so bad, so full of its gimmick of "3D"  which was NO WHERE NEAR new in 1983, by the way  that they actually turned the one-hit-wonder (the original, 1975's Jaws) into a jokefest. Sad. The one positive thing I can say about it, is that they really paved the way for Piranha 3DTWENTY-SEVEN YEARS LATER in 2010as there's a lot here that they held back on  it was Rated PG for some strange reason  that Piranha 3D took to the next level, or twenty. Seaworld's under attack by not one, but TWO sharks this time. Way to step it up from the previous "wimpy" films in the franchise that only involved one shark each. Somehow, without any investigation, its deemed the two sharks are parent and child. But, that's neither here, nor there. It's all about the fake 3D carnage. Really, I don't want to waste too much more time on this mess. I can even safely say, the Director and Writer feels the same way: they made a mess of poo and continuously wrote themselves into corners. There is no redeemable reasons to see this movie. Nothing that stands out, such as the "Okay, it's bad, but you gotta see this" scene. Of course, that makes me conclude with: You think this is bad? Wait until the next installment  I mean, who the *BLEEP* believed so deeply in this series, by this point, that they green lit the abomination that was to follow?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3-D This Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set several years after the events of Part II, Chief Brody's sons Mike & Sean(Roy Scheider did not return) are now young adults at Sea World in Florida, where yet another killer great white shark emerges, trying to track down its baby, who is being kept there and studied. Scientists and hunters must team up to defeat this menace before it kills the incoming tourists... Now in(shoddy) 3-D, this film is just inept, with a ridiculous, uninspired plot, poor science regarding sharks, and no story involvement whatsoever. Utterly devoid of a point, just a blatant cash-in on the title and resurgent popularity of 3-D(Third Jaws film in 3-D, clever no?) A bust.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Mockery To The 'Jaws' Name
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movieman
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3 has to be the worst movie I've ever seen in my whole life. If I could rate it 0 stars then I would. I didn't believe one bit that there was a shark in the waters, even though I did i Jaws 1 and 2. Firstly, the special effects were so out of date. In the dolphin scene, were they first saw the shark, when you see the Great White for the first time, I found that they just stole the footage from an old National Geographic Documentary. Secondly, this movie was full of sexual references. For example, Sean Brody says to his older brother Michael Brody, "I was so close to doing it in the water last night." after doing something inappropriate at the beach the previous night. Finally, the amount of shark facts they got wrong was just tremendous. I completely lost count. Overall, if you want to watch all of the 'Jaws' movies, I advise you skip this to 'Jaws: The Revenge' for nothing important happens in this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great idea, not done right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Dalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3-D had so much potential and it could have been the best in the series if they had done it right. The story is pure gold but unfortunately the scenes didn't go that far or break any rules. Not to mention that the 3D was awful. Another problem with this movie is that the dialogue was bad and the acting was horrible for the most part. If you want to see this movie, keep your expectations very low because you will likely be disappointed. Jaws 3-D as a whole was just mediocre as a whole but it does have some redeeming features. The things that are good about this movie are that the shark attack scenes were pretty cool and scarier than the first two and that the story is wildly original compared to the first two.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really isn't all that bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alienator Donut
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D was a satisfactory sequel with only very few flaws. The 3D visual effects were quite laughable. The plot was promising enough, it is set at Sea World, where a group of people set up an aquarium, It IS different to the other Jaws films, because Chief Brody does not make an appearance, (Even though he is often mentioned, and his sons are main characters in this film.) My personal favourite scene was the scene involving the very slow moving shark swimming to the screen with crashing into the glass window, it is later blown up! With laughable CGI special effects, and a soundtrack with a melody sounding like the Christmas song: "Joy to the world!" Jaws 3D is an entertaining enough second sequel! However, it looks like Citizen Kane, compared to its so bad it's hilarious follow up: "Jaws: The Revenge!" 6/10 Written By Alienator Donut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What, Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    suckmeoffflemwad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now Jaws 2 was a totally unnecessary sequel as I have said, however this film, Jaws 3-D is even more foul and pestilent, for starters, it lacks, and I mean it lacks, the signature shark theme from all the other films, this is what made Jaws so powerful and startling, that iconic theme. They have removed the power of the monster by replacing its theme with some bullshit merry melody, and here we barely even get to see the shark at all, I mean not like in the first, I mean in a bad way, and it kills very few people, it poses barely any threat at all, and for Christ's sake, its baby dies, and it wants revenge, sharks will eat their babies if they don't mature and scamper off quick enough, I mean seriously those idiots got even more dumb. Sharks don't have bonds, sharks are cold and emotionless, they don't take mates, and they don't care for their children a whole awful lot, they are just brainless instinctual fish, that must keep moving or they will die, this is why the geniuses in the movie put the baby in a cramped little tank, and shocked it shitless with a whole crowd of gawking people. Now this movie is very pointless, and very bad, and the way they kill the shark is pathetic, it can't swallow a guy whole for some reason when it can all those other times, and somehow he doesn't let go of his grenade, and they are able to pull the pin, I mean it just sounds utterly ridiculous. This film is horrifying and stupid in every single way, and I want to never defile my eyes by viewing it again, oh wait I just did, and saw that they used the shark theme, but still.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D The best thing about seeing a Great White Shark in 3D is that you'll look so stupid wearing those 3D glasses that it'll be too busy laughing at you to attack. However, no comical-looking headgear could keep the aquatic killer in this horror movie from ravaging you. A juvenile shark infiltrates the gates separating SeaWorld from the sea. Inside the underwater attraction, the finned-intruder begins preying on the animals and their trainers. When employees (Dennis Quaid, Bess Armstrong) go to the park manager (Louis Gossett, Jr.) with this news, he decides to profit off it. But when the mother comes looking for her pup, visitors trapped in the park's submerged tunnel system become its victims. The second sequel to Jaws, Jaws 3D is a lackluster contribution to the seafaring series that jumps the shark with this installment. Besides, SeaWorld doesn't need any outside help in killing their captive animal population. (Red Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just okay, no matter how many dimensions you see it in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even aside from the timely numerical designation of this sequel, the Jaws franchise seems like a natural for the realm of 3-D. The requisite underwater terrain alone is a perfect medium for textured dimensional rendering, and the idea of a terrifying, relentless killing machine swimming off-screen into audiences' laps is inherently awesome in and of itself. Sadly, this uneven offering never takes full advantage of its technology or its subject matter, and while it's nowhere near as bad as the truly abysmal Jaws: The Revenge (few things are), it's also nowhere near as good as the flawless original or the excellent and unfairly dismissed follow-up. Even without its potentially interesting visual ploy, Jaws 3-D has all of the ingredients to be a great sequel on paper: a stellar cast, a fresh concept, and, of course, a toothy behemoth that had already generated some of the scariest moments in screen history. These assets are ultimately squandered however. The seasoned ensemble is given very little to do, so the character studies at the heart of Jaws and Jaws 2 are bypassed entirely. The Sea World setting is woefully underused, and instead of giving our beast a novel killing ground, the park mostly functions as merely another mass of water for the action to unfold in. Worse, the shark itself isn't ever used in a suspenseful fashion, and the handful of deaths attributed to the monster are blatantly telegraphed and largely ineffective. Like many 3-D films that are stripped of their visual device for the home market, this one contains multiple scenes that may have been fun to behold on theater screens, but become utterly silly here. Floating fish heads and severed limbs bobbing with the tide might have provided cheap thrills for the opening weekend audience, but in a flat DVD representation, they simply function as camera shots that linger for far too long. The shark effects range from serviceable to downright awful, and since footage of actual sharks is utilized rather extensively, the titular titan more clearly resembles a synthetic puppet when we're seeing it at work. A couple of scenes of the creature slamming into gates and boats seem to have been created by using a plastic mock-up instead the sophisticated robotic construct that populated the first two Jaws outings, and since little effort is made to sell these moments, you can actually see the rubber shark bounce off its targets upon collision. When these flashes are integrated alongside the graceful maneuvering of real great whites, there is little symmetry between the two versions and the complete suspension of disbelief required to make a scenario like this pay off is rarely achieved. Apart from its obviousness as a prop, the shark in Jaws 3-D just isn't all that frightening because the meager body count doesn't allow it to prove itself as an insatiable murder machine. A couple of random victims are thrown in early on, but when the shark finally makes its way into the water park, where a virtual sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord of flailing legs awaits, every single person the shark pursues easily escapes its titular Jaws. Only one of the major characters gets bit during this extended sequence, and she gets away with little more than a few scratches on her leg. There are a few solid jump scares peppered throughout the film, but while the tension seems to be mounting every step of the way, the movie invariably pulls back before anything all that spectacular or horrifying occurs. Even the promising climax goes flaccid when the absolute dumbest false 3-D moment occurs, and any menace our finned antagonist has generated along the way is readily diffused by a protracted shot of her slowly floating toward the camera and breaking through a plainly animated sheet of glass. The way the shark is dispatched is particularly hard to swallow (this is actually a pretty good pun if you've seen the film), and yet another silly extended "in your face" moment caps off a tremendously underwhelming resolution. Savvy collectors will easily be able to track down readily available bootleg DVDs that retain the original 3-D presentation, but even the cleanest transfer available on the secondary market is still high-generation and extremely murky, a state which naturally strips away the potency of the visual effects. Watching my copy gave me a headache, and I had to stop about every thirty minutes or so to take off the glasses and give my eyes a rest. I eventually made it through, but when I did, all I discovered was that Jaws 3-D isn't much more impressive in its original form. The obsessive collector in me knows that if this offering ever gets a proper Blu-Ray release I will have to add it to my collection and give the film at least one more go, but the realist in me is guessing that even digitized 3-D effects won't make up for the numerous other weaknesses on hand here. There are a few effective moments here that will hold the attention of admirers of the series, but the film as a whole is a missed opportunity that can only be rightfully recommended to the most forgiving killer fish fans. An even better recommendation for those who have digested every frame of the unmatchable original and simply must have more is to skip this one entirely and give Jaws 2 another look instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Third Dimension is Terrible!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It used to be so simple to point out the bad shark movies. There was "Jaws 3" and "Jaws 4: The Revenge", and that was it pretty much! But then, as per the late nineties approximately, we literally received an overflow of inferior and quite often downright retarded killer shark flicks. And now all of a sudden, the aforementioned Jaws sequels actually don't look too terrible anymore. It started in the late 90's with the still traditional but totally inept "Deep Blue Sea" and "Shark Attack", but then since the new Millennium things really got out of control with murderous sharks popping up in the most illogical of places (like the rivers in Venice, in Tsunami infested areas, swamps, etc) and  worse even  all kinds of ridiculous hybrids and genetically altered species, like dinosaur sharks, octopus-sharks and two-headed sharks. Sigh  whatever happened to good-old fashioned massively over-sized Great Whites, like in our classic early 80's stinker "Jaws 3-D"? Now, please don't misunderstand me, the third installment in the Jaws franchise is still a very lousy film, but at least it's not bad in a frustrating or annoying way. The underdeveloped screenplay, the laughable attempt to bring depth to the main characters, the hilarious 3D effects and all the totally irrelevant padding footage  It almost feels cheesy and charming in a positive sort of way now. Interesting detail here is that Universal Studios, the mastodon production company behind the Jaws franchise, sued the creators of an obscure Italian imitation for being too reminiscent, but then they were hypocrite enough to steal ideas from the movie they accused of stealing from them! That's Hollywood for you, I guess. The script attempts, poorly I may add, to build a bridge between the previous two movies by depicting the Brody boys (the sons of Roy Scheider) as pivot characters in the grand opening of a brand new Florida Ocean theme park. Mike, the oldest one, works there as the head engineer and his younger brother Sean  supposedly still suffering from his childhood trauma even though he blindly follows the first cute girl he meets straight in the water for a nightly swimming session  comes to visit him for the ceremony. Due to malfunctioning underwater fences and unreliable technical staff, the park quickly receives unforeseen visitors in the shape of a great white shark and its offspring. Also in good old Jaws tradition, the park's senior executive initially hopes to exploit the baby shark as a unique special attraction without realizing he puts the lives of hundreds of guests and personnel in danger. When Junior White dies in front of many spectators, mommy goes on a relentless killing and destruction spree. The body count is intolerably low for a shark movie, but that's probably because all the action is concentrated in the last twenty minutes of the film. Throughout more than an hour, we're only exposed to uninteresting relationship issues, dull family conversations and a whole lot of random waterskiing footage. Most of the supportive characters are embarrassing stereotypes (an Australian outback hunter?) and the effects are hysterical even by early 80's standards. Especially the shark's ultimate attack is legendary, as he approaches the underwater control room in slow motion while the people inside just pull stupid faces.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sea World with a difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris.
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    35 feet of white teeth-gnashing terror finds itself on the wrong side of marine gates established to keep the sea from the lagoon of a Sea World resort in Florida. This third instalment in the "Jaws" family is entertaining, if somewhat tripe in its handling of the subject matter. Despite being an absurd looking shark imitation, the sight of the great dorsal fin breaking water beside oblivious skiers, together with the signature pulsating rhythm of the theme music, still manages to send shivers down the spine. The young Brody kids (Dennis Quaid and John Putch) from the first two episodes have returned, now adults enjoying some catch-up at the recently revamped Sea World Resort, where the older brother (Quaid) works alongside his love interest (Armstrong). However their merry reunion is short-lived when a young Great White shark is discovered in the waterpark's lagoon. After an attempt to catch and conserve the shark in captivity fails, they soon discover that mother is also in the park, and not at all pleased at the exploitation of junior. Despite some amateurish-looking performances in the minor roles, and the occasional inane dialogue, this remains a mostly suspenseful and exciting third entry in the quartet, still capable of invoking a primal fear of the water. And in case you were wondering, there's a particularly graphic attack scene and aftermath (check out the inventive make-up effects employed) that should impress.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please Tap on This Glass. Repeatedly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oy vey. I actually defended Jaws 2. Did that come back to bite me on the ass for the horror Jaws 3D was? And just to clear up my last statement: I meant horror as in HORRIBLE MOVIE and not a suspenseful scarefest. At any rate, Jaws 3D is so bad, so full of its gimmick of "3D"  which was NO WHERE NEAR new in 1983, by the way  that they actually turned the one-hit-wonder (the original, 1975's Jaws) into a jokefest. Sad. The one positive thing I can say about it, is that they really paved the way for Piranha 3DTWENTY-SEVEN YEARS LATER in 2010as there's a lot here that they held back on  it was Rated PG for some strange reason  that Piranha 3D took to the next level, or twenty. Seaworld's under attack by not one, but TWO sharks this time. Way to step it up from the previous "wimpy" films in the franchise that only involved one shark each. Somehow, without any investigation, its deemed the two sharks are parent and child. But, that's neither here, nor there. It's all about the fake 3D carnage. Really, I don't want to waste too much more time on this mess. I can even safely say, the Director and Writer feels the same way: they made a mess of poo and continuously wrote themselves into corners. There is no redeemable reasons to see this movie. Nothing that stands out, such as the "Okay, it's bad, but you gotta see this" scene. Of course, that makes me conclude with: You think this is bad? Wait until the next installment  I mean, who the *BLEEP* believed so deeply in this series, by this point, that they green lit the abomination that was to follow?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3-D This Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set several years after the events of Part II, Chief Brody's sons Mike & Sean(Roy Scheider did not return) are now young adults at Sea World in Florida, where yet another killer great white shark emerges, trying to track down its baby, who is being kept there and studied. Scientists and hunters must team up to defeat this menace before it kills the incoming tourists... Now in(shoddy) 3-D, this film is just inept, with a ridiculous, uninspired plot, poor science regarding sharks, and no story involvement whatsoever. Utterly devoid of a point, just a blatant cash-in on the title and resurgent popularity of 3-D(Third Jaws film in 3-D, clever no?) A bust.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Mockery To The 'Jaws' Name
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movieman
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3 has to be the worst movie I've ever seen in my whole life. If I could rate it 0 stars then I would. I didn't believe one bit that there was a shark in the waters, even though I did i Jaws 1 and 2. Firstly, the special effects were so out of date. In the dolphin scene, were they first saw the shark, when you see the Great White for the first time, I found that they just stole the footage from an old National Geographic Documentary. Secondly, this movie was full of sexual references. For example, Sean Brody says to his older brother Michael Brody, "I was so close to doing it in the water last night." after doing something inappropriate at the beach the previous night. Finally, the amount of shark facts they got wrong was just tremendous. I completely lost count. Overall, if you want to watch all of the 'Jaws' movies, I advise you skip this to 'Jaws: The Revenge' for nothing important happens in this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great idea, not done right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Dalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3-D had so much potential and it could have been the best in the series if they had done it right. The story is pure gold but unfortunately the scenes didn't go that far or break any rules. Not to mention that the 3D was awful. Another problem with this movie is that the dialogue was bad and the acting was horrible for the most part. If you want to see this movie, keep your expectations very low because you will likely be disappointed. Jaws 3-D as a whole was just mediocre as a whole but it does have some redeeming features. The things that are good about this movie are that the shark attack scenes were pretty cool and scarier than the first two and that the story is wildly original compared to the first two.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really isn't all that bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alienator Donut
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D was a satisfactory sequel with only very few flaws. The 3D visual effects were quite laughable. The plot was promising enough, it is set at Sea World, where a group of people set up an aquarium, It IS different to the other Jaws films, because Chief Brody does not make an appearance, (Even though he is often mentioned, and his sons are main characters in this film.) My personal favourite scene was the scene involving the very slow moving shark swimming to the screen with crashing into the glass window, it is later blown up! With laughable CGI special effects, and a soundtrack with a melody sounding like the Christmas song: "Joy to the world!" Jaws 3D is an entertaining enough second sequel! However, it looks like Citizen Kane, compared to its so bad it's hilarious follow up: "Jaws: The Revenge!" 6/10 Written By Alienator Donut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What, Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    suckmeoffflemwad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now Jaws 2 was a totally unnecessary sequel as I have said, however this film, Jaws 3-D is even more foul and pestilent, for starters, it lacks, and I mean it lacks, the signature shark theme from all the other films, this is what made Jaws so powerful and startling, that iconic theme. They have removed the power of the monster by replacing its theme with some bullshit merry melody, and here we barely even get to see the shark at all, I mean not like in the first, I mean in a bad way, and it kills very few people, it poses barely any threat at all, and for Christ's sake, its baby dies, and it wants revenge, sharks will eat their babies if they don't mature and scamper off quick enough, I mean seriously those idiots got even more dumb. Sharks don't have bonds, sharks are cold and emotionless, they don't take mates, and they don't care for their children a whole awful lot, they are just brainless instinctual fish, that must keep moving or they will die, this is why the geniuses in the movie put the baby in a cramped little tank, and shocked it shitless with a whole crowd of gawking people. Now this movie is very pointless, and very bad, and the way they kill the shark is pathetic, it can't swallow a guy whole for some reason when it can all those other times, and somehow he doesn't let go of his grenade, and they are able to pull the pin, I mean it just sounds utterly ridiculous. This film is horrifying and stupid in every single way, and I want to never defile my eyes by viewing it again, oh wait I just did, and saw that they used the shark theme, but still.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D The best thing about seeing a Great White Shark in 3D is that you'll look so stupid wearing those 3D glasses that it'll be too busy laughing at you to attack. However, no comical-looking headgear could keep the aquatic killer in this horror movie from ravaging you. A juvenile shark infiltrates the gates separating SeaWorld from the sea. Inside the underwater attraction, the finned-intruder begins preying on the animals and their trainers. When employees (Dennis Quaid, Bess Armstrong) go to the park manager (Louis Gossett, Jr.) with this news, he decides to profit off it. But when the mother comes looking for her pup, visitors trapped in the park's submerged tunnel system become its victims. The second sequel to Jaws, Jaws 3D is a lackluster contribution to the seafaring series that jumps the shark with this installment. Besides, SeaWorld doesn't need any outside help in killing their captive animal population. (Red Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just okay, no matter how many dimensions you see it in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even aside from the timely numerical designation of this sequel, the Jaws franchise seems like a natural for the realm of 3-D. The requisite underwater terrain alone is a perfect medium for textured dimensional rendering, and the idea of a terrifying, relentless killing machine swimming off-screen into audiences' laps is inherently awesome in and of itself. Sadly, this uneven offering never takes full advantage of its technology or its subject matter, and while it's nowhere near as bad as the truly abysmal Jaws: The Revenge (few things are), it's also nowhere near as good as the flawless original or the excellent and unfairly dismissed follow-up. Even without its potentially interesting visual ploy, Jaws 3-D has all of the ingredients to be a great sequel on paper: a stellar cast, a fresh concept, and, of course, a toothy behemoth that had already generated some of the scariest moments in screen history. These assets are ultimately squandered however. The seasoned ensemble is given very little to do, so the character studies at the heart of Jaws and Jaws 2 are bypassed entirely. The Sea World setting is woefully underused, and instead of giving our beast a novel killing ground, the park mostly functions as merely another mass of water for the action to unfold in. Worse, the shark itself isn't ever used in a suspenseful fashion, and the handful of deaths attributed to the monster are blatantly telegraphed and largely ineffective. Like many 3-D films that are stripped of their visual device for the home market, this one contains multiple scenes that may have been fun to behold on theater screens, but become utterly silly here. Floating fish heads and severed limbs bobbing with the tide might have provided cheap thrills for the opening weekend audience, but in a flat DVD representation, they simply function as camera shots that linger for far too long. The shark effects range from serviceable to downright awful, and since footage of actual sharks is utilized rather extensively, the titular titan more clearly resembles a synthetic puppet when we're seeing it at work. A couple of scenes of the creature slamming into gates and boats seem to have been created by using a plastic mock-up instead the sophisticated robotic construct that populated the first two Jaws outings, and since little effort is made to sell these moments, you can actually see the rubber shark bounce off its targets upon collision. When these flashes are integrated alongside the graceful maneuvering of real great whites, there is little symmetry between the two versions and the complete suspension of disbelief required to make a scenario like this pay off is rarely achieved. Apart from its obviousness as a prop, the shark in Jaws 3-D just isn't all that frightening because the meager body count doesn't allow it to prove itself as an insatiable murder machine. A couple of random victims are thrown in early on, but when the shark finally makes its way into the water park, where a virtual sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord of flailing legs awaits, every single person the shark pursues easily escapes its titular Jaws. Only one of the major characters gets bit during this extended sequence, and she gets away with little more than a few scratches on her leg. There are a few solid jump scares peppered throughout the film, but while the tension seems to be mounting every step of the way, the movie invariably pulls back before anything all that spectacular or horrifying occurs. Even the promising climax goes flaccid when the absolute dumbest false 3-D moment occurs, and any menace our finned antagonist has generated along the way is readily diffused by a protracted shot of her slowly floating toward the camera and breaking through a plainly animated sheet of glass. The way the shark is dispatched is particularly hard to swallow (this is actually a pretty good pun if you've seen the film), and yet another silly extended "in your face" moment caps off a tremendously underwhelming resolution. Savvy collectors will easily be able to track down readily available bootleg DVDs that retain the original 3-D presentation, but even the cleanest transfer available on the secondary market is still high-generation and extremely murky, a state which naturally strips away the potency of the visual effects. Watching my copy gave me a headache, and I had to stop about every thirty minutes or so to take off the glasses and give my eyes a rest. I eventually made it through, but when I did, all I discovered was that Jaws 3-D isn't much more impressive in its original form. The obsessive collector in me knows that if this offering ever gets a proper Blu-Ray release I will have to add it to my collection and give the film at least one more go, but the realist in me is guessing that even digitized 3-D effects won't make up for the numerous other weaknesses on hand here. There are a few effective moments here that will hold the attention of admirers of the series, but the film as a whole is a missed opportunity that can only be rightfully recommended to the most forgiving killer fish fans. An even better recommendation for those who have digested every frame of the unmatchable original and simply must have more is to skip this one entirely and give Jaws 2 another look instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Third Dimension is Terrible!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It used to be so simple to point out the bad shark movies. There was "Jaws 3" and "Jaws 4: The Revenge", and that was it pretty much! But then, as per the late nineties approximately, we literally received an overflow of inferior and quite often downright retarded killer shark flicks. And now all of a sudden, the aforementioned Jaws sequels actually don't look too terrible anymore. It started in the late 90's with the still traditional but totally inept "Deep Blue Sea" and "Shark Attack", but then since the new Millennium things really got out of control with murderous sharks popping up in the most illogical of places (like the rivers in Venice, in Tsunami infested areas, swamps, etc) and  worse even  all kinds of ridiculous hybrids and genetically altered species, like dinosaur sharks, octopus-sharks and two-headed sharks. Sigh  whatever happened to good-old fashioned massively over-sized Great Whites, like in our classic early 80's stinker "Jaws 3-D"? Now, please don't misunderstand me, the third installment in the Jaws franchise is still a very lousy film, but at least it's not bad in a frustrating or annoying way. The underdeveloped screenplay, the laughable attempt to bring depth to the main characters, the hilarious 3D effects and all the totally irrelevant padding footage  It almost feels cheesy and charming in a positive sort of way now. Interesting detail here is that Universal Studios, the mastodon production company behind the Jaws franchise, sued the creators of an obscure Italian imitation for being too reminiscent, but then they were hypocrite enough to steal ideas from the movie they accused of stealing from them! That's Hollywood for you, I guess. The script attempts, poorly I may add, to build a bridge between the previous two movies by depicting the Brody boys (the sons of Roy Scheider) as pivot characters in the grand opening of a brand new Florida Ocean theme park. Mike, the oldest one, works there as the head engineer and his younger brother Sean  supposedly still suffering from his childhood trauma even though he blindly follows the first cute girl he meets straight in the water for a nightly swimming session  comes to visit him for the ceremony. Due to malfunctioning underwater fences and unreliable technical staff, the park quickly receives unforeseen visitors in the shape of a great white shark and its offspring. Also in good old Jaws tradition, the park's senior executive initially hopes to exploit the baby shark as a unique special attraction without realizing he puts the lives of hundreds of guests and personnel in danger. When Junior White dies in front of many spectators, mommy goes on a relentless killing and destruction spree. The body count is intolerably low for a shark movie, but that's probably because all the action is concentrated in the last twenty minutes of the film. Throughout more than an hour, we're only exposed to uninteresting relationship issues, dull family conversations and a whole lot of random waterskiing footage. Most of the supportive characters are embarrassing stereotypes (an Australian outback hunter?) and the effects are hysterical even by early 80's standards. Especially the shark's ultimate attack is legendary, as he approaches the underwater control room in slow motion while the people inside just pull stupid faces.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sea World with a difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris.
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    35 feet of white teeth-gnashing terror finds itself on the wrong side of marine gates established to keep the sea from the lagoon of a Sea World resort in Florida. This third instalment in the "Jaws" family is entertaining, if somewhat tripe in its handling of the subject matter. Despite being an absurd looking shark imitation, the sight of the great dorsal fin breaking water beside oblivious skiers, together with the signature pulsating rhythm of the theme music, still manages to send shivers down the spine. The young Brody kids (Dennis Quaid and John Putch) from the first two episodes have returned, now adults enjoying some catch-up at the recently revamped Sea World Resort, where the older brother (Quaid) works alongside his love interest (Armstrong). However their merry reunion is short-lived when a young Great White shark is discovered in the waterpark's lagoon. After an attempt to catch and conserve the shark in captivity fails, they soon discover that mother is also in the park, and not at all pleased at the exploitation of junior. Despite some amateurish-looking performances in the minor roles, and the occasional inane dialogue, this remains a mostly suspenseful and exciting third entry in the quartet, still capable of invoking a primal fear of the water. And in case you were wondering, there's a particularly graphic attack scene and aftermath (check out the inventive make-up effects employed) that should impress.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please Tap on This Glass. Repeatedly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oy vey. I actually defended Jaws 2. Did that come back to bite me on the ass for the horror Jaws 3D was? And just to clear up my last statement: I meant horror as in HORRIBLE MOVIE and not a suspenseful scarefest. At any rate, Jaws 3D is so bad, so full of its gimmick of "3D"  which was NO WHERE NEAR new in 1983, by the way  that they actually turned the one-hit-wonder (the original, 1975's Jaws) into a jokefest. Sad. The one positive thing I can say about it, is that they really paved the way for Piranha 3DTWENTY-SEVEN YEARS LATER in 2010as there's a lot here that they held back on  it was Rated PG for some strange reason  that Piranha 3D took to the next level, or twenty. Seaworld's under attack by not one, but TWO sharks this time. Way to step it up from the previous "wimpy" films in the franchise that only involved one shark each. Somehow, without any investigation, its deemed the two sharks are parent and child. But, that's neither here, nor there. It's all about the fake 3D carnage. Really, I don't want to waste too much more time on this mess. I can even safely say, the Director and Writer feels the same way: they made a mess of poo and continuously wrote themselves into corners. There is no redeemable reasons to see this movie. Nothing that stands out, such as the "Okay, it's bad, but you gotta see this" scene. Of course, that makes me conclude with: You think this is bad? Wait until the next installment  I mean, who the *BLEEP* believed so deeply in this series, by this point, that they green lit the abomination that was to follow?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3-D This Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set several years after the events of Part II, Chief Brody's sons Mike & Sean(Roy Scheider did not return) are now young adults at Sea World in Florida, where yet another killer great white shark emerges, trying to track down its baby, who is being kept there and studied. Scientists and hunters must team up to defeat this menace before it kills the incoming tourists... Now in(shoddy) 3-D, this film is just inept, with a ridiculous, uninspired plot, poor science regarding sharks, and no story involvement whatsoever. Utterly devoid of a point, just a blatant cash-in on the title and resurgent popularity of 3-D(Third Jaws film in 3-D, clever no?) A bust.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Mockery To The 'Jaws' Name
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movieman
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3 has to be the worst movie I've ever seen in my whole life. If I could rate it 0 stars then I would. I didn't believe one bit that there was a shark in the waters, even though I did i Jaws 1 and 2. Firstly, the special effects were so out of date. In the dolphin scene, were they first saw the shark, when you see the Great White for the first time, I found that they just stole the footage from an old National Geographic Documentary. Secondly, this movie was full of sexual references. For example, Sean Brody says to his older brother Michael Brody, "I was so close to doing it in the water last night." after doing something inappropriate at the beach the previous night. Finally, the amount of shark facts they got wrong was just tremendous. I completely lost count. Overall, if you want to watch all of the 'Jaws' movies, I advise you skip this to 'Jaws: The Revenge' for nothing important happens in this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great idea, not done right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Dalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3-D had so much potential and it could have been the best in the series if they had done it right. The story is pure gold but unfortunately the scenes didn't go that far or break any rules. Not to mention that the 3D was awful. Another problem with this movie is that the dialogue was bad and the acting was horrible for the most part. If you want to see this movie, keep your expectations very low because you will likely be disappointed. Jaws 3-D as a whole was just mediocre as a whole but it does have some redeeming features. The things that are good about this movie are that the shark attack scenes were pretty cool and scarier than the first two and that the story is wildly original compared to the first two.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really isn't all that bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alienator Donut
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D was a satisfactory sequel with only very few flaws. The 3D visual effects were quite laughable. The plot was promising enough, it is set at Sea World, where a group of people set up an aquarium, It IS different to the other Jaws films, because Chief Brody does not make an appearance, (Even though he is often mentioned, and his sons are main characters in this film.) My personal favourite scene was the scene involving the very slow moving shark swimming to the screen with crashing into the glass window, it is later blown up! With laughable CGI special effects, and a soundtrack with a melody sounding like the Christmas song: "Joy to the world!" Jaws 3D is an entertaining enough second sequel! However, it looks like Citizen Kane, compared to its so bad it's hilarious follow up: "Jaws: The Revenge!" 6/10 Written By Alienator Donut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What, Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    suckmeoffflemwad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now Jaws 2 was a totally unnecessary sequel as I have said, however this film, Jaws 3-D is even more foul and pestilent, for starters, it lacks, and I mean it lacks, the signature shark theme from all the other films, this is what made Jaws so powerful and startling, that iconic theme. They have removed the power of the monster by replacing its theme with some bullshit merry melody, and here we barely even get to see the shark at all, I mean not like in the first, I mean in a bad way, and it kills very few people, it poses barely any threat at all, and for Christ's sake, its baby dies, and it wants revenge, sharks will eat their babies if they don't mature and scamper off quick enough, I mean seriously those idiots got even more dumb. Sharks don't have bonds, sharks are cold and emotionless, they don't take mates, and they don't care for their children a whole awful lot, they are just brainless instinctual fish, that must keep moving or they will die, this is why the geniuses in the movie put the baby in a cramped little tank, and shocked it shitless with a whole crowd of gawking people. Now this movie is very pointless, and very bad, and the way they kill the shark is pathetic, it can't swallow a guy whole for some reason when it can all those other times, and somehow he doesn't let go of his grenade, and they are able to pull the pin, I mean it just sounds utterly ridiculous. This film is horrifying and stupid in every single way, and I want to never defile my eyes by viewing it again, oh wait I just did, and saw that they used the shark theme, but still.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D The best thing about seeing a Great White Shark in 3D is that you'll look so stupid wearing those 3D glasses that it'll be too busy laughing at you to attack. However, no comical-looking headgear could keep the aquatic killer in this horror movie from ravaging you. A juvenile shark infiltrates the gates separating SeaWorld from the sea. Inside the underwater attraction, the finned-intruder begins preying on the animals and their trainers. When employees (Dennis Quaid, Bess Armstrong) go to the park manager (Louis Gossett, Jr.) with this news, he decides to profit off it. But when the mother comes looking for her pup, visitors trapped in the park's submerged tunnel system become its victims. The second sequel to Jaws, Jaws 3D is a lackluster contribution to the seafaring series that jumps the shark with this installment. Besides, SeaWorld doesn't need any outside help in killing their captive animal population. (Red Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just okay, no matter how many dimensions you see it in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even aside from the timely numerical designation of this sequel, the Jaws franchise seems like a natural for the realm of 3-D. The requisite underwater terrain alone is a perfect medium for textured dimensional rendering, and the idea of a terrifying, relentless killing machine swimming off-screen into audiences' laps is inherently awesome in and of itself. Sadly, this uneven offering never takes full advantage of its technology or its subject matter, and while it's nowhere near as bad as the truly abysmal Jaws: The Revenge (few things are), it's also nowhere near as good as the flawless original or the excellent and unfairly dismissed follow-up. Even without its potentially interesting visual ploy, Jaws 3-D has all of the ingredients to be a great sequel on paper: a stellar cast, a fresh concept, and, of course, a toothy behemoth that had already generated some of the scariest moments in screen history. These assets are ultimately squandered however. The seasoned ensemble is given very little to do, so the character studies at the heart of Jaws and Jaws 2 are bypassed entirely. The Sea World setting is woefully underused, and instead of giving our beast a novel killing ground, the park mostly functions as merely another mass of water for the action to unfold in. Worse, the shark itself isn't ever used in a suspenseful fashion, and the handful of deaths attributed to the monster are blatantly telegraphed and largely ineffective. Like many 3-D films that are stripped of their visual device for the home market, this one contains multiple scenes that may have been fun to behold on theater screens, but become utterly silly here. Floating fish heads and severed limbs bobbing with the tide might have provided cheap thrills for the opening weekend audience, but in a flat DVD representation, they simply function as camera shots that linger for far too long. The shark effects range from serviceable to downright awful, and since footage of actual sharks is utilized rather extensively, the titular titan more clearly resembles a synthetic puppet when we're seeing it at work. A couple of scenes of the creature slamming into gates and boats seem to have been created by using a plastic mock-up instead the sophisticated robotic construct that populated the first two Jaws outings, and since little effort is made to sell these moments, you can actually see the rubber shark bounce off its targets upon collision. When these flashes are integrated alongside the graceful maneuvering of real great whites, there is little symmetry between the two versions and the complete suspension of disbelief required to make a scenario like this pay off is rarely achieved. Apart from its obviousness as a prop, the shark in Jaws 3-D just isn't all that frightening because the meager body count doesn't allow it to prove itself as an insatiable murder machine. A couple of random victims are thrown in early on, but when the shark finally makes its way into the water park, where a virtual sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord of flailing legs awaits, every single person the shark pursues easily escapes its titular Jaws. Only one of the major characters gets bit during this extended sequence, and she gets away with little more than a few scratches on her leg. There are a few solid jump scares peppered throughout the film, but while the tension seems to be mounting every step of the way, the movie invariably pulls back before anything all that spectacular or horrifying occurs. Even the promising climax goes flaccid when the absolute dumbest false 3-D moment occurs, and any menace our finned antagonist has generated along the way is readily diffused by a protracted shot of her slowly floating toward the camera and breaking through a plainly animated sheet of glass. The way the shark is dispatched is particularly hard to swallow (this is actually a pretty good pun if you've seen the film), and yet another silly extended "in your face" moment caps off a tremendously underwhelming resolution. Savvy collectors will easily be able to track down readily available bootleg DVDs that retain the original 3-D presentation, but even the cleanest transfer available on the secondary market is still high-generation and extremely murky, a state which naturally strips away the potency of the visual effects. Watching my copy gave me a headache, and I had to stop about every thirty minutes or so to take off the glasses and give my eyes a rest. I eventually made it through, but when I did, all I discovered was that Jaws 3-D isn't much more impressive in its original form. The obsessive collector in me knows that if this offering ever gets a proper Blu-Ray release I will have to add it to my collection and give the film at least one more go, but the realist in me is guessing that even digitized 3-D effects won't make up for the numerous other weaknesses on hand here. There are a few effective moments here that will hold the attention of admirers of the series, but the film as a whole is a missed opportunity that can only be rightfully recommended to the most forgiving killer fish fans. An even better recommendation for those who have digested every frame of the unmatchable original and simply must have more is to skip this one entirely and give Jaws 2 another look instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Third Dimension is Terrible!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It used to be so simple to point out the bad shark movies. There was "Jaws 3" and "Jaws 4: The Revenge", and that was it pretty much! But then, as per the late nineties approximately, we literally received an overflow of inferior and quite often downright retarded killer shark flicks. And now all of a sudden, the aforementioned Jaws sequels actually don't look too terrible anymore. It started in the late 90's with the still traditional but totally inept "Deep Blue Sea" and "Shark Attack", but then since the new Millennium things really got out of control with murderous sharks popping up in the most illogical of places (like the rivers in Venice, in Tsunami infested areas, swamps, etc) and  worse even  all kinds of ridiculous hybrids and genetically altered species, like dinosaur sharks, octopus-sharks and two-headed sharks. Sigh  whatever happened to good-old fashioned massively over-sized Great Whites, like in our classic early 80's stinker "Jaws 3-D"? Now, please don't misunderstand me, the third installment in the Jaws franchise is still a very lousy film, but at least it's not bad in a frustrating or annoying way. The underdeveloped screenplay, the laughable attempt to bring depth to the main characters, the hilarious 3D effects and all the totally irrelevant padding footage  It almost feels cheesy and charming in a positive sort of way now. Interesting detail here is that Universal Studios, the mastodon production company behind the Jaws franchise, sued the creators of an obscure Italian imitation for being too reminiscent, but then they were hypocrite enough to steal ideas from the movie they accused of stealing from them! That's Hollywood for you, I guess. The script attempts, poorly I may add, to build a bridge between the previous two movies by depicting the Brody boys (the sons of Roy Scheider) as pivot characters in the grand opening of a brand new Florida Ocean theme park. Mike, the oldest one, works there as the head engineer and his younger brother Sean  supposedly still suffering from his childhood trauma even though he blindly follows the first cute girl he meets straight in the water for a nightly swimming session  comes to visit him for the ceremony. Due to malfunctioning underwater fences and unreliable technical staff, the park quickly receives unforeseen visitors in the shape of a great white shark and its offspring. Also in good old Jaws tradition, the park's senior executive initially hopes to exploit the baby shark as a unique special attraction without realizing he puts the lives of hundreds of guests and personnel in danger. When Junior White dies in front of many spectators, mommy goes on a relentless killing and destruction spree. The body count is intolerably low for a shark movie, but that's probably because all the action is concentrated in the last twenty minutes of the film. Throughout more than an hour, we're only exposed to uninteresting relationship issues, dull family conversations and a whole lot of random waterskiing footage. Most of the supportive characters are embarrassing stereotypes (an Australian outback hunter?) and the effects are hysterical even by early 80's standards. Especially the shark's ultimate attack is legendary, as he approaches the underwater control room in slow motion while the people inside just pull stupid faces.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sea World with a difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris.
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    35 feet of white teeth-gnashing terror finds itself on the wrong side of marine gates established to keep the sea from the lagoon of a Sea World resort in Florida. This third instalment in the "Jaws" family is entertaining, if somewhat tripe in its handling of the subject matter. Despite being an absurd looking shark imitation, the sight of the great dorsal fin breaking water beside oblivious skiers, together with the signature pulsating rhythm of the theme music, still manages to send shivers down the spine. The young Brody kids (Dennis Quaid and John Putch) from the first two episodes have returned, now adults enjoying some catch-up at the recently revamped Sea World Resort, where the older brother (Quaid) works alongside his love interest (Armstrong). However their merry reunion is short-lived when a young Great White shark is discovered in the waterpark's lagoon. After an attempt to catch and conserve the shark in captivity fails, they soon discover that mother is also in the park, and not at all pleased at the exploitation of junior. Despite some amateurish-looking performances in the minor roles, and the occasional inane dialogue, this remains a mostly suspenseful and exciting third entry in the quartet, still capable of invoking a primal fear of the water. And in case you were wondering, there's a particularly graphic attack scene and aftermath (check out the inventive make-up effects employed) that should impress.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please Tap on This Glass. Repeatedly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oy vey. I actually defended Jaws 2. Did that come back to bite me on the ass for the horror Jaws 3D was? And just to clear up my last statement: I meant horror as in HORRIBLE MOVIE and not a suspenseful scarefest. At any rate, Jaws 3D is so bad, so full of its gimmick of "3D"  which was NO WHERE NEAR new in 1983, by the way  that they actually turned the one-hit-wonder (the original, 1975's Jaws) into a jokefest. Sad. The one positive thing I can say about it, is that they really paved the way for Piranha 3DTWENTY-SEVEN YEARS LATER in 2010as there's a lot here that they held back on  it was Rated PG for some strange reason  that Piranha 3D took to the next level, or twenty. Seaworld's under attack by not one, but TWO sharks this time. Way to step it up from the previous "wimpy" films in the franchise that only involved one shark each. Somehow, without any investigation, its deemed the two sharks are parent and child. But, that's neither here, nor there. It's all about the fake 3D carnage. Really, I don't want to waste too much more time on this mess. I can even safely say, the Director and Writer feels the same way: they made a mess of poo and continuously wrote themselves into corners. There is no redeemable reasons to see this movie. Nothing that stands out, such as the "Okay, it's bad, but you gotta see this" scene. Of course, that makes me conclude with: You think this is bad? Wait until the next installment  I mean, who the *BLEEP* believed so deeply in this series, by this point, that they green lit the abomination that was to follow?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    3-D This Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set several years after the events of Part II, Chief Brody's sons Mike & Sean(Roy Scheider did not return) are now young adults at Sea World in Florida, where yet another killer great white shark emerges, trying to track down its baby, who is being kept there and studied. Scientists and hunters must team up to defeat this menace before it kills the incoming tourists... Now in(shoddy) 3-D, this film is just inept, with a ridiculous, uninspired plot, poor science regarding sharks, and no story involvement whatsoever. Utterly devoid of a point, just a blatant cash-in on the title and resurgent popularity of 3-D(Third Jaws film in 3-D, clever no?) A bust.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Mockery To The 'Jaws' Name
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movieman
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3 has to be the worst movie I've ever seen in my whole life. If I could rate it 0 stars then I would. I didn't believe one bit that there was a shark in the waters, even though I did i Jaws 1 and 2. Firstly, the special effects were so out of date. In the dolphin scene, were they first saw the shark, when you see the Great White for the first time, I found that they just stole the footage from an old National Geographic Documentary. Secondly, this movie was full of sexual references. For example, Sean Brody says to his older brother Michael Brody, "I was so close to doing it in the water last night." after doing something inappropriate at the beach the previous night. Finally, the amount of shark facts they got wrong was just tremendous. I completely lost count. Overall, if you want to watch all of the 'Jaws' movies, I advise you skip this to 'Jaws: The Revenge' for nothing important happens in this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great idea, not done right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Dalton
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3-D had so much potential and it could have been the best in the series if they had done it right. The story is pure gold but unfortunately the scenes didn't go that far or break any rules. Not to mention that the 3D was awful. Another problem with this movie is that the dialogue was bad and the acting was horrible for the most part. If you want to see this movie, keep your expectations very low because you will likely be disappointed. Jaws 3-D as a whole was just mediocre as a whole but it does have some redeeming features. The things that are good about this movie are that the shark attack scenes were pretty cool and scarier than the first two and that the story is wildly original compared to the first two.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It really isn't all that bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alienator Donut
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D was a satisfactory sequel with only very few flaws. The 3D visual effects were quite laughable. The plot was promising enough, it is set at Sea World, where a group of people set up an aquarium, It IS different to the other Jaws films, because Chief Brody does not make an appearance, (Even though he is often mentioned, and his sons are main characters in this film.) My personal favourite scene was the scene involving the very slow moving shark swimming to the screen with crashing into the glass window, it is later blown up! With laughable CGI special effects, and a soundtrack with a melody sounding like the Christmas song: "Joy to the world!" Jaws 3D is an entertaining enough second sequel! However, it looks like Citizen Kane, compared to its so bad it's hilarious follow up: "Jaws: The Revenge!" 6/10 Written By Alienator Donut.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What, Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    suckmeoffflemwad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now Jaws 2 was a totally unnecessary sequel as I have said, however this film, Jaws 3-D is even more foul and pestilent, for starters, it lacks, and I mean it lacks, the signature shark theme from all the other films, this is what made Jaws so powerful and startling, that iconic theme. They have removed the power of the monster by replacing its theme with some bullshit merry melody, and here we barely even get to see the shark at all, I mean not like in the first, I mean in a bad way, and it kills very few people, it poses barely any threat at all, and for Christ's sake, its baby dies, and it wants revenge, sharks will eat their babies if they don't mature and scamper off quick enough, I mean seriously those idiots got even more dumb. Sharks don't have bonds, sharks are cold and emotionless, they don't take mates, and they don't care for their children a whole awful lot, they are just brainless instinctual fish, that must keep moving or they will die, this is why the geniuses in the movie put the baby in a cramped little tank, and shocked it shitless with a whole crowd of gawking people. Now this movie is very pointless, and very bad, and the way they kill the shark is pathetic, it can't swallow a guy whole for some reason when it can all those other times, and somehow he doesn't let go of his grenade, and they are able to pull the pin, I mean it just sounds utterly ridiculous. This film is horrifying and stupid in every single way, and I want to never defile my eyes by viewing it again, oh wait I just did, and saw that they used the shark theme, but still.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jaws 3D The best thing about seeing a Great White Shark in 3D is that you'll look so stupid wearing those 3D glasses that it'll be too busy laughing at you to attack. However, no comical-looking headgear could keep the aquatic killer in this horror movie from ravaging you. A juvenile shark infiltrates the gates separating SeaWorld from the sea. Inside the underwater attraction, the finned-intruder begins preying on the animals and their trainers. When employees (Dennis Quaid, Bess Armstrong) go to the park manager (Louis Gossett, Jr.) with this news, he decides to profit off it. But when the mother comes looking for her pup, visitors trapped in the park's submerged tunnel system become its victims. The second sequel to Jaws, Jaws 3D is a lackluster contribution to the seafaring series that jumps the shark with this installment. Besides, SeaWorld doesn't need any outside help in killing their captive animal population. (Red Light) vidiotreviews.blogspot.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just okay, no matter how many dimensions you see it in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even aside from the timely numerical designation of this sequel, the Jaws franchise seems like a natural for the realm of 3-D. The requisite underwater terrain alone is a perfect medium for textured dimensional rendering, and the idea of a terrifying, relentless killing machine swimming off-screen into audiences' laps is inherently awesome in and of itself. Sadly, this uneven offering never takes full advantage of its technology or its subject matter, and while it's nowhere near as bad as the truly abysmal Jaws: The Revenge (few things are), it's also nowhere near as good as the flawless original or the excellent and unfairly dismissed follow-up. Even without its potentially interesting visual ploy, Jaws 3-D has all of the ingredients to be a great sequel on paper: a stellar cast, a fresh concept, and, of course, a toothy behemoth that had already generated some of the scariest moments in screen history. These assets are ultimately squandered however. The seasoned ensemble is given very little to do, so the character studies at the heart of Jaws and Jaws 2 are bypassed entirely. The Sea World setting is woefully underused, and instead of giving our beast a novel killing ground, the park mostly functions as merely another mass of water for the action to unfold in. Worse, the shark itself isn't ever used in a suspenseful fashion, and the handful of deaths attributed to the monster are blatantly telegraphed and largely ineffective. Like many 3-D films that are stripped of their visual device for the home market, this one contains multiple scenes that may have been fun to behold on theater screens, but become utterly silly here. Floating fish heads and severed limbs bobbing with the tide might have provided cheap thrills for the opening weekend audience, but in a flat DVD representation, they simply function as camera shots that linger for far too long. The shark effects range from serviceable to downright awful, and since footage of actual sharks is utilized rather extensively, the titular titan more clearly resembles a synthetic puppet when we're seeing it at work. A couple of scenes of the creature slamming into gates and boats seem to have been created by using a plastic mock-up instead the sophisticated robotic construct that populated the first two Jaws outings, and since little effort is made to sell these moments, you can actually see the rubber shark bounce off its targets upon collision. When these flashes are integrated alongside the graceful maneuvering of real great whites, there is little symmetry between the two versions and the complete suspension of disbelief required to make a scenario like this pay off is rarely achieved. Apart from its obviousness as a prop, the shark in Jaws 3-D just isn't all that frightening because the meager body count doesn't allow it to prove itself as an insatiable murder machine. A couple of random victims are thrown in early on, but when the shark finally makes its way into the water park, where a virtual sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord of flailing legs awaits, every single person the shark pursues easily escapes its titular Jaws. Only one of the major characters gets bit during this extended sequence, and she gets away with little more than a few scratches on her leg. There are a few solid jump scares peppered throughout the film, but while the tension seems to be mounting every step of the way, the movie invariably pulls back before anything all that spectacular or horrifying occurs. Even the promising climax goes flaccid when the absolute dumbest false 3-D moment occurs, and any menace our finned antagonist has generated along the way is readily diffused by a protracted shot of her slowly floating toward the camera and breaking through a plainly animated sheet of glass. The way the shark is dispatched is particularly hard to swallow (this is actually a pretty good pun if you've seen the film), and yet another silly extended "in your face" moment caps off a tremendously underwhelming resolution. Savvy collectors will easily be able to track down readily available bootleg DVDs that retain the original 3-D presentation, but even the cleanest transfer available on the secondary market is still high-generation and extremely murky, a state which naturally strips away the potency of the visual effects. Watching my copy gave me a headache, and I had to stop about every thirty minutes or so to take off the glasses and give my eyes a rest. I eventually made it through, but when I did, all I discovered was that Jaws 3-D isn't much more impressive in its original form. The obsessive collector in me knows that if this offering ever gets a proper Blu-Ray release I will have to add it to my collection and give the film at least one more go, but the realist in me is guessing that even digitized 3-D effects won't make up for the numerous other weaknesses on hand here. There are a few effective moments here that will hold the attention of admirers of the series, but the film as a whole is a missed opportunity that can only be rightfully recommended to the most forgiving killer fish fans. An even better recommendation for those who have digested every frame of the unmatchable original and simply must have more is to skip this one entirely and give Jaws 2 another look instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Third Dimension is Terrible!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It used to be so simple to point out the bad shark movies. There was "Jaws 3" and "Jaws 4: The Revenge", and that was it pretty much! But then, as per the late nineties approximately, we literally received an overflow of inferior and quite often downright retarded killer shark flicks. And now all of a sudden, the aforementioned Jaws sequels actually don't look too terrible anymore. It started in the late 90's with the still traditional but totally inept "Deep Blue Sea" and "Shark Attack", but then since the new Millennium things really got out of control with murderous sharks popping up in the most illogical of places (like the rivers in Venice, in Tsunami infested areas, swamps, etc) and  worse even  all kinds of ridiculous hybrids and genetically altered species, like dinosaur sharks, octopus-sharks and two-headed sharks. Sigh  whatever happened to good-old fashioned massively over-sized Great Whites, like in our classic early 80's stinker "Jaws 3-D"? Now, please don't misunderstand me, the third installment in the Jaws franchise is still a very lousy film, but at least it's not bad in a frustrating or annoying way. The underdeveloped screenplay, the laughable attempt to bring depth to the main characters, the hilarious 3D effects and all the totally irrelevant padding footage  It almost feels cheesy and charming in a positive sort of way now. Interesting detail here is that Universal Studios, the mastodon production company behind the Jaws franchise, sued the creators of an obscure Italian imitation for being too reminiscent, but then they were hypocrite enough to steal ideas from the movie they accused of stealing from them! That's Hollywood for you, I guess. The script attempts, poorly I may add, to build a bridge between the previous two movies by depicting the Brody boys (the sons of Roy Scheider) as pivot characters in the grand opening of a brand new Florida Ocean theme park. Mike, the oldest one, works there as the head engineer and his younger brother Sean  supposedly still suffering from his childhood trauma even though he blindly follows the first cute girl he meets straight in the water for a nightly swimming session  comes to visit him for the ceremony. Due to malfunctioning underwater fences and unreliable technical staff, the park quickly receives unforeseen visitors in the shape of a great white shark and its offspring. Also in good old Jaws tradition, the park's senior executive initially hopes to exploit the baby shark as a unique special attraction without realizing he puts the lives of hundreds of guests and personnel in danger. When Junior White dies in front of many spectators, mommy goes on a relentless killing and destruction spree. The body count is intolerably low for a shark movie, but that's probably because all the action is concentrated in the last twenty minutes of the film. Throughout more than an hour, we're only exposed to uninteresting relationship issues, dull family conversations and a whole lot of random waterskiing footage. Most of the supportive characters are embarrassing stereotypes (an Australian outback hunter?) and the effects are hysterical even by early 80's standards. Especially the shark's ultimate attack is legendary, as he approaches the underwater control room in slow motion while the people inside just pull stupid faces.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sea World with a difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris.
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    35 feet of white teeth-gnashing terror finds itself on the wrong side of marine gates established to keep the sea from the lagoon of a Sea World resort in Florida. This third instalment in the "Jaws" family is entertaining, if somewhat tripe in its handling of the subject matter. Despite being an absurd looking shark imitation, the sight of the great dorsal fin breaking water beside oblivious skiers, together with the signature pulsating rhythm of the theme music, still manages to send shivers down the spine. The young Brody kids (Dennis Quaid and John Putch) from the first two episodes have returned, now adults enjoying some catch-up at the recently revamped Sea World Resort, where the older brother (Quaid) works alongside his love interest (Armstrong). However their merry reunion is short-lived when a young Great White shark is discovered in the waterpark's lagoon. After an attempt to catch and conserve the shark in captivity fails, they soon discover that mother is also in the park, and not at all pleased at the exploitation of junior. Despite some amateurish-looking performances in the minor roles, and the occasional inane dialogue, this remains a mostly suspenseful and exciting third entry in the quartet, still capable of invoking a primal fear of the water. And in case you were wondering, there's a particularly graphic attack scene and aftermath (check out the inventive make-up effects employed) that should impress.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please Tap on This Glass. Repeatedly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oy vey. I actually defended Jaws 2. Did that come back to bite me on the ass for the horror Jaws 3D was? And just to clear up my last statement: I meant horror as in HORRIBLE MOVIE and not a suspenseful scarefest. At any rate, Jaws 3D is so bad, so full of its gimmick of "3D"  which was NO WHERE NEAR new in 1983, by the way  that they actually turned the one-hit-wonder (the original, 1975's Jaws) into a jokefest. Sad. The one positive thing I can say about it, is that they really paved the way for Piranha 3DTWENTY-SEVEN YEARS LATER in 2010as there's a lot here that they held back on  it was Rated PG for some strange reason  that Piranha 3D took to the next level, or twenty. Seaworld's under attack by not one, but TWO sharks this time. Way to step it up from the previous "wimpy" films in the franchise that only involved one shark each. Somehow, without any investigation, its deemed the two sharks are parent and child. But, that's neither here, nor there. It's all about the fake 3D carnage. Really, I don't want to waste too much more time on this mess. I can even safely say, the Director and Writer feels the same way: they made a mess of poo and continuously wrote themselves into corners. There is no redeemable reasons to see this movie. Nothing that stands out, such as the "Okay, it's bad, but you gotta see this" scene. Of course, that makes me conclude with: You think this is bad? Wait until the next installment  I mean, who the *BLEEP* believed so deeply in this series, by this point, that they green lit the abomination that was to follow?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
