<filme>
 <id>
  454
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115633
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Marcas do Sil&ecirc;ncio
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Difficult tale of poor, struggling South Carolinian mother & daughter, who each face painful choices with their resolve and pride. Bone, the eldest daughter, and Anney her tired mother, ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Difficult tale of poor, struggling South Carolinian mother & daughter, who each face painful choices with their resolve and pride. Bone, the eldest daughter, and Anney her tired mother, grow both closer and farther apart: Anney sees Glen as her last chance.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   starving child
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bottle smashed over someone's head
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   beating
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   compassion
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   childhood trauma
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Anjelica Huston
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Dorothy Allison
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Anne Meredith
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jennifer Jason Leigh
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ron Eldard
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Glenne Headly
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story takes place in (I'm guessing) the 1930s in the deep south. Anney (Jennifer Jason Leigh) is an unwed mother with two girls the oldest being Ruthann (Jena Malone). She meets handsome lively Glen (Ron Eldard) and marries him. But Glen has a bad temper and beats Ruthann regularly. Her mother doesn't know it and Glen keeps getting angrier and angrier. VERY disturbing but well-done movie. The actors all fake authentic Southern accents and it captures the era perfectly. The acting is just incredible. Leigh was just letter perfect as the mother. She does love her girls and her husband and is horrified when she realizes what's going on. Eldard was a little one-note in his performance but that was mostly cause the script didn't really explore his character. He was downright terrifying when he loses control a few times. Malone was only 10 when she did this and she was incredible! VERY talented for such a young child and holds her own especially in downright horrific sequence at the end. Even the supporting roles were well-acted with Michael Rooker and Glenne Headly being standouts. Also it's all narrated by Laura Dern. As for the beatings--they're never really shown until the very end. You HEAR them though and that's bad enough. The acting is so good by Malone and Eldard you believe every second of them. One complaint--the movie feels unfinished. It looks like either a lot was cut out of the script or out of the movie. Some scenes come and go quickly and have characters you've never met. Still this is well worth watching...but it is disturbing (as it should be) and powerful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strong Performances and Direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bastard Out of Carolina (1996) *** (out of 4) Graphic adaptation of the Dorothy Allison novel takes place in the South Carolina as a young girl (Jena Malone) begins to be physically and sexually abused by her stepfather (Ron Eldard) while her mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh) keeps overlooking what's going on. BASTARD OUT OF CAROLINA was the directorial debut from Anjelica Huston and while I'd question some of the flow in the story there's no question that she dives head first into the abuse and doesn't pull any punches. This here is a pretty hard film to watch because of how graphic it is towards the abuse in the film. I was really shocked at how much detail was shown when it came to the abuse because most of the time the camera pulls away with a child involved but that wasn't the case here. It's clear that Huston wanted to show how horrid the abuse of a child was and this here was shown and it certainly wasn't easy to watch. The film really benefits from some incredibly strong performances with Malone leading the way as the abused girl. She's completely believable in the part and it was certainly needed because the actress really makes you feel that she's this smart little girl being forced to grow up quickly because of her situation. Jennfier Jason Leigh also turns in a powerful performance as the mother who can't leave her husband even though he's hurting her daughter. Eldard is a complete slime here and perfectly captures the spirit of the character. We also get strong supporting performances by Michael Rooker, Lyle Lovett, Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diane Scarwid and Pat Hingle. Christina Ricci appears in one scene. I think there were times when the film didn't flow as good as it could have but there's no question that Huston gets her message across. The film is hard to recommend to most people due to how depressing and graphic it is but those who do sit through the film will be rewarded with a strong picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unnecessarily praised.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aslowriot
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film delves deeply into the subject of child abuse. Jena Malone's character, Bone, is a young girl who suffers through horrific acts of violence perpetrated by her mother's husband who is not her paternal father. The depravity of the film spans beyond the child abuse it features. Despite the remarkable cast and their outstanding performances, the film raises issues which it never confronts or resolves. The film is nothing more than a portrait of a despicable life, without any hope or resolution to be found within the context. Simply put, a daughter suffers immense cruelty at the hands of her mother's husband, and rather than fight for the maternal bond between mother and daughter, the mother decides to abandon her daughter for the love she finds from her husband who has abused her daughter. This film hardly even rises to the level of a documentary, in which case you might expect the depiction of depravity to be senseless and obscene. Instead the film raises a litany of questions for which it offers no answers. Why does the mother continually disregard the abuse she is fully aware her daughter is suffering at the hands of her husband? Does the mother have any concern for the chances of her younger daughter being subjected to the same abuse from her husband? Is severing the relationship between both daughters to be considered healthy? Is abandoning her abused daughter the mother's misconceived idea as to how to make amends? What is accomplished or signified by the abused daughter's refusal to name her abuser, purely out of inescapable love for her mother who doesn't protect her? How does the abused and then abandoned daughter relate to the world around her and how will she in the future? With utmost respect to the acting talents of the cast, the few undeveloped phrases that are stated, which one hopes will provide insight into the questions raised by the film, fail to suffice in properly addressing the base topics depicted. One could easily glean from a department of children and families case file the same pain, revulsion, and sorrow this film presents. Quite disappointing, but highly recommended to those film viewers who enjoy or are satisfied with dismal portrayals of tragedy which offer nothing in the way of redemption or adequate depiction of the subject matter at hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This story is so southern.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ttratar21
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched this movie on Lifetime, and was reminded of my time living in the south. When I was living in the south, time after time, I would see a husband who was a total scumbag, and his wife would never leave him. In other parts of the United States there would be a separation instantly. But in the South Women are afraid to stand up to their man. This movie was tough to watch. This little girl was severely abused, and molested by her step- father, and her mother refused to do anything about it. When she told her daughter at the end of the movie that she still Love's Glen, I was sick to my stomach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bastard out of Carolina
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lyndsay Page
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece.It deals with a touchy subject. The actors and actresses play there parts so well. You can actually see the sadness in Malone and the hate in Eldard's face. Its sad because things like this happen all the time. This movie is not some fake movie that someone made up in there head. Its truth this does happen to people. And its sad because Leigh's character as the lonely mother is real there are mothers out there that are stuck between loving there child or there lover. Its a sad situation and this movie shows you life. This movie is for sure excellent 10 stars from me. I would recommend this movie to anyone who likes serious movies that just have you on the edge of your seat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Messy Southern Gothic with too many characters and a lumpy narrative...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston, an unequivocally wise and intuitive actress, takes on a dark, rambling Southern tale for her first directorial effort, an adaptation of Dorothy Allison's book with so many peaks and valleys it plays like a chopped up TV mini-series, the CliffsNotes version. Story centers on an illegitimate young girl (Jena Malone) in the South during the 1950s and her woebegone waitress-mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who has had terrible luck with men. Seems her third husband (Ron Eldard) has a violent streak when provoked, and when he begins lashing out at the child in both violent and sexual ways, relatives step in to help her. Rare to find a cast so full of solid acting talent, yet this script takes great pains to introduce characters without giving them anything to do (some of the relatives, like the uptown cousin played by Christina Ricci or Dermot Mulroney's doomed Husband #2, appear and disappear in record time). The central performances are fine, with pre-teen Malone doing some very nice work; a child actress with a solemn reserve and faraway eyes, Malone is perhaps too studied in her approach (she isn't an untrained natural), yet Huston handles her gently and some of the strongest moments are the ones where Malone is allowed to take a breath and emote. However, this film, a failed theatrical effort which was sold instead to cable television, is packed (or padded, as it were) with short-hand tragedy, and the editing is so poor and the narrative so confusing you might need a scorecard to keep up with all the melodrama. Despite her sensitivity in staging some shattering scenes, Huston doesn't allow the picture to flow, to absorb the audience. It's jagged and piqued, and one recoils from it instead of being drawn into the plot. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful, disturbing, heinous is the human stain.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston's directorial debut is based on a novel by Dorothy Allison. A potent, emotional driven drama deep in the ways of poor South Carolina. It is post-WWII and a young Anney Boatwright(Jennifer Jason Leigh)gives birth to an illegitimate child. She names her baby Ruth Anne(Jena Malone), but she will be known as 'Bone'. Life is difficult for the struggling waitress, who has another daughter and is forced to bury a husband(Dermot Mulroney)killed in an auto accident. Anney's brother Earle(Michael Rooker)introduces her to her future...Glen Waddell(Ron Eldard). The two marry, but soon Glen starts taking his anger out on 'Bone'. The bonds between mother and daughter will become dangerously strained when Anney finds her husband raping 'Bone'. This following the constant violent physical abuse of the child behind her mother's back. There is a strong ensemble cast, but the young Malone is brilliant beyond her age. Other players: Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diana Scarwid, Lyle Lovett, Christina Ricci, Pat Hingle and narrated by Laura Dern. Rated R for the strong depiction of sexual and violent abuse including two rape scenes of a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Favourite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    loumcp
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a terrific film that explored painful subject matter and did it well. The creeping malice and cowardice of Glenn (a brave role for Ron Eldard) was terrifying and will be recognized as realistic by any survivor of child abuse, as will Bone's sense of isolation and responsibility for "keeping the peace." The women in the film acted their roles with real strength and tenderness - particularly, I thought, Glenne Headly as Aunt Ruth. Jena Malone was a natural. I also loved Grace Zabriskie as Grandma. Displaying the lives of people commonly labeled "poor white trash" could have gone horribly wrong, but "Bastard" doesn't patronize or demean. One wishes that those who made hay about the brutal child-rape scene in this film would devote this energy to protesting the actual occurrence of such things. The graphic nature of this scene was disturbing, to be sure, but not gratuitous or exploitative. A worthwhile rendering of Dorothy Allison's semi-autobiographical novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought provoking story.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (luster1@flash.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see a lot of nice, beautiful, adrenalin rush, horror, on the screen, these days, but not a lot of thought provoking pseudo docudrama. This story parallels social attitudes, during a period in which our parents lived, when a kid wasn't bottle-fed information, about everything, via movies, TV, & the Internet. This movie isn't just about abuse of a child, but the struggles of the unlearned adult poor, "just making it", in every quarter, of the United States, during the '40s. I've enjoyed J. Leigh for a good many years, & found her up to par, in this movie. I'm gaining a tremendous respect, for the abilities of Miss Malone. I just watched, last night, another of her efforts, "The Ballad of Lucy ????" last night. I recommend this film, even for a minor (with parent present for questions). Ted Luster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie was good. Although, disturbing (Spoiler*)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StrikinglyStunning
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have read this book, Bastard Out Of Carolina by Dorthy Allison, and it was a great book. It was so good, I was interested in watching the movie. It came on Lifetime, and the movie basically covered the book. It's about this girl Anne Boatwright (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who meets this guy Glen Waddell (Ron Eldard). At first, he is this good looking guy who is really nice and wants to be the father of Bone (Jena Malone) and Reese. He asks Reese to call him "Daddy" and she has no problem calling him that. Bone, can't say it for the simple fact that he's not really her dad. He gets angry. This was a man who was all about control. He gets Ruth Anne pregnant, and while she was giving birth, Glen , the two kids, Reese & Bone were in the car. The kids were asleep. Glen wakes Bone up and rapes her in the car. -VERY DISTURBING SCENE It was too horrible to watch, I had to change the channel. I didn't have the stomach for it. It all about physical abuse, he beats her because Bone was "direspecting him", and Ruth Anne believes Glen over her own daughter Bone. Ruth Anne sends Bone to go and live with Aunt Alma. When no one was in the house with her, Glen rides along, and goes over there. Unfortunately, he rapes her again. Again, I had to change the channel. It was absolutely horrific what he was doing to Bone. The movie is VERY graphic, you see almost everything. I didn't have the stomach to watch all those gruesome parts. I remember watching Sleepers, with Ron Eldard, now, I don't think I can look at him the same. He's good at playing bad guys. It was a good movie. (Although, very disturbing. I' not sure I can watch it again)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story takes place in (I'm guessing) the 1930s in the deep south. Anney (Jennifer Jason Leigh) is an unwed mother with two girls the oldest being Ruthann (Jena Malone). She meets handsome lively Glen (Ron Eldard) and marries him. But Glen has a bad temper and beats Ruthann regularly. Her mother doesn't know it and Glen keeps getting angrier and angrier. VERY disturbing but well-done movie. The actors all fake authentic Southern accents and it captures the era perfectly. The acting is just incredible. Leigh was just letter perfect as the mother. She does love her girls and her husband and is horrified when she realizes what's going on. Eldard was a little one-note in his performance but that was mostly cause the script didn't really explore his character. He was downright terrifying when he loses control a few times. Malone was only 10 when she did this and she was incredible! VERY talented for such a young child and holds her own especially in downright horrific sequence at the end. Even the supporting roles were well-acted with Michael Rooker and Glenne Headly being standouts. Also it's all narrated by Laura Dern. As for the beatings--they're never really shown until the very end. You HEAR them though and that's bad enough. The acting is so good by Malone and Eldard you believe every second of them. One complaint--the movie feels unfinished. It looks like either a lot was cut out of the script or out of the movie. Some scenes come and go quickly and have characters you've never met. Still this is well worth watching...but it is disturbing (as it should be) and powerful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strong Performances and Direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bastard Out of Carolina (1996) *** (out of 4) Graphic adaptation of the Dorothy Allison novel takes place in the South Carolina as a young girl (Jena Malone) begins to be physically and sexually abused by her stepfather (Ron Eldard) while her mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh) keeps overlooking what's going on. BASTARD OUT OF CAROLINA was the directorial debut from Anjelica Huston and while I'd question some of the flow in the story there's no question that she dives head first into the abuse and doesn't pull any punches. This here is a pretty hard film to watch because of how graphic it is towards the abuse in the film. I was really shocked at how much detail was shown when it came to the abuse because most of the time the camera pulls away with a child involved but that wasn't the case here. It's clear that Huston wanted to show how horrid the abuse of a child was and this here was shown and it certainly wasn't easy to watch. The film really benefits from some incredibly strong performances with Malone leading the way as the abused girl. She's completely believable in the part and it was certainly needed because the actress really makes you feel that she's this smart little girl being forced to grow up quickly because of her situation. Jennfier Jason Leigh also turns in a powerful performance as the mother who can't leave her husband even though he's hurting her daughter. Eldard is a complete slime here and perfectly captures the spirit of the character. We also get strong supporting performances by Michael Rooker, Lyle Lovett, Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diane Scarwid and Pat Hingle. Christina Ricci appears in one scene. I think there were times when the film didn't flow as good as it could have but there's no question that Huston gets her message across. The film is hard to recommend to most people due to how depressing and graphic it is but those who do sit through the film will be rewarded with a strong picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unnecessarily praised.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aslowriot
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film delves deeply into the subject of child abuse. Jena Malone's character, Bone, is a young girl who suffers through horrific acts of violence perpetrated by her mother's husband who is not her paternal father. The depravity of the film spans beyond the child abuse it features. Despite the remarkable cast and their outstanding performances, the film raises issues which it never confronts or resolves. The film is nothing more than a portrait of a despicable life, without any hope or resolution to be found within the context. Simply put, a daughter suffers immense cruelty at the hands of her mother's husband, and rather than fight for the maternal bond between mother and daughter, the mother decides to abandon her daughter for the love she finds from her husband who has abused her daughter. This film hardly even rises to the level of a documentary, in which case you might expect the depiction of depravity to be senseless and obscene. Instead the film raises a litany of questions for which it offers no answers. Why does the mother continually disregard the abuse she is fully aware her daughter is suffering at the hands of her husband? Does the mother have any concern for the chances of her younger daughter being subjected to the same abuse from her husband? Is severing the relationship between both daughters to be considered healthy? Is abandoning her abused daughter the mother's misconceived idea as to how to make amends? What is accomplished or signified by the abused daughter's refusal to name her abuser, purely out of inescapable love for her mother who doesn't protect her? How does the abused and then abandoned daughter relate to the world around her and how will she in the future? With utmost respect to the acting talents of the cast, the few undeveloped phrases that are stated, which one hopes will provide insight into the questions raised by the film, fail to suffice in properly addressing the base topics depicted. One could easily glean from a department of children and families case file the same pain, revulsion, and sorrow this film presents. Quite disappointing, but highly recommended to those film viewers who enjoy or are satisfied with dismal portrayals of tragedy which offer nothing in the way of redemption or adequate depiction of the subject matter at hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This story is so southern.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ttratar21
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched this movie on Lifetime, and was reminded of my time living in the south. When I was living in the south, time after time, I would see a husband who was a total scumbag, and his wife would never leave him. In other parts of the United States there would be a separation instantly. But in the South Women are afraid to stand up to their man. This movie was tough to watch. This little girl was severely abused, and molested by her step- father, and her mother refused to do anything about it. When she told her daughter at the end of the movie that she still Love's Glen, I was sick to my stomach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bastard out of Carolina
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lyndsay Page
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece.It deals with a touchy subject. The actors and actresses play there parts so well. You can actually see the sadness in Malone and the hate in Eldard's face. Its sad because things like this happen all the time. This movie is not some fake movie that someone made up in there head. Its truth this does happen to people. And its sad because Leigh's character as the lonely mother is real there are mothers out there that are stuck between loving there child or there lover. Its a sad situation and this movie shows you life. This movie is for sure excellent 10 stars from me. I would recommend this movie to anyone who likes serious movies that just have you on the edge of your seat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Messy Southern Gothic with too many characters and a lumpy narrative...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston, an unequivocally wise and intuitive actress, takes on a dark, rambling Southern tale for her first directorial effort, an adaptation of Dorothy Allison's book with so many peaks and valleys it plays like a chopped up TV mini-series, the CliffsNotes version. Story centers on an illegitimate young girl (Jena Malone) in the South during the 1950s and her woebegone waitress-mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who has had terrible luck with men. Seems her third husband (Ron Eldard) has a violent streak when provoked, and when he begins lashing out at the child in both violent and sexual ways, relatives step in to help her. Rare to find a cast so full of solid acting talent, yet this script takes great pains to introduce characters without giving them anything to do (some of the relatives, like the uptown cousin played by Christina Ricci or Dermot Mulroney's doomed Husband #2, appear and disappear in record time). The central performances are fine, with pre-teen Malone doing some very nice work; a child actress with a solemn reserve and faraway eyes, Malone is perhaps too studied in her approach (she isn't an untrained natural), yet Huston handles her gently and some of the strongest moments are the ones where Malone is allowed to take a breath and emote. However, this film, a failed theatrical effort which was sold instead to cable television, is packed (or padded, as it were) with short-hand tragedy, and the editing is so poor and the narrative so confusing you might need a scorecard to keep up with all the melodrama. Despite her sensitivity in staging some shattering scenes, Huston doesn't allow the picture to flow, to absorb the audience. It's jagged and piqued, and one recoils from it instead of being drawn into the plot. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful, disturbing, heinous is the human stain.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston's directorial debut is based on a novel by Dorothy Allison. A potent, emotional driven drama deep in the ways of poor South Carolina. It is post-WWII and a young Anney Boatwright(Jennifer Jason Leigh)gives birth to an illegitimate child. She names her baby Ruth Anne(Jena Malone), but she will be known as 'Bone'. Life is difficult for the struggling waitress, who has another daughter and is forced to bury a husband(Dermot Mulroney)killed in an auto accident. Anney's brother Earle(Michael Rooker)introduces her to her future...Glen Waddell(Ron Eldard). The two marry, but soon Glen starts taking his anger out on 'Bone'. The bonds between mother and daughter will become dangerously strained when Anney finds her husband raping 'Bone'. This following the constant violent physical abuse of the child behind her mother's back. There is a strong ensemble cast, but the young Malone is brilliant beyond her age. Other players: Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diana Scarwid, Lyle Lovett, Christina Ricci, Pat Hingle and narrated by Laura Dern. Rated R for the strong depiction of sexual and violent abuse including two rape scenes of a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Favourite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    loumcp
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a terrific film that explored painful subject matter and did it well. The creeping malice and cowardice of Glenn (a brave role for Ron Eldard) was terrifying and will be recognized as realistic by any survivor of child abuse, as will Bone's sense of isolation and responsibility for "keeping the peace." The women in the film acted their roles with real strength and tenderness - particularly, I thought, Glenne Headly as Aunt Ruth. Jena Malone was a natural. I also loved Grace Zabriskie as Grandma. Displaying the lives of people commonly labeled "poor white trash" could have gone horribly wrong, but "Bastard" doesn't patronize or demean. One wishes that those who made hay about the brutal child-rape scene in this film would devote this energy to protesting the actual occurrence of such things. The graphic nature of this scene was disturbing, to be sure, but not gratuitous or exploitative. A worthwhile rendering of Dorothy Allison's semi-autobiographical novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought provoking story.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (luster1@flash.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see a lot of nice, beautiful, adrenalin rush, horror, on the screen, these days, but not a lot of thought provoking pseudo docudrama. This story parallels social attitudes, during a period in which our parents lived, when a kid wasn't bottle-fed information, about everything, via movies, TV, & the Internet. This movie isn't just about abuse of a child, but the struggles of the unlearned adult poor, "just making it", in every quarter, of the United States, during the '40s. I've enjoyed J. Leigh for a good many years, & found her up to par, in this movie. I'm gaining a tremendous respect, for the abilities of Miss Malone. I just watched, last night, another of her efforts, "The Ballad of Lucy ????" last night. I recommend this film, even for a minor (with parent present for questions). Ted Luster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie was good. Although, disturbing (Spoiler*)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StrikinglyStunning
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have read this book, Bastard Out Of Carolina by Dorthy Allison, and it was a great book. It was so good, I was interested in watching the movie. It came on Lifetime, and the movie basically covered the book. It's about this girl Anne Boatwright (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who meets this guy Glen Waddell (Ron Eldard). At first, he is this good looking guy who is really nice and wants to be the father of Bone (Jena Malone) and Reese. He asks Reese to call him "Daddy" and she has no problem calling him that. Bone, can't say it for the simple fact that he's not really her dad. He gets angry. This was a man who was all about control. He gets Ruth Anne pregnant, and while she was giving birth, Glen , the two kids, Reese & Bone were in the car. The kids were asleep. Glen wakes Bone up and rapes her in the car. -VERY DISTURBING SCENE It was too horrible to watch, I had to change the channel. I didn't have the stomach for it. It all about physical abuse, he beats her because Bone was "direspecting him", and Ruth Anne believes Glen over her own daughter Bone. Ruth Anne sends Bone to go and live with Aunt Alma. When no one was in the house with her, Glen rides along, and goes over there. Unfortunately, he rapes her again. Again, I had to change the channel. It was absolutely horrific what he was doing to Bone. The movie is VERY graphic, you see almost everything. I didn't have the stomach to watch all those gruesome parts. I remember watching Sleepers, with Ron Eldard, now, I don't think I can look at him the same. He's good at playing bad guys. It was a good movie. (Although, very disturbing. I' not sure I can watch it again)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story takes place in (I'm guessing) the 1930s in the deep south. Anney (Jennifer Jason Leigh) is an unwed mother with two girls the oldest being Ruthann (Jena Malone). She meets handsome lively Glen (Ron Eldard) and marries him. But Glen has a bad temper and beats Ruthann regularly. Her mother doesn't know it and Glen keeps getting angrier and angrier. VERY disturbing but well-done movie. The actors all fake authentic Southern accents and it captures the era perfectly. The acting is just incredible. Leigh was just letter perfect as the mother. She does love her girls and her husband and is horrified when she realizes what's going on. Eldard was a little one-note in his performance but that was mostly cause the script didn't really explore his character. He was downright terrifying when he loses control a few times. Malone was only 10 when she did this and she was incredible! VERY talented for such a young child and holds her own especially in downright horrific sequence at the end. Even the supporting roles were well-acted with Michael Rooker and Glenne Headly being standouts. Also it's all narrated by Laura Dern. As for the beatings--they're never really shown until the very end. You HEAR them though and that's bad enough. The acting is so good by Malone and Eldard you believe every second of them. One complaint--the movie feels unfinished. It looks like either a lot was cut out of the script or out of the movie. Some scenes come and go quickly and have characters you've never met. Still this is well worth watching...but it is disturbing (as it should be) and powerful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strong Performances and Direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bastard Out of Carolina (1996) *** (out of 4) Graphic adaptation of the Dorothy Allison novel takes place in the South Carolina as a young girl (Jena Malone) begins to be physically and sexually abused by her stepfather (Ron Eldard) while her mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh) keeps overlooking what's going on. BASTARD OUT OF CAROLINA was the directorial debut from Anjelica Huston and while I'd question some of the flow in the story there's no question that she dives head first into the abuse and doesn't pull any punches. This here is a pretty hard film to watch because of how graphic it is towards the abuse in the film. I was really shocked at how much detail was shown when it came to the abuse because most of the time the camera pulls away with a child involved but that wasn't the case here. It's clear that Huston wanted to show how horrid the abuse of a child was and this here was shown and it certainly wasn't easy to watch. The film really benefits from some incredibly strong performances with Malone leading the way as the abused girl. She's completely believable in the part and it was certainly needed because the actress really makes you feel that she's this smart little girl being forced to grow up quickly because of her situation. Jennfier Jason Leigh also turns in a powerful performance as the mother who can't leave her husband even though he's hurting her daughter. Eldard is a complete slime here and perfectly captures the spirit of the character. We also get strong supporting performances by Michael Rooker, Lyle Lovett, Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diane Scarwid and Pat Hingle. Christina Ricci appears in one scene. I think there were times when the film didn't flow as good as it could have but there's no question that Huston gets her message across. The film is hard to recommend to most people due to how depressing and graphic it is but those who do sit through the film will be rewarded with a strong picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unnecessarily praised.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aslowriot
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film delves deeply into the subject of child abuse. Jena Malone's character, Bone, is a young girl who suffers through horrific acts of violence perpetrated by her mother's husband who is not her paternal father. The depravity of the film spans beyond the child abuse it features. Despite the remarkable cast and their outstanding performances, the film raises issues which it never confronts or resolves. The film is nothing more than a portrait of a despicable life, without any hope or resolution to be found within the context. Simply put, a daughter suffers immense cruelty at the hands of her mother's husband, and rather than fight for the maternal bond between mother and daughter, the mother decides to abandon her daughter for the love she finds from her husband who has abused her daughter. This film hardly even rises to the level of a documentary, in which case you might expect the depiction of depravity to be senseless and obscene. Instead the film raises a litany of questions for which it offers no answers. Why does the mother continually disregard the abuse she is fully aware her daughter is suffering at the hands of her husband? Does the mother have any concern for the chances of her younger daughter being subjected to the same abuse from her husband? Is severing the relationship between both daughters to be considered healthy? Is abandoning her abused daughter the mother's misconceived idea as to how to make amends? What is accomplished or signified by the abused daughter's refusal to name her abuser, purely out of inescapable love for her mother who doesn't protect her? How does the abused and then abandoned daughter relate to the world around her and how will she in the future? With utmost respect to the acting talents of the cast, the few undeveloped phrases that are stated, which one hopes will provide insight into the questions raised by the film, fail to suffice in properly addressing the base topics depicted. One could easily glean from a department of children and families case file the same pain, revulsion, and sorrow this film presents. Quite disappointing, but highly recommended to those film viewers who enjoy or are satisfied with dismal portrayals of tragedy which offer nothing in the way of redemption or adequate depiction of the subject matter at hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This story is so southern.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ttratar21
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched this movie on Lifetime, and was reminded of my time living in the south. When I was living in the south, time after time, I would see a husband who was a total scumbag, and his wife would never leave him. In other parts of the United States there would be a separation instantly. But in the South Women are afraid to stand up to their man. This movie was tough to watch. This little girl was severely abused, and molested by her step- father, and her mother refused to do anything about it. When she told her daughter at the end of the movie that she still Love's Glen, I was sick to my stomach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bastard out of Carolina
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lyndsay Page
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece.It deals with a touchy subject. The actors and actresses play there parts so well. You can actually see the sadness in Malone and the hate in Eldard's face. Its sad because things like this happen all the time. This movie is not some fake movie that someone made up in there head. Its truth this does happen to people. And its sad because Leigh's character as the lonely mother is real there are mothers out there that are stuck between loving there child or there lover. Its a sad situation and this movie shows you life. This movie is for sure excellent 10 stars from me. I would recommend this movie to anyone who likes serious movies that just have you on the edge of your seat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Messy Southern Gothic with too many characters and a lumpy narrative...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston, an unequivocally wise and intuitive actress, takes on a dark, rambling Southern tale for her first directorial effort, an adaptation of Dorothy Allison's book with so many peaks and valleys it plays like a chopped up TV mini-series, the CliffsNotes version. Story centers on an illegitimate young girl (Jena Malone) in the South during the 1950s and her woebegone waitress-mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who has had terrible luck with men. Seems her third husband (Ron Eldard) has a violent streak when provoked, and when he begins lashing out at the child in both violent and sexual ways, relatives step in to help her. Rare to find a cast so full of solid acting talent, yet this script takes great pains to introduce characters without giving them anything to do (some of the relatives, like the uptown cousin played by Christina Ricci or Dermot Mulroney's doomed Husband #2, appear and disappear in record time). The central performances are fine, with pre-teen Malone doing some very nice work; a child actress with a solemn reserve and faraway eyes, Malone is perhaps too studied in her approach (she isn't an untrained natural), yet Huston handles her gently and some of the strongest moments are the ones where Malone is allowed to take a breath and emote. However, this film, a failed theatrical effort which was sold instead to cable television, is packed (or padded, as it were) with short-hand tragedy, and the editing is so poor and the narrative so confusing you might need a scorecard to keep up with all the melodrama. Despite her sensitivity in staging some shattering scenes, Huston doesn't allow the picture to flow, to absorb the audience. It's jagged and piqued, and one recoils from it instead of being drawn into the plot. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful, disturbing, heinous is the human stain.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston's directorial debut is based on a novel by Dorothy Allison. A potent, emotional driven drama deep in the ways of poor South Carolina. It is post-WWII and a young Anney Boatwright(Jennifer Jason Leigh)gives birth to an illegitimate child. She names her baby Ruth Anne(Jena Malone), but she will be known as 'Bone'. Life is difficult for the struggling waitress, who has another daughter and is forced to bury a husband(Dermot Mulroney)killed in an auto accident. Anney's brother Earle(Michael Rooker)introduces her to her future...Glen Waddell(Ron Eldard). The two marry, but soon Glen starts taking his anger out on 'Bone'. The bonds between mother and daughter will become dangerously strained when Anney finds her husband raping 'Bone'. This following the constant violent physical abuse of the child behind her mother's back. There is a strong ensemble cast, but the young Malone is brilliant beyond her age. Other players: Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diana Scarwid, Lyle Lovett, Christina Ricci, Pat Hingle and narrated by Laura Dern. Rated R for the strong depiction of sexual and violent abuse including two rape scenes of a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Favourite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    loumcp
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a terrific film that explored painful subject matter and did it well. The creeping malice and cowardice of Glenn (a brave role for Ron Eldard) was terrifying and will be recognized as realistic by any survivor of child abuse, as will Bone's sense of isolation and responsibility for "keeping the peace." The women in the film acted their roles with real strength and tenderness - particularly, I thought, Glenne Headly as Aunt Ruth. Jena Malone was a natural. I also loved Grace Zabriskie as Grandma. Displaying the lives of people commonly labeled "poor white trash" could have gone horribly wrong, but "Bastard" doesn't patronize or demean. One wishes that those who made hay about the brutal child-rape scene in this film would devote this energy to protesting the actual occurrence of such things. The graphic nature of this scene was disturbing, to be sure, but not gratuitous or exploitative. A worthwhile rendering of Dorothy Allison's semi-autobiographical novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought provoking story.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (luster1@flash.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see a lot of nice, beautiful, adrenalin rush, horror, on the screen, these days, but not a lot of thought provoking pseudo docudrama. This story parallels social attitudes, during a period in which our parents lived, when a kid wasn't bottle-fed information, about everything, via movies, TV, & the Internet. This movie isn't just about abuse of a child, but the struggles of the unlearned adult poor, "just making it", in every quarter, of the United States, during the '40s. I've enjoyed J. Leigh for a good many years, & found her up to par, in this movie. I'm gaining a tremendous respect, for the abilities of Miss Malone. I just watched, last night, another of her efforts, "The Ballad of Lucy ????" last night. I recommend this film, even for a minor (with parent present for questions). Ted Luster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie was good. Although, disturbing (Spoiler*)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StrikinglyStunning
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have read this book, Bastard Out Of Carolina by Dorthy Allison, and it was a great book. It was so good, I was interested in watching the movie. It came on Lifetime, and the movie basically covered the book. It's about this girl Anne Boatwright (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who meets this guy Glen Waddell (Ron Eldard). At first, he is this good looking guy who is really nice and wants to be the father of Bone (Jena Malone) and Reese. He asks Reese to call him "Daddy" and she has no problem calling him that. Bone, can't say it for the simple fact that he's not really her dad. He gets angry. This was a man who was all about control. He gets Ruth Anne pregnant, and while she was giving birth, Glen , the two kids, Reese & Bone were in the car. The kids were asleep. Glen wakes Bone up and rapes her in the car. -VERY DISTURBING SCENE It was too horrible to watch, I had to change the channel. I didn't have the stomach for it. It all about physical abuse, he beats her because Bone was "direspecting him", and Ruth Anne believes Glen over her own daughter Bone. Ruth Anne sends Bone to go and live with Aunt Alma. When no one was in the house with her, Glen rides along, and goes over there. Unfortunately, he rapes her again. Again, I had to change the channel. It was absolutely horrific what he was doing to Bone. The movie is VERY graphic, you see almost everything. I didn't have the stomach to watch all those gruesome parts. I remember watching Sleepers, with Ron Eldard, now, I don't think I can look at him the same. He's good at playing bad guys. It was a good movie. (Although, very disturbing. I' not sure I can watch it again)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story takes place in (I'm guessing) the 1930s in the deep south. Anney (Jennifer Jason Leigh) is an unwed mother with two girls the oldest being Ruthann (Jena Malone). She meets handsome lively Glen (Ron Eldard) and marries him. But Glen has a bad temper and beats Ruthann regularly. Her mother doesn't know it and Glen keeps getting angrier and angrier. VERY disturbing but well-done movie. The actors all fake authentic Southern accents and it captures the era perfectly. The acting is just incredible. Leigh was just letter perfect as the mother. She does love her girls and her husband and is horrified when she realizes what's going on. Eldard was a little one-note in his performance but that was mostly cause the script didn't really explore his character. He was downright terrifying when he loses control a few times. Malone was only 10 when she did this and she was incredible! VERY talented for such a young child and holds her own especially in downright horrific sequence at the end. Even the supporting roles were well-acted with Michael Rooker and Glenne Headly being standouts. Also it's all narrated by Laura Dern. As for the beatings--they're never really shown until the very end. You HEAR them though and that's bad enough. The acting is so good by Malone and Eldard you believe every second of them. One complaint--the movie feels unfinished. It looks like either a lot was cut out of the script or out of the movie. Some scenes come and go quickly and have characters you've never met. Still this is well worth watching...but it is disturbing (as it should be) and powerful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strong Performances and Direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bastard Out of Carolina (1996) *** (out of 4) Graphic adaptation of the Dorothy Allison novel takes place in the South Carolina as a young girl (Jena Malone) begins to be physically and sexually abused by her stepfather (Ron Eldard) while her mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh) keeps overlooking what's going on. BASTARD OUT OF CAROLINA was the directorial debut from Anjelica Huston and while I'd question some of the flow in the story there's no question that she dives head first into the abuse and doesn't pull any punches. This here is a pretty hard film to watch because of how graphic it is towards the abuse in the film. I was really shocked at how much detail was shown when it came to the abuse because most of the time the camera pulls away with a child involved but that wasn't the case here. It's clear that Huston wanted to show how horrid the abuse of a child was and this here was shown and it certainly wasn't easy to watch. The film really benefits from some incredibly strong performances with Malone leading the way as the abused girl. She's completely believable in the part and it was certainly needed because the actress really makes you feel that she's this smart little girl being forced to grow up quickly because of her situation. Jennfier Jason Leigh also turns in a powerful performance as the mother who can't leave her husband even though he's hurting her daughter. Eldard is a complete slime here and perfectly captures the spirit of the character. We also get strong supporting performances by Michael Rooker, Lyle Lovett, Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diane Scarwid and Pat Hingle. Christina Ricci appears in one scene. I think there were times when the film didn't flow as good as it could have but there's no question that Huston gets her message across. The film is hard to recommend to most people due to how depressing and graphic it is but those who do sit through the film will be rewarded with a strong picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unnecessarily praised.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aslowriot
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film delves deeply into the subject of child abuse. Jena Malone's character, Bone, is a young girl who suffers through horrific acts of violence perpetrated by her mother's husband who is not her paternal father. The depravity of the film spans beyond the child abuse it features. Despite the remarkable cast and their outstanding performances, the film raises issues which it never confronts or resolves. The film is nothing more than a portrait of a despicable life, without any hope or resolution to be found within the context. Simply put, a daughter suffers immense cruelty at the hands of her mother's husband, and rather than fight for the maternal bond between mother and daughter, the mother decides to abandon her daughter for the love she finds from her husband who has abused her daughter. This film hardly even rises to the level of a documentary, in which case you might expect the depiction of depravity to be senseless and obscene. Instead the film raises a litany of questions for which it offers no answers. Why does the mother continually disregard the abuse she is fully aware her daughter is suffering at the hands of her husband? Does the mother have any concern for the chances of her younger daughter being subjected to the same abuse from her husband? Is severing the relationship between both daughters to be considered healthy? Is abandoning her abused daughter the mother's misconceived idea as to how to make amends? What is accomplished or signified by the abused daughter's refusal to name her abuser, purely out of inescapable love for her mother who doesn't protect her? How does the abused and then abandoned daughter relate to the world around her and how will she in the future? With utmost respect to the acting talents of the cast, the few undeveloped phrases that are stated, which one hopes will provide insight into the questions raised by the film, fail to suffice in properly addressing the base topics depicted. One could easily glean from a department of children and families case file the same pain, revulsion, and sorrow this film presents. Quite disappointing, but highly recommended to those film viewers who enjoy or are satisfied with dismal portrayals of tragedy which offer nothing in the way of redemption or adequate depiction of the subject matter at hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This story is so southern.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ttratar21
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched this movie on Lifetime, and was reminded of my time living in the south. When I was living in the south, time after time, I would see a husband who was a total scumbag, and his wife would never leave him. In other parts of the United States there would be a separation instantly. But in the South Women are afraid to stand up to their man. This movie was tough to watch. This little girl was severely abused, and molested by her step- father, and her mother refused to do anything about it. When she told her daughter at the end of the movie that she still Love's Glen, I was sick to my stomach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bastard out of Carolina
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lyndsay Page
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece.It deals with a touchy subject. The actors and actresses play there parts so well. You can actually see the sadness in Malone and the hate in Eldard's face. Its sad because things like this happen all the time. This movie is not some fake movie that someone made up in there head. Its truth this does happen to people. And its sad because Leigh's character as the lonely mother is real there are mothers out there that are stuck between loving there child or there lover. Its a sad situation and this movie shows you life. This movie is for sure excellent 10 stars from me. I would recommend this movie to anyone who likes serious movies that just have you on the edge of your seat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Messy Southern Gothic with too many characters and a lumpy narrative...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston, an unequivocally wise and intuitive actress, takes on a dark, rambling Southern tale for her first directorial effort, an adaptation of Dorothy Allison's book with so many peaks and valleys it plays like a chopped up TV mini-series, the CliffsNotes version. Story centers on an illegitimate young girl (Jena Malone) in the South during the 1950s and her woebegone waitress-mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who has had terrible luck with men. Seems her third husband (Ron Eldard) has a violent streak when provoked, and when he begins lashing out at the child in both violent and sexual ways, relatives step in to help her. Rare to find a cast so full of solid acting talent, yet this script takes great pains to introduce characters without giving them anything to do (some of the relatives, like the uptown cousin played by Christina Ricci or Dermot Mulroney's doomed Husband #2, appear and disappear in record time). The central performances are fine, with pre-teen Malone doing some very nice work; a child actress with a solemn reserve and faraway eyes, Malone is perhaps too studied in her approach (she isn't an untrained natural), yet Huston handles her gently and some of the strongest moments are the ones where Malone is allowed to take a breath and emote. However, this film, a failed theatrical effort which was sold instead to cable television, is packed (or padded, as it were) with short-hand tragedy, and the editing is so poor and the narrative so confusing you might need a scorecard to keep up with all the melodrama. Despite her sensitivity in staging some shattering scenes, Huston doesn't allow the picture to flow, to absorb the audience. It's jagged and piqued, and one recoils from it instead of being drawn into the plot. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful, disturbing, heinous is the human stain.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston's directorial debut is based on a novel by Dorothy Allison. A potent, emotional driven drama deep in the ways of poor South Carolina. It is post-WWII and a young Anney Boatwright(Jennifer Jason Leigh)gives birth to an illegitimate child. She names her baby Ruth Anne(Jena Malone), but she will be known as 'Bone'. Life is difficult for the struggling waitress, who has another daughter and is forced to bury a husband(Dermot Mulroney)killed in an auto accident. Anney's brother Earle(Michael Rooker)introduces her to her future...Glen Waddell(Ron Eldard). The two marry, but soon Glen starts taking his anger out on 'Bone'. The bonds between mother and daughter will become dangerously strained when Anney finds her husband raping 'Bone'. This following the constant violent physical abuse of the child behind her mother's back. There is a strong ensemble cast, but the young Malone is brilliant beyond her age. Other players: Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diana Scarwid, Lyle Lovett, Christina Ricci, Pat Hingle and narrated by Laura Dern. Rated R for the strong depiction of sexual and violent abuse including two rape scenes of a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Favourite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    loumcp
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a terrific film that explored painful subject matter and did it well. The creeping malice and cowardice of Glenn (a brave role for Ron Eldard) was terrifying and will be recognized as realistic by any survivor of child abuse, as will Bone's sense of isolation and responsibility for "keeping the peace." The women in the film acted their roles with real strength and tenderness - particularly, I thought, Glenne Headly as Aunt Ruth. Jena Malone was a natural. I also loved Grace Zabriskie as Grandma. Displaying the lives of people commonly labeled "poor white trash" could have gone horribly wrong, but "Bastard" doesn't patronize or demean. One wishes that those who made hay about the brutal child-rape scene in this film would devote this energy to protesting the actual occurrence of such things. The graphic nature of this scene was disturbing, to be sure, but not gratuitous or exploitative. A worthwhile rendering of Dorothy Allison's semi-autobiographical novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought provoking story.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (luster1@flash.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see a lot of nice, beautiful, adrenalin rush, horror, on the screen, these days, but not a lot of thought provoking pseudo docudrama. This story parallels social attitudes, during a period in which our parents lived, when a kid wasn't bottle-fed information, about everything, via movies, TV, & the Internet. This movie isn't just about abuse of a child, but the struggles of the unlearned adult poor, "just making it", in every quarter, of the United States, during the '40s. I've enjoyed J. Leigh for a good many years, & found her up to par, in this movie. I'm gaining a tremendous respect, for the abilities of Miss Malone. I just watched, last night, another of her efforts, "The Ballad of Lucy ????" last night. I recommend this film, even for a minor (with parent present for questions). Ted Luster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie was good. Although, disturbing (Spoiler*)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StrikinglyStunning
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have read this book, Bastard Out Of Carolina by Dorthy Allison, and it was a great book. It was so good, I was interested in watching the movie. It came on Lifetime, and the movie basically covered the book. It's about this girl Anne Boatwright (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who meets this guy Glen Waddell (Ron Eldard). At first, he is this good looking guy who is really nice and wants to be the father of Bone (Jena Malone) and Reese. He asks Reese to call him "Daddy" and she has no problem calling him that. Bone, can't say it for the simple fact that he's not really her dad. He gets angry. This was a man who was all about control. He gets Ruth Anne pregnant, and while she was giving birth, Glen , the two kids, Reese & Bone were in the car. The kids were asleep. Glen wakes Bone up and rapes her in the car. -VERY DISTURBING SCENE It was too horrible to watch, I had to change the channel. I didn't have the stomach for it. It all about physical abuse, he beats her because Bone was "direspecting him", and Ruth Anne believes Glen over her own daughter Bone. Ruth Anne sends Bone to go and live with Aunt Alma. When no one was in the house with her, Glen rides along, and goes over there. Unfortunately, he rapes her again. Again, I had to change the channel. It was absolutely horrific what he was doing to Bone. The movie is VERY graphic, you see almost everything. I didn't have the stomach to watch all those gruesome parts. I remember watching Sleepers, with Ron Eldard, now, I don't think I can look at him the same. He's good at playing bad guys. It was a good movie. (Although, very disturbing. I' not sure I can watch it again)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story takes place in (I'm guessing) the 1930s in the deep south. Anney (Jennifer Jason Leigh) is an unwed mother with two girls the oldest being Ruthann (Jena Malone). She meets handsome lively Glen (Ron Eldard) and marries him. But Glen has a bad temper and beats Ruthann regularly. Her mother doesn't know it and Glen keeps getting angrier and angrier. VERY disturbing but well-done movie. The actors all fake authentic Southern accents and it captures the era perfectly. The acting is just incredible. Leigh was just letter perfect as the mother. She does love her girls and her husband and is horrified when she realizes what's going on. Eldard was a little one-note in his performance but that was mostly cause the script didn't really explore his character. He was downright terrifying when he loses control a few times. Malone was only 10 when she did this and she was incredible! VERY talented for such a young child and holds her own especially in downright horrific sequence at the end. Even the supporting roles were well-acted with Michael Rooker and Glenne Headly being standouts. Also it's all narrated by Laura Dern. As for the beatings--they're never really shown until the very end. You HEAR them though and that's bad enough. The acting is so good by Malone and Eldard you believe every second of them. One complaint--the movie feels unfinished. It looks like either a lot was cut out of the script or out of the movie. Some scenes come and go quickly and have characters you've never met. Still this is well worth watching...but it is disturbing (as it should be) and powerful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strong Performances and Direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bastard Out of Carolina (1996) *** (out of 4) Graphic adaptation of the Dorothy Allison novel takes place in the South Carolina as a young girl (Jena Malone) begins to be physically and sexually abused by her stepfather (Ron Eldard) while her mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh) keeps overlooking what's going on. BASTARD OUT OF CAROLINA was the directorial debut from Anjelica Huston and while I'd question some of the flow in the story there's no question that she dives head first into the abuse and doesn't pull any punches. This here is a pretty hard film to watch because of how graphic it is towards the abuse in the film. I was really shocked at how much detail was shown when it came to the abuse because most of the time the camera pulls away with a child involved but that wasn't the case here. It's clear that Huston wanted to show how horrid the abuse of a child was and this here was shown and it certainly wasn't easy to watch. The film really benefits from some incredibly strong performances with Malone leading the way as the abused girl. She's completely believable in the part and it was certainly needed because the actress really makes you feel that she's this smart little girl being forced to grow up quickly because of her situation. Jennfier Jason Leigh also turns in a powerful performance as the mother who can't leave her husband even though he's hurting her daughter. Eldard is a complete slime here and perfectly captures the spirit of the character. We also get strong supporting performances by Michael Rooker, Lyle Lovett, Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diane Scarwid and Pat Hingle. Christina Ricci appears in one scene. I think there were times when the film didn't flow as good as it could have but there's no question that Huston gets her message across. The film is hard to recommend to most people due to how depressing and graphic it is but those who do sit through the film will be rewarded with a strong picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unnecessarily praised.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aslowriot
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film delves deeply into the subject of child abuse. Jena Malone's character, Bone, is a young girl who suffers through horrific acts of violence perpetrated by her mother's husband who is not her paternal father. The depravity of the film spans beyond the child abuse it features. Despite the remarkable cast and their outstanding performances, the film raises issues which it never confronts or resolves. The film is nothing more than a portrait of a despicable life, without any hope or resolution to be found within the context. Simply put, a daughter suffers immense cruelty at the hands of her mother's husband, and rather than fight for the maternal bond between mother and daughter, the mother decides to abandon her daughter for the love she finds from her husband who has abused her daughter. This film hardly even rises to the level of a documentary, in which case you might expect the depiction of depravity to be senseless and obscene. Instead the film raises a litany of questions for which it offers no answers. Why does the mother continually disregard the abuse she is fully aware her daughter is suffering at the hands of her husband? Does the mother have any concern for the chances of her younger daughter being subjected to the same abuse from her husband? Is severing the relationship between both daughters to be considered healthy? Is abandoning her abused daughter the mother's misconceived idea as to how to make amends? What is accomplished or signified by the abused daughter's refusal to name her abuser, purely out of inescapable love for her mother who doesn't protect her? How does the abused and then abandoned daughter relate to the world around her and how will she in the future? With utmost respect to the acting talents of the cast, the few undeveloped phrases that are stated, which one hopes will provide insight into the questions raised by the film, fail to suffice in properly addressing the base topics depicted. One could easily glean from a department of children and families case file the same pain, revulsion, and sorrow this film presents. Quite disappointing, but highly recommended to those film viewers who enjoy or are satisfied with dismal portrayals of tragedy which offer nothing in the way of redemption or adequate depiction of the subject matter at hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This story is so southern.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ttratar21
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched this movie on Lifetime, and was reminded of my time living in the south. When I was living in the south, time after time, I would see a husband who was a total scumbag, and his wife would never leave him. In other parts of the United States there would be a separation instantly. But in the South Women are afraid to stand up to their man. This movie was tough to watch. This little girl was severely abused, and molested by her step- father, and her mother refused to do anything about it. When she told her daughter at the end of the movie that she still Love's Glen, I was sick to my stomach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bastard out of Carolina
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lyndsay Page
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece.It deals with a touchy subject. The actors and actresses play there parts so well. You can actually see the sadness in Malone and the hate in Eldard's face. Its sad because things like this happen all the time. This movie is not some fake movie that someone made up in there head. Its truth this does happen to people. And its sad because Leigh's character as the lonely mother is real there are mothers out there that are stuck between loving there child or there lover. Its a sad situation and this movie shows you life. This movie is for sure excellent 10 stars from me. I would recommend this movie to anyone who likes serious movies that just have you on the edge of your seat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Messy Southern Gothic with too many characters and a lumpy narrative...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston, an unequivocally wise and intuitive actress, takes on a dark, rambling Southern tale for her first directorial effort, an adaptation of Dorothy Allison's book with so many peaks and valleys it plays like a chopped up TV mini-series, the CliffsNotes version. Story centers on an illegitimate young girl (Jena Malone) in the South during the 1950s and her woebegone waitress-mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who has had terrible luck with men. Seems her third husband (Ron Eldard) has a violent streak when provoked, and when he begins lashing out at the child in both violent and sexual ways, relatives step in to help her. Rare to find a cast so full of solid acting talent, yet this script takes great pains to introduce characters without giving them anything to do (some of the relatives, like the uptown cousin played by Christina Ricci or Dermot Mulroney's doomed Husband #2, appear and disappear in record time). The central performances are fine, with pre-teen Malone doing some very nice work; a child actress with a solemn reserve and faraway eyes, Malone is perhaps too studied in her approach (she isn't an untrained natural), yet Huston handles her gently and some of the strongest moments are the ones where Malone is allowed to take a breath and emote. However, this film, a failed theatrical effort which was sold instead to cable television, is packed (or padded, as it were) with short-hand tragedy, and the editing is so poor and the narrative so confusing you might need a scorecard to keep up with all the melodrama. Despite her sensitivity in staging some shattering scenes, Huston doesn't allow the picture to flow, to absorb the audience. It's jagged and piqued, and one recoils from it instead of being drawn into the plot. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful, disturbing, heinous is the human stain.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston's directorial debut is based on a novel by Dorothy Allison. A potent, emotional driven drama deep in the ways of poor South Carolina. It is post-WWII and a young Anney Boatwright(Jennifer Jason Leigh)gives birth to an illegitimate child. She names her baby Ruth Anne(Jena Malone), but she will be known as 'Bone'. Life is difficult for the struggling waitress, who has another daughter and is forced to bury a husband(Dermot Mulroney)killed in an auto accident. Anney's brother Earle(Michael Rooker)introduces her to her future...Glen Waddell(Ron Eldard). The two marry, but soon Glen starts taking his anger out on 'Bone'. The bonds between mother and daughter will become dangerously strained when Anney finds her husband raping 'Bone'. This following the constant violent physical abuse of the child behind her mother's back. There is a strong ensemble cast, but the young Malone is brilliant beyond her age. Other players: Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diana Scarwid, Lyle Lovett, Christina Ricci, Pat Hingle and narrated by Laura Dern. Rated R for the strong depiction of sexual and violent abuse including two rape scenes of a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Favourite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    loumcp
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a terrific film that explored painful subject matter and did it well. The creeping malice and cowardice of Glenn (a brave role for Ron Eldard) was terrifying and will be recognized as realistic by any survivor of child abuse, as will Bone's sense of isolation and responsibility for "keeping the peace." The women in the film acted their roles with real strength and tenderness - particularly, I thought, Glenne Headly as Aunt Ruth. Jena Malone was a natural. I also loved Grace Zabriskie as Grandma. Displaying the lives of people commonly labeled "poor white trash" could have gone horribly wrong, but "Bastard" doesn't patronize or demean. One wishes that those who made hay about the brutal child-rape scene in this film would devote this energy to protesting the actual occurrence of such things. The graphic nature of this scene was disturbing, to be sure, but not gratuitous or exploitative. A worthwhile rendering of Dorothy Allison's semi-autobiographical novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought provoking story.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (luster1@flash.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see a lot of nice, beautiful, adrenalin rush, horror, on the screen, these days, but not a lot of thought provoking pseudo docudrama. This story parallels social attitudes, during a period in which our parents lived, when a kid wasn't bottle-fed information, about everything, via movies, TV, & the Internet. This movie isn't just about abuse of a child, but the struggles of the unlearned adult poor, "just making it", in every quarter, of the United States, during the '40s. I've enjoyed J. Leigh for a good many years, & found her up to par, in this movie. I'm gaining a tremendous respect, for the abilities of Miss Malone. I just watched, last night, another of her efforts, "The Ballad of Lucy ????" last night. I recommend this film, even for a minor (with parent present for questions). Ted Luster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie was good. Although, disturbing (Spoiler*)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StrikinglyStunning
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have read this book, Bastard Out Of Carolina by Dorthy Allison, and it was a great book. It was so good, I was interested in watching the movie. It came on Lifetime, and the movie basically covered the book. It's about this girl Anne Boatwright (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who meets this guy Glen Waddell (Ron Eldard). At first, he is this good looking guy who is really nice and wants to be the father of Bone (Jena Malone) and Reese. He asks Reese to call him "Daddy" and she has no problem calling him that. Bone, can't say it for the simple fact that he's not really her dad. He gets angry. This was a man who was all about control. He gets Ruth Anne pregnant, and while she was giving birth, Glen , the two kids, Reese & Bone were in the car. The kids were asleep. Glen wakes Bone up and rapes her in the car. -VERY DISTURBING SCENE It was too horrible to watch, I had to change the channel. I didn't have the stomach for it. It all about physical abuse, he beats her because Bone was "direspecting him", and Ruth Anne believes Glen over her own daughter Bone. Ruth Anne sends Bone to go and live with Aunt Alma. When no one was in the house with her, Glen rides along, and goes over there. Unfortunately, he rapes her again. Again, I had to change the channel. It was absolutely horrific what he was doing to Bone. The movie is VERY graphic, you see almost everything. I didn't have the stomach to watch all those gruesome parts. I remember watching Sleepers, with Ron Eldard, now, I don't think I can look at him the same. He's good at playing bad guys. It was a good movie. (Although, very disturbing. I' not sure I can watch it again)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story takes place in (I'm guessing) the 1930s in the deep south. Anney (Jennifer Jason Leigh) is an unwed mother with two girls the oldest being Ruthann (Jena Malone). She meets handsome lively Glen (Ron Eldard) and marries him. But Glen has a bad temper and beats Ruthann regularly. Her mother doesn't know it and Glen keeps getting angrier and angrier. VERY disturbing but well-done movie. The actors all fake authentic Southern accents and it captures the era perfectly. The acting is just incredible. Leigh was just letter perfect as the mother. She does love her girls and her husband and is horrified when she realizes what's going on. Eldard was a little one-note in his performance but that was mostly cause the script didn't really explore his character. He was downright terrifying when he loses control a few times. Malone was only 10 when she did this and she was incredible! VERY talented for such a young child and holds her own especially in downright horrific sequence at the end. Even the supporting roles were well-acted with Michael Rooker and Glenne Headly being standouts. Also it's all narrated by Laura Dern. As for the beatings--they're never really shown until the very end. You HEAR them though and that's bad enough. The acting is so good by Malone and Eldard you believe every second of them. One complaint--the movie feels unfinished. It looks like either a lot was cut out of the script or out of the movie. Some scenes come and go quickly and have characters you've never met. Still this is well worth watching...but it is disturbing (as it should be) and powerful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strong Performances and Direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bastard Out of Carolina (1996) *** (out of 4) Graphic adaptation of the Dorothy Allison novel takes place in the South Carolina as a young girl (Jena Malone) begins to be physically and sexually abused by her stepfather (Ron Eldard) while her mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh) keeps overlooking what's going on. BASTARD OUT OF CAROLINA was the directorial debut from Anjelica Huston and while I'd question some of the flow in the story there's no question that she dives head first into the abuse and doesn't pull any punches. This here is a pretty hard film to watch because of how graphic it is towards the abuse in the film. I was really shocked at how much detail was shown when it came to the abuse because most of the time the camera pulls away with a child involved but that wasn't the case here. It's clear that Huston wanted to show how horrid the abuse of a child was and this here was shown and it certainly wasn't easy to watch. The film really benefits from some incredibly strong performances with Malone leading the way as the abused girl. She's completely believable in the part and it was certainly needed because the actress really makes you feel that she's this smart little girl being forced to grow up quickly because of her situation. Jennfier Jason Leigh also turns in a powerful performance as the mother who can't leave her husband even though he's hurting her daughter. Eldard is a complete slime here and perfectly captures the spirit of the character. We also get strong supporting performances by Michael Rooker, Lyle Lovett, Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diane Scarwid and Pat Hingle. Christina Ricci appears in one scene. I think there were times when the film didn't flow as good as it could have but there's no question that Huston gets her message across. The film is hard to recommend to most people due to how depressing and graphic it is but those who do sit through the film will be rewarded with a strong picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unnecessarily praised.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aslowriot
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film delves deeply into the subject of child abuse. Jena Malone's character, Bone, is a young girl who suffers through horrific acts of violence perpetrated by her mother's husband who is not her paternal father. The depravity of the film spans beyond the child abuse it features. Despite the remarkable cast and their outstanding performances, the film raises issues which it never confronts or resolves. The film is nothing more than a portrait of a despicable life, without any hope or resolution to be found within the context. Simply put, a daughter suffers immense cruelty at the hands of her mother's husband, and rather than fight for the maternal bond between mother and daughter, the mother decides to abandon her daughter for the love she finds from her husband who has abused her daughter. This film hardly even rises to the level of a documentary, in which case you might expect the depiction of depravity to be senseless and obscene. Instead the film raises a litany of questions for which it offers no answers. Why does the mother continually disregard the abuse she is fully aware her daughter is suffering at the hands of her husband? Does the mother have any concern for the chances of her younger daughter being subjected to the same abuse from her husband? Is severing the relationship between both daughters to be considered healthy? Is abandoning her abused daughter the mother's misconceived idea as to how to make amends? What is accomplished or signified by the abused daughter's refusal to name her abuser, purely out of inescapable love for her mother who doesn't protect her? How does the abused and then abandoned daughter relate to the world around her and how will she in the future? With utmost respect to the acting talents of the cast, the few undeveloped phrases that are stated, which one hopes will provide insight into the questions raised by the film, fail to suffice in properly addressing the base topics depicted. One could easily glean from a department of children and families case file the same pain, revulsion, and sorrow this film presents. Quite disappointing, but highly recommended to those film viewers who enjoy or are satisfied with dismal portrayals of tragedy which offer nothing in the way of redemption or adequate depiction of the subject matter at hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This story is so southern.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ttratar21
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched this movie on Lifetime, and was reminded of my time living in the south. When I was living in the south, time after time, I would see a husband who was a total scumbag, and his wife would never leave him. In other parts of the United States there would be a separation instantly. But in the South Women are afraid to stand up to their man. This movie was tough to watch. This little girl was severely abused, and molested by her step- father, and her mother refused to do anything about it. When she told her daughter at the end of the movie that she still Love's Glen, I was sick to my stomach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bastard out of Carolina
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lyndsay Page
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece.It deals with a touchy subject. The actors and actresses play there parts so well. You can actually see the sadness in Malone and the hate in Eldard's face. Its sad because things like this happen all the time. This movie is not some fake movie that someone made up in there head. Its truth this does happen to people. And its sad because Leigh's character as the lonely mother is real there are mothers out there that are stuck between loving there child or there lover. Its a sad situation and this movie shows you life. This movie is for sure excellent 10 stars from me. I would recommend this movie to anyone who likes serious movies that just have you on the edge of your seat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Messy Southern Gothic with too many characters and a lumpy narrative...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston, an unequivocally wise and intuitive actress, takes on a dark, rambling Southern tale for her first directorial effort, an adaptation of Dorothy Allison's book with so many peaks and valleys it plays like a chopped up TV mini-series, the CliffsNotes version. Story centers on an illegitimate young girl (Jena Malone) in the South during the 1950s and her woebegone waitress-mother (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who has had terrible luck with men. Seems her third husband (Ron Eldard) has a violent streak when provoked, and when he begins lashing out at the child in both violent and sexual ways, relatives step in to help her. Rare to find a cast so full of solid acting talent, yet this script takes great pains to introduce characters without giving them anything to do (some of the relatives, like the uptown cousin played by Christina Ricci or Dermot Mulroney's doomed Husband #2, appear and disappear in record time). The central performances are fine, with pre-teen Malone doing some very nice work; a child actress with a solemn reserve and faraway eyes, Malone is perhaps too studied in her approach (she isn't an untrained natural), yet Huston handles her gently and some of the strongest moments are the ones where Malone is allowed to take a breath and emote. However, this film, a failed theatrical effort which was sold instead to cable television, is packed (or padded, as it were) with short-hand tragedy, and the editing is so poor and the narrative so confusing you might need a scorecard to keep up with all the melodrama. Despite her sensitivity in staging some shattering scenes, Huston doesn't allow the picture to flow, to absorb the audience. It's jagged and piqued, and one recoils from it instead of being drawn into the plot. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful, disturbing, heinous is the human stain.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael O'Keefe
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anjelica Huston's directorial debut is based on a novel by Dorothy Allison. A potent, emotional driven drama deep in the ways of poor South Carolina. It is post-WWII and a young Anney Boatwright(Jennifer Jason Leigh)gives birth to an illegitimate child. She names her baby Ruth Anne(Jena Malone), but she will be known as 'Bone'. Life is difficult for the struggling waitress, who has another daughter and is forced to bury a husband(Dermot Mulroney)killed in an auto accident. Anney's brother Earle(Michael Rooker)introduces her to her future...Glen Waddell(Ron Eldard). The two marry, but soon Glen starts taking his anger out on 'Bone'. The bonds between mother and daughter will become dangerously strained when Anney finds her husband raping 'Bone'. This following the constant violent physical abuse of the child behind her mother's back. There is a strong ensemble cast, but the young Malone is brilliant beyond her age. Other players: Glenn Headly, Grace Zabriske, Diana Scarwid, Lyle Lovett, Christina Ricci, Pat Hingle and narrated by Laura Dern. Rated R for the strong depiction of sexual and violent abuse including two rape scenes of a child.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Favourite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    loumcp
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a terrific film that explored painful subject matter and did it well. The creeping malice and cowardice of Glenn (a brave role for Ron Eldard) was terrifying and will be recognized as realistic by any survivor of child abuse, as will Bone's sense of isolation and responsibility for "keeping the peace." The women in the film acted their roles with real strength and tenderness - particularly, I thought, Glenne Headly as Aunt Ruth. Jena Malone was a natural. I also loved Grace Zabriskie as Grandma. Displaying the lives of people commonly labeled "poor white trash" could have gone horribly wrong, but "Bastard" doesn't patronize or demean. One wishes that those who made hay about the brutal child-rape scene in this film would devote this energy to protesting the actual occurrence of such things. The graphic nature of this scene was disturbing, to be sure, but not gratuitous or exploitative. A worthwhile rendering of Dorothy Allison's semi-autobiographical novel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought provoking story.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (luster1@flash.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We see a lot of nice, beautiful, adrenalin rush, horror, on the screen, these days, but not a lot of thought provoking pseudo docudrama. This story parallels social attitudes, during a period in which our parents lived, when a kid wasn't bottle-fed information, about everything, via movies, TV, & the Internet. This movie isn't just about abuse of a child, but the struggles of the unlearned adult poor, "just making it", in every quarter, of the United States, during the '40s. I've enjoyed J. Leigh for a good many years, & found her up to par, in this movie. I'm gaining a tremendous respect, for the abilities of Miss Malone. I just watched, last night, another of her efforts, "The Ballad of Lucy ????" last night. I recommend this film, even for a minor (with parent present for questions). Ted Luster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The movie was good. Although, disturbing (Spoiler*)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StrikinglyStunning
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have read this book, Bastard Out Of Carolina by Dorthy Allison, and it was a great book. It was so good, I was interested in watching the movie. It came on Lifetime, and the movie basically covered the book. It's about this girl Anne Boatwright (Jennifer Jason Leigh), who meets this guy Glen Waddell (Ron Eldard). At first, he is this good looking guy who is really nice and wants to be the father of Bone (Jena Malone) and Reese. He asks Reese to call him "Daddy" and she has no problem calling him that. Bone, can't say it for the simple fact that he's not really her dad. He gets angry. This was a man who was all about control. He gets Ruth Anne pregnant, and while she was giving birth, Glen , the two kids, Reese & Bone were in the car. The kids were asleep. Glen wakes Bone up and rapes her in the car. -VERY DISTURBING SCENE It was too horrible to watch, I had to change the channel. I didn't have the stomach for it. It all about physical abuse, he beats her because Bone was "direspecting him", and Ruth Anne believes Glen over her own daughter Bone. Ruth Anne sends Bone to go and live with Aunt Alma. When no one was in the house with her, Glen rides along, and goes over there. Unfortunately, he rapes her again. Again, I had to change the channel. It was absolutely horrific what he was doing to Bone. The movie is VERY graphic, you see almost everything. I didn't have the stomach to watch all those gruesome parts. I remember watching Sleepers, with Ron Eldard, now, I don't think I can look at him the same. He's good at playing bad guys. It was a good movie. (Although, very disturbing. I' not sure I can watch it again)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
