<filme>
 <id>
  457
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119152
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Free Willy 3: O Resgate
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A teenage Jesse and old friend Randolph try to foil an illegal whaler threatening Willy and his pregnant mate.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Willy the whale is back, this time threatened by illegal whalers making money off sushi. Jesse, now 16, has taken a job on an orca-researching ship, along with old friend Randolph and a sarcastic scientist, Drew. On the whaler's ship is captain John Wesley and his son, Max, who isn't really pleased about his father's job, but doesn't have the gut to say so. Along the way, Willy reunites with Jesse, who helps Max realize that whales are a little more than just cheese burgers.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   whaler
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   whale
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   scientist
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Sam Pillsbury
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Keith Walker
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   John Mattson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jason James Richter
  </ator>
  <ator>
   August Schellenberg
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Annie Corley
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the screenplay for "Free Willy 3: The Rescue" follows its politically correct formula without a whole lot of style
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1998, a man named Steinar Bastesen publicly declared his opinion that the money spent on training the captive orca Keiko should instead be spent on grinding the poor animal into six tons of meatballs as foreign aid for the starving people in Africa. This coming from the same man who would probably encourage families with more than a single pet to grind up one of their cats for the villages of China. Well, Mr. Bastesen would have probably beenand just might have been, depending if he saw the movie or notjust as infuriated by the content of the last movie that Keiko had starred in. The movie is "Free Willy 3: The Rescue," and it takes a politically correct hand holding a politically correct spear and jabs it into the guts of people like Mr. Bastesen. I support the cause all the way. I just wish I could support the movie for its dramatic content. Again, this is a review of the movie, not the movie's cause. "Free Willy 3: The Rescue" is a prime example of an underwritten kids' movie sequel: something we unfortunately get too much of these days. It is the third anduntil just recentlylast installment in the popular franchise about a young boy (Jason James Richter) and his friendship with a six-ton whale (Keiko). In the previous two movies, Mr. Richter saved Keiko first from a neglectful theme park owner and then later from oil-infested waters. Now the threat comes from a band of poachers, the leader of whom is taking his son along on the hunt for the very first time. As one would expect, the son (Vincent Berry) doesn't conform to his father's illicit way of making a living and ends up siding with Mr. Richter to save Willy and his family. There are good elements to "Free Willy 3." One of the promising dynamic between Mr. Berry and the superb actor Patrick Kilpatrick as his father. The latter does a particularly good job portraying a man who devotedly loves his family and blindly does what he does partially out of the desire to support his loved ones and partially because his family tree essentially demands it of him. His grandfather harpooned sperm whales so he feels he should harpoon orcas. I also appreciated how well Mr. Berry displayed enthusiasm at the beginninggoing on a big event with his fatherand then the horror when he first sees an innocent animal getting run clean through with a harpoon. The emotion in this sequence doubles the emotionand lessens the gimmicky disturbancefrom a similar scene in Michael Anderson's pretentious 1977 film "Orca." I also enjoyed Mr. Richter's third-time-around performance. The only other returning character is August Schellenberg; he's reliable as well. Apart from that, I did enjoy some of the scenery when the characters on land; there's something magnetic about looking at a coastal village: the docks, the boats, the water shoreline, the coastal trees. It's the sort of place one thinks about retiring to someday. However, the screenplay to "Free Willy 3" follows its politically correct formula without a whole lot of style. Now the first "Free Willy" movie, released in 1993, did not say anything we didn't already know about the issue of whales in captivity, but it approached the subject with a great deal of heart. Hence why it won over the hearts of many children, myself included. But John Mattson's script for the third movie does not have very much of this, and there is zero sense of friendship between Jason James Richter and the whale. As far as the movie is concerned, these two just met for the first time and Mr. Richter is merely fascinated by the whale. And even the whale is not given much to do. The movie might as well be about a trivial whale, not one that starred in two previous pictures. The animatronic stand-ins for Keiko are utilized too often now, and the jaws open and close with too much hectic speed to convince that it's flesh and blood. A scene where the protagonist feed Willy and his mate oranges is very revealing. There's no sensation from past events, such as the time Willy saved Mr. Richter from drowning in the tank in the first film. And although Vincent Berry does have some cute scenes between him and the whale (at one point they start to play volleyball with the whale launching the ball back onto the decks of the boat), there are not enough of them. The movie overall is a lazy effort with a rushed mindset. It ironically comes alive mostly when it is on land and is not so exciting when on the water. And even the usually interesting concluding shots of the whales swimming and leaping freely through the frigid North Pacific waters is disappointing this time around, as they are merely reusing stock shots from the previous two pictures. It's really jarring when at one point the whales are moving behind a blue sky, then a red-laced dusk setting, and then a blue one again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad as far as sequels go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am going to start off by saying I really like the first two Free Willy movies. I would hardly call them the best movies ever, but they are very nice movies and I think underrated. This sequel is a worthy one. While there is a predictable story, some weak spots in the script and a lacklustre ending Free Willy 3:The Rescue is a nice and worthy sequel, that could have been so much worse. Flaws aside, Free Willy 3 does have some stunning cinematography, and I loved the scene when Randolph throws the oranges in the water. I also loved the scenes between Nikki and Willy, and the one when Nikki gives birth which was brilliantly done. The score is absolutely beautiful, the pacing is brisk and the direction is amiable. And the characters are appealing especially Willy and Nikki, while Jesse and Max are great characters and the father is a sympathetic figure even for the villain of the piece, except I don't see him as a proper villain, just someone who means well but doesn't know exactly what he wants. The acting is good too, Jason James Richter and Vincent Berry are very likable, August Schellenberg makes a welcome return as Randolph and Patrick Kalpatrick does a great job with his character. All in all, a pleasant family film. 7/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free Willy 3: The Rescue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first wildlife family film is alright fun, the sequel wasn't as likable (once in a while), so I had to finish the trilogy, and see which of all of them is most bearable. Basically, (Jesse Jason James) Richter is now sixteen years old, and has taken a job on a ship as both researcher and protector of Orca whales. He is working with old friend Randolph Johnson (August Schellenberg), sarcastic scientist Drew Halbert (Annie Corley), and on the ocean he is of course reunited with old friend Willy the Whale (Keiko). Meanwhile, on a whaling ship is John Wesley (Patrick Kilpatrick) and his young son Max (Vincent Berry), who after seeing many of them isn't very keen on killing the Orca whales. While he doesn't have the guts to say no to his Dad, Jesse gets Max to meet Willy and his new girlfriend who is pregnant with their baby, and he realises that his Dad is doing something illegal and nasty to nature. Also starring Tasha Simms as Mary Wesley, Peter LaCroix as 1st Mate Sanderson, Stephen E. Miller as Dineen, Ian Tracey as Kron and Matthew Walker as Captain Drake. The problem with this one is that the human story takes over and we hardly see enough of the beautiful, originally show stealing creatures, the birth of a baby nearly makes up for the lack of time they are used, but the first film is always going to be the one to watch. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid "A"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ihdg_2334
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Granted, I understand how others were expecting adventure kind of things in this movie but it was not bad at all. This movie was more, how I like to say nonfiction than fiction meaning that it tells of what really happens without exaggerating the facts like most movies do. Most people who gave it a low rating were expecting exaggerated things, amazing adventure like no other and hence they were disappointed. This move, though short (that's what I thought), was simple and sensitive. The ending was rather lame they could have spiced it up like sending the guy to jail or something like that but right afterward you see the female whale give birth-hence with the facts without being too much like a lot of movies are nowadays. So this movie deserves a solid "A" and even Sisko and Ebert gave it two thumps up and they are movie experts, so there you go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ignore the low rating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EJ Lorge
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a VERY entertaining family film. I had not seen either previous Willy flics, yet I was into it from beginning to end (along with my 4 year old daughter). So why the low rating? My hunch is people judge family films by adult criteria. Which is totally absurd, since we all know children's movies today are far superior than 95% of the so called, adult films coming out (which ironically enough, seem made for audiences with a teenager's intelligence). In short: ignore the low rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tedious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is the worst of the Free Willy movies,in my opinion.this thing just plodded along,slower than a snail's pace.i found it tedious,to say the least.it has the shortest running time of all three movies,but it felt longer than the other two.the story was also thin and uninteresting.there is virtually no excitement in this film.there are also very few scenes with the whales.the title makes it sound like it could be a movie with some adventure,but it sure isn't.i nearly turned this one off before it was over.i stuck with it,in the hope it would get better.it didn't,and i wish i had stopped watching.for me,Free Willy 3 is a 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its yet another adventure for Willy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukepic123
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, here we go again. The blonde dude is getting older and so it Willy time for one more adventure I think. This film wouldn't be so down rated it it maybe had been the second instalment. By now we have seen enough of the same stuff. In Willy 1 it was kind of boring and in 2 it was a little better but nothing too exciting, apart front he exploding boat of oil. So I would suggest watching number 1 (If you like wales) and number 2 (If you really love wales). But if you don't pass on by the whole lot of them. This is the final instalment, if your desperate for Willy watch, if not... Watch Spykids. Not saying thats any better either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this movie have such a low rating?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hhallmark
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay guys, the fact that this movie got such a low rating really makes my blood boil! If you can't appreciate such a touching film as Free Willy 3: The Rescue, I'd like to see what you guys watch. This movie really touched me, so did the other two movies in the trilogy. I'll admit, this movie may not have been as good as the other two, which is why I'm only giving it a 9 out of 10, but it still is quite the masterpiece. It's better than any of those other bullshit movies about animals, like air bud or MVP! Those movies were garbage and have absolutely nothing on free Willy. Free Willy 3: The Rescue, has, and always will have, a special place in my heart. I grew up with this trilogy and I hold it very dear to my heart. If you're a parent and you want your child to see some quality film making, I advise you to rent Free Willy 3. This movie doesn't have any violence or anything that'll warp your child's mind into growing up to be some crack-head, animal beating criminal, which is what most movies tend to be doing these days. No, this movie will inspire your kid to do good with his life, it'll make your child appreciate the beauty of animal life. If you haven't seen this movie, I recommend you watch it asap. It will appeal to people of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK this is officially the most stupid animal on the planet earth!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sweetooth-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    right in the first movie: whale gets caught, gets freed...fair enough Second time: gets caught again...well everyone makes mistakes third time: what a stupid freaking whale! oh look a big net, lets swim into it, oh wait what happened the last time i did that?? oh too late I'm doing freaking circus tricks again. actually no the most stupid animal ever is the Barn Owl... its so stupid it has to have its home in its name so it doesn't forget where it lives !! i mean come on! honestly! i once saw a barn owl. it was in a pet store, i was rather impressed with its ability to turn its head, i didn't really like pet stores. i always wanted a mouse. which i would call Guinness. isn't that the greatest name for a mouse ever? you have to remember Guinness is rather nice, well because it Irish wow Irish alcohol, whatever next. and yes Guinness is black and white just like a certain stupid freaking killer whale named Willy. (see what i did there, what a link back) my belief is that dumb ass whale should be shot. i give this movie: -3 out of 16.2
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it was OK
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Kristycoolbeans@comcast.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's nothing really wrong w/this movie, but it's not as enchanting as the 1st 2 & if nothing else forces the story to an end. Jesse, 16, & Randolph are 1ce again siting whales as a job, & discover that Willy has a girlfriend, Nikki - who's pregnant! Meanwhile, 10-year-old Max gets to go "fishing" w/his father John, which is a big deal. But he falls overboard & is saved by Willy, & when he learns that John is actually an illegal whaler it upsets him - but he doesn't have the nerve to say so. Jesse's harmonica signal is discovered by John's crew, & when they realize it draws Willy they plan to exploit it to call whales. Jesse knows what danger Willy & his future family are in. When he meets Max, he pretends to be looking for work as a whaler, then reveals he knows John's work & wants to stop it, while showing Max Willy. Now Max tries to figure out whether or how to tell his father to stop hunting, while Jesse & Randolph try to get proof of his illegal actions. Really it's a good movie, but not as interesting as the others - the action is a bit slow. I take it as a warning sign that Max, not Jesse, is the 1st character shown. The friendship between Jesse & Willy is still there (of course) but not the similarity they have in families - in the 1st, they both miss theirs & share pain, in the 2nd Jesse learns his mom dies & he has a brother while Willy rejoins his family, but here Willy is about to become a father & Jesse definitely isn't. No girlfriend either - wonder why, he was interested in girls in the 2nd. The Greenwoods are mentioned 1ce but never shown, when Max describes a large family: "It's like any other family, you know", Jesse only replies "No, I don't." Except some music, Randolph's Indian culture, something I've always loved, is gone - the story isn't even told to Max, unlike Elvis. The asst, Drew, is pain & gives Jesse a hard time. This is good, but I prefer the others - I've never been a sequels fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the screenplay for "Free Willy 3: The Rescue" follows its politically correct formula without a whole lot of style
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1998, a man named Steinar Bastesen publicly declared his opinion that the money spent on training the captive orca Keiko should instead be spent on grinding the poor animal into six tons of meatballs as foreign aid for the starving people in Africa. This coming from the same man who would probably encourage families with more than a single pet to grind up one of their cats for the villages of China. Well, Mr. Bastesen would have probably beenand just might have been, depending if he saw the movie or notjust as infuriated by the content of the last movie that Keiko had starred in. The movie is "Free Willy 3: The Rescue," and it takes a politically correct hand holding a politically correct spear and jabs it into the guts of people like Mr. Bastesen. I support the cause all the way. I just wish I could support the movie for its dramatic content. Again, this is a review of the movie, not the movie's cause. "Free Willy 3: The Rescue" is a prime example of an underwritten kids' movie sequel: something we unfortunately get too much of these days. It is the third anduntil just recentlylast installment in the popular franchise about a young boy (Jason James Richter) and his friendship with a six-ton whale (Keiko). In the previous two movies, Mr. Richter saved Keiko first from a neglectful theme park owner and then later from oil-infested waters. Now the threat comes from a band of poachers, the leader of whom is taking his son along on the hunt for the very first time. As one would expect, the son (Vincent Berry) doesn't conform to his father's illicit way of making a living and ends up siding with Mr. Richter to save Willy and his family. There are good elements to "Free Willy 3." One of the promising dynamic between Mr. Berry and the superb actor Patrick Kilpatrick as his father. The latter does a particularly good job portraying a man who devotedly loves his family and blindly does what he does partially out of the desire to support his loved ones and partially because his family tree essentially demands it of him. His grandfather harpooned sperm whales so he feels he should harpoon orcas. I also appreciated how well Mr. Berry displayed enthusiasm at the beginninggoing on a big event with his fatherand then the horror when he first sees an innocent animal getting run clean through with a harpoon. The emotion in this sequence doubles the emotionand lessens the gimmicky disturbancefrom a similar scene in Michael Anderson's pretentious 1977 film "Orca." I also enjoyed Mr. Richter's third-time-around performance. The only other returning character is August Schellenberg; he's reliable as well. Apart from that, I did enjoy some of the scenery when the characters on land; there's something magnetic about looking at a coastal village: the docks, the boats, the water shoreline, the coastal trees. It's the sort of place one thinks about retiring to someday. However, the screenplay to "Free Willy 3" follows its politically correct formula without a whole lot of style. Now the first "Free Willy" movie, released in 1993, did not say anything we didn't already know about the issue of whales in captivity, but it approached the subject with a great deal of heart. Hence why it won over the hearts of many children, myself included. But John Mattson's script for the third movie does not have very much of this, and there is zero sense of friendship between Jason James Richter and the whale. As far as the movie is concerned, these two just met for the first time and Mr. Richter is merely fascinated by the whale. And even the whale is not given much to do. The movie might as well be about a trivial whale, not one that starred in two previous pictures. The animatronic stand-ins for Keiko are utilized too often now, and the jaws open and close with too much hectic speed to convince that it's flesh and blood. A scene where the protagonist feed Willy and his mate oranges is very revealing. There's no sensation from past events, such as the time Willy saved Mr. Richter from drowning in the tank in the first film. And although Vincent Berry does have some cute scenes between him and the whale (at one point they start to play volleyball with the whale launching the ball back onto the decks of the boat), there are not enough of them. The movie overall is a lazy effort with a rushed mindset. It ironically comes alive mostly when it is on land and is not so exciting when on the water. And even the usually interesting concluding shots of the whales swimming and leaping freely through the frigid North Pacific waters is disappointing this time around, as they are merely reusing stock shots from the previous two pictures. It's really jarring when at one point the whales are moving behind a blue sky, then a red-laced dusk setting, and then a blue one again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad as far as sequels go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am going to start off by saying I really like the first two Free Willy movies. I would hardly call them the best movies ever, but they are very nice movies and I think underrated. This sequel is a worthy one. While there is a predictable story, some weak spots in the script and a lacklustre ending Free Willy 3:The Rescue is a nice and worthy sequel, that could have been so much worse. Flaws aside, Free Willy 3 does have some stunning cinematography, and I loved the scene when Randolph throws the oranges in the water. I also loved the scenes between Nikki and Willy, and the one when Nikki gives birth which was brilliantly done. The score is absolutely beautiful, the pacing is brisk and the direction is amiable. And the characters are appealing especially Willy and Nikki, while Jesse and Max are great characters and the father is a sympathetic figure even for the villain of the piece, except I don't see him as a proper villain, just someone who means well but doesn't know exactly what he wants. The acting is good too, Jason James Richter and Vincent Berry are very likable, August Schellenberg makes a welcome return as Randolph and Patrick Kalpatrick does a great job with his character. All in all, a pleasant family film. 7/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free Willy 3: The Rescue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first wildlife family film is alright fun, the sequel wasn't as likable (once in a while), so I had to finish the trilogy, and see which of all of them is most bearable. Basically, (Jesse Jason James) Richter is now sixteen years old, and has taken a job on a ship as both researcher and protector of Orca whales. He is working with old friend Randolph Johnson (August Schellenberg), sarcastic scientist Drew Halbert (Annie Corley), and on the ocean he is of course reunited with old friend Willy the Whale (Keiko). Meanwhile, on a whaling ship is John Wesley (Patrick Kilpatrick) and his young son Max (Vincent Berry), who after seeing many of them isn't very keen on killing the Orca whales. While he doesn't have the guts to say no to his Dad, Jesse gets Max to meet Willy and his new girlfriend who is pregnant with their baby, and he realises that his Dad is doing something illegal and nasty to nature. Also starring Tasha Simms as Mary Wesley, Peter LaCroix as 1st Mate Sanderson, Stephen E. Miller as Dineen, Ian Tracey as Kron and Matthew Walker as Captain Drake. The problem with this one is that the human story takes over and we hardly see enough of the beautiful, originally show stealing creatures, the birth of a baby nearly makes up for the lack of time they are used, but the first film is always going to be the one to watch. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid "A"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ihdg_2334
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Granted, I understand how others were expecting adventure kind of things in this movie but it was not bad at all. This movie was more, how I like to say nonfiction than fiction meaning that it tells of what really happens without exaggerating the facts like most movies do. Most people who gave it a low rating were expecting exaggerated things, amazing adventure like no other and hence they were disappointed. This move, though short (that's what I thought), was simple and sensitive. The ending was rather lame they could have spiced it up like sending the guy to jail or something like that but right afterward you see the female whale give birth-hence with the facts without being too much like a lot of movies are nowadays. So this movie deserves a solid "A" and even Sisko and Ebert gave it two thumps up and they are movie experts, so there you go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ignore the low rating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EJ Lorge
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a VERY entertaining family film. I had not seen either previous Willy flics, yet I was into it from beginning to end (along with my 4 year old daughter). So why the low rating? My hunch is people judge family films by adult criteria. Which is totally absurd, since we all know children's movies today are far superior than 95% of the so called, adult films coming out (which ironically enough, seem made for audiences with a teenager's intelligence). In short: ignore the low rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tedious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is the worst of the Free Willy movies,in my opinion.this thing just plodded along,slower than a snail's pace.i found it tedious,to say the least.it has the shortest running time of all three movies,but it felt longer than the other two.the story was also thin and uninteresting.there is virtually no excitement in this film.there are also very few scenes with the whales.the title makes it sound like it could be a movie with some adventure,but it sure isn't.i nearly turned this one off before it was over.i stuck with it,in the hope it would get better.it didn't,and i wish i had stopped watching.for me,Free Willy 3 is a 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its yet another adventure for Willy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukepic123
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, here we go again. The blonde dude is getting older and so it Willy time for one more adventure I think. This film wouldn't be so down rated it it maybe had been the second instalment. By now we have seen enough of the same stuff. In Willy 1 it was kind of boring and in 2 it was a little better but nothing too exciting, apart front he exploding boat of oil. So I would suggest watching number 1 (If you like wales) and number 2 (If you really love wales). But if you don't pass on by the whole lot of them. This is the final instalment, if your desperate for Willy watch, if not... Watch Spykids. Not saying thats any better either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this movie have such a low rating?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hhallmark
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay guys, the fact that this movie got such a low rating really makes my blood boil! If you can't appreciate such a touching film as Free Willy 3: The Rescue, I'd like to see what you guys watch. This movie really touched me, so did the other two movies in the trilogy. I'll admit, this movie may not have been as good as the other two, which is why I'm only giving it a 9 out of 10, but it still is quite the masterpiece. It's better than any of those other bullshit movies about animals, like air bud or MVP! Those movies were garbage and have absolutely nothing on free Willy. Free Willy 3: The Rescue, has, and always will have, a special place in my heart. I grew up with this trilogy and I hold it very dear to my heart. If you're a parent and you want your child to see some quality film making, I advise you to rent Free Willy 3. This movie doesn't have any violence or anything that'll warp your child's mind into growing up to be some crack-head, animal beating criminal, which is what most movies tend to be doing these days. No, this movie will inspire your kid to do good with his life, it'll make your child appreciate the beauty of animal life. If you haven't seen this movie, I recommend you watch it asap. It will appeal to people of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK this is officially the most stupid animal on the planet earth!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sweetooth-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    right in the first movie: whale gets caught, gets freed...fair enough Second time: gets caught again...well everyone makes mistakes third time: what a stupid freaking whale! oh look a big net, lets swim into it, oh wait what happened the last time i did that?? oh too late I'm doing freaking circus tricks again. actually no the most stupid animal ever is the Barn Owl... its so stupid it has to have its home in its name so it doesn't forget where it lives !! i mean come on! honestly! i once saw a barn owl. it was in a pet store, i was rather impressed with its ability to turn its head, i didn't really like pet stores. i always wanted a mouse. which i would call Guinness. isn't that the greatest name for a mouse ever? you have to remember Guinness is rather nice, well because it Irish wow Irish alcohol, whatever next. and yes Guinness is black and white just like a certain stupid freaking killer whale named Willy. (see what i did there, what a link back) my belief is that dumb ass whale should be shot. i give this movie: -3 out of 16.2
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it was OK
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Kristycoolbeans@comcast.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's nothing really wrong w/this movie, but it's not as enchanting as the 1st 2 & if nothing else forces the story to an end. Jesse, 16, & Randolph are 1ce again siting whales as a job, & discover that Willy has a girlfriend, Nikki - who's pregnant! Meanwhile, 10-year-old Max gets to go "fishing" w/his father John, which is a big deal. But he falls overboard & is saved by Willy, & when he learns that John is actually an illegal whaler it upsets him - but he doesn't have the nerve to say so. Jesse's harmonica signal is discovered by John's crew, & when they realize it draws Willy they plan to exploit it to call whales. Jesse knows what danger Willy & his future family are in. When he meets Max, he pretends to be looking for work as a whaler, then reveals he knows John's work & wants to stop it, while showing Max Willy. Now Max tries to figure out whether or how to tell his father to stop hunting, while Jesse & Randolph try to get proof of his illegal actions. Really it's a good movie, but not as interesting as the others - the action is a bit slow. I take it as a warning sign that Max, not Jesse, is the 1st character shown. The friendship between Jesse & Willy is still there (of course) but not the similarity they have in families - in the 1st, they both miss theirs & share pain, in the 2nd Jesse learns his mom dies & he has a brother while Willy rejoins his family, but here Willy is about to become a father & Jesse definitely isn't. No girlfriend either - wonder why, he was interested in girls in the 2nd. The Greenwoods are mentioned 1ce but never shown, when Max describes a large family: "It's like any other family, you know", Jesse only replies "No, I don't." Except some music, Randolph's Indian culture, something I've always loved, is gone - the story isn't even told to Max, unlike Elvis. The asst, Drew, is pain & gives Jesse a hard time. This is good, but I prefer the others - I've never been a sequels fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the screenplay for "Free Willy 3: The Rescue" follows its politically correct formula without a whole lot of style
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1998, a man named Steinar Bastesen publicly declared his opinion that the money spent on training the captive orca Keiko should instead be spent on grinding the poor animal into six tons of meatballs as foreign aid for the starving people in Africa. This coming from the same man who would probably encourage families with more than a single pet to grind up one of their cats for the villages of China. Well, Mr. Bastesen would have probably beenand just might have been, depending if he saw the movie or notjust as infuriated by the content of the last movie that Keiko had starred in. The movie is "Free Willy 3: The Rescue," and it takes a politically correct hand holding a politically correct spear and jabs it into the guts of people like Mr. Bastesen. I support the cause all the way. I just wish I could support the movie for its dramatic content. Again, this is a review of the movie, not the movie's cause. "Free Willy 3: The Rescue" is a prime example of an underwritten kids' movie sequel: something we unfortunately get too much of these days. It is the third anduntil just recentlylast installment in the popular franchise about a young boy (Jason James Richter) and his friendship with a six-ton whale (Keiko). In the previous two movies, Mr. Richter saved Keiko first from a neglectful theme park owner and then later from oil-infested waters. Now the threat comes from a band of poachers, the leader of whom is taking his son along on the hunt for the very first time. As one would expect, the son (Vincent Berry) doesn't conform to his father's illicit way of making a living and ends up siding with Mr. Richter to save Willy and his family. There are good elements to "Free Willy 3." One of the promising dynamic between Mr. Berry and the superb actor Patrick Kilpatrick as his father. The latter does a particularly good job portraying a man who devotedly loves his family and blindly does what he does partially out of the desire to support his loved ones and partially because his family tree essentially demands it of him. His grandfather harpooned sperm whales so he feels he should harpoon orcas. I also appreciated how well Mr. Berry displayed enthusiasm at the beginninggoing on a big event with his fatherand then the horror when he first sees an innocent animal getting run clean through with a harpoon. The emotion in this sequence doubles the emotionand lessens the gimmicky disturbancefrom a similar scene in Michael Anderson's pretentious 1977 film "Orca." I also enjoyed Mr. Richter's third-time-around performance. The only other returning character is August Schellenberg; he's reliable as well. Apart from that, I did enjoy some of the scenery when the characters on land; there's something magnetic about looking at a coastal village: the docks, the boats, the water shoreline, the coastal trees. It's the sort of place one thinks about retiring to someday. However, the screenplay to "Free Willy 3" follows its politically correct formula without a whole lot of style. Now the first "Free Willy" movie, released in 1993, did not say anything we didn't already know about the issue of whales in captivity, but it approached the subject with a great deal of heart. Hence why it won over the hearts of many children, myself included. But John Mattson's script for the third movie does not have very much of this, and there is zero sense of friendship between Jason James Richter and the whale. As far as the movie is concerned, these two just met for the first time and Mr. Richter is merely fascinated by the whale. And even the whale is not given much to do. The movie might as well be about a trivial whale, not one that starred in two previous pictures. The animatronic stand-ins for Keiko are utilized too often now, and the jaws open and close with too much hectic speed to convince that it's flesh and blood. A scene where the protagonist feed Willy and his mate oranges is very revealing. There's no sensation from past events, such as the time Willy saved Mr. Richter from drowning in the tank in the first film. And although Vincent Berry does have some cute scenes between him and the whale (at one point they start to play volleyball with the whale launching the ball back onto the decks of the boat), there are not enough of them. The movie overall is a lazy effort with a rushed mindset. It ironically comes alive mostly when it is on land and is not so exciting when on the water. And even the usually interesting concluding shots of the whales swimming and leaping freely through the frigid North Pacific waters is disappointing this time around, as they are merely reusing stock shots from the previous two pictures. It's really jarring when at one point the whales are moving behind a blue sky, then a red-laced dusk setting, and then a blue one again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad as far as sequels go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am going to start off by saying I really like the first two Free Willy movies. I would hardly call them the best movies ever, but they are very nice movies and I think underrated. This sequel is a worthy one. While there is a predictable story, some weak spots in the script and a lacklustre ending Free Willy 3:The Rescue is a nice and worthy sequel, that could have been so much worse. Flaws aside, Free Willy 3 does have some stunning cinematography, and I loved the scene when Randolph throws the oranges in the water. I also loved the scenes between Nikki and Willy, and the one when Nikki gives birth which was brilliantly done. The score is absolutely beautiful, the pacing is brisk and the direction is amiable. And the characters are appealing especially Willy and Nikki, while Jesse and Max are great characters and the father is a sympathetic figure even for the villain of the piece, except I don't see him as a proper villain, just someone who means well but doesn't know exactly what he wants. The acting is good too, Jason James Richter and Vincent Berry are very likable, August Schellenberg makes a welcome return as Randolph and Patrick Kalpatrick does a great job with his character. All in all, a pleasant family film. 7/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Free Willy 3: The Rescue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first wildlife family film is alright fun, the sequel wasn't as likable (once in a while), so I had to finish the trilogy, and see which of all of them is most bearable. Basically, (Jesse Jason James) Richter is now sixteen years old, and has taken a job on a ship as both researcher and protector of Orca whales. He is working with old friend Randolph Johnson (August Schellenberg), sarcastic scientist Drew Halbert (Annie Corley), and on the ocean he is of course reunited with old friend Willy the Whale (Keiko). Meanwhile, on a whaling ship is John Wesley (Patrick Kilpatrick) and his young son Max (Vincent Berry), who after seeing many of them isn't very keen on killing the Orca whales. While he doesn't have the guts to say no to his Dad, Jesse gets Max to meet Willy and his new girlfriend who is pregnant with their baby, and he realises that his Dad is doing something illegal and nasty to nature. Also starring Tasha Simms as Mary Wesley, Peter LaCroix as 1st Mate Sanderson, Stephen E. Miller as Dineen, Ian Tracey as Kron and Matthew Walker as Captain Drake. The problem with this one is that the human story takes over and we hardly see enough of the beautiful, originally show stealing creatures, the birth of a baby nearly makes up for the lack of time they are used, but the first film is always going to be the one to watch. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid "A"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ihdg_2334
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Granted, I understand how others were expecting adventure kind of things in this movie but it was not bad at all. This movie was more, how I like to say nonfiction than fiction meaning that it tells of what really happens without exaggerating the facts like most movies do. Most people who gave it a low rating were expecting exaggerated things, amazing adventure like no other and hence they were disappointed. This move, though short (that's what I thought), was simple and sensitive. The ending was rather lame they could have spiced it up like sending the guy to jail or something like that but right afterward you see the female whale give birth-hence with the facts without being too much like a lot of movies are nowadays. So this movie deserves a solid "A" and even Sisko and Ebert gave it two thumps up and they are movie experts, so there you go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ignore the low rating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EJ Lorge
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a VERY entertaining family film. I had not seen either previous Willy flics, yet I was into it from beginning to end (along with my 4 year old daughter). So why the low rating? My hunch is people judge family films by adult criteria. Which is totally absurd, since we all know children's movies today are far superior than 95% of the so called, adult films coming out (which ironically enough, seem made for audiences with a teenager's intelligence). In short: ignore the low rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tedious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is the worst of the Free Willy movies,in my opinion.this thing just plodded along,slower than a snail's pace.i found it tedious,to say the least.it has the shortest running time of all three movies,but it felt longer than the other two.the story was also thin and uninteresting.there is virtually no excitement in this film.there are also very few scenes with the whales.the title makes it sound like it could be a movie with some adventure,but it sure isn't.i nearly turned this one off before it was over.i stuck with it,in the hope it would get better.it didn't,and i wish i had stopped watching.for me,Free Willy 3 is a 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its yet another adventure for Willy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukepic123
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, here we go again. The blonde dude is getting older and so it Willy time for one more adventure I think. This film wouldn't be so down rated it it maybe had been the second instalment. By now we have seen enough of the same stuff. In Willy 1 it was kind of boring and in 2 it was a little better but nothing too exciting, apart front he exploding boat of oil. So I would suggest watching number 1 (If you like wales) and number 2 (If you really love wales). But if you don't pass on by the whole lot of them. This is the final instalment, if your desperate for Willy watch, if not... Watch Spykids. Not saying thats any better either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this movie have such a low rating?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hhallmark
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay guys, the fact that this movie got such a low rating really makes my blood boil! If you can't appreciate such a touching film as Free Willy 3: The Rescue, I'd like to see what you guys watch. This movie really touched me, so did the other two movies in the trilogy. I'll admit, this movie may not have been as good as the other two, which is why I'm only giving it a 9 out of 10, but it still is quite the masterpiece. It's better than any of those other bullshit movies about animals, like air bud or MVP! Those movies were garbage and have absolutely nothing on free Willy. Free Willy 3: The Rescue, has, and always will have, a special place in my heart. I grew up with this trilogy and I hold it very dear to my heart. If you're a parent and you want your child to see some quality film making, I advise you to rent Free Willy 3. This movie doesn't have any violence or anything that'll warp your child's mind into growing up to be some crack-head, animal beating criminal, which is what most movies tend to be doing these days. No, this movie will inspire your kid to do good with his life, it'll make your child appreciate the beauty of animal life. If you haven't seen this movie, I recommend you watch it asap. It will appeal to people of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK this is officially the most stupid animal on the planet earth!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sweetooth-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    right in the first movie: whale gets caught, gets freed...fair enough Second time: gets caught again...well everyone makes mistakes third time: what a stupid freaking whale! oh look a big net, lets swim into it, oh wait what happened the last time i did that?? oh too late I'm doing freaking circus tricks again. actually no the most stupid animal ever is the Barn Owl... its so stupid it has to have its home in its name so it doesn't forget where it lives !! i mean come on! honestly! i once saw a barn owl. it was in a pet store, i was rather impressed with its ability to turn its head, i didn't really like pet stores. i always wanted a mouse. which i would call Guinness. isn't that the greatest name for a mouse ever? you have to remember Guinness is rather nice, well because it Irish wow Irish alcohol, whatever next. and yes Guinness is black and white just like a certain stupid freaking killer whale named Willy. (see what i did there, what a link back) my belief is that dumb ass whale should be shot. i give this movie: -3 out of 16.2
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well, it was OK
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Kristycoolbeans@comcast.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's nothing really wrong w/this movie, but it's not as enchanting as the 1st 2 & if nothing else forces the story to an end. Jesse, 16, & Randolph are 1ce again siting whales as a job, & discover that Willy has a girlfriend, Nikki - who's pregnant! Meanwhile, 10-year-old Max gets to go "fishing" w/his father John, which is a big deal. But he falls overboard & is saved by Willy, & when he learns that John is actually an illegal whaler it upsets him - but he doesn't have the nerve to say so. Jesse's harmonica signal is discovered by John's crew, & when they realize it draws Willy they plan to exploit it to call whales. Jesse knows what danger Willy & his future family are in. When he meets Max, he pretends to be looking for work as a whaler, then reveals he knows John's work & wants to stop it, while showing Max Willy. Now Max tries to figure out whether or how to tell his father to stop hunting, while Jesse & Randolph try to get proof of his illegal actions. Really it's a good movie, but not as interesting as the others - the action is a bit slow. I take it as a warning sign that Max, not Jesse, is the 1st character shown. The friendship between Jesse & Willy is still there (of course) but not the similarity they have in families - in the 1st, they both miss theirs & share pain, in the 2nd Jesse learns his mom dies & he has a brother while Willy rejoins his family, but here Willy is about to become a father & Jesse definitely isn't. No girlfriend either - wonder why, he was interested in girls in the 2nd. The Greenwoods are mentioned 1ce but never shown, when Max describes a large family: "It's like any other family, you know", Jesse only replies "No, I don't." Except some music, Randolph's Indian culture, something I've always loved, is gone - the story isn't even told to Max, unlike Elvis. The asst, Drew, is pain & gives Jesse a hard time. This is good, but I prefer the others - I've never been a sequels fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
