<filme>
 <id>
  46
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109759
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Ex&oacute;tica
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The 'Exotica' is a nightclub on the outskirts of Toronto, where Eric, DJ and MC, watches nightly as his ex-girlfriend Christina performs. Watches jealously, especially as far as the extra ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The 'Exotica' is a nightclub on the outskirts of Toronto, where Eric, DJ and MC, watches nightly as his ex-girlfriend Christina performs. Watches jealously, especially as far as the extra attentions regular customer Francis garners are concerned. Thomas, meanwhile and erstwhile, goes through a series of, um, interesting situations involving his pet shop, a gruff taxi-sharing stranger, unexpected tickets to the opera and smuggled eggs of a rare bird. Multiple story lines unfold in a splendid tangle of cutbacks, forward and backward references and recurring themes, all woven around the Exotica, its customers and employees. A calm roller-coaster ride of a movie, visually and intriguingly and emotionally moving. O, and the sound track is notable, too.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   egg
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bird
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nightclub
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pet shop
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   eel
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Atom Egoyan
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Atom Egoyan
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Bruce Greenwood
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Elias Koteas
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Don McKellar
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, dark, cold seduction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exotica is my first Atom Egoyan film, and I'm now inclined to go out and go through his entire catalog. The title and DVD cover may make is seem like an erotic thriller at first, when in fact nothing could be further from the truth; Exotica is a beautiful, dark, low-key drama that seduces the viewer with sensuality and sexuality but maintains a chilly distance throughout. Exotica takes place in a strip club but isn't at any time titillating. It keeps the viewer out both sexually and emotionally - it's a character study piece that doesn't allow us to get into the head of any of the characters, one that doesn't have a real protagonist. Every character is a stranger to us and they all keep secrets from us and from each other, secrets that unravel as the film unfolds in a deliberately slow and strictly structured pace. I'm glad that I went into Exotica knowing next to nothing about it, and so should you. Quit reading reviews and just watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I have seen this movie was 10 year ago. I recorded it on video back then and watched it at least 4 times in last 10 years. It's very unusual for me, I rarely watch a movie twice. This movie has all ingredients that make a good movie for me: Awesome characters, perfectly fitting actors that play them well. Great music and a stunning atmosphere. (The music is simplified, unusual and perfectly fitting.) An amazing story that moves you and keeps you interested till the end. In addition to that, the movie has some nice bonus points: It's sexy (I love Mia Kirshner), intelligent and forces you to think. - And that is probably the one thing I like the most about movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a review of "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica", two films by Atom Egoyan, both of which deal with tragedy and loss and both of which feature the same actors in similar roles. Like most of his films, Egoyan's "The Sweet Hereafter" is structured as a jigsaw possible assembled around a single traumatic event. As the film unfolds, and the cast's relationship to the central event grows in clarity, some moment of revelation is achieved. Virtually all of Egoyan's films adopt this narrative structure, which seems to blend a modernist search for truth with a decidedly postmodern admittance that truth requires the careful sorting of both vantage points and testimonials. The traumatic event in this case is an accident involving a school bus. The bus skids off a road and veers onto a frozen lake. The ice breaks, the bus sinks and 14 children die. Of course, everyone in the town then suffers the knock-on effect of this accident. Man, you might say, is a creature constantly in search of meaning (the brain itself is a pattern recognition machine). He creates myths, patterns and rhymes, trying desperately to assert some measure of order. He cannot accept the chaotic cruelty of the universe, preferring instead to create comfortable rituals and routines in the hope of insulating himself from pain. When the unexpected does occur, man lifts his head and cries "Why?". But God never answers. Into this vacuum steps Ian Holm, who in "The Sweet Hereafter" plays a lawyer trying desperately to assign meaning to the film's central bus crash. He wants the parents of the dead children to band together and file a law suit. A law suit against who? The guilty bus driver? Nope, the driver is broke. He wants to go after the company that made the bus. He wants to sue them for millions. It is their fault. Alone. At first Ian Holm comes across as a greedy pig. Here is a man milking suffering for money. But gradually we learn that he is himself a man intimately familiar with loss. His life has been one of misery, and the film is peppered with flashbacks detailing his relationship with his daughter, a drug addict who is dying of AIDS. Like the parents whom he hopes to represent, this lawyer is looking for the meaning of his own suffering. "Why me?" he cries. Lashing out against others and assigning blame is the only way he can rationalise things. Similarly, the small town in which the accident occurs seems at first to be a picturesque postcard village. But gradually this image is shattered, as promiscuity, infidelity, alcoholism and sexual abuse all raise their heads. Director Atom Egoyan, an outspoken fan of "The Shining", even uses the famous "Horse and Train" picture from Kubrick's film, a recognition that both films deal subliminally with the same buried, almost invisible horrors. On top of all this, Egoyan adds a layer of myth. He has one of the film's children narrate Robert Browning's "The Pied Piper of Hamelin". In a self referential moment, the child asks "Who took the children? Who was the piper? Why did the fabled portal in the mountain (the breaking ice) open up and swallow the kids?" In this way, Egoyan approaches his central the tragedy from at least 3 angles. Firstly, as a fateful moment of chance, secondly, as a mythical act of God (God smites the parent's for their sins) and thirdly as an event exploited by a vengeful pilgrim of pain. All three approaches seek to lay blame, targeting either the failures of parents, the actions of a punishing god or the laws of a wholly arbitrary cosmos. "The Sweet Hereafter" is a very hopeless film, man never able to grasp absolute clarity (which of my behaviours, if any, caused this?). But there's also something very hopeful about Egoyan's ending. The sweet hereafter of the title is that zone of wisdom (found by the child who narrates the Piped Piper) where we ultimately come to accept the unacceptable and go on living. Similar in structure, Egoyan's "Exotica" approaches the same themes from a different angle. A man (Francis) loses his wife and daughter in a car crash. To cope with the pain he hires a young girl to come over to his house every day and babysit the daughter he lost. This babysitter simply plays a piano and lurks about his empty house, after which the bereaved father drives her home and pays her for babysitting nothingness. This ritual helps Francis assuage his pain. Every night Francis also visits a strip-club called "Exotica". There he watches a young woman (Christina), dressed in a schoolgirl's outfit, strip. But their relationship is an odd one. They seem to have a strange history. When she dances for him, it has nothing to do with sex and more to do with longing and loss. Of course both Francis and the stripper have a secret which is incrementally revealed, the truth peeled back like a stripper's clothes, leading to that revelatory final payoff that is typical of Egoyan's work. I won't spoil that moment. Suffice to say that this movie takes us into fairly interesting places. For Egoyan, man seems to live a life of cyclical substitution (we grow or are pushed out of everything and are forced to find substitutes). It's a bleak film, but unlike the work of Sam Mendes, to whom Egoyan is often wrongly compared, Egoyan eschews easy sensationalism and carnival freak-shows. 8.5/10 - Worth two viewings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What Could Have Been Superficial Is Astonishingly Deep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cosmicly
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What might seem at first to be a superficial story about middle aged guys seeking escape in the exotic world of young and beautiful strippers is actually a deep and intricately woven story of intersecting lives. And those seemingly ordinary lives are charged with extraordinary catastrophe. Excellent directing by Atom Egoyan. Superb acting by Mia Kirshner, Elias Koteas, Bruce Greenwood and Don McKellar. And the power of the film is amplified by an unforgettable soundtrack that includes the haunting lament of Leonard Cohen's classic "Everybody Knows." At the denouement, we are left with an abiding sense of cosmic ache, and a hope that there is truth in Dostoevsky's assertion that "our evils are expiated by suffering."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barriers Between Humans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egoyan's 'Exotica' is about emotionally isolated people who try to connect with each other. With every interaction between the characters there are symbolic barriers either in the form of finance, two way mirrors and social rules. But once this barrier is seized (symbolically) in the form of physical contact like the touch between Thomas and Chrissy and between Frances and Eric they form a connection. Egoyan does not resolve the 'problems' by showing the characters healed but instead what he demonstrates is that this human connection has brought change within them. In contrast, we also see how the characters once connected but now have drifted apart like Frances and Kristina or Zoe and Eric or Thomas and the officer. Explaining it more would be giving away too much of the story. While we see all these characters struggle to connect, there is Zoe who tries to keep things together but she too is sitting behind a one-way mirror. Egoyan uses plenty of symbolism and simple storytelling just isn't his style. He uses a rather suggestive approach. What he does in 'Exotica' is reveal very slowly. Moving at a slow pace, the film does 'test' the viewer's patience but there are a lot of subtle things happening and one has to observe closely to see that things aren't what they seem on the surface. There's a film-noire type quality to it. A lot of darkness is used, both symbolically and actually. The dialogues are simple but profound in depth. The haunting soundtrack gives the film a seductive and sensual edge. The performances are superb all the way. This is the first time I see Bruce Greenwood turn in a decent performance. Elias Koteas and Don McKellar are first rate. A very young Sarah Polley shows what potential she has. Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian is terrific. Mia Kirschner blends excellently blends sensuality, pain, fragility and kindness into Chrissy. 'Exotica' is not everyone's kind of film. Some may find its theme too dark and too intense but it's a film that isn't afraid to reveal, suggest and challenge the viewer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The essentials of a masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jexline
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Atom Egoyan's "Exotica" is perhaps the most perfect and beautifully intricate film I have seen. Filmed on a $2 million Canadian budget with his mostly usual staple of actors it explores territory usually left unchartered in the film world. Francis Brown (Bruce Greenwood) is a tax auditor for Revenue Canada who makes nightly visits to Exotica, a local gentleman's club, where he also asks for his favorite dancer, Christina (Mia Kirschner). The activity of the club is told to us by Eric, the D.J. (Elias Koteas)who makes suggestive comments about the dancers. The club is owned by the pregnant Zoe (Arsinee Khanjian; Egoyan's wife). The other main character of the story is Thomas Pinto (Don McKellar), a latently gay pet shop owner being audited by Francis. The film is largely about replacements and rituals. Eric used to be Christina's lover and relives the relationship through MCing suggestive fantasies of her. The club used to be owned by Zoe's mother and she is taking her mother's place since it's easier than creating her own options. Francis has his niece (Sarah Polley) babysit while he's gone, even though there's no baby to sit and pays her $20 a night and pays Christina $5 a dance. Thomas goes to the opera on a regular basis and scalps tickets in order to meet up with other men. The film doesn't truly come together until the conclusion where everything makes sense. This film features some great performances, especially Bruce Greenwood as the troubled and intense Francis. Elias Koteas is equally good as the jealous DJ. This is a sorely underrated film with the essentials of a masterpiece. The score is also excellent and I highly recommend the soundtrack as well. Overall, one of my all-time favorite films. A must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Obsession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Exotica" deals totally with obsession. Writer/director Atom Egoyan does well to get us hooked on his central characters, without knowing why they are behaving as they do. The plot centres around strip club "Exotica" as Egoyan teases out his tale like a striptease, little by little showing us more of who these people are and why. The resolution is perhaps disappointing (like a striptease when all has been revealed), failing to fulfill our high hopes. Best character is Francis, who appears to change before our eyes as the film progresses. It is not really he who changes however, but our perception of him. Likewise we view all the players differently in the end, though some of their motivations are hastily explained, if at all. Fantastic performances wrap up this oft times mesmerising film, with Bruce Greenwood a particular standout as Francis. Mia Kirshner (Christina) and Don McKellar (Thomas) are strong too. Also stars Elias Koteas as Eric and Arsinee Khanjian as Zoe. The exotic score is from Mychael Danna, and Paul Sarossy's camera captures Linda del Rosario and Richard Paris' production design (eye catching at times) well. Monday, November 3, 1997 - Hoyts Croydon Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More of a woman's POV movie than might be expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dennis Littrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Note: Over 500 of my movie reviews are now available in my book "Cut to the Chaise Lounge or I Can't Believe I Swallowed the Remote!" Get it at Amazon.) Atom Egoyan's Exotica is an outstanding movie. I have seen Egoyan's The Sweet Hereafter (1997) which is also very good. A father's (obsessive) love for his daughter(s) is featured in both movies, consequently the theme must mean something special to Egoyan. He is a most talented and original movie maker, a Canadian as are his players, Bruce Greenwood, (Francis Brown, the accountant whose daughter was murdered), Sarah Polley, (Tracey, the high school girl), and Mia Kirshner, (Christina, the exotic dancer). His wife, Arsinee Khanjian and Polley were also featured in The Sweet Hereafter. What really makes the movie is Egoyan's use of time and action sequence. He cuts up the chronological order of events and then presents them in a dramatic way. This is not so easy to do. Christopher Nolan in Memento (2000) used the same technique to great advantage. I have come late to such a technique and would love to master it myself. I worked on it last year and a couple of years before. You can't just scissor it and then paste it back together. Something must be gained from reversing the order of events. When Eric and Christina are shown walking the fields in a long line of people I jumped to the conclusion that Tracey would be found dead. We don't learn that Francis lost his daughter until the film is nearly finished. The psychology of Francis and the young girls is interesting. Christina says she gave something to him and he gave something to her. This vagueness with its unmistakable sexuality is something that always exists between young girls and older men. And, as Egoyan observes, there are rules and awkwardness, and confused emotions. However the girl wants it made unmistakably clear that she is desired physically and just talk is almost never sufficient. She often doesn't know whether she really wants to be "taken" fully, and of course that is usually, shall we say, problematic. Some great subtly is required in handled such a theme, and Egoyan realizes that. His character Francis Brown is content with fantasy and does not touch at all. This film would have found a larger audience except for the title, the theme, and the milieu. The female audience for the most part didn't even consider watching the movie since, as one woman said, I thought it was just another movie with an older man lusting after a girl half his age. That theme bores women to death. But surprisingly at the IMDb a viewer asks how women feel about the film and several write in to say that they liked it. Another poster remarks that women over forty actually liked Exotica in higher percentages than males. I thought the veracious and business-like depiction of the exotic dancer club was well done. The very nice side plot with the gay animal importer was just a perfect fit for the main plot. Egoyan wrote the script. It is a great script. So much surprises. It's almost too good. For me, since I have seen so many, many movies, something different, some surprises in plot, in character, in treatment are always welcome. And the plot does surprise. Even when the protagonist, Francis waits outside the club to shoot Eric, Egoyan turns the situation on its head by having Eric appear from the side and explain something that changes Francis's attitude toward him. I am being vague because I don't want to spoil the story. Some moviesmost movies I would say, since I go back to the generation that would go into the theatre and sit down during the middle of the movie; and then four or five hours later, realize, "This is where I came in"--in most movies to know the ending or the plot would not spoil the movie. We know so and so dies at the end. What is interesting is how he dies, how the actions develops. But in this movie to know the plot would take something away. I think. I'm not sure. Anyway Francis is a tax auditor who lost his daughter when she was less than eight years old. She was murdered. The police initially thought he did it, but he was found innocent and the murderer was apprehended and convicted. But Francis is left hollow and tries to bring her back in a way by having teenage girls "babysit" his nonexistent daughter. Egoyan teases us near the beginning by showing Francis and Tracey in his car as he drops her off at her home giving her some money and asking, "Are you free Thursday?" Very near the end of the movie we find that Tracey had a precursor in that babysitting role. You might be able to guess who it was. The sound track features "Everybody Knows" by Leonard Cohen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated, I'm afraid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Comparing this to Uwe Boll's stuff is a bit unfair, but I see where that reviewer is coming from. But, LOL, calling Leonard Cohen a Tom Waits wannabe, that's the funniest thing I've heard all year. The photography in this film almost redeems its many failings, but not quite. I get a lot of chuckles from the gushing reviews from art-house hangers-on; there is a kind of "Art-house clich&eacute;" which arises from the deliberate avoidance of Hollywood clich&eacute;. This film is full of it. You might call it "anti-clich&eacute;". But it amounts to the same thing. I see none of the freshness and vigour I look for in a good indy film. It mightn't be so bad if the plot didn't require so much suspension of disbelief. There couldn't exist a strip club such as this one, it would be just ludicrous. And why doesn't Mr. Egoyan find something else for his wife to do besides "acting" in all his movies? Anyhow, watch this if you've got nothing better on, but expect to be bored rigid waiting for the good bits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bust A Move...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    newkfl
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would have to admit that Exotica turned out to be a better film than I had imagined. It was slow in parts, but I guess it was to counter some of the scenes in the movie. There were some very disturbing characters in the movie too that really did not have problems so to speak, but certainly could have used some help from a trained sexual therapist. I would have certainly kept my distance from the character with the very hairy chest. I do not even think that he knew what he was going to do next. There was some good bar scene shots and dialog, but all in all, I think that the ending was a little bit rushed. It made me think of several ways that the movie could have been changed to fit the ending. Do not blink!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, dark, cold seduction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exotica is my first Atom Egoyan film, and I'm now inclined to go out and go through his entire catalog. The title and DVD cover may make is seem like an erotic thriller at first, when in fact nothing could be further from the truth; Exotica is a beautiful, dark, low-key drama that seduces the viewer with sensuality and sexuality but maintains a chilly distance throughout. Exotica takes place in a strip club but isn't at any time titillating. It keeps the viewer out both sexually and emotionally - it's a character study piece that doesn't allow us to get into the head of any of the characters, one that doesn't have a real protagonist. Every character is a stranger to us and they all keep secrets from us and from each other, secrets that unravel as the film unfolds in a deliberately slow and strictly structured pace. I'm glad that I went into Exotica knowing next to nothing about it, and so should you. Quit reading reviews and just watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I have seen this movie was 10 year ago. I recorded it on video back then and watched it at least 4 times in last 10 years. It's very unusual for me, I rarely watch a movie twice. This movie has all ingredients that make a good movie for me: Awesome characters, perfectly fitting actors that play them well. Great music and a stunning atmosphere. (The music is simplified, unusual and perfectly fitting.) An amazing story that moves you and keeps you interested till the end. In addition to that, the movie has some nice bonus points: It's sexy (I love Mia Kirshner), intelligent and forces you to think. - And that is probably the one thing I like the most about movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a review of "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica", two films by Atom Egoyan, both of which deal with tragedy and loss and both of which feature the same actors in similar roles. Like most of his films, Egoyan's "The Sweet Hereafter" is structured as a jigsaw possible assembled around a single traumatic event. As the film unfolds, and the cast's relationship to the central event grows in clarity, some moment of revelation is achieved. Virtually all of Egoyan's films adopt this narrative structure, which seems to blend a modernist search for truth with a decidedly postmodern admittance that truth requires the careful sorting of both vantage points and testimonials. The traumatic event in this case is an accident involving a school bus. The bus skids off a road and veers onto a frozen lake. The ice breaks, the bus sinks and 14 children die. Of course, everyone in the town then suffers the knock-on effect of this accident. Man, you might say, is a creature constantly in search of meaning (the brain itself is a pattern recognition machine). He creates myths, patterns and rhymes, trying desperately to assert some measure of order. He cannot accept the chaotic cruelty of the universe, preferring instead to create comfortable rituals and routines in the hope of insulating himself from pain. When the unexpected does occur, man lifts his head and cries "Why?". But God never answers. Into this vacuum steps Ian Holm, who in "The Sweet Hereafter" plays a lawyer trying desperately to assign meaning to the film's central bus crash. He wants the parents of the dead children to band together and file a law suit. A law suit against who? The guilty bus driver? Nope, the driver is broke. He wants to go after the company that made the bus. He wants to sue them for millions. It is their fault. Alone. At first Ian Holm comes across as a greedy pig. Here is a man milking suffering for money. But gradually we learn that he is himself a man intimately familiar with loss. His life has been one of misery, and the film is peppered with flashbacks detailing his relationship with his daughter, a drug addict who is dying of AIDS. Like the parents whom he hopes to represent, this lawyer is looking for the meaning of his own suffering. "Why me?" he cries. Lashing out against others and assigning blame is the only way he can rationalise things. Similarly, the small town in which the accident occurs seems at first to be a picturesque postcard village. But gradually this image is shattered, as promiscuity, infidelity, alcoholism and sexual abuse all raise their heads. Director Atom Egoyan, an outspoken fan of "The Shining", even uses the famous "Horse and Train" picture from Kubrick's film, a recognition that both films deal subliminally with the same buried, almost invisible horrors. On top of all this, Egoyan adds a layer of myth. He has one of the film's children narrate Robert Browning's "The Pied Piper of Hamelin". In a self referential moment, the child asks "Who took the children? Who was the piper? Why did the fabled portal in the mountain (the breaking ice) open up and swallow the kids?" In this way, Egoyan approaches his central the tragedy from at least 3 angles. Firstly, as a fateful moment of chance, secondly, as a mythical act of God (God smites the parent's for their sins) and thirdly as an event exploited by a vengeful pilgrim of pain. All three approaches seek to lay blame, targeting either the failures of parents, the actions of a punishing god or the laws of a wholly arbitrary cosmos. "The Sweet Hereafter" is a very hopeless film, man never able to grasp absolute clarity (which of my behaviours, if any, caused this?). But there's also something very hopeful about Egoyan's ending. The sweet hereafter of the title is that zone of wisdom (found by the child who narrates the Piped Piper) where we ultimately come to accept the unacceptable and go on living. Similar in structure, Egoyan's "Exotica" approaches the same themes from a different angle. A man (Francis) loses his wife and daughter in a car crash. To cope with the pain he hires a young girl to come over to his house every day and babysit the daughter he lost. This babysitter simply plays a piano and lurks about his empty house, after which the bereaved father drives her home and pays her for babysitting nothingness. This ritual helps Francis assuage his pain. Every night Francis also visits a strip-club called "Exotica". There he watches a young woman (Christina), dressed in a schoolgirl's outfit, strip. But their relationship is an odd one. They seem to have a strange history. When she dances for him, it has nothing to do with sex and more to do with longing and loss. Of course both Francis and the stripper have a secret which is incrementally revealed, the truth peeled back like a stripper's clothes, leading to that revelatory final payoff that is typical of Egoyan's work. I won't spoil that moment. Suffice to say that this movie takes us into fairly interesting places. For Egoyan, man seems to live a life of cyclical substitution (we grow or are pushed out of everything and are forced to find substitutes). It's a bleak film, but unlike the work of Sam Mendes, to whom Egoyan is often wrongly compared, Egoyan eschews easy sensationalism and carnival freak-shows. 8.5/10 - Worth two viewings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What Could Have Been Superficial Is Astonishingly Deep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cosmicly
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What might seem at first to be a superficial story about middle aged guys seeking escape in the exotic world of young and beautiful strippers is actually a deep and intricately woven story of intersecting lives. And those seemingly ordinary lives are charged with extraordinary catastrophe. Excellent directing by Atom Egoyan. Superb acting by Mia Kirshner, Elias Koteas, Bruce Greenwood and Don McKellar. And the power of the film is amplified by an unforgettable soundtrack that includes the haunting lament of Leonard Cohen's classic "Everybody Knows." At the denouement, we are left with an abiding sense of cosmic ache, and a hope that there is truth in Dostoevsky's assertion that "our evils are expiated by suffering."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barriers Between Humans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egoyan's 'Exotica' is about emotionally isolated people who try to connect with each other. With every interaction between the characters there are symbolic barriers either in the form of finance, two way mirrors and social rules. But once this barrier is seized (symbolically) in the form of physical contact like the touch between Thomas and Chrissy and between Frances and Eric they form a connection. Egoyan does not resolve the 'problems' by showing the characters healed but instead what he demonstrates is that this human connection has brought change within them. In contrast, we also see how the characters once connected but now have drifted apart like Frances and Kristina or Zoe and Eric or Thomas and the officer. Explaining it more would be giving away too much of the story. While we see all these characters struggle to connect, there is Zoe who tries to keep things together but she too is sitting behind a one-way mirror. Egoyan uses plenty of symbolism and simple storytelling just isn't his style. He uses a rather suggestive approach. What he does in 'Exotica' is reveal very slowly. Moving at a slow pace, the film does 'test' the viewer's patience but there are a lot of subtle things happening and one has to observe closely to see that things aren't what they seem on the surface. There's a film-noire type quality to it. A lot of darkness is used, both symbolically and actually. The dialogues are simple but profound in depth. The haunting soundtrack gives the film a seductive and sensual edge. The performances are superb all the way. This is the first time I see Bruce Greenwood turn in a decent performance. Elias Koteas and Don McKellar are first rate. A very young Sarah Polley shows what potential she has. Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian is terrific. Mia Kirschner blends excellently blends sensuality, pain, fragility and kindness into Chrissy. 'Exotica' is not everyone's kind of film. Some may find its theme too dark and too intense but it's a film that isn't afraid to reveal, suggest and challenge the viewer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The essentials of a masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jexline
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Atom Egoyan's "Exotica" is perhaps the most perfect and beautifully intricate film I have seen. Filmed on a $2 million Canadian budget with his mostly usual staple of actors it explores territory usually left unchartered in the film world. Francis Brown (Bruce Greenwood) is a tax auditor for Revenue Canada who makes nightly visits to Exotica, a local gentleman's club, where he also asks for his favorite dancer, Christina (Mia Kirschner). The activity of the club is told to us by Eric, the D.J. (Elias Koteas)who makes suggestive comments about the dancers. The club is owned by the pregnant Zoe (Arsinee Khanjian; Egoyan's wife). The other main character of the story is Thomas Pinto (Don McKellar), a latently gay pet shop owner being audited by Francis. The film is largely about replacements and rituals. Eric used to be Christina's lover and relives the relationship through MCing suggestive fantasies of her. The club used to be owned by Zoe's mother and she is taking her mother's place since it's easier than creating her own options. Francis has his niece (Sarah Polley) babysit while he's gone, even though there's no baby to sit and pays her $20 a night and pays Christina $5 a dance. Thomas goes to the opera on a regular basis and scalps tickets in order to meet up with other men. The film doesn't truly come together until the conclusion where everything makes sense. This film features some great performances, especially Bruce Greenwood as the troubled and intense Francis. Elias Koteas is equally good as the jealous DJ. This is a sorely underrated film with the essentials of a masterpiece. The score is also excellent and I highly recommend the soundtrack as well. Overall, one of my all-time favorite films. A must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Obsession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Exotica" deals totally with obsession. Writer/director Atom Egoyan does well to get us hooked on his central characters, without knowing why they are behaving as they do. The plot centres around strip club "Exotica" as Egoyan teases out his tale like a striptease, little by little showing us more of who these people are and why. The resolution is perhaps disappointing (like a striptease when all has been revealed), failing to fulfill our high hopes. Best character is Francis, who appears to change before our eyes as the film progresses. It is not really he who changes however, but our perception of him. Likewise we view all the players differently in the end, though some of their motivations are hastily explained, if at all. Fantastic performances wrap up this oft times mesmerising film, with Bruce Greenwood a particular standout as Francis. Mia Kirshner (Christina) and Don McKellar (Thomas) are strong too. Also stars Elias Koteas as Eric and Arsinee Khanjian as Zoe. The exotic score is from Mychael Danna, and Paul Sarossy's camera captures Linda del Rosario and Richard Paris' production design (eye catching at times) well. Monday, November 3, 1997 - Hoyts Croydon Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More of a woman's POV movie than might be expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dennis Littrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Note: Over 500 of my movie reviews are now available in my book "Cut to the Chaise Lounge or I Can't Believe I Swallowed the Remote!" Get it at Amazon.) Atom Egoyan's Exotica is an outstanding movie. I have seen Egoyan's The Sweet Hereafter (1997) which is also very good. A father's (obsessive) love for his daughter(s) is featured in both movies, consequently the theme must mean something special to Egoyan. He is a most talented and original movie maker, a Canadian as are his players, Bruce Greenwood, (Francis Brown, the accountant whose daughter was murdered), Sarah Polley, (Tracey, the high school girl), and Mia Kirshner, (Christina, the exotic dancer). His wife, Arsinee Khanjian and Polley were also featured in The Sweet Hereafter. What really makes the movie is Egoyan's use of time and action sequence. He cuts up the chronological order of events and then presents them in a dramatic way. This is not so easy to do. Christopher Nolan in Memento (2000) used the same technique to great advantage. I have come late to such a technique and would love to master it myself. I worked on it last year and a couple of years before. You can't just scissor it and then paste it back together. Something must be gained from reversing the order of events. When Eric and Christina are shown walking the fields in a long line of people I jumped to the conclusion that Tracey would be found dead. We don't learn that Francis lost his daughter until the film is nearly finished. The psychology of Francis and the young girls is interesting. Christina says she gave something to him and he gave something to her. This vagueness with its unmistakable sexuality is something that always exists between young girls and older men. And, as Egoyan observes, there are rules and awkwardness, and confused emotions. However the girl wants it made unmistakably clear that she is desired physically and just talk is almost never sufficient. She often doesn't know whether she really wants to be "taken" fully, and of course that is usually, shall we say, problematic. Some great subtly is required in handled such a theme, and Egoyan realizes that. His character Francis Brown is content with fantasy and does not touch at all. This film would have found a larger audience except for the title, the theme, and the milieu. The female audience for the most part didn't even consider watching the movie since, as one woman said, I thought it was just another movie with an older man lusting after a girl half his age. That theme bores women to death. But surprisingly at the IMDb a viewer asks how women feel about the film and several write in to say that they liked it. Another poster remarks that women over forty actually liked Exotica in higher percentages than males. I thought the veracious and business-like depiction of the exotic dancer club was well done. The very nice side plot with the gay animal importer was just a perfect fit for the main plot. Egoyan wrote the script. It is a great script. So much surprises. It's almost too good. For me, since I have seen so many, many movies, something different, some surprises in plot, in character, in treatment are always welcome. And the plot does surprise. Even when the protagonist, Francis waits outside the club to shoot Eric, Egoyan turns the situation on its head by having Eric appear from the side and explain something that changes Francis's attitude toward him. I am being vague because I don't want to spoil the story. Some moviesmost movies I would say, since I go back to the generation that would go into the theatre and sit down during the middle of the movie; and then four or five hours later, realize, "This is where I came in"--in most movies to know the ending or the plot would not spoil the movie. We know so and so dies at the end. What is interesting is how he dies, how the actions develops. But in this movie to know the plot would take something away. I think. I'm not sure. Anyway Francis is a tax auditor who lost his daughter when she was less than eight years old. She was murdered. The police initially thought he did it, but he was found innocent and the murderer was apprehended and convicted. But Francis is left hollow and tries to bring her back in a way by having teenage girls "babysit" his nonexistent daughter. Egoyan teases us near the beginning by showing Francis and Tracey in his car as he drops her off at her home giving her some money and asking, "Are you free Thursday?" Very near the end of the movie we find that Tracey had a precursor in that babysitting role. You might be able to guess who it was. The sound track features "Everybody Knows" by Leonard Cohen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated, I'm afraid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Comparing this to Uwe Boll's stuff is a bit unfair, but I see where that reviewer is coming from. But, LOL, calling Leonard Cohen a Tom Waits wannabe, that's the funniest thing I've heard all year. The photography in this film almost redeems its many failings, but not quite. I get a lot of chuckles from the gushing reviews from art-house hangers-on; there is a kind of "Art-house clich&eacute;" which arises from the deliberate avoidance of Hollywood clich&eacute;. This film is full of it. You might call it "anti-clich&eacute;". But it amounts to the same thing. I see none of the freshness and vigour I look for in a good indy film. It mightn't be so bad if the plot didn't require so much suspension of disbelief. There couldn't exist a strip club such as this one, it would be just ludicrous. And why doesn't Mr. Egoyan find something else for his wife to do besides "acting" in all his movies? Anyhow, watch this if you've got nothing better on, but expect to be bored rigid waiting for the good bits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bust A Move...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    newkfl
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would have to admit that Exotica turned out to be a better film than I had imagined. It was slow in parts, but I guess it was to counter some of the scenes in the movie. There were some very disturbing characters in the movie too that really did not have problems so to speak, but certainly could have used some help from a trained sexual therapist. I would have certainly kept my distance from the character with the very hairy chest. I do not even think that he knew what he was going to do next. There was some good bar scene shots and dialog, but all in all, I think that the ending was a little bit rushed. It made me think of several ways that the movie could have been changed to fit the ending. Do not blink!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, dark, cold seduction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exotica is my first Atom Egoyan film, and I'm now inclined to go out and go through his entire catalog. The title and DVD cover may make is seem like an erotic thriller at first, when in fact nothing could be further from the truth; Exotica is a beautiful, dark, low-key drama that seduces the viewer with sensuality and sexuality but maintains a chilly distance throughout. Exotica takes place in a strip club but isn't at any time titillating. It keeps the viewer out both sexually and emotionally - it's a character study piece that doesn't allow us to get into the head of any of the characters, one that doesn't have a real protagonist. Every character is a stranger to us and they all keep secrets from us and from each other, secrets that unravel as the film unfolds in a deliberately slow and strictly structured pace. I'm glad that I went into Exotica knowing next to nothing about it, and so should you. Quit reading reviews and just watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I have seen this movie was 10 year ago. I recorded it on video back then and watched it at least 4 times in last 10 years. It's very unusual for me, I rarely watch a movie twice. This movie has all ingredients that make a good movie for me: Awesome characters, perfectly fitting actors that play them well. Great music and a stunning atmosphere. (The music is simplified, unusual and perfectly fitting.) An amazing story that moves you and keeps you interested till the end. In addition to that, the movie has some nice bonus points: It's sexy (I love Mia Kirshner), intelligent and forces you to think. - And that is probably the one thing I like the most about movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a review of "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica", two films by Atom Egoyan, both of which deal with tragedy and loss and both of which feature the same actors in similar roles. Like most of his films, Egoyan's "The Sweet Hereafter" is structured as a jigsaw possible assembled around a single traumatic event. As the film unfolds, and the cast's relationship to the central event grows in clarity, some moment of revelation is achieved. Virtually all of Egoyan's films adopt this narrative structure, which seems to blend a modernist search for truth with a decidedly postmodern admittance that truth requires the careful sorting of both vantage points and testimonials. The traumatic event in this case is an accident involving a school bus. The bus skids off a road and veers onto a frozen lake. The ice breaks, the bus sinks and 14 children die. Of course, everyone in the town then suffers the knock-on effect of this accident. Man, you might say, is a creature constantly in search of meaning (the brain itself is a pattern recognition machine). He creates myths, patterns and rhymes, trying desperately to assert some measure of order. He cannot accept the chaotic cruelty of the universe, preferring instead to create comfortable rituals and routines in the hope of insulating himself from pain. When the unexpected does occur, man lifts his head and cries "Why?". But God never answers. Into this vacuum steps Ian Holm, who in "The Sweet Hereafter" plays a lawyer trying desperately to assign meaning to the film's central bus crash. He wants the parents of the dead children to band together and file a law suit. A law suit against who? The guilty bus driver? Nope, the driver is broke. He wants to go after the company that made the bus. He wants to sue them for millions. It is their fault. Alone. At first Ian Holm comes across as a greedy pig. Here is a man milking suffering for money. But gradually we learn that he is himself a man intimately familiar with loss. His life has been one of misery, and the film is peppered with flashbacks detailing his relationship with his daughter, a drug addict who is dying of AIDS. Like the parents whom he hopes to represent, this lawyer is looking for the meaning of his own suffering. "Why me?" he cries. Lashing out against others and assigning blame is the only way he can rationalise things. Similarly, the small town in which the accident occurs seems at first to be a picturesque postcard village. But gradually this image is shattered, as promiscuity, infidelity, alcoholism and sexual abuse all raise their heads. Director Atom Egoyan, an outspoken fan of "The Shining", even uses the famous "Horse and Train" picture from Kubrick's film, a recognition that both films deal subliminally with the same buried, almost invisible horrors. On top of all this, Egoyan adds a layer of myth. He has one of the film's children narrate Robert Browning's "The Pied Piper of Hamelin". In a self referential moment, the child asks "Who took the children? Who was the piper? Why did the fabled portal in the mountain (the breaking ice) open up and swallow the kids?" In this way, Egoyan approaches his central the tragedy from at least 3 angles. Firstly, as a fateful moment of chance, secondly, as a mythical act of God (God smites the parent's for their sins) and thirdly as an event exploited by a vengeful pilgrim of pain. All three approaches seek to lay blame, targeting either the failures of parents, the actions of a punishing god or the laws of a wholly arbitrary cosmos. "The Sweet Hereafter" is a very hopeless film, man never able to grasp absolute clarity (which of my behaviours, if any, caused this?). But there's also something very hopeful about Egoyan's ending. The sweet hereafter of the title is that zone of wisdom (found by the child who narrates the Piped Piper) where we ultimately come to accept the unacceptable and go on living. Similar in structure, Egoyan's "Exotica" approaches the same themes from a different angle. A man (Francis) loses his wife and daughter in a car crash. To cope with the pain he hires a young girl to come over to his house every day and babysit the daughter he lost. This babysitter simply plays a piano and lurks about his empty house, after which the bereaved father drives her home and pays her for babysitting nothingness. This ritual helps Francis assuage his pain. Every night Francis also visits a strip-club called "Exotica". There he watches a young woman (Christina), dressed in a schoolgirl's outfit, strip. But their relationship is an odd one. They seem to have a strange history. When she dances for him, it has nothing to do with sex and more to do with longing and loss. Of course both Francis and the stripper have a secret which is incrementally revealed, the truth peeled back like a stripper's clothes, leading to that revelatory final payoff that is typical of Egoyan's work. I won't spoil that moment. Suffice to say that this movie takes us into fairly interesting places. For Egoyan, man seems to live a life of cyclical substitution (we grow or are pushed out of everything and are forced to find substitutes). It's a bleak film, but unlike the work of Sam Mendes, to whom Egoyan is often wrongly compared, Egoyan eschews easy sensationalism and carnival freak-shows. 8.5/10 - Worth two viewings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What Could Have Been Superficial Is Astonishingly Deep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cosmicly
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What might seem at first to be a superficial story about middle aged guys seeking escape in the exotic world of young and beautiful strippers is actually a deep and intricately woven story of intersecting lives. And those seemingly ordinary lives are charged with extraordinary catastrophe. Excellent directing by Atom Egoyan. Superb acting by Mia Kirshner, Elias Koteas, Bruce Greenwood and Don McKellar. And the power of the film is amplified by an unforgettable soundtrack that includes the haunting lament of Leonard Cohen's classic "Everybody Knows." At the denouement, we are left with an abiding sense of cosmic ache, and a hope that there is truth in Dostoevsky's assertion that "our evils are expiated by suffering."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barriers Between Humans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egoyan's 'Exotica' is about emotionally isolated people who try to connect with each other. With every interaction between the characters there are symbolic barriers either in the form of finance, two way mirrors and social rules. But once this barrier is seized (symbolically) in the form of physical contact like the touch between Thomas and Chrissy and between Frances and Eric they form a connection. Egoyan does not resolve the 'problems' by showing the characters healed but instead what he demonstrates is that this human connection has brought change within them. In contrast, we also see how the characters once connected but now have drifted apart like Frances and Kristina or Zoe and Eric or Thomas and the officer. Explaining it more would be giving away too much of the story. While we see all these characters struggle to connect, there is Zoe who tries to keep things together but she too is sitting behind a one-way mirror. Egoyan uses plenty of symbolism and simple storytelling just isn't his style. He uses a rather suggestive approach. What he does in 'Exotica' is reveal very slowly. Moving at a slow pace, the film does 'test' the viewer's patience but there are a lot of subtle things happening and one has to observe closely to see that things aren't what they seem on the surface. There's a film-noire type quality to it. A lot of darkness is used, both symbolically and actually. The dialogues are simple but profound in depth. The haunting soundtrack gives the film a seductive and sensual edge. The performances are superb all the way. This is the first time I see Bruce Greenwood turn in a decent performance. Elias Koteas and Don McKellar are first rate. A very young Sarah Polley shows what potential she has. Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian is terrific. Mia Kirschner blends excellently blends sensuality, pain, fragility and kindness into Chrissy. 'Exotica' is not everyone's kind of film. Some may find its theme too dark and too intense but it's a film that isn't afraid to reveal, suggest and challenge the viewer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The essentials of a masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jexline
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Atom Egoyan's "Exotica" is perhaps the most perfect and beautifully intricate film I have seen. Filmed on a $2 million Canadian budget with his mostly usual staple of actors it explores territory usually left unchartered in the film world. Francis Brown (Bruce Greenwood) is a tax auditor for Revenue Canada who makes nightly visits to Exotica, a local gentleman's club, where he also asks for his favorite dancer, Christina (Mia Kirschner). The activity of the club is told to us by Eric, the D.J. (Elias Koteas)who makes suggestive comments about the dancers. The club is owned by the pregnant Zoe (Arsinee Khanjian; Egoyan's wife). The other main character of the story is Thomas Pinto (Don McKellar), a latently gay pet shop owner being audited by Francis. The film is largely about replacements and rituals. Eric used to be Christina's lover and relives the relationship through MCing suggestive fantasies of her. The club used to be owned by Zoe's mother and she is taking her mother's place since it's easier than creating her own options. Francis has his niece (Sarah Polley) babysit while he's gone, even though there's no baby to sit and pays her $20 a night and pays Christina $5 a dance. Thomas goes to the opera on a regular basis and scalps tickets in order to meet up with other men. The film doesn't truly come together until the conclusion where everything makes sense. This film features some great performances, especially Bruce Greenwood as the troubled and intense Francis. Elias Koteas is equally good as the jealous DJ. This is a sorely underrated film with the essentials of a masterpiece. The score is also excellent and I highly recommend the soundtrack as well. Overall, one of my all-time favorite films. A must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Obsession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Exotica" deals totally with obsession. Writer/director Atom Egoyan does well to get us hooked on his central characters, without knowing why they are behaving as they do. The plot centres around strip club "Exotica" as Egoyan teases out his tale like a striptease, little by little showing us more of who these people are and why. The resolution is perhaps disappointing (like a striptease when all has been revealed), failing to fulfill our high hopes. Best character is Francis, who appears to change before our eyes as the film progresses. It is not really he who changes however, but our perception of him. Likewise we view all the players differently in the end, though some of their motivations are hastily explained, if at all. Fantastic performances wrap up this oft times mesmerising film, with Bruce Greenwood a particular standout as Francis. Mia Kirshner (Christina) and Don McKellar (Thomas) are strong too. Also stars Elias Koteas as Eric and Arsinee Khanjian as Zoe. The exotic score is from Mychael Danna, and Paul Sarossy's camera captures Linda del Rosario and Richard Paris' production design (eye catching at times) well. Monday, November 3, 1997 - Hoyts Croydon Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More of a woman's POV movie than might be expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dennis Littrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Note: Over 500 of my movie reviews are now available in my book "Cut to the Chaise Lounge or I Can't Believe I Swallowed the Remote!" Get it at Amazon.) Atom Egoyan's Exotica is an outstanding movie. I have seen Egoyan's The Sweet Hereafter (1997) which is also very good. A father's (obsessive) love for his daughter(s) is featured in both movies, consequently the theme must mean something special to Egoyan. He is a most talented and original movie maker, a Canadian as are his players, Bruce Greenwood, (Francis Brown, the accountant whose daughter was murdered), Sarah Polley, (Tracey, the high school girl), and Mia Kirshner, (Christina, the exotic dancer). His wife, Arsinee Khanjian and Polley were also featured in The Sweet Hereafter. What really makes the movie is Egoyan's use of time and action sequence. He cuts up the chronological order of events and then presents them in a dramatic way. This is not so easy to do. Christopher Nolan in Memento (2000) used the same technique to great advantage. I have come late to such a technique and would love to master it myself. I worked on it last year and a couple of years before. You can't just scissor it and then paste it back together. Something must be gained from reversing the order of events. When Eric and Christina are shown walking the fields in a long line of people I jumped to the conclusion that Tracey would be found dead. We don't learn that Francis lost his daughter until the film is nearly finished. The psychology of Francis and the young girls is interesting. Christina says she gave something to him and he gave something to her. This vagueness with its unmistakable sexuality is something that always exists between young girls and older men. And, as Egoyan observes, there are rules and awkwardness, and confused emotions. However the girl wants it made unmistakably clear that she is desired physically and just talk is almost never sufficient. She often doesn't know whether she really wants to be "taken" fully, and of course that is usually, shall we say, problematic. Some great subtly is required in handled such a theme, and Egoyan realizes that. His character Francis Brown is content with fantasy and does not touch at all. This film would have found a larger audience except for the title, the theme, and the milieu. The female audience for the most part didn't even consider watching the movie since, as one woman said, I thought it was just another movie with an older man lusting after a girl half his age. That theme bores women to death. But surprisingly at the IMDb a viewer asks how women feel about the film and several write in to say that they liked it. Another poster remarks that women over forty actually liked Exotica in higher percentages than males. I thought the veracious and business-like depiction of the exotic dancer club was well done. The very nice side plot with the gay animal importer was just a perfect fit for the main plot. Egoyan wrote the script. It is a great script. So much surprises. It's almost too good. For me, since I have seen so many, many movies, something different, some surprises in plot, in character, in treatment are always welcome. And the plot does surprise. Even when the protagonist, Francis waits outside the club to shoot Eric, Egoyan turns the situation on its head by having Eric appear from the side and explain something that changes Francis's attitude toward him. I am being vague because I don't want to spoil the story. Some moviesmost movies I would say, since I go back to the generation that would go into the theatre and sit down during the middle of the movie; and then four or five hours later, realize, "This is where I came in"--in most movies to know the ending or the plot would not spoil the movie. We know so and so dies at the end. What is interesting is how he dies, how the actions develops. But in this movie to know the plot would take something away. I think. I'm not sure. Anyway Francis is a tax auditor who lost his daughter when she was less than eight years old. She was murdered. The police initially thought he did it, but he was found innocent and the murderer was apprehended and convicted. But Francis is left hollow and tries to bring her back in a way by having teenage girls "babysit" his nonexistent daughter. Egoyan teases us near the beginning by showing Francis and Tracey in his car as he drops her off at her home giving her some money and asking, "Are you free Thursday?" Very near the end of the movie we find that Tracey had a precursor in that babysitting role. You might be able to guess who it was. The sound track features "Everybody Knows" by Leonard Cohen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated, I'm afraid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Comparing this to Uwe Boll's stuff is a bit unfair, but I see where that reviewer is coming from. But, LOL, calling Leonard Cohen a Tom Waits wannabe, that's the funniest thing I've heard all year. The photography in this film almost redeems its many failings, but not quite. I get a lot of chuckles from the gushing reviews from art-house hangers-on; there is a kind of "Art-house clich&eacute;" which arises from the deliberate avoidance of Hollywood clich&eacute;. This film is full of it. You might call it "anti-clich&eacute;". But it amounts to the same thing. I see none of the freshness and vigour I look for in a good indy film. It mightn't be so bad if the plot didn't require so much suspension of disbelief. There couldn't exist a strip club such as this one, it would be just ludicrous. And why doesn't Mr. Egoyan find something else for his wife to do besides "acting" in all his movies? Anyhow, watch this if you've got nothing better on, but expect to be bored rigid waiting for the good bits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bust A Move...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    newkfl
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would have to admit that Exotica turned out to be a better film than I had imagined. It was slow in parts, but I guess it was to counter some of the scenes in the movie. There were some very disturbing characters in the movie too that really did not have problems so to speak, but certainly could have used some help from a trained sexual therapist. I would have certainly kept my distance from the character with the very hairy chest. I do not even think that he knew what he was going to do next. There was some good bar scene shots and dialog, but all in all, I think that the ending was a little bit rushed. It made me think of several ways that the movie could have been changed to fit the ending. Do not blink!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, dark, cold seduction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exotica is my first Atom Egoyan film, and I'm now inclined to go out and go through his entire catalog. The title and DVD cover may make is seem like an erotic thriller at first, when in fact nothing could be further from the truth; Exotica is a beautiful, dark, low-key drama that seduces the viewer with sensuality and sexuality but maintains a chilly distance throughout. Exotica takes place in a strip club but isn't at any time titillating. It keeps the viewer out both sexually and emotionally - it's a character study piece that doesn't allow us to get into the head of any of the characters, one that doesn't have a real protagonist. Every character is a stranger to us and they all keep secrets from us and from each other, secrets that unravel as the film unfolds in a deliberately slow and strictly structured pace. I'm glad that I went into Exotica knowing next to nothing about it, and so should you. Quit reading reviews and just watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I have seen this movie was 10 year ago. I recorded it on video back then and watched it at least 4 times in last 10 years. It's very unusual for me, I rarely watch a movie twice. This movie has all ingredients that make a good movie for me: Awesome characters, perfectly fitting actors that play them well. Great music and a stunning atmosphere. (The music is simplified, unusual and perfectly fitting.) An amazing story that moves you and keeps you interested till the end. In addition to that, the movie has some nice bonus points: It's sexy (I love Mia Kirshner), intelligent and forces you to think. - And that is probably the one thing I like the most about movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a review of "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica", two films by Atom Egoyan, both of which deal with tragedy and loss and both of which feature the same actors in similar roles. Like most of his films, Egoyan's "The Sweet Hereafter" is structured as a jigsaw possible assembled around a single traumatic event. As the film unfolds, and the cast's relationship to the central event grows in clarity, some moment of revelation is achieved. Virtually all of Egoyan's films adopt this narrative structure, which seems to blend a modernist search for truth with a decidedly postmodern admittance that truth requires the careful sorting of both vantage points and testimonials. The traumatic event in this case is an accident involving a school bus. The bus skids off a road and veers onto a frozen lake. The ice breaks, the bus sinks and 14 children die. Of course, everyone in the town then suffers the knock-on effect of this accident. Man, you might say, is a creature constantly in search of meaning (the brain itself is a pattern recognition machine). He creates myths, patterns and rhymes, trying desperately to assert some measure of order. He cannot accept the chaotic cruelty of the universe, preferring instead to create comfortable rituals and routines in the hope of insulating himself from pain. When the unexpected does occur, man lifts his head and cries "Why?". But God never answers. Into this vacuum steps Ian Holm, who in "The Sweet Hereafter" plays a lawyer trying desperately to assign meaning to the film's central bus crash. He wants the parents of the dead children to band together and file a law suit. A law suit against who? The guilty bus driver? Nope, the driver is broke. He wants to go after the company that made the bus. He wants to sue them for millions. It is their fault. Alone. At first Ian Holm comes across as a greedy pig. Here is a man milking suffering for money. But gradually we learn that he is himself a man intimately familiar with loss. His life has been one of misery, and the film is peppered with flashbacks detailing his relationship with his daughter, a drug addict who is dying of AIDS. Like the parents whom he hopes to represent, this lawyer is looking for the meaning of his own suffering. "Why me?" he cries. Lashing out against others and assigning blame is the only way he can rationalise things. Similarly, the small town in which the accident occurs seems at first to be a picturesque postcard village. But gradually this image is shattered, as promiscuity, infidelity, alcoholism and sexual abuse all raise their heads. Director Atom Egoyan, an outspoken fan of "The Shining", even uses the famous "Horse and Train" picture from Kubrick's film, a recognition that both films deal subliminally with the same buried, almost invisible horrors. On top of all this, Egoyan adds a layer of myth. He has one of the film's children narrate Robert Browning's "The Pied Piper of Hamelin". In a self referential moment, the child asks "Who took the children? Who was the piper? Why did the fabled portal in the mountain (the breaking ice) open up and swallow the kids?" In this way, Egoyan approaches his central the tragedy from at least 3 angles. Firstly, as a fateful moment of chance, secondly, as a mythical act of God (God smites the parent's for their sins) and thirdly as an event exploited by a vengeful pilgrim of pain. All three approaches seek to lay blame, targeting either the failures of parents, the actions of a punishing god or the laws of a wholly arbitrary cosmos. "The Sweet Hereafter" is a very hopeless film, man never able to grasp absolute clarity (which of my behaviours, if any, caused this?). But there's also something very hopeful about Egoyan's ending. The sweet hereafter of the title is that zone of wisdom (found by the child who narrates the Piped Piper) where we ultimately come to accept the unacceptable and go on living. Similar in structure, Egoyan's "Exotica" approaches the same themes from a different angle. A man (Francis) loses his wife and daughter in a car crash. To cope with the pain he hires a young girl to come over to his house every day and babysit the daughter he lost. This babysitter simply plays a piano and lurks about his empty house, after which the bereaved father drives her home and pays her for babysitting nothingness. This ritual helps Francis assuage his pain. Every night Francis also visits a strip-club called "Exotica". There he watches a young woman (Christina), dressed in a schoolgirl's outfit, strip. But their relationship is an odd one. They seem to have a strange history. When she dances for him, it has nothing to do with sex and more to do with longing and loss. Of course both Francis and the stripper have a secret which is incrementally revealed, the truth peeled back like a stripper's clothes, leading to that revelatory final payoff that is typical of Egoyan's work. I won't spoil that moment. Suffice to say that this movie takes us into fairly interesting places. For Egoyan, man seems to live a life of cyclical substitution (we grow or are pushed out of everything and are forced to find substitutes). It's a bleak film, but unlike the work of Sam Mendes, to whom Egoyan is often wrongly compared, Egoyan eschews easy sensationalism and carnival freak-shows. 8.5/10 - Worth two viewings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What Could Have Been Superficial Is Astonishingly Deep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cosmicly
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What might seem at first to be a superficial story about middle aged guys seeking escape in the exotic world of young and beautiful strippers is actually a deep and intricately woven story of intersecting lives. And those seemingly ordinary lives are charged with extraordinary catastrophe. Excellent directing by Atom Egoyan. Superb acting by Mia Kirshner, Elias Koteas, Bruce Greenwood and Don McKellar. And the power of the film is amplified by an unforgettable soundtrack that includes the haunting lament of Leonard Cohen's classic "Everybody Knows." At the denouement, we are left with an abiding sense of cosmic ache, and a hope that there is truth in Dostoevsky's assertion that "our evils are expiated by suffering."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barriers Between Humans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egoyan's 'Exotica' is about emotionally isolated people who try to connect with each other. With every interaction between the characters there are symbolic barriers either in the form of finance, two way mirrors and social rules. But once this barrier is seized (symbolically) in the form of physical contact like the touch between Thomas and Chrissy and between Frances and Eric they form a connection. Egoyan does not resolve the 'problems' by showing the characters healed but instead what he demonstrates is that this human connection has brought change within them. In contrast, we also see how the characters once connected but now have drifted apart like Frances and Kristina or Zoe and Eric or Thomas and the officer. Explaining it more would be giving away too much of the story. While we see all these characters struggle to connect, there is Zoe who tries to keep things together but she too is sitting behind a one-way mirror. Egoyan uses plenty of symbolism and simple storytelling just isn't his style. He uses a rather suggestive approach. What he does in 'Exotica' is reveal very slowly. Moving at a slow pace, the film does 'test' the viewer's patience but there are a lot of subtle things happening and one has to observe closely to see that things aren't what they seem on the surface. There's a film-noire type quality to it. A lot of darkness is used, both symbolically and actually. The dialogues are simple but profound in depth. The haunting soundtrack gives the film a seductive and sensual edge. The performances are superb all the way. This is the first time I see Bruce Greenwood turn in a decent performance. Elias Koteas and Don McKellar are first rate. A very young Sarah Polley shows what potential she has. Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian is terrific. Mia Kirschner blends excellently blends sensuality, pain, fragility and kindness into Chrissy. 'Exotica' is not everyone's kind of film. Some may find its theme too dark and too intense but it's a film that isn't afraid to reveal, suggest and challenge the viewer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The essentials of a masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jexline
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Atom Egoyan's "Exotica" is perhaps the most perfect and beautifully intricate film I have seen. Filmed on a $2 million Canadian budget with his mostly usual staple of actors it explores territory usually left unchartered in the film world. Francis Brown (Bruce Greenwood) is a tax auditor for Revenue Canada who makes nightly visits to Exotica, a local gentleman's club, where he also asks for his favorite dancer, Christina (Mia Kirschner). The activity of the club is told to us by Eric, the D.J. (Elias Koteas)who makes suggestive comments about the dancers. The club is owned by the pregnant Zoe (Arsinee Khanjian; Egoyan's wife). The other main character of the story is Thomas Pinto (Don McKellar), a latently gay pet shop owner being audited by Francis. The film is largely about replacements and rituals. Eric used to be Christina's lover and relives the relationship through MCing suggestive fantasies of her. The club used to be owned by Zoe's mother and she is taking her mother's place since it's easier than creating her own options. Francis has his niece (Sarah Polley) babysit while he's gone, even though there's no baby to sit and pays her $20 a night and pays Christina $5 a dance. Thomas goes to the opera on a regular basis and scalps tickets in order to meet up with other men. The film doesn't truly come together until the conclusion where everything makes sense. This film features some great performances, especially Bruce Greenwood as the troubled and intense Francis. Elias Koteas is equally good as the jealous DJ. This is a sorely underrated film with the essentials of a masterpiece. The score is also excellent and I highly recommend the soundtrack as well. Overall, one of my all-time favorite films. A must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Obsession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Exotica" deals totally with obsession. Writer/director Atom Egoyan does well to get us hooked on his central characters, without knowing why they are behaving as they do. The plot centres around strip club "Exotica" as Egoyan teases out his tale like a striptease, little by little showing us more of who these people are and why. The resolution is perhaps disappointing (like a striptease when all has been revealed), failing to fulfill our high hopes. Best character is Francis, who appears to change before our eyes as the film progresses. It is not really he who changes however, but our perception of him. Likewise we view all the players differently in the end, though some of their motivations are hastily explained, if at all. Fantastic performances wrap up this oft times mesmerising film, with Bruce Greenwood a particular standout as Francis. Mia Kirshner (Christina) and Don McKellar (Thomas) are strong too. Also stars Elias Koteas as Eric and Arsinee Khanjian as Zoe. The exotic score is from Mychael Danna, and Paul Sarossy's camera captures Linda del Rosario and Richard Paris' production design (eye catching at times) well. Monday, November 3, 1997 - Hoyts Croydon Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More of a woman's POV movie than might be expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dennis Littrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Note: Over 500 of my movie reviews are now available in my book "Cut to the Chaise Lounge or I Can't Believe I Swallowed the Remote!" Get it at Amazon.) Atom Egoyan's Exotica is an outstanding movie. I have seen Egoyan's The Sweet Hereafter (1997) which is also very good. A father's (obsessive) love for his daughter(s) is featured in both movies, consequently the theme must mean something special to Egoyan. He is a most talented and original movie maker, a Canadian as are his players, Bruce Greenwood, (Francis Brown, the accountant whose daughter was murdered), Sarah Polley, (Tracey, the high school girl), and Mia Kirshner, (Christina, the exotic dancer). His wife, Arsinee Khanjian and Polley were also featured in The Sweet Hereafter. What really makes the movie is Egoyan's use of time and action sequence. He cuts up the chronological order of events and then presents them in a dramatic way. This is not so easy to do. Christopher Nolan in Memento (2000) used the same technique to great advantage. I have come late to such a technique and would love to master it myself. I worked on it last year and a couple of years before. You can't just scissor it and then paste it back together. Something must be gained from reversing the order of events. When Eric and Christina are shown walking the fields in a long line of people I jumped to the conclusion that Tracey would be found dead. We don't learn that Francis lost his daughter until the film is nearly finished. The psychology of Francis and the young girls is interesting. Christina says she gave something to him and he gave something to her. This vagueness with its unmistakable sexuality is something that always exists between young girls and older men. And, as Egoyan observes, there are rules and awkwardness, and confused emotions. However the girl wants it made unmistakably clear that she is desired physically and just talk is almost never sufficient. She often doesn't know whether she really wants to be "taken" fully, and of course that is usually, shall we say, problematic. Some great subtly is required in handled such a theme, and Egoyan realizes that. His character Francis Brown is content with fantasy and does not touch at all. This film would have found a larger audience except for the title, the theme, and the milieu. The female audience for the most part didn't even consider watching the movie since, as one woman said, I thought it was just another movie with an older man lusting after a girl half his age. That theme bores women to death. But surprisingly at the IMDb a viewer asks how women feel about the film and several write in to say that they liked it. Another poster remarks that women over forty actually liked Exotica in higher percentages than males. I thought the veracious and business-like depiction of the exotic dancer club was well done. The very nice side plot with the gay animal importer was just a perfect fit for the main plot. Egoyan wrote the script. It is a great script. So much surprises. It's almost too good. For me, since I have seen so many, many movies, something different, some surprises in plot, in character, in treatment are always welcome. And the plot does surprise. Even when the protagonist, Francis waits outside the club to shoot Eric, Egoyan turns the situation on its head by having Eric appear from the side and explain something that changes Francis's attitude toward him. I am being vague because I don't want to spoil the story. Some moviesmost movies I would say, since I go back to the generation that would go into the theatre and sit down during the middle of the movie; and then four or five hours later, realize, "This is where I came in"--in most movies to know the ending or the plot would not spoil the movie. We know so and so dies at the end. What is interesting is how he dies, how the actions develops. But in this movie to know the plot would take something away. I think. I'm not sure. Anyway Francis is a tax auditor who lost his daughter when she was less than eight years old. She was murdered. The police initially thought he did it, but he was found innocent and the murderer was apprehended and convicted. But Francis is left hollow and tries to bring her back in a way by having teenage girls "babysit" his nonexistent daughter. Egoyan teases us near the beginning by showing Francis and Tracey in his car as he drops her off at her home giving her some money and asking, "Are you free Thursday?" Very near the end of the movie we find that Tracey had a precursor in that babysitting role. You might be able to guess who it was. The sound track features "Everybody Knows" by Leonard Cohen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated, I'm afraid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Comparing this to Uwe Boll's stuff is a bit unfair, but I see where that reviewer is coming from. But, LOL, calling Leonard Cohen a Tom Waits wannabe, that's the funniest thing I've heard all year. The photography in this film almost redeems its many failings, but not quite. I get a lot of chuckles from the gushing reviews from art-house hangers-on; there is a kind of "Art-house clich&eacute;" which arises from the deliberate avoidance of Hollywood clich&eacute;. This film is full of it. You might call it "anti-clich&eacute;". But it amounts to the same thing. I see none of the freshness and vigour I look for in a good indy film. It mightn't be so bad if the plot didn't require so much suspension of disbelief. There couldn't exist a strip club such as this one, it would be just ludicrous. And why doesn't Mr. Egoyan find something else for his wife to do besides "acting" in all his movies? Anyhow, watch this if you've got nothing better on, but expect to be bored rigid waiting for the good bits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bust A Move...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    newkfl
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would have to admit that Exotica turned out to be a better film than I had imagined. It was slow in parts, but I guess it was to counter some of the scenes in the movie. There were some very disturbing characters in the movie too that really did not have problems so to speak, but certainly could have used some help from a trained sexual therapist. I would have certainly kept my distance from the character with the very hairy chest. I do not even think that he knew what he was going to do next. There was some good bar scene shots and dialog, but all in all, I think that the ending was a little bit rushed. It made me think of several ways that the movie could have been changed to fit the ending. Do not blink!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, dark, cold seduction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exotica is my first Atom Egoyan film, and I'm now inclined to go out and go through his entire catalog. The title and DVD cover may make is seem like an erotic thriller at first, when in fact nothing could be further from the truth; Exotica is a beautiful, dark, low-key drama that seduces the viewer with sensuality and sexuality but maintains a chilly distance throughout. Exotica takes place in a strip club but isn't at any time titillating. It keeps the viewer out both sexually and emotionally - it's a character study piece that doesn't allow us to get into the head of any of the characters, one that doesn't have a real protagonist. Every character is a stranger to us and they all keep secrets from us and from each other, secrets that unravel as the film unfolds in a deliberately slow and strictly structured pace. I'm glad that I went into Exotica knowing next to nothing about it, and so should you. Quit reading reviews and just watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I have seen this movie was 10 year ago. I recorded it on video back then and watched it at least 4 times in last 10 years. It's very unusual for me, I rarely watch a movie twice. This movie has all ingredients that make a good movie for me: Awesome characters, perfectly fitting actors that play them well. Great music and a stunning atmosphere. (The music is simplified, unusual and perfectly fitting.) An amazing story that moves you and keeps you interested till the end. In addition to that, the movie has some nice bonus points: It's sexy (I love Mia Kirshner), intelligent and forces you to think. - And that is probably the one thing I like the most about movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a review of "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica", two films by Atom Egoyan, both of which deal with tragedy and loss and both of which feature the same actors in similar roles. Like most of his films, Egoyan's "The Sweet Hereafter" is structured as a jigsaw possible assembled around a single traumatic event. As the film unfolds, and the cast's relationship to the central event grows in clarity, some moment of revelation is achieved. Virtually all of Egoyan's films adopt this narrative structure, which seems to blend a modernist search for truth with a decidedly postmodern admittance that truth requires the careful sorting of both vantage points and testimonials. The traumatic event in this case is an accident involving a school bus. The bus skids off a road and veers onto a frozen lake. The ice breaks, the bus sinks and 14 children die. Of course, everyone in the town then suffers the knock-on effect of this accident. Man, you might say, is a creature constantly in search of meaning (the brain itself is a pattern recognition machine). He creates myths, patterns and rhymes, trying desperately to assert some measure of order. He cannot accept the chaotic cruelty of the universe, preferring instead to create comfortable rituals and routines in the hope of insulating himself from pain. When the unexpected does occur, man lifts his head and cries "Why?". But God never answers. Into this vacuum steps Ian Holm, who in "The Sweet Hereafter" plays a lawyer trying desperately to assign meaning to the film's central bus crash. He wants the parents of the dead children to band together and file a law suit. A law suit against who? The guilty bus driver? Nope, the driver is broke. He wants to go after the company that made the bus. He wants to sue them for millions. It is their fault. Alone. At first Ian Holm comes across as a greedy pig. Here is a man milking suffering for money. But gradually we learn that he is himself a man intimately familiar with loss. His life has been one of misery, and the film is peppered with flashbacks detailing his relationship with his daughter, a drug addict who is dying of AIDS. Like the parents whom he hopes to represent, this lawyer is looking for the meaning of his own suffering. "Why me?" he cries. Lashing out against others and assigning blame is the only way he can rationalise things. Similarly, the small town in which the accident occurs seems at first to be a picturesque postcard village. But gradually this image is shattered, as promiscuity, infidelity, alcoholism and sexual abuse all raise their heads. Director Atom Egoyan, an outspoken fan of "The Shining", even uses the famous "Horse and Train" picture from Kubrick's film, a recognition that both films deal subliminally with the same buried, almost invisible horrors. On top of all this, Egoyan adds a layer of myth. He has one of the film's children narrate Robert Browning's "The Pied Piper of Hamelin". In a self referential moment, the child asks "Who took the children? Who was the piper? Why did the fabled portal in the mountain (the breaking ice) open up and swallow the kids?" In this way, Egoyan approaches his central the tragedy from at least 3 angles. Firstly, as a fateful moment of chance, secondly, as a mythical act of God (God smites the parent's for their sins) and thirdly as an event exploited by a vengeful pilgrim of pain. All three approaches seek to lay blame, targeting either the failures of parents, the actions of a punishing god or the laws of a wholly arbitrary cosmos. "The Sweet Hereafter" is a very hopeless film, man never able to grasp absolute clarity (which of my behaviours, if any, caused this?). But there's also something very hopeful about Egoyan's ending. The sweet hereafter of the title is that zone of wisdom (found by the child who narrates the Piped Piper) where we ultimately come to accept the unacceptable and go on living. Similar in structure, Egoyan's "Exotica" approaches the same themes from a different angle. A man (Francis) loses his wife and daughter in a car crash. To cope with the pain he hires a young girl to come over to his house every day and babysit the daughter he lost. This babysitter simply plays a piano and lurks about his empty house, after which the bereaved father drives her home and pays her for babysitting nothingness. This ritual helps Francis assuage his pain. Every night Francis also visits a strip-club called "Exotica". There he watches a young woman (Christina), dressed in a schoolgirl's outfit, strip. But their relationship is an odd one. They seem to have a strange history. When she dances for him, it has nothing to do with sex and more to do with longing and loss. Of course both Francis and the stripper have a secret which is incrementally revealed, the truth peeled back like a stripper's clothes, leading to that revelatory final payoff that is typical of Egoyan's work. I won't spoil that moment. Suffice to say that this movie takes us into fairly interesting places. For Egoyan, man seems to live a life of cyclical substitution (we grow or are pushed out of everything and are forced to find substitutes). It's a bleak film, but unlike the work of Sam Mendes, to whom Egoyan is often wrongly compared, Egoyan eschews easy sensationalism and carnival freak-shows. 8.5/10 - Worth two viewings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What Could Have Been Superficial Is Astonishingly Deep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cosmicly
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What might seem at first to be a superficial story about middle aged guys seeking escape in the exotic world of young and beautiful strippers is actually a deep and intricately woven story of intersecting lives. And those seemingly ordinary lives are charged with extraordinary catastrophe. Excellent directing by Atom Egoyan. Superb acting by Mia Kirshner, Elias Koteas, Bruce Greenwood and Don McKellar. And the power of the film is amplified by an unforgettable soundtrack that includes the haunting lament of Leonard Cohen's classic "Everybody Knows." At the denouement, we are left with an abiding sense of cosmic ache, and a hope that there is truth in Dostoevsky's assertion that "our evils are expiated by suffering."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barriers Between Humans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egoyan's 'Exotica' is about emotionally isolated people who try to connect with each other. With every interaction between the characters there are symbolic barriers either in the form of finance, two way mirrors and social rules. But once this barrier is seized (symbolically) in the form of physical contact like the touch between Thomas and Chrissy and between Frances and Eric they form a connection. Egoyan does not resolve the 'problems' by showing the characters healed but instead what he demonstrates is that this human connection has brought change within them. In contrast, we also see how the characters once connected but now have drifted apart like Frances and Kristina or Zoe and Eric or Thomas and the officer. Explaining it more would be giving away too much of the story. While we see all these characters struggle to connect, there is Zoe who tries to keep things together but she too is sitting behind a one-way mirror. Egoyan uses plenty of symbolism and simple storytelling just isn't his style. He uses a rather suggestive approach. What he does in 'Exotica' is reveal very slowly. Moving at a slow pace, the film does 'test' the viewer's patience but there are a lot of subtle things happening and one has to observe closely to see that things aren't what they seem on the surface. There's a film-noire type quality to it. A lot of darkness is used, both symbolically and actually. The dialogues are simple but profound in depth. The haunting soundtrack gives the film a seductive and sensual edge. The performances are superb all the way. This is the first time I see Bruce Greenwood turn in a decent performance. Elias Koteas and Don McKellar are first rate. A very young Sarah Polley shows what potential she has. Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian is terrific. Mia Kirschner blends excellently blends sensuality, pain, fragility and kindness into Chrissy. 'Exotica' is not everyone's kind of film. Some may find its theme too dark and too intense but it's a film that isn't afraid to reveal, suggest and challenge the viewer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The essentials of a masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jexline
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Atom Egoyan's "Exotica" is perhaps the most perfect and beautifully intricate film I have seen. Filmed on a $2 million Canadian budget with his mostly usual staple of actors it explores territory usually left unchartered in the film world. Francis Brown (Bruce Greenwood) is a tax auditor for Revenue Canada who makes nightly visits to Exotica, a local gentleman's club, where he also asks for his favorite dancer, Christina (Mia Kirschner). The activity of the club is told to us by Eric, the D.J. (Elias Koteas)who makes suggestive comments about the dancers. The club is owned by the pregnant Zoe (Arsinee Khanjian; Egoyan's wife). The other main character of the story is Thomas Pinto (Don McKellar), a latently gay pet shop owner being audited by Francis. The film is largely about replacements and rituals. Eric used to be Christina's lover and relives the relationship through MCing suggestive fantasies of her. The club used to be owned by Zoe's mother and she is taking her mother's place since it's easier than creating her own options. Francis has his niece (Sarah Polley) babysit while he's gone, even though there's no baby to sit and pays her $20 a night and pays Christina $5 a dance. Thomas goes to the opera on a regular basis and scalps tickets in order to meet up with other men. The film doesn't truly come together until the conclusion where everything makes sense. This film features some great performances, especially Bruce Greenwood as the troubled and intense Francis. Elias Koteas is equally good as the jealous DJ. This is a sorely underrated film with the essentials of a masterpiece. The score is also excellent and I highly recommend the soundtrack as well. Overall, one of my all-time favorite films. A must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Obsession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Exotica" deals totally with obsession. Writer/director Atom Egoyan does well to get us hooked on his central characters, without knowing why they are behaving as they do. The plot centres around strip club "Exotica" as Egoyan teases out his tale like a striptease, little by little showing us more of who these people are and why. The resolution is perhaps disappointing (like a striptease when all has been revealed), failing to fulfill our high hopes. Best character is Francis, who appears to change before our eyes as the film progresses. It is not really he who changes however, but our perception of him. Likewise we view all the players differently in the end, though some of their motivations are hastily explained, if at all. Fantastic performances wrap up this oft times mesmerising film, with Bruce Greenwood a particular standout as Francis. Mia Kirshner (Christina) and Don McKellar (Thomas) are strong too. Also stars Elias Koteas as Eric and Arsinee Khanjian as Zoe. The exotic score is from Mychael Danna, and Paul Sarossy's camera captures Linda del Rosario and Richard Paris' production design (eye catching at times) well. Monday, November 3, 1997 - Hoyts Croydon Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More of a woman's POV movie than might be expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dennis Littrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Note: Over 500 of my movie reviews are now available in my book "Cut to the Chaise Lounge or I Can't Believe I Swallowed the Remote!" Get it at Amazon.) Atom Egoyan's Exotica is an outstanding movie. I have seen Egoyan's The Sweet Hereafter (1997) which is also very good. A father's (obsessive) love for his daughter(s) is featured in both movies, consequently the theme must mean something special to Egoyan. He is a most talented and original movie maker, a Canadian as are his players, Bruce Greenwood, (Francis Brown, the accountant whose daughter was murdered), Sarah Polley, (Tracey, the high school girl), and Mia Kirshner, (Christina, the exotic dancer). His wife, Arsinee Khanjian and Polley were also featured in The Sweet Hereafter. What really makes the movie is Egoyan's use of time and action sequence. He cuts up the chronological order of events and then presents them in a dramatic way. This is not so easy to do. Christopher Nolan in Memento (2000) used the same technique to great advantage. I have come late to such a technique and would love to master it myself. I worked on it last year and a couple of years before. You can't just scissor it and then paste it back together. Something must be gained from reversing the order of events. When Eric and Christina are shown walking the fields in a long line of people I jumped to the conclusion that Tracey would be found dead. We don't learn that Francis lost his daughter until the film is nearly finished. The psychology of Francis and the young girls is interesting. Christina says she gave something to him and he gave something to her. This vagueness with its unmistakable sexuality is something that always exists between young girls and older men. And, as Egoyan observes, there are rules and awkwardness, and confused emotions. However the girl wants it made unmistakably clear that she is desired physically and just talk is almost never sufficient. She often doesn't know whether she really wants to be "taken" fully, and of course that is usually, shall we say, problematic. Some great subtly is required in handled such a theme, and Egoyan realizes that. His character Francis Brown is content with fantasy and does not touch at all. This film would have found a larger audience except for the title, the theme, and the milieu. The female audience for the most part didn't even consider watching the movie since, as one woman said, I thought it was just another movie with an older man lusting after a girl half his age. That theme bores women to death. But surprisingly at the IMDb a viewer asks how women feel about the film and several write in to say that they liked it. Another poster remarks that women over forty actually liked Exotica in higher percentages than males. I thought the veracious and business-like depiction of the exotic dancer club was well done. The very nice side plot with the gay animal importer was just a perfect fit for the main plot. Egoyan wrote the script. It is a great script. So much surprises. It's almost too good. For me, since I have seen so many, many movies, something different, some surprises in plot, in character, in treatment are always welcome. And the plot does surprise. Even when the protagonist, Francis waits outside the club to shoot Eric, Egoyan turns the situation on its head by having Eric appear from the side and explain something that changes Francis's attitude toward him. I am being vague because I don't want to spoil the story. Some moviesmost movies I would say, since I go back to the generation that would go into the theatre and sit down during the middle of the movie; and then four or five hours later, realize, "This is where I came in"--in most movies to know the ending or the plot would not spoil the movie. We know so and so dies at the end. What is interesting is how he dies, how the actions develops. But in this movie to know the plot would take something away. I think. I'm not sure. Anyway Francis is a tax auditor who lost his daughter when she was less than eight years old. She was murdered. The police initially thought he did it, but he was found innocent and the murderer was apprehended and convicted. But Francis is left hollow and tries to bring her back in a way by having teenage girls "babysit" his nonexistent daughter. Egoyan teases us near the beginning by showing Francis and Tracey in his car as he drops her off at her home giving her some money and asking, "Are you free Thursday?" Very near the end of the movie we find that Tracey had a precursor in that babysitting role. You might be able to guess who it was. The sound track features "Everybody Knows" by Leonard Cohen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated, I'm afraid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Comparing this to Uwe Boll's stuff is a bit unfair, but I see where that reviewer is coming from. But, LOL, calling Leonard Cohen a Tom Waits wannabe, that's the funniest thing I've heard all year. The photography in this film almost redeems its many failings, but not quite. I get a lot of chuckles from the gushing reviews from art-house hangers-on; there is a kind of "Art-house clich&eacute;" which arises from the deliberate avoidance of Hollywood clich&eacute;. This film is full of it. You might call it "anti-clich&eacute;". But it amounts to the same thing. I see none of the freshness and vigour I look for in a good indy film. It mightn't be so bad if the plot didn't require so much suspension of disbelief. There couldn't exist a strip club such as this one, it would be just ludicrous. And why doesn't Mr. Egoyan find something else for his wife to do besides "acting" in all his movies? Anyhow, watch this if you've got nothing better on, but expect to be bored rigid waiting for the good bits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bust A Move...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    newkfl
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would have to admit that Exotica turned out to be a better film than I had imagined. It was slow in parts, but I guess it was to counter some of the scenes in the movie. There were some very disturbing characters in the movie too that really did not have problems so to speak, but certainly could have used some help from a trained sexual therapist. I would have certainly kept my distance from the character with the very hairy chest. I do not even think that he knew what he was going to do next. There was some good bar scene shots and dialog, but all in all, I think that the ending was a little bit rushed. It made me think of several ways that the movie could have been changed to fit the ending. Do not blink!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, dark, cold seduction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exotica is my first Atom Egoyan film, and I'm now inclined to go out and go through his entire catalog. The title and DVD cover may make is seem like an erotic thriller at first, when in fact nothing could be further from the truth; Exotica is a beautiful, dark, low-key drama that seduces the viewer with sensuality and sexuality but maintains a chilly distance throughout. Exotica takes place in a strip club but isn't at any time titillating. It keeps the viewer out both sexually and emotionally - it's a character study piece that doesn't allow us to get into the head of any of the characters, one that doesn't have a real protagonist. Every character is a stranger to us and they all keep secrets from us and from each other, secrets that unravel as the film unfolds in a deliberately slow and strictly structured pace. I'm glad that I went into Exotica knowing next to nothing about it, and so should you. Quit reading reviews and just watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I have seen this movie was 10 year ago. I recorded it on video back then and watched it at least 4 times in last 10 years. It's very unusual for me, I rarely watch a movie twice. This movie has all ingredients that make a good movie for me: Awesome characters, perfectly fitting actors that play them well. Great music and a stunning atmosphere. (The music is simplified, unusual and perfectly fitting.) An amazing story that moves you and keeps you interested till the end. In addition to that, the movie has some nice bonus points: It's sexy (I love Mia Kirshner), intelligent and forces you to think. - And that is probably the one thing I like the most about movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a review of "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica", two films by Atom Egoyan, both of which deal with tragedy and loss and both of which feature the same actors in similar roles. Like most of his films, Egoyan's "The Sweet Hereafter" is structured as a jigsaw possible assembled around a single traumatic event. As the film unfolds, and the cast's relationship to the central event grows in clarity, some moment of revelation is achieved. Virtually all of Egoyan's films adopt this narrative structure, which seems to blend a modernist search for truth with a decidedly postmodern admittance that truth requires the careful sorting of both vantage points and testimonials. The traumatic event in this case is an accident involving a school bus. The bus skids off a road and veers onto a frozen lake. The ice breaks, the bus sinks and 14 children die. Of course, everyone in the town then suffers the knock-on effect of this accident. Man, you might say, is a creature constantly in search of meaning (the brain itself is a pattern recognition machine). He creates myths, patterns and rhymes, trying desperately to assert some measure of order. He cannot accept the chaotic cruelty of the universe, preferring instead to create comfortable rituals and routines in the hope of insulating himself from pain. When the unexpected does occur, man lifts his head and cries "Why?". But God never answers. Into this vacuum steps Ian Holm, who in "The Sweet Hereafter" plays a lawyer trying desperately to assign meaning to the film's central bus crash. He wants the parents of the dead children to band together and file a law suit. A law suit against who? The guilty bus driver? Nope, the driver is broke. He wants to go after the company that made the bus. He wants to sue them for millions. It is their fault. Alone. At first Ian Holm comes across as a greedy pig. Here is a man milking suffering for money. But gradually we learn that he is himself a man intimately familiar with loss. His life has been one of misery, and the film is peppered with flashbacks detailing his relationship with his daughter, a drug addict who is dying of AIDS. Like the parents whom he hopes to represent, this lawyer is looking for the meaning of his own suffering. "Why me?" he cries. Lashing out against others and assigning blame is the only way he can rationalise things. Similarly, the small town in which the accident occurs seems at first to be a picturesque postcard village. But gradually this image is shattered, as promiscuity, infidelity, alcoholism and sexual abuse all raise their heads. Director Atom Egoyan, an outspoken fan of "The Shining", even uses the famous "Horse and Train" picture from Kubrick's film, a recognition that both films deal subliminally with the same buried, almost invisible horrors. On top of all this, Egoyan adds a layer of myth. He has one of the film's children narrate Robert Browning's "The Pied Piper of Hamelin". In a self referential moment, the child asks "Who took the children? Who was the piper? Why did the fabled portal in the mountain (the breaking ice) open up and swallow the kids?" In this way, Egoyan approaches his central the tragedy from at least 3 angles. Firstly, as a fateful moment of chance, secondly, as a mythical act of God (God smites the parent's for their sins) and thirdly as an event exploited by a vengeful pilgrim of pain. All three approaches seek to lay blame, targeting either the failures of parents, the actions of a punishing god or the laws of a wholly arbitrary cosmos. "The Sweet Hereafter" is a very hopeless film, man never able to grasp absolute clarity (which of my behaviours, if any, caused this?). But there's also something very hopeful about Egoyan's ending. The sweet hereafter of the title is that zone of wisdom (found by the child who narrates the Piped Piper) where we ultimately come to accept the unacceptable and go on living. Similar in structure, Egoyan's "Exotica" approaches the same themes from a different angle. A man (Francis) loses his wife and daughter in a car crash. To cope with the pain he hires a young girl to come over to his house every day and babysit the daughter he lost. This babysitter simply plays a piano and lurks about his empty house, after which the bereaved father drives her home and pays her for babysitting nothingness. This ritual helps Francis assuage his pain. Every night Francis also visits a strip-club called "Exotica". There he watches a young woman (Christina), dressed in a schoolgirl's outfit, strip. But their relationship is an odd one. They seem to have a strange history. When she dances for him, it has nothing to do with sex and more to do with longing and loss. Of course both Francis and the stripper have a secret which is incrementally revealed, the truth peeled back like a stripper's clothes, leading to that revelatory final payoff that is typical of Egoyan's work. I won't spoil that moment. Suffice to say that this movie takes us into fairly interesting places. For Egoyan, man seems to live a life of cyclical substitution (we grow or are pushed out of everything and are forced to find substitutes). It's a bleak film, but unlike the work of Sam Mendes, to whom Egoyan is often wrongly compared, Egoyan eschews easy sensationalism and carnival freak-shows. 8.5/10 - Worth two viewings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What Could Have Been Superficial Is Astonishingly Deep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cosmicly
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What might seem at first to be a superficial story about middle aged guys seeking escape in the exotic world of young and beautiful strippers is actually a deep and intricately woven story of intersecting lives. And those seemingly ordinary lives are charged with extraordinary catastrophe. Excellent directing by Atom Egoyan. Superb acting by Mia Kirshner, Elias Koteas, Bruce Greenwood and Don McKellar. And the power of the film is amplified by an unforgettable soundtrack that includes the haunting lament of Leonard Cohen's classic "Everybody Knows." At the denouement, we are left with an abiding sense of cosmic ache, and a hope that there is truth in Dostoevsky's assertion that "our evils are expiated by suffering."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barriers Between Humans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egoyan's 'Exotica' is about emotionally isolated people who try to connect with each other. With every interaction between the characters there are symbolic barriers either in the form of finance, two way mirrors and social rules. But once this barrier is seized (symbolically) in the form of physical contact like the touch between Thomas and Chrissy and between Frances and Eric they form a connection. Egoyan does not resolve the 'problems' by showing the characters healed but instead what he demonstrates is that this human connection has brought change within them. In contrast, we also see how the characters once connected but now have drifted apart like Frances and Kristina or Zoe and Eric or Thomas and the officer. Explaining it more would be giving away too much of the story. While we see all these characters struggle to connect, there is Zoe who tries to keep things together but she too is sitting behind a one-way mirror. Egoyan uses plenty of symbolism and simple storytelling just isn't his style. He uses a rather suggestive approach. What he does in 'Exotica' is reveal very slowly. Moving at a slow pace, the film does 'test' the viewer's patience but there are a lot of subtle things happening and one has to observe closely to see that things aren't what they seem on the surface. There's a film-noire type quality to it. A lot of darkness is used, both symbolically and actually. The dialogues are simple but profound in depth. The haunting soundtrack gives the film a seductive and sensual edge. The performances are superb all the way. This is the first time I see Bruce Greenwood turn in a decent performance. Elias Koteas and Don McKellar are first rate. A very young Sarah Polley shows what potential she has. Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian is terrific. Mia Kirschner blends excellently blends sensuality, pain, fragility and kindness into Chrissy. 'Exotica' is not everyone's kind of film. Some may find its theme too dark and too intense but it's a film that isn't afraid to reveal, suggest and challenge the viewer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The essentials of a masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jexline
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Atom Egoyan's "Exotica" is perhaps the most perfect and beautifully intricate film I have seen. Filmed on a $2 million Canadian budget with his mostly usual staple of actors it explores territory usually left unchartered in the film world. Francis Brown (Bruce Greenwood) is a tax auditor for Revenue Canada who makes nightly visits to Exotica, a local gentleman's club, where he also asks for his favorite dancer, Christina (Mia Kirschner). The activity of the club is told to us by Eric, the D.J. (Elias Koteas)who makes suggestive comments about the dancers. The club is owned by the pregnant Zoe (Arsinee Khanjian; Egoyan's wife). The other main character of the story is Thomas Pinto (Don McKellar), a latently gay pet shop owner being audited by Francis. The film is largely about replacements and rituals. Eric used to be Christina's lover and relives the relationship through MCing suggestive fantasies of her. The club used to be owned by Zoe's mother and she is taking her mother's place since it's easier than creating her own options. Francis has his niece (Sarah Polley) babysit while he's gone, even though there's no baby to sit and pays her $20 a night and pays Christina $5 a dance. Thomas goes to the opera on a regular basis and scalps tickets in order to meet up with other men. The film doesn't truly come together until the conclusion where everything makes sense. This film features some great performances, especially Bruce Greenwood as the troubled and intense Francis. Elias Koteas is equally good as the jealous DJ. This is a sorely underrated film with the essentials of a masterpiece. The score is also excellent and I highly recommend the soundtrack as well. Overall, one of my all-time favorite films. A must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Obsession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Exotica" deals totally with obsession. Writer/director Atom Egoyan does well to get us hooked on his central characters, without knowing why they are behaving as they do. The plot centres around strip club "Exotica" as Egoyan teases out his tale like a striptease, little by little showing us more of who these people are and why. The resolution is perhaps disappointing (like a striptease when all has been revealed), failing to fulfill our high hopes. Best character is Francis, who appears to change before our eyes as the film progresses. It is not really he who changes however, but our perception of him. Likewise we view all the players differently in the end, though some of their motivations are hastily explained, if at all. Fantastic performances wrap up this oft times mesmerising film, with Bruce Greenwood a particular standout as Francis. Mia Kirshner (Christina) and Don McKellar (Thomas) are strong too. Also stars Elias Koteas as Eric and Arsinee Khanjian as Zoe. The exotic score is from Mychael Danna, and Paul Sarossy's camera captures Linda del Rosario and Richard Paris' production design (eye catching at times) well. Monday, November 3, 1997 - Hoyts Croydon Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More of a woman's POV movie than might be expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dennis Littrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Note: Over 500 of my movie reviews are now available in my book "Cut to the Chaise Lounge or I Can't Believe I Swallowed the Remote!" Get it at Amazon.) Atom Egoyan's Exotica is an outstanding movie. I have seen Egoyan's The Sweet Hereafter (1997) which is also very good. A father's (obsessive) love for his daughter(s) is featured in both movies, consequently the theme must mean something special to Egoyan. He is a most talented and original movie maker, a Canadian as are his players, Bruce Greenwood, (Francis Brown, the accountant whose daughter was murdered), Sarah Polley, (Tracey, the high school girl), and Mia Kirshner, (Christina, the exotic dancer). His wife, Arsinee Khanjian and Polley were also featured in The Sweet Hereafter. What really makes the movie is Egoyan's use of time and action sequence. He cuts up the chronological order of events and then presents them in a dramatic way. This is not so easy to do. Christopher Nolan in Memento (2000) used the same technique to great advantage. I have come late to such a technique and would love to master it myself. I worked on it last year and a couple of years before. You can't just scissor it and then paste it back together. Something must be gained from reversing the order of events. When Eric and Christina are shown walking the fields in a long line of people I jumped to the conclusion that Tracey would be found dead. We don't learn that Francis lost his daughter until the film is nearly finished. The psychology of Francis and the young girls is interesting. Christina says she gave something to him and he gave something to her. This vagueness with its unmistakable sexuality is something that always exists between young girls and older men. And, as Egoyan observes, there are rules and awkwardness, and confused emotions. However the girl wants it made unmistakably clear that she is desired physically and just talk is almost never sufficient. She often doesn't know whether she really wants to be "taken" fully, and of course that is usually, shall we say, problematic. Some great subtly is required in handled such a theme, and Egoyan realizes that. His character Francis Brown is content with fantasy and does not touch at all. This film would have found a larger audience except for the title, the theme, and the milieu. The female audience for the most part didn't even consider watching the movie since, as one woman said, I thought it was just another movie with an older man lusting after a girl half his age. That theme bores women to death. But surprisingly at the IMDb a viewer asks how women feel about the film and several write in to say that they liked it. Another poster remarks that women over forty actually liked Exotica in higher percentages than males. I thought the veracious and business-like depiction of the exotic dancer club was well done. The very nice side plot with the gay animal importer was just a perfect fit for the main plot. Egoyan wrote the script. It is a great script. So much surprises. It's almost too good. For me, since I have seen so many, many movies, something different, some surprises in plot, in character, in treatment are always welcome. And the plot does surprise. Even when the protagonist, Francis waits outside the club to shoot Eric, Egoyan turns the situation on its head by having Eric appear from the side and explain something that changes Francis's attitude toward him. I am being vague because I don't want to spoil the story. Some moviesmost movies I would say, since I go back to the generation that would go into the theatre and sit down during the middle of the movie; and then four or five hours later, realize, "This is where I came in"--in most movies to know the ending or the plot would not spoil the movie. We know so and so dies at the end. What is interesting is how he dies, how the actions develops. But in this movie to know the plot would take something away. I think. I'm not sure. Anyway Francis is a tax auditor who lost his daughter when she was less than eight years old. She was murdered. The police initially thought he did it, but he was found innocent and the murderer was apprehended and convicted. But Francis is left hollow and tries to bring her back in a way by having teenage girls "babysit" his nonexistent daughter. Egoyan teases us near the beginning by showing Francis and Tracey in his car as he drops her off at her home giving her some money and asking, "Are you free Thursday?" Very near the end of the movie we find that Tracey had a precursor in that babysitting role. You might be able to guess who it was. The sound track features "Everybody Knows" by Leonard Cohen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated, I'm afraid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Comparing this to Uwe Boll's stuff is a bit unfair, but I see where that reviewer is coming from. But, LOL, calling Leonard Cohen a Tom Waits wannabe, that's the funniest thing I've heard all year. The photography in this film almost redeems its many failings, but not quite. I get a lot of chuckles from the gushing reviews from art-house hangers-on; there is a kind of "Art-house clich&eacute;" which arises from the deliberate avoidance of Hollywood clich&eacute;. This film is full of it. You might call it "anti-clich&eacute;". But it amounts to the same thing. I see none of the freshness and vigour I look for in a good indy film. It mightn't be so bad if the plot didn't require so much suspension of disbelief. There couldn't exist a strip club such as this one, it would be just ludicrous. And why doesn't Mr. Egoyan find something else for his wife to do besides "acting" in all his movies? Anyhow, watch this if you've got nothing better on, but expect to be bored rigid waiting for the good bits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bust A Move...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    newkfl
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would have to admit that Exotica turned out to be a better film than I had imagined. It was slow in parts, but I guess it was to counter some of the scenes in the movie. There were some very disturbing characters in the movie too that really did not have problems so to speak, but certainly could have used some help from a trained sexual therapist. I would have certainly kept my distance from the character with the very hairy chest. I do not even think that he knew what he was going to do next. There was some good bar scene shots and dialog, but all in all, I think that the ending was a little bit rushed. It made me think of several ways that the movie could have been changed to fit the ending. Do not blink!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, dark, cold seduction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exotica is my first Atom Egoyan film, and I'm now inclined to go out and go through his entire catalog. The title and DVD cover may make is seem like an erotic thriller at first, when in fact nothing could be further from the truth; Exotica is a beautiful, dark, low-key drama that seduces the viewer with sensuality and sexuality but maintains a chilly distance throughout. Exotica takes place in a strip club but isn't at any time titillating. It keeps the viewer out both sexually and emotionally - it's a character study piece that doesn't allow us to get into the head of any of the characters, one that doesn't have a real protagonist. Every character is a stranger to us and they all keep secrets from us and from each other, secrets that unravel as the film unfolds in a deliberately slow and strictly structured pace. I'm glad that I went into Exotica knowing next to nothing about it, and so should you. Quit reading reviews and just watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I have seen this movie was 10 year ago. I recorded it on video back then and watched it at least 4 times in last 10 years. It's very unusual for me, I rarely watch a movie twice. This movie has all ingredients that make a good movie for me: Awesome characters, perfectly fitting actors that play them well. Great music and a stunning atmosphere. (The music is simplified, unusual and perfectly fitting.) An amazing story that moves you and keeps you interested till the end. In addition to that, the movie has some nice bonus points: It's sexy (I love Mia Kirshner), intelligent and forces you to think. - And that is probably the one thing I like the most about movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a review of "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica", two films by Atom Egoyan, both of which deal with tragedy and loss and both of which feature the same actors in similar roles. Like most of his films, Egoyan's "The Sweet Hereafter" is structured as a jigsaw possible assembled around a single traumatic event. As the film unfolds, and the cast's relationship to the central event grows in clarity, some moment of revelation is achieved. Virtually all of Egoyan's films adopt this narrative structure, which seems to blend a modernist search for truth with a decidedly postmodern admittance that truth requires the careful sorting of both vantage points and testimonials. The traumatic event in this case is an accident involving a school bus. The bus skids off a road and veers onto a frozen lake. The ice breaks, the bus sinks and 14 children die. Of course, everyone in the town then suffers the knock-on effect of this accident. Man, you might say, is a creature constantly in search of meaning (the brain itself is a pattern recognition machine). He creates myths, patterns and rhymes, trying desperately to assert some measure of order. He cannot accept the chaotic cruelty of the universe, preferring instead to create comfortable rituals and routines in the hope of insulating himself from pain. When the unexpected does occur, man lifts his head and cries "Why?". But God never answers. Into this vacuum steps Ian Holm, who in "The Sweet Hereafter" plays a lawyer trying desperately to assign meaning to the film's central bus crash. He wants the parents of the dead children to band together and file a law suit. A law suit against who? The guilty bus driver? Nope, the driver is broke. He wants to go after the company that made the bus. He wants to sue them for millions. It is their fault. Alone. At first Ian Holm comes across as a greedy pig. Here is a man milking suffering for money. But gradually we learn that he is himself a man intimately familiar with loss. His life has been one of misery, and the film is peppered with flashbacks detailing his relationship with his daughter, a drug addict who is dying of AIDS. Like the parents whom he hopes to represent, this lawyer is looking for the meaning of his own suffering. "Why me?" he cries. Lashing out against others and assigning blame is the only way he can rationalise things. Similarly, the small town in which the accident occurs seems at first to be a picturesque postcard village. But gradually this image is shattered, as promiscuity, infidelity, alcoholism and sexual abuse all raise their heads. Director Atom Egoyan, an outspoken fan of "The Shining", even uses the famous "Horse and Train" picture from Kubrick's film, a recognition that both films deal subliminally with the same buried, almost invisible horrors. On top of all this, Egoyan adds a layer of myth. He has one of the film's children narrate Robert Browning's "The Pied Piper of Hamelin". In a self referential moment, the child asks "Who took the children? Who was the piper? Why did the fabled portal in the mountain (the breaking ice) open up and swallow the kids?" In this way, Egoyan approaches his central the tragedy from at least 3 angles. Firstly, as a fateful moment of chance, secondly, as a mythical act of God (God smites the parent's for their sins) and thirdly as an event exploited by a vengeful pilgrim of pain. All three approaches seek to lay blame, targeting either the failures of parents, the actions of a punishing god or the laws of a wholly arbitrary cosmos. "The Sweet Hereafter" is a very hopeless film, man never able to grasp absolute clarity (which of my behaviours, if any, caused this?). But there's also something very hopeful about Egoyan's ending. The sweet hereafter of the title is that zone of wisdom (found by the child who narrates the Piped Piper) where we ultimately come to accept the unacceptable and go on living. Similar in structure, Egoyan's "Exotica" approaches the same themes from a different angle. A man (Francis) loses his wife and daughter in a car crash. To cope with the pain he hires a young girl to come over to his house every day and babysit the daughter he lost. This babysitter simply plays a piano and lurks about his empty house, after which the bereaved father drives her home and pays her for babysitting nothingness. This ritual helps Francis assuage his pain. Every night Francis also visits a strip-club called "Exotica". There he watches a young woman (Christina), dressed in a schoolgirl's outfit, strip. But their relationship is an odd one. They seem to have a strange history. When she dances for him, it has nothing to do with sex and more to do with longing and loss. Of course both Francis and the stripper have a secret which is incrementally revealed, the truth peeled back like a stripper's clothes, leading to that revelatory final payoff that is typical of Egoyan's work. I won't spoil that moment. Suffice to say that this movie takes us into fairly interesting places. For Egoyan, man seems to live a life of cyclical substitution (we grow or are pushed out of everything and are forced to find substitutes). It's a bleak film, but unlike the work of Sam Mendes, to whom Egoyan is often wrongly compared, Egoyan eschews easy sensationalism and carnival freak-shows. 8.5/10 - Worth two viewings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What Could Have Been Superficial Is Astonishingly Deep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cosmicly
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What might seem at first to be a superficial story about middle aged guys seeking escape in the exotic world of young and beautiful strippers is actually a deep and intricately woven story of intersecting lives. And those seemingly ordinary lives are charged with extraordinary catastrophe. Excellent directing by Atom Egoyan. Superb acting by Mia Kirshner, Elias Koteas, Bruce Greenwood and Don McKellar. And the power of the film is amplified by an unforgettable soundtrack that includes the haunting lament of Leonard Cohen's classic "Everybody Knows." At the denouement, we are left with an abiding sense of cosmic ache, and a hope that there is truth in Dostoevsky's assertion that "our evils are expiated by suffering."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barriers Between Humans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egoyan's 'Exotica' is about emotionally isolated people who try to connect with each other. With every interaction between the characters there are symbolic barriers either in the form of finance, two way mirrors and social rules. But once this barrier is seized (symbolically) in the form of physical contact like the touch between Thomas and Chrissy and between Frances and Eric they form a connection. Egoyan does not resolve the 'problems' by showing the characters healed but instead what he demonstrates is that this human connection has brought change within them. In contrast, we also see how the characters once connected but now have drifted apart like Frances and Kristina or Zoe and Eric or Thomas and the officer. Explaining it more would be giving away too much of the story. While we see all these characters struggle to connect, there is Zoe who tries to keep things together but she too is sitting behind a one-way mirror. Egoyan uses plenty of symbolism and simple storytelling just isn't his style. He uses a rather suggestive approach. What he does in 'Exotica' is reveal very slowly. Moving at a slow pace, the film does 'test' the viewer's patience but there are a lot of subtle things happening and one has to observe closely to see that things aren't what they seem on the surface. There's a film-noire type quality to it. A lot of darkness is used, both symbolically and actually. The dialogues are simple but profound in depth. The haunting soundtrack gives the film a seductive and sensual edge. The performances are superb all the way. This is the first time I see Bruce Greenwood turn in a decent performance. Elias Koteas and Don McKellar are first rate. A very young Sarah Polley shows what potential she has. Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian is terrific. Mia Kirschner blends excellently blends sensuality, pain, fragility and kindness into Chrissy. 'Exotica' is not everyone's kind of film. Some may find its theme too dark and too intense but it's a film that isn't afraid to reveal, suggest and challenge the viewer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The essentials of a masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jexline
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Atom Egoyan's "Exotica" is perhaps the most perfect and beautifully intricate film I have seen. Filmed on a $2 million Canadian budget with his mostly usual staple of actors it explores territory usually left unchartered in the film world. Francis Brown (Bruce Greenwood) is a tax auditor for Revenue Canada who makes nightly visits to Exotica, a local gentleman's club, where he also asks for his favorite dancer, Christina (Mia Kirschner). The activity of the club is told to us by Eric, the D.J. (Elias Koteas)who makes suggestive comments about the dancers. The club is owned by the pregnant Zoe (Arsinee Khanjian; Egoyan's wife). The other main character of the story is Thomas Pinto (Don McKellar), a latently gay pet shop owner being audited by Francis. The film is largely about replacements and rituals. Eric used to be Christina's lover and relives the relationship through MCing suggestive fantasies of her. The club used to be owned by Zoe's mother and she is taking her mother's place since it's easier than creating her own options. Francis has his niece (Sarah Polley) babysit while he's gone, even though there's no baby to sit and pays her $20 a night and pays Christina $5 a dance. Thomas goes to the opera on a regular basis and scalps tickets in order to meet up with other men. The film doesn't truly come together until the conclusion where everything makes sense. This film features some great performances, especially Bruce Greenwood as the troubled and intense Francis. Elias Koteas is equally good as the jealous DJ. This is a sorely underrated film with the essentials of a masterpiece. The score is also excellent and I highly recommend the soundtrack as well. Overall, one of my all-time favorite films. A must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Obsession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Exotica" deals totally with obsession. Writer/director Atom Egoyan does well to get us hooked on his central characters, without knowing why they are behaving as they do. The plot centres around strip club "Exotica" as Egoyan teases out his tale like a striptease, little by little showing us more of who these people are and why. The resolution is perhaps disappointing (like a striptease when all has been revealed), failing to fulfill our high hopes. Best character is Francis, who appears to change before our eyes as the film progresses. It is not really he who changes however, but our perception of him. Likewise we view all the players differently in the end, though some of their motivations are hastily explained, if at all. Fantastic performances wrap up this oft times mesmerising film, with Bruce Greenwood a particular standout as Francis. Mia Kirshner (Christina) and Don McKellar (Thomas) are strong too. Also stars Elias Koteas as Eric and Arsinee Khanjian as Zoe. The exotic score is from Mychael Danna, and Paul Sarossy's camera captures Linda del Rosario and Richard Paris' production design (eye catching at times) well. Monday, November 3, 1997 - Hoyts Croydon Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More of a woman's POV movie than might be expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dennis Littrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Note: Over 500 of my movie reviews are now available in my book "Cut to the Chaise Lounge or I Can't Believe I Swallowed the Remote!" Get it at Amazon.) Atom Egoyan's Exotica is an outstanding movie. I have seen Egoyan's The Sweet Hereafter (1997) which is also very good. A father's (obsessive) love for his daughter(s) is featured in both movies, consequently the theme must mean something special to Egoyan. He is a most talented and original movie maker, a Canadian as are his players, Bruce Greenwood, (Francis Brown, the accountant whose daughter was murdered), Sarah Polley, (Tracey, the high school girl), and Mia Kirshner, (Christina, the exotic dancer). His wife, Arsinee Khanjian and Polley were also featured in The Sweet Hereafter. What really makes the movie is Egoyan's use of time and action sequence. He cuts up the chronological order of events and then presents them in a dramatic way. This is not so easy to do. Christopher Nolan in Memento (2000) used the same technique to great advantage. I have come late to such a technique and would love to master it myself. I worked on it last year and a couple of years before. You can't just scissor it and then paste it back together. Something must be gained from reversing the order of events. When Eric and Christina are shown walking the fields in a long line of people I jumped to the conclusion that Tracey would be found dead. We don't learn that Francis lost his daughter until the film is nearly finished. The psychology of Francis and the young girls is interesting. Christina says she gave something to him and he gave something to her. This vagueness with its unmistakable sexuality is something that always exists between young girls and older men. And, as Egoyan observes, there are rules and awkwardness, and confused emotions. However the girl wants it made unmistakably clear that she is desired physically and just talk is almost never sufficient. She often doesn't know whether she really wants to be "taken" fully, and of course that is usually, shall we say, problematic. Some great subtly is required in handled such a theme, and Egoyan realizes that. His character Francis Brown is content with fantasy and does not touch at all. This film would have found a larger audience except for the title, the theme, and the milieu. The female audience for the most part didn't even consider watching the movie since, as one woman said, I thought it was just another movie with an older man lusting after a girl half his age. That theme bores women to death. But surprisingly at the IMDb a viewer asks how women feel about the film and several write in to say that they liked it. Another poster remarks that women over forty actually liked Exotica in higher percentages than males. I thought the veracious and business-like depiction of the exotic dancer club was well done. The very nice side plot with the gay animal importer was just a perfect fit for the main plot. Egoyan wrote the script. It is a great script. So much surprises. It's almost too good. For me, since I have seen so many, many movies, something different, some surprises in plot, in character, in treatment are always welcome. And the plot does surprise. Even when the protagonist, Francis waits outside the club to shoot Eric, Egoyan turns the situation on its head by having Eric appear from the side and explain something that changes Francis's attitude toward him. I am being vague because I don't want to spoil the story. Some moviesmost movies I would say, since I go back to the generation that would go into the theatre and sit down during the middle of the movie; and then four or five hours later, realize, "This is where I came in"--in most movies to know the ending or the plot would not spoil the movie. We know so and so dies at the end. What is interesting is how he dies, how the actions develops. But in this movie to know the plot would take something away. I think. I'm not sure. Anyway Francis is a tax auditor who lost his daughter when she was less than eight years old. She was murdered. The police initially thought he did it, but he was found innocent and the murderer was apprehended and convicted. But Francis is left hollow and tries to bring her back in a way by having teenage girls "babysit" his nonexistent daughter. Egoyan teases us near the beginning by showing Francis and Tracey in his car as he drops her off at her home giving her some money and asking, "Are you free Thursday?" Very near the end of the movie we find that Tracey had a precursor in that babysitting role. You might be able to guess who it was. The sound track features "Everybody Knows" by Leonard Cohen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated, I'm afraid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Comparing this to Uwe Boll's stuff is a bit unfair, but I see where that reviewer is coming from. But, LOL, calling Leonard Cohen a Tom Waits wannabe, that's the funniest thing I've heard all year. The photography in this film almost redeems its many failings, but not quite. I get a lot of chuckles from the gushing reviews from art-house hangers-on; there is a kind of "Art-house clich&eacute;" which arises from the deliberate avoidance of Hollywood clich&eacute;. This film is full of it. You might call it "anti-clich&eacute;". But it amounts to the same thing. I see none of the freshness and vigour I look for in a good indy film. It mightn't be so bad if the plot didn't require so much suspension of disbelief. There couldn't exist a strip club such as this one, it would be just ludicrous. And why doesn't Mr. Egoyan find something else for his wife to do besides "acting" in all his movies? Anyhow, watch this if you've got nothing better on, but expect to be bored rigid waiting for the good bits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bust A Move...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    newkfl
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would have to admit that Exotica turned out to be a better film than I had imagined. It was slow in parts, but I guess it was to counter some of the scenes in the movie. There were some very disturbing characters in the movie too that really did not have problems so to speak, but certainly could have used some help from a trained sexual therapist. I would have certainly kept my distance from the character with the very hairy chest. I do not even think that he knew what he was going to do next. There was some good bar scene shots and dialog, but all in all, I think that the ending was a little bit rushed. It made me think of several ways that the movie could have been changed to fit the ending. Do not blink!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, dark, cold seduction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exotica is my first Atom Egoyan film, and I'm now inclined to go out and go through his entire catalog. The title and DVD cover may make is seem like an erotic thriller at first, when in fact nothing could be further from the truth; Exotica is a beautiful, dark, low-key drama that seduces the viewer with sensuality and sexuality but maintains a chilly distance throughout. Exotica takes place in a strip club but isn't at any time titillating. It keeps the viewer out both sexually and emotionally - it's a character study piece that doesn't allow us to get into the head of any of the characters, one that doesn't have a real protagonist. Every character is a stranger to us and they all keep secrets from us and from each other, secrets that unravel as the film unfolds in a deliberately slow and strictly structured pace. I'm glad that I went into Exotica knowing next to nothing about it, and so should you. Quit reading reviews and just watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I have seen this movie was 10 year ago. I recorded it on video back then and watched it at least 4 times in last 10 years. It's very unusual for me, I rarely watch a movie twice. This movie has all ingredients that make a good movie for me: Awesome characters, perfectly fitting actors that play them well. Great music and a stunning atmosphere. (The music is simplified, unusual and perfectly fitting.) An amazing story that moves you and keeps you interested till the end. In addition to that, the movie has some nice bonus points: It's sexy (I love Mia Kirshner), intelligent and forces you to think. - And that is probably the one thing I like the most about movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a review of "The Sweet Hereafter" and "Exotica", two films by Atom Egoyan, both of which deal with tragedy and loss and both of which feature the same actors in similar roles. Like most of his films, Egoyan's "The Sweet Hereafter" is structured as a jigsaw possible assembled around a single traumatic event. As the film unfolds, and the cast's relationship to the central event grows in clarity, some moment of revelation is achieved. Virtually all of Egoyan's films adopt this narrative structure, which seems to blend a modernist search for truth with a decidedly postmodern admittance that truth requires the careful sorting of both vantage points and testimonials. The traumatic event in this case is an accident involving a school bus. The bus skids off a road and veers onto a frozen lake. The ice breaks, the bus sinks and 14 children die. Of course, everyone in the town then suffers the knock-on effect of this accident. Man, you might say, is a creature constantly in search of meaning (the brain itself is a pattern recognition machine). He creates myths, patterns and rhymes, trying desperately to assert some measure of order. He cannot accept the chaotic cruelty of the universe, preferring instead to create comfortable rituals and routines in the hope of insulating himself from pain. When the unexpected does occur, man lifts his head and cries "Why?". But God never answers. Into this vacuum steps Ian Holm, who in "The Sweet Hereafter" plays a lawyer trying desperately to assign meaning to the film's central bus crash. He wants the parents of the dead children to band together and file a law suit. A law suit against who? The guilty bus driver? Nope, the driver is broke. He wants to go after the company that made the bus. He wants to sue them for millions. It is their fault. Alone. At first Ian Holm comes across as a greedy pig. Here is a man milking suffering for money. But gradually we learn that he is himself a man intimately familiar with loss. His life has been one of misery, and the film is peppered with flashbacks detailing his relationship with his daughter, a drug addict who is dying of AIDS. Like the parents whom he hopes to represent, this lawyer is looking for the meaning of his own suffering. "Why me?" he cries. Lashing out against others and assigning blame is the only way he can rationalise things. Similarly, the small town in which the accident occurs seems at first to be a picturesque postcard village. But gradually this image is shattered, as promiscuity, infidelity, alcoholism and sexual abuse all raise their heads. Director Atom Egoyan, an outspoken fan of "The Shining", even uses the famous "Horse and Train" picture from Kubrick's film, a recognition that both films deal subliminally with the same buried, almost invisible horrors. On top of all this, Egoyan adds a layer of myth. He has one of the film's children narrate Robert Browning's "The Pied Piper of Hamelin". In a self referential moment, the child asks "Who took the children? Who was the piper? Why did the fabled portal in the mountain (the breaking ice) open up and swallow the kids?" In this way, Egoyan approaches his central the tragedy from at least 3 angles. Firstly, as a fateful moment of chance, secondly, as a mythical act of God (God smites the parent's for their sins) and thirdly as an event exploited by a vengeful pilgrim of pain. All three approaches seek to lay blame, targeting either the failures of parents, the actions of a punishing god or the laws of a wholly arbitrary cosmos. "The Sweet Hereafter" is a very hopeless film, man never able to grasp absolute clarity (which of my behaviours, if any, caused this?). But there's also something very hopeful about Egoyan's ending. The sweet hereafter of the title is that zone of wisdom (found by the child who narrates the Piped Piper) where we ultimately come to accept the unacceptable and go on living. Similar in structure, Egoyan's "Exotica" approaches the same themes from a different angle. A man (Francis) loses his wife and daughter in a car crash. To cope with the pain he hires a young girl to come over to his house every day and babysit the daughter he lost. This babysitter simply plays a piano and lurks about his empty house, after which the bereaved father drives her home and pays her for babysitting nothingness. This ritual helps Francis assuage his pain. Every night Francis also visits a strip-club called "Exotica". There he watches a young woman (Christina), dressed in a schoolgirl's outfit, strip. But their relationship is an odd one. They seem to have a strange history. When she dances for him, it has nothing to do with sex and more to do with longing and loss. Of course both Francis and the stripper have a secret which is incrementally revealed, the truth peeled back like a stripper's clothes, leading to that revelatory final payoff that is typical of Egoyan's work. I won't spoil that moment. Suffice to say that this movie takes us into fairly interesting places. For Egoyan, man seems to live a life of cyclical substitution (we grow or are pushed out of everything and are forced to find substitutes). It's a bleak film, but unlike the work of Sam Mendes, to whom Egoyan is often wrongly compared, Egoyan eschews easy sensationalism and carnival freak-shows. 8.5/10 - Worth two viewings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What Could Have Been Superficial Is Astonishingly Deep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cosmicly
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What might seem at first to be a superficial story about middle aged guys seeking escape in the exotic world of young and beautiful strippers is actually a deep and intricately woven story of intersecting lives. And those seemingly ordinary lives are charged with extraordinary catastrophe. Excellent directing by Atom Egoyan. Superb acting by Mia Kirshner, Elias Koteas, Bruce Greenwood and Don McKellar. And the power of the film is amplified by an unforgettable soundtrack that includes the haunting lament of Leonard Cohen's classic "Everybody Knows." At the denouement, we are left with an abiding sense of cosmic ache, and a hope that there is truth in Dostoevsky's assertion that "our evils are expiated by suffering."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barriers Between Humans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egoyan's 'Exotica' is about emotionally isolated people who try to connect with each other. With every interaction between the characters there are symbolic barriers either in the form of finance, two way mirrors and social rules. But once this barrier is seized (symbolically) in the form of physical contact like the touch between Thomas and Chrissy and between Frances and Eric they form a connection. Egoyan does not resolve the 'problems' by showing the characters healed but instead what he demonstrates is that this human connection has brought change within them. In contrast, we also see how the characters once connected but now have drifted apart like Frances and Kristina or Zoe and Eric or Thomas and the officer. Explaining it more would be giving away too much of the story. While we see all these characters struggle to connect, there is Zoe who tries to keep things together but she too is sitting behind a one-way mirror. Egoyan uses plenty of symbolism and simple storytelling just isn't his style. He uses a rather suggestive approach. What he does in 'Exotica' is reveal very slowly. Moving at a slow pace, the film does 'test' the viewer's patience but there are a lot of subtle things happening and one has to observe closely to see that things aren't what they seem on the surface. There's a film-noire type quality to it. A lot of darkness is used, both symbolically and actually. The dialogues are simple but profound in depth. The haunting soundtrack gives the film a seductive and sensual edge. The performances are superb all the way. This is the first time I see Bruce Greenwood turn in a decent performance. Elias Koteas and Don McKellar are first rate. A very young Sarah Polley shows what potential she has. Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian is terrific. Mia Kirschner blends excellently blends sensuality, pain, fragility and kindness into Chrissy. 'Exotica' is not everyone's kind of film. Some may find its theme too dark and too intense but it's a film that isn't afraid to reveal, suggest and challenge the viewer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The essentials of a masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jexline
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Atom Egoyan's "Exotica" is perhaps the most perfect and beautifully intricate film I have seen. Filmed on a $2 million Canadian budget with his mostly usual staple of actors it explores territory usually left unchartered in the film world. Francis Brown (Bruce Greenwood) is a tax auditor for Revenue Canada who makes nightly visits to Exotica, a local gentleman's club, where he also asks for his favorite dancer, Christina (Mia Kirschner). The activity of the club is told to us by Eric, the D.J. (Elias Koteas)who makes suggestive comments about the dancers. The club is owned by the pregnant Zoe (Arsinee Khanjian; Egoyan's wife). The other main character of the story is Thomas Pinto (Don McKellar), a latently gay pet shop owner being audited by Francis. The film is largely about replacements and rituals. Eric used to be Christina's lover and relives the relationship through MCing suggestive fantasies of her. The club used to be owned by Zoe's mother and she is taking her mother's place since it's easier than creating her own options. Francis has his niece (Sarah Polley) babysit while he's gone, even though there's no baby to sit and pays her $20 a night and pays Christina $5 a dance. Thomas goes to the opera on a regular basis and scalps tickets in order to meet up with other men. The film doesn't truly come together until the conclusion where everything makes sense. This film features some great performances, especially Bruce Greenwood as the troubled and intense Francis. Elias Koteas is equally good as the jealous DJ. This is a sorely underrated film with the essentials of a masterpiece. The score is also excellent and I highly recommend the soundtrack as well. Overall, one of my all-time favorite films. A must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete Obsession
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Exotica" deals totally with obsession. Writer/director Atom Egoyan does well to get us hooked on his central characters, without knowing why they are behaving as they do. The plot centres around strip club "Exotica" as Egoyan teases out his tale like a striptease, little by little showing us more of who these people are and why. The resolution is perhaps disappointing (like a striptease when all has been revealed), failing to fulfill our high hopes. Best character is Francis, who appears to change before our eyes as the film progresses. It is not really he who changes however, but our perception of him. Likewise we view all the players differently in the end, though some of their motivations are hastily explained, if at all. Fantastic performances wrap up this oft times mesmerising film, with Bruce Greenwood a particular standout as Francis. Mia Kirshner (Christina) and Don McKellar (Thomas) are strong too. Also stars Elias Koteas as Eric and Arsinee Khanjian as Zoe. The exotic score is from Mychael Danna, and Paul Sarossy's camera captures Linda del Rosario and Richard Paris' production design (eye catching at times) well. Monday, November 3, 1997 - Hoyts Croydon Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More of a woman's POV movie than might be expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dennis Littrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Note: Over 500 of my movie reviews are now available in my book "Cut to the Chaise Lounge or I Can't Believe I Swallowed the Remote!" Get it at Amazon.) Atom Egoyan's Exotica is an outstanding movie. I have seen Egoyan's The Sweet Hereafter (1997) which is also very good. A father's (obsessive) love for his daughter(s) is featured in both movies, consequently the theme must mean something special to Egoyan. He is a most talented and original movie maker, a Canadian as are his players, Bruce Greenwood, (Francis Brown, the accountant whose daughter was murdered), Sarah Polley, (Tracey, the high school girl), and Mia Kirshner, (Christina, the exotic dancer). His wife, Arsinee Khanjian and Polley were also featured in The Sweet Hereafter. What really makes the movie is Egoyan's use of time and action sequence. He cuts up the chronological order of events and then presents them in a dramatic way. This is not so easy to do. Christopher Nolan in Memento (2000) used the same technique to great advantage. I have come late to such a technique and would love to master it myself. I worked on it last year and a couple of years before. You can't just scissor it and then paste it back together. Something must be gained from reversing the order of events. When Eric and Christina are shown walking the fields in a long line of people I jumped to the conclusion that Tracey would be found dead. We don't learn that Francis lost his daughter until the film is nearly finished. The psychology of Francis and the young girls is interesting. Christina says she gave something to him and he gave something to her. This vagueness with its unmistakable sexuality is something that always exists between young girls and older men. And, as Egoyan observes, there are rules and awkwardness, and confused emotions. However the girl wants it made unmistakably clear that she is desired physically and just talk is almost never sufficient. She often doesn't know whether she really wants to be "taken" fully, and of course that is usually, shall we say, problematic. Some great subtly is required in handled such a theme, and Egoyan realizes that. His character Francis Brown is content with fantasy and does not touch at all. This film would have found a larger audience except for the title, the theme, and the milieu. The female audience for the most part didn't even consider watching the movie since, as one woman said, I thought it was just another movie with an older man lusting after a girl half his age. That theme bores women to death. But surprisingly at the IMDb a viewer asks how women feel about the film and several write in to say that they liked it. Another poster remarks that women over forty actually liked Exotica in higher percentages than males. I thought the veracious and business-like depiction of the exotic dancer club was well done. The very nice side plot with the gay animal importer was just a perfect fit for the main plot. Egoyan wrote the script. It is a great script. So much surprises. It's almost too good. For me, since I have seen so many, many movies, something different, some surprises in plot, in character, in treatment are always welcome. And the plot does surprise. Even when the protagonist, Francis waits outside the club to shoot Eric, Egoyan turns the situation on its head by having Eric appear from the side and explain something that changes Francis's attitude toward him. I am being vague because I don't want to spoil the story. Some moviesmost movies I would say, since I go back to the generation that would go into the theatre and sit down during the middle of the movie; and then four or five hours later, realize, "This is where I came in"--in most movies to know the ending or the plot would not spoil the movie. We know so and so dies at the end. What is interesting is how he dies, how the actions develops. But in this movie to know the plot would take something away. I think. I'm not sure. Anyway Francis is a tax auditor who lost his daughter when she was less than eight years old. She was murdered. The police initially thought he did it, but he was found innocent and the murderer was apprehended and convicted. But Francis is left hollow and tries to bring her back in a way by having teenage girls "babysit" his nonexistent daughter. Egoyan teases us near the beginning by showing Francis and Tracey in his car as he drops her off at her home giving her some money and asking, "Are you free Thursday?" Very near the end of the movie we find that Tracey had a precursor in that babysitting role. You might be able to guess who it was. The sound track features "Everybody Knows" by Leonard Cohen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated, I'm afraid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Comparing this to Uwe Boll's stuff is a bit unfair, but I see where that reviewer is coming from. But, LOL, calling Leonard Cohen a Tom Waits wannabe, that's the funniest thing I've heard all year. The photography in this film almost redeems its many failings, but not quite. I get a lot of chuckles from the gushing reviews from art-house hangers-on; there is a kind of "Art-house clich&eacute;" which arises from the deliberate avoidance of Hollywood clich&eacute;. This film is full of it. You might call it "anti-clich&eacute;". But it amounts to the same thing. I see none of the freshness and vigour I look for in a good indy film. It mightn't be so bad if the plot didn't require so much suspension of disbelief. There couldn't exist a strip club such as this one, it would be just ludicrous. And why doesn't Mr. Egoyan find something else for his wife to do besides "acting" in all his movies? Anyhow, watch this if you've got nothing better on, but expect to be bored rigid waiting for the good bits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bust A Move...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    newkfl
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I would have to admit that Exotica turned out to be a better film than I had imagined. It was slow in parts, but I guess it was to counter some of the scenes in the movie. There were some very disturbing characters in the movie too that really did not have problems so to speak, but certainly could have used some help from a trained sexual therapist. I would have certainly kept my distance from the character with the very hairy chest. I do not even think that he knew what he was going to do next. There was some good bar scene shots and dialog, but all in all, I think that the ending was a little bit rushed. It made me think of several ways that the movie could have been changed to fit the ending. Do not blink!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
