<filme>
 <id>
  462
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0103994
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1992
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Como &Aacute;gua Para Chocolate
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  This movie is about how life used to be in Mexico. It is a love story between Pedro and Tita, and why they coudn't get married because Tita's mother wanted her oldest daughter to get ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  This movie is about how life used to be in Mexico. It is a love story between Pedro and Tita, and why they coudn't get married because Tita's mother wanted her oldest daughter to get married first, and have Tita to stay and take care of her. It shows how marriage was imposed on those times, and how a love between two people can change everything. This picture set a new epoch in Mexican movies all over the world.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mexico
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wedding
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   marriage
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wedding cake
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Alfonso Arau
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Laura Esquivel
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Marco Leonardi
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lumi Cavazos
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Regina Torn&eacute;
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensual and Atmospheric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of a Mexican family is recounted, spanning decades. This is an interesting fable that manages to turn cooking into a sensual experience. It is helped by beautiful cinematography and a fine score. The acting is generally good, with Cavazos giving a standout performance as a young woman who is controlled by a domineering mother. Unfortunately, the latter is portrayed as so one-dimensionally evil that she makes Cinderalla's stepmother seem like a candidate for Mother of the Year. The story moves in fits and starts, lingering too long on some scenes but then abruptly skipping ahead by a decade. Director Arau is known mainly as an actor, but he does a fine job of creating an evocative atmosphere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth having in your cultural hard-drive, but the book is probably better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SeriousJest
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I didn't read the book, so if you've read the book, you might like this movie less than I did. The story is a good folk tale, and gives one insight into some aspects of Latino culture (i.e., traditions & so much more are often passed down through food; the strange traditions regarding family duty, even in the face of common sense). While watching the movie, I suspected the book is better, and I have been told by others that it is. The actor who played John was very exaggerated, although I don't know if that was done on purpose. Further, I had problems with Pedro's initial decision (the big one); as Tita later points out, there seem to have been many other decisions that would have made much more sense. Warning: this is a chick flick! In the end, though, my identity as a hispanic edged out my identity as a manly man, so I consider this movie worth watching, since the story is worth having in your cultural hard-drive. For more reviews and a kickass podcast, check out: www.livemancave.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie when uncut.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    normanc-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well filmed with great backdrops. For anyone who has lived in Mexico, it is historically accurate in its portrayal of life in northern Mexico during Revolutionary times. It comes close to following the book, which has a recipe for all of the movie meals, and more - one for each month. My wife cooked the quail in rose petals and..... Parts of the film are erotic without being graphic. All of the actors are wonderfully cast in their roles. If you want the DVD, the uncut 113 minute version has interesting scenes omitted in the American version 105 minute one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subtitled movie, but True Love in old Mexico is something to behold.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keyska2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes this is a romance movie, but it is a fantastic fantasy fairy tale quality love story. Pedro and Tita fall in love but Tita's mother objects. Tita is the youngest in the family and she must stay home and take care of her mother until she dies. Her mother even arranges a marriage between Pedro and Tita's older sister Rosaura so Tita and Pedro can never become as one. As I said this is a fantasy, and once you get past all of the initial story buildup for all of the characters the fun begins. Tita was born in the kitchen and befriended by Nacha the hired cook. Nacha raises Tita as her own teaching her how to cook and enjoy life. Once Tita's mother sets down the law of how things will be, Tita changes. Tita's cooking becomes magic. Whatever Tita is feeling when she cooks, it comes to truth in the final product. If Tita is sad and lonely, anyone who eats her cooking feels those emotions. I have watched this film several times since it was made in 1992, and it always leaves me feeling full of loves emotions. You have to watch this movie to understand the fullness of these emotions. I have gotten use to the subtitles over the years and prefer them to the English dubbed version of the movie. I love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cultural and erotic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sl-pierce
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 1992 Mexican film is full of both symbolism and cultural significance, and it helped me to appreciate the fantasy and mysticism reflected within the narrative. Tita is the youngest of three daughters, held captive by the traditions of her tenacious mother, which dictate that she is not allowed to marry, as she must care for her mother until her death. Yet, Pedro has already announced his passionate love for Tita, and in hopes of being near her, marries her older sister. Tita soon discovers she is able to communicate and share her emotions through her cooking, which she makes for Pedro to demonstrate her love for him. I found the film to be very intriguing in a symbolic sense, and would be interested to read the original book. I enjoyed viewing the early twentieth century culture richly interwoven into the storyline, and the eroticism was very prevalent, but portrayed in an artistic and reflective manner; however, it's not a film I would choose to watch again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts out well, descends into melodramatic drivel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeachHamBeach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS FOR SURE You think you'll be saying Yum, but you'll end up saying Yuck! This story about early 20th century Mexican/Texican women falling in love and grappling with family tradition began on a very promising note. Young Tita is in love with handsome Pedro...though you're never given any real reason to latch onto them or cheer them on. You don't get a story about how they meet, what drew them together...maybe just good ol' hot Latin lust (ew)? Anyway, Pedro marries Rosaura, the older sister, to "be close to his true love" while Tita is bossed around by her bitch of a mother, who isn't satisfied just ruining Tita's lovelife, she has to ridicule and criticize Tita's every move. Tita escapes her daily misery by whipping up delicious foods in the kitchen, but even this isn't given much screen time. Aside from the quails with rose petal sauce, most of the recipes are given a perfunctory glance. Most of the movie consists of Tita and Pedro pining, exchanging a few hasty kisses, and the one sex scene is completely in the dark. In short, this movie really has nothing to offer, even for us pervs who like passionate, if vapid, sex scenes as a last resort for entertainment. The grand climax comes when the two lovebirds finally get their opportunity to be a legit couple, and a spectacular fire erupts as a result of their illicit passions...Repeat after me: vomitrocious!!! I got this movie because I wanted to see all the recent/semirecent movies about food and love. This one stinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7.2? No way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaredmgoldberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having read the book from which this is adapted, this movie deserves not the praise it received. First and foremost, the movie completely misconstrues the message of the book. The book stresses the importance of FOOD, and how the food is Tita's method of both coping with her realities and her method of communicating the feelings that are being suppressed by Mama Elena. In the movie, the beauty of the food is drowned by a disgusting, almost stereotypical soap-opera-like drama. The acting is cheesy, at best, and the feelings between Tita and Pedro are poorly conveyed as love. Rather, they are portrayed by a simple, unforgiving lust. Also, the last scene was TERRIBLE. The last scene is supposed to contain a grand crescendo of feelings that ultimately lead to Pedro's, and the Tita's, deaths. However, it simply appears that Pedro has an orgasm and then faints. There is absolutely no way, without having prior knowledge of the story, to correlate between this scene and the matches theory. Also, the way in which Tita days poorly illustrates the match theory. It seems like she just eats the matches and then dies. By this, however, the intense emotion required to kindle the inner matches is just not there. By its lonesome, this movie receives a 3 (soap opera quality crap).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    true disappointment compared to the book
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (abezahler123@AOL.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the movie Like Water For Chocolate was a disappointing experience for me. After I had read the very gripping and interesting book I was looking forward to the movie. I was excited to see how the creators of the movie were going to show the most interesting part of the book, the magical realism. To my dismay i was deeply disappointed when I saw the magical realism "scenes" in the movie. The parts in the movie with magical realism were too short and random. A few examples are; when she wore the knitted blanket and it was ridiculously long, or when Tita's tears were shown dripping down the steps. The scenes seemed like they were add ons to the movie that were unnecessary. I found that the magical realism actually took away from the story in the movie. It Distanced the viewer from the characters, making them difficult to relate to. Conversely in the novel the magical realism did not take away from the story but it did not significantly add anything to the story. The movie also was lacking in depth beyond the external plot. In the book there were many underlying meanings hidden in the text. But because the acting was so terrible in the movie it felt like a soap, that meant nothing more than the crumby lines being shoved in the actors mouths. To summarize, if anyone is interested in watching this film I recommend reading the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I did not really like this movie, but it wasn't horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smhorsegirl314
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not really enjoy the movie, since I really like the ways they connected Tita and her food and made it so magical in the book. It was a disappointment in the movie when the kitchen scenes were so much less magical. The food did not come to life on the screen and it felt so much less important in the movie.I thought that the music choice made it a little corny but that part did not affect the actual movie much.I did not like the way the magical realism was portrayed with the sparks when they were making love. It seemed to impersonal I would have liked it to be portrayed in a way that better reflected the romance between Tita and Pedro.But I did think they did a good job when they had Mama Elena come back as a ghost.They used the actress and did not overdue the fact that she was a ghost, by using the typical white sheet ghost stereotype.I think they did a good job casting the three sisters making Tita very pretty and giving Gertrudis a somewhat manly look. Her man like physic lead well into the fact that she became a revolutionary. I think that making Rosaura look ugly in each scene made me sympathize with her instead of feeling guilty for Tita and her lost love. They did not emphasize Nachas role enough in the movie and her death was a lot less sad in the movie then in the book. I think that her motherly figure was an important part of the storyline and showed how Tita became who she is. The same way that they did not stress Titas role as a mother for the first baby of Rosaura and Pedro. I wish they had shown the relationships more thoroughly. The movie was entertaining but not my top choice and I think the parts of it they decided to stress were not what I would have chosen from the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nicsolomon
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not think that this was a particularly bad movie because it was able to capture some scenes that i thought would be difficult to do in a movie. The acting in this movie was not great, I found John's character to be creepy and depressing instead of the loving upbeat character I read about. I also thought that the film work was below par and if this movie were in English and released in American movie theaters it would have much more negative criticism. This movie also rushes through many important scenes and does not allow the plot to develop. If someone were to watch this movie without reading the book they would leave the movie extremely confused. Some of the positives in this movie are how they display magical realism in very interesting ways. For example in the beginning of the movie when there is rushing water to represent tears and then they harvest the salt from the tears seemed like it was represented the magical realism very well. Also the actresses who played the sisters did a good job of creating interesting sister- sister relationships. For example how Gertrudis and Tita had a very caring relationship where as the relationship between Rosura and Tita always seemed to be very competitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensual and Atmospheric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of a Mexican family is recounted, spanning decades. This is an interesting fable that manages to turn cooking into a sensual experience. It is helped by beautiful cinematography and a fine score. The acting is generally good, with Cavazos giving a standout performance as a young woman who is controlled by a domineering mother. Unfortunately, the latter is portrayed as so one-dimensionally evil that she makes Cinderalla's stepmother seem like a candidate for Mother of the Year. The story moves in fits and starts, lingering too long on some scenes but then abruptly skipping ahead by a decade. Director Arau is known mainly as an actor, but he does a fine job of creating an evocative atmosphere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth having in your cultural hard-drive, but the book is probably better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SeriousJest
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I didn't read the book, so if you've read the book, you might like this movie less than I did. The story is a good folk tale, and gives one insight into some aspects of Latino culture (i.e., traditions & so much more are often passed down through food; the strange traditions regarding family duty, even in the face of common sense). While watching the movie, I suspected the book is better, and I have been told by others that it is. The actor who played John was very exaggerated, although I don't know if that was done on purpose. Further, I had problems with Pedro's initial decision (the big one); as Tita later points out, there seem to have been many other decisions that would have made much more sense. Warning: this is a chick flick! In the end, though, my identity as a hispanic edged out my identity as a manly man, so I consider this movie worth watching, since the story is worth having in your cultural hard-drive. For more reviews and a kickass podcast, check out: www.livemancave.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie when uncut.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    normanc-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well filmed with great backdrops. For anyone who has lived in Mexico, it is historically accurate in its portrayal of life in northern Mexico during Revolutionary times. It comes close to following the book, which has a recipe for all of the movie meals, and more - one for each month. My wife cooked the quail in rose petals and..... Parts of the film are erotic without being graphic. All of the actors are wonderfully cast in their roles. If you want the DVD, the uncut 113 minute version has interesting scenes omitted in the American version 105 minute one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subtitled movie, but True Love in old Mexico is something to behold.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keyska2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes this is a romance movie, but it is a fantastic fantasy fairy tale quality love story. Pedro and Tita fall in love but Tita's mother objects. Tita is the youngest in the family and she must stay home and take care of her mother until she dies. Her mother even arranges a marriage between Pedro and Tita's older sister Rosaura so Tita and Pedro can never become as one. As I said this is a fantasy, and once you get past all of the initial story buildup for all of the characters the fun begins. Tita was born in the kitchen and befriended by Nacha the hired cook. Nacha raises Tita as her own teaching her how to cook and enjoy life. Once Tita's mother sets down the law of how things will be, Tita changes. Tita's cooking becomes magic. Whatever Tita is feeling when she cooks, it comes to truth in the final product. If Tita is sad and lonely, anyone who eats her cooking feels those emotions. I have watched this film several times since it was made in 1992, and it always leaves me feeling full of loves emotions. You have to watch this movie to understand the fullness of these emotions. I have gotten use to the subtitles over the years and prefer them to the English dubbed version of the movie. I love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cultural and erotic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sl-pierce
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 1992 Mexican film is full of both symbolism and cultural significance, and it helped me to appreciate the fantasy and mysticism reflected within the narrative. Tita is the youngest of three daughters, held captive by the traditions of her tenacious mother, which dictate that she is not allowed to marry, as she must care for her mother until her death. Yet, Pedro has already announced his passionate love for Tita, and in hopes of being near her, marries her older sister. Tita soon discovers she is able to communicate and share her emotions through her cooking, which she makes for Pedro to demonstrate her love for him. I found the film to be very intriguing in a symbolic sense, and would be interested to read the original book. I enjoyed viewing the early twentieth century culture richly interwoven into the storyline, and the eroticism was very prevalent, but portrayed in an artistic and reflective manner; however, it's not a film I would choose to watch again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts out well, descends into melodramatic drivel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeachHamBeach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS FOR SURE You think you'll be saying Yum, but you'll end up saying Yuck! This story about early 20th century Mexican/Texican women falling in love and grappling with family tradition began on a very promising note. Young Tita is in love with handsome Pedro...though you're never given any real reason to latch onto them or cheer them on. You don't get a story about how they meet, what drew them together...maybe just good ol' hot Latin lust (ew)? Anyway, Pedro marries Rosaura, the older sister, to "be close to his true love" while Tita is bossed around by her bitch of a mother, who isn't satisfied just ruining Tita's lovelife, she has to ridicule and criticize Tita's every move. Tita escapes her daily misery by whipping up delicious foods in the kitchen, but even this isn't given much screen time. Aside from the quails with rose petal sauce, most of the recipes are given a perfunctory glance. Most of the movie consists of Tita and Pedro pining, exchanging a few hasty kisses, and the one sex scene is completely in the dark. In short, this movie really has nothing to offer, even for us pervs who like passionate, if vapid, sex scenes as a last resort for entertainment. The grand climax comes when the two lovebirds finally get their opportunity to be a legit couple, and a spectacular fire erupts as a result of their illicit passions...Repeat after me: vomitrocious!!! I got this movie because I wanted to see all the recent/semirecent movies about food and love. This one stinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7.2? No way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaredmgoldberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having read the book from which this is adapted, this movie deserves not the praise it received. First and foremost, the movie completely misconstrues the message of the book. The book stresses the importance of FOOD, and how the food is Tita's method of both coping with her realities and her method of communicating the feelings that are being suppressed by Mama Elena. In the movie, the beauty of the food is drowned by a disgusting, almost stereotypical soap-opera-like drama. The acting is cheesy, at best, and the feelings between Tita and Pedro are poorly conveyed as love. Rather, they are portrayed by a simple, unforgiving lust. Also, the last scene was TERRIBLE. The last scene is supposed to contain a grand crescendo of feelings that ultimately lead to Pedro's, and the Tita's, deaths. However, it simply appears that Pedro has an orgasm and then faints. There is absolutely no way, without having prior knowledge of the story, to correlate between this scene and the matches theory. Also, the way in which Tita days poorly illustrates the match theory. It seems like she just eats the matches and then dies. By this, however, the intense emotion required to kindle the inner matches is just not there. By its lonesome, this movie receives a 3 (soap opera quality crap).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    true disappointment compared to the book
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (abezahler123@AOL.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the movie Like Water For Chocolate was a disappointing experience for me. After I had read the very gripping and interesting book I was looking forward to the movie. I was excited to see how the creators of the movie were going to show the most interesting part of the book, the magical realism. To my dismay i was deeply disappointed when I saw the magical realism "scenes" in the movie. The parts in the movie with magical realism were too short and random. A few examples are; when she wore the knitted blanket and it was ridiculously long, or when Tita's tears were shown dripping down the steps. The scenes seemed like they were add ons to the movie that were unnecessary. I found that the magical realism actually took away from the story in the movie. It Distanced the viewer from the characters, making them difficult to relate to. Conversely in the novel the magical realism did not take away from the story but it did not significantly add anything to the story. The movie also was lacking in depth beyond the external plot. In the book there were many underlying meanings hidden in the text. But because the acting was so terrible in the movie it felt like a soap, that meant nothing more than the crumby lines being shoved in the actors mouths. To summarize, if anyone is interested in watching this film I recommend reading the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I did not really like this movie, but it wasn't horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smhorsegirl314
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not really enjoy the movie, since I really like the ways they connected Tita and her food and made it so magical in the book. It was a disappointment in the movie when the kitchen scenes were so much less magical. The food did not come to life on the screen and it felt so much less important in the movie.I thought that the music choice made it a little corny but that part did not affect the actual movie much.I did not like the way the magical realism was portrayed with the sparks when they were making love. It seemed to impersonal I would have liked it to be portrayed in a way that better reflected the romance between Tita and Pedro.But I did think they did a good job when they had Mama Elena come back as a ghost.They used the actress and did not overdue the fact that she was a ghost, by using the typical white sheet ghost stereotype.I think they did a good job casting the three sisters making Tita very pretty and giving Gertrudis a somewhat manly look. Her man like physic lead well into the fact that she became a revolutionary. I think that making Rosaura look ugly in each scene made me sympathize with her instead of feeling guilty for Tita and her lost love. They did not emphasize Nachas role enough in the movie and her death was a lot less sad in the movie then in the book. I think that her motherly figure was an important part of the storyline and showed how Tita became who she is. The same way that they did not stress Titas role as a mother for the first baby of Rosaura and Pedro. I wish they had shown the relationships more thoroughly. The movie was entertaining but not my top choice and I think the parts of it they decided to stress were not what I would have chosen from the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nicsolomon
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not think that this was a particularly bad movie because it was able to capture some scenes that i thought would be difficult to do in a movie. The acting in this movie was not great, I found John's character to be creepy and depressing instead of the loving upbeat character I read about. I also thought that the film work was below par and if this movie were in English and released in American movie theaters it would have much more negative criticism. This movie also rushes through many important scenes and does not allow the plot to develop. If someone were to watch this movie without reading the book they would leave the movie extremely confused. Some of the positives in this movie are how they display magical realism in very interesting ways. For example in the beginning of the movie when there is rushing water to represent tears and then they harvest the salt from the tears seemed like it was represented the magical realism very well. Also the actresses who played the sisters did a good job of creating interesting sister- sister relationships. For example how Gertrudis and Tita had a very caring relationship where as the relationship between Rosura and Tita always seemed to be very competitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensual and Atmospheric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of a Mexican family is recounted, spanning decades. This is an interesting fable that manages to turn cooking into a sensual experience. It is helped by beautiful cinematography and a fine score. The acting is generally good, with Cavazos giving a standout performance as a young woman who is controlled by a domineering mother. Unfortunately, the latter is portrayed as so one-dimensionally evil that she makes Cinderalla's stepmother seem like a candidate for Mother of the Year. The story moves in fits and starts, lingering too long on some scenes but then abruptly skipping ahead by a decade. Director Arau is known mainly as an actor, but he does a fine job of creating an evocative atmosphere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth having in your cultural hard-drive, but the book is probably better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SeriousJest
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I didn't read the book, so if you've read the book, you might like this movie less than I did. The story is a good folk tale, and gives one insight into some aspects of Latino culture (i.e., traditions & so much more are often passed down through food; the strange traditions regarding family duty, even in the face of common sense). While watching the movie, I suspected the book is better, and I have been told by others that it is. The actor who played John was very exaggerated, although I don't know if that was done on purpose. Further, I had problems with Pedro's initial decision (the big one); as Tita later points out, there seem to have been many other decisions that would have made much more sense. Warning: this is a chick flick! In the end, though, my identity as a hispanic edged out my identity as a manly man, so I consider this movie worth watching, since the story is worth having in your cultural hard-drive. For more reviews and a kickass podcast, check out: www.livemancave.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie when uncut.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    normanc-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well filmed with great backdrops. For anyone who has lived in Mexico, it is historically accurate in its portrayal of life in northern Mexico during Revolutionary times. It comes close to following the book, which has a recipe for all of the movie meals, and more - one for each month. My wife cooked the quail in rose petals and..... Parts of the film are erotic without being graphic. All of the actors are wonderfully cast in their roles. If you want the DVD, the uncut 113 minute version has interesting scenes omitted in the American version 105 minute one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subtitled movie, but True Love in old Mexico is something to behold.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keyska2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes this is a romance movie, but it is a fantastic fantasy fairy tale quality love story. Pedro and Tita fall in love but Tita's mother objects. Tita is the youngest in the family and she must stay home and take care of her mother until she dies. Her mother even arranges a marriage between Pedro and Tita's older sister Rosaura so Tita and Pedro can never become as one. As I said this is a fantasy, and once you get past all of the initial story buildup for all of the characters the fun begins. Tita was born in the kitchen and befriended by Nacha the hired cook. Nacha raises Tita as her own teaching her how to cook and enjoy life. Once Tita's mother sets down the law of how things will be, Tita changes. Tita's cooking becomes magic. Whatever Tita is feeling when she cooks, it comes to truth in the final product. If Tita is sad and lonely, anyone who eats her cooking feels those emotions. I have watched this film several times since it was made in 1992, and it always leaves me feeling full of loves emotions. You have to watch this movie to understand the fullness of these emotions. I have gotten use to the subtitles over the years and prefer them to the English dubbed version of the movie. I love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cultural and erotic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sl-pierce
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 1992 Mexican film is full of both symbolism and cultural significance, and it helped me to appreciate the fantasy and mysticism reflected within the narrative. Tita is the youngest of three daughters, held captive by the traditions of her tenacious mother, which dictate that she is not allowed to marry, as she must care for her mother until her death. Yet, Pedro has already announced his passionate love for Tita, and in hopes of being near her, marries her older sister. Tita soon discovers she is able to communicate and share her emotions through her cooking, which she makes for Pedro to demonstrate her love for him. I found the film to be very intriguing in a symbolic sense, and would be interested to read the original book. I enjoyed viewing the early twentieth century culture richly interwoven into the storyline, and the eroticism was very prevalent, but portrayed in an artistic and reflective manner; however, it's not a film I would choose to watch again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts out well, descends into melodramatic drivel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeachHamBeach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS FOR SURE You think you'll be saying Yum, but you'll end up saying Yuck! This story about early 20th century Mexican/Texican women falling in love and grappling with family tradition began on a very promising note. Young Tita is in love with handsome Pedro...though you're never given any real reason to latch onto them or cheer them on. You don't get a story about how they meet, what drew them together...maybe just good ol' hot Latin lust (ew)? Anyway, Pedro marries Rosaura, the older sister, to "be close to his true love" while Tita is bossed around by her bitch of a mother, who isn't satisfied just ruining Tita's lovelife, she has to ridicule and criticize Tita's every move. Tita escapes her daily misery by whipping up delicious foods in the kitchen, but even this isn't given much screen time. Aside from the quails with rose petal sauce, most of the recipes are given a perfunctory glance. Most of the movie consists of Tita and Pedro pining, exchanging a few hasty kisses, and the one sex scene is completely in the dark. In short, this movie really has nothing to offer, even for us pervs who like passionate, if vapid, sex scenes as a last resort for entertainment. The grand climax comes when the two lovebirds finally get their opportunity to be a legit couple, and a spectacular fire erupts as a result of their illicit passions...Repeat after me: vomitrocious!!! I got this movie because I wanted to see all the recent/semirecent movies about food and love. This one stinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7.2? No way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaredmgoldberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having read the book from which this is adapted, this movie deserves not the praise it received. First and foremost, the movie completely misconstrues the message of the book. The book stresses the importance of FOOD, and how the food is Tita's method of both coping with her realities and her method of communicating the feelings that are being suppressed by Mama Elena. In the movie, the beauty of the food is drowned by a disgusting, almost stereotypical soap-opera-like drama. The acting is cheesy, at best, and the feelings between Tita and Pedro are poorly conveyed as love. Rather, they are portrayed by a simple, unforgiving lust. Also, the last scene was TERRIBLE. The last scene is supposed to contain a grand crescendo of feelings that ultimately lead to Pedro's, and the Tita's, deaths. However, it simply appears that Pedro has an orgasm and then faints. There is absolutely no way, without having prior knowledge of the story, to correlate between this scene and the matches theory. Also, the way in which Tita days poorly illustrates the match theory. It seems like she just eats the matches and then dies. By this, however, the intense emotion required to kindle the inner matches is just not there. By its lonesome, this movie receives a 3 (soap opera quality crap).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    true disappointment compared to the book
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (abezahler123@AOL.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the movie Like Water For Chocolate was a disappointing experience for me. After I had read the very gripping and interesting book I was looking forward to the movie. I was excited to see how the creators of the movie were going to show the most interesting part of the book, the magical realism. To my dismay i was deeply disappointed when I saw the magical realism "scenes" in the movie. The parts in the movie with magical realism were too short and random. A few examples are; when she wore the knitted blanket and it was ridiculously long, or when Tita's tears were shown dripping down the steps. The scenes seemed like they were add ons to the movie that were unnecessary. I found that the magical realism actually took away from the story in the movie. It Distanced the viewer from the characters, making them difficult to relate to. Conversely in the novel the magical realism did not take away from the story but it did not significantly add anything to the story. The movie also was lacking in depth beyond the external plot. In the book there were many underlying meanings hidden in the text. But because the acting was so terrible in the movie it felt like a soap, that meant nothing more than the crumby lines being shoved in the actors mouths. To summarize, if anyone is interested in watching this film I recommend reading the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I did not really like this movie, but it wasn't horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smhorsegirl314
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not really enjoy the movie, since I really like the ways they connected Tita and her food and made it so magical in the book. It was a disappointment in the movie when the kitchen scenes were so much less magical. The food did not come to life on the screen and it felt so much less important in the movie.I thought that the music choice made it a little corny but that part did not affect the actual movie much.I did not like the way the magical realism was portrayed with the sparks when they were making love. It seemed to impersonal I would have liked it to be portrayed in a way that better reflected the romance between Tita and Pedro.But I did think they did a good job when they had Mama Elena come back as a ghost.They used the actress and did not overdue the fact that she was a ghost, by using the typical white sheet ghost stereotype.I think they did a good job casting the three sisters making Tita very pretty and giving Gertrudis a somewhat manly look. Her man like physic lead well into the fact that she became a revolutionary. I think that making Rosaura look ugly in each scene made me sympathize with her instead of feeling guilty for Tita and her lost love. They did not emphasize Nachas role enough in the movie and her death was a lot less sad in the movie then in the book. I think that her motherly figure was an important part of the storyline and showed how Tita became who she is. The same way that they did not stress Titas role as a mother for the first baby of Rosaura and Pedro. I wish they had shown the relationships more thoroughly. The movie was entertaining but not my top choice and I think the parts of it they decided to stress were not what I would have chosen from the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nicsolomon
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not think that this was a particularly bad movie because it was able to capture some scenes that i thought would be difficult to do in a movie. The acting in this movie was not great, I found John's character to be creepy and depressing instead of the loving upbeat character I read about. I also thought that the film work was below par and if this movie were in English and released in American movie theaters it would have much more negative criticism. This movie also rushes through many important scenes and does not allow the plot to develop. If someone were to watch this movie without reading the book they would leave the movie extremely confused. Some of the positives in this movie are how they display magical realism in very interesting ways. For example in the beginning of the movie when there is rushing water to represent tears and then they harvest the salt from the tears seemed like it was represented the magical realism very well. Also the actresses who played the sisters did a good job of creating interesting sister- sister relationships. For example how Gertrudis and Tita had a very caring relationship where as the relationship between Rosura and Tita always seemed to be very competitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensual and Atmospheric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of a Mexican family is recounted, spanning decades. This is an interesting fable that manages to turn cooking into a sensual experience. It is helped by beautiful cinematography and a fine score. The acting is generally good, with Cavazos giving a standout performance as a young woman who is controlled by a domineering mother. Unfortunately, the latter is portrayed as so one-dimensionally evil that she makes Cinderalla's stepmother seem like a candidate for Mother of the Year. The story moves in fits and starts, lingering too long on some scenes but then abruptly skipping ahead by a decade. Director Arau is known mainly as an actor, but he does a fine job of creating an evocative atmosphere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth having in your cultural hard-drive, but the book is probably better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SeriousJest
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I didn't read the book, so if you've read the book, you might like this movie less than I did. The story is a good folk tale, and gives one insight into some aspects of Latino culture (i.e., traditions & so much more are often passed down through food; the strange traditions regarding family duty, even in the face of common sense). While watching the movie, I suspected the book is better, and I have been told by others that it is. The actor who played John was very exaggerated, although I don't know if that was done on purpose. Further, I had problems with Pedro's initial decision (the big one); as Tita later points out, there seem to have been many other decisions that would have made much more sense. Warning: this is a chick flick! In the end, though, my identity as a hispanic edged out my identity as a manly man, so I consider this movie worth watching, since the story is worth having in your cultural hard-drive. For more reviews and a kickass podcast, check out: www.livemancave.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie when uncut.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    normanc-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well filmed with great backdrops. For anyone who has lived in Mexico, it is historically accurate in its portrayal of life in northern Mexico during Revolutionary times. It comes close to following the book, which has a recipe for all of the movie meals, and more - one for each month. My wife cooked the quail in rose petals and..... Parts of the film are erotic without being graphic. All of the actors are wonderfully cast in their roles. If you want the DVD, the uncut 113 minute version has interesting scenes omitted in the American version 105 minute one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subtitled movie, but True Love in old Mexico is something to behold.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keyska2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes this is a romance movie, but it is a fantastic fantasy fairy tale quality love story. Pedro and Tita fall in love but Tita's mother objects. Tita is the youngest in the family and she must stay home and take care of her mother until she dies. Her mother even arranges a marriage between Pedro and Tita's older sister Rosaura so Tita and Pedro can never become as one. As I said this is a fantasy, and once you get past all of the initial story buildup for all of the characters the fun begins. Tita was born in the kitchen and befriended by Nacha the hired cook. Nacha raises Tita as her own teaching her how to cook and enjoy life. Once Tita's mother sets down the law of how things will be, Tita changes. Tita's cooking becomes magic. Whatever Tita is feeling when she cooks, it comes to truth in the final product. If Tita is sad and lonely, anyone who eats her cooking feels those emotions. I have watched this film several times since it was made in 1992, and it always leaves me feeling full of loves emotions. You have to watch this movie to understand the fullness of these emotions. I have gotten use to the subtitles over the years and prefer them to the English dubbed version of the movie. I love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cultural and erotic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sl-pierce
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 1992 Mexican film is full of both symbolism and cultural significance, and it helped me to appreciate the fantasy and mysticism reflected within the narrative. Tita is the youngest of three daughters, held captive by the traditions of her tenacious mother, which dictate that she is not allowed to marry, as she must care for her mother until her death. Yet, Pedro has already announced his passionate love for Tita, and in hopes of being near her, marries her older sister. Tita soon discovers she is able to communicate and share her emotions through her cooking, which she makes for Pedro to demonstrate her love for him. I found the film to be very intriguing in a symbolic sense, and would be interested to read the original book. I enjoyed viewing the early twentieth century culture richly interwoven into the storyline, and the eroticism was very prevalent, but portrayed in an artistic and reflective manner; however, it's not a film I would choose to watch again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts out well, descends into melodramatic drivel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeachHamBeach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS FOR SURE You think you'll be saying Yum, but you'll end up saying Yuck! This story about early 20th century Mexican/Texican women falling in love and grappling with family tradition began on a very promising note. Young Tita is in love with handsome Pedro...though you're never given any real reason to latch onto them or cheer them on. You don't get a story about how they meet, what drew them together...maybe just good ol' hot Latin lust (ew)? Anyway, Pedro marries Rosaura, the older sister, to "be close to his true love" while Tita is bossed around by her bitch of a mother, who isn't satisfied just ruining Tita's lovelife, she has to ridicule and criticize Tita's every move. Tita escapes her daily misery by whipping up delicious foods in the kitchen, but even this isn't given much screen time. Aside from the quails with rose petal sauce, most of the recipes are given a perfunctory glance. Most of the movie consists of Tita and Pedro pining, exchanging a few hasty kisses, and the one sex scene is completely in the dark. In short, this movie really has nothing to offer, even for us pervs who like passionate, if vapid, sex scenes as a last resort for entertainment. The grand climax comes when the two lovebirds finally get their opportunity to be a legit couple, and a spectacular fire erupts as a result of their illicit passions...Repeat after me: vomitrocious!!! I got this movie because I wanted to see all the recent/semirecent movies about food and love. This one stinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7.2? No way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaredmgoldberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having read the book from which this is adapted, this movie deserves not the praise it received. First and foremost, the movie completely misconstrues the message of the book. The book stresses the importance of FOOD, and how the food is Tita's method of both coping with her realities and her method of communicating the feelings that are being suppressed by Mama Elena. In the movie, the beauty of the food is drowned by a disgusting, almost stereotypical soap-opera-like drama. The acting is cheesy, at best, and the feelings between Tita and Pedro are poorly conveyed as love. Rather, they are portrayed by a simple, unforgiving lust. Also, the last scene was TERRIBLE. The last scene is supposed to contain a grand crescendo of feelings that ultimately lead to Pedro's, and the Tita's, deaths. However, it simply appears that Pedro has an orgasm and then faints. There is absolutely no way, without having prior knowledge of the story, to correlate between this scene and the matches theory. Also, the way in which Tita days poorly illustrates the match theory. It seems like she just eats the matches and then dies. By this, however, the intense emotion required to kindle the inner matches is just not there. By its lonesome, this movie receives a 3 (soap opera quality crap).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    true disappointment compared to the book
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (abezahler123@AOL.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the movie Like Water For Chocolate was a disappointing experience for me. After I had read the very gripping and interesting book I was looking forward to the movie. I was excited to see how the creators of the movie were going to show the most interesting part of the book, the magical realism. To my dismay i was deeply disappointed when I saw the magical realism "scenes" in the movie. The parts in the movie with magical realism were too short and random. A few examples are; when she wore the knitted blanket and it was ridiculously long, or when Tita's tears were shown dripping down the steps. The scenes seemed like they were add ons to the movie that were unnecessary. I found that the magical realism actually took away from the story in the movie. It Distanced the viewer from the characters, making them difficult to relate to. Conversely in the novel the magical realism did not take away from the story but it did not significantly add anything to the story. The movie also was lacking in depth beyond the external plot. In the book there were many underlying meanings hidden in the text. But because the acting was so terrible in the movie it felt like a soap, that meant nothing more than the crumby lines being shoved in the actors mouths. To summarize, if anyone is interested in watching this film I recommend reading the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I did not really like this movie, but it wasn't horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smhorsegirl314
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not really enjoy the movie, since I really like the ways they connected Tita and her food and made it so magical in the book. It was a disappointment in the movie when the kitchen scenes were so much less magical. The food did not come to life on the screen and it felt so much less important in the movie.I thought that the music choice made it a little corny but that part did not affect the actual movie much.I did not like the way the magical realism was portrayed with the sparks when they were making love. It seemed to impersonal I would have liked it to be portrayed in a way that better reflected the romance between Tita and Pedro.But I did think they did a good job when they had Mama Elena come back as a ghost.They used the actress and did not overdue the fact that she was a ghost, by using the typical white sheet ghost stereotype.I think they did a good job casting the three sisters making Tita very pretty and giving Gertrudis a somewhat manly look. Her man like physic lead well into the fact that she became a revolutionary. I think that making Rosaura look ugly in each scene made me sympathize with her instead of feeling guilty for Tita and her lost love. They did not emphasize Nachas role enough in the movie and her death was a lot less sad in the movie then in the book. I think that her motherly figure was an important part of the storyline and showed how Tita became who she is. The same way that they did not stress Titas role as a mother for the first baby of Rosaura and Pedro. I wish they had shown the relationships more thoroughly. The movie was entertaining but not my top choice and I think the parts of it they decided to stress were not what I would have chosen from the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nicsolomon
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not think that this was a particularly bad movie because it was able to capture some scenes that i thought would be difficult to do in a movie. The acting in this movie was not great, I found John's character to be creepy and depressing instead of the loving upbeat character I read about. I also thought that the film work was below par and if this movie were in English and released in American movie theaters it would have much more negative criticism. This movie also rushes through many important scenes and does not allow the plot to develop. If someone were to watch this movie without reading the book they would leave the movie extremely confused. Some of the positives in this movie are how they display magical realism in very interesting ways. For example in the beginning of the movie when there is rushing water to represent tears and then they harvest the salt from the tears seemed like it was represented the magical realism very well. Also the actresses who played the sisters did a good job of creating interesting sister- sister relationships. For example how Gertrudis and Tita had a very caring relationship where as the relationship between Rosura and Tita always seemed to be very competitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensual and Atmospheric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of a Mexican family is recounted, spanning decades. This is an interesting fable that manages to turn cooking into a sensual experience. It is helped by beautiful cinematography and a fine score. The acting is generally good, with Cavazos giving a standout performance as a young woman who is controlled by a domineering mother. Unfortunately, the latter is portrayed as so one-dimensionally evil that she makes Cinderalla's stepmother seem like a candidate for Mother of the Year. The story moves in fits and starts, lingering too long on some scenes but then abruptly skipping ahead by a decade. Director Arau is known mainly as an actor, but he does a fine job of creating an evocative atmosphere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth having in your cultural hard-drive, but the book is probably better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SeriousJest
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I didn't read the book, so if you've read the book, you might like this movie less than I did. The story is a good folk tale, and gives one insight into some aspects of Latino culture (i.e., traditions & so much more are often passed down through food; the strange traditions regarding family duty, even in the face of common sense). While watching the movie, I suspected the book is better, and I have been told by others that it is. The actor who played John was very exaggerated, although I don't know if that was done on purpose. Further, I had problems with Pedro's initial decision (the big one); as Tita later points out, there seem to have been many other decisions that would have made much more sense. Warning: this is a chick flick! In the end, though, my identity as a hispanic edged out my identity as a manly man, so I consider this movie worth watching, since the story is worth having in your cultural hard-drive. For more reviews and a kickass podcast, check out: www.livemancave.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie when uncut.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    normanc-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well filmed with great backdrops. For anyone who has lived in Mexico, it is historically accurate in its portrayal of life in northern Mexico during Revolutionary times. It comes close to following the book, which has a recipe for all of the movie meals, and more - one for each month. My wife cooked the quail in rose petals and..... Parts of the film are erotic without being graphic. All of the actors are wonderfully cast in their roles. If you want the DVD, the uncut 113 minute version has interesting scenes omitted in the American version 105 minute one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subtitled movie, but True Love in old Mexico is something to behold.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keyska2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes this is a romance movie, but it is a fantastic fantasy fairy tale quality love story. Pedro and Tita fall in love but Tita's mother objects. Tita is the youngest in the family and she must stay home and take care of her mother until she dies. Her mother even arranges a marriage between Pedro and Tita's older sister Rosaura so Tita and Pedro can never become as one. As I said this is a fantasy, and once you get past all of the initial story buildup for all of the characters the fun begins. Tita was born in the kitchen and befriended by Nacha the hired cook. Nacha raises Tita as her own teaching her how to cook and enjoy life. Once Tita's mother sets down the law of how things will be, Tita changes. Tita's cooking becomes magic. Whatever Tita is feeling when she cooks, it comes to truth in the final product. If Tita is sad and lonely, anyone who eats her cooking feels those emotions. I have watched this film several times since it was made in 1992, and it always leaves me feeling full of loves emotions. You have to watch this movie to understand the fullness of these emotions. I have gotten use to the subtitles over the years and prefer them to the English dubbed version of the movie. I love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cultural and erotic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sl-pierce
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 1992 Mexican film is full of both symbolism and cultural significance, and it helped me to appreciate the fantasy and mysticism reflected within the narrative. Tita is the youngest of three daughters, held captive by the traditions of her tenacious mother, which dictate that she is not allowed to marry, as she must care for her mother until her death. Yet, Pedro has already announced his passionate love for Tita, and in hopes of being near her, marries her older sister. Tita soon discovers she is able to communicate and share her emotions through her cooking, which she makes for Pedro to demonstrate her love for him. I found the film to be very intriguing in a symbolic sense, and would be interested to read the original book. I enjoyed viewing the early twentieth century culture richly interwoven into the storyline, and the eroticism was very prevalent, but portrayed in an artistic and reflective manner; however, it's not a film I would choose to watch again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts out well, descends into melodramatic drivel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeachHamBeach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS FOR SURE You think you'll be saying Yum, but you'll end up saying Yuck! This story about early 20th century Mexican/Texican women falling in love and grappling with family tradition began on a very promising note. Young Tita is in love with handsome Pedro...though you're never given any real reason to latch onto them or cheer them on. You don't get a story about how they meet, what drew them together...maybe just good ol' hot Latin lust (ew)? Anyway, Pedro marries Rosaura, the older sister, to "be close to his true love" while Tita is bossed around by her bitch of a mother, who isn't satisfied just ruining Tita's lovelife, she has to ridicule and criticize Tita's every move. Tita escapes her daily misery by whipping up delicious foods in the kitchen, but even this isn't given much screen time. Aside from the quails with rose petal sauce, most of the recipes are given a perfunctory glance. Most of the movie consists of Tita and Pedro pining, exchanging a few hasty kisses, and the one sex scene is completely in the dark. In short, this movie really has nothing to offer, even for us pervs who like passionate, if vapid, sex scenes as a last resort for entertainment. The grand climax comes when the two lovebirds finally get their opportunity to be a legit couple, and a spectacular fire erupts as a result of their illicit passions...Repeat after me: vomitrocious!!! I got this movie because I wanted to see all the recent/semirecent movies about food and love. This one stinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7.2? No way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaredmgoldberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having read the book from which this is adapted, this movie deserves not the praise it received. First and foremost, the movie completely misconstrues the message of the book. The book stresses the importance of FOOD, and how the food is Tita's method of both coping with her realities and her method of communicating the feelings that are being suppressed by Mama Elena. In the movie, the beauty of the food is drowned by a disgusting, almost stereotypical soap-opera-like drama. The acting is cheesy, at best, and the feelings between Tita and Pedro are poorly conveyed as love. Rather, they are portrayed by a simple, unforgiving lust. Also, the last scene was TERRIBLE. The last scene is supposed to contain a grand crescendo of feelings that ultimately lead to Pedro's, and the Tita's, deaths. However, it simply appears that Pedro has an orgasm and then faints. There is absolutely no way, without having prior knowledge of the story, to correlate between this scene and the matches theory. Also, the way in which Tita days poorly illustrates the match theory. It seems like she just eats the matches and then dies. By this, however, the intense emotion required to kindle the inner matches is just not there. By its lonesome, this movie receives a 3 (soap opera quality crap).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    true disappointment compared to the book
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (abezahler123@AOL.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the movie Like Water For Chocolate was a disappointing experience for me. After I had read the very gripping and interesting book I was looking forward to the movie. I was excited to see how the creators of the movie were going to show the most interesting part of the book, the magical realism. To my dismay i was deeply disappointed when I saw the magical realism "scenes" in the movie. The parts in the movie with magical realism were too short and random. A few examples are; when she wore the knitted blanket and it was ridiculously long, or when Tita's tears were shown dripping down the steps. The scenes seemed like they were add ons to the movie that were unnecessary. I found that the magical realism actually took away from the story in the movie. It Distanced the viewer from the characters, making them difficult to relate to. Conversely in the novel the magical realism did not take away from the story but it did not significantly add anything to the story. The movie also was lacking in depth beyond the external plot. In the book there were many underlying meanings hidden in the text. But because the acting was so terrible in the movie it felt like a soap, that meant nothing more than the crumby lines being shoved in the actors mouths. To summarize, if anyone is interested in watching this film I recommend reading the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I did not really like this movie, but it wasn't horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smhorsegirl314
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not really enjoy the movie, since I really like the ways they connected Tita and her food and made it so magical in the book. It was a disappointment in the movie when the kitchen scenes were so much less magical. The food did not come to life on the screen and it felt so much less important in the movie.I thought that the music choice made it a little corny but that part did not affect the actual movie much.I did not like the way the magical realism was portrayed with the sparks when they were making love. It seemed to impersonal I would have liked it to be portrayed in a way that better reflected the romance between Tita and Pedro.But I did think they did a good job when they had Mama Elena come back as a ghost.They used the actress and did not overdue the fact that she was a ghost, by using the typical white sheet ghost stereotype.I think they did a good job casting the three sisters making Tita very pretty and giving Gertrudis a somewhat manly look. Her man like physic lead well into the fact that she became a revolutionary. I think that making Rosaura look ugly in each scene made me sympathize with her instead of feeling guilty for Tita and her lost love. They did not emphasize Nachas role enough in the movie and her death was a lot less sad in the movie then in the book. I think that her motherly figure was an important part of the storyline and showed how Tita became who she is. The same way that they did not stress Titas role as a mother for the first baby of Rosaura and Pedro. I wish they had shown the relationships more thoroughly. The movie was entertaining but not my top choice and I think the parts of it they decided to stress were not what I would have chosen from the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nicsolomon
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not think that this was a particularly bad movie because it was able to capture some scenes that i thought would be difficult to do in a movie. The acting in this movie was not great, I found John's character to be creepy and depressing instead of the loving upbeat character I read about. I also thought that the film work was below par and if this movie were in English and released in American movie theaters it would have much more negative criticism. This movie also rushes through many important scenes and does not allow the plot to develop. If someone were to watch this movie without reading the book they would leave the movie extremely confused. Some of the positives in this movie are how they display magical realism in very interesting ways. For example in the beginning of the movie when there is rushing water to represent tears and then they harvest the salt from the tears seemed like it was represented the magical realism very well. Also the actresses who played the sisters did a good job of creating interesting sister- sister relationships. For example how Gertrudis and Tita had a very caring relationship where as the relationship between Rosura and Tita always seemed to be very competitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensual and Atmospheric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of a Mexican family is recounted, spanning decades. This is an interesting fable that manages to turn cooking into a sensual experience. It is helped by beautiful cinematography and a fine score. The acting is generally good, with Cavazos giving a standout performance as a young woman who is controlled by a domineering mother. Unfortunately, the latter is portrayed as so one-dimensionally evil that she makes Cinderalla's stepmother seem like a candidate for Mother of the Year. The story moves in fits and starts, lingering too long on some scenes but then abruptly skipping ahead by a decade. Director Arau is known mainly as an actor, but he does a fine job of creating an evocative atmosphere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth having in your cultural hard-drive, but the book is probably better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SeriousJest
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I didn't read the book, so if you've read the book, you might like this movie less than I did. The story is a good folk tale, and gives one insight into some aspects of Latino culture (i.e., traditions & so much more are often passed down through food; the strange traditions regarding family duty, even in the face of common sense). While watching the movie, I suspected the book is better, and I have been told by others that it is. The actor who played John was very exaggerated, although I don't know if that was done on purpose. Further, I had problems with Pedro's initial decision (the big one); as Tita later points out, there seem to have been many other decisions that would have made much more sense. Warning: this is a chick flick! In the end, though, my identity as a hispanic edged out my identity as a manly man, so I consider this movie worth watching, since the story is worth having in your cultural hard-drive. For more reviews and a kickass podcast, check out: www.livemancave.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie when uncut.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    normanc-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well filmed with great backdrops. For anyone who has lived in Mexico, it is historically accurate in its portrayal of life in northern Mexico during Revolutionary times. It comes close to following the book, which has a recipe for all of the movie meals, and more - one for each month. My wife cooked the quail in rose petals and..... Parts of the film are erotic without being graphic. All of the actors are wonderfully cast in their roles. If you want the DVD, the uncut 113 minute version has interesting scenes omitted in the American version 105 minute one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subtitled movie, but True Love in old Mexico is something to behold.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keyska2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes this is a romance movie, but it is a fantastic fantasy fairy tale quality love story. Pedro and Tita fall in love but Tita's mother objects. Tita is the youngest in the family and she must stay home and take care of her mother until she dies. Her mother even arranges a marriage between Pedro and Tita's older sister Rosaura so Tita and Pedro can never become as one. As I said this is a fantasy, and once you get past all of the initial story buildup for all of the characters the fun begins. Tita was born in the kitchen and befriended by Nacha the hired cook. Nacha raises Tita as her own teaching her how to cook and enjoy life. Once Tita's mother sets down the law of how things will be, Tita changes. Tita's cooking becomes magic. Whatever Tita is feeling when she cooks, it comes to truth in the final product. If Tita is sad and lonely, anyone who eats her cooking feels those emotions. I have watched this film several times since it was made in 1992, and it always leaves me feeling full of loves emotions. You have to watch this movie to understand the fullness of these emotions. I have gotten use to the subtitles over the years and prefer them to the English dubbed version of the movie. I love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cultural and erotic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sl-pierce
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 1992 Mexican film is full of both symbolism and cultural significance, and it helped me to appreciate the fantasy and mysticism reflected within the narrative. Tita is the youngest of three daughters, held captive by the traditions of her tenacious mother, which dictate that she is not allowed to marry, as she must care for her mother until her death. Yet, Pedro has already announced his passionate love for Tita, and in hopes of being near her, marries her older sister. Tita soon discovers she is able to communicate and share her emotions through her cooking, which she makes for Pedro to demonstrate her love for him. I found the film to be very intriguing in a symbolic sense, and would be interested to read the original book. I enjoyed viewing the early twentieth century culture richly interwoven into the storyline, and the eroticism was very prevalent, but portrayed in an artistic and reflective manner; however, it's not a film I would choose to watch again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts out well, descends into melodramatic drivel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeachHamBeach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS FOR SURE You think you'll be saying Yum, but you'll end up saying Yuck! This story about early 20th century Mexican/Texican women falling in love and grappling with family tradition began on a very promising note. Young Tita is in love with handsome Pedro...though you're never given any real reason to latch onto them or cheer them on. You don't get a story about how they meet, what drew them together...maybe just good ol' hot Latin lust (ew)? Anyway, Pedro marries Rosaura, the older sister, to "be close to his true love" while Tita is bossed around by her bitch of a mother, who isn't satisfied just ruining Tita's lovelife, she has to ridicule and criticize Tita's every move. Tita escapes her daily misery by whipping up delicious foods in the kitchen, but even this isn't given much screen time. Aside from the quails with rose petal sauce, most of the recipes are given a perfunctory glance. Most of the movie consists of Tita and Pedro pining, exchanging a few hasty kisses, and the one sex scene is completely in the dark. In short, this movie really has nothing to offer, even for us pervs who like passionate, if vapid, sex scenes as a last resort for entertainment. The grand climax comes when the two lovebirds finally get their opportunity to be a legit couple, and a spectacular fire erupts as a result of their illicit passions...Repeat after me: vomitrocious!!! I got this movie because I wanted to see all the recent/semirecent movies about food and love. This one stinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7.2? No way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaredmgoldberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having read the book from which this is adapted, this movie deserves not the praise it received. First and foremost, the movie completely misconstrues the message of the book. The book stresses the importance of FOOD, and how the food is Tita's method of both coping with her realities and her method of communicating the feelings that are being suppressed by Mama Elena. In the movie, the beauty of the food is drowned by a disgusting, almost stereotypical soap-opera-like drama. The acting is cheesy, at best, and the feelings between Tita and Pedro are poorly conveyed as love. Rather, they are portrayed by a simple, unforgiving lust. Also, the last scene was TERRIBLE. The last scene is supposed to contain a grand crescendo of feelings that ultimately lead to Pedro's, and the Tita's, deaths. However, it simply appears that Pedro has an orgasm and then faints. There is absolutely no way, without having prior knowledge of the story, to correlate between this scene and the matches theory. Also, the way in which Tita days poorly illustrates the match theory. It seems like she just eats the matches and then dies. By this, however, the intense emotion required to kindle the inner matches is just not there. By its lonesome, this movie receives a 3 (soap opera quality crap).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    true disappointment compared to the book
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (abezahler123@AOL.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the movie Like Water For Chocolate was a disappointing experience for me. After I had read the very gripping and interesting book I was looking forward to the movie. I was excited to see how the creators of the movie were going to show the most interesting part of the book, the magical realism. To my dismay i was deeply disappointed when I saw the magical realism "scenes" in the movie. The parts in the movie with magical realism were too short and random. A few examples are; when she wore the knitted blanket and it was ridiculously long, or when Tita's tears were shown dripping down the steps. The scenes seemed like they were add ons to the movie that were unnecessary. I found that the magical realism actually took away from the story in the movie. It Distanced the viewer from the characters, making them difficult to relate to. Conversely in the novel the magical realism did not take away from the story but it did not significantly add anything to the story. The movie also was lacking in depth beyond the external plot. In the book there were many underlying meanings hidden in the text. But because the acting was so terrible in the movie it felt like a soap, that meant nothing more than the crumby lines being shoved in the actors mouths. To summarize, if anyone is interested in watching this film I recommend reading the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I did not really like this movie, but it wasn't horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smhorsegirl314
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not really enjoy the movie, since I really like the ways they connected Tita and her food and made it so magical in the book. It was a disappointment in the movie when the kitchen scenes were so much less magical. The food did not come to life on the screen and it felt so much less important in the movie.I thought that the music choice made it a little corny but that part did not affect the actual movie much.I did not like the way the magical realism was portrayed with the sparks when they were making love. It seemed to impersonal I would have liked it to be portrayed in a way that better reflected the romance between Tita and Pedro.But I did think they did a good job when they had Mama Elena come back as a ghost.They used the actress and did not overdue the fact that she was a ghost, by using the typical white sheet ghost stereotype.I think they did a good job casting the three sisters making Tita very pretty and giving Gertrudis a somewhat manly look. Her man like physic lead well into the fact that she became a revolutionary. I think that making Rosaura look ugly in each scene made me sympathize with her instead of feeling guilty for Tita and her lost love. They did not emphasize Nachas role enough in the movie and her death was a lot less sad in the movie then in the book. I think that her motherly figure was an important part of the storyline and showed how Tita became who she is. The same way that they did not stress Titas role as a mother for the first baby of Rosaura and Pedro. I wish they had shown the relationships more thoroughly. The movie was entertaining but not my top choice and I think the parts of it they decided to stress were not what I would have chosen from the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nicsolomon
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not think that this was a particularly bad movie because it was able to capture some scenes that i thought would be difficult to do in a movie. The acting in this movie was not great, I found John's character to be creepy and depressing instead of the loving upbeat character I read about. I also thought that the film work was below par and if this movie were in English and released in American movie theaters it would have much more negative criticism. This movie also rushes through many important scenes and does not allow the plot to develop. If someone were to watch this movie without reading the book they would leave the movie extremely confused. Some of the positives in this movie are how they display magical realism in very interesting ways. For example in the beginning of the movie when there is rushing water to represent tears and then they harvest the salt from the tears seemed like it was represented the magical realism very well. Also the actresses who played the sisters did a good job of creating interesting sister- sister relationships. For example how Gertrudis and Tita had a very caring relationship where as the relationship between Rosura and Tita always seemed to be very competitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensual and Atmospheric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of a Mexican family is recounted, spanning decades. This is an interesting fable that manages to turn cooking into a sensual experience. It is helped by beautiful cinematography and a fine score. The acting is generally good, with Cavazos giving a standout performance as a young woman who is controlled by a domineering mother. Unfortunately, the latter is portrayed as so one-dimensionally evil that she makes Cinderalla's stepmother seem like a candidate for Mother of the Year. The story moves in fits and starts, lingering too long on some scenes but then abruptly skipping ahead by a decade. Director Arau is known mainly as an actor, but he does a fine job of creating an evocative atmosphere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth having in your cultural hard-drive, but the book is probably better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SeriousJest
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I didn't read the book, so if you've read the book, you might like this movie less than I did. The story is a good folk tale, and gives one insight into some aspects of Latino culture (i.e., traditions & so much more are often passed down through food; the strange traditions regarding family duty, even in the face of common sense). While watching the movie, I suspected the book is better, and I have been told by others that it is. The actor who played John was very exaggerated, although I don't know if that was done on purpose. Further, I had problems with Pedro's initial decision (the big one); as Tita later points out, there seem to have been many other decisions that would have made much more sense. Warning: this is a chick flick! In the end, though, my identity as a hispanic edged out my identity as a manly man, so I consider this movie worth watching, since the story is worth having in your cultural hard-drive. For more reviews and a kickass podcast, check out: www.livemancave.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie when uncut.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    normanc-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well filmed with great backdrops. For anyone who has lived in Mexico, it is historically accurate in its portrayal of life in northern Mexico during Revolutionary times. It comes close to following the book, which has a recipe for all of the movie meals, and more - one for each month. My wife cooked the quail in rose petals and..... Parts of the film are erotic without being graphic. All of the actors are wonderfully cast in their roles. If you want the DVD, the uncut 113 minute version has interesting scenes omitted in the American version 105 minute one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subtitled movie, but True Love in old Mexico is something to behold.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keyska2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes this is a romance movie, but it is a fantastic fantasy fairy tale quality love story. Pedro and Tita fall in love but Tita's mother objects. Tita is the youngest in the family and she must stay home and take care of her mother until she dies. Her mother even arranges a marriage between Pedro and Tita's older sister Rosaura so Tita and Pedro can never become as one. As I said this is a fantasy, and once you get past all of the initial story buildup for all of the characters the fun begins. Tita was born in the kitchen and befriended by Nacha the hired cook. Nacha raises Tita as her own teaching her how to cook and enjoy life. Once Tita's mother sets down the law of how things will be, Tita changes. Tita's cooking becomes magic. Whatever Tita is feeling when she cooks, it comes to truth in the final product. If Tita is sad and lonely, anyone who eats her cooking feels those emotions. I have watched this film several times since it was made in 1992, and it always leaves me feeling full of loves emotions. You have to watch this movie to understand the fullness of these emotions. I have gotten use to the subtitles over the years and prefer them to the English dubbed version of the movie. I love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cultural and erotic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sl-pierce
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 1992 Mexican film is full of both symbolism and cultural significance, and it helped me to appreciate the fantasy and mysticism reflected within the narrative. Tita is the youngest of three daughters, held captive by the traditions of her tenacious mother, which dictate that she is not allowed to marry, as she must care for her mother until her death. Yet, Pedro has already announced his passionate love for Tita, and in hopes of being near her, marries her older sister. Tita soon discovers she is able to communicate and share her emotions through her cooking, which she makes for Pedro to demonstrate her love for him. I found the film to be very intriguing in a symbolic sense, and would be interested to read the original book. I enjoyed viewing the early twentieth century culture richly interwoven into the storyline, and the eroticism was very prevalent, but portrayed in an artistic and reflective manner; however, it's not a film I would choose to watch again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts out well, descends into melodramatic drivel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeachHamBeach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS FOR SURE You think you'll be saying Yum, but you'll end up saying Yuck! This story about early 20th century Mexican/Texican women falling in love and grappling with family tradition began on a very promising note. Young Tita is in love with handsome Pedro...though you're never given any real reason to latch onto them or cheer them on. You don't get a story about how they meet, what drew them together...maybe just good ol' hot Latin lust (ew)? Anyway, Pedro marries Rosaura, the older sister, to "be close to his true love" while Tita is bossed around by her bitch of a mother, who isn't satisfied just ruining Tita's lovelife, she has to ridicule and criticize Tita's every move. Tita escapes her daily misery by whipping up delicious foods in the kitchen, but even this isn't given much screen time. Aside from the quails with rose petal sauce, most of the recipes are given a perfunctory glance. Most of the movie consists of Tita and Pedro pining, exchanging a few hasty kisses, and the one sex scene is completely in the dark. In short, this movie really has nothing to offer, even for us pervs who like passionate, if vapid, sex scenes as a last resort for entertainment. The grand climax comes when the two lovebirds finally get their opportunity to be a legit couple, and a spectacular fire erupts as a result of their illicit passions...Repeat after me: vomitrocious!!! I got this movie because I wanted to see all the recent/semirecent movies about food and love. This one stinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7.2? No way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaredmgoldberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having read the book from which this is adapted, this movie deserves not the praise it received. First and foremost, the movie completely misconstrues the message of the book. The book stresses the importance of FOOD, and how the food is Tita's method of both coping with her realities and her method of communicating the feelings that are being suppressed by Mama Elena. In the movie, the beauty of the food is drowned by a disgusting, almost stereotypical soap-opera-like drama. The acting is cheesy, at best, and the feelings between Tita and Pedro are poorly conveyed as love. Rather, they are portrayed by a simple, unforgiving lust. Also, the last scene was TERRIBLE. The last scene is supposed to contain a grand crescendo of feelings that ultimately lead to Pedro's, and the Tita's, deaths. However, it simply appears that Pedro has an orgasm and then faints. There is absolutely no way, without having prior knowledge of the story, to correlate between this scene and the matches theory. Also, the way in which Tita days poorly illustrates the match theory. It seems like she just eats the matches and then dies. By this, however, the intense emotion required to kindle the inner matches is just not there. By its lonesome, this movie receives a 3 (soap opera quality crap).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    true disappointment compared to the book
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (abezahler123@AOL.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the movie Like Water For Chocolate was a disappointing experience for me. After I had read the very gripping and interesting book I was looking forward to the movie. I was excited to see how the creators of the movie were going to show the most interesting part of the book, the magical realism. To my dismay i was deeply disappointed when I saw the magical realism "scenes" in the movie. The parts in the movie with magical realism were too short and random. A few examples are; when she wore the knitted blanket and it was ridiculously long, or when Tita's tears were shown dripping down the steps. The scenes seemed like they were add ons to the movie that were unnecessary. I found that the magical realism actually took away from the story in the movie. It Distanced the viewer from the characters, making them difficult to relate to. Conversely in the novel the magical realism did not take away from the story but it did not significantly add anything to the story. The movie also was lacking in depth beyond the external plot. In the book there were many underlying meanings hidden in the text. But because the acting was so terrible in the movie it felt like a soap, that meant nothing more than the crumby lines being shoved in the actors mouths. To summarize, if anyone is interested in watching this film I recommend reading the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I did not really like this movie, but it wasn't horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smhorsegirl314
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not really enjoy the movie, since I really like the ways they connected Tita and her food and made it so magical in the book. It was a disappointment in the movie when the kitchen scenes were so much less magical. The food did not come to life on the screen and it felt so much less important in the movie.I thought that the music choice made it a little corny but that part did not affect the actual movie much.I did not like the way the magical realism was portrayed with the sparks when they were making love. It seemed to impersonal I would have liked it to be portrayed in a way that better reflected the romance between Tita and Pedro.But I did think they did a good job when they had Mama Elena come back as a ghost.They used the actress and did not overdue the fact that she was a ghost, by using the typical white sheet ghost stereotype.I think they did a good job casting the three sisters making Tita very pretty and giving Gertrudis a somewhat manly look. Her man like physic lead well into the fact that she became a revolutionary. I think that making Rosaura look ugly in each scene made me sympathize with her instead of feeling guilty for Tita and her lost love. They did not emphasize Nachas role enough in the movie and her death was a lot less sad in the movie then in the book. I think that her motherly figure was an important part of the storyline and showed how Tita became who she is. The same way that they did not stress Titas role as a mother for the first baby of Rosaura and Pedro. I wish they had shown the relationships more thoroughly. The movie was entertaining but not my top choice and I think the parts of it they decided to stress were not what I would have chosen from the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nicsolomon
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not think that this was a particularly bad movie because it was able to capture some scenes that i thought would be difficult to do in a movie. The acting in this movie was not great, I found John's character to be creepy and depressing instead of the loving upbeat character I read about. I also thought that the film work was below par and if this movie were in English and released in American movie theaters it would have much more negative criticism. This movie also rushes through many important scenes and does not allow the plot to develop. If someone were to watch this movie without reading the book they would leave the movie extremely confused. Some of the positives in this movie are how they display magical realism in very interesting ways. For example in the beginning of the movie when there is rushing water to represent tears and then they harvest the salt from the tears seemed like it was represented the magical realism very well. Also the actresses who played the sisters did a good job of creating interesting sister- sister relationships. For example how Gertrudis and Tita had a very caring relationship where as the relationship between Rosura and Tita always seemed to be very competitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensual and Atmospheric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of a Mexican family is recounted, spanning decades. This is an interesting fable that manages to turn cooking into a sensual experience. It is helped by beautiful cinematography and a fine score. The acting is generally good, with Cavazos giving a standout performance as a young woman who is controlled by a domineering mother. Unfortunately, the latter is portrayed as so one-dimensionally evil that she makes Cinderalla's stepmother seem like a candidate for Mother of the Year. The story moves in fits and starts, lingering too long on some scenes but then abruptly skipping ahead by a decade. Director Arau is known mainly as an actor, but he does a fine job of creating an evocative atmosphere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth having in your cultural hard-drive, but the book is probably better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SeriousJest
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I didn't read the book, so if you've read the book, you might like this movie less than I did. The story is a good folk tale, and gives one insight into some aspects of Latino culture (i.e., traditions & so much more are often passed down through food; the strange traditions regarding family duty, even in the face of common sense). While watching the movie, I suspected the book is better, and I have been told by others that it is. The actor who played John was very exaggerated, although I don't know if that was done on purpose. Further, I had problems with Pedro's initial decision (the big one); as Tita later points out, there seem to have been many other decisions that would have made much more sense. Warning: this is a chick flick! In the end, though, my identity as a hispanic edged out my identity as a manly man, so I consider this movie worth watching, since the story is worth having in your cultural hard-drive. For more reviews and a kickass podcast, check out: www.livemancave.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie when uncut.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    normanc-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well filmed with great backdrops. For anyone who has lived in Mexico, it is historically accurate in its portrayal of life in northern Mexico during Revolutionary times. It comes close to following the book, which has a recipe for all of the movie meals, and more - one for each month. My wife cooked the quail in rose petals and..... Parts of the film are erotic without being graphic. All of the actors are wonderfully cast in their roles. If you want the DVD, the uncut 113 minute version has interesting scenes omitted in the American version 105 minute one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subtitled movie, but True Love in old Mexico is something to behold.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keyska2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes this is a romance movie, but it is a fantastic fantasy fairy tale quality love story. Pedro and Tita fall in love but Tita's mother objects. Tita is the youngest in the family and she must stay home and take care of her mother until she dies. Her mother even arranges a marriage between Pedro and Tita's older sister Rosaura so Tita and Pedro can never become as one. As I said this is a fantasy, and once you get past all of the initial story buildup for all of the characters the fun begins. Tita was born in the kitchen and befriended by Nacha the hired cook. Nacha raises Tita as her own teaching her how to cook and enjoy life. Once Tita's mother sets down the law of how things will be, Tita changes. Tita's cooking becomes magic. Whatever Tita is feeling when she cooks, it comes to truth in the final product. If Tita is sad and lonely, anyone who eats her cooking feels those emotions. I have watched this film several times since it was made in 1992, and it always leaves me feeling full of loves emotions. You have to watch this movie to understand the fullness of these emotions. I have gotten use to the subtitles over the years and prefer them to the English dubbed version of the movie. I love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cultural and erotic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sl-pierce
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 1992 Mexican film is full of both symbolism and cultural significance, and it helped me to appreciate the fantasy and mysticism reflected within the narrative. Tita is the youngest of three daughters, held captive by the traditions of her tenacious mother, which dictate that she is not allowed to marry, as she must care for her mother until her death. Yet, Pedro has already announced his passionate love for Tita, and in hopes of being near her, marries her older sister. Tita soon discovers she is able to communicate and share her emotions through her cooking, which she makes for Pedro to demonstrate her love for him. I found the film to be very intriguing in a symbolic sense, and would be interested to read the original book. I enjoyed viewing the early twentieth century culture richly interwoven into the storyline, and the eroticism was very prevalent, but portrayed in an artistic and reflective manner; however, it's not a film I would choose to watch again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts out well, descends into melodramatic drivel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeachHamBeach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS FOR SURE You think you'll be saying Yum, but you'll end up saying Yuck! This story about early 20th century Mexican/Texican women falling in love and grappling with family tradition began on a very promising note. Young Tita is in love with handsome Pedro...though you're never given any real reason to latch onto them or cheer them on. You don't get a story about how they meet, what drew them together...maybe just good ol' hot Latin lust (ew)? Anyway, Pedro marries Rosaura, the older sister, to "be close to his true love" while Tita is bossed around by her bitch of a mother, who isn't satisfied just ruining Tita's lovelife, she has to ridicule and criticize Tita's every move. Tita escapes her daily misery by whipping up delicious foods in the kitchen, but even this isn't given much screen time. Aside from the quails with rose petal sauce, most of the recipes are given a perfunctory glance. Most of the movie consists of Tita and Pedro pining, exchanging a few hasty kisses, and the one sex scene is completely in the dark. In short, this movie really has nothing to offer, even for us pervs who like passionate, if vapid, sex scenes as a last resort for entertainment. The grand climax comes when the two lovebirds finally get their opportunity to be a legit couple, and a spectacular fire erupts as a result of their illicit passions...Repeat after me: vomitrocious!!! I got this movie because I wanted to see all the recent/semirecent movies about food and love. This one stinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7.2? No way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaredmgoldberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having read the book from which this is adapted, this movie deserves not the praise it received. First and foremost, the movie completely misconstrues the message of the book. The book stresses the importance of FOOD, and how the food is Tita's method of both coping with her realities and her method of communicating the feelings that are being suppressed by Mama Elena. In the movie, the beauty of the food is drowned by a disgusting, almost stereotypical soap-opera-like drama. The acting is cheesy, at best, and the feelings between Tita and Pedro are poorly conveyed as love. Rather, they are portrayed by a simple, unforgiving lust. Also, the last scene was TERRIBLE. The last scene is supposed to contain a grand crescendo of feelings that ultimately lead to Pedro's, and the Tita's, deaths. However, it simply appears that Pedro has an orgasm and then faints. There is absolutely no way, without having prior knowledge of the story, to correlate between this scene and the matches theory. Also, the way in which Tita days poorly illustrates the match theory. It seems like she just eats the matches and then dies. By this, however, the intense emotion required to kindle the inner matches is just not there. By its lonesome, this movie receives a 3 (soap opera quality crap).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    true disappointment compared to the book
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (abezahler123@AOL.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the movie Like Water For Chocolate was a disappointing experience for me. After I had read the very gripping and interesting book I was looking forward to the movie. I was excited to see how the creators of the movie were going to show the most interesting part of the book, the magical realism. To my dismay i was deeply disappointed when I saw the magical realism "scenes" in the movie. The parts in the movie with magical realism were too short and random. A few examples are; when she wore the knitted blanket and it was ridiculously long, or when Tita's tears were shown dripping down the steps. The scenes seemed like they were add ons to the movie that were unnecessary. I found that the magical realism actually took away from the story in the movie. It Distanced the viewer from the characters, making them difficult to relate to. Conversely in the novel the magical realism did not take away from the story but it did not significantly add anything to the story. The movie also was lacking in depth beyond the external plot. In the book there were many underlying meanings hidden in the text. But because the acting was so terrible in the movie it felt like a soap, that meant nothing more than the crumby lines being shoved in the actors mouths. To summarize, if anyone is interested in watching this film I recommend reading the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I did not really like this movie, but it wasn't horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smhorsegirl314
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not really enjoy the movie, since I really like the ways they connected Tita and her food and made it so magical in the book. It was a disappointment in the movie when the kitchen scenes were so much less magical. The food did not come to life on the screen and it felt so much less important in the movie.I thought that the music choice made it a little corny but that part did not affect the actual movie much.I did not like the way the magical realism was portrayed with the sparks when they were making love. It seemed to impersonal I would have liked it to be portrayed in a way that better reflected the romance between Tita and Pedro.But I did think they did a good job when they had Mama Elena come back as a ghost.They used the actress and did not overdue the fact that she was a ghost, by using the typical white sheet ghost stereotype.I think they did a good job casting the three sisters making Tita very pretty and giving Gertrudis a somewhat manly look. Her man like physic lead well into the fact that she became a revolutionary. I think that making Rosaura look ugly in each scene made me sympathize with her instead of feeling guilty for Tita and her lost love. They did not emphasize Nachas role enough in the movie and her death was a lot less sad in the movie then in the book. I think that her motherly figure was an important part of the storyline and showed how Tita became who she is. The same way that they did not stress Titas role as a mother for the first baby of Rosaura and Pedro. I wish they had shown the relationships more thoroughly. The movie was entertaining but not my top choice and I think the parts of it they decided to stress were not what I would have chosen from the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nicsolomon
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not think that this was a particularly bad movie because it was able to capture some scenes that i thought would be difficult to do in a movie. The acting in this movie was not great, I found John's character to be creepy and depressing instead of the loving upbeat character I read about. I also thought that the film work was below par and if this movie were in English and released in American movie theaters it would have much more negative criticism. This movie also rushes through many important scenes and does not allow the plot to develop. If someone were to watch this movie without reading the book they would leave the movie extremely confused. Some of the positives in this movie are how they display magical realism in very interesting ways. For example in the beginning of the movie when there is rushing water to represent tears and then they harvest the salt from the tears seemed like it was represented the magical realism very well. Also the actresses who played the sisters did a good job of creating interesting sister- sister relationships. For example how Gertrudis and Tita had a very caring relationship where as the relationship between Rosura and Tita always seemed to be very competitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensual and Atmospheric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of a Mexican family is recounted, spanning decades. This is an interesting fable that manages to turn cooking into a sensual experience. It is helped by beautiful cinematography and a fine score. The acting is generally good, with Cavazos giving a standout performance as a young woman who is controlled by a domineering mother. Unfortunately, the latter is portrayed as so one-dimensionally evil that she makes Cinderalla's stepmother seem like a candidate for Mother of the Year. The story moves in fits and starts, lingering too long on some scenes but then abruptly skipping ahead by a decade. Director Arau is known mainly as an actor, but he does a fine job of creating an evocative atmosphere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth having in your cultural hard-drive, but the book is probably better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SeriousJest
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I didn't read the book, so if you've read the book, you might like this movie less than I did. The story is a good folk tale, and gives one insight into some aspects of Latino culture (i.e., traditions & so much more are often passed down through food; the strange traditions regarding family duty, even in the face of common sense). While watching the movie, I suspected the book is better, and I have been told by others that it is. The actor who played John was very exaggerated, although I don't know if that was done on purpose. Further, I had problems with Pedro's initial decision (the big one); as Tita later points out, there seem to have been many other decisions that would have made much more sense. Warning: this is a chick flick! In the end, though, my identity as a hispanic edged out my identity as a manly man, so I consider this movie worth watching, since the story is worth having in your cultural hard-drive. For more reviews and a kickass podcast, check out: www.livemancave.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie when uncut.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    normanc-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well filmed with great backdrops. For anyone who has lived in Mexico, it is historically accurate in its portrayal of life in northern Mexico during Revolutionary times. It comes close to following the book, which has a recipe for all of the movie meals, and more - one for each month. My wife cooked the quail in rose petals and..... Parts of the film are erotic without being graphic. All of the actors are wonderfully cast in their roles. If you want the DVD, the uncut 113 minute version has interesting scenes omitted in the American version 105 minute one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subtitled movie, but True Love in old Mexico is something to behold.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keyska2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes this is a romance movie, but it is a fantastic fantasy fairy tale quality love story. Pedro and Tita fall in love but Tita's mother objects. Tita is the youngest in the family and she must stay home and take care of her mother until she dies. Her mother even arranges a marriage between Pedro and Tita's older sister Rosaura so Tita and Pedro can never become as one. As I said this is a fantasy, and once you get past all of the initial story buildup for all of the characters the fun begins. Tita was born in the kitchen and befriended by Nacha the hired cook. Nacha raises Tita as her own teaching her how to cook and enjoy life. Once Tita's mother sets down the law of how things will be, Tita changes. Tita's cooking becomes magic. Whatever Tita is feeling when she cooks, it comes to truth in the final product. If Tita is sad and lonely, anyone who eats her cooking feels those emotions. I have watched this film several times since it was made in 1992, and it always leaves me feeling full of loves emotions. You have to watch this movie to understand the fullness of these emotions. I have gotten use to the subtitles over the years and prefer them to the English dubbed version of the movie. I love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cultural and erotic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sl-pierce
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 1992 Mexican film is full of both symbolism and cultural significance, and it helped me to appreciate the fantasy and mysticism reflected within the narrative. Tita is the youngest of three daughters, held captive by the traditions of her tenacious mother, which dictate that she is not allowed to marry, as she must care for her mother until her death. Yet, Pedro has already announced his passionate love for Tita, and in hopes of being near her, marries her older sister. Tita soon discovers she is able to communicate and share her emotions through her cooking, which she makes for Pedro to demonstrate her love for him. I found the film to be very intriguing in a symbolic sense, and would be interested to read the original book. I enjoyed viewing the early twentieth century culture richly interwoven into the storyline, and the eroticism was very prevalent, but portrayed in an artistic and reflective manner; however, it's not a film I would choose to watch again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts out well, descends into melodramatic drivel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeachHamBeach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS FOR SURE You think you'll be saying Yum, but you'll end up saying Yuck! This story about early 20th century Mexican/Texican women falling in love and grappling with family tradition began on a very promising note. Young Tita is in love with handsome Pedro...though you're never given any real reason to latch onto them or cheer them on. You don't get a story about how they meet, what drew them together...maybe just good ol' hot Latin lust (ew)? Anyway, Pedro marries Rosaura, the older sister, to "be close to his true love" while Tita is bossed around by her bitch of a mother, who isn't satisfied just ruining Tita's lovelife, she has to ridicule and criticize Tita's every move. Tita escapes her daily misery by whipping up delicious foods in the kitchen, but even this isn't given much screen time. Aside from the quails with rose petal sauce, most of the recipes are given a perfunctory glance. Most of the movie consists of Tita and Pedro pining, exchanging a few hasty kisses, and the one sex scene is completely in the dark. In short, this movie really has nothing to offer, even for us pervs who like passionate, if vapid, sex scenes as a last resort for entertainment. The grand climax comes when the two lovebirds finally get their opportunity to be a legit couple, and a spectacular fire erupts as a result of their illicit passions...Repeat after me: vomitrocious!!! I got this movie because I wanted to see all the recent/semirecent movies about food and love. This one stinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7.2? No way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaredmgoldberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having read the book from which this is adapted, this movie deserves not the praise it received. First and foremost, the movie completely misconstrues the message of the book. The book stresses the importance of FOOD, and how the food is Tita's method of both coping with her realities and her method of communicating the feelings that are being suppressed by Mama Elena. In the movie, the beauty of the food is drowned by a disgusting, almost stereotypical soap-opera-like drama. The acting is cheesy, at best, and the feelings between Tita and Pedro are poorly conveyed as love. Rather, they are portrayed by a simple, unforgiving lust. Also, the last scene was TERRIBLE. The last scene is supposed to contain a grand crescendo of feelings that ultimately lead to Pedro's, and the Tita's, deaths. However, it simply appears that Pedro has an orgasm and then faints. There is absolutely no way, without having prior knowledge of the story, to correlate between this scene and the matches theory. Also, the way in which Tita days poorly illustrates the match theory. It seems like she just eats the matches and then dies. By this, however, the intense emotion required to kindle the inner matches is just not there. By its lonesome, this movie receives a 3 (soap opera quality crap).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    true disappointment compared to the book
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (abezahler123@AOL.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the movie Like Water For Chocolate was a disappointing experience for me. After I had read the very gripping and interesting book I was looking forward to the movie. I was excited to see how the creators of the movie were going to show the most interesting part of the book, the magical realism. To my dismay i was deeply disappointed when I saw the magical realism "scenes" in the movie. The parts in the movie with magical realism were too short and random. A few examples are; when she wore the knitted blanket and it was ridiculously long, or when Tita's tears were shown dripping down the steps. The scenes seemed like they were add ons to the movie that were unnecessary. I found that the magical realism actually took away from the story in the movie. It Distanced the viewer from the characters, making them difficult to relate to. Conversely in the novel the magical realism did not take away from the story but it did not significantly add anything to the story. The movie also was lacking in depth beyond the external plot. In the book there were many underlying meanings hidden in the text. But because the acting was so terrible in the movie it felt like a soap, that meant nothing more than the crumby lines being shoved in the actors mouths. To summarize, if anyone is interested in watching this film I recommend reading the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I did not really like this movie, but it wasn't horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smhorsegirl314
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not really enjoy the movie, since I really like the ways they connected Tita and her food and made it so magical in the book. It was a disappointment in the movie when the kitchen scenes were so much less magical. The food did not come to life on the screen and it felt so much less important in the movie.I thought that the music choice made it a little corny but that part did not affect the actual movie much.I did not like the way the magical realism was portrayed with the sparks when they were making love. It seemed to impersonal I would have liked it to be portrayed in a way that better reflected the romance between Tita and Pedro.But I did think they did a good job when they had Mama Elena come back as a ghost.They used the actress and did not overdue the fact that she was a ghost, by using the typical white sheet ghost stereotype.I think they did a good job casting the three sisters making Tita very pretty and giving Gertrudis a somewhat manly look. Her man like physic lead well into the fact that she became a revolutionary. I think that making Rosaura look ugly in each scene made me sympathize with her instead of feeling guilty for Tita and her lost love. They did not emphasize Nachas role enough in the movie and her death was a lot less sad in the movie then in the book. I think that her motherly figure was an important part of the storyline and showed how Tita became who she is. The same way that they did not stress Titas role as a mother for the first baby of Rosaura and Pedro. I wish they had shown the relationships more thoroughly. The movie was entertaining but not my top choice and I think the parts of it they decided to stress were not what I would have chosen from the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nicsolomon
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not think that this was a particularly bad movie because it was able to capture some scenes that i thought would be difficult to do in a movie. The acting in this movie was not great, I found John's character to be creepy and depressing instead of the loving upbeat character I read about. I also thought that the film work was below par and if this movie were in English and released in American movie theaters it would have much more negative criticism. This movie also rushes through many important scenes and does not allow the plot to develop. If someone were to watch this movie without reading the book they would leave the movie extremely confused. Some of the positives in this movie are how they display magical realism in very interesting ways. For example in the beginning of the movie when there is rushing water to represent tears and then they harvest the salt from the tears seemed like it was represented the magical realism very well. Also the actresses who played the sisters did a good job of creating interesting sister- sister relationships. For example how Gertrudis and Tita had a very caring relationship where as the relationship between Rosura and Tita always seemed to be very competitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensual and Atmospheric
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of a Mexican family is recounted, spanning decades. This is an interesting fable that manages to turn cooking into a sensual experience. It is helped by beautiful cinematography and a fine score. The acting is generally good, with Cavazos giving a standout performance as a young woman who is controlled by a domineering mother. Unfortunately, the latter is portrayed as so one-dimensionally evil that she makes Cinderalla's stepmother seem like a candidate for Mother of the Year. The story moves in fits and starts, lingering too long on some scenes but then abruptly skipping ahead by a decade. Director Arau is known mainly as an actor, but he does a fine job of creating an evocative atmosphere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth having in your cultural hard-drive, but the book is probably better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SeriousJest
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I didn't read the book, so if you've read the book, you might like this movie less than I did. The story is a good folk tale, and gives one insight into some aspects of Latino culture (i.e., traditions & so much more are often passed down through food; the strange traditions regarding family duty, even in the face of common sense). While watching the movie, I suspected the book is better, and I have been told by others that it is. The actor who played John was very exaggerated, although I don't know if that was done on purpose. Further, I had problems with Pedro's initial decision (the big one); as Tita later points out, there seem to have been many other decisions that would have made much more sense. Warning: this is a chick flick! In the end, though, my identity as a hispanic edged out my identity as a manly man, so I consider this movie worth watching, since the story is worth having in your cultural hard-drive. For more reviews and a kickass podcast, check out: www.livemancave.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie when uncut.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    normanc-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well filmed with great backdrops. For anyone who has lived in Mexico, it is historically accurate in its portrayal of life in northern Mexico during Revolutionary times. It comes close to following the book, which has a recipe for all of the movie meals, and more - one for each month. My wife cooked the quail in rose petals and..... Parts of the film are erotic without being graphic. All of the actors are wonderfully cast in their roles. If you want the DVD, the uncut 113 minute version has interesting scenes omitted in the American version 105 minute one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subtitled movie, but True Love in old Mexico is something to behold.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Keyska2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes this is a romance movie, but it is a fantastic fantasy fairy tale quality love story. Pedro and Tita fall in love but Tita's mother objects. Tita is the youngest in the family and she must stay home and take care of her mother until she dies. Her mother even arranges a marriage between Pedro and Tita's older sister Rosaura so Tita and Pedro can never become as one. As I said this is a fantasy, and once you get past all of the initial story buildup for all of the characters the fun begins. Tita was born in the kitchen and befriended by Nacha the hired cook. Nacha raises Tita as her own teaching her how to cook and enjoy life. Once Tita's mother sets down the law of how things will be, Tita changes. Tita's cooking becomes magic. Whatever Tita is feeling when she cooks, it comes to truth in the final product. If Tita is sad and lonely, anyone who eats her cooking feels those emotions. I have watched this film several times since it was made in 1992, and it always leaves me feeling full of loves emotions. You have to watch this movie to understand the fullness of these emotions. I have gotten use to the subtitles over the years and prefer them to the English dubbed version of the movie. I love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A cultural and erotic work of art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sl-pierce
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 1992 Mexican film is full of both symbolism and cultural significance, and it helped me to appreciate the fantasy and mysticism reflected within the narrative. Tita is the youngest of three daughters, held captive by the traditions of her tenacious mother, which dictate that she is not allowed to marry, as she must care for her mother until her death. Yet, Pedro has already announced his passionate love for Tita, and in hopes of being near her, marries her older sister. Tita soon discovers she is able to communicate and share her emotions through her cooking, which she makes for Pedro to demonstrate her love for him. I found the film to be very intriguing in a symbolic sense, and would be interested to read the original book. I enjoyed viewing the early twentieth century culture richly interwoven into the storyline, and the eroticism was very prevalent, but portrayed in an artistic and reflective manner; however, it's not a film I would choose to watch again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Starts out well, descends into melodramatic drivel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeachHamBeach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS FOR SURE You think you'll be saying Yum, but you'll end up saying Yuck! This story about early 20th century Mexican/Texican women falling in love and grappling with family tradition began on a very promising note. Young Tita is in love with handsome Pedro...though you're never given any real reason to latch onto them or cheer them on. You don't get a story about how they meet, what drew them together...maybe just good ol' hot Latin lust (ew)? Anyway, Pedro marries Rosaura, the older sister, to "be close to his true love" while Tita is bossed around by her bitch of a mother, who isn't satisfied just ruining Tita's lovelife, she has to ridicule and criticize Tita's every move. Tita escapes her daily misery by whipping up delicious foods in the kitchen, but even this isn't given much screen time. Aside from the quails with rose petal sauce, most of the recipes are given a perfunctory glance. Most of the movie consists of Tita and Pedro pining, exchanging a few hasty kisses, and the one sex scene is completely in the dark. In short, this movie really has nothing to offer, even for us pervs who like passionate, if vapid, sex scenes as a last resort for entertainment. The grand climax comes when the two lovebirds finally get their opportunity to be a legit couple, and a spectacular fire erupts as a result of their illicit passions...Repeat after me: vomitrocious!!! I got this movie because I wanted to see all the recent/semirecent movies about food and love. This one stinks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7.2? No way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaredmgoldberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After having read the book from which this is adapted, this movie deserves not the praise it received. First and foremost, the movie completely misconstrues the message of the book. The book stresses the importance of FOOD, and how the food is Tita's method of both coping with her realities and her method of communicating the feelings that are being suppressed by Mama Elena. In the movie, the beauty of the food is drowned by a disgusting, almost stereotypical soap-opera-like drama. The acting is cheesy, at best, and the feelings between Tita and Pedro are poorly conveyed as love. Rather, they are portrayed by a simple, unforgiving lust. Also, the last scene was TERRIBLE. The last scene is supposed to contain a grand crescendo of feelings that ultimately lead to Pedro's, and the Tita's, deaths. However, it simply appears that Pedro has an orgasm and then faints. There is absolutely no way, without having prior knowledge of the story, to correlate between this scene and the matches theory. Also, the way in which Tita days poorly illustrates the match theory. It seems like she just eats the matches and then dies. By this, however, the intense emotion required to kindle the inner matches is just not there. By its lonesome, this movie receives a 3 (soap opera quality crap).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    true disappointment compared to the book
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (abezahler123@AOL.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the movie Like Water For Chocolate was a disappointing experience for me. After I had read the very gripping and interesting book I was looking forward to the movie. I was excited to see how the creators of the movie were going to show the most interesting part of the book, the magical realism. To my dismay i was deeply disappointed when I saw the magical realism "scenes" in the movie. The parts in the movie with magical realism were too short and random. A few examples are; when she wore the knitted blanket and it was ridiculously long, or when Tita's tears were shown dripping down the steps. The scenes seemed like they were add ons to the movie that were unnecessary. I found that the magical realism actually took away from the story in the movie. It Distanced the viewer from the characters, making them difficult to relate to. Conversely in the novel the magical realism did not take away from the story but it did not significantly add anything to the story. The movie also was lacking in depth beyond the external plot. In the book there were many underlying meanings hidden in the text. But because the acting was so terrible in the movie it felt like a soap, that meant nothing more than the crumby lines being shoved in the actors mouths. To summarize, if anyone is interested in watching this film I recommend reading the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I did not really like this movie, but it wasn't horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    smhorsegirl314
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not really enjoy the movie, since I really like the ways they connected Tita and her food and made it so magical in the book. It was a disappointment in the movie when the kitchen scenes were so much less magical. The food did not come to life on the screen and it felt so much less important in the movie.I thought that the music choice made it a little corny but that part did not affect the actual movie much.I did not like the way the magical realism was portrayed with the sparks when they were making love. It seemed to impersonal I would have liked it to be portrayed in a way that better reflected the romance between Tita and Pedro.But I did think they did a good job when they had Mama Elena come back as a ghost.They used the actress and did not overdue the fact that she was a ghost, by using the typical white sheet ghost stereotype.I think they did a good job casting the three sisters making Tita very pretty and giving Gertrudis a somewhat manly look. Her man like physic lead well into the fact that she became a revolutionary. I think that making Rosaura look ugly in each scene made me sympathize with her instead of feeling guilty for Tita and her lost love. They did not emphasize Nachas role enough in the movie and her death was a lot less sad in the movie then in the book. I think that her motherly figure was an important part of the storyline and showed how Tita became who she is. The same way that they did not stress Titas role as a mother for the first baby of Rosaura and Pedro. I wish they had shown the relationships more thoroughly. The movie was entertaining but not my top choice and I think the parts of it they decided to stress were not what I would have chosen from the book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nicsolomon
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not think that this was a particularly bad movie because it was able to capture some scenes that i thought would be difficult to do in a movie. The acting in this movie was not great, I found John's character to be creepy and depressing instead of the loving upbeat character I read about. I also thought that the film work was below par and if this movie were in English and released in American movie theaters it would have much more negative criticism. This movie also rushes through many important scenes and does not allow the plot to develop. If someone were to watch this movie without reading the book they would leave the movie extremely confused. Some of the positives in this movie are how they display magical realism in very interesting ways. For example in the beginning of the movie when there is rushing water to represent tears and then they harvest the salt from the tears seemed like it was represented the magical realism very well. Also the actresses who played the sisters did a good job of creating interesting sister- sister relationships. For example how Gertrudis and Tita had a very caring relationship where as the relationship between Rosura and Tita always seemed to be very competitive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
