<filme>
 <id>
  463
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111112
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Mist&eacute;rio da Ilha
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  10-year-old Fiona is sent to live with her grandparents in a small fishing village in Donegal, Ireland. She soon learns the local legend that an ancestor of hers married a Selkie - a seal ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  10-year-old Fiona is sent to live with her grandparents in a small fishing village in Donegal, Ireland. She soon learns the local legend that an ancestor of hers married a Selkie - a seal who can turn into a human. Years earlier, her baby brother washed out to sea in a cradle shaped like a boat; someone in the family believes the boy is being raised by the seals. Then Fiona catches sight of a naked little boy on the abandoned Isle of Roan Inish and takes an active role in uncovering The Secret of Roan Inish. Written by John Oswalt.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   seal
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ireland
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   selkie
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   family relationships
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   island
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Sayles
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Rosalie K. Fry
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   John Sayles
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jeni Courtney
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Eileen Colgan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mick Lally
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanmarkel
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people would label this a children's movie...and yet, it has all the mystery and beauty that accompanies films for adults who love poetry and traditional storytelling and classic literature. Watch this film, and you'll get a good idea of Irish tradition and life and their constant belief in legend and lore, which has made them into the wonderful and strong race that they are today. There is a deep sense of family...a truly strong family who has clearly had its ups and downs and yet has come out even stronger than before. A family that has been through generations of change, adapted, continues to change and yet still holds onto the traditions and stories along the way. Stories that others might assume are myth and faery tales. And stories that we know aren't anything but the truth woven into a magical tale. In most Irish tales and legends I've read, there is a quest which keeps the main character(s) pushing forward through all the challenges of life. Fiona's store in this movie is no different. She's a little girl lost at the beginning when we meet her, wandering through the smog of the city to find some way to latch onto her father who is lost and sad with grief over a dead wife and a dead and missing baby boy. Her true quest begins when she is sent to live with her grandparents who still live by the sea. And the quest truly becomes a quest when she learns that her baby brother Jamie has been spotted on Roan Inish, the Island of the Seals where her family originated from. The music weaves itself around the characters and the story to make it more complete than it would be without it. It is both peaceful and stirring, providing the background for the cultural ear. With the music and the intricate storytelling, one can become truly lost in this story. And truly a part of it. If I had children, this is one movie I would have them watch over and over again. Like Disney's "Darby O'Gill and the Little People," this is a movie to entertain children of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Music to my fears
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much like "The Secret Garden", this is a film about the unlikely combination of everyday reality and pure magic. The character of Fiona (played by Jeni Courtney) is like every free and beautiful little girl that you've ever encountered rolled into one. She has such a wonderful outlook on life; honest and serious, faithful and fanciful. This is an improbable film for director John Sayles, an American filmmaker who usually sticks much closer to home. More pleasing still is the fact that he takes an honest, unfiltered view of the Irish culture that is so intrinsic to the story being told. "The Secret of Roan Inish" is about storytelling, from an inner and outer perspective. Each character is deeply concerned with sharing his or her own tale or take on local folklore. The script takes all sorts of beautiful sidelines into the tales of Fiona's relatives and anyone else who happens to pass by. Particularly fascinating is the performance of John Lynch, whose character tells the legend of the Selkie (played by his sister, Susan Lynch). The images of the seal woman are breathtaking, painful in their uncertain waking beauty. The final result of the film is something between the purity of childhood and the trust of self. I was taken in not only by the overwhelming sense of the unknown, but by everything fearful and wonderful in the making known of the same. This is one of the most enrapturing motion pictures I've ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celtic crowd pleaser masquerading as edgy indie art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The older the fiddle, the sweeter the tune." - Irish proverb Part of cinema's "Irish boom" in the lead up to the Anglo-Irish ceasefires, "The Secret of Roan Inish" is a low key, fairly unassuming piece of fantasy by director John Sales, notable mostly for some good cinematography by the legendary Haskell Wexler. Like all of these films ("Waking Ned Devine", "Far and Away", "Riverdance" etc), "The Secret of Roan Inish" exemplifies what writer Natasha Casey calls "Cletic commodification", reducing Ireland and Irishness to "Celtic myths", quaint, pre-modern, rural landscapes, and a depiction of the nation as being forever pre-colonised. Unsurprisingly, the film was widely distributed in America and Britian (since John Ford, "Irishness" has always been used as a vehicle to allow white audiences to role-play being white minorities/victims), but only had a limited release in Ireland. Its pastoral, regressive image of Irish society is more commercially viable outside of its home territory. The film is often touted as being Sayles' only non-political film, but this isn't true. Its tales of when "man and beast lived side-by-side, sharing the sea", of "monsters shedding their past skins", of a little girl's self determination and slow journey back to her roots, are designed specifically for the Irish diaspora. It's a call for a people to return to their homes and live alongside the now tamed beasts of Old England. "Everyone wants to march into the future," one haggard Irish character says, mourning about how his country "just got left behind." But the film's solution is to avoid modernization and to delve deeper into the past; a regression into some mythical "pure origins", a move backward to re-establish a pre-colonial Ireland. This is not surprising. The grand narrative of a society moving from the pre-modern to the modern to the post-modern, breaks down in Ireland. After the Anglo-Irish and Civil wars, as well as hundreds of years of struggle, the Irish were concerned with maintaining the nationalist cultural identity that they were finally free to express in their self-governance. But what Sayles' film does is advocate delving into the "rich identity of Ireland's past", whilst serving up only Disneyland trinkets. It's the condescending David Lean view of Ireland; the art house equivalent of a Lucky Charms cereal box. So it's not only that the film fails to give a genuine ideology of contemporary Ireland, or that it chooses an escape to the past instead of clarifying historical events, but that it pretends to be about "identity" when actually it's relying on mythology in order to avoid questions of authenticity (or the impossibility thereof). Ironically, with the Irish film industry in ruins, "Irishness" has increasingly become a sort of "viscious circle", foreigners projecting "Irishness" onto a country who must now parrot (and export) such cosy, plastic "Irishness" in their own art if they hope to garner international attention. Sayles is unwittingly participating here in the kind of damaging, bottled-tourism and cultural kitsch that he denounces so well in "Limbo" and "Sunshine State". Ignoring these issues, the film works fairly well as a children's fantasy, though I suspect most kids and adults will find "Roan Inish" too plain and too slow. Compare the film to Victor Erice's "The Spirit of the Beehive", a masterpiece which, like "Roan Inish", merges history, myth and childhood. 7/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quiet gem of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Momcat_of_Lomita
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a rare movie: one that can hold the attention of adults while at the same time keeping children entranced. That said, I have to add: this is not a movie for very young kids, who will not understand the mythology involved or "get" the plot. It is also not a film for people who are looking for a lot of action, special effects, cornball humor or over-the-top near-hysterical acting. It's a movie that works quietly for its effects. The first thing I have to comment on is the beautiful setting of the film and the photography. The setting is the west coast of Ireland, in a small fishing village, and on the sea and the land around the village. I believe "Secret" is as successful at conveying the rugged beauty of this landscape and seascape as any movie made. No tricks, no special effects, just the beauty of a place that has a lot of history and mythology associated with it. The actors and actresses in this film are not big names and not well-known, and I would say that this is a movie that is more story-driven than character-driven. At the same time, the lack of "name" actors or big bravura performances works to the advantage of the film, in that the personalities of the actors are submerged in the plot. There is a lot of kindness in this film, and a sense of the people being really connected to one another and caring for and about each other, and about the land and time they live in. That's one of the things that I loved about this film: there are no real villains, nothing evil. Nobody is considered stupid or demeaned in any way. And yet there is a tension to the story, and a move towards resolution of a history that had sadness and tragedy in a way that is literally magical. I loved this movie and I recommend it to anyone who can enjoy a movie that isn't big on action, that doesn't try to do more than tell a story in a way that's thoughtful and beautiful and makes you wish that you could find that kind of magic in your own life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Family values" in the best sense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Screen-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a true family film -- for and about families. Except for very small children (who might get bored) this film is has something for all ages. The actors -- both young and old, animal and human -- are excellent. The story-line is interesting for children but complex enough for adults. It's as beautiful as most "art movies" but as plot-driven as a Hollywood movie, again making it appealing to a broad range of people. It's non-offensive but not at all cloying like some family movies. (Well, unless you're offended by drinking or toddler nudity.) It's magical and mythic but still rooted in characters that seem believable. It also has interesting rural Irish culture which, I assume is accurate. My wife and I saw this movie in the theater before we had children and we now watch it with our kids on DVD. I've seen it three or four times and I'm still not tired of it! The only possible downside I can think of are the fairly thick Irish accents. I have no problem understanding but some people might.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Burin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the soundtrack to Tarantino's Kill Bill, Vol. 1, rapper RZA dedicates his witless contribution to character O-Ren Ishii, "half-Chinese, half-Japanese-ie". Well this review is dedicated in its entirety to the isle of Roan Inish, all Irish, no Japan-inish. John Sayles has spent most of his stellar career as a writer-director documenting the making of modern America: with the searing, masterfully-woven race relations dramas Lone Star and Sunshine State and the classic coming-of-age film Baby It's You, which doubles as a portrait of the immigrant experience. This change-of-pace outing finds him amidst the myths and mysteries of rural Ireland, where a 10-year-old girl is hunting for the baby brother who was swept to sea when her family evacuated its remote island home. The film builds slowly, mesmerisingly towards a cathartic act of mercy, incorporating several nuanced diversions which either bolster the narrative or flesh out its highly evocative portrait of a sea-faring community. Medium Cool director Haskell Wexler's lustrous cinematography and a soundtrack of Celtic folk songs add to the very special atmosphere, while the sensitive performances remain doggedly unsentimental, young Jeni Courtney representing the movie's poetic but earthy sensibility as the resourceful, single-minded heroine. Meanwhile, Sayles' unmatched ear for dialogue is as attuned as ever, his empathy for the characters reinforced by inventive direction that sees the world from Courtney's height for its first five minutes. Roan Inish is a tender, affecting and ultimately magical film - and one of the best few I'll see this year. RZA was unavailable for comment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing Happened!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cooperreynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just finished watching this movie and immediately went online to see just how terrible the reviews were only to see it has a 97% on rotten tomatoes upwards of 7 out of 10 on IMDb. Shocked by this I filled out the required information just to write this one review. This film struck me as borderline unwatchable. The child acting is on par The Phantom Menace. The little girl is cute, but good lord it was just embarrassing to watch. I kept telling myself it had to be intended as a children's movie and I was being unfair to assess it as harshly as I was until the movie had been playing for about an hour and NOTHING HAD HAPPENED! The only event that had occurred, excluding the painfully boring exposition, was the little girl chasing the naked kid for 40 seconds or so only to lose him in his little boat. I kept holding on hoping something, anything, would happen, but it never really did. This is literally how the movie ends: The little girl's family , for no reason, starts believing her about the little boy so they go out in the storm to find him. They walk outside their newly repaired house and the girl yells "Look!" We then see the kid on the shore and when he sees his sister he tries to flee, perhaps horrified at his sister's acting ability. When he tries to get in his little boat some seals, bear with me, come onto the shore. One seal chases him away from his boat and the others push the boat into the water. The family captures him and that's the happy ending? Does that not seem, at best, extremely dumb to anyone else? I can maybe buy someone liking the cultural overtones of the movie or even the occasional whimsy, but who in their right mind could truly say that they were ENTERTAINED by this film? Maybe this movie just went over my head, but in order for me to enjoy a movie i would need a few events to occur and maybe a plot or something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evocative, somewhat slow - an excellent children's film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While seeming to aim for the sense of mystery of 'Picnic at Hanging Rock', 'Roan Inish' never rises above the level of a strong TV drama. The problem isn't the central performance of Jeni Courtney as Fiona, which is outstandingly good, or the rest of the cast who must have frozen their assets impressively filming the lives of poor fishermen on the East Atlantic foreshore. More power to them. The kid playing the lost boy Jamie, Cillian Byrne (who didn't trouble the costume department), is also amazing, the way he (apparently) steers that floating cradle; and the scene with the seal and him having 'tea' is tremendous. But essentially this is a children's film, a sort of 'Railway Children' with Irish pipes and seals. Lots of Irish pipes. Lots of seals. Lots of seagulls. Lots of cold-looking water and rowboats. Lots of beaches, grass and flowers. Yet more Irish music. The only real suspense is whether there's a happy ending or not, which I won't give away, but no-one ever doubts that Fiona's story of what she has seen is true. Fair enough, they're simple people who believe in faery folk, but it all seems a bit cut-and-dried in the end. At the beginning, there's too much exposition from blarney-gushing Oirish characters, the late middle segue sequence goes on a bit too long and the pacing tends to slow up towards the end. But it's a genuine, well-made, innocent sort of film that you can safely let your smallest kids watch. The sort of film to rent at Xmas, or Easter. Especially if there's any Irish in you, or you particularly like seals. Much better than 'Ryan's Daughter', btw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cosmoeticadotcom (cosmoetica@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If John Sayles, the independent American filmmaker, is not the greatest director in the history of the medium, he certainly has to be considered among the most daring and diverse filmmakers ever. From tales set in America's past (Matewan), to yuppy dramadies (The Return Of The Secaucus Seven), to urban social satires (The Brother From Another Planet), to more modern looks at American life (Sunshine State, Lone Star, Casa De Los Babys), Sayles has shown a desire to explore things no other filmmaker has. And while he does not have a distinctive look nor style, each of films is well wrought, and a worthy addition to world cinema. One of his most daring films was actually one of his most popular and financially successful- 1995's Irish fantasy film, The Secret Of Roan Inish. OK, let me rephrase- to call The Secret Of Roan Inish a fantasy film- even if Sayles adapted the screenplay from a 1957 children's book (The Secret Of Ron Mor Skerry) by Rosalie K. Fry, is to sell it short. It is a very sly and deep look at childhood and the loneliness that accompanies such. In this way, it is very much in league with such other explorations of early childhood loneliness as Val Lewton's 1944 film The Curse Of The Cat People and 1968's Godzilla's Revenge. It is also very much a great family film along the lines of October Sky and My Dog Skip. It is also very much a mythic film. That term is often overused to describe films that deal with 'epic' characters or situations, but that sort of description and film too often wallows in the pseudo-babble of faux intellectuals like Joseph Campbell. This film succeeds by using the exact opposite tack- it presents the film very much from a child's eye point of view, that of its lead character Fiona Coneely (Jeni Courtney)- a cute ten year old blond girl who goes to live with her grandparents after World War Two, because her mother has died, and her father has had to go off to Scotland to find work. The film did only mediocre at the box office, but that's because it is a terrific and deep film that never condescends. It is a children's film sans explosions and wiseass children, and explodes the idea that films aimed at children need be lesser versions of their adult counterparts. In fact, they have a greater charge- to appeal to kids as well as adults, and on both levels. Children's films, in fact, should have more ideas crammed into them as children can absorb more and learn from them without the biases and fears that a typical adult has acquired. The film runs a crisp hour and forty-three minutes, and not a second is wasted. The only quibble one might have with the film is its title. It really should have been called The Secrets (plural) Of Roan Inish, for more than the secret of Jamie's fate is involved. Yet, the flaws in this film are very minor- such as Fiona's repeated inability to outwit her wild child brother, compared to the film's virtues- almost all else. The Secret Of Roan Inish is one of Sayles' best films, and arguably a great film in its own right. That this film did what it did with so little shows that true creativity thrives no matter what its source of nourishment is, and that when that creativity is a product of John Sayles' mind, it's likely to be something well beyond the norm.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intersection of Nature and Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pierotti@ku.edu)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the most emotionally satisfying film John Sayles has ever made, which tops a long and excellent list. Working with a virtually unknown Irish cast, Sayles brings to life a story that wanders on the borderland between mystical and blue-collar realism, without becoming cloying or simplistic. The only film to which i think Roan Inish can be effectively compared is Whale Rider, but with no insult intended to Whale Rider, to me Roan Inish is a richer and more complex film. The basic story concerns the relationship between humans and non-humans and how long- standing relationships between species can be torn apart by world events; in this case the Second World War, which forces a community of Irish fisherfolk to relocate to the mainland. A young girl, whose family has been damaged through these actions and other forces, is sent to live with her grandparents on the coast, at which point her nonhuman relatives contrive to bring her and her family back to the home they once shared with other life forms. The little girl, Fiona, who is the primary human character, played by Jenny Courtney, is wonderfully written and played. She is not your standard cutie-pie, but a budding force of nature. It is obvious why of all the members of her family, the nonhumans single her out for their attention. The story is drawn from the traditional Irish and Scots stories of relationships between humans and seals, or selchies, but transposes this into a more modern setting, without losing any of the mystery or wonder. One of the strongest recommendations I can give this film is that has become one of the most popular and respected films at Haskell Indian Nations University here in Kansas. Indigenous Americans seem to identify with the experience of the Irish, which shows them that modern European culture has been destructive to Indigenous peoples in Europe, and allows them to realize that there have been and continue to be, Indigenous people with distinct cultures in Europe as well as the Americas. I was once in a video store, when a person I knew slightly asked me if I could recommend a film that would appeal both to him and his children. Without hesitation I went over and picked up the store's copy of Roan Inish, and told him, "Not only will you enjoy this, but it will give you and your kids a lot to think and talk about." I make the same recommendation to anyone who reads this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanmarkel
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people would label this a children's movie...and yet, it has all the mystery and beauty that accompanies films for adults who love poetry and traditional storytelling and classic literature. Watch this film, and you'll get a good idea of Irish tradition and life and their constant belief in legend and lore, which has made them into the wonderful and strong race that they are today. There is a deep sense of family...a truly strong family who has clearly had its ups and downs and yet has come out even stronger than before. A family that has been through generations of change, adapted, continues to change and yet still holds onto the traditions and stories along the way. Stories that others might assume are myth and faery tales. And stories that we know aren't anything but the truth woven into a magical tale. In most Irish tales and legends I've read, there is a quest which keeps the main character(s) pushing forward through all the challenges of life. Fiona's store in this movie is no different. She's a little girl lost at the beginning when we meet her, wandering through the smog of the city to find some way to latch onto her father who is lost and sad with grief over a dead wife and a dead and missing baby boy. Her true quest begins when she is sent to live with her grandparents who still live by the sea. And the quest truly becomes a quest when she learns that her baby brother Jamie has been spotted on Roan Inish, the Island of the Seals where her family originated from. The music weaves itself around the characters and the story to make it more complete than it would be without it. It is both peaceful and stirring, providing the background for the cultural ear. With the music and the intricate storytelling, one can become truly lost in this story. And truly a part of it. If I had children, this is one movie I would have them watch over and over again. Like Disney's "Darby O'Gill and the Little People," this is a movie to entertain children of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Music to my fears
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much like "The Secret Garden", this is a film about the unlikely combination of everyday reality and pure magic. The character of Fiona (played by Jeni Courtney) is like every free and beautiful little girl that you've ever encountered rolled into one. She has such a wonderful outlook on life; honest and serious, faithful and fanciful. This is an improbable film for director John Sayles, an American filmmaker who usually sticks much closer to home. More pleasing still is the fact that he takes an honest, unfiltered view of the Irish culture that is so intrinsic to the story being told. "The Secret of Roan Inish" is about storytelling, from an inner and outer perspective. Each character is deeply concerned with sharing his or her own tale or take on local folklore. The script takes all sorts of beautiful sidelines into the tales of Fiona's relatives and anyone else who happens to pass by. Particularly fascinating is the performance of John Lynch, whose character tells the legend of the Selkie (played by his sister, Susan Lynch). The images of the seal woman are breathtaking, painful in their uncertain waking beauty. The final result of the film is something between the purity of childhood and the trust of self. I was taken in not only by the overwhelming sense of the unknown, but by everything fearful and wonderful in the making known of the same. This is one of the most enrapturing motion pictures I've ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celtic crowd pleaser masquerading as edgy indie art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The older the fiddle, the sweeter the tune." - Irish proverb Part of cinema's "Irish boom" in the lead up to the Anglo-Irish ceasefires, "The Secret of Roan Inish" is a low key, fairly unassuming piece of fantasy by director John Sales, notable mostly for some good cinematography by the legendary Haskell Wexler. Like all of these films ("Waking Ned Devine", "Far and Away", "Riverdance" etc), "The Secret of Roan Inish" exemplifies what writer Natasha Casey calls "Cletic commodification", reducing Ireland and Irishness to "Celtic myths", quaint, pre-modern, rural landscapes, and a depiction of the nation as being forever pre-colonised. Unsurprisingly, the film was widely distributed in America and Britian (since John Ford, "Irishness" has always been used as a vehicle to allow white audiences to role-play being white minorities/victims), but only had a limited release in Ireland. Its pastoral, regressive image of Irish society is more commercially viable outside of its home territory. The film is often touted as being Sayles' only non-political film, but this isn't true. Its tales of when "man and beast lived side-by-side, sharing the sea", of "monsters shedding their past skins", of a little girl's self determination and slow journey back to her roots, are designed specifically for the Irish diaspora. It's a call for a people to return to their homes and live alongside the now tamed beasts of Old England. "Everyone wants to march into the future," one haggard Irish character says, mourning about how his country "just got left behind." But the film's solution is to avoid modernization and to delve deeper into the past; a regression into some mythical "pure origins", a move backward to re-establish a pre-colonial Ireland. This is not surprising. The grand narrative of a society moving from the pre-modern to the modern to the post-modern, breaks down in Ireland. After the Anglo-Irish and Civil wars, as well as hundreds of years of struggle, the Irish were concerned with maintaining the nationalist cultural identity that they were finally free to express in their self-governance. But what Sayles' film does is advocate delving into the "rich identity of Ireland's past", whilst serving up only Disneyland trinkets. It's the condescending David Lean view of Ireland; the art house equivalent of a Lucky Charms cereal box. So it's not only that the film fails to give a genuine ideology of contemporary Ireland, or that it chooses an escape to the past instead of clarifying historical events, but that it pretends to be about "identity" when actually it's relying on mythology in order to avoid questions of authenticity (or the impossibility thereof). Ironically, with the Irish film industry in ruins, "Irishness" has increasingly become a sort of "viscious circle", foreigners projecting "Irishness" onto a country who must now parrot (and export) such cosy, plastic "Irishness" in their own art if they hope to garner international attention. Sayles is unwittingly participating here in the kind of damaging, bottled-tourism and cultural kitsch that he denounces so well in "Limbo" and "Sunshine State". Ignoring these issues, the film works fairly well as a children's fantasy, though I suspect most kids and adults will find "Roan Inish" too plain and too slow. Compare the film to Victor Erice's "The Spirit of the Beehive", a masterpiece which, like "Roan Inish", merges history, myth and childhood. 7/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quiet gem of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Momcat_of_Lomita
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a rare movie: one that can hold the attention of adults while at the same time keeping children entranced. That said, I have to add: this is not a movie for very young kids, who will not understand the mythology involved or "get" the plot. It is also not a film for people who are looking for a lot of action, special effects, cornball humor or over-the-top near-hysterical acting. It's a movie that works quietly for its effects. The first thing I have to comment on is the beautiful setting of the film and the photography. The setting is the west coast of Ireland, in a small fishing village, and on the sea and the land around the village. I believe "Secret" is as successful at conveying the rugged beauty of this landscape and seascape as any movie made. No tricks, no special effects, just the beauty of a place that has a lot of history and mythology associated with it. The actors and actresses in this film are not big names and not well-known, and I would say that this is a movie that is more story-driven than character-driven. At the same time, the lack of "name" actors or big bravura performances works to the advantage of the film, in that the personalities of the actors are submerged in the plot. There is a lot of kindness in this film, and a sense of the people being really connected to one another and caring for and about each other, and about the land and time they live in. That's one of the things that I loved about this film: there are no real villains, nothing evil. Nobody is considered stupid or demeaned in any way. And yet there is a tension to the story, and a move towards resolution of a history that had sadness and tragedy in a way that is literally magical. I loved this movie and I recommend it to anyone who can enjoy a movie that isn't big on action, that doesn't try to do more than tell a story in a way that's thoughtful and beautiful and makes you wish that you could find that kind of magic in your own life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Family values" in the best sense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Screen-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a true family film -- for and about families. Except for very small children (who might get bored) this film is has something for all ages. The actors -- both young and old, animal and human -- are excellent. The story-line is interesting for children but complex enough for adults. It's as beautiful as most "art movies" but as plot-driven as a Hollywood movie, again making it appealing to a broad range of people. It's non-offensive but not at all cloying like some family movies. (Well, unless you're offended by drinking or toddler nudity.) It's magical and mythic but still rooted in characters that seem believable. It also has interesting rural Irish culture which, I assume is accurate. My wife and I saw this movie in the theater before we had children and we now watch it with our kids on DVD. I've seen it three or four times and I'm still not tired of it! The only possible downside I can think of are the fairly thick Irish accents. I have no problem understanding but some people might.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Burin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the soundtrack to Tarantino's Kill Bill, Vol. 1, rapper RZA dedicates his witless contribution to character O-Ren Ishii, "half-Chinese, half-Japanese-ie". Well this review is dedicated in its entirety to the isle of Roan Inish, all Irish, no Japan-inish. John Sayles has spent most of his stellar career as a writer-director documenting the making of modern America: with the searing, masterfully-woven race relations dramas Lone Star and Sunshine State and the classic coming-of-age film Baby It's You, which doubles as a portrait of the immigrant experience. This change-of-pace outing finds him amidst the myths and mysteries of rural Ireland, where a 10-year-old girl is hunting for the baby brother who was swept to sea when her family evacuated its remote island home. The film builds slowly, mesmerisingly towards a cathartic act of mercy, incorporating several nuanced diversions which either bolster the narrative or flesh out its highly evocative portrait of a sea-faring community. Medium Cool director Haskell Wexler's lustrous cinematography and a soundtrack of Celtic folk songs add to the very special atmosphere, while the sensitive performances remain doggedly unsentimental, young Jeni Courtney representing the movie's poetic but earthy sensibility as the resourceful, single-minded heroine. Meanwhile, Sayles' unmatched ear for dialogue is as attuned as ever, his empathy for the characters reinforced by inventive direction that sees the world from Courtney's height for its first five minutes. Roan Inish is a tender, affecting and ultimately magical film - and one of the best few I'll see this year. RZA was unavailable for comment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing Happened!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cooperreynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just finished watching this movie and immediately went online to see just how terrible the reviews were only to see it has a 97% on rotten tomatoes upwards of 7 out of 10 on IMDb. Shocked by this I filled out the required information just to write this one review. This film struck me as borderline unwatchable. The child acting is on par The Phantom Menace. The little girl is cute, but good lord it was just embarrassing to watch. I kept telling myself it had to be intended as a children's movie and I was being unfair to assess it as harshly as I was until the movie had been playing for about an hour and NOTHING HAD HAPPENED! The only event that had occurred, excluding the painfully boring exposition, was the little girl chasing the naked kid for 40 seconds or so only to lose him in his little boat. I kept holding on hoping something, anything, would happen, but it never really did. This is literally how the movie ends: The little girl's family , for no reason, starts believing her about the little boy so they go out in the storm to find him. They walk outside their newly repaired house and the girl yells "Look!" We then see the kid on the shore and when he sees his sister he tries to flee, perhaps horrified at his sister's acting ability. When he tries to get in his little boat some seals, bear with me, come onto the shore. One seal chases him away from his boat and the others push the boat into the water. The family captures him and that's the happy ending? Does that not seem, at best, extremely dumb to anyone else? I can maybe buy someone liking the cultural overtones of the movie or even the occasional whimsy, but who in their right mind could truly say that they were ENTERTAINED by this film? Maybe this movie just went over my head, but in order for me to enjoy a movie i would need a few events to occur and maybe a plot or something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evocative, somewhat slow - an excellent children's film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While seeming to aim for the sense of mystery of 'Picnic at Hanging Rock', 'Roan Inish' never rises above the level of a strong TV drama. The problem isn't the central performance of Jeni Courtney as Fiona, which is outstandingly good, or the rest of the cast who must have frozen their assets impressively filming the lives of poor fishermen on the East Atlantic foreshore. More power to them. The kid playing the lost boy Jamie, Cillian Byrne (who didn't trouble the costume department), is also amazing, the way he (apparently) steers that floating cradle; and the scene with the seal and him having 'tea' is tremendous. But essentially this is a children's film, a sort of 'Railway Children' with Irish pipes and seals. Lots of Irish pipes. Lots of seals. Lots of seagulls. Lots of cold-looking water and rowboats. Lots of beaches, grass and flowers. Yet more Irish music. The only real suspense is whether there's a happy ending or not, which I won't give away, but no-one ever doubts that Fiona's story of what she has seen is true. Fair enough, they're simple people who believe in faery folk, but it all seems a bit cut-and-dried in the end. At the beginning, there's too much exposition from blarney-gushing Oirish characters, the late middle segue sequence goes on a bit too long and the pacing tends to slow up towards the end. But it's a genuine, well-made, innocent sort of film that you can safely let your smallest kids watch. The sort of film to rent at Xmas, or Easter. Especially if there's any Irish in you, or you particularly like seals. Much better than 'Ryan's Daughter', btw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cosmoeticadotcom (cosmoetica@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If John Sayles, the independent American filmmaker, is not the greatest director in the history of the medium, he certainly has to be considered among the most daring and diverse filmmakers ever. From tales set in America's past (Matewan), to yuppy dramadies (The Return Of The Secaucus Seven), to urban social satires (The Brother From Another Planet), to more modern looks at American life (Sunshine State, Lone Star, Casa De Los Babys), Sayles has shown a desire to explore things no other filmmaker has. And while he does not have a distinctive look nor style, each of films is well wrought, and a worthy addition to world cinema. One of his most daring films was actually one of his most popular and financially successful- 1995's Irish fantasy film, The Secret Of Roan Inish. OK, let me rephrase- to call The Secret Of Roan Inish a fantasy film- even if Sayles adapted the screenplay from a 1957 children's book (The Secret Of Ron Mor Skerry) by Rosalie K. Fry, is to sell it short. It is a very sly and deep look at childhood and the loneliness that accompanies such. In this way, it is very much in league with such other explorations of early childhood loneliness as Val Lewton's 1944 film The Curse Of The Cat People and 1968's Godzilla's Revenge. It is also very much a great family film along the lines of October Sky and My Dog Skip. It is also very much a mythic film. That term is often overused to describe films that deal with 'epic' characters or situations, but that sort of description and film too often wallows in the pseudo-babble of faux intellectuals like Joseph Campbell. This film succeeds by using the exact opposite tack- it presents the film very much from a child's eye point of view, that of its lead character Fiona Coneely (Jeni Courtney)- a cute ten year old blond girl who goes to live with her grandparents after World War Two, because her mother has died, and her father has had to go off to Scotland to find work. The film did only mediocre at the box office, but that's because it is a terrific and deep film that never condescends. It is a children's film sans explosions and wiseass children, and explodes the idea that films aimed at children need be lesser versions of their adult counterparts. In fact, they have a greater charge- to appeal to kids as well as adults, and on both levels. Children's films, in fact, should have more ideas crammed into them as children can absorb more and learn from them without the biases and fears that a typical adult has acquired. The film runs a crisp hour and forty-three minutes, and not a second is wasted. The only quibble one might have with the film is its title. It really should have been called The Secrets (plural) Of Roan Inish, for more than the secret of Jamie's fate is involved. Yet, the flaws in this film are very minor- such as Fiona's repeated inability to outwit her wild child brother, compared to the film's virtues- almost all else. The Secret Of Roan Inish is one of Sayles' best films, and arguably a great film in its own right. That this film did what it did with so little shows that true creativity thrives no matter what its source of nourishment is, and that when that creativity is a product of John Sayles' mind, it's likely to be something well beyond the norm.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intersection of Nature and Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pierotti@ku.edu)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the most emotionally satisfying film John Sayles has ever made, which tops a long and excellent list. Working with a virtually unknown Irish cast, Sayles brings to life a story that wanders on the borderland between mystical and blue-collar realism, without becoming cloying or simplistic. The only film to which i think Roan Inish can be effectively compared is Whale Rider, but with no insult intended to Whale Rider, to me Roan Inish is a richer and more complex film. The basic story concerns the relationship between humans and non-humans and how long- standing relationships between species can be torn apart by world events; in this case the Second World War, which forces a community of Irish fisherfolk to relocate to the mainland. A young girl, whose family has been damaged through these actions and other forces, is sent to live with her grandparents on the coast, at which point her nonhuman relatives contrive to bring her and her family back to the home they once shared with other life forms. The little girl, Fiona, who is the primary human character, played by Jenny Courtney, is wonderfully written and played. She is not your standard cutie-pie, but a budding force of nature. It is obvious why of all the members of her family, the nonhumans single her out for their attention. The story is drawn from the traditional Irish and Scots stories of relationships between humans and seals, or selchies, but transposes this into a more modern setting, without losing any of the mystery or wonder. One of the strongest recommendations I can give this film is that has become one of the most popular and respected films at Haskell Indian Nations University here in Kansas. Indigenous Americans seem to identify with the experience of the Irish, which shows them that modern European culture has been destructive to Indigenous peoples in Europe, and allows them to realize that there have been and continue to be, Indigenous people with distinct cultures in Europe as well as the Americas. I was once in a video store, when a person I knew slightly asked me if I could recommend a film that would appeal both to him and his children. Without hesitation I went over and picked up the store's copy of Roan Inish, and told him, "Not only will you enjoy this, but it will give you and your kids a lot to think and talk about." I make the same recommendation to anyone who reads this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanmarkel
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people would label this a children's movie...and yet, it has all the mystery and beauty that accompanies films for adults who love poetry and traditional storytelling and classic literature. Watch this film, and you'll get a good idea of Irish tradition and life and their constant belief in legend and lore, which has made them into the wonderful and strong race that they are today. There is a deep sense of family...a truly strong family who has clearly had its ups and downs and yet has come out even stronger than before. A family that has been through generations of change, adapted, continues to change and yet still holds onto the traditions and stories along the way. Stories that others might assume are myth and faery tales. And stories that we know aren't anything but the truth woven into a magical tale. In most Irish tales and legends I've read, there is a quest which keeps the main character(s) pushing forward through all the challenges of life. Fiona's store in this movie is no different. She's a little girl lost at the beginning when we meet her, wandering through the smog of the city to find some way to latch onto her father who is lost and sad with grief over a dead wife and a dead and missing baby boy. Her true quest begins when she is sent to live with her grandparents who still live by the sea. And the quest truly becomes a quest when she learns that her baby brother Jamie has been spotted on Roan Inish, the Island of the Seals where her family originated from. The music weaves itself around the characters and the story to make it more complete than it would be without it. It is both peaceful and stirring, providing the background for the cultural ear. With the music and the intricate storytelling, one can become truly lost in this story. And truly a part of it. If I had children, this is one movie I would have them watch over and over again. Like Disney's "Darby O'Gill and the Little People," this is a movie to entertain children of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Music to my fears
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much like "The Secret Garden", this is a film about the unlikely combination of everyday reality and pure magic. The character of Fiona (played by Jeni Courtney) is like every free and beautiful little girl that you've ever encountered rolled into one. She has such a wonderful outlook on life; honest and serious, faithful and fanciful. This is an improbable film for director John Sayles, an American filmmaker who usually sticks much closer to home. More pleasing still is the fact that he takes an honest, unfiltered view of the Irish culture that is so intrinsic to the story being told. "The Secret of Roan Inish" is about storytelling, from an inner and outer perspective. Each character is deeply concerned with sharing his or her own tale or take on local folklore. The script takes all sorts of beautiful sidelines into the tales of Fiona's relatives and anyone else who happens to pass by. Particularly fascinating is the performance of John Lynch, whose character tells the legend of the Selkie (played by his sister, Susan Lynch). The images of the seal woman are breathtaking, painful in their uncertain waking beauty. The final result of the film is something between the purity of childhood and the trust of self. I was taken in not only by the overwhelming sense of the unknown, but by everything fearful and wonderful in the making known of the same. This is one of the most enrapturing motion pictures I've ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celtic crowd pleaser masquerading as edgy indie art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The older the fiddle, the sweeter the tune." - Irish proverb Part of cinema's "Irish boom" in the lead up to the Anglo-Irish ceasefires, "The Secret of Roan Inish" is a low key, fairly unassuming piece of fantasy by director John Sales, notable mostly for some good cinematography by the legendary Haskell Wexler. Like all of these films ("Waking Ned Devine", "Far and Away", "Riverdance" etc), "The Secret of Roan Inish" exemplifies what writer Natasha Casey calls "Cletic commodification", reducing Ireland and Irishness to "Celtic myths", quaint, pre-modern, rural landscapes, and a depiction of the nation as being forever pre-colonised. Unsurprisingly, the film was widely distributed in America and Britian (since John Ford, "Irishness" has always been used as a vehicle to allow white audiences to role-play being white minorities/victims), but only had a limited release in Ireland. Its pastoral, regressive image of Irish society is more commercially viable outside of its home territory. The film is often touted as being Sayles' only non-political film, but this isn't true. Its tales of when "man and beast lived side-by-side, sharing the sea", of "monsters shedding their past skins", of a little girl's self determination and slow journey back to her roots, are designed specifically for the Irish diaspora. It's a call for a people to return to their homes and live alongside the now tamed beasts of Old England. "Everyone wants to march into the future," one haggard Irish character says, mourning about how his country "just got left behind." But the film's solution is to avoid modernization and to delve deeper into the past; a regression into some mythical "pure origins", a move backward to re-establish a pre-colonial Ireland. This is not surprising. The grand narrative of a society moving from the pre-modern to the modern to the post-modern, breaks down in Ireland. After the Anglo-Irish and Civil wars, as well as hundreds of years of struggle, the Irish were concerned with maintaining the nationalist cultural identity that they were finally free to express in their self-governance. But what Sayles' film does is advocate delving into the "rich identity of Ireland's past", whilst serving up only Disneyland trinkets. It's the condescending David Lean view of Ireland; the art house equivalent of a Lucky Charms cereal box. So it's not only that the film fails to give a genuine ideology of contemporary Ireland, or that it chooses an escape to the past instead of clarifying historical events, but that it pretends to be about "identity" when actually it's relying on mythology in order to avoid questions of authenticity (or the impossibility thereof). Ironically, with the Irish film industry in ruins, "Irishness" has increasingly become a sort of "viscious circle", foreigners projecting "Irishness" onto a country who must now parrot (and export) such cosy, plastic "Irishness" in their own art if they hope to garner international attention. Sayles is unwittingly participating here in the kind of damaging, bottled-tourism and cultural kitsch that he denounces so well in "Limbo" and "Sunshine State". Ignoring these issues, the film works fairly well as a children's fantasy, though I suspect most kids and adults will find "Roan Inish" too plain and too slow. Compare the film to Victor Erice's "The Spirit of the Beehive", a masterpiece which, like "Roan Inish", merges history, myth and childhood. 7/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quiet gem of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Momcat_of_Lomita
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a rare movie: one that can hold the attention of adults while at the same time keeping children entranced. That said, I have to add: this is not a movie for very young kids, who will not understand the mythology involved or "get" the plot. It is also not a film for people who are looking for a lot of action, special effects, cornball humor or over-the-top near-hysterical acting. It's a movie that works quietly for its effects. The first thing I have to comment on is the beautiful setting of the film and the photography. The setting is the west coast of Ireland, in a small fishing village, and on the sea and the land around the village. I believe "Secret" is as successful at conveying the rugged beauty of this landscape and seascape as any movie made. No tricks, no special effects, just the beauty of a place that has a lot of history and mythology associated with it. The actors and actresses in this film are not big names and not well-known, and I would say that this is a movie that is more story-driven than character-driven. At the same time, the lack of "name" actors or big bravura performances works to the advantage of the film, in that the personalities of the actors are submerged in the plot. There is a lot of kindness in this film, and a sense of the people being really connected to one another and caring for and about each other, and about the land and time they live in. That's one of the things that I loved about this film: there are no real villains, nothing evil. Nobody is considered stupid or demeaned in any way. And yet there is a tension to the story, and a move towards resolution of a history that had sadness and tragedy in a way that is literally magical. I loved this movie and I recommend it to anyone who can enjoy a movie that isn't big on action, that doesn't try to do more than tell a story in a way that's thoughtful and beautiful and makes you wish that you could find that kind of magic in your own life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Family values" in the best sense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Screen-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a true family film -- for and about families. Except for very small children (who might get bored) this film is has something for all ages. The actors -- both young and old, animal and human -- are excellent. The story-line is interesting for children but complex enough for adults. It's as beautiful as most "art movies" but as plot-driven as a Hollywood movie, again making it appealing to a broad range of people. It's non-offensive but not at all cloying like some family movies. (Well, unless you're offended by drinking or toddler nudity.) It's magical and mythic but still rooted in characters that seem believable. It also has interesting rural Irish culture which, I assume is accurate. My wife and I saw this movie in the theater before we had children and we now watch it with our kids on DVD. I've seen it three or four times and I'm still not tired of it! The only possible downside I can think of are the fairly thick Irish accents. I have no problem understanding but some people might.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Burin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the soundtrack to Tarantino's Kill Bill, Vol. 1, rapper RZA dedicates his witless contribution to character O-Ren Ishii, "half-Chinese, half-Japanese-ie". Well this review is dedicated in its entirety to the isle of Roan Inish, all Irish, no Japan-inish. John Sayles has spent most of his stellar career as a writer-director documenting the making of modern America: with the searing, masterfully-woven race relations dramas Lone Star and Sunshine State and the classic coming-of-age film Baby It's You, which doubles as a portrait of the immigrant experience. This change-of-pace outing finds him amidst the myths and mysteries of rural Ireland, where a 10-year-old girl is hunting for the baby brother who was swept to sea when her family evacuated its remote island home. The film builds slowly, mesmerisingly towards a cathartic act of mercy, incorporating several nuanced diversions which either bolster the narrative or flesh out its highly evocative portrait of a sea-faring community. Medium Cool director Haskell Wexler's lustrous cinematography and a soundtrack of Celtic folk songs add to the very special atmosphere, while the sensitive performances remain doggedly unsentimental, young Jeni Courtney representing the movie's poetic but earthy sensibility as the resourceful, single-minded heroine. Meanwhile, Sayles' unmatched ear for dialogue is as attuned as ever, his empathy for the characters reinforced by inventive direction that sees the world from Courtney's height for its first five minutes. Roan Inish is a tender, affecting and ultimately magical film - and one of the best few I'll see this year. RZA was unavailable for comment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing Happened!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cooperreynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just finished watching this movie and immediately went online to see just how terrible the reviews were only to see it has a 97% on rotten tomatoes upwards of 7 out of 10 on IMDb. Shocked by this I filled out the required information just to write this one review. This film struck me as borderline unwatchable. The child acting is on par The Phantom Menace. The little girl is cute, but good lord it was just embarrassing to watch. I kept telling myself it had to be intended as a children's movie and I was being unfair to assess it as harshly as I was until the movie had been playing for about an hour and NOTHING HAD HAPPENED! The only event that had occurred, excluding the painfully boring exposition, was the little girl chasing the naked kid for 40 seconds or so only to lose him in his little boat. I kept holding on hoping something, anything, would happen, but it never really did. This is literally how the movie ends: The little girl's family , for no reason, starts believing her about the little boy so they go out in the storm to find him. They walk outside their newly repaired house and the girl yells "Look!" We then see the kid on the shore and when he sees his sister he tries to flee, perhaps horrified at his sister's acting ability. When he tries to get in his little boat some seals, bear with me, come onto the shore. One seal chases him away from his boat and the others push the boat into the water. The family captures him and that's the happy ending? Does that not seem, at best, extremely dumb to anyone else? I can maybe buy someone liking the cultural overtones of the movie or even the occasional whimsy, but who in their right mind could truly say that they were ENTERTAINED by this film? Maybe this movie just went over my head, but in order for me to enjoy a movie i would need a few events to occur and maybe a plot or something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evocative, somewhat slow - an excellent children's film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While seeming to aim for the sense of mystery of 'Picnic at Hanging Rock', 'Roan Inish' never rises above the level of a strong TV drama. The problem isn't the central performance of Jeni Courtney as Fiona, which is outstandingly good, or the rest of the cast who must have frozen their assets impressively filming the lives of poor fishermen on the East Atlantic foreshore. More power to them. The kid playing the lost boy Jamie, Cillian Byrne (who didn't trouble the costume department), is also amazing, the way he (apparently) steers that floating cradle; and the scene with the seal and him having 'tea' is tremendous. But essentially this is a children's film, a sort of 'Railway Children' with Irish pipes and seals. Lots of Irish pipes. Lots of seals. Lots of seagulls. Lots of cold-looking water and rowboats. Lots of beaches, grass and flowers. Yet more Irish music. The only real suspense is whether there's a happy ending or not, which I won't give away, but no-one ever doubts that Fiona's story of what she has seen is true. Fair enough, they're simple people who believe in faery folk, but it all seems a bit cut-and-dried in the end. At the beginning, there's too much exposition from blarney-gushing Oirish characters, the late middle segue sequence goes on a bit too long and the pacing tends to slow up towards the end. But it's a genuine, well-made, innocent sort of film that you can safely let your smallest kids watch. The sort of film to rent at Xmas, or Easter. Especially if there's any Irish in you, or you particularly like seals. Much better than 'Ryan's Daughter', btw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cosmoeticadotcom (cosmoetica@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If John Sayles, the independent American filmmaker, is not the greatest director in the history of the medium, he certainly has to be considered among the most daring and diverse filmmakers ever. From tales set in America's past (Matewan), to yuppy dramadies (The Return Of The Secaucus Seven), to urban social satires (The Brother From Another Planet), to more modern looks at American life (Sunshine State, Lone Star, Casa De Los Babys), Sayles has shown a desire to explore things no other filmmaker has. And while he does not have a distinctive look nor style, each of films is well wrought, and a worthy addition to world cinema. One of his most daring films was actually one of his most popular and financially successful- 1995's Irish fantasy film, The Secret Of Roan Inish. OK, let me rephrase- to call The Secret Of Roan Inish a fantasy film- even if Sayles adapted the screenplay from a 1957 children's book (The Secret Of Ron Mor Skerry) by Rosalie K. Fry, is to sell it short. It is a very sly and deep look at childhood and the loneliness that accompanies such. In this way, it is very much in league with such other explorations of early childhood loneliness as Val Lewton's 1944 film The Curse Of The Cat People and 1968's Godzilla's Revenge. It is also very much a great family film along the lines of October Sky and My Dog Skip. It is also very much a mythic film. That term is often overused to describe films that deal with 'epic' characters or situations, but that sort of description and film too often wallows in the pseudo-babble of faux intellectuals like Joseph Campbell. This film succeeds by using the exact opposite tack- it presents the film very much from a child's eye point of view, that of its lead character Fiona Coneely (Jeni Courtney)- a cute ten year old blond girl who goes to live with her grandparents after World War Two, because her mother has died, and her father has had to go off to Scotland to find work. The film did only mediocre at the box office, but that's because it is a terrific and deep film that never condescends. It is a children's film sans explosions and wiseass children, and explodes the idea that films aimed at children need be lesser versions of their adult counterparts. In fact, they have a greater charge- to appeal to kids as well as adults, and on both levels. Children's films, in fact, should have more ideas crammed into them as children can absorb more and learn from them without the biases and fears that a typical adult has acquired. The film runs a crisp hour and forty-three minutes, and not a second is wasted. The only quibble one might have with the film is its title. It really should have been called The Secrets (plural) Of Roan Inish, for more than the secret of Jamie's fate is involved. Yet, the flaws in this film are very minor- such as Fiona's repeated inability to outwit her wild child brother, compared to the film's virtues- almost all else. The Secret Of Roan Inish is one of Sayles' best films, and arguably a great film in its own right. That this film did what it did with so little shows that true creativity thrives no matter what its source of nourishment is, and that when that creativity is a product of John Sayles' mind, it's likely to be something well beyond the norm.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intersection of Nature and Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pierotti@ku.edu)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the most emotionally satisfying film John Sayles has ever made, which tops a long and excellent list. Working with a virtually unknown Irish cast, Sayles brings to life a story that wanders on the borderland between mystical and blue-collar realism, without becoming cloying or simplistic. The only film to which i think Roan Inish can be effectively compared is Whale Rider, but with no insult intended to Whale Rider, to me Roan Inish is a richer and more complex film. The basic story concerns the relationship between humans and non-humans and how long- standing relationships between species can be torn apart by world events; in this case the Second World War, which forces a community of Irish fisherfolk to relocate to the mainland. A young girl, whose family has been damaged through these actions and other forces, is sent to live with her grandparents on the coast, at which point her nonhuman relatives contrive to bring her and her family back to the home they once shared with other life forms. The little girl, Fiona, who is the primary human character, played by Jenny Courtney, is wonderfully written and played. She is not your standard cutie-pie, but a budding force of nature. It is obvious why of all the members of her family, the nonhumans single her out for their attention. The story is drawn from the traditional Irish and Scots stories of relationships between humans and seals, or selchies, but transposes this into a more modern setting, without losing any of the mystery or wonder. One of the strongest recommendations I can give this film is that has become one of the most popular and respected films at Haskell Indian Nations University here in Kansas. Indigenous Americans seem to identify with the experience of the Irish, which shows them that modern European culture has been destructive to Indigenous peoples in Europe, and allows them to realize that there have been and continue to be, Indigenous people with distinct cultures in Europe as well as the Americas. I was once in a video store, when a person I knew slightly asked me if I could recommend a film that would appeal both to him and his children. Without hesitation I went over and picked up the store's copy of Roan Inish, and told him, "Not only will you enjoy this, but it will give you and your kids a lot to think and talk about." I make the same recommendation to anyone who reads this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanmarkel
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people would label this a children's movie...and yet, it has all the mystery and beauty that accompanies films for adults who love poetry and traditional storytelling and classic literature. Watch this film, and you'll get a good idea of Irish tradition and life and their constant belief in legend and lore, which has made them into the wonderful and strong race that they are today. There is a deep sense of family...a truly strong family who has clearly had its ups and downs and yet has come out even stronger than before. A family that has been through generations of change, adapted, continues to change and yet still holds onto the traditions and stories along the way. Stories that others might assume are myth and faery tales. And stories that we know aren't anything but the truth woven into a magical tale. In most Irish tales and legends I've read, there is a quest which keeps the main character(s) pushing forward through all the challenges of life. Fiona's store in this movie is no different. She's a little girl lost at the beginning when we meet her, wandering through the smog of the city to find some way to latch onto her father who is lost and sad with grief over a dead wife and a dead and missing baby boy. Her true quest begins when she is sent to live with her grandparents who still live by the sea. And the quest truly becomes a quest when she learns that her baby brother Jamie has been spotted on Roan Inish, the Island of the Seals where her family originated from. The music weaves itself around the characters and the story to make it more complete than it would be without it. It is both peaceful and stirring, providing the background for the cultural ear. With the music and the intricate storytelling, one can become truly lost in this story. And truly a part of it. If I had children, this is one movie I would have them watch over and over again. Like Disney's "Darby O'Gill and the Little People," this is a movie to entertain children of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Music to my fears
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much like "The Secret Garden", this is a film about the unlikely combination of everyday reality and pure magic. The character of Fiona (played by Jeni Courtney) is like every free and beautiful little girl that you've ever encountered rolled into one. She has such a wonderful outlook on life; honest and serious, faithful and fanciful. This is an improbable film for director John Sayles, an American filmmaker who usually sticks much closer to home. More pleasing still is the fact that he takes an honest, unfiltered view of the Irish culture that is so intrinsic to the story being told. "The Secret of Roan Inish" is about storytelling, from an inner and outer perspective. Each character is deeply concerned with sharing his or her own tale or take on local folklore. The script takes all sorts of beautiful sidelines into the tales of Fiona's relatives and anyone else who happens to pass by. Particularly fascinating is the performance of John Lynch, whose character tells the legend of the Selkie (played by his sister, Susan Lynch). The images of the seal woman are breathtaking, painful in their uncertain waking beauty. The final result of the film is something between the purity of childhood and the trust of self. I was taken in not only by the overwhelming sense of the unknown, but by everything fearful and wonderful in the making known of the same. This is one of the most enrapturing motion pictures I've ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celtic crowd pleaser masquerading as edgy indie art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The older the fiddle, the sweeter the tune." - Irish proverb Part of cinema's "Irish boom" in the lead up to the Anglo-Irish ceasefires, "The Secret of Roan Inish" is a low key, fairly unassuming piece of fantasy by director John Sales, notable mostly for some good cinematography by the legendary Haskell Wexler. Like all of these films ("Waking Ned Devine", "Far and Away", "Riverdance" etc), "The Secret of Roan Inish" exemplifies what writer Natasha Casey calls "Cletic commodification", reducing Ireland and Irishness to "Celtic myths", quaint, pre-modern, rural landscapes, and a depiction of the nation as being forever pre-colonised. Unsurprisingly, the film was widely distributed in America and Britian (since John Ford, "Irishness" has always been used as a vehicle to allow white audiences to role-play being white minorities/victims), but only had a limited release in Ireland. Its pastoral, regressive image of Irish society is more commercially viable outside of its home territory. The film is often touted as being Sayles' only non-political film, but this isn't true. Its tales of when "man and beast lived side-by-side, sharing the sea", of "monsters shedding their past skins", of a little girl's self determination and slow journey back to her roots, are designed specifically for the Irish diaspora. It's a call for a people to return to their homes and live alongside the now tamed beasts of Old England. "Everyone wants to march into the future," one haggard Irish character says, mourning about how his country "just got left behind." But the film's solution is to avoid modernization and to delve deeper into the past; a regression into some mythical "pure origins", a move backward to re-establish a pre-colonial Ireland. This is not surprising. The grand narrative of a society moving from the pre-modern to the modern to the post-modern, breaks down in Ireland. After the Anglo-Irish and Civil wars, as well as hundreds of years of struggle, the Irish were concerned with maintaining the nationalist cultural identity that they were finally free to express in their self-governance. But what Sayles' film does is advocate delving into the "rich identity of Ireland's past", whilst serving up only Disneyland trinkets. It's the condescending David Lean view of Ireland; the art house equivalent of a Lucky Charms cereal box. So it's not only that the film fails to give a genuine ideology of contemporary Ireland, or that it chooses an escape to the past instead of clarifying historical events, but that it pretends to be about "identity" when actually it's relying on mythology in order to avoid questions of authenticity (or the impossibility thereof). Ironically, with the Irish film industry in ruins, "Irishness" has increasingly become a sort of "viscious circle", foreigners projecting "Irishness" onto a country who must now parrot (and export) such cosy, plastic "Irishness" in their own art if they hope to garner international attention. Sayles is unwittingly participating here in the kind of damaging, bottled-tourism and cultural kitsch that he denounces so well in "Limbo" and "Sunshine State". Ignoring these issues, the film works fairly well as a children's fantasy, though I suspect most kids and adults will find "Roan Inish" too plain and too slow. Compare the film to Victor Erice's "The Spirit of the Beehive", a masterpiece which, like "Roan Inish", merges history, myth and childhood. 7/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quiet gem of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Momcat_of_Lomita
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a rare movie: one that can hold the attention of adults while at the same time keeping children entranced. That said, I have to add: this is not a movie for very young kids, who will not understand the mythology involved or "get" the plot. It is also not a film for people who are looking for a lot of action, special effects, cornball humor or over-the-top near-hysterical acting. It's a movie that works quietly for its effects. The first thing I have to comment on is the beautiful setting of the film and the photography. The setting is the west coast of Ireland, in a small fishing village, and on the sea and the land around the village. I believe "Secret" is as successful at conveying the rugged beauty of this landscape and seascape as any movie made. No tricks, no special effects, just the beauty of a place that has a lot of history and mythology associated with it. The actors and actresses in this film are not big names and not well-known, and I would say that this is a movie that is more story-driven than character-driven. At the same time, the lack of "name" actors or big bravura performances works to the advantage of the film, in that the personalities of the actors are submerged in the plot. There is a lot of kindness in this film, and a sense of the people being really connected to one another and caring for and about each other, and about the land and time they live in. That's one of the things that I loved about this film: there are no real villains, nothing evil. Nobody is considered stupid or demeaned in any way. And yet there is a tension to the story, and a move towards resolution of a history that had sadness and tragedy in a way that is literally magical. I loved this movie and I recommend it to anyone who can enjoy a movie that isn't big on action, that doesn't try to do more than tell a story in a way that's thoughtful and beautiful and makes you wish that you could find that kind of magic in your own life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Family values" in the best sense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Screen-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a true family film -- for and about families. Except for very small children (who might get bored) this film is has something for all ages. The actors -- both young and old, animal and human -- are excellent. The story-line is interesting for children but complex enough for adults. It's as beautiful as most "art movies" but as plot-driven as a Hollywood movie, again making it appealing to a broad range of people. It's non-offensive but not at all cloying like some family movies. (Well, unless you're offended by drinking or toddler nudity.) It's magical and mythic but still rooted in characters that seem believable. It also has interesting rural Irish culture which, I assume is accurate. My wife and I saw this movie in the theater before we had children and we now watch it with our kids on DVD. I've seen it three or four times and I'm still not tired of it! The only possible downside I can think of are the fairly thick Irish accents. I have no problem understanding but some people might.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Burin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the soundtrack to Tarantino's Kill Bill, Vol. 1, rapper RZA dedicates his witless contribution to character O-Ren Ishii, "half-Chinese, half-Japanese-ie". Well this review is dedicated in its entirety to the isle of Roan Inish, all Irish, no Japan-inish. John Sayles has spent most of his stellar career as a writer-director documenting the making of modern America: with the searing, masterfully-woven race relations dramas Lone Star and Sunshine State and the classic coming-of-age film Baby It's You, which doubles as a portrait of the immigrant experience. This change-of-pace outing finds him amidst the myths and mysteries of rural Ireland, where a 10-year-old girl is hunting for the baby brother who was swept to sea when her family evacuated its remote island home. The film builds slowly, mesmerisingly towards a cathartic act of mercy, incorporating several nuanced diversions which either bolster the narrative or flesh out its highly evocative portrait of a sea-faring community. Medium Cool director Haskell Wexler's lustrous cinematography and a soundtrack of Celtic folk songs add to the very special atmosphere, while the sensitive performances remain doggedly unsentimental, young Jeni Courtney representing the movie's poetic but earthy sensibility as the resourceful, single-minded heroine. Meanwhile, Sayles' unmatched ear for dialogue is as attuned as ever, his empathy for the characters reinforced by inventive direction that sees the world from Courtney's height for its first five minutes. Roan Inish is a tender, affecting and ultimately magical film - and one of the best few I'll see this year. RZA was unavailable for comment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing Happened!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cooperreynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just finished watching this movie and immediately went online to see just how terrible the reviews were only to see it has a 97% on rotten tomatoes upwards of 7 out of 10 on IMDb. Shocked by this I filled out the required information just to write this one review. This film struck me as borderline unwatchable. The child acting is on par The Phantom Menace. The little girl is cute, but good lord it was just embarrassing to watch. I kept telling myself it had to be intended as a children's movie and I was being unfair to assess it as harshly as I was until the movie had been playing for about an hour and NOTHING HAD HAPPENED! The only event that had occurred, excluding the painfully boring exposition, was the little girl chasing the naked kid for 40 seconds or so only to lose him in his little boat. I kept holding on hoping something, anything, would happen, but it never really did. This is literally how the movie ends: The little girl's family , for no reason, starts believing her about the little boy so they go out in the storm to find him. They walk outside their newly repaired house and the girl yells "Look!" We then see the kid on the shore and when he sees his sister he tries to flee, perhaps horrified at his sister's acting ability. When he tries to get in his little boat some seals, bear with me, come onto the shore. One seal chases him away from his boat and the others push the boat into the water. The family captures him and that's the happy ending? Does that not seem, at best, extremely dumb to anyone else? I can maybe buy someone liking the cultural overtones of the movie or even the occasional whimsy, but who in their right mind could truly say that they were ENTERTAINED by this film? Maybe this movie just went over my head, but in order for me to enjoy a movie i would need a few events to occur and maybe a plot or something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evocative, somewhat slow - an excellent children's film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While seeming to aim for the sense of mystery of 'Picnic at Hanging Rock', 'Roan Inish' never rises above the level of a strong TV drama. The problem isn't the central performance of Jeni Courtney as Fiona, which is outstandingly good, or the rest of the cast who must have frozen their assets impressively filming the lives of poor fishermen on the East Atlantic foreshore. More power to them. The kid playing the lost boy Jamie, Cillian Byrne (who didn't trouble the costume department), is also amazing, the way he (apparently) steers that floating cradle; and the scene with the seal and him having 'tea' is tremendous. But essentially this is a children's film, a sort of 'Railway Children' with Irish pipes and seals. Lots of Irish pipes. Lots of seals. Lots of seagulls. Lots of cold-looking water and rowboats. Lots of beaches, grass and flowers. Yet more Irish music. The only real suspense is whether there's a happy ending or not, which I won't give away, but no-one ever doubts that Fiona's story of what she has seen is true. Fair enough, they're simple people who believe in faery folk, but it all seems a bit cut-and-dried in the end. At the beginning, there's too much exposition from blarney-gushing Oirish characters, the late middle segue sequence goes on a bit too long and the pacing tends to slow up towards the end. But it's a genuine, well-made, innocent sort of film that you can safely let your smallest kids watch. The sort of film to rent at Xmas, or Easter. Especially if there's any Irish in you, or you particularly like seals. Much better than 'Ryan's Daughter', btw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cosmoeticadotcom (cosmoetica@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If John Sayles, the independent American filmmaker, is not the greatest director in the history of the medium, he certainly has to be considered among the most daring and diverse filmmakers ever. From tales set in America's past (Matewan), to yuppy dramadies (The Return Of The Secaucus Seven), to urban social satires (The Brother From Another Planet), to more modern looks at American life (Sunshine State, Lone Star, Casa De Los Babys), Sayles has shown a desire to explore things no other filmmaker has. And while he does not have a distinctive look nor style, each of films is well wrought, and a worthy addition to world cinema. One of his most daring films was actually one of his most popular and financially successful- 1995's Irish fantasy film, The Secret Of Roan Inish. OK, let me rephrase- to call The Secret Of Roan Inish a fantasy film- even if Sayles adapted the screenplay from a 1957 children's book (The Secret Of Ron Mor Skerry) by Rosalie K. Fry, is to sell it short. It is a very sly and deep look at childhood and the loneliness that accompanies such. In this way, it is very much in league with such other explorations of early childhood loneliness as Val Lewton's 1944 film The Curse Of The Cat People and 1968's Godzilla's Revenge. It is also very much a great family film along the lines of October Sky and My Dog Skip. It is also very much a mythic film. That term is often overused to describe films that deal with 'epic' characters or situations, but that sort of description and film too often wallows in the pseudo-babble of faux intellectuals like Joseph Campbell. This film succeeds by using the exact opposite tack- it presents the film very much from a child's eye point of view, that of its lead character Fiona Coneely (Jeni Courtney)- a cute ten year old blond girl who goes to live with her grandparents after World War Two, because her mother has died, and her father has had to go off to Scotland to find work. The film did only mediocre at the box office, but that's because it is a terrific and deep film that never condescends. It is a children's film sans explosions and wiseass children, and explodes the idea that films aimed at children need be lesser versions of their adult counterparts. In fact, they have a greater charge- to appeal to kids as well as adults, and on both levels. Children's films, in fact, should have more ideas crammed into them as children can absorb more and learn from them without the biases and fears that a typical adult has acquired. The film runs a crisp hour and forty-three minutes, and not a second is wasted. The only quibble one might have with the film is its title. It really should have been called The Secrets (plural) Of Roan Inish, for more than the secret of Jamie's fate is involved. Yet, the flaws in this film are very minor- such as Fiona's repeated inability to outwit her wild child brother, compared to the film's virtues- almost all else. The Secret Of Roan Inish is one of Sayles' best films, and arguably a great film in its own right. That this film did what it did with so little shows that true creativity thrives no matter what its source of nourishment is, and that when that creativity is a product of John Sayles' mind, it's likely to be something well beyond the norm.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intersection of Nature and Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pierotti@ku.edu)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the most emotionally satisfying film John Sayles has ever made, which tops a long and excellent list. Working with a virtually unknown Irish cast, Sayles brings to life a story that wanders on the borderland between mystical and blue-collar realism, without becoming cloying or simplistic. The only film to which i think Roan Inish can be effectively compared is Whale Rider, but with no insult intended to Whale Rider, to me Roan Inish is a richer and more complex film. The basic story concerns the relationship between humans and non-humans and how long- standing relationships between species can be torn apart by world events; in this case the Second World War, which forces a community of Irish fisherfolk to relocate to the mainland. A young girl, whose family has been damaged through these actions and other forces, is sent to live with her grandparents on the coast, at which point her nonhuman relatives contrive to bring her and her family back to the home they once shared with other life forms. The little girl, Fiona, who is the primary human character, played by Jenny Courtney, is wonderfully written and played. She is not your standard cutie-pie, but a budding force of nature. It is obvious why of all the members of her family, the nonhumans single her out for their attention. The story is drawn from the traditional Irish and Scots stories of relationships between humans and seals, or selchies, but transposes this into a more modern setting, without losing any of the mystery or wonder. One of the strongest recommendations I can give this film is that has become one of the most popular and respected films at Haskell Indian Nations University here in Kansas. Indigenous Americans seem to identify with the experience of the Irish, which shows them that modern European culture has been destructive to Indigenous peoples in Europe, and allows them to realize that there have been and continue to be, Indigenous people with distinct cultures in Europe as well as the Americas. I was once in a video store, when a person I knew slightly asked me if I could recommend a film that would appeal both to him and his children. Without hesitation I went over and picked up the store's copy of Roan Inish, and told him, "Not only will you enjoy this, but it will give you and your kids a lot to think and talk about." I make the same recommendation to anyone who reads this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanmarkel
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people would label this a children's movie...and yet, it has all the mystery and beauty that accompanies films for adults who love poetry and traditional storytelling and classic literature. Watch this film, and you'll get a good idea of Irish tradition and life and their constant belief in legend and lore, which has made them into the wonderful and strong race that they are today. There is a deep sense of family...a truly strong family who has clearly had its ups and downs and yet has come out even stronger than before. A family that has been through generations of change, adapted, continues to change and yet still holds onto the traditions and stories along the way. Stories that others might assume are myth and faery tales. And stories that we know aren't anything but the truth woven into a magical tale. In most Irish tales and legends I've read, there is a quest which keeps the main character(s) pushing forward through all the challenges of life. Fiona's store in this movie is no different. She's a little girl lost at the beginning when we meet her, wandering through the smog of the city to find some way to latch onto her father who is lost and sad with grief over a dead wife and a dead and missing baby boy. Her true quest begins when she is sent to live with her grandparents who still live by the sea. And the quest truly becomes a quest when she learns that her baby brother Jamie has been spotted on Roan Inish, the Island of the Seals where her family originated from. The music weaves itself around the characters and the story to make it more complete than it would be without it. It is both peaceful and stirring, providing the background for the cultural ear. With the music and the intricate storytelling, one can become truly lost in this story. And truly a part of it. If I had children, this is one movie I would have them watch over and over again. Like Disney's "Darby O'Gill and the Little People," this is a movie to entertain children of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Music to my fears
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much like "The Secret Garden", this is a film about the unlikely combination of everyday reality and pure magic. The character of Fiona (played by Jeni Courtney) is like every free and beautiful little girl that you've ever encountered rolled into one. She has such a wonderful outlook on life; honest and serious, faithful and fanciful. This is an improbable film for director John Sayles, an American filmmaker who usually sticks much closer to home. More pleasing still is the fact that he takes an honest, unfiltered view of the Irish culture that is so intrinsic to the story being told. "The Secret of Roan Inish" is about storytelling, from an inner and outer perspective. Each character is deeply concerned with sharing his or her own tale or take on local folklore. The script takes all sorts of beautiful sidelines into the tales of Fiona's relatives and anyone else who happens to pass by. Particularly fascinating is the performance of John Lynch, whose character tells the legend of the Selkie (played by his sister, Susan Lynch). The images of the seal woman are breathtaking, painful in their uncertain waking beauty. The final result of the film is something between the purity of childhood and the trust of self. I was taken in not only by the overwhelming sense of the unknown, but by everything fearful and wonderful in the making known of the same. This is one of the most enrapturing motion pictures I've ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celtic crowd pleaser masquerading as edgy indie art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The older the fiddle, the sweeter the tune." - Irish proverb Part of cinema's "Irish boom" in the lead up to the Anglo-Irish ceasefires, "The Secret of Roan Inish" is a low key, fairly unassuming piece of fantasy by director John Sales, notable mostly for some good cinematography by the legendary Haskell Wexler. Like all of these films ("Waking Ned Devine", "Far and Away", "Riverdance" etc), "The Secret of Roan Inish" exemplifies what writer Natasha Casey calls "Cletic commodification", reducing Ireland and Irishness to "Celtic myths", quaint, pre-modern, rural landscapes, and a depiction of the nation as being forever pre-colonised. Unsurprisingly, the film was widely distributed in America and Britian (since John Ford, "Irishness" has always been used as a vehicle to allow white audiences to role-play being white minorities/victims), but only had a limited release in Ireland. Its pastoral, regressive image of Irish society is more commercially viable outside of its home territory. The film is often touted as being Sayles' only non-political film, but this isn't true. Its tales of when "man and beast lived side-by-side, sharing the sea", of "monsters shedding their past skins", of a little girl's self determination and slow journey back to her roots, are designed specifically for the Irish diaspora. It's a call for a people to return to their homes and live alongside the now tamed beasts of Old England. "Everyone wants to march into the future," one haggard Irish character says, mourning about how his country "just got left behind." But the film's solution is to avoid modernization and to delve deeper into the past; a regression into some mythical "pure origins", a move backward to re-establish a pre-colonial Ireland. This is not surprising. The grand narrative of a society moving from the pre-modern to the modern to the post-modern, breaks down in Ireland. After the Anglo-Irish and Civil wars, as well as hundreds of years of struggle, the Irish were concerned with maintaining the nationalist cultural identity that they were finally free to express in their self-governance. But what Sayles' film does is advocate delving into the "rich identity of Ireland's past", whilst serving up only Disneyland trinkets. It's the condescending David Lean view of Ireland; the art house equivalent of a Lucky Charms cereal box. So it's not only that the film fails to give a genuine ideology of contemporary Ireland, or that it chooses an escape to the past instead of clarifying historical events, but that it pretends to be about "identity" when actually it's relying on mythology in order to avoid questions of authenticity (or the impossibility thereof). Ironically, with the Irish film industry in ruins, "Irishness" has increasingly become a sort of "viscious circle", foreigners projecting "Irishness" onto a country who must now parrot (and export) such cosy, plastic "Irishness" in their own art if they hope to garner international attention. Sayles is unwittingly participating here in the kind of damaging, bottled-tourism and cultural kitsch that he denounces so well in "Limbo" and "Sunshine State". Ignoring these issues, the film works fairly well as a children's fantasy, though I suspect most kids and adults will find "Roan Inish" too plain and too slow. Compare the film to Victor Erice's "The Spirit of the Beehive", a masterpiece which, like "Roan Inish", merges history, myth and childhood. 7/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quiet gem of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Momcat_of_Lomita
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a rare movie: one that can hold the attention of adults while at the same time keeping children entranced. That said, I have to add: this is not a movie for very young kids, who will not understand the mythology involved or "get" the plot. It is also not a film for people who are looking for a lot of action, special effects, cornball humor or over-the-top near-hysterical acting. It's a movie that works quietly for its effects. The first thing I have to comment on is the beautiful setting of the film and the photography. The setting is the west coast of Ireland, in a small fishing village, and on the sea and the land around the village. I believe "Secret" is as successful at conveying the rugged beauty of this landscape and seascape as any movie made. No tricks, no special effects, just the beauty of a place that has a lot of history and mythology associated with it. The actors and actresses in this film are not big names and not well-known, and I would say that this is a movie that is more story-driven than character-driven. At the same time, the lack of "name" actors or big bravura performances works to the advantage of the film, in that the personalities of the actors are submerged in the plot. There is a lot of kindness in this film, and a sense of the people being really connected to one another and caring for and about each other, and about the land and time they live in. That's one of the things that I loved about this film: there are no real villains, nothing evil. Nobody is considered stupid or demeaned in any way. And yet there is a tension to the story, and a move towards resolution of a history that had sadness and tragedy in a way that is literally magical. I loved this movie and I recommend it to anyone who can enjoy a movie that isn't big on action, that doesn't try to do more than tell a story in a way that's thoughtful and beautiful and makes you wish that you could find that kind of magic in your own life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Family values" in the best sense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Screen-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a true family film -- for and about families. Except for very small children (who might get bored) this film is has something for all ages. The actors -- both young and old, animal and human -- are excellent. The story-line is interesting for children but complex enough for adults. It's as beautiful as most "art movies" but as plot-driven as a Hollywood movie, again making it appealing to a broad range of people. It's non-offensive but not at all cloying like some family movies. (Well, unless you're offended by drinking or toddler nudity.) It's magical and mythic but still rooted in characters that seem believable. It also has interesting rural Irish culture which, I assume is accurate. My wife and I saw this movie in the theater before we had children and we now watch it with our kids on DVD. I've seen it three or four times and I'm still not tired of it! The only possible downside I can think of are the fairly thick Irish accents. I have no problem understanding but some people might.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Burin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the soundtrack to Tarantino's Kill Bill, Vol. 1, rapper RZA dedicates his witless contribution to character O-Ren Ishii, "half-Chinese, half-Japanese-ie". Well this review is dedicated in its entirety to the isle of Roan Inish, all Irish, no Japan-inish. John Sayles has spent most of his stellar career as a writer-director documenting the making of modern America: with the searing, masterfully-woven race relations dramas Lone Star and Sunshine State and the classic coming-of-age film Baby It's You, which doubles as a portrait of the immigrant experience. This change-of-pace outing finds him amidst the myths and mysteries of rural Ireland, where a 10-year-old girl is hunting for the baby brother who was swept to sea when her family evacuated its remote island home. The film builds slowly, mesmerisingly towards a cathartic act of mercy, incorporating several nuanced diversions which either bolster the narrative or flesh out its highly evocative portrait of a sea-faring community. Medium Cool director Haskell Wexler's lustrous cinematography and a soundtrack of Celtic folk songs add to the very special atmosphere, while the sensitive performances remain doggedly unsentimental, young Jeni Courtney representing the movie's poetic but earthy sensibility as the resourceful, single-minded heroine. Meanwhile, Sayles' unmatched ear for dialogue is as attuned as ever, his empathy for the characters reinforced by inventive direction that sees the world from Courtney's height for its first five minutes. Roan Inish is a tender, affecting and ultimately magical film - and one of the best few I'll see this year. RZA was unavailable for comment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing Happened!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cooperreynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just finished watching this movie and immediately went online to see just how terrible the reviews were only to see it has a 97% on rotten tomatoes upwards of 7 out of 10 on IMDb. Shocked by this I filled out the required information just to write this one review. This film struck me as borderline unwatchable. The child acting is on par The Phantom Menace. The little girl is cute, but good lord it was just embarrassing to watch. I kept telling myself it had to be intended as a children's movie and I was being unfair to assess it as harshly as I was until the movie had been playing for about an hour and NOTHING HAD HAPPENED! The only event that had occurred, excluding the painfully boring exposition, was the little girl chasing the naked kid for 40 seconds or so only to lose him in his little boat. I kept holding on hoping something, anything, would happen, but it never really did. This is literally how the movie ends: The little girl's family , for no reason, starts believing her about the little boy so they go out in the storm to find him. They walk outside their newly repaired house and the girl yells "Look!" We then see the kid on the shore and when he sees his sister he tries to flee, perhaps horrified at his sister's acting ability. When he tries to get in his little boat some seals, bear with me, come onto the shore. One seal chases him away from his boat and the others push the boat into the water. The family captures him and that's the happy ending? Does that not seem, at best, extremely dumb to anyone else? I can maybe buy someone liking the cultural overtones of the movie or even the occasional whimsy, but who in their right mind could truly say that they were ENTERTAINED by this film? Maybe this movie just went over my head, but in order for me to enjoy a movie i would need a few events to occur and maybe a plot or something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evocative, somewhat slow - an excellent children's film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While seeming to aim for the sense of mystery of 'Picnic at Hanging Rock', 'Roan Inish' never rises above the level of a strong TV drama. The problem isn't the central performance of Jeni Courtney as Fiona, which is outstandingly good, or the rest of the cast who must have frozen their assets impressively filming the lives of poor fishermen on the East Atlantic foreshore. More power to them. The kid playing the lost boy Jamie, Cillian Byrne (who didn't trouble the costume department), is also amazing, the way he (apparently) steers that floating cradle; and the scene with the seal and him having 'tea' is tremendous. But essentially this is a children's film, a sort of 'Railway Children' with Irish pipes and seals. Lots of Irish pipes. Lots of seals. Lots of seagulls. Lots of cold-looking water and rowboats. Lots of beaches, grass and flowers. Yet more Irish music. The only real suspense is whether there's a happy ending or not, which I won't give away, but no-one ever doubts that Fiona's story of what she has seen is true. Fair enough, they're simple people who believe in faery folk, but it all seems a bit cut-and-dried in the end. At the beginning, there's too much exposition from blarney-gushing Oirish characters, the late middle segue sequence goes on a bit too long and the pacing tends to slow up towards the end. But it's a genuine, well-made, innocent sort of film that you can safely let your smallest kids watch. The sort of film to rent at Xmas, or Easter. Especially if there's any Irish in you, or you particularly like seals. Much better than 'Ryan's Daughter', btw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cosmoeticadotcom (cosmoetica@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If John Sayles, the independent American filmmaker, is not the greatest director in the history of the medium, he certainly has to be considered among the most daring and diverse filmmakers ever. From tales set in America's past (Matewan), to yuppy dramadies (The Return Of The Secaucus Seven), to urban social satires (The Brother From Another Planet), to more modern looks at American life (Sunshine State, Lone Star, Casa De Los Babys), Sayles has shown a desire to explore things no other filmmaker has. And while he does not have a distinctive look nor style, each of films is well wrought, and a worthy addition to world cinema. One of his most daring films was actually one of his most popular and financially successful- 1995's Irish fantasy film, The Secret Of Roan Inish. OK, let me rephrase- to call The Secret Of Roan Inish a fantasy film- even if Sayles adapted the screenplay from a 1957 children's book (The Secret Of Ron Mor Skerry) by Rosalie K. Fry, is to sell it short. It is a very sly and deep look at childhood and the loneliness that accompanies such. In this way, it is very much in league with such other explorations of early childhood loneliness as Val Lewton's 1944 film The Curse Of The Cat People and 1968's Godzilla's Revenge. It is also very much a great family film along the lines of October Sky and My Dog Skip. It is also very much a mythic film. That term is often overused to describe films that deal with 'epic' characters or situations, but that sort of description and film too often wallows in the pseudo-babble of faux intellectuals like Joseph Campbell. This film succeeds by using the exact opposite tack- it presents the film very much from a child's eye point of view, that of its lead character Fiona Coneely (Jeni Courtney)- a cute ten year old blond girl who goes to live with her grandparents after World War Two, because her mother has died, and her father has had to go off to Scotland to find work. The film did only mediocre at the box office, but that's because it is a terrific and deep film that never condescends. It is a children's film sans explosions and wiseass children, and explodes the idea that films aimed at children need be lesser versions of their adult counterparts. In fact, they have a greater charge- to appeal to kids as well as adults, and on both levels. Children's films, in fact, should have more ideas crammed into them as children can absorb more and learn from them without the biases and fears that a typical adult has acquired. The film runs a crisp hour and forty-three minutes, and not a second is wasted. The only quibble one might have with the film is its title. It really should have been called The Secrets (plural) Of Roan Inish, for more than the secret of Jamie's fate is involved. Yet, the flaws in this film are very minor- such as Fiona's repeated inability to outwit her wild child brother, compared to the film's virtues- almost all else. The Secret Of Roan Inish is one of Sayles' best films, and arguably a great film in its own right. That this film did what it did with so little shows that true creativity thrives no matter what its source of nourishment is, and that when that creativity is a product of John Sayles' mind, it's likely to be something well beyond the norm.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intersection of Nature and Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pierotti@ku.edu)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the most emotionally satisfying film John Sayles has ever made, which tops a long and excellent list. Working with a virtually unknown Irish cast, Sayles brings to life a story that wanders on the borderland between mystical and blue-collar realism, without becoming cloying or simplistic. The only film to which i think Roan Inish can be effectively compared is Whale Rider, but with no insult intended to Whale Rider, to me Roan Inish is a richer and more complex film. The basic story concerns the relationship between humans and non-humans and how long- standing relationships between species can be torn apart by world events; in this case the Second World War, which forces a community of Irish fisherfolk to relocate to the mainland. A young girl, whose family has been damaged through these actions and other forces, is sent to live with her grandparents on the coast, at which point her nonhuman relatives contrive to bring her and her family back to the home they once shared with other life forms. The little girl, Fiona, who is the primary human character, played by Jenny Courtney, is wonderfully written and played. She is not your standard cutie-pie, but a budding force of nature. It is obvious why of all the members of her family, the nonhumans single her out for their attention. The story is drawn from the traditional Irish and Scots stories of relationships between humans and seals, or selchies, but transposes this into a more modern setting, without losing any of the mystery or wonder. One of the strongest recommendations I can give this film is that has become one of the most popular and respected films at Haskell Indian Nations University here in Kansas. Indigenous Americans seem to identify with the experience of the Irish, which shows them that modern European culture has been destructive to Indigenous peoples in Europe, and allows them to realize that there have been and continue to be, Indigenous people with distinct cultures in Europe as well as the Americas. I was once in a video store, when a person I knew slightly asked me if I could recommend a film that would appeal both to him and his children. Without hesitation I went over and picked up the store's copy of Roan Inish, and told him, "Not only will you enjoy this, but it will give you and your kids a lot to think and talk about." I make the same recommendation to anyone who reads this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanmarkel
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people would label this a children's movie...and yet, it has all the mystery and beauty that accompanies films for adults who love poetry and traditional storytelling and classic literature. Watch this film, and you'll get a good idea of Irish tradition and life and their constant belief in legend and lore, which has made them into the wonderful and strong race that they are today. There is a deep sense of family...a truly strong family who has clearly had its ups and downs and yet has come out even stronger than before. A family that has been through generations of change, adapted, continues to change and yet still holds onto the traditions and stories along the way. Stories that others might assume are myth and faery tales. And stories that we know aren't anything but the truth woven into a magical tale. In most Irish tales and legends I've read, there is a quest which keeps the main character(s) pushing forward through all the challenges of life. Fiona's store in this movie is no different. She's a little girl lost at the beginning when we meet her, wandering through the smog of the city to find some way to latch onto her father who is lost and sad with grief over a dead wife and a dead and missing baby boy. Her true quest begins when she is sent to live with her grandparents who still live by the sea. And the quest truly becomes a quest when she learns that her baby brother Jamie has been spotted on Roan Inish, the Island of the Seals where her family originated from. The music weaves itself around the characters and the story to make it more complete than it would be without it. It is both peaceful and stirring, providing the background for the cultural ear. With the music and the intricate storytelling, one can become truly lost in this story. And truly a part of it. If I had children, this is one movie I would have them watch over and over again. Like Disney's "Darby O'Gill and the Little People," this is a movie to entertain children of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Music to my fears
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much like "The Secret Garden", this is a film about the unlikely combination of everyday reality and pure magic. The character of Fiona (played by Jeni Courtney) is like every free and beautiful little girl that you've ever encountered rolled into one. She has such a wonderful outlook on life; honest and serious, faithful and fanciful. This is an improbable film for director John Sayles, an American filmmaker who usually sticks much closer to home. More pleasing still is the fact that he takes an honest, unfiltered view of the Irish culture that is so intrinsic to the story being told. "The Secret of Roan Inish" is about storytelling, from an inner and outer perspective. Each character is deeply concerned with sharing his or her own tale or take on local folklore. The script takes all sorts of beautiful sidelines into the tales of Fiona's relatives and anyone else who happens to pass by. Particularly fascinating is the performance of John Lynch, whose character tells the legend of the Selkie (played by his sister, Susan Lynch). The images of the seal woman are breathtaking, painful in their uncertain waking beauty. The final result of the film is something between the purity of childhood and the trust of self. I was taken in not only by the overwhelming sense of the unknown, but by everything fearful and wonderful in the making known of the same. This is one of the most enrapturing motion pictures I've ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celtic crowd pleaser masquerading as edgy indie art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The older the fiddle, the sweeter the tune." - Irish proverb Part of cinema's "Irish boom" in the lead up to the Anglo-Irish ceasefires, "The Secret of Roan Inish" is a low key, fairly unassuming piece of fantasy by director John Sales, notable mostly for some good cinematography by the legendary Haskell Wexler. Like all of these films ("Waking Ned Devine", "Far and Away", "Riverdance" etc), "The Secret of Roan Inish" exemplifies what writer Natasha Casey calls "Cletic commodification", reducing Ireland and Irishness to "Celtic myths", quaint, pre-modern, rural landscapes, and a depiction of the nation as being forever pre-colonised. Unsurprisingly, the film was widely distributed in America and Britian (since John Ford, "Irishness" has always been used as a vehicle to allow white audiences to role-play being white minorities/victims), but only had a limited release in Ireland. Its pastoral, regressive image of Irish society is more commercially viable outside of its home territory. The film is often touted as being Sayles' only non-political film, but this isn't true. Its tales of when "man and beast lived side-by-side, sharing the sea", of "monsters shedding their past skins", of a little girl's self determination and slow journey back to her roots, are designed specifically for the Irish diaspora. It's a call for a people to return to their homes and live alongside the now tamed beasts of Old England. "Everyone wants to march into the future," one haggard Irish character says, mourning about how his country "just got left behind." But the film's solution is to avoid modernization and to delve deeper into the past; a regression into some mythical "pure origins", a move backward to re-establish a pre-colonial Ireland. This is not surprising. The grand narrative of a society moving from the pre-modern to the modern to the post-modern, breaks down in Ireland. After the Anglo-Irish and Civil wars, as well as hundreds of years of struggle, the Irish were concerned with maintaining the nationalist cultural identity that they were finally free to express in their self-governance. But what Sayles' film does is advocate delving into the "rich identity of Ireland's past", whilst serving up only Disneyland trinkets. It's the condescending David Lean view of Ireland; the art house equivalent of a Lucky Charms cereal box. So it's not only that the film fails to give a genuine ideology of contemporary Ireland, or that it chooses an escape to the past instead of clarifying historical events, but that it pretends to be about "identity" when actually it's relying on mythology in order to avoid questions of authenticity (or the impossibility thereof). Ironically, with the Irish film industry in ruins, "Irishness" has increasingly become a sort of "viscious circle", foreigners projecting "Irishness" onto a country who must now parrot (and export) such cosy, plastic "Irishness" in their own art if they hope to garner international attention. Sayles is unwittingly participating here in the kind of damaging, bottled-tourism and cultural kitsch that he denounces so well in "Limbo" and "Sunshine State". Ignoring these issues, the film works fairly well as a children's fantasy, though I suspect most kids and adults will find "Roan Inish" too plain and too slow. Compare the film to Victor Erice's "The Spirit of the Beehive", a masterpiece which, like "Roan Inish", merges history, myth and childhood. 7/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quiet gem of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Momcat_of_Lomita
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a rare movie: one that can hold the attention of adults while at the same time keeping children entranced. That said, I have to add: this is not a movie for very young kids, who will not understand the mythology involved or "get" the plot. It is also not a film for people who are looking for a lot of action, special effects, cornball humor or over-the-top near-hysterical acting. It's a movie that works quietly for its effects. The first thing I have to comment on is the beautiful setting of the film and the photography. The setting is the west coast of Ireland, in a small fishing village, and on the sea and the land around the village. I believe "Secret" is as successful at conveying the rugged beauty of this landscape and seascape as any movie made. No tricks, no special effects, just the beauty of a place that has a lot of history and mythology associated with it. The actors and actresses in this film are not big names and not well-known, and I would say that this is a movie that is more story-driven than character-driven. At the same time, the lack of "name" actors or big bravura performances works to the advantage of the film, in that the personalities of the actors are submerged in the plot. There is a lot of kindness in this film, and a sense of the people being really connected to one another and caring for and about each other, and about the land and time they live in. That's one of the things that I loved about this film: there are no real villains, nothing evil. Nobody is considered stupid or demeaned in any way. And yet there is a tension to the story, and a move towards resolution of a history that had sadness and tragedy in a way that is literally magical. I loved this movie and I recommend it to anyone who can enjoy a movie that isn't big on action, that doesn't try to do more than tell a story in a way that's thoughtful and beautiful and makes you wish that you could find that kind of magic in your own life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Family values" in the best sense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Screen-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a true family film -- for and about families. Except for very small children (who might get bored) this film is has something for all ages. The actors -- both young and old, animal and human -- are excellent. The story-line is interesting for children but complex enough for adults. It's as beautiful as most "art movies" but as plot-driven as a Hollywood movie, again making it appealing to a broad range of people. It's non-offensive but not at all cloying like some family movies. (Well, unless you're offended by drinking or toddler nudity.) It's magical and mythic but still rooted in characters that seem believable. It also has interesting rural Irish culture which, I assume is accurate. My wife and I saw this movie in the theater before we had children and we now watch it with our kids on DVD. I've seen it three or four times and I'm still not tired of it! The only possible downside I can think of are the fairly thick Irish accents. I have no problem understanding but some people might.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Burin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the soundtrack to Tarantino's Kill Bill, Vol. 1, rapper RZA dedicates his witless contribution to character O-Ren Ishii, "half-Chinese, half-Japanese-ie". Well this review is dedicated in its entirety to the isle of Roan Inish, all Irish, no Japan-inish. John Sayles has spent most of his stellar career as a writer-director documenting the making of modern America: with the searing, masterfully-woven race relations dramas Lone Star and Sunshine State and the classic coming-of-age film Baby It's You, which doubles as a portrait of the immigrant experience. This change-of-pace outing finds him amidst the myths and mysteries of rural Ireland, where a 10-year-old girl is hunting for the baby brother who was swept to sea when her family evacuated its remote island home. The film builds slowly, mesmerisingly towards a cathartic act of mercy, incorporating several nuanced diversions which either bolster the narrative or flesh out its highly evocative portrait of a sea-faring community. Medium Cool director Haskell Wexler's lustrous cinematography and a soundtrack of Celtic folk songs add to the very special atmosphere, while the sensitive performances remain doggedly unsentimental, young Jeni Courtney representing the movie's poetic but earthy sensibility as the resourceful, single-minded heroine. Meanwhile, Sayles' unmatched ear for dialogue is as attuned as ever, his empathy for the characters reinforced by inventive direction that sees the world from Courtney's height for its first five minutes. Roan Inish is a tender, affecting and ultimately magical film - and one of the best few I'll see this year. RZA was unavailable for comment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing Happened!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cooperreynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just finished watching this movie and immediately went online to see just how terrible the reviews were only to see it has a 97% on rotten tomatoes upwards of 7 out of 10 on IMDb. Shocked by this I filled out the required information just to write this one review. This film struck me as borderline unwatchable. The child acting is on par The Phantom Menace. The little girl is cute, but good lord it was just embarrassing to watch. I kept telling myself it had to be intended as a children's movie and I was being unfair to assess it as harshly as I was until the movie had been playing for about an hour and NOTHING HAD HAPPENED! The only event that had occurred, excluding the painfully boring exposition, was the little girl chasing the naked kid for 40 seconds or so only to lose him in his little boat. I kept holding on hoping something, anything, would happen, but it never really did. This is literally how the movie ends: The little girl's family , for no reason, starts believing her about the little boy so they go out in the storm to find him. They walk outside their newly repaired house and the girl yells "Look!" We then see the kid on the shore and when he sees his sister he tries to flee, perhaps horrified at his sister's acting ability. When he tries to get in his little boat some seals, bear with me, come onto the shore. One seal chases him away from his boat and the others push the boat into the water. The family captures him and that's the happy ending? Does that not seem, at best, extremely dumb to anyone else? I can maybe buy someone liking the cultural overtones of the movie or even the occasional whimsy, but who in their right mind could truly say that they were ENTERTAINED by this film? Maybe this movie just went over my head, but in order for me to enjoy a movie i would need a few events to occur and maybe a plot or something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evocative, somewhat slow - an excellent children's film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While seeming to aim for the sense of mystery of 'Picnic at Hanging Rock', 'Roan Inish' never rises above the level of a strong TV drama. The problem isn't the central performance of Jeni Courtney as Fiona, which is outstandingly good, or the rest of the cast who must have frozen their assets impressively filming the lives of poor fishermen on the East Atlantic foreshore. More power to them. The kid playing the lost boy Jamie, Cillian Byrne (who didn't trouble the costume department), is also amazing, the way he (apparently) steers that floating cradle; and the scene with the seal and him having 'tea' is tremendous. But essentially this is a children's film, a sort of 'Railway Children' with Irish pipes and seals. Lots of Irish pipes. Lots of seals. Lots of seagulls. Lots of cold-looking water and rowboats. Lots of beaches, grass and flowers. Yet more Irish music. The only real suspense is whether there's a happy ending or not, which I won't give away, but no-one ever doubts that Fiona's story of what she has seen is true. Fair enough, they're simple people who believe in faery folk, but it all seems a bit cut-and-dried in the end. At the beginning, there's too much exposition from blarney-gushing Oirish characters, the late middle segue sequence goes on a bit too long and the pacing tends to slow up towards the end. But it's a genuine, well-made, innocent sort of film that you can safely let your smallest kids watch. The sort of film to rent at Xmas, or Easter. Especially if there's any Irish in you, or you particularly like seals. Much better than 'Ryan's Daughter', btw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cosmoeticadotcom (cosmoetica@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If John Sayles, the independent American filmmaker, is not the greatest director in the history of the medium, he certainly has to be considered among the most daring and diverse filmmakers ever. From tales set in America's past (Matewan), to yuppy dramadies (The Return Of The Secaucus Seven), to urban social satires (The Brother From Another Planet), to more modern looks at American life (Sunshine State, Lone Star, Casa De Los Babys), Sayles has shown a desire to explore things no other filmmaker has. And while he does not have a distinctive look nor style, each of films is well wrought, and a worthy addition to world cinema. One of his most daring films was actually one of his most popular and financially successful- 1995's Irish fantasy film, The Secret Of Roan Inish. OK, let me rephrase- to call The Secret Of Roan Inish a fantasy film- even if Sayles adapted the screenplay from a 1957 children's book (The Secret Of Ron Mor Skerry) by Rosalie K. Fry, is to sell it short. It is a very sly and deep look at childhood and the loneliness that accompanies such. In this way, it is very much in league with such other explorations of early childhood loneliness as Val Lewton's 1944 film The Curse Of The Cat People and 1968's Godzilla's Revenge. It is also very much a great family film along the lines of October Sky and My Dog Skip. It is also very much a mythic film. That term is often overused to describe films that deal with 'epic' characters or situations, but that sort of description and film too often wallows in the pseudo-babble of faux intellectuals like Joseph Campbell. This film succeeds by using the exact opposite tack- it presents the film very much from a child's eye point of view, that of its lead character Fiona Coneely (Jeni Courtney)- a cute ten year old blond girl who goes to live with her grandparents after World War Two, because her mother has died, and her father has had to go off to Scotland to find work. The film did only mediocre at the box office, but that's because it is a terrific and deep film that never condescends. It is a children's film sans explosions and wiseass children, and explodes the idea that films aimed at children need be lesser versions of their adult counterparts. In fact, they have a greater charge- to appeal to kids as well as adults, and on both levels. Children's films, in fact, should have more ideas crammed into them as children can absorb more and learn from them without the biases and fears that a typical adult has acquired. The film runs a crisp hour and forty-three minutes, and not a second is wasted. The only quibble one might have with the film is its title. It really should have been called The Secrets (plural) Of Roan Inish, for more than the secret of Jamie's fate is involved. Yet, the flaws in this film are very minor- such as Fiona's repeated inability to outwit her wild child brother, compared to the film's virtues- almost all else. The Secret Of Roan Inish is one of Sayles' best films, and arguably a great film in its own right. That this film did what it did with so little shows that true creativity thrives no matter what its source of nourishment is, and that when that creativity is a product of John Sayles' mind, it's likely to be something well beyond the norm.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intersection of Nature and Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pierotti@ku.edu)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the most emotionally satisfying film John Sayles has ever made, which tops a long and excellent list. Working with a virtually unknown Irish cast, Sayles brings to life a story that wanders on the borderland between mystical and blue-collar realism, without becoming cloying or simplistic. The only film to which i think Roan Inish can be effectively compared is Whale Rider, but with no insult intended to Whale Rider, to me Roan Inish is a richer and more complex film. The basic story concerns the relationship between humans and non-humans and how long- standing relationships between species can be torn apart by world events; in this case the Second World War, which forces a community of Irish fisherfolk to relocate to the mainland. A young girl, whose family has been damaged through these actions and other forces, is sent to live with her grandparents on the coast, at which point her nonhuman relatives contrive to bring her and her family back to the home they once shared with other life forms. The little girl, Fiona, who is the primary human character, played by Jenny Courtney, is wonderfully written and played. She is not your standard cutie-pie, but a budding force of nature. It is obvious why of all the members of her family, the nonhumans single her out for their attention. The story is drawn from the traditional Irish and Scots stories of relationships between humans and seals, or selchies, but transposes this into a more modern setting, without losing any of the mystery or wonder. One of the strongest recommendations I can give this film is that has become one of the most popular and respected films at Haskell Indian Nations University here in Kansas. Indigenous Americans seem to identify with the experience of the Irish, which shows them that modern European culture has been destructive to Indigenous peoples in Europe, and allows them to realize that there have been and continue to be, Indigenous people with distinct cultures in Europe as well as the Americas. I was once in a video store, when a person I knew slightly asked me if I could recommend a film that would appeal both to him and his children. Without hesitation I went over and picked up the store's copy of Roan Inish, and told him, "Not only will you enjoy this, but it will give you and your kids a lot to think and talk about." I make the same recommendation to anyone who reads this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanmarkel
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people would label this a children's movie...and yet, it has all the mystery and beauty that accompanies films for adults who love poetry and traditional storytelling and classic literature. Watch this film, and you'll get a good idea of Irish tradition and life and their constant belief in legend and lore, which has made them into the wonderful and strong race that they are today. There is a deep sense of family...a truly strong family who has clearly had its ups and downs and yet has come out even stronger than before. A family that has been through generations of change, adapted, continues to change and yet still holds onto the traditions and stories along the way. Stories that others might assume are myth and faery tales. And stories that we know aren't anything but the truth woven into a magical tale. In most Irish tales and legends I've read, there is a quest which keeps the main character(s) pushing forward through all the challenges of life. Fiona's store in this movie is no different. She's a little girl lost at the beginning when we meet her, wandering through the smog of the city to find some way to latch onto her father who is lost and sad with grief over a dead wife and a dead and missing baby boy. Her true quest begins when she is sent to live with her grandparents who still live by the sea. And the quest truly becomes a quest when she learns that her baby brother Jamie has been spotted on Roan Inish, the Island of the Seals where her family originated from. The music weaves itself around the characters and the story to make it more complete than it would be without it. It is both peaceful and stirring, providing the background for the cultural ear. With the music and the intricate storytelling, one can become truly lost in this story. And truly a part of it. If I had children, this is one movie I would have them watch over and over again. Like Disney's "Darby O'Gill and the Little People," this is a movie to entertain children of all ages.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Music to my fears
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much like "The Secret Garden", this is a film about the unlikely combination of everyday reality and pure magic. The character of Fiona (played by Jeni Courtney) is like every free and beautiful little girl that you've ever encountered rolled into one. She has such a wonderful outlook on life; honest and serious, faithful and fanciful. This is an improbable film for director John Sayles, an American filmmaker who usually sticks much closer to home. More pleasing still is the fact that he takes an honest, unfiltered view of the Irish culture that is so intrinsic to the story being told. "The Secret of Roan Inish" is about storytelling, from an inner and outer perspective. Each character is deeply concerned with sharing his or her own tale or take on local folklore. The script takes all sorts of beautiful sidelines into the tales of Fiona's relatives and anyone else who happens to pass by. Particularly fascinating is the performance of John Lynch, whose character tells the legend of the Selkie (played by his sister, Susan Lynch). The images of the seal woman are breathtaking, painful in their uncertain waking beauty. The final result of the film is something between the purity of childhood and the trust of self. I was taken in not only by the overwhelming sense of the unknown, but by everything fearful and wonderful in the making known of the same. This is one of the most enrapturing motion pictures I've ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Celtic crowd pleaser masquerading as edgy indie art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The older the fiddle, the sweeter the tune." - Irish proverb Part of cinema's "Irish boom" in the lead up to the Anglo-Irish ceasefires, "The Secret of Roan Inish" is a low key, fairly unassuming piece of fantasy by director John Sales, notable mostly for some good cinematography by the legendary Haskell Wexler. Like all of these films ("Waking Ned Devine", "Far and Away", "Riverdance" etc), "The Secret of Roan Inish" exemplifies what writer Natasha Casey calls "Cletic commodification", reducing Ireland and Irishness to "Celtic myths", quaint, pre-modern, rural landscapes, and a depiction of the nation as being forever pre-colonised. Unsurprisingly, the film was widely distributed in America and Britian (since John Ford, "Irishness" has always been used as a vehicle to allow white audiences to role-play being white minorities/victims), but only had a limited release in Ireland. Its pastoral, regressive image of Irish society is more commercially viable outside of its home territory. The film is often touted as being Sayles' only non-political film, but this isn't true. Its tales of when "man and beast lived side-by-side, sharing the sea", of "monsters shedding their past skins", of a little girl's self determination and slow journey back to her roots, are designed specifically for the Irish diaspora. It's a call for a people to return to their homes and live alongside the now tamed beasts of Old England. "Everyone wants to march into the future," one haggard Irish character says, mourning about how his country "just got left behind." But the film's solution is to avoid modernization and to delve deeper into the past; a regression into some mythical "pure origins", a move backward to re-establish a pre-colonial Ireland. This is not surprising. The grand narrative of a society moving from the pre-modern to the modern to the post-modern, breaks down in Ireland. After the Anglo-Irish and Civil wars, as well as hundreds of years of struggle, the Irish were concerned with maintaining the nationalist cultural identity that they were finally free to express in their self-governance. But what Sayles' film does is advocate delving into the "rich identity of Ireland's past", whilst serving up only Disneyland trinkets. It's the condescending David Lean view of Ireland; the art house equivalent of a Lucky Charms cereal box. So it's not only that the film fails to give a genuine ideology of contemporary Ireland, or that it chooses an escape to the past instead of clarifying historical events, but that it pretends to be about "identity" when actually it's relying on mythology in order to avoid questions of authenticity (or the impossibility thereof). Ironically, with the Irish film industry in ruins, "Irishness" has increasingly become a sort of "viscious circle", foreigners projecting "Irishness" onto a country who must now parrot (and export) such cosy, plastic "Irishness" in their own art if they hope to garner international attention. Sayles is unwittingly participating here in the kind of damaging, bottled-tourism and cultural kitsch that he denounces so well in "Limbo" and "Sunshine State". Ignoring these issues, the film works fairly well as a children's fantasy, though I suspect most kids and adults will find "Roan Inish" too plain and too slow. Compare the film to Victor Erice's "The Spirit of the Beehive", a masterpiece which, like "Roan Inish", merges history, myth and childhood. 7/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quiet gem of a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Momcat_of_Lomita
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a rare movie: one that can hold the attention of adults while at the same time keeping children entranced. That said, I have to add: this is not a movie for very young kids, who will not understand the mythology involved or "get" the plot. It is also not a film for people who are looking for a lot of action, special effects, cornball humor or over-the-top near-hysterical acting. It's a movie that works quietly for its effects. The first thing I have to comment on is the beautiful setting of the film and the photography. The setting is the west coast of Ireland, in a small fishing village, and on the sea and the land around the village. I believe "Secret" is as successful at conveying the rugged beauty of this landscape and seascape as any movie made. No tricks, no special effects, just the beauty of a place that has a lot of history and mythology associated with it. The actors and actresses in this film are not big names and not well-known, and I would say that this is a movie that is more story-driven than character-driven. At the same time, the lack of "name" actors or big bravura performances works to the advantage of the film, in that the personalities of the actors are submerged in the plot. There is a lot of kindness in this film, and a sense of the people being really connected to one another and caring for and about each other, and about the land and time they live in. That's one of the things that I loved about this film: there are no real villains, nothing evil. Nobody is considered stupid or demeaned in any way. And yet there is a tension to the story, and a move towards resolution of a history that had sadness and tragedy in a way that is literally magical. I loved this movie and I recommend it to anyone who can enjoy a movie that isn't big on action, that doesn't try to do more than tell a story in a way that's thoughtful and beautiful and makes you wish that you could find that kind of magic in your own life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Family values" in the best sense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Screen-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a true family film -- for and about families. Except for very small children (who might get bored) this film is has something for all ages. The actors -- both young and old, animal and human -- are excellent. The story-line is interesting for children but complex enough for adults. It's as beautiful as most "art movies" but as plot-driven as a Hollywood movie, again making it appealing to a broad range of people. It's non-offensive but not at all cloying like some family movies. (Well, unless you're offended by drinking or toddler nudity.) It's magical and mythic but still rooted in characters that seem believable. It also has interesting rural Irish culture which, I assume is accurate. My wife and I saw this movie in the theater before we had children and we now watch it with our kids on DVD. I've seen it three or four times and I'm still not tired of it! The only possible downside I can think of are the fairly thick Irish accents. I have no problem understanding but some people might.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Burin
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the soundtrack to Tarantino's Kill Bill, Vol. 1, rapper RZA dedicates his witless contribution to character O-Ren Ishii, "half-Chinese, half-Japanese-ie". Well this review is dedicated in its entirety to the isle of Roan Inish, all Irish, no Japan-inish. John Sayles has spent most of his stellar career as a writer-director documenting the making of modern America: with the searing, masterfully-woven race relations dramas Lone Star and Sunshine State and the classic coming-of-age film Baby It's You, which doubles as a portrait of the immigrant experience. This change-of-pace outing finds him amidst the myths and mysteries of rural Ireland, where a 10-year-old girl is hunting for the baby brother who was swept to sea when her family evacuated its remote island home. The film builds slowly, mesmerisingly towards a cathartic act of mercy, incorporating several nuanced diversions which either bolster the narrative or flesh out its highly evocative portrait of a sea-faring community. Medium Cool director Haskell Wexler's lustrous cinematography and a soundtrack of Celtic folk songs add to the very special atmosphere, while the sensitive performances remain doggedly unsentimental, young Jeni Courtney representing the movie's poetic but earthy sensibility as the resourceful, single-minded heroine. Meanwhile, Sayles' unmatched ear for dialogue is as attuned as ever, his empathy for the characters reinforced by inventive direction that sees the world from Courtney's height for its first five minutes. Roan Inish is a tender, affecting and ultimately magical film - and one of the best few I'll see this year. RZA was unavailable for comment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing Happened!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cooperreynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just finished watching this movie and immediately went online to see just how terrible the reviews were only to see it has a 97% on rotten tomatoes upwards of 7 out of 10 on IMDb. Shocked by this I filled out the required information just to write this one review. This film struck me as borderline unwatchable. The child acting is on par The Phantom Menace. The little girl is cute, but good lord it was just embarrassing to watch. I kept telling myself it had to be intended as a children's movie and I was being unfair to assess it as harshly as I was until the movie had been playing for about an hour and NOTHING HAD HAPPENED! The only event that had occurred, excluding the painfully boring exposition, was the little girl chasing the naked kid for 40 seconds or so only to lose him in his little boat. I kept holding on hoping something, anything, would happen, but it never really did. This is literally how the movie ends: The little girl's family , for no reason, starts believing her about the little boy so they go out in the storm to find him. They walk outside their newly repaired house and the girl yells "Look!" We then see the kid on the shore and when he sees his sister he tries to flee, perhaps horrified at his sister's acting ability. When he tries to get in his little boat some seals, bear with me, come onto the shore. One seal chases him away from his boat and the others push the boat into the water. The family captures him and that's the happy ending? Does that not seem, at best, extremely dumb to anyone else? I can maybe buy someone liking the cultural overtones of the movie or even the occasional whimsy, but who in their right mind could truly say that they were ENTERTAINED by this film? Maybe this movie just went over my head, but in order for me to enjoy a movie i would need a few events to occur and maybe a plot or something.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evocative, somewhat slow - an excellent children's film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While seeming to aim for the sense of mystery of 'Picnic at Hanging Rock', 'Roan Inish' never rises above the level of a strong TV drama. The problem isn't the central performance of Jeni Courtney as Fiona, which is outstandingly good, or the rest of the cast who must have frozen their assets impressively filming the lives of poor fishermen on the East Atlantic foreshore. More power to them. The kid playing the lost boy Jamie, Cillian Byrne (who didn't trouble the costume department), is also amazing, the way he (apparently) steers that floating cradle; and the scene with the seal and him having 'tea' is tremendous. But essentially this is a children's film, a sort of 'Railway Children' with Irish pipes and seals. Lots of Irish pipes. Lots of seals. Lots of seagulls. Lots of cold-looking water and rowboats. Lots of beaches, grass and flowers. Yet more Irish music. The only real suspense is whether there's a happy ending or not, which I won't give away, but no-one ever doubts that Fiona's story of what she has seen is true. Fair enough, they're simple people who believe in faery folk, but it all seems a bit cut-and-dried in the end. At the beginning, there's too much exposition from blarney-gushing Oirish characters, the late middle segue sequence goes on a bit too long and the pacing tends to slow up towards the end. But it's a genuine, well-made, innocent sort of film that you can safely let your smallest kids watch. The sort of film to rent at Xmas, or Easter. Especially if there's any Irish in you, or you particularly like seals. Much better than 'Ryan's Daughter', btw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cosmoeticadotcom (cosmoetica@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If John Sayles, the independent American filmmaker, is not the greatest director in the history of the medium, he certainly has to be considered among the most daring and diverse filmmakers ever. From tales set in America's past (Matewan), to yuppy dramadies (The Return Of The Secaucus Seven), to urban social satires (The Brother From Another Planet), to more modern looks at American life (Sunshine State, Lone Star, Casa De Los Babys), Sayles has shown a desire to explore things no other filmmaker has. And while he does not have a distinctive look nor style, each of films is well wrought, and a worthy addition to world cinema. One of his most daring films was actually one of his most popular and financially successful- 1995's Irish fantasy film, The Secret Of Roan Inish. OK, let me rephrase- to call The Secret Of Roan Inish a fantasy film- even if Sayles adapted the screenplay from a 1957 children's book (The Secret Of Ron Mor Skerry) by Rosalie K. Fry, is to sell it short. It is a very sly and deep look at childhood and the loneliness that accompanies such. In this way, it is very much in league with such other explorations of early childhood loneliness as Val Lewton's 1944 film The Curse Of The Cat People and 1968's Godzilla's Revenge. It is also very much a great family film along the lines of October Sky and My Dog Skip. It is also very much a mythic film. That term is often overused to describe films that deal with 'epic' characters or situations, but that sort of description and film too often wallows in the pseudo-babble of faux intellectuals like Joseph Campbell. This film succeeds by using the exact opposite tack- it presents the film very much from a child's eye point of view, that of its lead character Fiona Coneely (Jeni Courtney)- a cute ten year old blond girl who goes to live with her grandparents after World War Two, because her mother has died, and her father has had to go off to Scotland to find work. The film did only mediocre at the box office, but that's because it is a terrific and deep film that never condescends. It is a children's film sans explosions and wiseass children, and explodes the idea that films aimed at children need be lesser versions of their adult counterparts. In fact, they have a greater charge- to appeal to kids as well as adults, and on both levels. Children's films, in fact, should have more ideas crammed into them as children can absorb more and learn from them without the biases and fears that a typical adult has acquired. The film runs a crisp hour and forty-three minutes, and not a second is wasted. The only quibble one might have with the film is its title. It really should have been called The Secrets (plural) Of Roan Inish, for more than the secret of Jamie's fate is involved. Yet, the flaws in this film are very minor- such as Fiona's repeated inability to outwit her wild child brother, compared to the film's virtues- almost all else. The Secret Of Roan Inish is one of Sayles' best films, and arguably a great film in its own right. That this film did what it did with so little shows that true creativity thrives no matter what its source of nourishment is, and that when that creativity is a product of John Sayles' mind, it's likely to be something well beyond the norm.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intersection of Nature and Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pierotti@ku.edu)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the most emotionally satisfying film John Sayles has ever made, which tops a long and excellent list. Working with a virtually unknown Irish cast, Sayles brings to life a story that wanders on the borderland between mystical and blue-collar realism, without becoming cloying or simplistic. The only film to which i think Roan Inish can be effectively compared is Whale Rider, but with no insult intended to Whale Rider, to me Roan Inish is a richer and more complex film. The basic story concerns the relationship between humans and non-humans and how long- standing relationships between species can be torn apart by world events; in this case the Second World War, which forces a community of Irish fisherfolk to relocate to the mainland. A young girl, whose family has been damaged through these actions and other forces, is sent to live with her grandparents on the coast, at which point her nonhuman relatives contrive to bring her and her family back to the home they once shared with other life forms. The little girl, Fiona, who is the primary human character, played by Jenny Courtney, is wonderfully written and played. She is not your standard cutie-pie, but a budding force of nature. It is obvious why of all the members of her family, the nonhumans single her out for their attention. The story is drawn from the traditional Irish and Scots stories of relationships between humans and seals, or selchies, but transposes this into a more modern setting, without losing any of the mystery or wonder. One of the strongest recommendations I can give this film is that has become one of the most popular and respected films at Haskell Indian Nations University here in Kansas. Indigenous Americans seem to identify with the experience of the Irish, which shows them that modern European culture has been destructive to Indigenous peoples in Europe, and allows them to realize that there have been and continue to be, Indigenous people with distinct cultures in Europe as well as the Americas. I was once in a video store, when a person I knew slightly asked me if I could recommend a film that would appeal both to him and his children. Without hesitation I went over and picked up the store's copy of Roan Inish, and told him, "Not only will you enjoy this, but it will give you and your kids a lot to think and talk about." I make the same recommendation to anyone who reads this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
