<filme>
 <id>
  471
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115956
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Coragem Sob Fogo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A US Army officer, despondent about a deadly mistake he made, investigates a female chopper commander's worthiness for the Medal of Honor.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The pilot of a rescue copter, Captain Karen Walden, died shortly before her helicopter crew was rescued after it crashed in Desert Storm. It first appears that she made a spectacular rescue of a downed helicopter crew, then held her own crew together to fight off the Iraqis after her copter crashed. Lt. Colonel Serling, who is struggling with his own demons from Desert Storm is assigned to investigate and award her the Medal of Honor. But some conflicting accounts, from her crew and soldiers in the area, cause him to question whether she deserves it.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   honor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   medal of honor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   helicopter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   desert storm
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   captain
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Edward Zwick
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Patrick Sheane Duncan
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Denzel Washington
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Meg Ryan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lou Diamond Phillips
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film with a couple of standout performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just for the record, at least here on IMDb, I think this is an underrated film. And I say that as a person who very rarely likes movies about the military. My dad was in the military most of his adult life, and when he would come home on leave he would always drag me to some war film. I hated it. So, I rarely watch a war movie. But this is a keeper. First, the cast. And let me review the actors in the order of how impressive they were in this film. Denzel Washington, as a Lieutenant Colonel investigating whether a dead female captain should receive the Medal Of Honor, and who himself may have been involved in friendly fire deaths, and who has an alcohol problem, is excellent. Lou Diamond Phillips, as a Staff Sergeant who was at the helicopter crash where the female soldier was killed, is superb here (I never knew he was such a hunk...just for the record). Regina Taylor, as the wife of Washington, is excellent! Meg Ryan, the helicopter pilot who dies, is good, but although her role is pivotal, this is not a very good showcase of her talents, and I do not see her here as the co-star to Denzel Washington. I found Matt Damon rather unimpressive here, but of course, this was just before his breakthrough role that immediately followed this film. Bronson Pinchot was an interesting choice as a White House aide, and he does okay. Michael Moriarty is good as a Brigadier General, as is Scott Glenn as a Washington Post reporter. While I can't say whether or not the Iraq battle scenes were realistic, they impressed me. Despite some inconsistencies, I think the story is a good one. And not a simple one, since the issues that Denzel Washington's character has are complicating his investigation of whether or not Ryan's character should receive the Medal Of Honor. Washington does an admirable job of mixing all these factors and fleshing out the character traits of his role. In fact, this was one of Washington's early films which convinced me that he was an actor that America should treasure. Despite a few flaws, highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overly Sentimental and Top Heavy...But Above Average
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a strong Story here as an investigation ensues about a potential Medal of Honor recipient and the mysterious conflict of testimonies. It is given a twist with a shot of estrogen as the Soldier involved is the first Female to possibly (Posthumously) be awarded the Nation's Highest Military Honor. That should be enough to make this a riveting Mystery and through flashbacks we are shown some striking battle Scenes. So why add the conflict and strife to the investigating Officer. It is completely unnecessary and is the weakest part of the Film and almost drags it down with unconvincing situations of Combat guilt and Family Dysfunction. That could be a whole other Movie. But with that bloating aside there are some strong Performances by the young Cast (actually outshining Denzel) in supporting Roles as the Combat Unit in question. There is a back Story to everyone and it holds up quite well with the central Theme. It must be mentioned here that although, Meg Ryan is miscast as the Captain, she tries her best but cannot outgrow her limitations and convince as a tough Girl in a hopeless, self sacrificing situation. Overall, not a bad Movie and is worth a watch for the strong parts, but there is much too much padding here, plus the heavy dose of sentimentality finally drags this down from Great Movie to just above Average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very, very pretentious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    floyd beck
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry, but I cannot stomach a movie that is pro-military when Meg Ryan, a devout Democrat and worshiper of John Kerry, the war-hater and devout liar, and Denzel Washington, a worshiper of President Obama and a devout Democrat who is said to be a devout Christian. One cannot be both...in 2011, the Democrats voted NO to have God inserted in their convention, in spite of the chairman's blatant lie; just one of 100 reasons. So, after my ranting, what about the movie? It is too hard to believe any of it because the actors are not sincere in true life. It would be like having an openly gay person portray Rudolph Valentino unless the movie was a comedy. Courage Under Fire does not pass as a comedy unless one forces one's mind to the point of insanity to see liberal war-hating actors and actresses pretend to be pro-military.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gutless Under Clich&eacute;
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunmore_ego
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, I know it's trying to be inspiring and heroic and poignant, but COURAGE UNDER FIRE is one of the most blatantly gutless movies ever made. About a soldier investigating whether a downed female United States helicopter pilot in Desert Storm deserves a posthumous Medal of Honor. So I ask you: in which universe will America ever make a movie where a Medal of Honor is investigated and NOT awarded? So it's a foregone conclusion--all the mystery and mayhem and maybes are simply wasting our time more than the actual war this story was set in--as it leads inexorably to the melodramatic military funeral, the flags, saluting, tears of the family, proud shiny buttons and white gloves, the flyover with one plane breaking formation, and that bilious, bleating orchestra swell. And the Medal. The End. Cry me a river; cry me a patently meaningless award, military swine. Then the coda: the investigating soldier visits pilot's grave, salutes grave, tiny flag, voice-over of dead pilot to American Pie Mom and Dad, talking of the Big Push and hero hero hero hero hero hero another blithering orchestra swell I'm going to vomit... Denzel Washington is the investigating soldier, with demons of his own. (Well, they're not really demons; they're roiling stabs of conscience he feels for stupidly shooting one of his own tanks during a skirmish, killing his own men in the hilariously black euphemism "friendly fire," and then having the military cover-up his blunder.) And whenever he has visions of that po' boy he fricasseed in that tank (Mmm! Soldierboy, the other white meat!), he heads straight for the alcohol... uh, cos he's a hero, see. When he's asked to investigate whether Captain Karen Walden (Meg Ryan) is worthy of receiving the Medal of Honor for "courage under fire," the story ends right there. Of course she's deserving of it. She's the first female officer recommended, she's regarded as a hero for sacrificing her life for her men--and she's Meg Ryan. As if the movie would go to all the trouble setting up her heroism and feminism and Ryanism and NOT award her the medal. And every clich&eacute; in the military lexicon is thrown at us like grenades lobbed into foxholes: the tragic family; damaged goods investigating damaged goods; the novice (Matt Damon), the toughguy (Lou Diamond Phillips), the hero-worshipper (Tim Guinee) and all the other bumboys like the Benetton passengers of SPEED; the hospitalized guy (Seth Gilliam) whose seen one battle too many; the military cover-up. And everyone's got Movie PTSD. Denzel wants to find out "what really happened," so COURAGE is constructed like a RASHOMON for rednecks, as we see all the alternate flashbacks with a coy Walden, an indecisive Walden and a butch Walden barking orders and trying not to look like a sex object. Not one of the scenarios is ambiguous about her Hero status--no matter if she threw Iraqi babies at walls or defunded the G.I. Bill. If we can call football players heroes, and people who jumped from the Twin Towers heroes, then this chopper pilot must be a shoo-in, so I ask again: what compels viewers to spend 120 minutes *pretending* there's any doubt? Denzel visits Walden's helicopter bumboys, who all give differing accounts of My Night In The Desert With Captain Walden. Diamond Phillips claims he was the toughguy, as he lies and plies himself with alcohol and commits suicide (cos he's a hero!); Damon claims Walden was a strategic hardnose, as he admits to being a junkie and afraid to go flying again (cos he's a hero!); Guinee relates how Walden sacrificed herself for them, even as he reveals how she got them shot down by taking another pass at an Iraqi tank when she could have flown away--cognitive dissonance rules!--while constantly telling his wife to shutup for calling Walden butch (cos he's a hero!); while Seth Gilliam pounds his medication to numb himself out of the running as a reputable eyewitness (cos he's a hero, see!). What's in it for her bumboys to report that she was a coward? Nothing. But saying she was a HERO makes them vicarious heroes alongside her. Ooo-rah! And here's a note to all you military wardogs whose first reaction is to Spock-chop me for "disrespecting" you (such heroes, fighting for peace!): When are you going to realize your own government, who pays you hypocritical lip service, regards you with even less respect than I do? I just consider you deluded and egotistical and sometimes uneducated, while they consider you cannon fodder! It's the United States government that fools you into getting your asses shot off for them in the first place; it's the United States government that refuses you and your family financial benefits when you return from war; it's the United States government that stop-losses you, reneging on your stipulated leave time, over and over and over again; it's the United States government that cuts your medical funding; it's the United States government that evicts your family, that lies about friendly fire, that doesn't provide armor for you or your vehicles; it's the United States government that kicks you out for being gay after you've dedicated your life to them; it's the United States government that supposedly trains you for PTSD and then all of you return from war with PTSD (Who are the a-holes? You, who are either failing your training, or the government who are failing to train you properly?). Is that what you bitches call "respect"? Under fire from your own government, it's about time you showed some real Courage Under Fire and tell them where to shove it next time they want to exploit you for political gain. That is, unless you really are as dumb as they consider you to be. Ooo-rah! --Poffy The Cucumber
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible Meg Ryan's Performance.Like Cpt. Walden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For people who just want to see Meg in the roles of this sugar romantic- goofy coms I guess that people were lobotomized by an actress and tarnish her, when she runs away from its stereotype and I'm outraged that they can not see versatility and potential Meg Ryan's polivalency.I just see the reviews, pure flattery these crappy actresses nowadays. Ask for Julia Roberts or Angelina Jolie Already piloted an US army chopper in a role? If Michelle Pffeifer or Goldie Hawn(Private Benjamin) played a role very perfectly and naturally of a single mother and determined who dipped the face on the war, and is required in command and demonstrates tight grip and mastery with weapons? without disparaging the Denzel Washignton, which signal, shone like Nathany when reports for soldiers a Karen Walden's deservering Medal of Honor, after Her death by Naphalms, but the episodes of drunkenness became a look dull and weak. Matt Damon,was terrific, skillfully retraced all the facts of 1991's Gulf War. Lou Diamond-Phillips was excellent as paper rebel, rough and impressive and opposite Cpt. Walden. whole more Credits goes to Meg Ryan & Lou D.Phillips, sure as Denzel is a Core person in this movie.Whatever, everybody stunned theirs performance ,But Meg Ryan razed ,and much. Meg Ryan deserves an Oscar. yet, once in her life gone to win.. If God willing.. She's Powerful and more Capable than Demi-Moore, Sharon Stone,and other contemporanies 90'ties Actresses,but Meg is overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    go night train, go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jack-964
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen this movie many years ago and remember i wasn't impressed by it. This was the movie that sunk Meg Ryan for me. I just saw it again and no, it's not worth remembering: I think its starts being lame with the story itself. Why on earth does it have to be a woman? If they wouldn't have put a woman in the center and obviously even worse, cast totally wrong, then the story could actually be interesting, elaborating on different views on the same event. But no, someone decided it had to be 'emancipated', then cast wrong, then pile up a load of unbelievable facts (like downing a tank with a fuel barrel from a helicopter under fire, yea right...) Also unbelievable is the fact that one guy can't stand the truth, even though he had no part in what happened, since he was injured. The other goes on drugs, even though he had no time to think about, let alone react to the lie the third one says. Which commits suicide all of a sudden, when urged to tell the truth, even though his life is going pretty well. And all this is investigated by someone that unknowingly killed a friend in combat, under fire, bla bla. The guy has a wife, kids, great job, status, money, house, and so on, but he can't cope with this accident? It's not all bad. You probably won't fall asleep, but when you find yourself rooting for the alleged bad guy, you know something is very wrong. Go night train go!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie helps heals me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sammy Young
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care about the petty "goofs" or parts of the story that other people point out- this movie means a lot to me as a disabled veteran with PTSD. This movie is about many things, but to me, the story is about how Col Sterling is trying to manage his survivor guilt and PTSD from his incident on one hand, and deal with his task to validate the medal for his General, his wife, his kids, etc. on the other. He resorts to booze (like we all do) to try to cope. That's what this movie is really about: how one guy is trying to come to grips with PTSD, which I can tell you first-hand is a challenge that I face every minute of everyday. And seeing this movie helps heal me. It reminds me that I too lost a promising career in the Navy, lost my marriage, lost my kids, and lost myself in the abyss of PTSD and alcoholism before I got help. That's the only negative I have on this movie- we don't see if Col Sterling got help. Otherwise, this movie has helped heal me in ways that no other movie I've ever seen has.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Prismatic Gulf War drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A strong contemporary war drama examining issues of loyalty, protocol, duty and ultimately truth in an unusually constructed film within a film, at the same using multiple viewpoints ( a la "Rashomon" or "Accident") to unfold the complicated truth at its heart. I'm not sure the somewhat contrived structure served the serious subject matter wholly convincingly, the cinematic devices detracting somewhat from the otherwise lifelike depiction of action in the Gulf War. I also thought Denzel Washington's framing role as the senior army officer given the seemingly straightforward task of reporting on the apparently automatic eligibility of Meg Ryan's posthumous award of the Army medal of honour detracted from the central mystery, especially as he wrestles with his own demons after unwittingly being involved in a tragic friendly-fire incident of his own. So Denz fights the bottle and walks out on his family, before uncovering the truth about Ryan's death and the way back to his own redemption. This final resolution and the underlying implication that the US Army welcomes openness is firstly too pat and improbable, especially in the wake of some real-life events that have come to light since then. All that said, the dramatisation of the war is very well realised and the acting is of a high order, Washington giving it strong and silent in a commanding lead role, but there are even better performances from a young Matt Damon and Lou Diamond-Phillips as two of Ryan's crew who survive the ordeal physically but not mentally. Ryan does well too and I was also impressed by the actress in the menial task of playing Washington's wife. Yes, the film ends up as you'd expect, replete with Washington's last respectful visit to Ryan's grave, but there was enough intrigue and grit in the tale to keep me watching throughout. A braver take on the story, inverting some of the discovered truths here might have made for a better film though, but of course there's no way that viewpoint would have been green-lighted in Hollywood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A resounding "meh"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Do you ever watch those movies that just elicit no reaction from you? I'm talking about the kind of movies that are just so straightforward and so flat that they draw out zero emotions in you and your opinion of the movie elevates to nothing above indifference. For me, this was the case with Courage Under Fire. It stars Denzel Washington as Col. Nat Serling, an army colonel investigating the legitimacy of a post humous Medal of Honor award going to Karen Warden, an army officer who was said to have died heroically while fighting the Iraqis during the Gulf War. However, there are too many discrepancies so Serling is enlisted to find out the truth about what happened to Warden the day her and her platoon went down in their chopper. The film is told through flashbacks which recount the events from different points of views. It's a Rashomon type of story in the way that the events are slightly altered depending on who is recounting them. It's a clever plot device, but not clever or interesting enough to make Courage Under Fire a great film. Don't get me wrong, it's decent. The story isn't something you will see every day and I have to give props to any film that utilizes a more unique narrative style. Akira Kurosawa's Rashomon started this style of the unreliable narrator in film, and it's films like Courage Under Fire that keep the style alive. The problem is that the film doesn't do anything particularly interesting with this narrative style. It plays out how you would expect it to and the actual structure of the film is pretty redundant as well. From start to finish it is essentially Denzel Washington going from place to place, interviewing people about the events that ended Warden's life until he finally gets the truth. There's no real feeling in this film and it lacks any kind of atmosphere or visual nuance. The story presented is engaging to an extent, but there's nothing else to really grab your attention. The bottom line behind Courage Under Fire is it is just a forgettable film. Nothing exists within this film that makes me want to tell people about it, or think about it down the line, or rewatch it ever again. It does things right and it isn't by any means a disaster, but due to its lack of feeling, dull atmosphere, and monotonous plot it just isn't what I would call a fantastic film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film About The 1991 Gulf War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Courage Under Fire is a film about the 1991 Gulf War.It stars Denzel Washington,Meg Ryan,Lou Diamond Phillips and Matt Damon. It is one of the first great films to depict the 1991 Gulf War as it tells a story of a US Army officer, despondent about a deadly mistake he made, investigates a female chopper commander's worthiness for the Medal of Honor.The movie was directed by Edward Zwick. Courage Under Fire has Lieutenant Colonel Nathaniel Serling involved in a friendly fire incident in Al Bathra during the Gulf War. He was an M1 Abrams tank battalion commander who, during the nighttime confusion of Iraqi tanks infiltrating his unit's lines, gave the order to fire, destroying one of his own tanks and killing his friend Lieutenant Boylar. The details were covered up and Serling was reassigned to a desk job.Later, he is assigned to determine if Army Captain Karen Emma Walden should be the first woman to receive the Medal of Honor for valor in combat in the Gulf War posthumously. A Medevac Huey commander, she was sent to rescue the crew of a helicopter that had been shot down. Finding them under heavy fire from an Iraqi tank and infantry, she had her men drop an auxiliary fuel tank on the tank and ignited it with a flare gun. Shortly after, her helicopter was also hit and downed. The two crews were unable to join forces. The survivors were rescued the next day, but Walden had been killed in action.At first, everything seems to be straightforward, but Serling begins to notice inconsistencies between the testimonies of the witnesses. Walden's co-pilot, Warrant Officer One Rady, praises Walden's character and performance, but was hit and unconscious early on. Serling then sees Walden's medic, Specialist Ilario, who also praises Walden. Staff Sergeant Monfriez, however, tells Serling that Walden was a coward. The members of the other downed crew also mention that they heard the distinctive sound of an M16 being used in the firefight during the rescue around the other helicopter, but Walden's crew denies firing one during the rescue, as theirs was out of ammunition. When Serling visits Walden's crew chief, Sergeant Altameyer, who is dying of cancer in a hospital. Altameyer manages to get some words out, further confusing Serling, before self-medicating himself into unconsciousness.Under pressure from the White House and his commander, Brigadier General Hershberg, to wrap things up quickly, Serling leaks the story to newspaper reporter Tony Gartner to prevent another cover up. When Serling puts pressure on Monfriez, the man pulls a pistol at him, then commits suicide by driving his car into an oncoming train.After finding Ilario, Serling discovers that Monfriez wanted to escape under cover of darkness, which would have meant leaving Rady behind. Altameyer was ready to follow his lead and Ilario was wavering, but Walden refused to go along, resulting in an armed standoff with Monfriez. When an Iraqi infantryman appeared suddenly behind Monfriez, Walden fired at him. Mistakenly believing he was the target, Monfriez shot back and seriously wounded her. Walden, however, regained control of her men.The next morning, Walden stayed behind to cover their evacuation, firing the M16. Monfriez deliberately lied to the rescuers, telling them that she was dead so she would be left behind. Altameyer, injured and unable to say anything was ignored. Ilario remained silent. A-10 airplanes then napalmed the wreckage.Serling presents his final report to Hershberg. Walden's young daughter receives the Medal of Honor in a White House ceremony. Later, Serling tearfully tells the Boylars the truth about the manner of their son's death. In the last moments of the film, it is shown that Walden had transported Boylar's body away from the battlefield. Courage Under Fire is definitely one outstanding film about the Gulf War.It tells an emotional and intriguing tale of a military officer who must review the merits of a fallen officer while confronting his own war demons that makes us feel for every character involved in the story.Also,the movie tells effectively the terrors brought about by war as well as its heartbreaking aftermath.It presents it treats with clarity and intelligence that truly makes it a brilliant film.Another good thing about it is the movie avoids the use of too much violence and swearing to present its story.The performances of the cast were great.Special mention must be given to Denzel Washington for he dominates a film with his quiet intensity and aura of introspection.Credit must also be given to Meg Ryan and Matt Damon,who tried his best to look realistic in his role by shedding many pounds to lose a lot of weight. Overall,Courage Under Fire is a movie that a viewer should not miss as it ranks up there with Platoon and Born On The Fourth Of July as outstanding war films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film with a couple of standout performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just for the record, at least here on IMDb, I think this is an underrated film. And I say that as a person who very rarely likes movies about the military. My dad was in the military most of his adult life, and when he would come home on leave he would always drag me to some war film. I hated it. So, I rarely watch a war movie. But this is a keeper. First, the cast. And let me review the actors in the order of how impressive they were in this film. Denzel Washington, as a Lieutenant Colonel investigating whether a dead female captain should receive the Medal Of Honor, and who himself may have been involved in friendly fire deaths, and who has an alcohol problem, is excellent. Lou Diamond Phillips, as a Staff Sergeant who was at the helicopter crash where the female soldier was killed, is superb here (I never knew he was such a hunk...just for the record). Regina Taylor, as the wife of Washington, is excellent! Meg Ryan, the helicopter pilot who dies, is good, but although her role is pivotal, this is not a very good showcase of her talents, and I do not see her here as the co-star to Denzel Washington. I found Matt Damon rather unimpressive here, but of course, this was just before his breakthrough role that immediately followed this film. Bronson Pinchot was an interesting choice as a White House aide, and he does okay. Michael Moriarty is good as a Brigadier General, as is Scott Glenn as a Washington Post reporter. While I can't say whether or not the Iraq battle scenes were realistic, they impressed me. Despite some inconsistencies, I think the story is a good one. And not a simple one, since the issues that Denzel Washington's character has are complicating his investigation of whether or not Ryan's character should receive the Medal Of Honor. Washington does an admirable job of mixing all these factors and fleshing out the character traits of his role. In fact, this was one of Washington's early films which convinced me that he was an actor that America should treasure. Despite a few flaws, highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overly Sentimental and Top Heavy...But Above Average
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a strong Story here as an investigation ensues about a potential Medal of Honor recipient and the mysterious conflict of testimonies. It is given a twist with a shot of estrogen as the Soldier involved is the first Female to possibly (Posthumously) be awarded the Nation's Highest Military Honor. That should be enough to make this a riveting Mystery and through flashbacks we are shown some striking battle Scenes. So why add the conflict and strife to the investigating Officer. It is completely unnecessary and is the weakest part of the Film and almost drags it down with unconvincing situations of Combat guilt and Family Dysfunction. That could be a whole other Movie. But with that bloating aside there are some strong Performances by the young Cast (actually outshining Denzel) in supporting Roles as the Combat Unit in question. There is a back Story to everyone and it holds up quite well with the central Theme. It must be mentioned here that although, Meg Ryan is miscast as the Captain, she tries her best but cannot outgrow her limitations and convince as a tough Girl in a hopeless, self sacrificing situation. Overall, not a bad Movie and is worth a watch for the strong parts, but there is much too much padding here, plus the heavy dose of sentimentality finally drags this down from Great Movie to just above Average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very, very pretentious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    floyd beck
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry, but I cannot stomach a movie that is pro-military when Meg Ryan, a devout Democrat and worshiper of John Kerry, the war-hater and devout liar, and Denzel Washington, a worshiper of President Obama and a devout Democrat who is said to be a devout Christian. One cannot be both...in 2011, the Democrats voted NO to have God inserted in their convention, in spite of the chairman's blatant lie; just one of 100 reasons. So, after my ranting, what about the movie? It is too hard to believe any of it because the actors are not sincere in true life. It would be like having an openly gay person portray Rudolph Valentino unless the movie was a comedy. Courage Under Fire does not pass as a comedy unless one forces one's mind to the point of insanity to see liberal war-hating actors and actresses pretend to be pro-military.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gutless Under Clich&eacute;
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunmore_ego
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, I know it's trying to be inspiring and heroic and poignant, but COURAGE UNDER FIRE is one of the most blatantly gutless movies ever made. About a soldier investigating whether a downed female United States helicopter pilot in Desert Storm deserves a posthumous Medal of Honor. So I ask you: in which universe will America ever make a movie where a Medal of Honor is investigated and NOT awarded? So it's a foregone conclusion--all the mystery and mayhem and maybes are simply wasting our time more than the actual war this story was set in--as it leads inexorably to the melodramatic military funeral, the flags, saluting, tears of the family, proud shiny buttons and white gloves, the flyover with one plane breaking formation, and that bilious, bleating orchestra swell. And the Medal. The End. Cry me a river; cry me a patently meaningless award, military swine. Then the coda: the investigating soldier visits pilot's grave, salutes grave, tiny flag, voice-over of dead pilot to American Pie Mom and Dad, talking of the Big Push and hero hero hero hero hero hero another blithering orchestra swell I'm going to vomit... Denzel Washington is the investigating soldier, with demons of his own. (Well, they're not really demons; they're roiling stabs of conscience he feels for stupidly shooting one of his own tanks during a skirmish, killing his own men in the hilariously black euphemism "friendly fire," and then having the military cover-up his blunder.) And whenever he has visions of that po' boy he fricasseed in that tank (Mmm! Soldierboy, the other white meat!), he heads straight for the alcohol... uh, cos he's a hero, see. When he's asked to investigate whether Captain Karen Walden (Meg Ryan) is worthy of receiving the Medal of Honor for "courage under fire," the story ends right there. Of course she's deserving of it. She's the first female officer recommended, she's regarded as a hero for sacrificing her life for her men--and she's Meg Ryan. As if the movie would go to all the trouble setting up her heroism and feminism and Ryanism and NOT award her the medal. And every clich&eacute; in the military lexicon is thrown at us like grenades lobbed into foxholes: the tragic family; damaged goods investigating damaged goods; the novice (Matt Damon), the toughguy (Lou Diamond Phillips), the hero-worshipper (Tim Guinee) and all the other bumboys like the Benetton passengers of SPEED; the hospitalized guy (Seth Gilliam) whose seen one battle too many; the military cover-up. And everyone's got Movie PTSD. Denzel wants to find out "what really happened," so COURAGE is constructed like a RASHOMON for rednecks, as we see all the alternate flashbacks with a coy Walden, an indecisive Walden and a butch Walden barking orders and trying not to look like a sex object. Not one of the scenarios is ambiguous about her Hero status--no matter if she threw Iraqi babies at walls or defunded the G.I. Bill. If we can call football players heroes, and people who jumped from the Twin Towers heroes, then this chopper pilot must be a shoo-in, so I ask again: what compels viewers to spend 120 minutes *pretending* there's any doubt? Denzel visits Walden's helicopter bumboys, who all give differing accounts of My Night In The Desert With Captain Walden. Diamond Phillips claims he was the toughguy, as he lies and plies himself with alcohol and commits suicide (cos he's a hero!); Damon claims Walden was a strategic hardnose, as he admits to being a junkie and afraid to go flying again (cos he's a hero!); Guinee relates how Walden sacrificed herself for them, even as he reveals how she got them shot down by taking another pass at an Iraqi tank when she could have flown away--cognitive dissonance rules!--while constantly telling his wife to shutup for calling Walden butch (cos he's a hero!); while Seth Gilliam pounds his medication to numb himself out of the running as a reputable eyewitness (cos he's a hero, see!). What's in it for her bumboys to report that she was a coward? Nothing. But saying she was a HERO makes them vicarious heroes alongside her. Ooo-rah! And here's a note to all you military wardogs whose first reaction is to Spock-chop me for "disrespecting" you (such heroes, fighting for peace!): When are you going to realize your own government, who pays you hypocritical lip service, regards you with even less respect than I do? I just consider you deluded and egotistical and sometimes uneducated, while they consider you cannon fodder! It's the United States government that fools you into getting your asses shot off for them in the first place; it's the United States government that refuses you and your family financial benefits when you return from war; it's the United States government that stop-losses you, reneging on your stipulated leave time, over and over and over again; it's the United States government that cuts your medical funding; it's the United States government that evicts your family, that lies about friendly fire, that doesn't provide armor for you or your vehicles; it's the United States government that kicks you out for being gay after you've dedicated your life to them; it's the United States government that supposedly trains you for PTSD and then all of you return from war with PTSD (Who are the a-holes? You, who are either failing your training, or the government who are failing to train you properly?). Is that what you bitches call "respect"? Under fire from your own government, it's about time you showed some real Courage Under Fire and tell them where to shove it next time they want to exploit you for political gain. That is, unless you really are as dumb as they consider you to be. Ooo-rah! --Poffy The Cucumber
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible Meg Ryan's Performance.Like Cpt. Walden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For people who just want to see Meg in the roles of this sugar romantic- goofy coms I guess that people were lobotomized by an actress and tarnish her, when she runs away from its stereotype and I'm outraged that they can not see versatility and potential Meg Ryan's polivalency.I just see the reviews, pure flattery these crappy actresses nowadays. Ask for Julia Roberts or Angelina Jolie Already piloted an US army chopper in a role? If Michelle Pffeifer or Goldie Hawn(Private Benjamin) played a role very perfectly and naturally of a single mother and determined who dipped the face on the war, and is required in command and demonstrates tight grip and mastery with weapons? without disparaging the Denzel Washignton, which signal, shone like Nathany when reports for soldiers a Karen Walden's deservering Medal of Honor, after Her death by Naphalms, but the episodes of drunkenness became a look dull and weak. Matt Damon,was terrific, skillfully retraced all the facts of 1991's Gulf War. Lou Diamond-Phillips was excellent as paper rebel, rough and impressive and opposite Cpt. Walden. whole more Credits goes to Meg Ryan & Lou D.Phillips, sure as Denzel is a Core person in this movie.Whatever, everybody stunned theirs performance ,But Meg Ryan razed ,and much. Meg Ryan deserves an Oscar. yet, once in her life gone to win.. If God willing.. She's Powerful and more Capable than Demi-Moore, Sharon Stone,and other contemporanies 90'ties Actresses,but Meg is overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    go night train, go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jack-964
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen this movie many years ago and remember i wasn't impressed by it. This was the movie that sunk Meg Ryan for me. I just saw it again and no, it's not worth remembering: I think its starts being lame with the story itself. Why on earth does it have to be a woman? If they wouldn't have put a woman in the center and obviously even worse, cast totally wrong, then the story could actually be interesting, elaborating on different views on the same event. But no, someone decided it had to be 'emancipated', then cast wrong, then pile up a load of unbelievable facts (like downing a tank with a fuel barrel from a helicopter under fire, yea right...) Also unbelievable is the fact that one guy can't stand the truth, even though he had no part in what happened, since he was injured. The other goes on drugs, even though he had no time to think about, let alone react to the lie the third one says. Which commits suicide all of a sudden, when urged to tell the truth, even though his life is going pretty well. And all this is investigated by someone that unknowingly killed a friend in combat, under fire, bla bla. The guy has a wife, kids, great job, status, money, house, and so on, but he can't cope with this accident? It's not all bad. You probably won't fall asleep, but when you find yourself rooting for the alleged bad guy, you know something is very wrong. Go night train go!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie helps heals me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sammy Young
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care about the petty "goofs" or parts of the story that other people point out- this movie means a lot to me as a disabled veteran with PTSD. This movie is about many things, but to me, the story is about how Col Sterling is trying to manage his survivor guilt and PTSD from his incident on one hand, and deal with his task to validate the medal for his General, his wife, his kids, etc. on the other. He resorts to booze (like we all do) to try to cope. That's what this movie is really about: how one guy is trying to come to grips with PTSD, which I can tell you first-hand is a challenge that I face every minute of everyday. And seeing this movie helps heal me. It reminds me that I too lost a promising career in the Navy, lost my marriage, lost my kids, and lost myself in the abyss of PTSD and alcoholism before I got help. That's the only negative I have on this movie- we don't see if Col Sterling got help. Otherwise, this movie has helped heal me in ways that no other movie I've ever seen has.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Prismatic Gulf War drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A strong contemporary war drama examining issues of loyalty, protocol, duty and ultimately truth in an unusually constructed film within a film, at the same using multiple viewpoints ( a la "Rashomon" or "Accident") to unfold the complicated truth at its heart. I'm not sure the somewhat contrived structure served the serious subject matter wholly convincingly, the cinematic devices detracting somewhat from the otherwise lifelike depiction of action in the Gulf War. I also thought Denzel Washington's framing role as the senior army officer given the seemingly straightforward task of reporting on the apparently automatic eligibility of Meg Ryan's posthumous award of the Army medal of honour detracted from the central mystery, especially as he wrestles with his own demons after unwittingly being involved in a tragic friendly-fire incident of his own. So Denz fights the bottle and walks out on his family, before uncovering the truth about Ryan's death and the way back to his own redemption. This final resolution and the underlying implication that the US Army welcomes openness is firstly too pat and improbable, especially in the wake of some real-life events that have come to light since then. All that said, the dramatisation of the war is very well realised and the acting is of a high order, Washington giving it strong and silent in a commanding lead role, but there are even better performances from a young Matt Damon and Lou Diamond-Phillips as two of Ryan's crew who survive the ordeal physically but not mentally. Ryan does well too and I was also impressed by the actress in the menial task of playing Washington's wife. Yes, the film ends up as you'd expect, replete with Washington's last respectful visit to Ryan's grave, but there was enough intrigue and grit in the tale to keep me watching throughout. A braver take on the story, inverting some of the discovered truths here might have made for a better film though, but of course there's no way that viewpoint would have been green-lighted in Hollywood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A resounding "meh"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Do you ever watch those movies that just elicit no reaction from you? I'm talking about the kind of movies that are just so straightforward and so flat that they draw out zero emotions in you and your opinion of the movie elevates to nothing above indifference. For me, this was the case with Courage Under Fire. It stars Denzel Washington as Col. Nat Serling, an army colonel investigating the legitimacy of a post humous Medal of Honor award going to Karen Warden, an army officer who was said to have died heroically while fighting the Iraqis during the Gulf War. However, there are too many discrepancies so Serling is enlisted to find out the truth about what happened to Warden the day her and her platoon went down in their chopper. The film is told through flashbacks which recount the events from different points of views. It's a Rashomon type of story in the way that the events are slightly altered depending on who is recounting them. It's a clever plot device, but not clever or interesting enough to make Courage Under Fire a great film. Don't get me wrong, it's decent. The story isn't something you will see every day and I have to give props to any film that utilizes a more unique narrative style. Akira Kurosawa's Rashomon started this style of the unreliable narrator in film, and it's films like Courage Under Fire that keep the style alive. The problem is that the film doesn't do anything particularly interesting with this narrative style. It plays out how you would expect it to and the actual structure of the film is pretty redundant as well. From start to finish it is essentially Denzel Washington going from place to place, interviewing people about the events that ended Warden's life until he finally gets the truth. There's no real feeling in this film and it lacks any kind of atmosphere or visual nuance. The story presented is engaging to an extent, but there's nothing else to really grab your attention. The bottom line behind Courage Under Fire is it is just a forgettable film. Nothing exists within this film that makes me want to tell people about it, or think about it down the line, or rewatch it ever again. It does things right and it isn't by any means a disaster, but due to its lack of feeling, dull atmosphere, and monotonous plot it just isn't what I would call a fantastic film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film About The 1991 Gulf War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Courage Under Fire is a film about the 1991 Gulf War.It stars Denzel Washington,Meg Ryan,Lou Diamond Phillips and Matt Damon. It is one of the first great films to depict the 1991 Gulf War as it tells a story of a US Army officer, despondent about a deadly mistake he made, investigates a female chopper commander's worthiness for the Medal of Honor.The movie was directed by Edward Zwick. Courage Under Fire has Lieutenant Colonel Nathaniel Serling involved in a friendly fire incident in Al Bathra during the Gulf War. He was an M1 Abrams tank battalion commander who, during the nighttime confusion of Iraqi tanks infiltrating his unit's lines, gave the order to fire, destroying one of his own tanks and killing his friend Lieutenant Boylar. The details were covered up and Serling was reassigned to a desk job.Later, he is assigned to determine if Army Captain Karen Emma Walden should be the first woman to receive the Medal of Honor for valor in combat in the Gulf War posthumously. A Medevac Huey commander, she was sent to rescue the crew of a helicopter that had been shot down. Finding them under heavy fire from an Iraqi tank and infantry, she had her men drop an auxiliary fuel tank on the tank and ignited it with a flare gun. Shortly after, her helicopter was also hit and downed. The two crews were unable to join forces. The survivors were rescued the next day, but Walden had been killed in action.At first, everything seems to be straightforward, but Serling begins to notice inconsistencies between the testimonies of the witnesses. Walden's co-pilot, Warrant Officer One Rady, praises Walden's character and performance, but was hit and unconscious early on. Serling then sees Walden's medic, Specialist Ilario, who also praises Walden. Staff Sergeant Monfriez, however, tells Serling that Walden was a coward. The members of the other downed crew also mention that they heard the distinctive sound of an M16 being used in the firefight during the rescue around the other helicopter, but Walden's crew denies firing one during the rescue, as theirs was out of ammunition. When Serling visits Walden's crew chief, Sergeant Altameyer, who is dying of cancer in a hospital. Altameyer manages to get some words out, further confusing Serling, before self-medicating himself into unconsciousness.Under pressure from the White House and his commander, Brigadier General Hershberg, to wrap things up quickly, Serling leaks the story to newspaper reporter Tony Gartner to prevent another cover up. When Serling puts pressure on Monfriez, the man pulls a pistol at him, then commits suicide by driving his car into an oncoming train.After finding Ilario, Serling discovers that Monfriez wanted to escape under cover of darkness, which would have meant leaving Rady behind. Altameyer was ready to follow his lead and Ilario was wavering, but Walden refused to go along, resulting in an armed standoff with Monfriez. When an Iraqi infantryman appeared suddenly behind Monfriez, Walden fired at him. Mistakenly believing he was the target, Monfriez shot back and seriously wounded her. Walden, however, regained control of her men.The next morning, Walden stayed behind to cover their evacuation, firing the M16. Monfriez deliberately lied to the rescuers, telling them that she was dead so she would be left behind. Altameyer, injured and unable to say anything was ignored. Ilario remained silent. A-10 airplanes then napalmed the wreckage.Serling presents his final report to Hershberg. Walden's young daughter receives the Medal of Honor in a White House ceremony. Later, Serling tearfully tells the Boylars the truth about the manner of their son's death. In the last moments of the film, it is shown that Walden had transported Boylar's body away from the battlefield. Courage Under Fire is definitely one outstanding film about the Gulf War.It tells an emotional and intriguing tale of a military officer who must review the merits of a fallen officer while confronting his own war demons that makes us feel for every character involved in the story.Also,the movie tells effectively the terrors brought about by war as well as its heartbreaking aftermath.It presents it treats with clarity and intelligence that truly makes it a brilliant film.Another good thing about it is the movie avoids the use of too much violence and swearing to present its story.The performances of the cast were great.Special mention must be given to Denzel Washington for he dominates a film with his quiet intensity and aura of introspection.Credit must also be given to Meg Ryan and Matt Damon,who tried his best to look realistic in his role by shedding many pounds to lose a lot of weight. Overall,Courage Under Fire is a movie that a viewer should not miss as it ranks up there with Platoon and Born On The Fourth Of July as outstanding war films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film with a couple of standout performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just for the record, at least here on IMDb, I think this is an underrated film. And I say that as a person who very rarely likes movies about the military. My dad was in the military most of his adult life, and when he would come home on leave he would always drag me to some war film. I hated it. So, I rarely watch a war movie. But this is a keeper. First, the cast. And let me review the actors in the order of how impressive they were in this film. Denzel Washington, as a Lieutenant Colonel investigating whether a dead female captain should receive the Medal Of Honor, and who himself may have been involved in friendly fire deaths, and who has an alcohol problem, is excellent. Lou Diamond Phillips, as a Staff Sergeant who was at the helicopter crash where the female soldier was killed, is superb here (I never knew he was such a hunk...just for the record). Regina Taylor, as the wife of Washington, is excellent! Meg Ryan, the helicopter pilot who dies, is good, but although her role is pivotal, this is not a very good showcase of her talents, and I do not see her here as the co-star to Denzel Washington. I found Matt Damon rather unimpressive here, but of course, this was just before his breakthrough role that immediately followed this film. Bronson Pinchot was an interesting choice as a White House aide, and he does okay. Michael Moriarty is good as a Brigadier General, as is Scott Glenn as a Washington Post reporter. While I can't say whether or not the Iraq battle scenes were realistic, they impressed me. Despite some inconsistencies, I think the story is a good one. And not a simple one, since the issues that Denzel Washington's character has are complicating his investigation of whether or not Ryan's character should receive the Medal Of Honor. Washington does an admirable job of mixing all these factors and fleshing out the character traits of his role. In fact, this was one of Washington's early films which convinced me that he was an actor that America should treasure. Despite a few flaws, highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overly Sentimental and Top Heavy...But Above Average
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a strong Story here as an investigation ensues about a potential Medal of Honor recipient and the mysterious conflict of testimonies. It is given a twist with a shot of estrogen as the Soldier involved is the first Female to possibly (Posthumously) be awarded the Nation's Highest Military Honor. That should be enough to make this a riveting Mystery and through flashbacks we are shown some striking battle Scenes. So why add the conflict and strife to the investigating Officer. It is completely unnecessary and is the weakest part of the Film and almost drags it down with unconvincing situations of Combat guilt and Family Dysfunction. That could be a whole other Movie. But with that bloating aside there are some strong Performances by the young Cast (actually outshining Denzel) in supporting Roles as the Combat Unit in question. There is a back Story to everyone and it holds up quite well with the central Theme. It must be mentioned here that although, Meg Ryan is miscast as the Captain, she tries her best but cannot outgrow her limitations and convince as a tough Girl in a hopeless, self sacrificing situation. Overall, not a bad Movie and is worth a watch for the strong parts, but there is much too much padding here, plus the heavy dose of sentimentality finally drags this down from Great Movie to just above Average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very, very pretentious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    floyd beck
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry, but I cannot stomach a movie that is pro-military when Meg Ryan, a devout Democrat and worshiper of John Kerry, the war-hater and devout liar, and Denzel Washington, a worshiper of President Obama and a devout Democrat who is said to be a devout Christian. One cannot be both...in 2011, the Democrats voted NO to have God inserted in their convention, in spite of the chairman's blatant lie; just one of 100 reasons. So, after my ranting, what about the movie? It is too hard to believe any of it because the actors are not sincere in true life. It would be like having an openly gay person portray Rudolph Valentino unless the movie was a comedy. Courage Under Fire does not pass as a comedy unless one forces one's mind to the point of insanity to see liberal war-hating actors and actresses pretend to be pro-military.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gutless Under Clich&eacute;
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunmore_ego
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, I know it's trying to be inspiring and heroic and poignant, but COURAGE UNDER FIRE is one of the most blatantly gutless movies ever made. About a soldier investigating whether a downed female United States helicopter pilot in Desert Storm deserves a posthumous Medal of Honor. So I ask you: in which universe will America ever make a movie where a Medal of Honor is investigated and NOT awarded? So it's a foregone conclusion--all the mystery and mayhem and maybes are simply wasting our time more than the actual war this story was set in--as it leads inexorably to the melodramatic military funeral, the flags, saluting, tears of the family, proud shiny buttons and white gloves, the flyover with one plane breaking formation, and that bilious, bleating orchestra swell. And the Medal. The End. Cry me a river; cry me a patently meaningless award, military swine. Then the coda: the investigating soldier visits pilot's grave, salutes grave, tiny flag, voice-over of dead pilot to American Pie Mom and Dad, talking of the Big Push and hero hero hero hero hero hero another blithering orchestra swell I'm going to vomit... Denzel Washington is the investigating soldier, with demons of his own. (Well, they're not really demons; they're roiling stabs of conscience he feels for stupidly shooting one of his own tanks during a skirmish, killing his own men in the hilariously black euphemism "friendly fire," and then having the military cover-up his blunder.) And whenever he has visions of that po' boy he fricasseed in that tank (Mmm! Soldierboy, the other white meat!), he heads straight for the alcohol... uh, cos he's a hero, see. When he's asked to investigate whether Captain Karen Walden (Meg Ryan) is worthy of receiving the Medal of Honor for "courage under fire," the story ends right there. Of course she's deserving of it. She's the first female officer recommended, she's regarded as a hero for sacrificing her life for her men--and she's Meg Ryan. As if the movie would go to all the trouble setting up her heroism and feminism and Ryanism and NOT award her the medal. And every clich&eacute; in the military lexicon is thrown at us like grenades lobbed into foxholes: the tragic family; damaged goods investigating damaged goods; the novice (Matt Damon), the toughguy (Lou Diamond Phillips), the hero-worshipper (Tim Guinee) and all the other bumboys like the Benetton passengers of SPEED; the hospitalized guy (Seth Gilliam) whose seen one battle too many; the military cover-up. And everyone's got Movie PTSD. Denzel wants to find out "what really happened," so COURAGE is constructed like a RASHOMON for rednecks, as we see all the alternate flashbacks with a coy Walden, an indecisive Walden and a butch Walden barking orders and trying not to look like a sex object. Not one of the scenarios is ambiguous about her Hero status--no matter if she threw Iraqi babies at walls or defunded the G.I. Bill. If we can call football players heroes, and people who jumped from the Twin Towers heroes, then this chopper pilot must be a shoo-in, so I ask again: what compels viewers to spend 120 minutes *pretending* there's any doubt? Denzel visits Walden's helicopter bumboys, who all give differing accounts of My Night In The Desert With Captain Walden. Diamond Phillips claims he was the toughguy, as he lies and plies himself with alcohol and commits suicide (cos he's a hero!); Damon claims Walden was a strategic hardnose, as he admits to being a junkie and afraid to go flying again (cos he's a hero!); Guinee relates how Walden sacrificed herself for them, even as he reveals how she got them shot down by taking another pass at an Iraqi tank when she could have flown away--cognitive dissonance rules!--while constantly telling his wife to shutup for calling Walden butch (cos he's a hero!); while Seth Gilliam pounds his medication to numb himself out of the running as a reputable eyewitness (cos he's a hero, see!). What's in it for her bumboys to report that she was a coward? Nothing. But saying she was a HERO makes them vicarious heroes alongside her. Ooo-rah! And here's a note to all you military wardogs whose first reaction is to Spock-chop me for "disrespecting" you (such heroes, fighting for peace!): When are you going to realize your own government, who pays you hypocritical lip service, regards you with even less respect than I do? I just consider you deluded and egotistical and sometimes uneducated, while they consider you cannon fodder! It's the United States government that fools you into getting your asses shot off for them in the first place; it's the United States government that refuses you and your family financial benefits when you return from war; it's the United States government that stop-losses you, reneging on your stipulated leave time, over and over and over again; it's the United States government that cuts your medical funding; it's the United States government that evicts your family, that lies about friendly fire, that doesn't provide armor for you or your vehicles; it's the United States government that kicks you out for being gay after you've dedicated your life to them; it's the United States government that supposedly trains you for PTSD and then all of you return from war with PTSD (Who are the a-holes? You, who are either failing your training, or the government who are failing to train you properly?). Is that what you bitches call "respect"? Under fire from your own government, it's about time you showed some real Courage Under Fire and tell them where to shove it next time they want to exploit you for political gain. That is, unless you really are as dumb as they consider you to be. Ooo-rah! --Poffy The Cucumber
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible Meg Ryan's Performance.Like Cpt. Walden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For people who just want to see Meg in the roles of this sugar romantic- goofy coms I guess that people were lobotomized by an actress and tarnish her, when she runs away from its stereotype and I'm outraged that they can not see versatility and potential Meg Ryan's polivalency.I just see the reviews, pure flattery these crappy actresses nowadays. Ask for Julia Roberts or Angelina Jolie Already piloted an US army chopper in a role? If Michelle Pffeifer or Goldie Hawn(Private Benjamin) played a role very perfectly and naturally of a single mother and determined who dipped the face on the war, and is required in command and demonstrates tight grip and mastery with weapons? without disparaging the Denzel Washignton, which signal, shone like Nathany when reports for soldiers a Karen Walden's deservering Medal of Honor, after Her death by Naphalms, but the episodes of drunkenness became a look dull and weak. Matt Damon,was terrific, skillfully retraced all the facts of 1991's Gulf War. Lou Diamond-Phillips was excellent as paper rebel, rough and impressive and opposite Cpt. Walden. whole more Credits goes to Meg Ryan & Lou D.Phillips, sure as Denzel is a Core person in this movie.Whatever, everybody stunned theirs performance ,But Meg Ryan razed ,and much. Meg Ryan deserves an Oscar. yet, once in her life gone to win.. If God willing.. She's Powerful and more Capable than Demi-Moore, Sharon Stone,and other contemporanies 90'ties Actresses,but Meg is overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    go night train, go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jack-964
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen this movie many years ago and remember i wasn't impressed by it. This was the movie that sunk Meg Ryan for me. I just saw it again and no, it's not worth remembering: I think its starts being lame with the story itself. Why on earth does it have to be a woman? If they wouldn't have put a woman in the center and obviously even worse, cast totally wrong, then the story could actually be interesting, elaborating on different views on the same event. But no, someone decided it had to be 'emancipated', then cast wrong, then pile up a load of unbelievable facts (like downing a tank with a fuel barrel from a helicopter under fire, yea right...) Also unbelievable is the fact that one guy can't stand the truth, even though he had no part in what happened, since he was injured. The other goes on drugs, even though he had no time to think about, let alone react to the lie the third one says. Which commits suicide all of a sudden, when urged to tell the truth, even though his life is going pretty well. And all this is investigated by someone that unknowingly killed a friend in combat, under fire, bla bla. The guy has a wife, kids, great job, status, money, house, and so on, but he can't cope with this accident? It's not all bad. You probably won't fall asleep, but when you find yourself rooting for the alleged bad guy, you know something is very wrong. Go night train go!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie helps heals me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sammy Young
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care about the petty "goofs" or parts of the story that other people point out- this movie means a lot to me as a disabled veteran with PTSD. This movie is about many things, but to me, the story is about how Col Sterling is trying to manage his survivor guilt and PTSD from his incident on one hand, and deal with his task to validate the medal for his General, his wife, his kids, etc. on the other. He resorts to booze (like we all do) to try to cope. That's what this movie is really about: how one guy is trying to come to grips with PTSD, which I can tell you first-hand is a challenge that I face every minute of everyday. And seeing this movie helps heal me. It reminds me that I too lost a promising career in the Navy, lost my marriage, lost my kids, and lost myself in the abyss of PTSD and alcoholism before I got help. That's the only negative I have on this movie- we don't see if Col Sterling got help. Otherwise, this movie has helped heal me in ways that no other movie I've ever seen has.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Prismatic Gulf War drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A strong contemporary war drama examining issues of loyalty, protocol, duty and ultimately truth in an unusually constructed film within a film, at the same using multiple viewpoints ( a la "Rashomon" or "Accident") to unfold the complicated truth at its heart. I'm not sure the somewhat contrived structure served the serious subject matter wholly convincingly, the cinematic devices detracting somewhat from the otherwise lifelike depiction of action in the Gulf War. I also thought Denzel Washington's framing role as the senior army officer given the seemingly straightforward task of reporting on the apparently automatic eligibility of Meg Ryan's posthumous award of the Army medal of honour detracted from the central mystery, especially as he wrestles with his own demons after unwittingly being involved in a tragic friendly-fire incident of his own. So Denz fights the bottle and walks out on his family, before uncovering the truth about Ryan's death and the way back to his own redemption. This final resolution and the underlying implication that the US Army welcomes openness is firstly too pat and improbable, especially in the wake of some real-life events that have come to light since then. All that said, the dramatisation of the war is very well realised and the acting is of a high order, Washington giving it strong and silent in a commanding lead role, but there are even better performances from a young Matt Damon and Lou Diamond-Phillips as two of Ryan's crew who survive the ordeal physically but not mentally. Ryan does well too and I was also impressed by the actress in the menial task of playing Washington's wife. Yes, the film ends up as you'd expect, replete with Washington's last respectful visit to Ryan's grave, but there was enough intrigue and grit in the tale to keep me watching throughout. A braver take on the story, inverting some of the discovered truths here might have made for a better film though, but of course there's no way that viewpoint would have been green-lighted in Hollywood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A resounding "meh"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Do you ever watch those movies that just elicit no reaction from you? I'm talking about the kind of movies that are just so straightforward and so flat that they draw out zero emotions in you and your opinion of the movie elevates to nothing above indifference. For me, this was the case with Courage Under Fire. It stars Denzel Washington as Col. Nat Serling, an army colonel investigating the legitimacy of a post humous Medal of Honor award going to Karen Warden, an army officer who was said to have died heroically while fighting the Iraqis during the Gulf War. However, there are too many discrepancies so Serling is enlisted to find out the truth about what happened to Warden the day her and her platoon went down in their chopper. The film is told through flashbacks which recount the events from different points of views. It's a Rashomon type of story in the way that the events are slightly altered depending on who is recounting them. It's a clever plot device, but not clever or interesting enough to make Courage Under Fire a great film. Don't get me wrong, it's decent. The story isn't something you will see every day and I have to give props to any film that utilizes a more unique narrative style. Akira Kurosawa's Rashomon started this style of the unreliable narrator in film, and it's films like Courage Under Fire that keep the style alive. The problem is that the film doesn't do anything particularly interesting with this narrative style. It plays out how you would expect it to and the actual structure of the film is pretty redundant as well. From start to finish it is essentially Denzel Washington going from place to place, interviewing people about the events that ended Warden's life until he finally gets the truth. There's no real feeling in this film and it lacks any kind of atmosphere or visual nuance. The story presented is engaging to an extent, but there's nothing else to really grab your attention. The bottom line behind Courage Under Fire is it is just a forgettable film. Nothing exists within this film that makes me want to tell people about it, or think about it down the line, or rewatch it ever again. It does things right and it isn't by any means a disaster, but due to its lack of feeling, dull atmosphere, and monotonous plot it just isn't what I would call a fantastic film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film About The 1991 Gulf War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Courage Under Fire is a film about the 1991 Gulf War.It stars Denzel Washington,Meg Ryan,Lou Diamond Phillips and Matt Damon. It is one of the first great films to depict the 1991 Gulf War as it tells a story of a US Army officer, despondent about a deadly mistake he made, investigates a female chopper commander's worthiness for the Medal of Honor.The movie was directed by Edward Zwick. Courage Under Fire has Lieutenant Colonel Nathaniel Serling involved in a friendly fire incident in Al Bathra during the Gulf War. He was an M1 Abrams tank battalion commander who, during the nighttime confusion of Iraqi tanks infiltrating his unit's lines, gave the order to fire, destroying one of his own tanks and killing his friend Lieutenant Boylar. The details were covered up and Serling was reassigned to a desk job.Later, he is assigned to determine if Army Captain Karen Emma Walden should be the first woman to receive the Medal of Honor for valor in combat in the Gulf War posthumously. A Medevac Huey commander, she was sent to rescue the crew of a helicopter that had been shot down. Finding them under heavy fire from an Iraqi tank and infantry, she had her men drop an auxiliary fuel tank on the tank and ignited it with a flare gun. Shortly after, her helicopter was also hit and downed. The two crews were unable to join forces. The survivors were rescued the next day, but Walden had been killed in action.At first, everything seems to be straightforward, but Serling begins to notice inconsistencies between the testimonies of the witnesses. Walden's co-pilot, Warrant Officer One Rady, praises Walden's character and performance, but was hit and unconscious early on. Serling then sees Walden's medic, Specialist Ilario, who also praises Walden. Staff Sergeant Monfriez, however, tells Serling that Walden was a coward. The members of the other downed crew also mention that they heard the distinctive sound of an M16 being used in the firefight during the rescue around the other helicopter, but Walden's crew denies firing one during the rescue, as theirs was out of ammunition. When Serling visits Walden's crew chief, Sergeant Altameyer, who is dying of cancer in a hospital. Altameyer manages to get some words out, further confusing Serling, before self-medicating himself into unconsciousness.Under pressure from the White House and his commander, Brigadier General Hershberg, to wrap things up quickly, Serling leaks the story to newspaper reporter Tony Gartner to prevent another cover up. When Serling puts pressure on Monfriez, the man pulls a pistol at him, then commits suicide by driving his car into an oncoming train.After finding Ilario, Serling discovers that Monfriez wanted to escape under cover of darkness, which would have meant leaving Rady behind. Altameyer was ready to follow his lead and Ilario was wavering, but Walden refused to go along, resulting in an armed standoff with Monfriez. When an Iraqi infantryman appeared suddenly behind Monfriez, Walden fired at him. Mistakenly believing he was the target, Monfriez shot back and seriously wounded her. Walden, however, regained control of her men.The next morning, Walden stayed behind to cover their evacuation, firing the M16. Monfriez deliberately lied to the rescuers, telling them that she was dead so she would be left behind. Altameyer, injured and unable to say anything was ignored. Ilario remained silent. A-10 airplanes then napalmed the wreckage.Serling presents his final report to Hershberg. Walden's young daughter receives the Medal of Honor in a White House ceremony. Later, Serling tearfully tells the Boylars the truth about the manner of their son's death. In the last moments of the film, it is shown that Walden had transported Boylar's body away from the battlefield. Courage Under Fire is definitely one outstanding film about the Gulf War.It tells an emotional and intriguing tale of a military officer who must review the merits of a fallen officer while confronting his own war demons that makes us feel for every character involved in the story.Also,the movie tells effectively the terrors brought about by war as well as its heartbreaking aftermath.It presents it treats with clarity and intelligence that truly makes it a brilliant film.Another good thing about it is the movie avoids the use of too much violence and swearing to present its story.The performances of the cast were great.Special mention must be given to Denzel Washington for he dominates a film with his quiet intensity and aura of introspection.Credit must also be given to Meg Ryan and Matt Damon,who tried his best to look realistic in his role by shedding many pounds to lose a lot of weight. Overall,Courage Under Fire is a movie that a viewer should not miss as it ranks up there with Platoon and Born On The Fourth Of July as outstanding war films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film with a couple of standout performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just for the record, at least here on IMDb, I think this is an underrated film. And I say that as a person who very rarely likes movies about the military. My dad was in the military most of his adult life, and when he would come home on leave he would always drag me to some war film. I hated it. So, I rarely watch a war movie. But this is a keeper. First, the cast. And let me review the actors in the order of how impressive they were in this film. Denzel Washington, as a Lieutenant Colonel investigating whether a dead female captain should receive the Medal Of Honor, and who himself may have been involved in friendly fire deaths, and who has an alcohol problem, is excellent. Lou Diamond Phillips, as a Staff Sergeant who was at the helicopter crash where the female soldier was killed, is superb here (I never knew he was such a hunk...just for the record). Regina Taylor, as the wife of Washington, is excellent! Meg Ryan, the helicopter pilot who dies, is good, but although her role is pivotal, this is not a very good showcase of her talents, and I do not see her here as the co-star to Denzel Washington. I found Matt Damon rather unimpressive here, but of course, this was just before his breakthrough role that immediately followed this film. Bronson Pinchot was an interesting choice as a White House aide, and he does okay. Michael Moriarty is good as a Brigadier General, as is Scott Glenn as a Washington Post reporter. While I can't say whether or not the Iraq battle scenes were realistic, they impressed me. Despite some inconsistencies, I think the story is a good one. And not a simple one, since the issues that Denzel Washington's character has are complicating his investigation of whether or not Ryan's character should receive the Medal Of Honor. Washington does an admirable job of mixing all these factors and fleshing out the character traits of his role. In fact, this was one of Washington's early films which convinced me that he was an actor that America should treasure. Despite a few flaws, highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overly Sentimental and Top Heavy...But Above Average
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a strong Story here as an investigation ensues about a potential Medal of Honor recipient and the mysterious conflict of testimonies. It is given a twist with a shot of estrogen as the Soldier involved is the first Female to possibly (Posthumously) be awarded the Nation's Highest Military Honor. That should be enough to make this a riveting Mystery and through flashbacks we are shown some striking battle Scenes. So why add the conflict and strife to the investigating Officer. It is completely unnecessary and is the weakest part of the Film and almost drags it down with unconvincing situations of Combat guilt and Family Dysfunction. That could be a whole other Movie. But with that bloating aside there are some strong Performances by the young Cast (actually outshining Denzel) in supporting Roles as the Combat Unit in question. There is a back Story to everyone and it holds up quite well with the central Theme. It must be mentioned here that although, Meg Ryan is miscast as the Captain, she tries her best but cannot outgrow her limitations and convince as a tough Girl in a hopeless, self sacrificing situation. Overall, not a bad Movie and is worth a watch for the strong parts, but there is much too much padding here, plus the heavy dose of sentimentality finally drags this down from Great Movie to just above Average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very, very pretentious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    floyd beck
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry, but I cannot stomach a movie that is pro-military when Meg Ryan, a devout Democrat and worshiper of John Kerry, the war-hater and devout liar, and Denzel Washington, a worshiper of President Obama and a devout Democrat who is said to be a devout Christian. One cannot be both...in 2011, the Democrats voted NO to have God inserted in their convention, in spite of the chairman's blatant lie; just one of 100 reasons. So, after my ranting, what about the movie? It is too hard to believe any of it because the actors are not sincere in true life. It would be like having an openly gay person portray Rudolph Valentino unless the movie was a comedy. Courage Under Fire does not pass as a comedy unless one forces one's mind to the point of insanity to see liberal war-hating actors and actresses pretend to be pro-military.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gutless Under Clich&eacute;
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunmore_ego
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, I know it's trying to be inspiring and heroic and poignant, but COURAGE UNDER FIRE is one of the most blatantly gutless movies ever made. About a soldier investigating whether a downed female United States helicopter pilot in Desert Storm deserves a posthumous Medal of Honor. So I ask you: in which universe will America ever make a movie where a Medal of Honor is investigated and NOT awarded? So it's a foregone conclusion--all the mystery and mayhem and maybes are simply wasting our time more than the actual war this story was set in--as it leads inexorably to the melodramatic military funeral, the flags, saluting, tears of the family, proud shiny buttons and white gloves, the flyover with one plane breaking formation, and that bilious, bleating orchestra swell. And the Medal. The End. Cry me a river; cry me a patently meaningless award, military swine. Then the coda: the investigating soldier visits pilot's grave, salutes grave, tiny flag, voice-over of dead pilot to American Pie Mom and Dad, talking of the Big Push and hero hero hero hero hero hero another blithering orchestra swell I'm going to vomit... Denzel Washington is the investigating soldier, with demons of his own. (Well, they're not really demons; they're roiling stabs of conscience he feels for stupidly shooting one of his own tanks during a skirmish, killing his own men in the hilariously black euphemism "friendly fire," and then having the military cover-up his blunder.) And whenever he has visions of that po' boy he fricasseed in that tank (Mmm! Soldierboy, the other white meat!), he heads straight for the alcohol... uh, cos he's a hero, see. When he's asked to investigate whether Captain Karen Walden (Meg Ryan) is worthy of receiving the Medal of Honor for "courage under fire," the story ends right there. Of course she's deserving of it. She's the first female officer recommended, she's regarded as a hero for sacrificing her life for her men--and she's Meg Ryan. As if the movie would go to all the trouble setting up her heroism and feminism and Ryanism and NOT award her the medal. And every clich&eacute; in the military lexicon is thrown at us like grenades lobbed into foxholes: the tragic family; damaged goods investigating damaged goods; the novice (Matt Damon), the toughguy (Lou Diamond Phillips), the hero-worshipper (Tim Guinee) and all the other bumboys like the Benetton passengers of SPEED; the hospitalized guy (Seth Gilliam) whose seen one battle too many; the military cover-up. And everyone's got Movie PTSD. Denzel wants to find out "what really happened," so COURAGE is constructed like a RASHOMON for rednecks, as we see all the alternate flashbacks with a coy Walden, an indecisive Walden and a butch Walden barking orders and trying not to look like a sex object. Not one of the scenarios is ambiguous about her Hero status--no matter if she threw Iraqi babies at walls or defunded the G.I. Bill. If we can call football players heroes, and people who jumped from the Twin Towers heroes, then this chopper pilot must be a shoo-in, so I ask again: what compels viewers to spend 120 minutes *pretending* there's any doubt? Denzel visits Walden's helicopter bumboys, who all give differing accounts of My Night In The Desert With Captain Walden. Diamond Phillips claims he was the toughguy, as he lies and plies himself with alcohol and commits suicide (cos he's a hero!); Damon claims Walden was a strategic hardnose, as he admits to being a junkie and afraid to go flying again (cos he's a hero!); Guinee relates how Walden sacrificed herself for them, even as he reveals how she got them shot down by taking another pass at an Iraqi tank when she could have flown away--cognitive dissonance rules!--while constantly telling his wife to shutup for calling Walden butch (cos he's a hero!); while Seth Gilliam pounds his medication to numb himself out of the running as a reputable eyewitness (cos he's a hero, see!). What's in it for her bumboys to report that she was a coward? Nothing. But saying she was a HERO makes them vicarious heroes alongside her. Ooo-rah! And here's a note to all you military wardogs whose first reaction is to Spock-chop me for "disrespecting" you (such heroes, fighting for peace!): When are you going to realize your own government, who pays you hypocritical lip service, regards you with even less respect than I do? I just consider you deluded and egotistical and sometimes uneducated, while they consider you cannon fodder! It's the United States government that fools you into getting your asses shot off for them in the first place; it's the United States government that refuses you and your family financial benefits when you return from war; it's the United States government that stop-losses you, reneging on your stipulated leave time, over and over and over again; it's the United States government that cuts your medical funding; it's the United States government that evicts your family, that lies about friendly fire, that doesn't provide armor for you or your vehicles; it's the United States government that kicks you out for being gay after you've dedicated your life to them; it's the United States government that supposedly trains you for PTSD and then all of you return from war with PTSD (Who are the a-holes? You, who are either failing your training, or the government who are failing to train you properly?). Is that what you bitches call "respect"? Under fire from your own government, it's about time you showed some real Courage Under Fire and tell them where to shove it next time they want to exploit you for political gain. That is, unless you really are as dumb as they consider you to be. Ooo-rah! --Poffy The Cucumber
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible Meg Ryan's Performance.Like Cpt. Walden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For people who just want to see Meg in the roles of this sugar romantic- goofy coms I guess that people were lobotomized by an actress and tarnish her, when she runs away from its stereotype and I'm outraged that they can not see versatility and potential Meg Ryan's polivalency.I just see the reviews, pure flattery these crappy actresses nowadays. Ask for Julia Roberts or Angelina Jolie Already piloted an US army chopper in a role? If Michelle Pffeifer or Goldie Hawn(Private Benjamin) played a role very perfectly and naturally of a single mother and determined who dipped the face on the war, and is required in command and demonstrates tight grip and mastery with weapons? without disparaging the Denzel Washignton, which signal, shone like Nathany when reports for soldiers a Karen Walden's deservering Medal of Honor, after Her death by Naphalms, but the episodes of drunkenness became a look dull and weak. Matt Damon,was terrific, skillfully retraced all the facts of 1991's Gulf War. Lou Diamond-Phillips was excellent as paper rebel, rough and impressive and opposite Cpt. Walden. whole more Credits goes to Meg Ryan & Lou D.Phillips, sure as Denzel is a Core person in this movie.Whatever, everybody stunned theirs performance ,But Meg Ryan razed ,and much. Meg Ryan deserves an Oscar. yet, once in her life gone to win.. If God willing.. She's Powerful and more Capable than Demi-Moore, Sharon Stone,and other contemporanies 90'ties Actresses,but Meg is overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    go night train, go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jack-964
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen this movie many years ago and remember i wasn't impressed by it. This was the movie that sunk Meg Ryan for me. I just saw it again and no, it's not worth remembering: I think its starts being lame with the story itself. Why on earth does it have to be a woman? If they wouldn't have put a woman in the center and obviously even worse, cast totally wrong, then the story could actually be interesting, elaborating on different views on the same event. But no, someone decided it had to be 'emancipated', then cast wrong, then pile up a load of unbelievable facts (like downing a tank with a fuel barrel from a helicopter under fire, yea right...) Also unbelievable is the fact that one guy can't stand the truth, even though he had no part in what happened, since he was injured. The other goes on drugs, even though he had no time to think about, let alone react to the lie the third one says. Which commits suicide all of a sudden, when urged to tell the truth, even though his life is going pretty well. And all this is investigated by someone that unknowingly killed a friend in combat, under fire, bla bla. The guy has a wife, kids, great job, status, money, house, and so on, but he can't cope with this accident? It's not all bad. You probably won't fall asleep, but when you find yourself rooting for the alleged bad guy, you know something is very wrong. Go night train go!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie helps heals me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sammy Young
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care about the petty "goofs" or parts of the story that other people point out- this movie means a lot to me as a disabled veteran with PTSD. This movie is about many things, but to me, the story is about how Col Sterling is trying to manage his survivor guilt and PTSD from his incident on one hand, and deal with his task to validate the medal for his General, his wife, his kids, etc. on the other. He resorts to booze (like we all do) to try to cope. That's what this movie is really about: how one guy is trying to come to grips with PTSD, which I can tell you first-hand is a challenge that I face every minute of everyday. And seeing this movie helps heal me. It reminds me that I too lost a promising career in the Navy, lost my marriage, lost my kids, and lost myself in the abyss of PTSD and alcoholism before I got help. That's the only negative I have on this movie- we don't see if Col Sterling got help. Otherwise, this movie has helped heal me in ways that no other movie I've ever seen has.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Prismatic Gulf War drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A strong contemporary war drama examining issues of loyalty, protocol, duty and ultimately truth in an unusually constructed film within a film, at the same using multiple viewpoints ( a la "Rashomon" or "Accident") to unfold the complicated truth at its heart. I'm not sure the somewhat contrived structure served the serious subject matter wholly convincingly, the cinematic devices detracting somewhat from the otherwise lifelike depiction of action in the Gulf War. I also thought Denzel Washington's framing role as the senior army officer given the seemingly straightforward task of reporting on the apparently automatic eligibility of Meg Ryan's posthumous award of the Army medal of honour detracted from the central mystery, especially as he wrestles with his own demons after unwittingly being involved in a tragic friendly-fire incident of his own. So Denz fights the bottle and walks out on his family, before uncovering the truth about Ryan's death and the way back to his own redemption. This final resolution and the underlying implication that the US Army welcomes openness is firstly too pat and improbable, especially in the wake of some real-life events that have come to light since then. All that said, the dramatisation of the war is very well realised and the acting is of a high order, Washington giving it strong and silent in a commanding lead role, but there are even better performances from a young Matt Damon and Lou Diamond-Phillips as two of Ryan's crew who survive the ordeal physically but not mentally. Ryan does well too and I was also impressed by the actress in the menial task of playing Washington's wife. Yes, the film ends up as you'd expect, replete with Washington's last respectful visit to Ryan's grave, but there was enough intrigue and grit in the tale to keep me watching throughout. A braver take on the story, inverting some of the discovered truths here might have made for a better film though, but of course there's no way that viewpoint would have been green-lighted in Hollywood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A resounding "meh"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Do you ever watch those movies that just elicit no reaction from you? I'm talking about the kind of movies that are just so straightforward and so flat that they draw out zero emotions in you and your opinion of the movie elevates to nothing above indifference. For me, this was the case with Courage Under Fire. It stars Denzel Washington as Col. Nat Serling, an army colonel investigating the legitimacy of a post humous Medal of Honor award going to Karen Warden, an army officer who was said to have died heroically while fighting the Iraqis during the Gulf War. However, there are too many discrepancies so Serling is enlisted to find out the truth about what happened to Warden the day her and her platoon went down in their chopper. The film is told through flashbacks which recount the events from different points of views. It's a Rashomon type of story in the way that the events are slightly altered depending on who is recounting them. It's a clever plot device, but not clever or interesting enough to make Courage Under Fire a great film. Don't get me wrong, it's decent. The story isn't something you will see every day and I have to give props to any film that utilizes a more unique narrative style. Akira Kurosawa's Rashomon started this style of the unreliable narrator in film, and it's films like Courage Under Fire that keep the style alive. The problem is that the film doesn't do anything particularly interesting with this narrative style. It plays out how you would expect it to and the actual structure of the film is pretty redundant as well. From start to finish it is essentially Denzel Washington going from place to place, interviewing people about the events that ended Warden's life until he finally gets the truth. There's no real feeling in this film and it lacks any kind of atmosphere or visual nuance. The story presented is engaging to an extent, but there's nothing else to really grab your attention. The bottom line behind Courage Under Fire is it is just a forgettable film. Nothing exists within this film that makes me want to tell people about it, or think about it down the line, or rewatch it ever again. It does things right and it isn't by any means a disaster, but due to its lack of feeling, dull atmosphere, and monotonous plot it just isn't what I would call a fantastic film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film About The 1991 Gulf War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Courage Under Fire is a film about the 1991 Gulf War.It stars Denzel Washington,Meg Ryan,Lou Diamond Phillips and Matt Damon. It is one of the first great films to depict the 1991 Gulf War as it tells a story of a US Army officer, despondent about a deadly mistake he made, investigates a female chopper commander's worthiness for the Medal of Honor.The movie was directed by Edward Zwick. Courage Under Fire has Lieutenant Colonel Nathaniel Serling involved in a friendly fire incident in Al Bathra during the Gulf War. He was an M1 Abrams tank battalion commander who, during the nighttime confusion of Iraqi tanks infiltrating his unit's lines, gave the order to fire, destroying one of his own tanks and killing his friend Lieutenant Boylar. The details were covered up and Serling was reassigned to a desk job.Later, he is assigned to determine if Army Captain Karen Emma Walden should be the first woman to receive the Medal of Honor for valor in combat in the Gulf War posthumously. A Medevac Huey commander, she was sent to rescue the crew of a helicopter that had been shot down. Finding them under heavy fire from an Iraqi tank and infantry, she had her men drop an auxiliary fuel tank on the tank and ignited it with a flare gun. Shortly after, her helicopter was also hit and downed. The two crews were unable to join forces. The survivors were rescued the next day, but Walden had been killed in action.At first, everything seems to be straightforward, but Serling begins to notice inconsistencies between the testimonies of the witnesses. Walden's co-pilot, Warrant Officer One Rady, praises Walden's character and performance, but was hit and unconscious early on. Serling then sees Walden's medic, Specialist Ilario, who also praises Walden. Staff Sergeant Monfriez, however, tells Serling that Walden was a coward. The members of the other downed crew also mention that they heard the distinctive sound of an M16 being used in the firefight during the rescue around the other helicopter, but Walden's crew denies firing one during the rescue, as theirs was out of ammunition. When Serling visits Walden's crew chief, Sergeant Altameyer, who is dying of cancer in a hospital. Altameyer manages to get some words out, further confusing Serling, before self-medicating himself into unconsciousness.Under pressure from the White House and his commander, Brigadier General Hershberg, to wrap things up quickly, Serling leaks the story to newspaper reporter Tony Gartner to prevent another cover up. When Serling puts pressure on Monfriez, the man pulls a pistol at him, then commits suicide by driving his car into an oncoming train.After finding Ilario, Serling discovers that Monfriez wanted to escape under cover of darkness, which would have meant leaving Rady behind. Altameyer was ready to follow his lead and Ilario was wavering, but Walden refused to go along, resulting in an armed standoff with Monfriez. When an Iraqi infantryman appeared suddenly behind Monfriez, Walden fired at him. Mistakenly believing he was the target, Monfriez shot back and seriously wounded her. Walden, however, regained control of her men.The next morning, Walden stayed behind to cover their evacuation, firing the M16. Monfriez deliberately lied to the rescuers, telling them that she was dead so she would be left behind. Altameyer, injured and unable to say anything was ignored. Ilario remained silent. A-10 airplanes then napalmed the wreckage.Serling presents his final report to Hershberg. Walden's young daughter receives the Medal of Honor in a White House ceremony. Later, Serling tearfully tells the Boylars the truth about the manner of their son's death. In the last moments of the film, it is shown that Walden had transported Boylar's body away from the battlefield. Courage Under Fire is definitely one outstanding film about the Gulf War.It tells an emotional and intriguing tale of a military officer who must review the merits of a fallen officer while confronting his own war demons that makes us feel for every character involved in the story.Also,the movie tells effectively the terrors brought about by war as well as its heartbreaking aftermath.It presents it treats with clarity and intelligence that truly makes it a brilliant film.Another good thing about it is the movie avoids the use of too much violence and swearing to present its story.The performances of the cast were great.Special mention must be given to Denzel Washington for he dominates a film with his quiet intensity and aura of introspection.Credit must also be given to Meg Ryan and Matt Damon,who tried his best to look realistic in his role by shedding many pounds to lose a lot of weight. Overall,Courage Under Fire is a movie that a viewer should not miss as it ranks up there with Platoon and Born On The Fourth Of July as outstanding war films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film with a couple of standout performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just for the record, at least here on IMDb, I think this is an underrated film. And I say that as a person who very rarely likes movies about the military. My dad was in the military most of his adult life, and when he would come home on leave he would always drag me to some war film. I hated it. So, I rarely watch a war movie. But this is a keeper. First, the cast. And let me review the actors in the order of how impressive they were in this film. Denzel Washington, as a Lieutenant Colonel investigating whether a dead female captain should receive the Medal Of Honor, and who himself may have been involved in friendly fire deaths, and who has an alcohol problem, is excellent. Lou Diamond Phillips, as a Staff Sergeant who was at the helicopter crash where the female soldier was killed, is superb here (I never knew he was such a hunk...just for the record). Regina Taylor, as the wife of Washington, is excellent! Meg Ryan, the helicopter pilot who dies, is good, but although her role is pivotal, this is not a very good showcase of her talents, and I do not see her here as the co-star to Denzel Washington. I found Matt Damon rather unimpressive here, but of course, this was just before his breakthrough role that immediately followed this film. Bronson Pinchot was an interesting choice as a White House aide, and he does okay. Michael Moriarty is good as a Brigadier General, as is Scott Glenn as a Washington Post reporter. While I can't say whether or not the Iraq battle scenes were realistic, they impressed me. Despite some inconsistencies, I think the story is a good one. And not a simple one, since the issues that Denzel Washington's character has are complicating his investigation of whether or not Ryan's character should receive the Medal Of Honor. Washington does an admirable job of mixing all these factors and fleshing out the character traits of his role. In fact, this was one of Washington's early films which convinced me that he was an actor that America should treasure. Despite a few flaws, highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overly Sentimental and Top Heavy...But Above Average
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a strong Story here as an investigation ensues about a potential Medal of Honor recipient and the mysterious conflict of testimonies. It is given a twist with a shot of estrogen as the Soldier involved is the first Female to possibly (Posthumously) be awarded the Nation's Highest Military Honor. That should be enough to make this a riveting Mystery and through flashbacks we are shown some striking battle Scenes. So why add the conflict and strife to the investigating Officer. It is completely unnecessary and is the weakest part of the Film and almost drags it down with unconvincing situations of Combat guilt and Family Dysfunction. That could be a whole other Movie. But with that bloating aside there are some strong Performances by the young Cast (actually outshining Denzel) in supporting Roles as the Combat Unit in question. There is a back Story to everyone and it holds up quite well with the central Theme. It must be mentioned here that although, Meg Ryan is miscast as the Captain, she tries her best but cannot outgrow her limitations and convince as a tough Girl in a hopeless, self sacrificing situation. Overall, not a bad Movie and is worth a watch for the strong parts, but there is much too much padding here, plus the heavy dose of sentimentality finally drags this down from Great Movie to just above Average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very, very pretentious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    floyd beck
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry, but I cannot stomach a movie that is pro-military when Meg Ryan, a devout Democrat and worshiper of John Kerry, the war-hater and devout liar, and Denzel Washington, a worshiper of President Obama and a devout Democrat who is said to be a devout Christian. One cannot be both...in 2011, the Democrats voted NO to have God inserted in their convention, in spite of the chairman's blatant lie; just one of 100 reasons. So, after my ranting, what about the movie? It is too hard to believe any of it because the actors are not sincere in true life. It would be like having an openly gay person portray Rudolph Valentino unless the movie was a comedy. Courage Under Fire does not pass as a comedy unless one forces one's mind to the point of insanity to see liberal war-hating actors and actresses pretend to be pro-military.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gutless Under Clich&eacute;
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunmore_ego
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, I know it's trying to be inspiring and heroic and poignant, but COURAGE UNDER FIRE is one of the most blatantly gutless movies ever made. About a soldier investigating whether a downed female United States helicopter pilot in Desert Storm deserves a posthumous Medal of Honor. So I ask you: in which universe will America ever make a movie where a Medal of Honor is investigated and NOT awarded? So it's a foregone conclusion--all the mystery and mayhem and maybes are simply wasting our time more than the actual war this story was set in--as it leads inexorably to the melodramatic military funeral, the flags, saluting, tears of the family, proud shiny buttons and white gloves, the flyover with one plane breaking formation, and that bilious, bleating orchestra swell. And the Medal. The End. Cry me a river; cry me a patently meaningless award, military swine. Then the coda: the investigating soldier visits pilot's grave, salutes grave, tiny flag, voice-over of dead pilot to American Pie Mom and Dad, talking of the Big Push and hero hero hero hero hero hero another blithering orchestra swell I'm going to vomit... Denzel Washington is the investigating soldier, with demons of his own. (Well, they're not really demons; they're roiling stabs of conscience he feels for stupidly shooting one of his own tanks during a skirmish, killing his own men in the hilariously black euphemism "friendly fire," and then having the military cover-up his blunder.) And whenever he has visions of that po' boy he fricasseed in that tank (Mmm! Soldierboy, the other white meat!), he heads straight for the alcohol... uh, cos he's a hero, see. When he's asked to investigate whether Captain Karen Walden (Meg Ryan) is worthy of receiving the Medal of Honor for "courage under fire," the story ends right there. Of course she's deserving of it. She's the first female officer recommended, she's regarded as a hero for sacrificing her life for her men--and she's Meg Ryan. As if the movie would go to all the trouble setting up her heroism and feminism and Ryanism and NOT award her the medal. And every clich&eacute; in the military lexicon is thrown at us like grenades lobbed into foxholes: the tragic family; damaged goods investigating damaged goods; the novice (Matt Damon), the toughguy (Lou Diamond Phillips), the hero-worshipper (Tim Guinee) and all the other bumboys like the Benetton passengers of SPEED; the hospitalized guy (Seth Gilliam) whose seen one battle too many; the military cover-up. And everyone's got Movie PTSD. Denzel wants to find out "what really happened," so COURAGE is constructed like a RASHOMON for rednecks, as we see all the alternate flashbacks with a coy Walden, an indecisive Walden and a butch Walden barking orders and trying not to look like a sex object. Not one of the scenarios is ambiguous about her Hero status--no matter if she threw Iraqi babies at walls or defunded the G.I. Bill. If we can call football players heroes, and people who jumped from the Twin Towers heroes, then this chopper pilot must be a shoo-in, so I ask again: what compels viewers to spend 120 minutes *pretending* there's any doubt? Denzel visits Walden's helicopter bumboys, who all give differing accounts of My Night In The Desert With Captain Walden. Diamond Phillips claims he was the toughguy, as he lies and plies himself with alcohol and commits suicide (cos he's a hero!); Damon claims Walden was a strategic hardnose, as he admits to being a junkie and afraid to go flying again (cos he's a hero!); Guinee relates how Walden sacrificed herself for them, even as he reveals how she got them shot down by taking another pass at an Iraqi tank when she could have flown away--cognitive dissonance rules!--while constantly telling his wife to shutup for calling Walden butch (cos he's a hero!); while Seth Gilliam pounds his medication to numb himself out of the running as a reputable eyewitness (cos he's a hero, see!). What's in it for her bumboys to report that she was a coward? Nothing. But saying she was a HERO makes them vicarious heroes alongside her. Ooo-rah! And here's a note to all you military wardogs whose first reaction is to Spock-chop me for "disrespecting" you (such heroes, fighting for peace!): When are you going to realize your own government, who pays you hypocritical lip service, regards you with even less respect than I do? I just consider you deluded and egotistical and sometimes uneducated, while they consider you cannon fodder! It's the United States government that fools you into getting your asses shot off for them in the first place; it's the United States government that refuses you and your family financial benefits when you return from war; it's the United States government that stop-losses you, reneging on your stipulated leave time, over and over and over again; it's the United States government that cuts your medical funding; it's the United States government that evicts your family, that lies about friendly fire, that doesn't provide armor for you or your vehicles; it's the United States government that kicks you out for being gay after you've dedicated your life to them; it's the United States government that supposedly trains you for PTSD and then all of you return from war with PTSD (Who are the a-holes? You, who are either failing your training, or the government who are failing to train you properly?). Is that what you bitches call "respect"? Under fire from your own government, it's about time you showed some real Courage Under Fire and tell them where to shove it next time they want to exploit you for political gain. That is, unless you really are as dumb as they consider you to be. Ooo-rah! --Poffy The Cucumber
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible Meg Ryan's Performance.Like Cpt. Walden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For people who just want to see Meg in the roles of this sugar romantic- goofy coms I guess that people were lobotomized by an actress and tarnish her, when she runs away from its stereotype and I'm outraged that they can not see versatility and potential Meg Ryan's polivalency.I just see the reviews, pure flattery these crappy actresses nowadays. Ask for Julia Roberts or Angelina Jolie Already piloted an US army chopper in a role? If Michelle Pffeifer or Goldie Hawn(Private Benjamin) played a role very perfectly and naturally of a single mother and determined who dipped the face on the war, and is required in command and demonstrates tight grip and mastery with weapons? without disparaging the Denzel Washignton, which signal, shone like Nathany when reports for soldiers a Karen Walden's deservering Medal of Honor, after Her death by Naphalms, but the episodes of drunkenness became a look dull and weak. Matt Damon,was terrific, skillfully retraced all the facts of 1991's Gulf War. Lou Diamond-Phillips was excellent as paper rebel, rough and impressive and opposite Cpt. Walden. whole more Credits goes to Meg Ryan & Lou D.Phillips, sure as Denzel is a Core person in this movie.Whatever, everybody stunned theirs performance ,But Meg Ryan razed ,and much. Meg Ryan deserves an Oscar. yet, once in her life gone to win.. If God willing.. She's Powerful and more Capable than Demi-Moore, Sharon Stone,and other contemporanies 90'ties Actresses,but Meg is overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    go night train, go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jack-964
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen this movie many years ago and remember i wasn't impressed by it. This was the movie that sunk Meg Ryan for me. I just saw it again and no, it's not worth remembering: I think its starts being lame with the story itself. Why on earth does it have to be a woman? If they wouldn't have put a woman in the center and obviously even worse, cast totally wrong, then the story could actually be interesting, elaborating on different views on the same event. But no, someone decided it had to be 'emancipated', then cast wrong, then pile up a load of unbelievable facts (like downing a tank with a fuel barrel from a helicopter under fire, yea right...) Also unbelievable is the fact that one guy can't stand the truth, even though he had no part in what happened, since he was injured. The other goes on drugs, even though he had no time to think about, let alone react to the lie the third one says. Which commits suicide all of a sudden, when urged to tell the truth, even though his life is going pretty well. And all this is investigated by someone that unknowingly killed a friend in combat, under fire, bla bla. The guy has a wife, kids, great job, status, money, house, and so on, but he can't cope with this accident? It's not all bad. You probably won't fall asleep, but when you find yourself rooting for the alleged bad guy, you know something is very wrong. Go night train go!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie helps heals me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sammy Young
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care about the petty "goofs" or parts of the story that other people point out- this movie means a lot to me as a disabled veteran with PTSD. This movie is about many things, but to me, the story is about how Col Sterling is trying to manage his survivor guilt and PTSD from his incident on one hand, and deal with his task to validate the medal for his General, his wife, his kids, etc. on the other. He resorts to booze (like we all do) to try to cope. That's what this movie is really about: how one guy is trying to come to grips with PTSD, which I can tell you first-hand is a challenge that I face every minute of everyday. And seeing this movie helps heal me. It reminds me that I too lost a promising career in the Navy, lost my marriage, lost my kids, and lost myself in the abyss of PTSD and alcoholism before I got help. That's the only negative I have on this movie- we don't see if Col Sterling got help. Otherwise, this movie has helped heal me in ways that no other movie I've ever seen has.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Prismatic Gulf War drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A strong contemporary war drama examining issues of loyalty, protocol, duty and ultimately truth in an unusually constructed film within a film, at the same using multiple viewpoints ( a la "Rashomon" or "Accident") to unfold the complicated truth at its heart. I'm not sure the somewhat contrived structure served the serious subject matter wholly convincingly, the cinematic devices detracting somewhat from the otherwise lifelike depiction of action in the Gulf War. I also thought Denzel Washington's framing role as the senior army officer given the seemingly straightforward task of reporting on the apparently automatic eligibility of Meg Ryan's posthumous award of the Army medal of honour detracted from the central mystery, especially as he wrestles with his own demons after unwittingly being involved in a tragic friendly-fire incident of his own. So Denz fights the bottle and walks out on his family, before uncovering the truth about Ryan's death and the way back to his own redemption. This final resolution and the underlying implication that the US Army welcomes openness is firstly too pat and improbable, especially in the wake of some real-life events that have come to light since then. All that said, the dramatisation of the war is very well realised and the acting is of a high order, Washington giving it strong and silent in a commanding lead role, but there are even better performances from a young Matt Damon and Lou Diamond-Phillips as two of Ryan's crew who survive the ordeal physically but not mentally. Ryan does well too and I was also impressed by the actress in the menial task of playing Washington's wife. Yes, the film ends up as you'd expect, replete with Washington's last respectful visit to Ryan's grave, but there was enough intrigue and grit in the tale to keep me watching throughout. A braver take on the story, inverting some of the discovered truths here might have made for a better film though, but of course there's no way that viewpoint would have been green-lighted in Hollywood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A resounding "meh"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Do you ever watch those movies that just elicit no reaction from you? I'm talking about the kind of movies that are just so straightforward and so flat that they draw out zero emotions in you and your opinion of the movie elevates to nothing above indifference. For me, this was the case with Courage Under Fire. It stars Denzel Washington as Col. Nat Serling, an army colonel investigating the legitimacy of a post humous Medal of Honor award going to Karen Warden, an army officer who was said to have died heroically while fighting the Iraqis during the Gulf War. However, there are too many discrepancies so Serling is enlisted to find out the truth about what happened to Warden the day her and her platoon went down in their chopper. The film is told through flashbacks which recount the events from different points of views. It's a Rashomon type of story in the way that the events are slightly altered depending on who is recounting them. It's a clever plot device, but not clever or interesting enough to make Courage Under Fire a great film. Don't get me wrong, it's decent. The story isn't something you will see every day and I have to give props to any film that utilizes a more unique narrative style. Akira Kurosawa's Rashomon started this style of the unreliable narrator in film, and it's films like Courage Under Fire that keep the style alive. The problem is that the film doesn't do anything particularly interesting with this narrative style. It plays out how you would expect it to and the actual structure of the film is pretty redundant as well. From start to finish it is essentially Denzel Washington going from place to place, interviewing people about the events that ended Warden's life until he finally gets the truth. There's no real feeling in this film and it lacks any kind of atmosphere or visual nuance. The story presented is engaging to an extent, but there's nothing else to really grab your attention. The bottom line behind Courage Under Fire is it is just a forgettable film. Nothing exists within this film that makes me want to tell people about it, or think about it down the line, or rewatch it ever again. It does things right and it isn't by any means a disaster, but due to its lack of feeling, dull atmosphere, and monotonous plot it just isn't what I would call a fantastic film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film About The 1991 Gulf War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Courage Under Fire is a film about the 1991 Gulf War.It stars Denzel Washington,Meg Ryan,Lou Diamond Phillips and Matt Damon. It is one of the first great films to depict the 1991 Gulf War as it tells a story of a US Army officer, despondent about a deadly mistake he made, investigates a female chopper commander's worthiness for the Medal of Honor.The movie was directed by Edward Zwick. Courage Under Fire has Lieutenant Colonel Nathaniel Serling involved in a friendly fire incident in Al Bathra during the Gulf War. He was an M1 Abrams tank battalion commander who, during the nighttime confusion of Iraqi tanks infiltrating his unit's lines, gave the order to fire, destroying one of his own tanks and killing his friend Lieutenant Boylar. The details were covered up and Serling was reassigned to a desk job.Later, he is assigned to determine if Army Captain Karen Emma Walden should be the first woman to receive the Medal of Honor for valor in combat in the Gulf War posthumously. A Medevac Huey commander, she was sent to rescue the crew of a helicopter that had been shot down. Finding them under heavy fire from an Iraqi tank and infantry, she had her men drop an auxiliary fuel tank on the tank and ignited it with a flare gun. Shortly after, her helicopter was also hit and downed. The two crews were unable to join forces. The survivors were rescued the next day, but Walden had been killed in action.At first, everything seems to be straightforward, but Serling begins to notice inconsistencies between the testimonies of the witnesses. Walden's co-pilot, Warrant Officer One Rady, praises Walden's character and performance, but was hit and unconscious early on. Serling then sees Walden's medic, Specialist Ilario, who also praises Walden. Staff Sergeant Monfriez, however, tells Serling that Walden was a coward. The members of the other downed crew also mention that they heard the distinctive sound of an M16 being used in the firefight during the rescue around the other helicopter, but Walden's crew denies firing one during the rescue, as theirs was out of ammunition. When Serling visits Walden's crew chief, Sergeant Altameyer, who is dying of cancer in a hospital. Altameyer manages to get some words out, further confusing Serling, before self-medicating himself into unconsciousness.Under pressure from the White House and his commander, Brigadier General Hershberg, to wrap things up quickly, Serling leaks the story to newspaper reporter Tony Gartner to prevent another cover up. When Serling puts pressure on Monfriez, the man pulls a pistol at him, then commits suicide by driving his car into an oncoming train.After finding Ilario, Serling discovers that Monfriez wanted to escape under cover of darkness, which would have meant leaving Rady behind. Altameyer was ready to follow his lead and Ilario was wavering, but Walden refused to go along, resulting in an armed standoff with Monfriez. When an Iraqi infantryman appeared suddenly behind Monfriez, Walden fired at him. Mistakenly believing he was the target, Monfriez shot back and seriously wounded her. Walden, however, regained control of her men.The next morning, Walden stayed behind to cover their evacuation, firing the M16. Monfriez deliberately lied to the rescuers, telling them that she was dead so she would be left behind. Altameyer, injured and unable to say anything was ignored. Ilario remained silent. A-10 airplanes then napalmed the wreckage.Serling presents his final report to Hershberg. Walden's young daughter receives the Medal of Honor in a White House ceremony. Later, Serling tearfully tells the Boylars the truth about the manner of their son's death. In the last moments of the film, it is shown that Walden had transported Boylar's body away from the battlefield. Courage Under Fire is definitely one outstanding film about the Gulf War.It tells an emotional and intriguing tale of a military officer who must review the merits of a fallen officer while confronting his own war demons that makes us feel for every character involved in the story.Also,the movie tells effectively the terrors brought about by war as well as its heartbreaking aftermath.It presents it treats with clarity and intelligence that truly makes it a brilliant film.Another good thing about it is the movie avoids the use of too much violence and swearing to present its story.The performances of the cast were great.Special mention must be given to Denzel Washington for he dominates a film with his quiet intensity and aura of introspection.Credit must also be given to Meg Ryan and Matt Damon,who tried his best to look realistic in his role by shedding many pounds to lose a lot of weight. Overall,Courage Under Fire is a movie that a viewer should not miss as it ranks up there with Platoon and Born On The Fourth Of July as outstanding war films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film with a couple of standout performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just for the record, at least here on IMDb, I think this is an underrated film. And I say that as a person who very rarely likes movies about the military. My dad was in the military most of his adult life, and when he would come home on leave he would always drag me to some war film. I hated it. So, I rarely watch a war movie. But this is a keeper. First, the cast. And let me review the actors in the order of how impressive they were in this film. Denzel Washington, as a Lieutenant Colonel investigating whether a dead female captain should receive the Medal Of Honor, and who himself may have been involved in friendly fire deaths, and who has an alcohol problem, is excellent. Lou Diamond Phillips, as a Staff Sergeant who was at the helicopter crash where the female soldier was killed, is superb here (I never knew he was such a hunk...just for the record). Regina Taylor, as the wife of Washington, is excellent! Meg Ryan, the helicopter pilot who dies, is good, but although her role is pivotal, this is not a very good showcase of her talents, and I do not see her here as the co-star to Denzel Washington. I found Matt Damon rather unimpressive here, but of course, this was just before his breakthrough role that immediately followed this film. Bronson Pinchot was an interesting choice as a White House aide, and he does okay. Michael Moriarty is good as a Brigadier General, as is Scott Glenn as a Washington Post reporter. While I can't say whether or not the Iraq battle scenes were realistic, they impressed me. Despite some inconsistencies, I think the story is a good one. And not a simple one, since the issues that Denzel Washington's character has are complicating his investigation of whether or not Ryan's character should receive the Medal Of Honor. Washington does an admirable job of mixing all these factors and fleshing out the character traits of his role. In fact, this was one of Washington's early films which convinced me that he was an actor that America should treasure. Despite a few flaws, highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overly Sentimental and Top Heavy...But Above Average
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a strong Story here as an investigation ensues about a potential Medal of Honor recipient and the mysterious conflict of testimonies. It is given a twist with a shot of estrogen as the Soldier involved is the first Female to possibly (Posthumously) be awarded the Nation's Highest Military Honor. That should be enough to make this a riveting Mystery and through flashbacks we are shown some striking battle Scenes. So why add the conflict and strife to the investigating Officer. It is completely unnecessary and is the weakest part of the Film and almost drags it down with unconvincing situations of Combat guilt and Family Dysfunction. That could be a whole other Movie. But with that bloating aside there are some strong Performances by the young Cast (actually outshining Denzel) in supporting Roles as the Combat Unit in question. There is a back Story to everyone and it holds up quite well with the central Theme. It must be mentioned here that although, Meg Ryan is miscast as the Captain, she tries her best but cannot outgrow her limitations and convince as a tough Girl in a hopeless, self sacrificing situation. Overall, not a bad Movie and is worth a watch for the strong parts, but there is much too much padding here, plus the heavy dose of sentimentality finally drags this down from Great Movie to just above Average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very, very pretentious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    floyd beck
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry, but I cannot stomach a movie that is pro-military when Meg Ryan, a devout Democrat and worshiper of John Kerry, the war-hater and devout liar, and Denzel Washington, a worshiper of President Obama and a devout Democrat who is said to be a devout Christian. One cannot be both...in 2011, the Democrats voted NO to have God inserted in their convention, in spite of the chairman's blatant lie; just one of 100 reasons. So, after my ranting, what about the movie? It is too hard to believe any of it because the actors are not sincere in true life. It would be like having an openly gay person portray Rudolph Valentino unless the movie was a comedy. Courage Under Fire does not pass as a comedy unless one forces one's mind to the point of insanity to see liberal war-hating actors and actresses pretend to be pro-military.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gutless Under Clich&eacute;
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunmore_ego
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, I know it's trying to be inspiring and heroic and poignant, but COURAGE UNDER FIRE is one of the most blatantly gutless movies ever made. About a soldier investigating whether a downed female United States helicopter pilot in Desert Storm deserves a posthumous Medal of Honor. So I ask you: in which universe will America ever make a movie where a Medal of Honor is investigated and NOT awarded? So it's a foregone conclusion--all the mystery and mayhem and maybes are simply wasting our time more than the actual war this story was set in--as it leads inexorably to the melodramatic military funeral, the flags, saluting, tears of the family, proud shiny buttons and white gloves, the flyover with one plane breaking formation, and that bilious, bleating orchestra swell. And the Medal. The End. Cry me a river; cry me a patently meaningless award, military swine. Then the coda: the investigating soldier visits pilot's grave, salutes grave, tiny flag, voice-over of dead pilot to American Pie Mom and Dad, talking of the Big Push and hero hero hero hero hero hero another blithering orchestra swell I'm going to vomit... Denzel Washington is the investigating soldier, with demons of his own. (Well, they're not really demons; they're roiling stabs of conscience he feels for stupidly shooting one of his own tanks during a skirmish, killing his own men in the hilariously black euphemism "friendly fire," and then having the military cover-up his blunder.) And whenever he has visions of that po' boy he fricasseed in that tank (Mmm! Soldierboy, the other white meat!), he heads straight for the alcohol... uh, cos he's a hero, see. When he's asked to investigate whether Captain Karen Walden (Meg Ryan) is worthy of receiving the Medal of Honor for "courage under fire," the story ends right there. Of course she's deserving of it. She's the first female officer recommended, she's regarded as a hero for sacrificing her life for her men--and she's Meg Ryan. As if the movie would go to all the trouble setting up her heroism and feminism and Ryanism and NOT award her the medal. And every clich&eacute; in the military lexicon is thrown at us like grenades lobbed into foxholes: the tragic family; damaged goods investigating damaged goods; the novice (Matt Damon), the toughguy (Lou Diamond Phillips), the hero-worshipper (Tim Guinee) and all the other bumboys like the Benetton passengers of SPEED; the hospitalized guy (Seth Gilliam) whose seen one battle too many; the military cover-up. And everyone's got Movie PTSD. Denzel wants to find out "what really happened," so COURAGE is constructed like a RASHOMON for rednecks, as we see all the alternate flashbacks with a coy Walden, an indecisive Walden and a butch Walden barking orders and trying not to look like a sex object. Not one of the scenarios is ambiguous about her Hero status--no matter if she threw Iraqi babies at walls or defunded the G.I. Bill. If we can call football players heroes, and people who jumped from the Twin Towers heroes, then this chopper pilot must be a shoo-in, so I ask again: what compels viewers to spend 120 minutes *pretending* there's any doubt? Denzel visits Walden's helicopter bumboys, who all give differing accounts of My Night In The Desert With Captain Walden. Diamond Phillips claims he was the toughguy, as he lies and plies himself with alcohol and commits suicide (cos he's a hero!); Damon claims Walden was a strategic hardnose, as he admits to being a junkie and afraid to go flying again (cos he's a hero!); Guinee relates how Walden sacrificed herself for them, even as he reveals how she got them shot down by taking another pass at an Iraqi tank when she could have flown away--cognitive dissonance rules!--while constantly telling his wife to shutup for calling Walden butch (cos he's a hero!); while Seth Gilliam pounds his medication to numb himself out of the running as a reputable eyewitness (cos he's a hero, see!). What's in it for her bumboys to report that she was a coward? Nothing. But saying she was a HERO makes them vicarious heroes alongside her. Ooo-rah! And here's a note to all you military wardogs whose first reaction is to Spock-chop me for "disrespecting" you (such heroes, fighting for peace!): When are you going to realize your own government, who pays you hypocritical lip service, regards you with even less respect than I do? I just consider you deluded and egotistical and sometimes uneducated, while they consider you cannon fodder! It's the United States government that fools you into getting your asses shot off for them in the first place; it's the United States government that refuses you and your family financial benefits when you return from war; it's the United States government that stop-losses you, reneging on your stipulated leave time, over and over and over again; it's the United States government that cuts your medical funding; it's the United States government that evicts your family, that lies about friendly fire, that doesn't provide armor for you or your vehicles; it's the United States government that kicks you out for being gay after you've dedicated your life to them; it's the United States government that supposedly trains you for PTSD and then all of you return from war with PTSD (Who are the a-holes? You, who are either failing your training, or the government who are failing to train you properly?). Is that what you bitches call "respect"? Under fire from your own government, it's about time you showed some real Courage Under Fire and tell them where to shove it next time they want to exploit you for political gain. That is, unless you really are as dumb as they consider you to be. Ooo-rah! --Poffy The Cucumber
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible Meg Ryan's Performance.Like Cpt. Walden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For people who just want to see Meg in the roles of this sugar romantic- goofy coms I guess that people were lobotomized by an actress and tarnish her, when she runs away from its stereotype and I'm outraged that they can not see versatility and potential Meg Ryan's polivalency.I just see the reviews, pure flattery these crappy actresses nowadays. Ask for Julia Roberts or Angelina Jolie Already piloted an US army chopper in a role? If Michelle Pffeifer or Goldie Hawn(Private Benjamin) played a role very perfectly and naturally of a single mother and determined who dipped the face on the war, and is required in command and demonstrates tight grip and mastery with weapons? without disparaging the Denzel Washignton, which signal, shone like Nathany when reports for soldiers a Karen Walden's deservering Medal of Honor, after Her death by Naphalms, but the episodes of drunkenness became a look dull and weak. Matt Damon,was terrific, skillfully retraced all the facts of 1991's Gulf War. Lou Diamond-Phillips was excellent as paper rebel, rough and impressive and opposite Cpt. Walden. whole more Credits goes to Meg Ryan & Lou D.Phillips, sure as Denzel is a Core person in this movie.Whatever, everybody stunned theirs performance ,But Meg Ryan razed ,and much. Meg Ryan deserves an Oscar. yet, once in her life gone to win.. If God willing.. She's Powerful and more Capable than Demi-Moore, Sharon Stone,and other contemporanies 90'ties Actresses,but Meg is overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    go night train, go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jack-964
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen this movie many years ago and remember i wasn't impressed by it. This was the movie that sunk Meg Ryan for me. I just saw it again and no, it's not worth remembering: I think its starts being lame with the story itself. Why on earth does it have to be a woman? If they wouldn't have put a woman in the center and obviously even worse, cast totally wrong, then the story could actually be interesting, elaborating on different views on the same event. But no, someone decided it had to be 'emancipated', then cast wrong, then pile up a load of unbelievable facts (like downing a tank with a fuel barrel from a helicopter under fire, yea right...) Also unbelievable is the fact that one guy can't stand the truth, even though he had no part in what happened, since he was injured. The other goes on drugs, even though he had no time to think about, let alone react to the lie the third one says. Which commits suicide all of a sudden, when urged to tell the truth, even though his life is going pretty well. And all this is investigated by someone that unknowingly killed a friend in combat, under fire, bla bla. The guy has a wife, kids, great job, status, money, house, and so on, but he can't cope with this accident? It's not all bad. You probably won't fall asleep, but when you find yourself rooting for the alleged bad guy, you know something is very wrong. Go night train go!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie helps heals me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sammy Young
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care about the petty "goofs" or parts of the story that other people point out- this movie means a lot to me as a disabled veteran with PTSD. This movie is about many things, but to me, the story is about how Col Sterling is trying to manage his survivor guilt and PTSD from his incident on one hand, and deal with his task to validate the medal for his General, his wife, his kids, etc. on the other. He resorts to booze (like we all do) to try to cope. That's what this movie is really about: how one guy is trying to come to grips with PTSD, which I can tell you first-hand is a challenge that I face every minute of everyday. And seeing this movie helps heal me. It reminds me that I too lost a promising career in the Navy, lost my marriage, lost my kids, and lost myself in the abyss of PTSD and alcoholism before I got help. That's the only negative I have on this movie- we don't see if Col Sterling got help. Otherwise, this movie has helped heal me in ways that no other movie I've ever seen has.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Prismatic Gulf War drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A strong contemporary war drama examining issues of loyalty, protocol, duty and ultimately truth in an unusually constructed film within a film, at the same using multiple viewpoints ( a la "Rashomon" or "Accident") to unfold the complicated truth at its heart. I'm not sure the somewhat contrived structure served the serious subject matter wholly convincingly, the cinematic devices detracting somewhat from the otherwise lifelike depiction of action in the Gulf War. I also thought Denzel Washington's framing role as the senior army officer given the seemingly straightforward task of reporting on the apparently automatic eligibility of Meg Ryan's posthumous award of the Army medal of honour detracted from the central mystery, especially as he wrestles with his own demons after unwittingly being involved in a tragic friendly-fire incident of his own. So Denz fights the bottle and walks out on his family, before uncovering the truth about Ryan's death and the way back to his own redemption. This final resolution and the underlying implication that the US Army welcomes openness is firstly too pat and improbable, especially in the wake of some real-life events that have come to light since then. All that said, the dramatisation of the war is very well realised and the acting is of a high order, Washington giving it strong and silent in a commanding lead role, but there are even better performances from a young Matt Damon and Lou Diamond-Phillips as two of Ryan's crew who survive the ordeal physically but not mentally. Ryan does well too and I was also impressed by the actress in the menial task of playing Washington's wife. Yes, the film ends up as you'd expect, replete with Washington's last respectful visit to Ryan's grave, but there was enough intrigue and grit in the tale to keep me watching throughout. A braver take on the story, inverting some of the discovered truths here might have made for a better film though, but of course there's no way that viewpoint would have been green-lighted in Hollywood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A resounding "meh"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Do you ever watch those movies that just elicit no reaction from you? I'm talking about the kind of movies that are just so straightforward and so flat that they draw out zero emotions in you and your opinion of the movie elevates to nothing above indifference. For me, this was the case with Courage Under Fire. It stars Denzel Washington as Col. Nat Serling, an army colonel investigating the legitimacy of a post humous Medal of Honor award going to Karen Warden, an army officer who was said to have died heroically while fighting the Iraqis during the Gulf War. However, there are too many discrepancies so Serling is enlisted to find out the truth about what happened to Warden the day her and her platoon went down in their chopper. The film is told through flashbacks which recount the events from different points of views. It's a Rashomon type of story in the way that the events are slightly altered depending on who is recounting them. It's a clever plot device, but not clever or interesting enough to make Courage Under Fire a great film. Don't get me wrong, it's decent. The story isn't something you will see every day and I have to give props to any film that utilizes a more unique narrative style. Akira Kurosawa's Rashomon started this style of the unreliable narrator in film, and it's films like Courage Under Fire that keep the style alive. The problem is that the film doesn't do anything particularly interesting with this narrative style. It plays out how you would expect it to and the actual structure of the film is pretty redundant as well. From start to finish it is essentially Denzel Washington going from place to place, interviewing people about the events that ended Warden's life until he finally gets the truth. There's no real feeling in this film and it lacks any kind of atmosphere or visual nuance. The story presented is engaging to an extent, but there's nothing else to really grab your attention. The bottom line behind Courage Under Fire is it is just a forgettable film. Nothing exists within this film that makes me want to tell people about it, or think about it down the line, or rewatch it ever again. It does things right and it isn't by any means a disaster, but due to its lack of feeling, dull atmosphere, and monotonous plot it just isn't what I would call a fantastic film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film About The 1991 Gulf War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Courage Under Fire is a film about the 1991 Gulf War.It stars Denzel Washington,Meg Ryan,Lou Diamond Phillips and Matt Damon. It is one of the first great films to depict the 1991 Gulf War as it tells a story of a US Army officer, despondent about a deadly mistake he made, investigates a female chopper commander's worthiness for the Medal of Honor.The movie was directed by Edward Zwick. Courage Under Fire has Lieutenant Colonel Nathaniel Serling involved in a friendly fire incident in Al Bathra during the Gulf War. He was an M1 Abrams tank battalion commander who, during the nighttime confusion of Iraqi tanks infiltrating his unit's lines, gave the order to fire, destroying one of his own tanks and killing his friend Lieutenant Boylar. The details were covered up and Serling was reassigned to a desk job.Later, he is assigned to determine if Army Captain Karen Emma Walden should be the first woman to receive the Medal of Honor for valor in combat in the Gulf War posthumously. A Medevac Huey commander, she was sent to rescue the crew of a helicopter that had been shot down. Finding them under heavy fire from an Iraqi tank and infantry, she had her men drop an auxiliary fuel tank on the tank and ignited it with a flare gun. Shortly after, her helicopter was also hit and downed. The two crews were unable to join forces. The survivors were rescued the next day, but Walden had been killed in action.At first, everything seems to be straightforward, but Serling begins to notice inconsistencies between the testimonies of the witnesses. Walden's co-pilot, Warrant Officer One Rady, praises Walden's character and performance, but was hit and unconscious early on. Serling then sees Walden's medic, Specialist Ilario, who also praises Walden. Staff Sergeant Monfriez, however, tells Serling that Walden was a coward. The members of the other downed crew also mention that they heard the distinctive sound of an M16 being used in the firefight during the rescue around the other helicopter, but Walden's crew denies firing one during the rescue, as theirs was out of ammunition. When Serling visits Walden's crew chief, Sergeant Altameyer, who is dying of cancer in a hospital. Altameyer manages to get some words out, further confusing Serling, before self-medicating himself into unconsciousness.Under pressure from the White House and his commander, Brigadier General Hershberg, to wrap things up quickly, Serling leaks the story to newspaper reporter Tony Gartner to prevent another cover up. When Serling puts pressure on Monfriez, the man pulls a pistol at him, then commits suicide by driving his car into an oncoming train.After finding Ilario, Serling discovers that Monfriez wanted to escape under cover of darkness, which would have meant leaving Rady behind. Altameyer was ready to follow his lead and Ilario was wavering, but Walden refused to go along, resulting in an armed standoff with Monfriez. When an Iraqi infantryman appeared suddenly behind Monfriez, Walden fired at him. Mistakenly believing he was the target, Monfriez shot back and seriously wounded her. Walden, however, regained control of her men.The next morning, Walden stayed behind to cover their evacuation, firing the M16. Monfriez deliberately lied to the rescuers, telling them that she was dead so she would be left behind. Altameyer, injured and unable to say anything was ignored. Ilario remained silent. A-10 airplanes then napalmed the wreckage.Serling presents his final report to Hershberg. Walden's young daughter receives the Medal of Honor in a White House ceremony. Later, Serling tearfully tells the Boylars the truth about the manner of their son's death. In the last moments of the film, it is shown that Walden had transported Boylar's body away from the battlefield. Courage Under Fire is definitely one outstanding film about the Gulf War.It tells an emotional and intriguing tale of a military officer who must review the merits of a fallen officer while confronting his own war demons that makes us feel for every character involved in the story.Also,the movie tells effectively the terrors brought about by war as well as its heartbreaking aftermath.It presents it treats with clarity and intelligence that truly makes it a brilliant film.Another good thing about it is the movie avoids the use of too much violence and swearing to present its story.The performances of the cast were great.Special mention must be given to Denzel Washington for he dominates a film with his quiet intensity and aura of introspection.Credit must also be given to Meg Ryan and Matt Damon,who tried his best to look realistic in his role by shedding many pounds to lose a lot of weight. Overall,Courage Under Fire is a movie that a viewer should not miss as it ranks up there with Platoon and Born On The Fourth Of July as outstanding war films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film with a couple of standout performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just for the record, at least here on IMDb, I think this is an underrated film. And I say that as a person who very rarely likes movies about the military. My dad was in the military most of his adult life, and when he would come home on leave he would always drag me to some war film. I hated it. So, I rarely watch a war movie. But this is a keeper. First, the cast. And let me review the actors in the order of how impressive they were in this film. Denzel Washington, as a Lieutenant Colonel investigating whether a dead female captain should receive the Medal Of Honor, and who himself may have been involved in friendly fire deaths, and who has an alcohol problem, is excellent. Lou Diamond Phillips, as a Staff Sergeant who was at the helicopter crash where the female soldier was killed, is superb here (I never knew he was such a hunk...just for the record). Regina Taylor, as the wife of Washington, is excellent! Meg Ryan, the helicopter pilot who dies, is good, but although her role is pivotal, this is not a very good showcase of her talents, and I do not see her here as the co-star to Denzel Washington. I found Matt Damon rather unimpressive here, but of course, this was just before his breakthrough role that immediately followed this film. Bronson Pinchot was an interesting choice as a White House aide, and he does okay. Michael Moriarty is good as a Brigadier General, as is Scott Glenn as a Washington Post reporter. While I can't say whether or not the Iraq battle scenes were realistic, they impressed me. Despite some inconsistencies, I think the story is a good one. And not a simple one, since the issues that Denzel Washington's character has are complicating his investigation of whether or not Ryan's character should receive the Medal Of Honor. Washington does an admirable job of mixing all these factors and fleshing out the character traits of his role. In fact, this was one of Washington's early films which convinced me that he was an actor that America should treasure. Despite a few flaws, highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overly Sentimental and Top Heavy...But Above Average
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a strong Story here as an investigation ensues about a potential Medal of Honor recipient and the mysterious conflict of testimonies. It is given a twist with a shot of estrogen as the Soldier involved is the first Female to possibly (Posthumously) be awarded the Nation's Highest Military Honor. That should be enough to make this a riveting Mystery and through flashbacks we are shown some striking battle Scenes. So why add the conflict and strife to the investigating Officer. It is completely unnecessary and is the weakest part of the Film and almost drags it down with unconvincing situations of Combat guilt and Family Dysfunction. That could be a whole other Movie. But with that bloating aside there are some strong Performances by the young Cast (actually outshining Denzel) in supporting Roles as the Combat Unit in question. There is a back Story to everyone and it holds up quite well with the central Theme. It must be mentioned here that although, Meg Ryan is miscast as the Captain, she tries her best but cannot outgrow her limitations and convince as a tough Girl in a hopeless, self sacrificing situation. Overall, not a bad Movie and is worth a watch for the strong parts, but there is much too much padding here, plus the heavy dose of sentimentality finally drags this down from Great Movie to just above Average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very, very pretentious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    floyd beck
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry, but I cannot stomach a movie that is pro-military when Meg Ryan, a devout Democrat and worshiper of John Kerry, the war-hater and devout liar, and Denzel Washington, a worshiper of President Obama and a devout Democrat who is said to be a devout Christian. One cannot be both...in 2011, the Democrats voted NO to have God inserted in their convention, in spite of the chairman's blatant lie; just one of 100 reasons. So, after my ranting, what about the movie? It is too hard to believe any of it because the actors are not sincere in true life. It would be like having an openly gay person portray Rudolph Valentino unless the movie was a comedy. Courage Under Fire does not pass as a comedy unless one forces one's mind to the point of insanity to see liberal war-hating actors and actresses pretend to be pro-military.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gutless Under Clich&eacute;
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunmore_ego
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, I know it's trying to be inspiring and heroic and poignant, but COURAGE UNDER FIRE is one of the most blatantly gutless movies ever made. About a soldier investigating whether a downed female United States helicopter pilot in Desert Storm deserves a posthumous Medal of Honor. So I ask you: in which universe will America ever make a movie where a Medal of Honor is investigated and NOT awarded? So it's a foregone conclusion--all the mystery and mayhem and maybes are simply wasting our time more than the actual war this story was set in--as it leads inexorably to the melodramatic military funeral, the flags, saluting, tears of the family, proud shiny buttons and white gloves, the flyover with one plane breaking formation, and that bilious, bleating orchestra swell. And the Medal. The End. Cry me a river; cry me a patently meaningless award, military swine. Then the coda: the investigating soldier visits pilot's grave, salutes grave, tiny flag, voice-over of dead pilot to American Pie Mom and Dad, talking of the Big Push and hero hero hero hero hero hero another blithering orchestra swell I'm going to vomit... Denzel Washington is the investigating soldier, with demons of his own. (Well, they're not really demons; they're roiling stabs of conscience he feels for stupidly shooting one of his own tanks during a skirmish, killing his own men in the hilariously black euphemism "friendly fire," and then having the military cover-up his blunder.) And whenever he has visions of that po' boy he fricasseed in that tank (Mmm! Soldierboy, the other white meat!), he heads straight for the alcohol... uh, cos he's a hero, see. When he's asked to investigate whether Captain Karen Walden (Meg Ryan) is worthy of receiving the Medal of Honor for "courage under fire," the story ends right there. Of course she's deserving of it. She's the first female officer recommended, she's regarded as a hero for sacrificing her life for her men--and she's Meg Ryan. As if the movie would go to all the trouble setting up her heroism and feminism and Ryanism and NOT award her the medal. And every clich&eacute; in the military lexicon is thrown at us like grenades lobbed into foxholes: the tragic family; damaged goods investigating damaged goods; the novice (Matt Damon), the toughguy (Lou Diamond Phillips), the hero-worshipper (Tim Guinee) and all the other bumboys like the Benetton passengers of SPEED; the hospitalized guy (Seth Gilliam) whose seen one battle too many; the military cover-up. And everyone's got Movie PTSD. Denzel wants to find out "what really happened," so COURAGE is constructed like a RASHOMON for rednecks, as we see all the alternate flashbacks with a coy Walden, an indecisive Walden and a butch Walden barking orders and trying not to look like a sex object. Not one of the scenarios is ambiguous about her Hero status--no matter if she threw Iraqi babies at walls or defunded the G.I. Bill. If we can call football players heroes, and people who jumped from the Twin Towers heroes, then this chopper pilot must be a shoo-in, so I ask again: what compels viewers to spend 120 minutes *pretending* there's any doubt? Denzel visits Walden's helicopter bumboys, who all give differing accounts of My Night In The Desert With Captain Walden. Diamond Phillips claims he was the toughguy, as he lies and plies himself with alcohol and commits suicide (cos he's a hero!); Damon claims Walden was a strategic hardnose, as he admits to being a junkie and afraid to go flying again (cos he's a hero!); Guinee relates how Walden sacrificed herself for them, even as he reveals how she got them shot down by taking another pass at an Iraqi tank when she could have flown away--cognitive dissonance rules!--while constantly telling his wife to shutup for calling Walden butch (cos he's a hero!); while Seth Gilliam pounds his medication to numb himself out of the running as a reputable eyewitness (cos he's a hero, see!). What's in it for her bumboys to report that she was a coward? Nothing. But saying she was a HERO makes them vicarious heroes alongside her. Ooo-rah! And here's a note to all you military wardogs whose first reaction is to Spock-chop me for "disrespecting" you (such heroes, fighting for peace!): When are you going to realize your own government, who pays you hypocritical lip service, regards you with even less respect than I do? I just consider you deluded and egotistical and sometimes uneducated, while they consider you cannon fodder! It's the United States government that fools you into getting your asses shot off for them in the first place; it's the United States government that refuses you and your family financial benefits when you return from war; it's the United States government that stop-losses you, reneging on your stipulated leave time, over and over and over again; it's the United States government that cuts your medical funding; it's the United States government that evicts your family, that lies about friendly fire, that doesn't provide armor for you or your vehicles; it's the United States government that kicks you out for being gay after you've dedicated your life to them; it's the United States government that supposedly trains you for PTSD and then all of you return from war with PTSD (Who are the a-holes? You, who are either failing your training, or the government who are failing to train you properly?). Is that what you bitches call "respect"? Under fire from your own government, it's about time you showed some real Courage Under Fire and tell them where to shove it next time they want to exploit you for political gain. That is, unless you really are as dumb as they consider you to be. Ooo-rah! --Poffy The Cucumber
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible Meg Ryan's Performance.Like Cpt. Walden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For people who just want to see Meg in the roles of this sugar romantic- goofy coms I guess that people were lobotomized by an actress and tarnish her, when she runs away from its stereotype and I'm outraged that they can not see versatility and potential Meg Ryan's polivalency.I just see the reviews, pure flattery these crappy actresses nowadays. Ask for Julia Roberts or Angelina Jolie Already piloted an US army chopper in a role? If Michelle Pffeifer or Goldie Hawn(Private Benjamin) played a role very perfectly and naturally of a single mother and determined who dipped the face on the war, and is required in command and demonstrates tight grip and mastery with weapons? without disparaging the Denzel Washignton, which signal, shone like Nathany when reports for soldiers a Karen Walden's deservering Medal of Honor, after Her death by Naphalms, but the episodes of drunkenness became a look dull and weak. Matt Damon,was terrific, skillfully retraced all the facts of 1991's Gulf War. Lou Diamond-Phillips was excellent as paper rebel, rough and impressive and opposite Cpt. Walden. whole more Credits goes to Meg Ryan & Lou D.Phillips, sure as Denzel is a Core person in this movie.Whatever, everybody stunned theirs performance ,But Meg Ryan razed ,and much. Meg Ryan deserves an Oscar. yet, once in her life gone to win.. If God willing.. She's Powerful and more Capable than Demi-Moore, Sharon Stone,and other contemporanies 90'ties Actresses,but Meg is overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    go night train, go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jack-964
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen this movie many years ago and remember i wasn't impressed by it. This was the movie that sunk Meg Ryan for me. I just saw it again and no, it's not worth remembering: I think its starts being lame with the story itself. Why on earth does it have to be a woman? If they wouldn't have put a woman in the center and obviously even worse, cast totally wrong, then the story could actually be interesting, elaborating on different views on the same event. But no, someone decided it had to be 'emancipated', then cast wrong, then pile up a load of unbelievable facts (like downing a tank with a fuel barrel from a helicopter under fire, yea right...) Also unbelievable is the fact that one guy can't stand the truth, even though he had no part in what happened, since he was injured. The other goes on drugs, even though he had no time to think about, let alone react to the lie the third one says. Which commits suicide all of a sudden, when urged to tell the truth, even though his life is going pretty well. And all this is investigated by someone that unknowingly killed a friend in combat, under fire, bla bla. The guy has a wife, kids, great job, status, money, house, and so on, but he can't cope with this accident? It's not all bad. You probably won't fall asleep, but when you find yourself rooting for the alleged bad guy, you know something is very wrong. Go night train go!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie helps heals me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sammy Young
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care about the petty "goofs" or parts of the story that other people point out- this movie means a lot to me as a disabled veteran with PTSD. This movie is about many things, but to me, the story is about how Col Sterling is trying to manage his survivor guilt and PTSD from his incident on one hand, and deal with his task to validate the medal for his General, his wife, his kids, etc. on the other. He resorts to booze (like we all do) to try to cope. That's what this movie is really about: how one guy is trying to come to grips with PTSD, which I can tell you first-hand is a challenge that I face every minute of everyday. And seeing this movie helps heal me. It reminds me that I too lost a promising career in the Navy, lost my marriage, lost my kids, and lost myself in the abyss of PTSD and alcoholism before I got help. That's the only negative I have on this movie- we don't see if Col Sterling got help. Otherwise, this movie has helped heal me in ways that no other movie I've ever seen has.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Prismatic Gulf War drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A strong contemporary war drama examining issues of loyalty, protocol, duty and ultimately truth in an unusually constructed film within a film, at the same using multiple viewpoints ( a la "Rashomon" or "Accident") to unfold the complicated truth at its heart. I'm not sure the somewhat contrived structure served the serious subject matter wholly convincingly, the cinematic devices detracting somewhat from the otherwise lifelike depiction of action in the Gulf War. I also thought Denzel Washington's framing role as the senior army officer given the seemingly straightforward task of reporting on the apparently automatic eligibility of Meg Ryan's posthumous award of the Army medal of honour detracted from the central mystery, especially as he wrestles with his own demons after unwittingly being involved in a tragic friendly-fire incident of his own. So Denz fights the bottle and walks out on his family, before uncovering the truth about Ryan's death and the way back to his own redemption. This final resolution and the underlying implication that the US Army welcomes openness is firstly too pat and improbable, especially in the wake of some real-life events that have come to light since then. All that said, the dramatisation of the war is very well realised and the acting is of a high order, Washington giving it strong and silent in a commanding lead role, but there are even better performances from a young Matt Damon and Lou Diamond-Phillips as two of Ryan's crew who survive the ordeal physically but not mentally. Ryan does well too and I was also impressed by the actress in the menial task of playing Washington's wife. Yes, the film ends up as you'd expect, replete with Washington's last respectful visit to Ryan's grave, but there was enough intrigue and grit in the tale to keep me watching throughout. A braver take on the story, inverting some of the discovered truths here might have made for a better film though, but of course there's no way that viewpoint would have been green-lighted in Hollywood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A resounding "meh"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Do you ever watch those movies that just elicit no reaction from you? I'm talking about the kind of movies that are just so straightforward and so flat that they draw out zero emotions in you and your opinion of the movie elevates to nothing above indifference. For me, this was the case with Courage Under Fire. It stars Denzel Washington as Col. Nat Serling, an army colonel investigating the legitimacy of a post humous Medal of Honor award going to Karen Warden, an army officer who was said to have died heroically while fighting the Iraqis during the Gulf War. However, there are too many discrepancies so Serling is enlisted to find out the truth about what happened to Warden the day her and her platoon went down in their chopper. The film is told through flashbacks which recount the events from different points of views. It's a Rashomon type of story in the way that the events are slightly altered depending on who is recounting them. It's a clever plot device, but not clever or interesting enough to make Courage Under Fire a great film. Don't get me wrong, it's decent. The story isn't something you will see every day and I have to give props to any film that utilizes a more unique narrative style. Akira Kurosawa's Rashomon started this style of the unreliable narrator in film, and it's films like Courage Under Fire that keep the style alive. The problem is that the film doesn't do anything particularly interesting with this narrative style. It plays out how you would expect it to and the actual structure of the film is pretty redundant as well. From start to finish it is essentially Denzel Washington going from place to place, interviewing people about the events that ended Warden's life until he finally gets the truth. There's no real feeling in this film and it lacks any kind of atmosphere or visual nuance. The story presented is engaging to an extent, but there's nothing else to really grab your attention. The bottom line behind Courage Under Fire is it is just a forgettable film. Nothing exists within this film that makes me want to tell people about it, or think about it down the line, or rewatch it ever again. It does things right and it isn't by any means a disaster, but due to its lack of feeling, dull atmosphere, and monotonous plot it just isn't what I would call a fantastic film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film About The 1991 Gulf War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Courage Under Fire is a film about the 1991 Gulf War.It stars Denzel Washington,Meg Ryan,Lou Diamond Phillips and Matt Damon. It is one of the first great films to depict the 1991 Gulf War as it tells a story of a US Army officer, despondent about a deadly mistake he made, investigates a female chopper commander's worthiness for the Medal of Honor.The movie was directed by Edward Zwick. Courage Under Fire has Lieutenant Colonel Nathaniel Serling involved in a friendly fire incident in Al Bathra during the Gulf War. He was an M1 Abrams tank battalion commander who, during the nighttime confusion of Iraqi tanks infiltrating his unit's lines, gave the order to fire, destroying one of his own tanks and killing his friend Lieutenant Boylar. The details were covered up and Serling was reassigned to a desk job.Later, he is assigned to determine if Army Captain Karen Emma Walden should be the first woman to receive the Medal of Honor for valor in combat in the Gulf War posthumously. A Medevac Huey commander, she was sent to rescue the crew of a helicopter that had been shot down. Finding them under heavy fire from an Iraqi tank and infantry, she had her men drop an auxiliary fuel tank on the tank and ignited it with a flare gun. Shortly after, her helicopter was also hit and downed. The two crews were unable to join forces. The survivors were rescued the next day, but Walden had been killed in action.At first, everything seems to be straightforward, but Serling begins to notice inconsistencies between the testimonies of the witnesses. Walden's co-pilot, Warrant Officer One Rady, praises Walden's character and performance, but was hit and unconscious early on. Serling then sees Walden's medic, Specialist Ilario, who also praises Walden. Staff Sergeant Monfriez, however, tells Serling that Walden was a coward. The members of the other downed crew also mention that they heard the distinctive sound of an M16 being used in the firefight during the rescue around the other helicopter, but Walden's crew denies firing one during the rescue, as theirs was out of ammunition. When Serling visits Walden's crew chief, Sergeant Altameyer, who is dying of cancer in a hospital. Altameyer manages to get some words out, further confusing Serling, before self-medicating himself into unconsciousness.Under pressure from the White House and his commander, Brigadier General Hershberg, to wrap things up quickly, Serling leaks the story to newspaper reporter Tony Gartner to prevent another cover up. When Serling puts pressure on Monfriez, the man pulls a pistol at him, then commits suicide by driving his car into an oncoming train.After finding Ilario, Serling discovers that Monfriez wanted to escape under cover of darkness, which would have meant leaving Rady behind. Altameyer was ready to follow his lead and Ilario was wavering, but Walden refused to go along, resulting in an armed standoff with Monfriez. When an Iraqi infantryman appeared suddenly behind Monfriez, Walden fired at him. Mistakenly believing he was the target, Monfriez shot back and seriously wounded her. Walden, however, regained control of her men.The next morning, Walden stayed behind to cover their evacuation, firing the M16. Monfriez deliberately lied to the rescuers, telling them that she was dead so she would be left behind. Altameyer, injured and unable to say anything was ignored. Ilario remained silent. A-10 airplanes then napalmed the wreckage.Serling presents his final report to Hershberg. Walden's young daughter receives the Medal of Honor in a White House ceremony. Later, Serling tearfully tells the Boylars the truth about the manner of their son's death. In the last moments of the film, it is shown that Walden had transported Boylar's body away from the battlefield. Courage Under Fire is definitely one outstanding film about the Gulf War.It tells an emotional and intriguing tale of a military officer who must review the merits of a fallen officer while confronting his own war demons that makes us feel for every character involved in the story.Also,the movie tells effectively the terrors brought about by war as well as its heartbreaking aftermath.It presents it treats with clarity and intelligence that truly makes it a brilliant film.Another good thing about it is the movie avoids the use of too much violence and swearing to present its story.The performances of the cast were great.Special mention must be given to Denzel Washington for he dominates a film with his quiet intensity and aura of introspection.Credit must also be given to Meg Ryan and Matt Damon,who tried his best to look realistic in his role by shedding many pounds to lose a lot of weight. Overall,Courage Under Fire is a movie that a viewer should not miss as it ranks up there with Platoon and Born On The Fourth Of July as outstanding war films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film with a couple of standout performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just for the record, at least here on IMDb, I think this is an underrated film. And I say that as a person who very rarely likes movies about the military. My dad was in the military most of his adult life, and when he would come home on leave he would always drag me to some war film. I hated it. So, I rarely watch a war movie. But this is a keeper. First, the cast. And let me review the actors in the order of how impressive they were in this film. Denzel Washington, as a Lieutenant Colonel investigating whether a dead female captain should receive the Medal Of Honor, and who himself may have been involved in friendly fire deaths, and who has an alcohol problem, is excellent. Lou Diamond Phillips, as a Staff Sergeant who was at the helicopter crash where the female soldier was killed, is superb here (I never knew he was such a hunk...just for the record). Regina Taylor, as the wife of Washington, is excellent! Meg Ryan, the helicopter pilot who dies, is good, but although her role is pivotal, this is not a very good showcase of her talents, and I do not see her here as the co-star to Denzel Washington. I found Matt Damon rather unimpressive here, but of course, this was just before his breakthrough role that immediately followed this film. Bronson Pinchot was an interesting choice as a White House aide, and he does okay. Michael Moriarty is good as a Brigadier General, as is Scott Glenn as a Washington Post reporter. While I can't say whether or not the Iraq battle scenes were realistic, they impressed me. Despite some inconsistencies, I think the story is a good one. And not a simple one, since the issues that Denzel Washington's character has are complicating his investigation of whether or not Ryan's character should receive the Medal Of Honor. Washington does an admirable job of mixing all these factors and fleshing out the character traits of his role. In fact, this was one of Washington's early films which convinced me that he was an actor that America should treasure. Despite a few flaws, highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overly Sentimental and Top Heavy...But Above Average
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a strong Story here as an investigation ensues about a potential Medal of Honor recipient and the mysterious conflict of testimonies. It is given a twist with a shot of estrogen as the Soldier involved is the first Female to possibly (Posthumously) be awarded the Nation's Highest Military Honor. That should be enough to make this a riveting Mystery and through flashbacks we are shown some striking battle Scenes. So why add the conflict and strife to the investigating Officer. It is completely unnecessary and is the weakest part of the Film and almost drags it down with unconvincing situations of Combat guilt and Family Dysfunction. That could be a whole other Movie. But with that bloating aside there are some strong Performances by the young Cast (actually outshining Denzel) in supporting Roles as the Combat Unit in question. There is a back Story to everyone and it holds up quite well with the central Theme. It must be mentioned here that although, Meg Ryan is miscast as the Captain, she tries her best but cannot outgrow her limitations and convince as a tough Girl in a hopeless, self sacrificing situation. Overall, not a bad Movie and is worth a watch for the strong parts, but there is much too much padding here, plus the heavy dose of sentimentality finally drags this down from Great Movie to just above Average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very, very pretentious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    floyd beck
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry, but I cannot stomach a movie that is pro-military when Meg Ryan, a devout Democrat and worshiper of John Kerry, the war-hater and devout liar, and Denzel Washington, a worshiper of President Obama and a devout Democrat who is said to be a devout Christian. One cannot be both...in 2011, the Democrats voted NO to have God inserted in their convention, in spite of the chairman's blatant lie; just one of 100 reasons. So, after my ranting, what about the movie? It is too hard to believe any of it because the actors are not sincere in true life. It would be like having an openly gay person portray Rudolph Valentino unless the movie was a comedy. Courage Under Fire does not pass as a comedy unless one forces one's mind to the point of insanity to see liberal war-hating actors and actresses pretend to be pro-military.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gutless Under Clich&eacute;
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunmore_ego
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, I know it's trying to be inspiring and heroic and poignant, but COURAGE UNDER FIRE is one of the most blatantly gutless movies ever made. About a soldier investigating whether a downed female United States helicopter pilot in Desert Storm deserves a posthumous Medal of Honor. So I ask you: in which universe will America ever make a movie where a Medal of Honor is investigated and NOT awarded? So it's a foregone conclusion--all the mystery and mayhem and maybes are simply wasting our time more than the actual war this story was set in--as it leads inexorably to the melodramatic military funeral, the flags, saluting, tears of the family, proud shiny buttons and white gloves, the flyover with one plane breaking formation, and that bilious, bleating orchestra swell. And the Medal. The End. Cry me a river; cry me a patently meaningless award, military swine. Then the coda: the investigating soldier visits pilot's grave, salutes grave, tiny flag, voice-over of dead pilot to American Pie Mom and Dad, talking of the Big Push and hero hero hero hero hero hero another blithering orchestra swell I'm going to vomit... Denzel Washington is the investigating soldier, with demons of his own. (Well, they're not really demons; they're roiling stabs of conscience he feels for stupidly shooting one of his own tanks during a skirmish, killing his own men in the hilariously black euphemism "friendly fire," and then having the military cover-up his blunder.) And whenever he has visions of that po' boy he fricasseed in that tank (Mmm! Soldierboy, the other white meat!), he heads straight for the alcohol... uh, cos he's a hero, see. When he's asked to investigate whether Captain Karen Walden (Meg Ryan) is worthy of receiving the Medal of Honor for "courage under fire," the story ends right there. Of course she's deserving of it. She's the first female officer recommended, she's regarded as a hero for sacrificing her life for her men--and she's Meg Ryan. As if the movie would go to all the trouble setting up her heroism and feminism and Ryanism and NOT award her the medal. And every clich&eacute; in the military lexicon is thrown at us like grenades lobbed into foxholes: the tragic family; damaged goods investigating damaged goods; the novice (Matt Damon), the toughguy (Lou Diamond Phillips), the hero-worshipper (Tim Guinee) and all the other bumboys like the Benetton passengers of SPEED; the hospitalized guy (Seth Gilliam) whose seen one battle too many; the military cover-up. And everyone's got Movie PTSD. Denzel wants to find out "what really happened," so COURAGE is constructed like a RASHOMON for rednecks, as we see all the alternate flashbacks with a coy Walden, an indecisive Walden and a butch Walden barking orders and trying not to look like a sex object. Not one of the scenarios is ambiguous about her Hero status--no matter if she threw Iraqi babies at walls or defunded the G.I. Bill. If we can call football players heroes, and people who jumped from the Twin Towers heroes, then this chopper pilot must be a shoo-in, so I ask again: what compels viewers to spend 120 minutes *pretending* there's any doubt? Denzel visits Walden's helicopter bumboys, who all give differing accounts of My Night In The Desert With Captain Walden. Diamond Phillips claims he was the toughguy, as he lies and plies himself with alcohol and commits suicide (cos he's a hero!); Damon claims Walden was a strategic hardnose, as he admits to being a junkie and afraid to go flying again (cos he's a hero!); Guinee relates how Walden sacrificed herself for them, even as he reveals how she got them shot down by taking another pass at an Iraqi tank when she could have flown away--cognitive dissonance rules!--while constantly telling his wife to shutup for calling Walden butch (cos he's a hero!); while Seth Gilliam pounds his medication to numb himself out of the running as a reputable eyewitness (cos he's a hero, see!). What's in it for her bumboys to report that she was a coward? Nothing. But saying she was a HERO makes them vicarious heroes alongside her. Ooo-rah! And here's a note to all you military wardogs whose first reaction is to Spock-chop me for "disrespecting" you (such heroes, fighting for peace!): When are you going to realize your own government, who pays you hypocritical lip service, regards you with even less respect than I do? I just consider you deluded and egotistical and sometimes uneducated, while they consider you cannon fodder! It's the United States government that fools you into getting your asses shot off for them in the first place; it's the United States government that refuses you and your family financial benefits when you return from war; it's the United States government that stop-losses you, reneging on your stipulated leave time, over and over and over again; it's the United States government that cuts your medical funding; it's the United States government that evicts your family, that lies about friendly fire, that doesn't provide armor for you or your vehicles; it's the United States government that kicks you out for being gay after you've dedicated your life to them; it's the United States government that supposedly trains you for PTSD and then all of you return from war with PTSD (Who are the a-holes? You, who are either failing your training, or the government who are failing to train you properly?). Is that what you bitches call "respect"? Under fire from your own government, it's about time you showed some real Courage Under Fire and tell them where to shove it next time they want to exploit you for political gain. That is, unless you really are as dumb as they consider you to be. Ooo-rah! --Poffy The Cucumber
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible Meg Ryan's Performance.Like Cpt. Walden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For people who just want to see Meg in the roles of this sugar romantic- goofy coms I guess that people were lobotomized by an actress and tarnish her, when she runs away from its stereotype and I'm outraged that they can not see versatility and potential Meg Ryan's polivalency.I just see the reviews, pure flattery these crappy actresses nowadays. Ask for Julia Roberts or Angelina Jolie Already piloted an US army chopper in a role? If Michelle Pffeifer or Goldie Hawn(Private Benjamin) played a role very perfectly and naturally of a single mother and determined who dipped the face on the war, and is required in command and demonstrates tight grip and mastery with weapons? without disparaging the Denzel Washignton, which signal, shone like Nathany when reports for soldiers a Karen Walden's deservering Medal of Honor, after Her death by Naphalms, but the episodes of drunkenness became a look dull and weak. Matt Damon,was terrific, skillfully retraced all the facts of 1991's Gulf War. Lou Diamond-Phillips was excellent as paper rebel, rough and impressive and opposite Cpt. Walden. whole more Credits goes to Meg Ryan & Lou D.Phillips, sure as Denzel is a Core person in this movie.Whatever, everybody stunned theirs performance ,But Meg Ryan razed ,and much. Meg Ryan deserves an Oscar. yet, once in her life gone to win.. If God willing.. She's Powerful and more Capable than Demi-Moore, Sharon Stone,and other contemporanies 90'ties Actresses,but Meg is overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    go night train, go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jack-964
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen this movie many years ago and remember i wasn't impressed by it. This was the movie that sunk Meg Ryan for me. I just saw it again and no, it's not worth remembering: I think its starts being lame with the story itself. Why on earth does it have to be a woman? If they wouldn't have put a woman in the center and obviously even worse, cast totally wrong, then the story could actually be interesting, elaborating on different views on the same event. But no, someone decided it had to be 'emancipated', then cast wrong, then pile up a load of unbelievable facts (like downing a tank with a fuel barrel from a helicopter under fire, yea right...) Also unbelievable is the fact that one guy can't stand the truth, even though he had no part in what happened, since he was injured. The other goes on drugs, even though he had no time to think about, let alone react to the lie the third one says. Which commits suicide all of a sudden, when urged to tell the truth, even though his life is going pretty well. And all this is investigated by someone that unknowingly killed a friend in combat, under fire, bla bla. The guy has a wife, kids, great job, status, money, house, and so on, but he can't cope with this accident? It's not all bad. You probably won't fall asleep, but when you find yourself rooting for the alleged bad guy, you know something is very wrong. Go night train go!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie helps heals me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sammy Young
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care about the petty "goofs" or parts of the story that other people point out- this movie means a lot to me as a disabled veteran with PTSD. This movie is about many things, but to me, the story is about how Col Sterling is trying to manage his survivor guilt and PTSD from his incident on one hand, and deal with his task to validate the medal for his General, his wife, his kids, etc. on the other. He resorts to booze (like we all do) to try to cope. That's what this movie is really about: how one guy is trying to come to grips with PTSD, which I can tell you first-hand is a challenge that I face every minute of everyday. And seeing this movie helps heal me. It reminds me that I too lost a promising career in the Navy, lost my marriage, lost my kids, and lost myself in the abyss of PTSD and alcoholism before I got help. That's the only negative I have on this movie- we don't see if Col Sterling got help. Otherwise, this movie has helped heal me in ways that no other movie I've ever seen has.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Prismatic Gulf War drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A strong contemporary war drama examining issues of loyalty, protocol, duty and ultimately truth in an unusually constructed film within a film, at the same using multiple viewpoints ( a la "Rashomon" or "Accident") to unfold the complicated truth at its heart. I'm not sure the somewhat contrived structure served the serious subject matter wholly convincingly, the cinematic devices detracting somewhat from the otherwise lifelike depiction of action in the Gulf War. I also thought Denzel Washington's framing role as the senior army officer given the seemingly straightforward task of reporting on the apparently automatic eligibility of Meg Ryan's posthumous award of the Army medal of honour detracted from the central mystery, especially as he wrestles with his own demons after unwittingly being involved in a tragic friendly-fire incident of his own. So Denz fights the bottle and walks out on his family, before uncovering the truth about Ryan's death and the way back to his own redemption. This final resolution and the underlying implication that the US Army welcomes openness is firstly too pat and improbable, especially in the wake of some real-life events that have come to light since then. All that said, the dramatisation of the war is very well realised and the acting is of a high order, Washington giving it strong and silent in a commanding lead role, but there are even better performances from a young Matt Damon and Lou Diamond-Phillips as two of Ryan's crew who survive the ordeal physically but not mentally. Ryan does well too and I was also impressed by the actress in the menial task of playing Washington's wife. Yes, the film ends up as you'd expect, replete with Washington's last respectful visit to Ryan's grave, but there was enough intrigue and grit in the tale to keep me watching throughout. A braver take on the story, inverting some of the discovered truths here might have made for a better film though, but of course there's no way that viewpoint would have been green-lighted in Hollywood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A resounding "meh"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Do you ever watch those movies that just elicit no reaction from you? I'm talking about the kind of movies that are just so straightforward and so flat that they draw out zero emotions in you and your opinion of the movie elevates to nothing above indifference. For me, this was the case with Courage Under Fire. It stars Denzel Washington as Col. Nat Serling, an army colonel investigating the legitimacy of a post humous Medal of Honor award going to Karen Warden, an army officer who was said to have died heroically while fighting the Iraqis during the Gulf War. However, there are too many discrepancies so Serling is enlisted to find out the truth about what happened to Warden the day her and her platoon went down in their chopper. The film is told through flashbacks which recount the events from different points of views. It's a Rashomon type of story in the way that the events are slightly altered depending on who is recounting them. It's a clever plot device, but not clever or interesting enough to make Courage Under Fire a great film. Don't get me wrong, it's decent. The story isn't something you will see every day and I have to give props to any film that utilizes a more unique narrative style. Akira Kurosawa's Rashomon started this style of the unreliable narrator in film, and it's films like Courage Under Fire that keep the style alive. The problem is that the film doesn't do anything particularly interesting with this narrative style. It plays out how you would expect it to and the actual structure of the film is pretty redundant as well. From start to finish it is essentially Denzel Washington going from place to place, interviewing people about the events that ended Warden's life until he finally gets the truth. There's no real feeling in this film and it lacks any kind of atmosphere or visual nuance. The story presented is engaging to an extent, but there's nothing else to really grab your attention. The bottom line behind Courage Under Fire is it is just a forgettable film. Nothing exists within this film that makes me want to tell people about it, or think about it down the line, or rewatch it ever again. It does things right and it isn't by any means a disaster, but due to its lack of feeling, dull atmosphere, and monotonous plot it just isn't what I would call a fantastic film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film About The 1991 Gulf War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Courage Under Fire is a film about the 1991 Gulf War.It stars Denzel Washington,Meg Ryan,Lou Diamond Phillips and Matt Damon. It is one of the first great films to depict the 1991 Gulf War as it tells a story of a US Army officer, despondent about a deadly mistake he made, investigates a female chopper commander's worthiness for the Medal of Honor.The movie was directed by Edward Zwick. Courage Under Fire has Lieutenant Colonel Nathaniel Serling involved in a friendly fire incident in Al Bathra during the Gulf War. He was an M1 Abrams tank battalion commander who, during the nighttime confusion of Iraqi tanks infiltrating his unit's lines, gave the order to fire, destroying one of his own tanks and killing his friend Lieutenant Boylar. The details were covered up and Serling was reassigned to a desk job.Later, he is assigned to determine if Army Captain Karen Emma Walden should be the first woman to receive the Medal of Honor for valor in combat in the Gulf War posthumously. A Medevac Huey commander, she was sent to rescue the crew of a helicopter that had been shot down. Finding them under heavy fire from an Iraqi tank and infantry, she had her men drop an auxiliary fuel tank on the tank and ignited it with a flare gun. Shortly after, her helicopter was also hit and downed. The two crews were unable to join forces. The survivors were rescued the next day, but Walden had been killed in action.At first, everything seems to be straightforward, but Serling begins to notice inconsistencies between the testimonies of the witnesses. Walden's co-pilot, Warrant Officer One Rady, praises Walden's character and performance, but was hit and unconscious early on. Serling then sees Walden's medic, Specialist Ilario, who also praises Walden. Staff Sergeant Monfriez, however, tells Serling that Walden was a coward. The members of the other downed crew also mention that they heard the distinctive sound of an M16 being used in the firefight during the rescue around the other helicopter, but Walden's crew denies firing one during the rescue, as theirs was out of ammunition. When Serling visits Walden's crew chief, Sergeant Altameyer, who is dying of cancer in a hospital. Altameyer manages to get some words out, further confusing Serling, before self-medicating himself into unconsciousness.Under pressure from the White House and his commander, Brigadier General Hershberg, to wrap things up quickly, Serling leaks the story to newspaper reporter Tony Gartner to prevent another cover up. When Serling puts pressure on Monfriez, the man pulls a pistol at him, then commits suicide by driving his car into an oncoming train.After finding Ilario, Serling discovers that Monfriez wanted to escape under cover of darkness, which would have meant leaving Rady behind. Altameyer was ready to follow his lead and Ilario was wavering, but Walden refused to go along, resulting in an armed standoff with Monfriez. When an Iraqi infantryman appeared suddenly behind Monfriez, Walden fired at him. Mistakenly believing he was the target, Monfriez shot back and seriously wounded her. Walden, however, regained control of her men.The next morning, Walden stayed behind to cover their evacuation, firing the M16. Monfriez deliberately lied to the rescuers, telling them that she was dead so she would be left behind. Altameyer, injured and unable to say anything was ignored. Ilario remained silent. A-10 airplanes then napalmed the wreckage.Serling presents his final report to Hershberg. Walden's young daughter receives the Medal of Honor in a White House ceremony. Later, Serling tearfully tells the Boylars the truth about the manner of their son's death. In the last moments of the film, it is shown that Walden had transported Boylar's body away from the battlefield. Courage Under Fire is definitely one outstanding film about the Gulf War.It tells an emotional and intriguing tale of a military officer who must review the merits of a fallen officer while confronting his own war demons that makes us feel for every character involved in the story.Also,the movie tells effectively the terrors brought about by war as well as its heartbreaking aftermath.It presents it treats with clarity and intelligence that truly makes it a brilliant film.Another good thing about it is the movie avoids the use of too much violence and swearing to present its story.The performances of the cast were great.Special mention must be given to Denzel Washington for he dominates a film with his quiet intensity and aura of introspection.Credit must also be given to Meg Ryan and Matt Damon,who tried his best to look realistic in his role by shedding many pounds to lose a lot of weight. Overall,Courage Under Fire is a movie that a viewer should not miss as it ranks up there with Platoon and Born On The Fourth Of July as outstanding war films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film with a couple of standout performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just for the record, at least here on IMDb, I think this is an underrated film. And I say that as a person who very rarely likes movies about the military. My dad was in the military most of his adult life, and when he would come home on leave he would always drag me to some war film. I hated it. So, I rarely watch a war movie. But this is a keeper. First, the cast. And let me review the actors in the order of how impressive they were in this film. Denzel Washington, as a Lieutenant Colonel investigating whether a dead female captain should receive the Medal Of Honor, and who himself may have been involved in friendly fire deaths, and who has an alcohol problem, is excellent. Lou Diamond Phillips, as a Staff Sergeant who was at the helicopter crash where the female soldier was killed, is superb here (I never knew he was such a hunk...just for the record). Regina Taylor, as the wife of Washington, is excellent! Meg Ryan, the helicopter pilot who dies, is good, but although her role is pivotal, this is not a very good showcase of her talents, and I do not see her here as the co-star to Denzel Washington. I found Matt Damon rather unimpressive here, but of course, this was just before his breakthrough role that immediately followed this film. Bronson Pinchot was an interesting choice as a White House aide, and he does okay. Michael Moriarty is good as a Brigadier General, as is Scott Glenn as a Washington Post reporter. While I can't say whether or not the Iraq battle scenes were realistic, they impressed me. Despite some inconsistencies, I think the story is a good one. And not a simple one, since the issues that Denzel Washington's character has are complicating his investigation of whether or not Ryan's character should receive the Medal Of Honor. Washington does an admirable job of mixing all these factors and fleshing out the character traits of his role. In fact, this was one of Washington's early films which convinced me that he was an actor that America should treasure. Despite a few flaws, highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overly Sentimental and Top Heavy...But Above Average
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a strong Story here as an investigation ensues about a potential Medal of Honor recipient and the mysterious conflict of testimonies. It is given a twist with a shot of estrogen as the Soldier involved is the first Female to possibly (Posthumously) be awarded the Nation's Highest Military Honor. That should be enough to make this a riveting Mystery and through flashbacks we are shown some striking battle Scenes. So why add the conflict and strife to the investigating Officer. It is completely unnecessary and is the weakest part of the Film and almost drags it down with unconvincing situations of Combat guilt and Family Dysfunction. That could be a whole other Movie. But with that bloating aside there are some strong Performances by the young Cast (actually outshining Denzel) in supporting Roles as the Combat Unit in question. There is a back Story to everyone and it holds up quite well with the central Theme. It must be mentioned here that although, Meg Ryan is miscast as the Captain, she tries her best but cannot outgrow her limitations and convince as a tough Girl in a hopeless, self sacrificing situation. Overall, not a bad Movie and is worth a watch for the strong parts, but there is much too much padding here, plus the heavy dose of sentimentality finally drags this down from Great Movie to just above Average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very, very pretentious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    floyd beck
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry, but I cannot stomach a movie that is pro-military when Meg Ryan, a devout Democrat and worshiper of John Kerry, the war-hater and devout liar, and Denzel Washington, a worshiper of President Obama and a devout Democrat who is said to be a devout Christian. One cannot be both...in 2011, the Democrats voted NO to have God inserted in their convention, in spite of the chairman's blatant lie; just one of 100 reasons. So, after my ranting, what about the movie? It is too hard to believe any of it because the actors are not sincere in true life. It would be like having an openly gay person portray Rudolph Valentino unless the movie was a comedy. Courage Under Fire does not pass as a comedy unless one forces one's mind to the point of insanity to see liberal war-hating actors and actresses pretend to be pro-military.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gutless Under Clich&eacute;
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunmore_ego
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, I know it's trying to be inspiring and heroic and poignant, but COURAGE UNDER FIRE is one of the most blatantly gutless movies ever made. About a soldier investigating whether a downed female United States helicopter pilot in Desert Storm deserves a posthumous Medal of Honor. So I ask you: in which universe will America ever make a movie where a Medal of Honor is investigated and NOT awarded? So it's a foregone conclusion--all the mystery and mayhem and maybes are simply wasting our time more than the actual war this story was set in--as it leads inexorably to the melodramatic military funeral, the flags, saluting, tears of the family, proud shiny buttons and white gloves, the flyover with one plane breaking formation, and that bilious, bleating orchestra swell. And the Medal. The End. Cry me a river; cry me a patently meaningless award, military swine. Then the coda: the investigating soldier visits pilot's grave, salutes grave, tiny flag, voice-over of dead pilot to American Pie Mom and Dad, talking of the Big Push and hero hero hero hero hero hero another blithering orchestra swell I'm going to vomit... Denzel Washington is the investigating soldier, with demons of his own. (Well, they're not really demons; they're roiling stabs of conscience he feels for stupidly shooting one of his own tanks during a skirmish, killing his own men in the hilariously black euphemism "friendly fire," and then having the military cover-up his blunder.) And whenever he has visions of that po' boy he fricasseed in that tank (Mmm! Soldierboy, the other white meat!), he heads straight for the alcohol... uh, cos he's a hero, see. When he's asked to investigate whether Captain Karen Walden (Meg Ryan) is worthy of receiving the Medal of Honor for "courage under fire," the story ends right there. Of course she's deserving of it. She's the first female officer recommended, she's regarded as a hero for sacrificing her life for her men--and she's Meg Ryan. As if the movie would go to all the trouble setting up her heroism and feminism and Ryanism and NOT award her the medal. And every clich&eacute; in the military lexicon is thrown at us like grenades lobbed into foxholes: the tragic family; damaged goods investigating damaged goods; the novice (Matt Damon), the toughguy (Lou Diamond Phillips), the hero-worshipper (Tim Guinee) and all the other bumboys like the Benetton passengers of SPEED; the hospitalized guy (Seth Gilliam) whose seen one battle too many; the military cover-up. And everyone's got Movie PTSD. Denzel wants to find out "what really happened," so COURAGE is constructed like a RASHOMON for rednecks, as we see all the alternate flashbacks with a coy Walden, an indecisive Walden and a butch Walden barking orders and trying not to look like a sex object. Not one of the scenarios is ambiguous about her Hero status--no matter if she threw Iraqi babies at walls or defunded the G.I. Bill. If we can call football players heroes, and people who jumped from the Twin Towers heroes, then this chopper pilot must be a shoo-in, so I ask again: what compels viewers to spend 120 minutes *pretending* there's any doubt? Denzel visits Walden's helicopter bumboys, who all give differing accounts of My Night In The Desert With Captain Walden. Diamond Phillips claims he was the toughguy, as he lies and plies himself with alcohol and commits suicide (cos he's a hero!); Damon claims Walden was a strategic hardnose, as he admits to being a junkie and afraid to go flying again (cos he's a hero!); Guinee relates how Walden sacrificed herself for them, even as he reveals how she got them shot down by taking another pass at an Iraqi tank when she could have flown away--cognitive dissonance rules!--while constantly telling his wife to shutup for calling Walden butch (cos he's a hero!); while Seth Gilliam pounds his medication to numb himself out of the running as a reputable eyewitness (cos he's a hero, see!). What's in it for her bumboys to report that she was a coward? Nothing. But saying she was a HERO makes them vicarious heroes alongside her. Ooo-rah! And here's a note to all you military wardogs whose first reaction is to Spock-chop me for "disrespecting" you (such heroes, fighting for peace!): When are you going to realize your own government, who pays you hypocritical lip service, regards you with even less respect than I do? I just consider you deluded and egotistical and sometimes uneducated, while they consider you cannon fodder! It's the United States government that fools you into getting your asses shot off for them in the first place; it's the United States government that refuses you and your family financial benefits when you return from war; it's the United States government that stop-losses you, reneging on your stipulated leave time, over and over and over again; it's the United States government that cuts your medical funding; it's the United States government that evicts your family, that lies about friendly fire, that doesn't provide armor for you or your vehicles; it's the United States government that kicks you out for being gay after you've dedicated your life to them; it's the United States government that supposedly trains you for PTSD and then all of you return from war with PTSD (Who are the a-holes? You, who are either failing your training, or the government who are failing to train you properly?). Is that what you bitches call "respect"? Under fire from your own government, it's about time you showed some real Courage Under Fire and tell them where to shove it next time they want to exploit you for political gain. That is, unless you really are as dumb as they consider you to be. Ooo-rah! --Poffy The Cucumber
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible Meg Ryan's Performance.Like Cpt. Walden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For people who just want to see Meg in the roles of this sugar romantic- goofy coms I guess that people were lobotomized by an actress and tarnish her, when she runs away from its stereotype and I'm outraged that they can not see versatility and potential Meg Ryan's polivalency.I just see the reviews, pure flattery these crappy actresses nowadays. Ask for Julia Roberts or Angelina Jolie Already piloted an US army chopper in a role? If Michelle Pffeifer or Goldie Hawn(Private Benjamin) played a role very perfectly and naturally of a single mother and determined who dipped the face on the war, and is required in command and demonstrates tight grip and mastery with weapons? without disparaging the Denzel Washignton, which signal, shone like Nathany when reports for soldiers a Karen Walden's deservering Medal of Honor, after Her death by Naphalms, but the episodes of drunkenness became a look dull and weak. Matt Damon,was terrific, skillfully retraced all the facts of 1991's Gulf War. Lou Diamond-Phillips was excellent as paper rebel, rough and impressive and opposite Cpt. Walden. whole more Credits goes to Meg Ryan & Lou D.Phillips, sure as Denzel is a Core person in this movie.Whatever, everybody stunned theirs performance ,But Meg Ryan razed ,and much. Meg Ryan deserves an Oscar. yet, once in her life gone to win.. If God willing.. She's Powerful and more Capable than Demi-Moore, Sharon Stone,and other contemporanies 90'ties Actresses,but Meg is overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    go night train, go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jack-964
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen this movie many years ago and remember i wasn't impressed by it. This was the movie that sunk Meg Ryan for me. I just saw it again and no, it's not worth remembering: I think its starts being lame with the story itself. Why on earth does it have to be a woman? If they wouldn't have put a woman in the center and obviously even worse, cast totally wrong, then the story could actually be interesting, elaborating on different views on the same event. But no, someone decided it had to be 'emancipated', then cast wrong, then pile up a load of unbelievable facts (like downing a tank with a fuel barrel from a helicopter under fire, yea right...) Also unbelievable is the fact that one guy can't stand the truth, even though he had no part in what happened, since he was injured. The other goes on drugs, even though he had no time to think about, let alone react to the lie the third one says. Which commits suicide all of a sudden, when urged to tell the truth, even though his life is going pretty well. And all this is investigated by someone that unknowingly killed a friend in combat, under fire, bla bla. The guy has a wife, kids, great job, status, money, house, and so on, but he can't cope with this accident? It's not all bad. You probably won't fall asleep, but when you find yourself rooting for the alleged bad guy, you know something is very wrong. Go night train go!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie helps heals me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sammy Young
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care about the petty "goofs" or parts of the story that other people point out- this movie means a lot to me as a disabled veteran with PTSD. This movie is about many things, but to me, the story is about how Col Sterling is trying to manage his survivor guilt and PTSD from his incident on one hand, and deal with his task to validate the medal for his General, his wife, his kids, etc. on the other. He resorts to booze (like we all do) to try to cope. That's what this movie is really about: how one guy is trying to come to grips with PTSD, which I can tell you first-hand is a challenge that I face every minute of everyday. And seeing this movie helps heal me. It reminds me that I too lost a promising career in the Navy, lost my marriage, lost my kids, and lost myself in the abyss of PTSD and alcoholism before I got help. That's the only negative I have on this movie- we don't see if Col Sterling got help. Otherwise, this movie has helped heal me in ways that no other movie I've ever seen has.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Prismatic Gulf War drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A strong contemporary war drama examining issues of loyalty, protocol, duty and ultimately truth in an unusually constructed film within a film, at the same using multiple viewpoints ( a la "Rashomon" or "Accident") to unfold the complicated truth at its heart. I'm not sure the somewhat contrived structure served the serious subject matter wholly convincingly, the cinematic devices detracting somewhat from the otherwise lifelike depiction of action in the Gulf War. I also thought Denzel Washington's framing role as the senior army officer given the seemingly straightforward task of reporting on the apparently automatic eligibility of Meg Ryan's posthumous award of the Army medal of honour detracted from the central mystery, especially as he wrestles with his own demons after unwittingly being involved in a tragic friendly-fire incident of his own. So Denz fights the bottle and walks out on his family, before uncovering the truth about Ryan's death and the way back to his own redemption. This final resolution and the underlying implication that the US Army welcomes openness is firstly too pat and improbable, especially in the wake of some real-life events that have come to light since then. All that said, the dramatisation of the war is very well realised and the acting is of a high order, Washington giving it strong and silent in a commanding lead role, but there are even better performances from a young Matt Damon and Lou Diamond-Phillips as two of Ryan's crew who survive the ordeal physically but not mentally. Ryan does well too and I was also impressed by the actress in the menial task of playing Washington's wife. Yes, the film ends up as you'd expect, replete with Washington's last respectful visit to Ryan's grave, but there was enough intrigue and grit in the tale to keep me watching throughout. A braver take on the story, inverting some of the discovered truths here might have made for a better film though, but of course there's no way that viewpoint would have been green-lighted in Hollywood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A resounding "meh"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Do you ever watch those movies that just elicit no reaction from you? I'm talking about the kind of movies that are just so straightforward and so flat that they draw out zero emotions in you and your opinion of the movie elevates to nothing above indifference. For me, this was the case with Courage Under Fire. It stars Denzel Washington as Col. Nat Serling, an army colonel investigating the legitimacy of a post humous Medal of Honor award going to Karen Warden, an army officer who was said to have died heroically while fighting the Iraqis during the Gulf War. However, there are too many discrepancies so Serling is enlisted to find out the truth about what happened to Warden the day her and her platoon went down in their chopper. The film is told through flashbacks which recount the events from different points of views. It's a Rashomon type of story in the way that the events are slightly altered depending on who is recounting them. It's a clever plot device, but not clever or interesting enough to make Courage Under Fire a great film. Don't get me wrong, it's decent. The story isn't something you will see every day and I have to give props to any film that utilizes a more unique narrative style. Akira Kurosawa's Rashomon started this style of the unreliable narrator in film, and it's films like Courage Under Fire that keep the style alive. The problem is that the film doesn't do anything particularly interesting with this narrative style. It plays out how you would expect it to and the actual structure of the film is pretty redundant as well. From start to finish it is essentially Denzel Washington going from place to place, interviewing people about the events that ended Warden's life until he finally gets the truth. There's no real feeling in this film and it lacks any kind of atmosphere or visual nuance. The story presented is engaging to an extent, but there's nothing else to really grab your attention. The bottom line behind Courage Under Fire is it is just a forgettable film. Nothing exists within this film that makes me want to tell people about it, or think about it down the line, or rewatch it ever again. It does things right and it isn't by any means a disaster, but due to its lack of feeling, dull atmosphere, and monotonous plot it just isn't what I would call a fantastic film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film About The 1991 Gulf War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Courage Under Fire is a film about the 1991 Gulf War.It stars Denzel Washington,Meg Ryan,Lou Diamond Phillips and Matt Damon. It is one of the first great films to depict the 1991 Gulf War as it tells a story of a US Army officer, despondent about a deadly mistake he made, investigates a female chopper commander's worthiness for the Medal of Honor.The movie was directed by Edward Zwick. Courage Under Fire has Lieutenant Colonel Nathaniel Serling involved in a friendly fire incident in Al Bathra during the Gulf War. He was an M1 Abrams tank battalion commander who, during the nighttime confusion of Iraqi tanks infiltrating his unit's lines, gave the order to fire, destroying one of his own tanks and killing his friend Lieutenant Boylar. The details were covered up and Serling was reassigned to a desk job.Later, he is assigned to determine if Army Captain Karen Emma Walden should be the first woman to receive the Medal of Honor for valor in combat in the Gulf War posthumously. A Medevac Huey commander, she was sent to rescue the crew of a helicopter that had been shot down. Finding them under heavy fire from an Iraqi tank and infantry, she had her men drop an auxiliary fuel tank on the tank and ignited it with a flare gun. Shortly after, her helicopter was also hit and downed. The two crews were unable to join forces. The survivors were rescued the next day, but Walden had been killed in action.At first, everything seems to be straightforward, but Serling begins to notice inconsistencies between the testimonies of the witnesses. Walden's co-pilot, Warrant Officer One Rady, praises Walden's character and performance, but was hit and unconscious early on. Serling then sees Walden's medic, Specialist Ilario, who also praises Walden. Staff Sergeant Monfriez, however, tells Serling that Walden was a coward. The members of the other downed crew also mention that they heard the distinctive sound of an M16 being used in the firefight during the rescue around the other helicopter, but Walden's crew denies firing one during the rescue, as theirs was out of ammunition. When Serling visits Walden's crew chief, Sergeant Altameyer, who is dying of cancer in a hospital. Altameyer manages to get some words out, further confusing Serling, before self-medicating himself into unconsciousness.Under pressure from the White House and his commander, Brigadier General Hershberg, to wrap things up quickly, Serling leaks the story to newspaper reporter Tony Gartner to prevent another cover up. When Serling puts pressure on Monfriez, the man pulls a pistol at him, then commits suicide by driving his car into an oncoming train.After finding Ilario, Serling discovers that Monfriez wanted to escape under cover of darkness, which would have meant leaving Rady behind. Altameyer was ready to follow his lead and Ilario was wavering, but Walden refused to go along, resulting in an armed standoff with Monfriez. When an Iraqi infantryman appeared suddenly behind Monfriez, Walden fired at him. Mistakenly believing he was the target, Monfriez shot back and seriously wounded her. Walden, however, regained control of her men.The next morning, Walden stayed behind to cover their evacuation, firing the M16. Monfriez deliberately lied to the rescuers, telling them that she was dead so she would be left behind. Altameyer, injured and unable to say anything was ignored. Ilario remained silent. A-10 airplanes then napalmed the wreckage.Serling presents his final report to Hershberg. Walden's young daughter receives the Medal of Honor in a White House ceremony. Later, Serling tearfully tells the Boylars the truth about the manner of their son's death. In the last moments of the film, it is shown that Walden had transported Boylar's body away from the battlefield. Courage Under Fire is definitely one outstanding film about the Gulf War.It tells an emotional and intriguing tale of a military officer who must review the merits of a fallen officer while confronting his own war demons that makes us feel for every character involved in the story.Also,the movie tells effectively the terrors brought about by war as well as its heartbreaking aftermath.It presents it treats with clarity and intelligence that truly makes it a brilliant film.Another good thing about it is the movie avoids the use of too much violence and swearing to present its story.The performances of the cast were great.Special mention must be given to Denzel Washington for he dominates a film with his quiet intensity and aura of introspection.Credit must also be given to Meg Ryan and Matt Damon,who tried his best to look realistic in his role by shedding many pounds to lose a lot of weight. Overall,Courage Under Fire is a movie that a viewer should not miss as it ranks up there with Platoon and Born On The Fourth Of July as outstanding war films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film with a couple of standout performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just for the record, at least here on IMDb, I think this is an underrated film. And I say that as a person who very rarely likes movies about the military. My dad was in the military most of his adult life, and when he would come home on leave he would always drag me to some war film. I hated it. So, I rarely watch a war movie. But this is a keeper. First, the cast. And let me review the actors in the order of how impressive they were in this film. Denzel Washington, as a Lieutenant Colonel investigating whether a dead female captain should receive the Medal Of Honor, and who himself may have been involved in friendly fire deaths, and who has an alcohol problem, is excellent. Lou Diamond Phillips, as a Staff Sergeant who was at the helicopter crash where the female soldier was killed, is superb here (I never knew he was such a hunk...just for the record). Regina Taylor, as the wife of Washington, is excellent! Meg Ryan, the helicopter pilot who dies, is good, but although her role is pivotal, this is not a very good showcase of her talents, and I do not see her here as the co-star to Denzel Washington. I found Matt Damon rather unimpressive here, but of course, this was just before his breakthrough role that immediately followed this film. Bronson Pinchot was an interesting choice as a White House aide, and he does okay. Michael Moriarty is good as a Brigadier General, as is Scott Glenn as a Washington Post reporter. While I can't say whether or not the Iraq battle scenes were realistic, they impressed me. Despite some inconsistencies, I think the story is a good one. And not a simple one, since the issues that Denzel Washington's character has are complicating his investigation of whether or not Ryan's character should receive the Medal Of Honor. Washington does an admirable job of mixing all these factors and fleshing out the character traits of his role. In fact, this was one of Washington's early films which convinced me that he was an actor that America should treasure. Despite a few flaws, highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overly Sentimental and Top Heavy...But Above Average
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a strong Story here as an investigation ensues about a potential Medal of Honor recipient and the mysterious conflict of testimonies. It is given a twist with a shot of estrogen as the Soldier involved is the first Female to possibly (Posthumously) be awarded the Nation's Highest Military Honor. That should be enough to make this a riveting Mystery and through flashbacks we are shown some striking battle Scenes. So why add the conflict and strife to the investigating Officer. It is completely unnecessary and is the weakest part of the Film and almost drags it down with unconvincing situations of Combat guilt and Family Dysfunction. That could be a whole other Movie. But with that bloating aside there are some strong Performances by the young Cast (actually outshining Denzel) in supporting Roles as the Combat Unit in question. There is a back Story to everyone and it holds up quite well with the central Theme. It must be mentioned here that although, Meg Ryan is miscast as the Captain, she tries her best but cannot outgrow her limitations and convince as a tough Girl in a hopeless, self sacrificing situation. Overall, not a bad Movie and is worth a watch for the strong parts, but there is much too much padding here, plus the heavy dose of sentimentality finally drags this down from Great Movie to just above Average.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very, very pretentious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    floyd beck
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry, but I cannot stomach a movie that is pro-military when Meg Ryan, a devout Democrat and worshiper of John Kerry, the war-hater and devout liar, and Denzel Washington, a worshiper of President Obama and a devout Democrat who is said to be a devout Christian. One cannot be both...in 2011, the Democrats voted NO to have God inserted in their convention, in spite of the chairman's blatant lie; just one of 100 reasons. So, after my ranting, what about the movie? It is too hard to believe any of it because the actors are not sincere in true life. It would be like having an openly gay person portray Rudolph Valentino unless the movie was a comedy. Courage Under Fire does not pass as a comedy unless one forces one's mind to the point of insanity to see liberal war-hating actors and actresses pretend to be pro-military.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gutless Under Clich&eacute;
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dunmore_ego
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, I know it's trying to be inspiring and heroic and poignant, but COURAGE UNDER FIRE is one of the most blatantly gutless movies ever made. About a soldier investigating whether a downed female United States helicopter pilot in Desert Storm deserves a posthumous Medal of Honor. So I ask you: in which universe will America ever make a movie where a Medal of Honor is investigated and NOT awarded? So it's a foregone conclusion--all the mystery and mayhem and maybes are simply wasting our time more than the actual war this story was set in--as it leads inexorably to the melodramatic military funeral, the flags, saluting, tears of the family, proud shiny buttons and white gloves, the flyover with one plane breaking formation, and that bilious, bleating orchestra swell. And the Medal. The End. Cry me a river; cry me a patently meaningless award, military swine. Then the coda: the investigating soldier visits pilot's grave, salutes grave, tiny flag, voice-over of dead pilot to American Pie Mom and Dad, talking of the Big Push and hero hero hero hero hero hero another blithering orchestra swell I'm going to vomit... Denzel Washington is the investigating soldier, with demons of his own. (Well, they're not really demons; they're roiling stabs of conscience he feels for stupidly shooting one of his own tanks during a skirmish, killing his own men in the hilariously black euphemism "friendly fire," and then having the military cover-up his blunder.) And whenever he has visions of that po' boy he fricasseed in that tank (Mmm! Soldierboy, the other white meat!), he heads straight for the alcohol... uh, cos he's a hero, see. When he's asked to investigate whether Captain Karen Walden (Meg Ryan) is worthy of receiving the Medal of Honor for "courage under fire," the story ends right there. Of course she's deserving of it. She's the first female officer recommended, she's regarded as a hero for sacrificing her life for her men--and she's Meg Ryan. As if the movie would go to all the trouble setting up her heroism and feminism and Ryanism and NOT award her the medal. And every clich&eacute; in the military lexicon is thrown at us like grenades lobbed into foxholes: the tragic family; damaged goods investigating damaged goods; the novice (Matt Damon), the toughguy (Lou Diamond Phillips), the hero-worshipper (Tim Guinee) and all the other bumboys like the Benetton passengers of SPEED; the hospitalized guy (Seth Gilliam) whose seen one battle too many; the military cover-up. And everyone's got Movie PTSD. Denzel wants to find out "what really happened," so COURAGE is constructed like a RASHOMON for rednecks, as we see all the alternate flashbacks with a coy Walden, an indecisive Walden and a butch Walden barking orders and trying not to look like a sex object. Not one of the scenarios is ambiguous about her Hero status--no matter if she threw Iraqi babies at walls or defunded the G.I. Bill. If we can call football players heroes, and people who jumped from the Twin Towers heroes, then this chopper pilot must be a shoo-in, so I ask again: what compels viewers to spend 120 minutes *pretending* there's any doubt? Denzel visits Walden's helicopter bumboys, who all give differing accounts of My Night In The Desert With Captain Walden. Diamond Phillips claims he was the toughguy, as he lies and plies himself with alcohol and commits suicide (cos he's a hero!); Damon claims Walden was a strategic hardnose, as he admits to being a junkie and afraid to go flying again (cos he's a hero!); Guinee relates how Walden sacrificed herself for them, even as he reveals how she got them shot down by taking another pass at an Iraqi tank when she could have flown away--cognitive dissonance rules!--while constantly telling his wife to shutup for calling Walden butch (cos he's a hero!); while Seth Gilliam pounds his medication to numb himself out of the running as a reputable eyewitness (cos he's a hero, see!). What's in it for her bumboys to report that she was a coward? Nothing. But saying she was a HERO makes them vicarious heroes alongside her. Ooo-rah! And here's a note to all you military wardogs whose first reaction is to Spock-chop me for "disrespecting" you (such heroes, fighting for peace!): When are you going to realize your own government, who pays you hypocritical lip service, regards you with even less respect than I do? I just consider you deluded and egotistical and sometimes uneducated, while they consider you cannon fodder! It's the United States government that fools you into getting your asses shot off for them in the first place; it's the United States government that refuses you and your family financial benefits when you return from war; it's the United States government that stop-losses you, reneging on your stipulated leave time, over and over and over again; it's the United States government that cuts your medical funding; it's the United States government that evicts your family, that lies about friendly fire, that doesn't provide armor for you or your vehicles; it's the United States government that kicks you out for being gay after you've dedicated your life to them; it's the United States government that supposedly trains you for PTSD and then all of you return from war with PTSD (Who are the a-holes? You, who are either failing your training, or the government who are failing to train you properly?). Is that what you bitches call "respect"? Under fire from your own government, it's about time you showed some real Courage Under Fire and tell them where to shove it next time they want to exploit you for political gain. That is, unless you really are as dumb as they consider you to be. Ooo-rah! --Poffy The Cucumber
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible Meg Ryan's Performance.Like Cpt. Walden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For people who just want to see Meg in the roles of this sugar romantic- goofy coms I guess that people were lobotomized by an actress and tarnish her, when she runs away from its stereotype and I'm outraged that they can not see versatility and potential Meg Ryan's polivalency.I just see the reviews, pure flattery these crappy actresses nowadays. Ask for Julia Roberts or Angelina Jolie Already piloted an US army chopper in a role? If Michelle Pffeifer or Goldie Hawn(Private Benjamin) played a role very perfectly and naturally of a single mother and determined who dipped the face on the war, and is required in command and demonstrates tight grip and mastery with weapons? without disparaging the Denzel Washignton, which signal, shone like Nathany when reports for soldiers a Karen Walden's deservering Medal of Honor, after Her death by Naphalms, but the episodes of drunkenness became a look dull and weak. Matt Damon,was terrific, skillfully retraced all the facts of 1991's Gulf War. Lou Diamond-Phillips was excellent as paper rebel, rough and impressive and opposite Cpt. Walden. whole more Credits goes to Meg Ryan & Lou D.Phillips, sure as Denzel is a Core person in this movie.Whatever, everybody stunned theirs performance ,But Meg Ryan razed ,and much. Meg Ryan deserves an Oscar. yet, once in her life gone to win.. If God willing.. She's Powerful and more Capable than Demi-Moore, Sharon Stone,and other contemporanies 90'ties Actresses,but Meg is overrated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    go night train, go
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jack-964
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen this movie many years ago and remember i wasn't impressed by it. This was the movie that sunk Meg Ryan for me. I just saw it again and no, it's not worth remembering: I think its starts being lame with the story itself. Why on earth does it have to be a woman? If they wouldn't have put a woman in the center and obviously even worse, cast totally wrong, then the story could actually be interesting, elaborating on different views on the same event. But no, someone decided it had to be 'emancipated', then cast wrong, then pile up a load of unbelievable facts (like downing a tank with a fuel barrel from a helicopter under fire, yea right...) Also unbelievable is the fact that one guy can't stand the truth, even though he had no part in what happened, since he was injured. The other goes on drugs, even though he had no time to think about, let alone react to the lie the third one says. Which commits suicide all of a sudden, when urged to tell the truth, even though his life is going pretty well. And all this is investigated by someone that unknowingly killed a friend in combat, under fire, bla bla. The guy has a wife, kids, great job, status, money, house, and so on, but he can't cope with this accident? It's not all bad. You probably won't fall asleep, but when you find yourself rooting for the alleged bad guy, you know something is very wrong. Go night train go!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie helps heals me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sammy Young
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care about the petty "goofs" or parts of the story that other people point out- this movie means a lot to me as a disabled veteran with PTSD. This movie is about many things, but to me, the story is about how Col Sterling is trying to manage his survivor guilt and PTSD from his incident on one hand, and deal with his task to validate the medal for his General, his wife, his kids, etc. on the other. He resorts to booze (like we all do) to try to cope. That's what this movie is really about: how one guy is trying to come to grips with PTSD, which I can tell you first-hand is a challenge that I face every minute of everyday. And seeing this movie helps heal me. It reminds me that I too lost a promising career in the Navy, lost my marriage, lost my kids, and lost myself in the abyss of PTSD and alcoholism before I got help. That's the only negative I have on this movie- we don't see if Col Sterling got help. Otherwise, this movie has helped heal me in ways that no other movie I've ever seen has.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Prismatic Gulf War drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A strong contemporary war drama examining issues of loyalty, protocol, duty and ultimately truth in an unusually constructed film within a film, at the same using multiple viewpoints ( a la "Rashomon" or "Accident") to unfold the complicated truth at its heart. I'm not sure the somewhat contrived structure served the serious subject matter wholly convincingly, the cinematic devices detracting somewhat from the otherwise lifelike depiction of action in the Gulf War. I also thought Denzel Washington's framing role as the senior army officer given the seemingly straightforward task of reporting on the apparently automatic eligibility of Meg Ryan's posthumous award of the Army medal of honour detracted from the central mystery, especially as he wrestles with his own demons after unwittingly being involved in a tragic friendly-fire incident of his own. So Denz fights the bottle and walks out on his family, before uncovering the truth about Ryan's death and the way back to his own redemption. This final resolution and the underlying implication that the US Army welcomes openness is firstly too pat and improbable, especially in the wake of some real-life events that have come to light since then. All that said, the dramatisation of the war is very well realised and the acting is of a high order, Washington giving it strong and silent in a commanding lead role, but there are even better performances from a young Matt Damon and Lou Diamond-Phillips as two of Ryan's crew who survive the ordeal physically but not mentally. Ryan does well too and I was also impressed by the actress in the menial task of playing Washington's wife. Yes, the film ends up as you'd expect, replete with Washington's last respectful visit to Ryan's grave, but there was enough intrigue and grit in the tale to keep me watching throughout. A braver take on the story, inverting some of the discovered truths here might have made for a better film though, but of course there's no way that viewpoint would have been green-lighted in Hollywood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A resounding "meh"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Do you ever watch those movies that just elicit no reaction from you? I'm talking about the kind of movies that are just so straightforward and so flat that they draw out zero emotions in you and your opinion of the movie elevates to nothing above indifference. For me, this was the case with Courage Under Fire. It stars Denzel Washington as Col. Nat Serling, an army colonel investigating the legitimacy of a post humous Medal of Honor award going to Karen Warden, an army officer who was said to have died heroically while fighting the Iraqis during the Gulf War. However, there are too many discrepancies so Serling is enlisted to find out the truth about what happened to Warden the day her and her platoon went down in their chopper. The film is told through flashbacks which recount the events from different points of views. It's a Rashomon type of story in the way that the events are slightly altered depending on who is recounting them. It's a clever plot device, but not clever or interesting enough to make Courage Under Fire a great film. Don't get me wrong, it's decent. The story isn't something you will see every day and I have to give props to any film that utilizes a more unique narrative style. Akira Kurosawa's Rashomon started this style of the unreliable narrator in film, and it's films like Courage Under Fire that keep the style alive. The problem is that the film doesn't do anything particularly interesting with this narrative style. It plays out how you would expect it to and the actual structure of the film is pretty redundant as well. From start to finish it is essentially Denzel Washington going from place to place, interviewing people about the events that ended Warden's life until he finally gets the truth. There's no real feeling in this film and it lacks any kind of atmosphere or visual nuance. The story presented is engaging to an extent, but there's nothing else to really grab your attention. The bottom line behind Courage Under Fire is it is just a forgettable film. Nothing exists within this film that makes me want to tell people about it, or think about it down the line, or rewatch it ever again. It does things right and it isn't by any means a disaster, but due to its lack of feeling, dull atmosphere, and monotonous plot it just isn't what I would call a fantastic film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film About The 1991 Gulf War
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Courage Under Fire is a film about the 1991 Gulf War.It stars Denzel Washington,Meg Ryan,Lou Diamond Phillips and Matt Damon. It is one of the first great films to depict the 1991 Gulf War as it tells a story of a US Army officer, despondent about a deadly mistake he made, investigates a female chopper commander's worthiness for the Medal of Honor.The movie was directed by Edward Zwick. Courage Under Fire has Lieutenant Colonel Nathaniel Serling involved in a friendly fire incident in Al Bathra during the Gulf War. He was an M1 Abrams tank battalion commander who, during the nighttime confusion of Iraqi tanks infiltrating his unit's lines, gave the order to fire, destroying one of his own tanks and killing his friend Lieutenant Boylar. The details were covered up and Serling was reassigned to a desk job.Later, he is assigned to determine if Army Captain Karen Emma Walden should be the first woman to receive the Medal of Honor for valor in combat in the Gulf War posthumously. A Medevac Huey commander, she was sent to rescue the crew of a helicopter that had been shot down. Finding them under heavy fire from an Iraqi tank and infantry, she had her men drop an auxiliary fuel tank on the tank and ignited it with a flare gun. Shortly after, her helicopter was also hit and downed. The two crews were unable to join forces. The survivors were rescued the next day, but Walden had been killed in action.At first, everything seems to be straightforward, but Serling begins to notice inconsistencies between the testimonies of the witnesses. Walden's co-pilot, Warrant Officer One Rady, praises Walden's character and performance, but was hit and unconscious early on. Serling then sees Walden's medic, Specialist Ilario, who also praises Walden. Staff Sergeant Monfriez, however, tells Serling that Walden was a coward. The members of the other downed crew also mention that they heard the distinctive sound of an M16 being used in the firefight during the rescue around the other helicopter, but Walden's crew denies firing one during the rescue, as theirs was out of ammunition. When Serling visits Walden's crew chief, Sergeant Altameyer, who is dying of cancer in a hospital. Altameyer manages to get some words out, further confusing Serling, before self-medicating himself into unconsciousness.Under pressure from the White House and his commander, Brigadier General Hershberg, to wrap things up quickly, Serling leaks the story to newspaper reporter Tony Gartner to prevent another cover up. When Serling puts pressure on Monfriez, the man pulls a pistol at him, then commits suicide by driving his car into an oncoming train.After finding Ilario, Serling discovers that Monfriez wanted to escape under cover of darkness, which would have meant leaving Rady behind. Altameyer was ready to follow his lead and Ilario was wavering, but Walden refused to go along, resulting in an armed standoff with Monfriez. When an Iraqi infantryman appeared suddenly behind Monfriez, Walden fired at him. Mistakenly believing he was the target, Monfriez shot back and seriously wounded her. Walden, however, regained control of her men.The next morning, Walden stayed behind to cover their evacuation, firing the M16. Monfriez deliberately lied to the rescuers, telling them that she was dead so she would be left behind. Altameyer, injured and unable to say anything was ignored. Ilario remained silent. A-10 airplanes then napalmed the wreckage.Serling presents his final report to Hershberg. Walden's young daughter receives the Medal of Honor in a White House ceremony. Later, Serling tearfully tells the Boylars the truth about the manner of their son's death. In the last moments of the film, it is shown that Walden had transported Boylar's body away from the battlefield. Courage Under Fire is definitely one outstanding film about the Gulf War.It tells an emotional and intriguing tale of a military officer who must review the merits of a fallen officer while confronting his own war demons that makes us feel for every character involved in the story.Also,the movie tells effectively the terrors brought about by war as well as its heartbreaking aftermath.It presents it treats with clarity and intelligence that truly makes it a brilliant film.Another good thing about it is the movie avoids the use of too much violence and swearing to present its story.The performances of the cast were great.Special mention must be given to Denzel Washington for he dominates a film with his quiet intensity and aura of introspection.Credit must also be given to Meg Ryan and Matt Damon,who tried his best to look realistic in his role by shedding many pounds to lose a lot of weight. Overall,Courage Under Fire is a movie that a viewer should not miss as it ranks up there with Platoon and Born On The Fourth Of July as outstanding war films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
