<filme>
 <id>
  472
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116136
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Cora&ccedil;&atilde;o de Drag&atilde;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The last dragon and a disillusioned dragonslaying knight must cooperate to stop an evil king who was given partial immortality.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The young, sickly King Einon was wounded in a battle. In order for him to survive, he is healed by Draco, a dragon. Some years later, Bowen, a dragon slayer, encounters Draco. The two team up to form a traveling duo that perform an act, but the act is only known by themselves. Bowen supposedly "slays" Draco and then collects a reward from the town or village that he protects by killing the dragon who had been "terrorizing" them. From there, Bowen and Draco must save the entire kingdom from the rule of the now evil King Einon, who is part of Draco and Draco a part of him.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   dragon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   king
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   evil king
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   battle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   immortality
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Rob Cohen
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Patrick Read Johnson
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Charles Edward Pogue
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dennis Quaid
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sean Connery
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dina Meyer
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the best fantasy movie, but okay nonetheless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the very few fantasy films that hit the screen and even then it is not as high as a movie like Willow is (though I should point out that I originally wrote this review in 1996). In fact, it is quite a low fantasy movie with the exception of the dragon, which creates some of the high fantasy in this movie. Straight out, it is an enjoyable movie to watch, but it goes little beyond that. A knight is training a prince in the art of honour and chivalry, but the prince has better ideas. When he sees his father wounded severely in a peasant uprising, he does not help him, but rather rips the crown from his hand. It is this event that shows us that the prince is, in his heart, evil. Unfortunately, when his is wounded, he is taken to a Dragon for help. The dragon gives him half of his heart and the boy survives. Unfortunately, all pain that the prince (now King) feels is felt by the dragon. The king does not change his ways, and the knight thus blames the dragon. The movie hasn't got a straight plot, but it isn't twisted either. What it focuses on is the knight, who first seeks to kill the dragon, then befriends him, and then decides to destroy the king's power, only to become king himself. The movie does have a tragic feel to it, as we soon come to know that the dragon is going to die because of his compassion, but it is not the tragedy where we can see the character constantly degrade to a point where he will die. In fact, even though we know he is going to die, it is not because of his actions, but because of the actions of the antagonist, and though we see a minor flag that an act of compassion at the beginning will lead to his downfall, we do not know enough to want to warn him away from doing it. The theology in the movie is quite dodgy as well. Though human theology is not looked at, dragon theology is. The way the dragon reaches heaven is my doing noteworthy and honourable deeds. Unfortunately, if those deeds backfire then the dragon is in big trouble. As such there is no certainty and as such we can be as good as we like, but never be guaranteed because our acts of goodness might backfire. What Christ offers is assurance. There is no being good because no amount of good deeds can get us on the right side of God. In fact by doing pure good deeds we are saying that we are not happy with the way God does things and want to do it ourselves, and thus offending God. As such it is a vicious circle for we attempt to be good, but by being good we are being offensive, which is bad. As such being good does not work, but rather by trusting what God has already done. By dying he has given us the option of accepting that our goodness will never be good enough and thus take Jesus' goodness for ourselves, and his resurrection tells us that he had the authority to do it. As for the movie, it is okay, and pleasant to watch as a fantasy movie, but beyond that it is really not all that much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can someone say... GENIUS?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Miller (miller.jmiller.jason@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie that sins it? Literally, nothing. The acting is great, the storyline is phenomenal, the humor thrives, and the special effects do not disappoint. The storyline portrays a young Prince with a tyrannic father, who dies. The boy is injured to near death, and a dragon gives half his heart to the boy. The boy himself becomes a tyrant. A knight vows to kill all dragons until he kills the one who gave the heart. But, not all is what it seems... This is definitely a movie for those whom enjoy a good, hearty film with a moral at its center. It is even a good family film, depending on your parenting methods (which one should hope are decent and logical). If you need a movie to kick back and relax to, watch on a snowy or rainy day, or just because, this is a great movie. The storyline lacks no potential; utilizing all elements and keeping the audience's attention. The chosen actors for the characters was ingenious and well planned. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. I promise, if you approach this movie with a joyous attitude, or even a skeptical one, you will enjoy it. ~~Go forth and review movies~~
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood style medieval adventure fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hduck1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sickeningly mawkish story. Typical Hollywood. Clownish and idiotic dialog. An attempt to interject humor in an otherwise adventurous tale. Compare this production to the British series, Merlin. The latter had better dialog, better storyline, equally good special effects. The only drawbacks I found in Merlin were with regard to casting, but Colin Morgan made an ideal young Merlin for me. John Hurt's voice made a more believable dragon than Sean Connery's voice. These fantasies are fun to watch when they are well made. However, I am always aware that the dragon is the biblical symbol of Satan. Therefore to make a noble beast of the creature is mockery of the Bible. "Merlin" did not exactly make the dragon a good creature - without the control of a "dragonlord" it became entirely destructive. It seems ironic to make any kind of pact with a dragon; it is literally making a pact with the devil. But as I say, the fantasy is fun when well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great dragon flick with a good charm to it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, how I love Dragonheart. This was made during the dawn of CGI. After Terminator 2 and Jurassic Park pushed the boundaries of special effects to a whole new level, Universal decided to try something different with computer effects and storytelling. The result was this lovable film that has, dare I say it, a burning passion. The story of a dragon (Sean Connery) and a dragon slayer (Dennis Quaid) becoming friends and teaming up against a tyrannical king is unforgettable. This movie is just full of comedy, action, and drama and the cast, especially Sean Connery, deliver terrific performances. It's not often you see a dragon movie like this and with that, it should be commended. I give this movie a 7 for entertainment value and a fiery extra point for the effort in which this was made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Talking Dragon Makes This Movie Corny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    airwolf-121-720419
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I did enjoy this movie for what it is, I would have to say that this movie was corny. Corny because we have a friendly talking dragon voiced by Sean Connery. Plus, the acting of the evil boy king was just really cheesy in my opinion. Aren't dragons supposed to be mythical creatures we are supposed to fear? If so, then why are they portrayed as a cuddle bear we can share our most inner thoughts while other movies portray dragons as something to fear? The only reason why I am giving this movie a 3 is that Dennis Quaid is in this movie. While I also like Connery, his part just didn't sit well with me. So even the actors couldn't revive this very corny movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable with a sense of humour added in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like fantasy films and especially the ones set in medi evil times with dragons and sword fights and beautiful landscapes etc. That isn't to say all the ones that have these are necessarily good films but it is a world we can only imagine. Dragonheart starts off a little slow, but still interesting that sets up the plot of the film. Luckily it starts getting really enjoyable when the Dragon comes into it who becomes an ally of Bowen (Dennis Quaid) who is out to settle a personal vendetta against a Dragon who has turned a student of his into a corrupt ruler in his role as King Einon (David Thewlis in a very convincing role as an arrogant ruler). What makes this film appealing is the fact that the Dragon named Draco (voiced by Sean Connery) is given a lot of personality and hence is able to bond with Bowen. It adds a lot to the sense of humour and the film doesn't become too dark or a film that is based purely on revenge themes. The visual effects were also decent and for what this film is worth, it feels like a B grade film but looks like an A Grade film with the good performances, decent visuals and good cinematography of the landscapes. The production design is pretty impressive too. It still has flaws. The action scenes needed better music score to make it a bit more exciting and dramatic and the story itself is a bit clich&eacute; in some respects. Julie Christie doesn't have much to do in her role which is a shame considering she had a good presence in the beginning then was sort of here now and then later on. Dennis Quaid is convincing as a boorish Dragon Slayer earning a living as a slayer and is a likable character. What is also good is that there is no silly romantic subplot which I suspected would have been thrown in which would have made the plot even more clich&eacute; but it avoided that even though I thought there were going to be hints at it. So I was surprised to find myself enjoying this. Sometimes films like these that you can just watch and just have a good time are what you need when you don't want to think too much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece of Fantasy Storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omega
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dennis Quaid is Knight of the Old Code Bowen, a strong and grand hearted man that in hope of saving his fatally wounded pupil and future king Einon, takes him to the lair of a Dragon that, in the hope of making him a true king, unlike his father, gives him the life again by taking a part of his heart and putting it into him. Bowen, upon this action of benevolence, promises the Dragon his services, as the creature himself remembers him that Einon must stay true to his promise of being a good Ruler. As years pass, Einon reveals himself to be an even worse King than his father was, treating his reign like the worst kind of Tyrant would. Bowen, believing that the Dragon was the cause, declares vengeance on all Dragons, only to come at the situation that only one remained (precisely the one that gave half of his heart to Einon ). The two make an improbable alliance that would bring an advantage to both. DragonHeart has always been one of those memorable films that just never fail to amaze, with the feelings they are able to transmit to the viewer. One moment you laugh, the next you are broken in tears. Few films are able to do this to the viewer - And DragonHeart strikes as excellent in this. The film features a strong cast that pulls out exceptionally good performances - Dennis Quaid is of course a strong actor and highlights very well the nature of his character. One of the turning points of the film is the delusion of Bowen, that has lived all his life on his ideals, and training his pupil, is forced to see him exactly, or more like, worse than the last king, his father, was. Dina Meyer represents perfectly the brave, rebel woman Kara is. The most memorable human character though is without a doubt Brother Gilbert, played by the late Pete Postlethwaite (may he rest in peace), the comic relief of the film that never ceases to bring a smile. Sean Connery is the voice for the Dragon, Draco, who is at turn created through the use of Computer Graphics by the artists of Industrial Light & Magic, known for their work on films such as Jurassic Park, who never cease to do their job none less than amazing, as Draco still holds up very well today. Connery's voice perfectly fits the character and makes it even more memorable. Draco is a noble hearted, gentle figure and the best character of the film. His death is one of those moments in a film that you quite never forget, for its strength in presentation, tear shredding score and incredibly sad yet heart warming combination of image and words. DragonHeart is truly a beautiful, old school fantasy Masterpiece and deserves a lot of praising for what it is, and the humanitary message it represents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than those overrated 'The Lord of the Rings' films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Dragonheart' is strangely underrated. Considering the unbelievable popularity of 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy (even today), we could ask ourselves why 'Dragonheart' didn't reach half of that fame. However, being underrated has a good side, as most underrated and less known films are far superior than the eternally popular and overrated ones. 'Dragonheart' is an okay movie, worthy for dragon lovers. I am a dragon lover myself. Dragons fascinate me. They're such huge, fantastic and beautiful beasts. I wish dragons existed in real life. Draco the dragon is, without a doubt, the only really likable character in the movie. I don't care much about the others. The dragon is what makes this movie good enough. Without him, the movie would be nothing. The dragon is voiced by perhaps the most popular "James Bond" ever: Sean Connery. Bowen, the character portrayed by Dennis Quaid, is a good guy but undeniably arrogant and much self-proud and at the same time he's a bad guy for one reason: he kills all dragons because he believes that all dragons are evil. He wanted to kill Draco as well, but ends up forming a partnership and friendship with him and later realizes he's not evil. Draco was always a good dragon. He only killed those who wanted to harm him, in self-defense. What he didn't know was that giving half of his heart to Einon would be a terrible mistake. Einon falsely promised to be good and to follow the "old code" but in no time he showed what he really is: a brutal tyrant who only pretended to be Bowen's friend so that he could learn how to use the sword. The sad thing is that, in order to kill the bad guy, the dragon has to die as well. This happens because, as they share the same heart, they feel the same pains and all. Realizing this, the dragon doesn't just beg to be killed, he demands. Bowen doesn't have courage to do it at first and you can't blame him for that. That is a horrible thing to do. I'd like to know if there wasn't any other solution. You know, like, maybe the dragon could have found a way to recover the half of his heart that he gave to the villain. That way they wouldn't share the same pain and the evil guy could have been killed without the dragon having to die with him. Much of the filming occurred in the ancient ruins of Spi Castle, Slovakia. The result is beautiful sceneries and landscapes, perfect for an epic film. The action is set somewhere in the late 10th century in England, after the Saxons's conquest of that country. The dragon might have been created by computer, but he looks great and very real - so different from CGI "art". This level of perfection is comparable to the dinosaurs of 'Jurassic Park'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven but decent enough fantasy adventure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dragonheart is set during 948 A.D. & starts as a peasant uprising is defeated by evil King Freyne (Peter Hric) & his troops, in a show a strength King Freyne rides into their village to set it alight but it was a trap & King Freyne is killed in front of his teenage son Einon (Lee Oakes) who himself is badly injured. Einon's mother takes her son to a Dragon as a last resort in order to save his life, the Dragon gives Einon half of his own heart which saves the boy's life. Twelve years later & Einon (David Thewlis) has grown up to be just as much an evil tyrant as his father was who rules with brutality, his former friend, teacher & knight of the old order Bowen (Dennis Quaid) has turned Dragonslayer since he blames the Dragon's heart for polluting Einon & making him evil but decides to team up with a friendly Dragon he names Draco as well as feisty young woman Kara (Dina Meyer) who together lead a revolt against Einon, his troops & all he stands for... Directed by Rob Cohen this fantasy adventure is one of the few mainstream films featuring a Dragon & while it's nothing amazing I didn't think it was too bad overall. Dragon films are thin on the ground to be honest, there's Dragonslayer (1981), Dragonworld (1994) prior to Dragonheart with Dungeons & Dragons (2000), Reign of Fire (2002) & Eargon (2007) afterwards & none of the films mentioned have been that good or done that well at the box-office. The script feels a bit uneven, while on the one hand you have this whimsical child like fantasy of a friendly talking Dragon there's the other side of the film with a peasant uprising which does get quite violent with necks being broken, people being stabbed, set on fire & one bloke is hit in the nuts with a huge battle axe (ouch) & the two distinctly different tones didn't sit together that well for me. Basically the violence is a little too strong for younger children while the silly talking friendly Dragon is a little childish for anyone over the age of ten. That's not to say Dragonheart isn't an enjoyable film for what it is because it is, it moves along at a decent enough pace, the mismatched partners Bowen & Draco surely have one of the bizarrest on screen buddy buddy relationships ever & it entertains but I didn't think the violence & childish fantasy sat well together & it's a little repetitive & predictable with an ending that goes on for too long, sure the Dragon dies but have an extended scene set to orchestral music with various star shining in the sky is just a bit too much. Dragonheart was made early in the days of CGI computer effects & you can see a lot of time & effort went into them & they hold up really well even now. The battle scenes & fights are good if a little predictable (the good guy always wins & the bad guy gets it) & as a period piece the costumes, sets & props all look the part. Draco the Dragon voiced by Sean Connery looks great, he moves convincingly, flies convincingly & definitely has a personality. In fact Dragonheart was nominated for a Best Visual Effects Oscar along with Twister (1996) but both deservedly lost out to Independence Day (1996). With a supposed budget of about $57,000,000 this had a lot of money spent on it & I would have though most of it was spent on the CGI effects, filmed on location in Slovakia. The acting is OK but nothing special, Pete Postlethwaite doesn't get much to do, Dennis Quid is somewhat bland, it's nice to see Brian Thompson in a Hollywood film while Sir John Gielgud has a voice cameo as King Arthur. Dragonheart is a solid enough fantasy adventure that may be too violent for youngsters while a bit too childish for adults, I thought it was good but nothing amazing overall. Followed by the straight to video sequel Dragonheart: A New Beginning (2000).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sean Connery as a Dragon. :)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this movie is fairly old but I really only just heard of it recently and seen it. I normally don't like dragon movies but I really did enjoy this one. My opinion there's just not that many good dragon movies out there. Which is kind of sad since I do love dragons and medieval times as a whole. This movie is kind of slow but I've found it's good to have patience. I found the acting wasn't half bad and the plot was fairly decent. Plus I think this movie had one of the first CGI dragons and I actually thought they didn't do too bad a job. I'd recommend it and say give it a chance. Seems to be a family friendly movie for the most part. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the best fantasy movie, but okay nonetheless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the very few fantasy films that hit the screen and even then it is not as high as a movie like Willow is (though I should point out that I originally wrote this review in 1996). In fact, it is quite a low fantasy movie with the exception of the dragon, which creates some of the high fantasy in this movie. Straight out, it is an enjoyable movie to watch, but it goes little beyond that. A knight is training a prince in the art of honour and chivalry, but the prince has better ideas. When he sees his father wounded severely in a peasant uprising, he does not help him, but rather rips the crown from his hand. It is this event that shows us that the prince is, in his heart, evil. Unfortunately, when his is wounded, he is taken to a Dragon for help. The dragon gives him half of his heart and the boy survives. Unfortunately, all pain that the prince (now King) feels is felt by the dragon. The king does not change his ways, and the knight thus blames the dragon. The movie hasn't got a straight plot, but it isn't twisted either. What it focuses on is the knight, who first seeks to kill the dragon, then befriends him, and then decides to destroy the king's power, only to become king himself. The movie does have a tragic feel to it, as we soon come to know that the dragon is going to die because of his compassion, but it is not the tragedy where we can see the character constantly degrade to a point where he will die. In fact, even though we know he is going to die, it is not because of his actions, but because of the actions of the antagonist, and though we see a minor flag that an act of compassion at the beginning will lead to his downfall, we do not know enough to want to warn him away from doing it. The theology in the movie is quite dodgy as well. Though human theology is not looked at, dragon theology is. The way the dragon reaches heaven is my doing noteworthy and honourable deeds. Unfortunately, if those deeds backfire then the dragon is in big trouble. As such there is no certainty and as such we can be as good as we like, but never be guaranteed because our acts of goodness might backfire. What Christ offers is assurance. There is no being good because no amount of good deeds can get us on the right side of God. In fact by doing pure good deeds we are saying that we are not happy with the way God does things and want to do it ourselves, and thus offending God. As such it is a vicious circle for we attempt to be good, but by being good we are being offensive, which is bad. As such being good does not work, but rather by trusting what God has already done. By dying he has given us the option of accepting that our goodness will never be good enough and thus take Jesus' goodness for ourselves, and his resurrection tells us that he had the authority to do it. As for the movie, it is okay, and pleasant to watch as a fantasy movie, but beyond that it is really not all that much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can someone say... GENIUS?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Miller (miller.jmiller.jason@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie that sins it? Literally, nothing. The acting is great, the storyline is phenomenal, the humor thrives, and the special effects do not disappoint. The storyline portrays a young Prince with a tyrannic father, who dies. The boy is injured to near death, and a dragon gives half his heart to the boy. The boy himself becomes a tyrant. A knight vows to kill all dragons until he kills the one who gave the heart. But, not all is what it seems... This is definitely a movie for those whom enjoy a good, hearty film with a moral at its center. It is even a good family film, depending on your parenting methods (which one should hope are decent and logical). If you need a movie to kick back and relax to, watch on a snowy or rainy day, or just because, this is a great movie. The storyline lacks no potential; utilizing all elements and keeping the audience's attention. The chosen actors for the characters was ingenious and well planned. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. I promise, if you approach this movie with a joyous attitude, or even a skeptical one, you will enjoy it. ~~Go forth and review movies~~
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood style medieval adventure fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hduck1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sickeningly mawkish story. Typical Hollywood. Clownish and idiotic dialog. An attempt to interject humor in an otherwise adventurous tale. Compare this production to the British series, Merlin. The latter had better dialog, better storyline, equally good special effects. The only drawbacks I found in Merlin were with regard to casting, but Colin Morgan made an ideal young Merlin for me. John Hurt's voice made a more believable dragon than Sean Connery's voice. These fantasies are fun to watch when they are well made. However, I am always aware that the dragon is the biblical symbol of Satan. Therefore to make a noble beast of the creature is mockery of the Bible. "Merlin" did not exactly make the dragon a good creature - without the control of a "dragonlord" it became entirely destructive. It seems ironic to make any kind of pact with a dragon; it is literally making a pact with the devil. But as I say, the fantasy is fun when well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great dragon flick with a good charm to it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, how I love Dragonheart. This was made during the dawn of CGI. After Terminator 2 and Jurassic Park pushed the boundaries of special effects to a whole new level, Universal decided to try something different with computer effects and storytelling. The result was this lovable film that has, dare I say it, a burning passion. The story of a dragon (Sean Connery) and a dragon slayer (Dennis Quaid) becoming friends and teaming up against a tyrannical king is unforgettable. This movie is just full of comedy, action, and drama and the cast, especially Sean Connery, deliver terrific performances. It's not often you see a dragon movie like this and with that, it should be commended. I give this movie a 7 for entertainment value and a fiery extra point for the effort in which this was made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Talking Dragon Makes This Movie Corny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    airwolf-121-720419
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I did enjoy this movie for what it is, I would have to say that this movie was corny. Corny because we have a friendly talking dragon voiced by Sean Connery. Plus, the acting of the evil boy king was just really cheesy in my opinion. Aren't dragons supposed to be mythical creatures we are supposed to fear? If so, then why are they portrayed as a cuddle bear we can share our most inner thoughts while other movies portray dragons as something to fear? The only reason why I am giving this movie a 3 is that Dennis Quaid is in this movie. While I also like Connery, his part just didn't sit well with me. So even the actors couldn't revive this very corny movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable with a sense of humour added in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like fantasy films and especially the ones set in medi evil times with dragons and sword fights and beautiful landscapes etc. That isn't to say all the ones that have these are necessarily good films but it is a world we can only imagine. Dragonheart starts off a little slow, but still interesting that sets up the plot of the film. Luckily it starts getting really enjoyable when the Dragon comes into it who becomes an ally of Bowen (Dennis Quaid) who is out to settle a personal vendetta against a Dragon who has turned a student of his into a corrupt ruler in his role as King Einon (David Thewlis in a very convincing role as an arrogant ruler). What makes this film appealing is the fact that the Dragon named Draco (voiced by Sean Connery) is given a lot of personality and hence is able to bond with Bowen. It adds a lot to the sense of humour and the film doesn't become too dark or a film that is based purely on revenge themes. The visual effects were also decent and for what this film is worth, it feels like a B grade film but looks like an A Grade film with the good performances, decent visuals and good cinematography of the landscapes. The production design is pretty impressive too. It still has flaws. The action scenes needed better music score to make it a bit more exciting and dramatic and the story itself is a bit clich&eacute; in some respects. Julie Christie doesn't have much to do in her role which is a shame considering she had a good presence in the beginning then was sort of here now and then later on. Dennis Quaid is convincing as a boorish Dragon Slayer earning a living as a slayer and is a likable character. What is also good is that there is no silly romantic subplot which I suspected would have been thrown in which would have made the plot even more clich&eacute; but it avoided that even though I thought there were going to be hints at it. So I was surprised to find myself enjoying this. Sometimes films like these that you can just watch and just have a good time are what you need when you don't want to think too much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece of Fantasy Storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omega
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dennis Quaid is Knight of the Old Code Bowen, a strong and grand hearted man that in hope of saving his fatally wounded pupil and future king Einon, takes him to the lair of a Dragon that, in the hope of making him a true king, unlike his father, gives him the life again by taking a part of his heart and putting it into him. Bowen, upon this action of benevolence, promises the Dragon his services, as the creature himself remembers him that Einon must stay true to his promise of being a good Ruler. As years pass, Einon reveals himself to be an even worse King than his father was, treating his reign like the worst kind of Tyrant would. Bowen, believing that the Dragon was the cause, declares vengeance on all Dragons, only to come at the situation that only one remained (precisely the one that gave half of his heart to Einon ). The two make an improbable alliance that would bring an advantage to both. DragonHeart has always been one of those memorable films that just never fail to amaze, with the feelings they are able to transmit to the viewer. One moment you laugh, the next you are broken in tears. Few films are able to do this to the viewer - And DragonHeart strikes as excellent in this. The film features a strong cast that pulls out exceptionally good performances - Dennis Quaid is of course a strong actor and highlights very well the nature of his character. One of the turning points of the film is the delusion of Bowen, that has lived all his life on his ideals, and training his pupil, is forced to see him exactly, or more like, worse than the last king, his father, was. Dina Meyer represents perfectly the brave, rebel woman Kara is. The most memorable human character though is without a doubt Brother Gilbert, played by the late Pete Postlethwaite (may he rest in peace), the comic relief of the film that never ceases to bring a smile. Sean Connery is the voice for the Dragon, Draco, who is at turn created through the use of Computer Graphics by the artists of Industrial Light & Magic, known for their work on films such as Jurassic Park, who never cease to do their job none less than amazing, as Draco still holds up very well today. Connery's voice perfectly fits the character and makes it even more memorable. Draco is a noble hearted, gentle figure and the best character of the film. His death is one of those moments in a film that you quite never forget, for its strength in presentation, tear shredding score and incredibly sad yet heart warming combination of image and words. DragonHeart is truly a beautiful, old school fantasy Masterpiece and deserves a lot of praising for what it is, and the humanitary message it represents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than those overrated 'The Lord of the Rings' films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Dragonheart' is strangely underrated. Considering the unbelievable popularity of 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy (even today), we could ask ourselves why 'Dragonheart' didn't reach half of that fame. However, being underrated has a good side, as most underrated and less known films are far superior than the eternally popular and overrated ones. 'Dragonheart' is an okay movie, worthy for dragon lovers. I am a dragon lover myself. Dragons fascinate me. They're such huge, fantastic and beautiful beasts. I wish dragons existed in real life. Draco the dragon is, without a doubt, the only really likable character in the movie. I don't care much about the others. The dragon is what makes this movie good enough. Without him, the movie would be nothing. The dragon is voiced by perhaps the most popular "James Bond" ever: Sean Connery. Bowen, the character portrayed by Dennis Quaid, is a good guy but undeniably arrogant and much self-proud and at the same time he's a bad guy for one reason: he kills all dragons because he believes that all dragons are evil. He wanted to kill Draco as well, but ends up forming a partnership and friendship with him and later realizes he's not evil. Draco was always a good dragon. He only killed those who wanted to harm him, in self-defense. What he didn't know was that giving half of his heart to Einon would be a terrible mistake. Einon falsely promised to be good and to follow the "old code" but in no time he showed what he really is: a brutal tyrant who only pretended to be Bowen's friend so that he could learn how to use the sword. The sad thing is that, in order to kill the bad guy, the dragon has to die as well. This happens because, as they share the same heart, they feel the same pains and all. Realizing this, the dragon doesn't just beg to be killed, he demands. Bowen doesn't have courage to do it at first and you can't blame him for that. That is a horrible thing to do. I'd like to know if there wasn't any other solution. You know, like, maybe the dragon could have found a way to recover the half of his heart that he gave to the villain. That way they wouldn't share the same pain and the evil guy could have been killed without the dragon having to die with him. Much of the filming occurred in the ancient ruins of Spi Castle, Slovakia. The result is beautiful sceneries and landscapes, perfect for an epic film. The action is set somewhere in the late 10th century in England, after the Saxons's conquest of that country. The dragon might have been created by computer, but he looks great and very real - so different from CGI "art". This level of perfection is comparable to the dinosaurs of 'Jurassic Park'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven but decent enough fantasy adventure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dragonheart is set during 948 A.D. & starts as a peasant uprising is defeated by evil King Freyne (Peter Hric) & his troops, in a show a strength King Freyne rides into their village to set it alight but it was a trap & King Freyne is killed in front of his teenage son Einon (Lee Oakes) who himself is badly injured. Einon's mother takes her son to a Dragon as a last resort in order to save his life, the Dragon gives Einon half of his own heart which saves the boy's life. Twelve years later & Einon (David Thewlis) has grown up to be just as much an evil tyrant as his father was who rules with brutality, his former friend, teacher & knight of the old order Bowen (Dennis Quaid) has turned Dragonslayer since he blames the Dragon's heart for polluting Einon & making him evil but decides to team up with a friendly Dragon he names Draco as well as feisty young woman Kara (Dina Meyer) who together lead a revolt against Einon, his troops & all he stands for... Directed by Rob Cohen this fantasy adventure is one of the few mainstream films featuring a Dragon & while it's nothing amazing I didn't think it was too bad overall. Dragon films are thin on the ground to be honest, there's Dragonslayer (1981), Dragonworld (1994) prior to Dragonheart with Dungeons & Dragons (2000), Reign of Fire (2002) & Eargon (2007) afterwards & none of the films mentioned have been that good or done that well at the box-office. The script feels a bit uneven, while on the one hand you have this whimsical child like fantasy of a friendly talking Dragon there's the other side of the film with a peasant uprising which does get quite violent with necks being broken, people being stabbed, set on fire & one bloke is hit in the nuts with a huge battle axe (ouch) & the two distinctly different tones didn't sit together that well for me. Basically the violence is a little too strong for younger children while the silly talking friendly Dragon is a little childish for anyone over the age of ten. That's not to say Dragonheart isn't an enjoyable film for what it is because it is, it moves along at a decent enough pace, the mismatched partners Bowen & Draco surely have one of the bizarrest on screen buddy buddy relationships ever & it entertains but I didn't think the violence & childish fantasy sat well together & it's a little repetitive & predictable with an ending that goes on for too long, sure the Dragon dies but have an extended scene set to orchestral music with various star shining in the sky is just a bit too much. Dragonheart was made early in the days of CGI computer effects & you can see a lot of time & effort went into them & they hold up really well even now. The battle scenes & fights are good if a little predictable (the good guy always wins & the bad guy gets it) & as a period piece the costumes, sets & props all look the part. Draco the Dragon voiced by Sean Connery looks great, he moves convincingly, flies convincingly & definitely has a personality. In fact Dragonheart was nominated for a Best Visual Effects Oscar along with Twister (1996) but both deservedly lost out to Independence Day (1996). With a supposed budget of about $57,000,000 this had a lot of money spent on it & I would have though most of it was spent on the CGI effects, filmed on location in Slovakia. The acting is OK but nothing special, Pete Postlethwaite doesn't get much to do, Dennis Quid is somewhat bland, it's nice to see Brian Thompson in a Hollywood film while Sir John Gielgud has a voice cameo as King Arthur. Dragonheart is a solid enough fantasy adventure that may be too violent for youngsters while a bit too childish for adults, I thought it was good but nothing amazing overall. Followed by the straight to video sequel Dragonheart: A New Beginning (2000).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sean Connery as a Dragon. :)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this movie is fairly old but I really only just heard of it recently and seen it. I normally don't like dragon movies but I really did enjoy this one. My opinion there's just not that many good dragon movies out there. Which is kind of sad since I do love dragons and medieval times as a whole. This movie is kind of slow but I've found it's good to have patience. I found the acting wasn't half bad and the plot was fairly decent. Plus I think this movie had one of the first CGI dragons and I actually thought they didn't do too bad a job. I'd recommend it and say give it a chance. Seems to be a family friendly movie for the most part. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the best fantasy movie, but okay nonetheless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the very few fantasy films that hit the screen and even then it is not as high as a movie like Willow is (though I should point out that I originally wrote this review in 1996). In fact, it is quite a low fantasy movie with the exception of the dragon, which creates some of the high fantasy in this movie. Straight out, it is an enjoyable movie to watch, but it goes little beyond that. A knight is training a prince in the art of honour and chivalry, but the prince has better ideas. When he sees his father wounded severely in a peasant uprising, he does not help him, but rather rips the crown from his hand. It is this event that shows us that the prince is, in his heart, evil. Unfortunately, when his is wounded, he is taken to a Dragon for help. The dragon gives him half of his heart and the boy survives. Unfortunately, all pain that the prince (now King) feels is felt by the dragon. The king does not change his ways, and the knight thus blames the dragon. The movie hasn't got a straight plot, but it isn't twisted either. What it focuses on is the knight, who first seeks to kill the dragon, then befriends him, and then decides to destroy the king's power, only to become king himself. The movie does have a tragic feel to it, as we soon come to know that the dragon is going to die because of his compassion, but it is not the tragedy where we can see the character constantly degrade to a point where he will die. In fact, even though we know he is going to die, it is not because of his actions, but because of the actions of the antagonist, and though we see a minor flag that an act of compassion at the beginning will lead to his downfall, we do not know enough to want to warn him away from doing it. The theology in the movie is quite dodgy as well. Though human theology is not looked at, dragon theology is. The way the dragon reaches heaven is my doing noteworthy and honourable deeds. Unfortunately, if those deeds backfire then the dragon is in big trouble. As such there is no certainty and as such we can be as good as we like, but never be guaranteed because our acts of goodness might backfire. What Christ offers is assurance. There is no being good because no amount of good deeds can get us on the right side of God. In fact by doing pure good deeds we are saying that we are not happy with the way God does things and want to do it ourselves, and thus offending God. As such it is a vicious circle for we attempt to be good, but by being good we are being offensive, which is bad. As such being good does not work, but rather by trusting what God has already done. By dying he has given us the option of accepting that our goodness will never be good enough and thus take Jesus' goodness for ourselves, and his resurrection tells us that he had the authority to do it. As for the movie, it is okay, and pleasant to watch as a fantasy movie, but beyond that it is really not all that much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can someone say... GENIUS?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Miller (miller.jmiller.jason@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie that sins it? Literally, nothing. The acting is great, the storyline is phenomenal, the humor thrives, and the special effects do not disappoint. The storyline portrays a young Prince with a tyrannic father, who dies. The boy is injured to near death, and a dragon gives half his heart to the boy. The boy himself becomes a tyrant. A knight vows to kill all dragons until he kills the one who gave the heart. But, not all is what it seems... This is definitely a movie for those whom enjoy a good, hearty film with a moral at its center. It is even a good family film, depending on your parenting methods (which one should hope are decent and logical). If you need a movie to kick back and relax to, watch on a snowy or rainy day, or just because, this is a great movie. The storyline lacks no potential; utilizing all elements and keeping the audience's attention. The chosen actors for the characters was ingenious and well planned. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. I promise, if you approach this movie with a joyous attitude, or even a skeptical one, you will enjoy it. ~~Go forth and review movies~~
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood style medieval adventure fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hduck1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sickeningly mawkish story. Typical Hollywood. Clownish and idiotic dialog. An attempt to interject humor in an otherwise adventurous tale. Compare this production to the British series, Merlin. The latter had better dialog, better storyline, equally good special effects. The only drawbacks I found in Merlin were with regard to casting, but Colin Morgan made an ideal young Merlin for me. John Hurt's voice made a more believable dragon than Sean Connery's voice. These fantasies are fun to watch when they are well made. However, I am always aware that the dragon is the biblical symbol of Satan. Therefore to make a noble beast of the creature is mockery of the Bible. "Merlin" did not exactly make the dragon a good creature - without the control of a "dragonlord" it became entirely destructive. It seems ironic to make any kind of pact with a dragon; it is literally making a pact with the devil. But as I say, the fantasy is fun when well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great dragon flick with a good charm to it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, how I love Dragonheart. This was made during the dawn of CGI. After Terminator 2 and Jurassic Park pushed the boundaries of special effects to a whole new level, Universal decided to try something different with computer effects and storytelling. The result was this lovable film that has, dare I say it, a burning passion. The story of a dragon (Sean Connery) and a dragon slayer (Dennis Quaid) becoming friends and teaming up against a tyrannical king is unforgettable. This movie is just full of comedy, action, and drama and the cast, especially Sean Connery, deliver terrific performances. It's not often you see a dragon movie like this and with that, it should be commended. I give this movie a 7 for entertainment value and a fiery extra point for the effort in which this was made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Talking Dragon Makes This Movie Corny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    airwolf-121-720419
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I did enjoy this movie for what it is, I would have to say that this movie was corny. Corny because we have a friendly talking dragon voiced by Sean Connery. Plus, the acting of the evil boy king was just really cheesy in my opinion. Aren't dragons supposed to be mythical creatures we are supposed to fear? If so, then why are they portrayed as a cuddle bear we can share our most inner thoughts while other movies portray dragons as something to fear? The only reason why I am giving this movie a 3 is that Dennis Quaid is in this movie. While I also like Connery, his part just didn't sit well with me. So even the actors couldn't revive this very corny movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable with a sense of humour added in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like fantasy films and especially the ones set in medi evil times with dragons and sword fights and beautiful landscapes etc. That isn't to say all the ones that have these are necessarily good films but it is a world we can only imagine. Dragonheart starts off a little slow, but still interesting that sets up the plot of the film. Luckily it starts getting really enjoyable when the Dragon comes into it who becomes an ally of Bowen (Dennis Quaid) who is out to settle a personal vendetta against a Dragon who has turned a student of his into a corrupt ruler in his role as King Einon (David Thewlis in a very convincing role as an arrogant ruler). What makes this film appealing is the fact that the Dragon named Draco (voiced by Sean Connery) is given a lot of personality and hence is able to bond with Bowen. It adds a lot to the sense of humour and the film doesn't become too dark or a film that is based purely on revenge themes. The visual effects were also decent and for what this film is worth, it feels like a B grade film but looks like an A Grade film with the good performances, decent visuals and good cinematography of the landscapes. The production design is pretty impressive too. It still has flaws. The action scenes needed better music score to make it a bit more exciting and dramatic and the story itself is a bit clich&eacute; in some respects. Julie Christie doesn't have much to do in her role which is a shame considering she had a good presence in the beginning then was sort of here now and then later on. Dennis Quaid is convincing as a boorish Dragon Slayer earning a living as a slayer and is a likable character. What is also good is that there is no silly romantic subplot which I suspected would have been thrown in which would have made the plot even more clich&eacute; but it avoided that even though I thought there were going to be hints at it. So I was surprised to find myself enjoying this. Sometimes films like these that you can just watch and just have a good time are what you need when you don't want to think too much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece of Fantasy Storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omega
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dennis Quaid is Knight of the Old Code Bowen, a strong and grand hearted man that in hope of saving his fatally wounded pupil and future king Einon, takes him to the lair of a Dragon that, in the hope of making him a true king, unlike his father, gives him the life again by taking a part of his heart and putting it into him. Bowen, upon this action of benevolence, promises the Dragon his services, as the creature himself remembers him that Einon must stay true to his promise of being a good Ruler. As years pass, Einon reveals himself to be an even worse King than his father was, treating his reign like the worst kind of Tyrant would. Bowen, believing that the Dragon was the cause, declares vengeance on all Dragons, only to come at the situation that only one remained (precisely the one that gave half of his heart to Einon ). The two make an improbable alliance that would bring an advantage to both. DragonHeart has always been one of those memorable films that just never fail to amaze, with the feelings they are able to transmit to the viewer. One moment you laugh, the next you are broken in tears. Few films are able to do this to the viewer - And DragonHeart strikes as excellent in this. The film features a strong cast that pulls out exceptionally good performances - Dennis Quaid is of course a strong actor and highlights very well the nature of his character. One of the turning points of the film is the delusion of Bowen, that has lived all his life on his ideals, and training his pupil, is forced to see him exactly, or more like, worse than the last king, his father, was. Dina Meyer represents perfectly the brave, rebel woman Kara is. The most memorable human character though is without a doubt Brother Gilbert, played by the late Pete Postlethwaite (may he rest in peace), the comic relief of the film that never ceases to bring a smile. Sean Connery is the voice for the Dragon, Draco, who is at turn created through the use of Computer Graphics by the artists of Industrial Light & Magic, known for their work on films such as Jurassic Park, who never cease to do their job none less than amazing, as Draco still holds up very well today. Connery's voice perfectly fits the character and makes it even more memorable. Draco is a noble hearted, gentle figure and the best character of the film. His death is one of those moments in a film that you quite never forget, for its strength in presentation, tear shredding score and incredibly sad yet heart warming combination of image and words. DragonHeart is truly a beautiful, old school fantasy Masterpiece and deserves a lot of praising for what it is, and the humanitary message it represents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than those overrated 'The Lord of the Rings' films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Dragonheart' is strangely underrated. Considering the unbelievable popularity of 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy (even today), we could ask ourselves why 'Dragonheart' didn't reach half of that fame. However, being underrated has a good side, as most underrated and less known films are far superior than the eternally popular and overrated ones. 'Dragonheart' is an okay movie, worthy for dragon lovers. I am a dragon lover myself. Dragons fascinate me. They're such huge, fantastic and beautiful beasts. I wish dragons existed in real life. Draco the dragon is, without a doubt, the only really likable character in the movie. I don't care much about the others. The dragon is what makes this movie good enough. Without him, the movie would be nothing. The dragon is voiced by perhaps the most popular "James Bond" ever: Sean Connery. Bowen, the character portrayed by Dennis Quaid, is a good guy but undeniably arrogant and much self-proud and at the same time he's a bad guy for one reason: he kills all dragons because he believes that all dragons are evil. He wanted to kill Draco as well, but ends up forming a partnership and friendship with him and later realizes he's not evil. Draco was always a good dragon. He only killed those who wanted to harm him, in self-defense. What he didn't know was that giving half of his heart to Einon would be a terrible mistake. Einon falsely promised to be good and to follow the "old code" but in no time he showed what he really is: a brutal tyrant who only pretended to be Bowen's friend so that he could learn how to use the sword. The sad thing is that, in order to kill the bad guy, the dragon has to die as well. This happens because, as they share the same heart, they feel the same pains and all. Realizing this, the dragon doesn't just beg to be killed, he demands. Bowen doesn't have courage to do it at first and you can't blame him for that. That is a horrible thing to do. I'd like to know if there wasn't any other solution. You know, like, maybe the dragon could have found a way to recover the half of his heart that he gave to the villain. That way they wouldn't share the same pain and the evil guy could have been killed without the dragon having to die with him. Much of the filming occurred in the ancient ruins of Spi Castle, Slovakia. The result is beautiful sceneries and landscapes, perfect for an epic film. The action is set somewhere in the late 10th century in England, after the Saxons's conquest of that country. The dragon might have been created by computer, but he looks great and very real - so different from CGI "art". This level of perfection is comparable to the dinosaurs of 'Jurassic Park'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven but decent enough fantasy adventure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dragonheart is set during 948 A.D. & starts as a peasant uprising is defeated by evil King Freyne (Peter Hric) & his troops, in a show a strength King Freyne rides into their village to set it alight but it was a trap & King Freyne is killed in front of his teenage son Einon (Lee Oakes) who himself is badly injured. Einon's mother takes her son to a Dragon as a last resort in order to save his life, the Dragon gives Einon half of his own heart which saves the boy's life. Twelve years later & Einon (David Thewlis) has grown up to be just as much an evil tyrant as his father was who rules with brutality, his former friend, teacher & knight of the old order Bowen (Dennis Quaid) has turned Dragonslayer since he blames the Dragon's heart for polluting Einon & making him evil but decides to team up with a friendly Dragon he names Draco as well as feisty young woman Kara (Dina Meyer) who together lead a revolt against Einon, his troops & all he stands for... Directed by Rob Cohen this fantasy adventure is one of the few mainstream films featuring a Dragon & while it's nothing amazing I didn't think it was too bad overall. Dragon films are thin on the ground to be honest, there's Dragonslayer (1981), Dragonworld (1994) prior to Dragonheart with Dungeons & Dragons (2000), Reign of Fire (2002) & Eargon (2007) afterwards & none of the films mentioned have been that good or done that well at the box-office. The script feels a bit uneven, while on the one hand you have this whimsical child like fantasy of a friendly talking Dragon there's the other side of the film with a peasant uprising which does get quite violent with necks being broken, people being stabbed, set on fire & one bloke is hit in the nuts with a huge battle axe (ouch) & the two distinctly different tones didn't sit together that well for me. Basically the violence is a little too strong for younger children while the silly talking friendly Dragon is a little childish for anyone over the age of ten. That's not to say Dragonheart isn't an enjoyable film for what it is because it is, it moves along at a decent enough pace, the mismatched partners Bowen & Draco surely have one of the bizarrest on screen buddy buddy relationships ever & it entertains but I didn't think the violence & childish fantasy sat well together & it's a little repetitive & predictable with an ending that goes on for too long, sure the Dragon dies but have an extended scene set to orchestral music with various star shining in the sky is just a bit too much. Dragonheart was made early in the days of CGI computer effects & you can see a lot of time & effort went into them & they hold up really well even now. The battle scenes & fights are good if a little predictable (the good guy always wins & the bad guy gets it) & as a period piece the costumes, sets & props all look the part. Draco the Dragon voiced by Sean Connery looks great, he moves convincingly, flies convincingly & definitely has a personality. In fact Dragonheart was nominated for a Best Visual Effects Oscar along with Twister (1996) but both deservedly lost out to Independence Day (1996). With a supposed budget of about $57,000,000 this had a lot of money spent on it & I would have though most of it was spent on the CGI effects, filmed on location in Slovakia. The acting is OK but nothing special, Pete Postlethwaite doesn't get much to do, Dennis Quid is somewhat bland, it's nice to see Brian Thompson in a Hollywood film while Sir John Gielgud has a voice cameo as King Arthur. Dragonheart is a solid enough fantasy adventure that may be too violent for youngsters while a bit too childish for adults, I thought it was good but nothing amazing overall. Followed by the straight to video sequel Dragonheart: A New Beginning (2000).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sean Connery as a Dragon. :)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this movie is fairly old but I really only just heard of it recently and seen it. I normally don't like dragon movies but I really did enjoy this one. My opinion there's just not that many good dragon movies out there. Which is kind of sad since I do love dragons and medieval times as a whole. This movie is kind of slow but I've found it's good to have patience. I found the acting wasn't half bad and the plot was fairly decent. Plus I think this movie had one of the first CGI dragons and I actually thought they didn't do too bad a job. I'd recommend it and say give it a chance. Seems to be a family friendly movie for the most part. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the best fantasy movie, but okay nonetheless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the very few fantasy films that hit the screen and even then it is not as high as a movie like Willow is (though I should point out that I originally wrote this review in 1996). In fact, it is quite a low fantasy movie with the exception of the dragon, which creates some of the high fantasy in this movie. Straight out, it is an enjoyable movie to watch, but it goes little beyond that. A knight is training a prince in the art of honour and chivalry, but the prince has better ideas. When he sees his father wounded severely in a peasant uprising, he does not help him, but rather rips the crown from his hand. It is this event that shows us that the prince is, in his heart, evil. Unfortunately, when his is wounded, he is taken to a Dragon for help. The dragon gives him half of his heart and the boy survives. Unfortunately, all pain that the prince (now King) feels is felt by the dragon. The king does not change his ways, and the knight thus blames the dragon. The movie hasn't got a straight plot, but it isn't twisted either. What it focuses on is the knight, who first seeks to kill the dragon, then befriends him, and then decides to destroy the king's power, only to become king himself. The movie does have a tragic feel to it, as we soon come to know that the dragon is going to die because of his compassion, but it is not the tragedy where we can see the character constantly degrade to a point where he will die. In fact, even though we know he is going to die, it is not because of his actions, but because of the actions of the antagonist, and though we see a minor flag that an act of compassion at the beginning will lead to his downfall, we do not know enough to want to warn him away from doing it. The theology in the movie is quite dodgy as well. Though human theology is not looked at, dragon theology is. The way the dragon reaches heaven is my doing noteworthy and honourable deeds. Unfortunately, if those deeds backfire then the dragon is in big trouble. As such there is no certainty and as such we can be as good as we like, but never be guaranteed because our acts of goodness might backfire. What Christ offers is assurance. There is no being good because no amount of good deeds can get us on the right side of God. In fact by doing pure good deeds we are saying that we are not happy with the way God does things and want to do it ourselves, and thus offending God. As such it is a vicious circle for we attempt to be good, but by being good we are being offensive, which is bad. As such being good does not work, but rather by trusting what God has already done. By dying he has given us the option of accepting that our goodness will never be good enough and thus take Jesus' goodness for ourselves, and his resurrection tells us that he had the authority to do it. As for the movie, it is okay, and pleasant to watch as a fantasy movie, but beyond that it is really not all that much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can someone say... GENIUS?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Miller (miller.jmiller.jason@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie that sins it? Literally, nothing. The acting is great, the storyline is phenomenal, the humor thrives, and the special effects do not disappoint. The storyline portrays a young Prince with a tyrannic father, who dies. The boy is injured to near death, and a dragon gives half his heart to the boy. The boy himself becomes a tyrant. A knight vows to kill all dragons until he kills the one who gave the heart. But, not all is what it seems... This is definitely a movie for those whom enjoy a good, hearty film with a moral at its center. It is even a good family film, depending on your parenting methods (which one should hope are decent and logical). If you need a movie to kick back and relax to, watch on a snowy or rainy day, or just because, this is a great movie. The storyline lacks no potential; utilizing all elements and keeping the audience's attention. The chosen actors for the characters was ingenious and well planned. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. I promise, if you approach this movie with a joyous attitude, or even a skeptical one, you will enjoy it. ~~Go forth and review movies~~
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood style medieval adventure fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hduck1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sickeningly mawkish story. Typical Hollywood. Clownish and idiotic dialog. An attempt to interject humor in an otherwise adventurous tale. Compare this production to the British series, Merlin. The latter had better dialog, better storyline, equally good special effects. The only drawbacks I found in Merlin were with regard to casting, but Colin Morgan made an ideal young Merlin for me. John Hurt's voice made a more believable dragon than Sean Connery's voice. These fantasies are fun to watch when they are well made. However, I am always aware that the dragon is the biblical symbol of Satan. Therefore to make a noble beast of the creature is mockery of the Bible. "Merlin" did not exactly make the dragon a good creature - without the control of a "dragonlord" it became entirely destructive. It seems ironic to make any kind of pact with a dragon; it is literally making a pact with the devil. But as I say, the fantasy is fun when well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great dragon flick with a good charm to it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, how I love Dragonheart. This was made during the dawn of CGI. After Terminator 2 and Jurassic Park pushed the boundaries of special effects to a whole new level, Universal decided to try something different with computer effects and storytelling. The result was this lovable film that has, dare I say it, a burning passion. The story of a dragon (Sean Connery) and a dragon slayer (Dennis Quaid) becoming friends and teaming up against a tyrannical king is unforgettable. This movie is just full of comedy, action, and drama and the cast, especially Sean Connery, deliver terrific performances. It's not often you see a dragon movie like this and with that, it should be commended. I give this movie a 7 for entertainment value and a fiery extra point for the effort in which this was made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Talking Dragon Makes This Movie Corny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    airwolf-121-720419
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I did enjoy this movie for what it is, I would have to say that this movie was corny. Corny because we have a friendly talking dragon voiced by Sean Connery. Plus, the acting of the evil boy king was just really cheesy in my opinion. Aren't dragons supposed to be mythical creatures we are supposed to fear? If so, then why are they portrayed as a cuddle bear we can share our most inner thoughts while other movies portray dragons as something to fear? The only reason why I am giving this movie a 3 is that Dennis Quaid is in this movie. While I also like Connery, his part just didn't sit well with me. So even the actors couldn't revive this very corny movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable with a sense of humour added in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like fantasy films and especially the ones set in medi evil times with dragons and sword fights and beautiful landscapes etc. That isn't to say all the ones that have these are necessarily good films but it is a world we can only imagine. Dragonheart starts off a little slow, but still interesting that sets up the plot of the film. Luckily it starts getting really enjoyable when the Dragon comes into it who becomes an ally of Bowen (Dennis Quaid) who is out to settle a personal vendetta against a Dragon who has turned a student of his into a corrupt ruler in his role as King Einon (David Thewlis in a very convincing role as an arrogant ruler). What makes this film appealing is the fact that the Dragon named Draco (voiced by Sean Connery) is given a lot of personality and hence is able to bond with Bowen. It adds a lot to the sense of humour and the film doesn't become too dark or a film that is based purely on revenge themes. The visual effects were also decent and for what this film is worth, it feels like a B grade film but looks like an A Grade film with the good performances, decent visuals and good cinematography of the landscapes. The production design is pretty impressive too. It still has flaws. The action scenes needed better music score to make it a bit more exciting and dramatic and the story itself is a bit clich&eacute; in some respects. Julie Christie doesn't have much to do in her role which is a shame considering she had a good presence in the beginning then was sort of here now and then later on. Dennis Quaid is convincing as a boorish Dragon Slayer earning a living as a slayer and is a likable character. What is also good is that there is no silly romantic subplot which I suspected would have been thrown in which would have made the plot even more clich&eacute; but it avoided that even though I thought there were going to be hints at it. So I was surprised to find myself enjoying this. Sometimes films like these that you can just watch and just have a good time are what you need when you don't want to think too much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece of Fantasy Storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omega
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dennis Quaid is Knight of the Old Code Bowen, a strong and grand hearted man that in hope of saving his fatally wounded pupil and future king Einon, takes him to the lair of a Dragon that, in the hope of making him a true king, unlike his father, gives him the life again by taking a part of his heart and putting it into him. Bowen, upon this action of benevolence, promises the Dragon his services, as the creature himself remembers him that Einon must stay true to his promise of being a good Ruler. As years pass, Einon reveals himself to be an even worse King than his father was, treating his reign like the worst kind of Tyrant would. Bowen, believing that the Dragon was the cause, declares vengeance on all Dragons, only to come at the situation that only one remained (precisely the one that gave half of his heart to Einon ). The two make an improbable alliance that would bring an advantage to both. DragonHeart has always been one of those memorable films that just never fail to amaze, with the feelings they are able to transmit to the viewer. One moment you laugh, the next you are broken in tears. Few films are able to do this to the viewer - And DragonHeart strikes as excellent in this. The film features a strong cast that pulls out exceptionally good performances - Dennis Quaid is of course a strong actor and highlights very well the nature of his character. One of the turning points of the film is the delusion of Bowen, that has lived all his life on his ideals, and training his pupil, is forced to see him exactly, or more like, worse than the last king, his father, was. Dina Meyer represents perfectly the brave, rebel woman Kara is. The most memorable human character though is without a doubt Brother Gilbert, played by the late Pete Postlethwaite (may he rest in peace), the comic relief of the film that never ceases to bring a smile. Sean Connery is the voice for the Dragon, Draco, who is at turn created through the use of Computer Graphics by the artists of Industrial Light & Magic, known for their work on films such as Jurassic Park, who never cease to do their job none less than amazing, as Draco still holds up very well today. Connery's voice perfectly fits the character and makes it even more memorable. Draco is a noble hearted, gentle figure and the best character of the film. His death is one of those moments in a film that you quite never forget, for its strength in presentation, tear shredding score and incredibly sad yet heart warming combination of image and words. DragonHeart is truly a beautiful, old school fantasy Masterpiece and deserves a lot of praising for what it is, and the humanitary message it represents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than those overrated 'The Lord of the Rings' films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Dragonheart' is strangely underrated. Considering the unbelievable popularity of 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy (even today), we could ask ourselves why 'Dragonheart' didn't reach half of that fame. However, being underrated has a good side, as most underrated and less known films are far superior than the eternally popular and overrated ones. 'Dragonheart' is an okay movie, worthy for dragon lovers. I am a dragon lover myself. Dragons fascinate me. They're such huge, fantastic and beautiful beasts. I wish dragons existed in real life. Draco the dragon is, without a doubt, the only really likable character in the movie. I don't care much about the others. The dragon is what makes this movie good enough. Without him, the movie would be nothing. The dragon is voiced by perhaps the most popular "James Bond" ever: Sean Connery. Bowen, the character portrayed by Dennis Quaid, is a good guy but undeniably arrogant and much self-proud and at the same time he's a bad guy for one reason: he kills all dragons because he believes that all dragons are evil. He wanted to kill Draco as well, but ends up forming a partnership and friendship with him and later realizes he's not evil. Draco was always a good dragon. He only killed those who wanted to harm him, in self-defense. What he didn't know was that giving half of his heart to Einon would be a terrible mistake. Einon falsely promised to be good and to follow the "old code" but in no time he showed what he really is: a brutal tyrant who only pretended to be Bowen's friend so that he could learn how to use the sword. The sad thing is that, in order to kill the bad guy, the dragon has to die as well. This happens because, as they share the same heart, they feel the same pains and all. Realizing this, the dragon doesn't just beg to be killed, he demands. Bowen doesn't have courage to do it at first and you can't blame him for that. That is a horrible thing to do. I'd like to know if there wasn't any other solution. You know, like, maybe the dragon could have found a way to recover the half of his heart that he gave to the villain. That way they wouldn't share the same pain and the evil guy could have been killed without the dragon having to die with him. Much of the filming occurred in the ancient ruins of Spi Castle, Slovakia. The result is beautiful sceneries and landscapes, perfect for an epic film. The action is set somewhere in the late 10th century in England, after the Saxons's conquest of that country. The dragon might have been created by computer, but he looks great and very real - so different from CGI "art". This level of perfection is comparable to the dinosaurs of 'Jurassic Park'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven but decent enough fantasy adventure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dragonheart is set during 948 A.D. & starts as a peasant uprising is defeated by evil King Freyne (Peter Hric) & his troops, in a show a strength King Freyne rides into their village to set it alight but it was a trap & King Freyne is killed in front of his teenage son Einon (Lee Oakes) who himself is badly injured. Einon's mother takes her son to a Dragon as a last resort in order to save his life, the Dragon gives Einon half of his own heart which saves the boy's life. Twelve years later & Einon (David Thewlis) has grown up to be just as much an evil tyrant as his father was who rules with brutality, his former friend, teacher & knight of the old order Bowen (Dennis Quaid) has turned Dragonslayer since he blames the Dragon's heart for polluting Einon & making him evil but decides to team up with a friendly Dragon he names Draco as well as feisty young woman Kara (Dina Meyer) who together lead a revolt against Einon, his troops & all he stands for... Directed by Rob Cohen this fantasy adventure is one of the few mainstream films featuring a Dragon & while it's nothing amazing I didn't think it was too bad overall. Dragon films are thin on the ground to be honest, there's Dragonslayer (1981), Dragonworld (1994) prior to Dragonheart with Dungeons & Dragons (2000), Reign of Fire (2002) & Eargon (2007) afterwards & none of the films mentioned have been that good or done that well at the box-office. The script feels a bit uneven, while on the one hand you have this whimsical child like fantasy of a friendly talking Dragon there's the other side of the film with a peasant uprising which does get quite violent with necks being broken, people being stabbed, set on fire & one bloke is hit in the nuts with a huge battle axe (ouch) & the two distinctly different tones didn't sit together that well for me. Basically the violence is a little too strong for younger children while the silly talking friendly Dragon is a little childish for anyone over the age of ten. That's not to say Dragonheart isn't an enjoyable film for what it is because it is, it moves along at a decent enough pace, the mismatched partners Bowen & Draco surely have one of the bizarrest on screen buddy buddy relationships ever & it entertains but I didn't think the violence & childish fantasy sat well together & it's a little repetitive & predictable with an ending that goes on for too long, sure the Dragon dies but have an extended scene set to orchestral music with various star shining in the sky is just a bit too much. Dragonheart was made early in the days of CGI computer effects & you can see a lot of time & effort went into them & they hold up really well even now. The battle scenes & fights are good if a little predictable (the good guy always wins & the bad guy gets it) & as a period piece the costumes, sets & props all look the part. Draco the Dragon voiced by Sean Connery looks great, he moves convincingly, flies convincingly & definitely has a personality. In fact Dragonheart was nominated for a Best Visual Effects Oscar along with Twister (1996) but both deservedly lost out to Independence Day (1996). With a supposed budget of about $57,000,000 this had a lot of money spent on it & I would have though most of it was spent on the CGI effects, filmed on location in Slovakia. The acting is OK but nothing special, Pete Postlethwaite doesn't get much to do, Dennis Quid is somewhat bland, it's nice to see Brian Thompson in a Hollywood film while Sir John Gielgud has a voice cameo as King Arthur. Dragonheart is a solid enough fantasy adventure that may be too violent for youngsters while a bit too childish for adults, I thought it was good but nothing amazing overall. Followed by the straight to video sequel Dragonheart: A New Beginning (2000).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sean Connery as a Dragon. :)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this movie is fairly old but I really only just heard of it recently and seen it. I normally don't like dragon movies but I really did enjoy this one. My opinion there's just not that many good dragon movies out there. Which is kind of sad since I do love dragons and medieval times as a whole. This movie is kind of slow but I've found it's good to have patience. I found the acting wasn't half bad and the plot was fairly decent. Plus I think this movie had one of the first CGI dragons and I actually thought they didn't do too bad a job. I'd recommend it and say give it a chance. Seems to be a family friendly movie for the most part. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the best fantasy movie, but okay nonetheless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the very few fantasy films that hit the screen and even then it is not as high as a movie like Willow is (though I should point out that I originally wrote this review in 1996). In fact, it is quite a low fantasy movie with the exception of the dragon, which creates some of the high fantasy in this movie. Straight out, it is an enjoyable movie to watch, but it goes little beyond that. A knight is training a prince in the art of honour and chivalry, but the prince has better ideas. When he sees his father wounded severely in a peasant uprising, he does not help him, but rather rips the crown from his hand. It is this event that shows us that the prince is, in his heart, evil. Unfortunately, when his is wounded, he is taken to a Dragon for help. The dragon gives him half of his heart and the boy survives. Unfortunately, all pain that the prince (now King) feels is felt by the dragon. The king does not change his ways, and the knight thus blames the dragon. The movie hasn't got a straight plot, but it isn't twisted either. What it focuses on is the knight, who first seeks to kill the dragon, then befriends him, and then decides to destroy the king's power, only to become king himself. The movie does have a tragic feel to it, as we soon come to know that the dragon is going to die because of his compassion, but it is not the tragedy where we can see the character constantly degrade to a point where he will die. In fact, even though we know he is going to die, it is not because of his actions, but because of the actions of the antagonist, and though we see a minor flag that an act of compassion at the beginning will lead to his downfall, we do not know enough to want to warn him away from doing it. The theology in the movie is quite dodgy as well. Though human theology is not looked at, dragon theology is. The way the dragon reaches heaven is my doing noteworthy and honourable deeds. Unfortunately, if those deeds backfire then the dragon is in big trouble. As such there is no certainty and as such we can be as good as we like, but never be guaranteed because our acts of goodness might backfire. What Christ offers is assurance. There is no being good because no amount of good deeds can get us on the right side of God. In fact by doing pure good deeds we are saying that we are not happy with the way God does things and want to do it ourselves, and thus offending God. As such it is a vicious circle for we attempt to be good, but by being good we are being offensive, which is bad. As such being good does not work, but rather by trusting what God has already done. By dying he has given us the option of accepting that our goodness will never be good enough and thus take Jesus' goodness for ourselves, and his resurrection tells us that he had the authority to do it. As for the movie, it is okay, and pleasant to watch as a fantasy movie, but beyond that it is really not all that much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can someone say... GENIUS?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Miller (miller.jmiller.jason@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie that sins it? Literally, nothing. The acting is great, the storyline is phenomenal, the humor thrives, and the special effects do not disappoint. The storyline portrays a young Prince with a tyrannic father, who dies. The boy is injured to near death, and a dragon gives half his heart to the boy. The boy himself becomes a tyrant. A knight vows to kill all dragons until he kills the one who gave the heart. But, not all is what it seems... This is definitely a movie for those whom enjoy a good, hearty film with a moral at its center. It is even a good family film, depending on your parenting methods (which one should hope are decent and logical). If you need a movie to kick back and relax to, watch on a snowy or rainy day, or just because, this is a great movie. The storyline lacks no potential; utilizing all elements and keeping the audience's attention. The chosen actors for the characters was ingenious and well planned. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. I promise, if you approach this movie with a joyous attitude, or even a skeptical one, you will enjoy it. ~~Go forth and review movies~~
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood style medieval adventure fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hduck1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sickeningly mawkish story. Typical Hollywood. Clownish and idiotic dialog. An attempt to interject humor in an otherwise adventurous tale. Compare this production to the British series, Merlin. The latter had better dialog, better storyline, equally good special effects. The only drawbacks I found in Merlin were with regard to casting, but Colin Morgan made an ideal young Merlin for me. John Hurt's voice made a more believable dragon than Sean Connery's voice. These fantasies are fun to watch when they are well made. However, I am always aware that the dragon is the biblical symbol of Satan. Therefore to make a noble beast of the creature is mockery of the Bible. "Merlin" did not exactly make the dragon a good creature - without the control of a "dragonlord" it became entirely destructive. It seems ironic to make any kind of pact with a dragon; it is literally making a pact with the devil. But as I say, the fantasy is fun when well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great dragon flick with a good charm to it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, how I love Dragonheart. This was made during the dawn of CGI. After Terminator 2 and Jurassic Park pushed the boundaries of special effects to a whole new level, Universal decided to try something different with computer effects and storytelling. The result was this lovable film that has, dare I say it, a burning passion. The story of a dragon (Sean Connery) and a dragon slayer (Dennis Quaid) becoming friends and teaming up against a tyrannical king is unforgettable. This movie is just full of comedy, action, and drama and the cast, especially Sean Connery, deliver terrific performances. It's not often you see a dragon movie like this and with that, it should be commended. I give this movie a 7 for entertainment value and a fiery extra point for the effort in which this was made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Talking Dragon Makes This Movie Corny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    airwolf-121-720419
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I did enjoy this movie for what it is, I would have to say that this movie was corny. Corny because we have a friendly talking dragon voiced by Sean Connery. Plus, the acting of the evil boy king was just really cheesy in my opinion. Aren't dragons supposed to be mythical creatures we are supposed to fear? If so, then why are they portrayed as a cuddle bear we can share our most inner thoughts while other movies portray dragons as something to fear? The only reason why I am giving this movie a 3 is that Dennis Quaid is in this movie. While I also like Connery, his part just didn't sit well with me. So even the actors couldn't revive this very corny movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable with a sense of humour added in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like fantasy films and especially the ones set in medi evil times with dragons and sword fights and beautiful landscapes etc. That isn't to say all the ones that have these are necessarily good films but it is a world we can only imagine. Dragonheart starts off a little slow, but still interesting that sets up the plot of the film. Luckily it starts getting really enjoyable when the Dragon comes into it who becomes an ally of Bowen (Dennis Quaid) who is out to settle a personal vendetta against a Dragon who has turned a student of his into a corrupt ruler in his role as King Einon (David Thewlis in a very convincing role as an arrogant ruler). What makes this film appealing is the fact that the Dragon named Draco (voiced by Sean Connery) is given a lot of personality and hence is able to bond with Bowen. It adds a lot to the sense of humour and the film doesn't become too dark or a film that is based purely on revenge themes. The visual effects were also decent and for what this film is worth, it feels like a B grade film but looks like an A Grade film with the good performances, decent visuals and good cinematography of the landscapes. The production design is pretty impressive too. It still has flaws. The action scenes needed better music score to make it a bit more exciting and dramatic and the story itself is a bit clich&eacute; in some respects. Julie Christie doesn't have much to do in her role which is a shame considering she had a good presence in the beginning then was sort of here now and then later on. Dennis Quaid is convincing as a boorish Dragon Slayer earning a living as a slayer and is a likable character. What is also good is that there is no silly romantic subplot which I suspected would have been thrown in which would have made the plot even more clich&eacute; but it avoided that even though I thought there were going to be hints at it. So I was surprised to find myself enjoying this. Sometimes films like these that you can just watch and just have a good time are what you need when you don't want to think too much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece of Fantasy Storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omega
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dennis Quaid is Knight of the Old Code Bowen, a strong and grand hearted man that in hope of saving his fatally wounded pupil and future king Einon, takes him to the lair of a Dragon that, in the hope of making him a true king, unlike his father, gives him the life again by taking a part of his heart and putting it into him. Bowen, upon this action of benevolence, promises the Dragon his services, as the creature himself remembers him that Einon must stay true to his promise of being a good Ruler. As years pass, Einon reveals himself to be an even worse King than his father was, treating his reign like the worst kind of Tyrant would. Bowen, believing that the Dragon was the cause, declares vengeance on all Dragons, only to come at the situation that only one remained (precisely the one that gave half of his heart to Einon ). The two make an improbable alliance that would bring an advantage to both. DragonHeart has always been one of those memorable films that just never fail to amaze, with the feelings they are able to transmit to the viewer. One moment you laugh, the next you are broken in tears. Few films are able to do this to the viewer - And DragonHeart strikes as excellent in this. The film features a strong cast that pulls out exceptionally good performances - Dennis Quaid is of course a strong actor and highlights very well the nature of his character. One of the turning points of the film is the delusion of Bowen, that has lived all his life on his ideals, and training his pupil, is forced to see him exactly, or more like, worse than the last king, his father, was. Dina Meyer represents perfectly the brave, rebel woman Kara is. The most memorable human character though is without a doubt Brother Gilbert, played by the late Pete Postlethwaite (may he rest in peace), the comic relief of the film that never ceases to bring a smile. Sean Connery is the voice for the Dragon, Draco, who is at turn created through the use of Computer Graphics by the artists of Industrial Light & Magic, known for their work on films such as Jurassic Park, who never cease to do their job none less than amazing, as Draco still holds up very well today. Connery's voice perfectly fits the character and makes it even more memorable. Draco is a noble hearted, gentle figure and the best character of the film. His death is one of those moments in a film that you quite never forget, for its strength in presentation, tear shredding score and incredibly sad yet heart warming combination of image and words. DragonHeart is truly a beautiful, old school fantasy Masterpiece and deserves a lot of praising for what it is, and the humanitary message it represents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than those overrated 'The Lord of the Rings' films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Dragonheart' is strangely underrated. Considering the unbelievable popularity of 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy (even today), we could ask ourselves why 'Dragonheart' didn't reach half of that fame. However, being underrated has a good side, as most underrated and less known films are far superior than the eternally popular and overrated ones. 'Dragonheart' is an okay movie, worthy for dragon lovers. I am a dragon lover myself. Dragons fascinate me. They're such huge, fantastic and beautiful beasts. I wish dragons existed in real life. Draco the dragon is, without a doubt, the only really likable character in the movie. I don't care much about the others. The dragon is what makes this movie good enough. Without him, the movie would be nothing. The dragon is voiced by perhaps the most popular "James Bond" ever: Sean Connery. Bowen, the character portrayed by Dennis Quaid, is a good guy but undeniably arrogant and much self-proud and at the same time he's a bad guy for one reason: he kills all dragons because he believes that all dragons are evil. He wanted to kill Draco as well, but ends up forming a partnership and friendship with him and later realizes he's not evil. Draco was always a good dragon. He only killed those who wanted to harm him, in self-defense. What he didn't know was that giving half of his heart to Einon would be a terrible mistake. Einon falsely promised to be good and to follow the "old code" but in no time he showed what he really is: a brutal tyrant who only pretended to be Bowen's friend so that he could learn how to use the sword. The sad thing is that, in order to kill the bad guy, the dragon has to die as well. This happens because, as they share the same heart, they feel the same pains and all. Realizing this, the dragon doesn't just beg to be killed, he demands. Bowen doesn't have courage to do it at first and you can't blame him for that. That is a horrible thing to do. I'd like to know if there wasn't any other solution. You know, like, maybe the dragon could have found a way to recover the half of his heart that he gave to the villain. That way they wouldn't share the same pain and the evil guy could have been killed without the dragon having to die with him. Much of the filming occurred in the ancient ruins of Spi Castle, Slovakia. The result is beautiful sceneries and landscapes, perfect for an epic film. The action is set somewhere in the late 10th century in England, after the Saxons's conquest of that country. The dragon might have been created by computer, but he looks great and very real - so different from CGI "art". This level of perfection is comparable to the dinosaurs of 'Jurassic Park'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven but decent enough fantasy adventure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dragonheart is set during 948 A.D. & starts as a peasant uprising is defeated by evil King Freyne (Peter Hric) & his troops, in a show a strength King Freyne rides into their village to set it alight but it was a trap & King Freyne is killed in front of his teenage son Einon (Lee Oakes) who himself is badly injured. Einon's mother takes her son to a Dragon as a last resort in order to save his life, the Dragon gives Einon half of his own heart which saves the boy's life. Twelve years later & Einon (David Thewlis) has grown up to be just as much an evil tyrant as his father was who rules with brutality, his former friend, teacher & knight of the old order Bowen (Dennis Quaid) has turned Dragonslayer since he blames the Dragon's heart for polluting Einon & making him evil but decides to team up with a friendly Dragon he names Draco as well as feisty young woman Kara (Dina Meyer) who together lead a revolt against Einon, his troops & all he stands for... Directed by Rob Cohen this fantasy adventure is one of the few mainstream films featuring a Dragon & while it's nothing amazing I didn't think it was too bad overall. Dragon films are thin on the ground to be honest, there's Dragonslayer (1981), Dragonworld (1994) prior to Dragonheart with Dungeons & Dragons (2000), Reign of Fire (2002) & Eargon (2007) afterwards & none of the films mentioned have been that good or done that well at the box-office. The script feels a bit uneven, while on the one hand you have this whimsical child like fantasy of a friendly talking Dragon there's the other side of the film with a peasant uprising which does get quite violent with necks being broken, people being stabbed, set on fire & one bloke is hit in the nuts with a huge battle axe (ouch) & the two distinctly different tones didn't sit together that well for me. Basically the violence is a little too strong for younger children while the silly talking friendly Dragon is a little childish for anyone over the age of ten. That's not to say Dragonheart isn't an enjoyable film for what it is because it is, it moves along at a decent enough pace, the mismatched partners Bowen & Draco surely have one of the bizarrest on screen buddy buddy relationships ever & it entertains but I didn't think the violence & childish fantasy sat well together & it's a little repetitive & predictable with an ending that goes on for too long, sure the Dragon dies but have an extended scene set to orchestral music with various star shining in the sky is just a bit too much. Dragonheart was made early in the days of CGI computer effects & you can see a lot of time & effort went into them & they hold up really well even now. The battle scenes & fights are good if a little predictable (the good guy always wins & the bad guy gets it) & as a period piece the costumes, sets & props all look the part. Draco the Dragon voiced by Sean Connery looks great, he moves convincingly, flies convincingly & definitely has a personality. In fact Dragonheart was nominated for a Best Visual Effects Oscar along with Twister (1996) but both deservedly lost out to Independence Day (1996). With a supposed budget of about $57,000,000 this had a lot of money spent on it & I would have though most of it was spent on the CGI effects, filmed on location in Slovakia. The acting is OK but nothing special, Pete Postlethwaite doesn't get much to do, Dennis Quid is somewhat bland, it's nice to see Brian Thompson in a Hollywood film while Sir John Gielgud has a voice cameo as King Arthur. Dragonheart is a solid enough fantasy adventure that may be too violent for youngsters while a bit too childish for adults, I thought it was good but nothing amazing overall. Followed by the straight to video sequel Dragonheart: A New Beginning (2000).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sean Connery as a Dragon. :)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this movie is fairly old but I really only just heard of it recently and seen it. I normally don't like dragon movies but I really did enjoy this one. My opinion there's just not that many good dragon movies out there. Which is kind of sad since I do love dragons and medieval times as a whole. This movie is kind of slow but I've found it's good to have patience. I found the acting wasn't half bad and the plot was fairly decent. Plus I think this movie had one of the first CGI dragons and I actually thought they didn't do too bad a job. I'd recommend it and say give it a chance. Seems to be a family friendly movie for the most part. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the best fantasy movie, but okay nonetheless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the very few fantasy films that hit the screen and even then it is not as high as a movie like Willow is (though I should point out that I originally wrote this review in 1996). In fact, it is quite a low fantasy movie with the exception of the dragon, which creates some of the high fantasy in this movie. Straight out, it is an enjoyable movie to watch, but it goes little beyond that. A knight is training a prince in the art of honour and chivalry, but the prince has better ideas. When he sees his father wounded severely in a peasant uprising, he does not help him, but rather rips the crown from his hand. It is this event that shows us that the prince is, in his heart, evil. Unfortunately, when his is wounded, he is taken to a Dragon for help. The dragon gives him half of his heart and the boy survives. Unfortunately, all pain that the prince (now King) feels is felt by the dragon. The king does not change his ways, and the knight thus blames the dragon. The movie hasn't got a straight plot, but it isn't twisted either. What it focuses on is the knight, who first seeks to kill the dragon, then befriends him, and then decides to destroy the king's power, only to become king himself. The movie does have a tragic feel to it, as we soon come to know that the dragon is going to die because of his compassion, but it is not the tragedy where we can see the character constantly degrade to a point where he will die. In fact, even though we know he is going to die, it is not because of his actions, but because of the actions of the antagonist, and though we see a minor flag that an act of compassion at the beginning will lead to his downfall, we do not know enough to want to warn him away from doing it. The theology in the movie is quite dodgy as well. Though human theology is not looked at, dragon theology is. The way the dragon reaches heaven is my doing noteworthy and honourable deeds. Unfortunately, if those deeds backfire then the dragon is in big trouble. As such there is no certainty and as such we can be as good as we like, but never be guaranteed because our acts of goodness might backfire. What Christ offers is assurance. There is no being good because no amount of good deeds can get us on the right side of God. In fact by doing pure good deeds we are saying that we are not happy with the way God does things and want to do it ourselves, and thus offending God. As such it is a vicious circle for we attempt to be good, but by being good we are being offensive, which is bad. As such being good does not work, but rather by trusting what God has already done. By dying he has given us the option of accepting that our goodness will never be good enough and thus take Jesus' goodness for ourselves, and his resurrection tells us that he had the authority to do it. As for the movie, it is okay, and pleasant to watch as a fantasy movie, but beyond that it is really not all that much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can someone say... GENIUS?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Miller (miller.jmiller.jason@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie that sins it? Literally, nothing. The acting is great, the storyline is phenomenal, the humor thrives, and the special effects do not disappoint. The storyline portrays a young Prince with a tyrannic father, who dies. The boy is injured to near death, and a dragon gives half his heart to the boy. The boy himself becomes a tyrant. A knight vows to kill all dragons until he kills the one who gave the heart. But, not all is what it seems... This is definitely a movie for those whom enjoy a good, hearty film with a moral at its center. It is even a good family film, depending on your parenting methods (which one should hope are decent and logical). If you need a movie to kick back and relax to, watch on a snowy or rainy day, or just because, this is a great movie. The storyline lacks no potential; utilizing all elements and keeping the audience's attention. The chosen actors for the characters was ingenious and well planned. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. I promise, if you approach this movie with a joyous attitude, or even a skeptical one, you will enjoy it. ~~Go forth and review movies~~
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood style medieval adventure fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hduck1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sickeningly mawkish story. Typical Hollywood. Clownish and idiotic dialog. An attempt to interject humor in an otherwise adventurous tale. Compare this production to the British series, Merlin. The latter had better dialog, better storyline, equally good special effects. The only drawbacks I found in Merlin were with regard to casting, but Colin Morgan made an ideal young Merlin for me. John Hurt's voice made a more believable dragon than Sean Connery's voice. These fantasies are fun to watch when they are well made. However, I am always aware that the dragon is the biblical symbol of Satan. Therefore to make a noble beast of the creature is mockery of the Bible. "Merlin" did not exactly make the dragon a good creature - without the control of a "dragonlord" it became entirely destructive. It seems ironic to make any kind of pact with a dragon; it is literally making a pact with the devil. But as I say, the fantasy is fun when well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great dragon flick with a good charm to it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, how I love Dragonheart. This was made during the dawn of CGI. After Terminator 2 and Jurassic Park pushed the boundaries of special effects to a whole new level, Universal decided to try something different with computer effects and storytelling. The result was this lovable film that has, dare I say it, a burning passion. The story of a dragon (Sean Connery) and a dragon slayer (Dennis Quaid) becoming friends and teaming up against a tyrannical king is unforgettable. This movie is just full of comedy, action, and drama and the cast, especially Sean Connery, deliver terrific performances. It's not often you see a dragon movie like this and with that, it should be commended. I give this movie a 7 for entertainment value and a fiery extra point for the effort in which this was made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Talking Dragon Makes This Movie Corny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    airwolf-121-720419
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I did enjoy this movie for what it is, I would have to say that this movie was corny. Corny because we have a friendly talking dragon voiced by Sean Connery. Plus, the acting of the evil boy king was just really cheesy in my opinion. Aren't dragons supposed to be mythical creatures we are supposed to fear? If so, then why are they portrayed as a cuddle bear we can share our most inner thoughts while other movies portray dragons as something to fear? The only reason why I am giving this movie a 3 is that Dennis Quaid is in this movie. While I also like Connery, his part just didn't sit well with me. So even the actors couldn't revive this very corny movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable with a sense of humour added in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like fantasy films and especially the ones set in medi evil times with dragons and sword fights and beautiful landscapes etc. That isn't to say all the ones that have these are necessarily good films but it is a world we can only imagine. Dragonheart starts off a little slow, but still interesting that sets up the plot of the film. Luckily it starts getting really enjoyable when the Dragon comes into it who becomes an ally of Bowen (Dennis Quaid) who is out to settle a personal vendetta against a Dragon who has turned a student of his into a corrupt ruler in his role as King Einon (David Thewlis in a very convincing role as an arrogant ruler). What makes this film appealing is the fact that the Dragon named Draco (voiced by Sean Connery) is given a lot of personality and hence is able to bond with Bowen. It adds a lot to the sense of humour and the film doesn't become too dark or a film that is based purely on revenge themes. The visual effects were also decent and for what this film is worth, it feels like a B grade film but looks like an A Grade film with the good performances, decent visuals and good cinematography of the landscapes. The production design is pretty impressive too. It still has flaws. The action scenes needed better music score to make it a bit more exciting and dramatic and the story itself is a bit clich&eacute; in some respects. Julie Christie doesn't have much to do in her role which is a shame considering she had a good presence in the beginning then was sort of here now and then later on. Dennis Quaid is convincing as a boorish Dragon Slayer earning a living as a slayer and is a likable character. What is also good is that there is no silly romantic subplot which I suspected would have been thrown in which would have made the plot even more clich&eacute; but it avoided that even though I thought there were going to be hints at it. So I was surprised to find myself enjoying this. Sometimes films like these that you can just watch and just have a good time are what you need when you don't want to think too much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece of Fantasy Storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omega
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dennis Quaid is Knight of the Old Code Bowen, a strong and grand hearted man that in hope of saving his fatally wounded pupil and future king Einon, takes him to the lair of a Dragon that, in the hope of making him a true king, unlike his father, gives him the life again by taking a part of his heart and putting it into him. Bowen, upon this action of benevolence, promises the Dragon his services, as the creature himself remembers him that Einon must stay true to his promise of being a good Ruler. As years pass, Einon reveals himself to be an even worse King than his father was, treating his reign like the worst kind of Tyrant would. Bowen, believing that the Dragon was the cause, declares vengeance on all Dragons, only to come at the situation that only one remained (precisely the one that gave half of his heart to Einon ). The two make an improbable alliance that would bring an advantage to both. DragonHeart has always been one of those memorable films that just never fail to amaze, with the feelings they are able to transmit to the viewer. One moment you laugh, the next you are broken in tears. Few films are able to do this to the viewer - And DragonHeart strikes as excellent in this. The film features a strong cast that pulls out exceptionally good performances - Dennis Quaid is of course a strong actor and highlights very well the nature of his character. One of the turning points of the film is the delusion of Bowen, that has lived all his life on his ideals, and training his pupil, is forced to see him exactly, or more like, worse than the last king, his father, was. Dina Meyer represents perfectly the brave, rebel woman Kara is. The most memorable human character though is without a doubt Brother Gilbert, played by the late Pete Postlethwaite (may he rest in peace), the comic relief of the film that never ceases to bring a smile. Sean Connery is the voice for the Dragon, Draco, who is at turn created through the use of Computer Graphics by the artists of Industrial Light & Magic, known for their work on films such as Jurassic Park, who never cease to do their job none less than amazing, as Draco still holds up very well today. Connery's voice perfectly fits the character and makes it even more memorable. Draco is a noble hearted, gentle figure and the best character of the film. His death is one of those moments in a film that you quite never forget, for its strength in presentation, tear shredding score and incredibly sad yet heart warming combination of image and words. DragonHeart is truly a beautiful, old school fantasy Masterpiece and deserves a lot of praising for what it is, and the humanitary message it represents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than those overrated 'The Lord of the Rings' films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Dragonheart' is strangely underrated. Considering the unbelievable popularity of 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy (even today), we could ask ourselves why 'Dragonheart' didn't reach half of that fame. However, being underrated has a good side, as most underrated and less known films are far superior than the eternally popular and overrated ones. 'Dragonheart' is an okay movie, worthy for dragon lovers. I am a dragon lover myself. Dragons fascinate me. They're such huge, fantastic and beautiful beasts. I wish dragons existed in real life. Draco the dragon is, without a doubt, the only really likable character in the movie. I don't care much about the others. The dragon is what makes this movie good enough. Without him, the movie would be nothing. The dragon is voiced by perhaps the most popular "James Bond" ever: Sean Connery. Bowen, the character portrayed by Dennis Quaid, is a good guy but undeniably arrogant and much self-proud and at the same time he's a bad guy for one reason: he kills all dragons because he believes that all dragons are evil. He wanted to kill Draco as well, but ends up forming a partnership and friendship with him and later realizes he's not evil. Draco was always a good dragon. He only killed those who wanted to harm him, in self-defense. What he didn't know was that giving half of his heart to Einon would be a terrible mistake. Einon falsely promised to be good and to follow the "old code" but in no time he showed what he really is: a brutal tyrant who only pretended to be Bowen's friend so that he could learn how to use the sword. The sad thing is that, in order to kill the bad guy, the dragon has to die as well. This happens because, as they share the same heart, they feel the same pains and all. Realizing this, the dragon doesn't just beg to be killed, he demands. Bowen doesn't have courage to do it at first and you can't blame him for that. That is a horrible thing to do. I'd like to know if there wasn't any other solution. You know, like, maybe the dragon could have found a way to recover the half of his heart that he gave to the villain. That way they wouldn't share the same pain and the evil guy could have been killed without the dragon having to die with him. Much of the filming occurred in the ancient ruins of Spi Castle, Slovakia. The result is beautiful sceneries and landscapes, perfect for an epic film. The action is set somewhere in the late 10th century in England, after the Saxons's conquest of that country. The dragon might have been created by computer, but he looks great and very real - so different from CGI "art". This level of perfection is comparable to the dinosaurs of 'Jurassic Park'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven but decent enough fantasy adventure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dragonheart is set during 948 A.D. & starts as a peasant uprising is defeated by evil King Freyne (Peter Hric) & his troops, in a show a strength King Freyne rides into their village to set it alight but it was a trap & King Freyne is killed in front of his teenage son Einon (Lee Oakes) who himself is badly injured. Einon's mother takes her son to a Dragon as a last resort in order to save his life, the Dragon gives Einon half of his own heart which saves the boy's life. Twelve years later & Einon (David Thewlis) has grown up to be just as much an evil tyrant as his father was who rules with brutality, his former friend, teacher & knight of the old order Bowen (Dennis Quaid) has turned Dragonslayer since he blames the Dragon's heart for polluting Einon & making him evil but decides to team up with a friendly Dragon he names Draco as well as feisty young woman Kara (Dina Meyer) who together lead a revolt against Einon, his troops & all he stands for... Directed by Rob Cohen this fantasy adventure is one of the few mainstream films featuring a Dragon & while it's nothing amazing I didn't think it was too bad overall. Dragon films are thin on the ground to be honest, there's Dragonslayer (1981), Dragonworld (1994) prior to Dragonheart with Dungeons & Dragons (2000), Reign of Fire (2002) & Eargon (2007) afterwards & none of the films mentioned have been that good or done that well at the box-office. The script feels a bit uneven, while on the one hand you have this whimsical child like fantasy of a friendly talking Dragon there's the other side of the film with a peasant uprising which does get quite violent with necks being broken, people being stabbed, set on fire & one bloke is hit in the nuts with a huge battle axe (ouch) & the two distinctly different tones didn't sit together that well for me. Basically the violence is a little too strong for younger children while the silly talking friendly Dragon is a little childish for anyone over the age of ten. That's not to say Dragonheart isn't an enjoyable film for what it is because it is, it moves along at a decent enough pace, the mismatched partners Bowen & Draco surely have one of the bizarrest on screen buddy buddy relationships ever & it entertains but I didn't think the violence & childish fantasy sat well together & it's a little repetitive & predictable with an ending that goes on for too long, sure the Dragon dies but have an extended scene set to orchestral music with various star shining in the sky is just a bit too much. Dragonheart was made early in the days of CGI computer effects & you can see a lot of time & effort went into them & they hold up really well even now. The battle scenes & fights are good if a little predictable (the good guy always wins & the bad guy gets it) & as a period piece the costumes, sets & props all look the part. Draco the Dragon voiced by Sean Connery looks great, he moves convincingly, flies convincingly & definitely has a personality. In fact Dragonheart was nominated for a Best Visual Effects Oscar along with Twister (1996) but both deservedly lost out to Independence Day (1996). With a supposed budget of about $57,000,000 this had a lot of money spent on it & I would have though most of it was spent on the CGI effects, filmed on location in Slovakia. The acting is OK but nothing special, Pete Postlethwaite doesn't get much to do, Dennis Quid is somewhat bland, it's nice to see Brian Thompson in a Hollywood film while Sir John Gielgud has a voice cameo as King Arthur. Dragonheart is a solid enough fantasy adventure that may be too violent for youngsters while a bit too childish for adults, I thought it was good but nothing amazing overall. Followed by the straight to video sequel Dragonheart: A New Beginning (2000).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sean Connery as a Dragon. :)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this movie is fairly old but I really only just heard of it recently and seen it. I normally don't like dragon movies but I really did enjoy this one. My opinion there's just not that many good dragon movies out there. Which is kind of sad since I do love dragons and medieval times as a whole. This movie is kind of slow but I've found it's good to have patience. I found the acting wasn't half bad and the plot was fairly decent. Plus I think this movie had one of the first CGI dragons and I actually thought they didn't do too bad a job. I'd recommend it and say give it a chance. Seems to be a family friendly movie for the most part. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the best fantasy movie, but okay nonetheless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the very few fantasy films that hit the screen and even then it is not as high as a movie like Willow is (though I should point out that I originally wrote this review in 1996). In fact, it is quite a low fantasy movie with the exception of the dragon, which creates some of the high fantasy in this movie. Straight out, it is an enjoyable movie to watch, but it goes little beyond that. A knight is training a prince in the art of honour and chivalry, but the prince has better ideas. When he sees his father wounded severely in a peasant uprising, he does not help him, but rather rips the crown from his hand. It is this event that shows us that the prince is, in his heart, evil. Unfortunately, when his is wounded, he is taken to a Dragon for help. The dragon gives him half of his heart and the boy survives. Unfortunately, all pain that the prince (now King) feels is felt by the dragon. The king does not change his ways, and the knight thus blames the dragon. The movie hasn't got a straight plot, but it isn't twisted either. What it focuses on is the knight, who first seeks to kill the dragon, then befriends him, and then decides to destroy the king's power, only to become king himself. The movie does have a tragic feel to it, as we soon come to know that the dragon is going to die because of his compassion, but it is not the tragedy where we can see the character constantly degrade to a point where he will die. In fact, even though we know he is going to die, it is not because of his actions, but because of the actions of the antagonist, and though we see a minor flag that an act of compassion at the beginning will lead to his downfall, we do not know enough to want to warn him away from doing it. The theology in the movie is quite dodgy as well. Though human theology is not looked at, dragon theology is. The way the dragon reaches heaven is my doing noteworthy and honourable deeds. Unfortunately, if those deeds backfire then the dragon is in big trouble. As such there is no certainty and as such we can be as good as we like, but never be guaranteed because our acts of goodness might backfire. What Christ offers is assurance. There is no being good because no amount of good deeds can get us on the right side of God. In fact by doing pure good deeds we are saying that we are not happy with the way God does things and want to do it ourselves, and thus offending God. As such it is a vicious circle for we attempt to be good, but by being good we are being offensive, which is bad. As such being good does not work, but rather by trusting what God has already done. By dying he has given us the option of accepting that our goodness will never be good enough and thus take Jesus' goodness for ourselves, and his resurrection tells us that he had the authority to do it. As for the movie, it is okay, and pleasant to watch as a fantasy movie, but beyond that it is really not all that much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can someone say... GENIUS?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Miller (miller.jmiller.jason@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie that sins it? Literally, nothing. The acting is great, the storyline is phenomenal, the humor thrives, and the special effects do not disappoint. The storyline portrays a young Prince with a tyrannic father, who dies. The boy is injured to near death, and a dragon gives half his heart to the boy. The boy himself becomes a tyrant. A knight vows to kill all dragons until he kills the one who gave the heart. But, not all is what it seems... This is definitely a movie for those whom enjoy a good, hearty film with a moral at its center. It is even a good family film, depending on your parenting methods (which one should hope are decent and logical). If you need a movie to kick back and relax to, watch on a snowy or rainy day, or just because, this is a great movie. The storyline lacks no potential; utilizing all elements and keeping the audience's attention. The chosen actors for the characters was ingenious and well planned. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. I promise, if you approach this movie with a joyous attitude, or even a skeptical one, you will enjoy it. ~~Go forth and review movies~~
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood style medieval adventure fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hduck1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sickeningly mawkish story. Typical Hollywood. Clownish and idiotic dialog. An attempt to interject humor in an otherwise adventurous tale. Compare this production to the British series, Merlin. The latter had better dialog, better storyline, equally good special effects. The only drawbacks I found in Merlin were with regard to casting, but Colin Morgan made an ideal young Merlin for me. John Hurt's voice made a more believable dragon than Sean Connery's voice. These fantasies are fun to watch when they are well made. However, I am always aware that the dragon is the biblical symbol of Satan. Therefore to make a noble beast of the creature is mockery of the Bible. "Merlin" did not exactly make the dragon a good creature - without the control of a "dragonlord" it became entirely destructive. It seems ironic to make any kind of pact with a dragon; it is literally making a pact with the devil. But as I say, the fantasy is fun when well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great dragon flick with a good charm to it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, how I love Dragonheart. This was made during the dawn of CGI. After Terminator 2 and Jurassic Park pushed the boundaries of special effects to a whole new level, Universal decided to try something different with computer effects and storytelling. The result was this lovable film that has, dare I say it, a burning passion. The story of a dragon (Sean Connery) and a dragon slayer (Dennis Quaid) becoming friends and teaming up against a tyrannical king is unforgettable. This movie is just full of comedy, action, and drama and the cast, especially Sean Connery, deliver terrific performances. It's not often you see a dragon movie like this and with that, it should be commended. I give this movie a 7 for entertainment value and a fiery extra point for the effort in which this was made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Talking Dragon Makes This Movie Corny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    airwolf-121-720419
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I did enjoy this movie for what it is, I would have to say that this movie was corny. Corny because we have a friendly talking dragon voiced by Sean Connery. Plus, the acting of the evil boy king was just really cheesy in my opinion. Aren't dragons supposed to be mythical creatures we are supposed to fear? If so, then why are they portrayed as a cuddle bear we can share our most inner thoughts while other movies portray dragons as something to fear? The only reason why I am giving this movie a 3 is that Dennis Quaid is in this movie. While I also like Connery, his part just didn't sit well with me. So even the actors couldn't revive this very corny movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable with a sense of humour added in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like fantasy films and especially the ones set in medi evil times with dragons and sword fights and beautiful landscapes etc. That isn't to say all the ones that have these are necessarily good films but it is a world we can only imagine. Dragonheart starts off a little slow, but still interesting that sets up the plot of the film. Luckily it starts getting really enjoyable when the Dragon comes into it who becomes an ally of Bowen (Dennis Quaid) who is out to settle a personal vendetta against a Dragon who has turned a student of his into a corrupt ruler in his role as King Einon (David Thewlis in a very convincing role as an arrogant ruler). What makes this film appealing is the fact that the Dragon named Draco (voiced by Sean Connery) is given a lot of personality and hence is able to bond with Bowen. It adds a lot to the sense of humour and the film doesn't become too dark or a film that is based purely on revenge themes. The visual effects were also decent and for what this film is worth, it feels like a B grade film but looks like an A Grade film with the good performances, decent visuals and good cinematography of the landscapes. The production design is pretty impressive too. It still has flaws. The action scenes needed better music score to make it a bit more exciting and dramatic and the story itself is a bit clich&eacute; in some respects. Julie Christie doesn't have much to do in her role which is a shame considering she had a good presence in the beginning then was sort of here now and then later on. Dennis Quaid is convincing as a boorish Dragon Slayer earning a living as a slayer and is a likable character. What is also good is that there is no silly romantic subplot which I suspected would have been thrown in which would have made the plot even more clich&eacute; but it avoided that even though I thought there were going to be hints at it. So I was surprised to find myself enjoying this. Sometimes films like these that you can just watch and just have a good time are what you need when you don't want to think too much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece of Fantasy Storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omega
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dennis Quaid is Knight of the Old Code Bowen, a strong and grand hearted man that in hope of saving his fatally wounded pupil and future king Einon, takes him to the lair of a Dragon that, in the hope of making him a true king, unlike his father, gives him the life again by taking a part of his heart and putting it into him. Bowen, upon this action of benevolence, promises the Dragon his services, as the creature himself remembers him that Einon must stay true to his promise of being a good Ruler. As years pass, Einon reveals himself to be an even worse King than his father was, treating his reign like the worst kind of Tyrant would. Bowen, believing that the Dragon was the cause, declares vengeance on all Dragons, only to come at the situation that only one remained (precisely the one that gave half of his heart to Einon ). The two make an improbable alliance that would bring an advantage to both. DragonHeart has always been one of those memorable films that just never fail to amaze, with the feelings they are able to transmit to the viewer. One moment you laugh, the next you are broken in tears. Few films are able to do this to the viewer - And DragonHeart strikes as excellent in this. The film features a strong cast that pulls out exceptionally good performances - Dennis Quaid is of course a strong actor and highlights very well the nature of his character. One of the turning points of the film is the delusion of Bowen, that has lived all his life on his ideals, and training his pupil, is forced to see him exactly, or more like, worse than the last king, his father, was. Dina Meyer represents perfectly the brave, rebel woman Kara is. The most memorable human character though is without a doubt Brother Gilbert, played by the late Pete Postlethwaite (may he rest in peace), the comic relief of the film that never ceases to bring a smile. Sean Connery is the voice for the Dragon, Draco, who is at turn created through the use of Computer Graphics by the artists of Industrial Light & Magic, known for their work on films such as Jurassic Park, who never cease to do their job none less than amazing, as Draco still holds up very well today. Connery's voice perfectly fits the character and makes it even more memorable. Draco is a noble hearted, gentle figure and the best character of the film. His death is one of those moments in a film that you quite never forget, for its strength in presentation, tear shredding score and incredibly sad yet heart warming combination of image and words. DragonHeart is truly a beautiful, old school fantasy Masterpiece and deserves a lot of praising for what it is, and the humanitary message it represents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than those overrated 'The Lord of the Rings' films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Dragonheart' is strangely underrated. Considering the unbelievable popularity of 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy (even today), we could ask ourselves why 'Dragonheart' didn't reach half of that fame. However, being underrated has a good side, as most underrated and less known films are far superior than the eternally popular and overrated ones. 'Dragonheart' is an okay movie, worthy for dragon lovers. I am a dragon lover myself. Dragons fascinate me. They're such huge, fantastic and beautiful beasts. I wish dragons existed in real life. Draco the dragon is, without a doubt, the only really likable character in the movie. I don't care much about the others. The dragon is what makes this movie good enough. Without him, the movie would be nothing. The dragon is voiced by perhaps the most popular "James Bond" ever: Sean Connery. Bowen, the character portrayed by Dennis Quaid, is a good guy but undeniably arrogant and much self-proud and at the same time he's a bad guy for one reason: he kills all dragons because he believes that all dragons are evil. He wanted to kill Draco as well, but ends up forming a partnership and friendship with him and later realizes he's not evil. Draco was always a good dragon. He only killed those who wanted to harm him, in self-defense. What he didn't know was that giving half of his heart to Einon would be a terrible mistake. Einon falsely promised to be good and to follow the "old code" but in no time he showed what he really is: a brutal tyrant who only pretended to be Bowen's friend so that he could learn how to use the sword. The sad thing is that, in order to kill the bad guy, the dragon has to die as well. This happens because, as they share the same heart, they feel the same pains and all. Realizing this, the dragon doesn't just beg to be killed, he demands. Bowen doesn't have courage to do it at first and you can't blame him for that. That is a horrible thing to do. I'd like to know if there wasn't any other solution. You know, like, maybe the dragon could have found a way to recover the half of his heart that he gave to the villain. That way they wouldn't share the same pain and the evil guy could have been killed without the dragon having to die with him. Much of the filming occurred in the ancient ruins of Spi Castle, Slovakia. The result is beautiful sceneries and landscapes, perfect for an epic film. The action is set somewhere in the late 10th century in England, after the Saxons's conquest of that country. The dragon might have been created by computer, but he looks great and very real - so different from CGI "art". This level of perfection is comparable to the dinosaurs of 'Jurassic Park'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven but decent enough fantasy adventure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dragonheart is set during 948 A.D. & starts as a peasant uprising is defeated by evil King Freyne (Peter Hric) & his troops, in a show a strength King Freyne rides into their village to set it alight but it was a trap & King Freyne is killed in front of his teenage son Einon (Lee Oakes) who himself is badly injured. Einon's mother takes her son to a Dragon as a last resort in order to save his life, the Dragon gives Einon half of his own heart which saves the boy's life. Twelve years later & Einon (David Thewlis) has grown up to be just as much an evil tyrant as his father was who rules with brutality, his former friend, teacher & knight of the old order Bowen (Dennis Quaid) has turned Dragonslayer since he blames the Dragon's heart for polluting Einon & making him evil but decides to team up with a friendly Dragon he names Draco as well as feisty young woman Kara (Dina Meyer) who together lead a revolt against Einon, his troops & all he stands for... Directed by Rob Cohen this fantasy adventure is one of the few mainstream films featuring a Dragon & while it's nothing amazing I didn't think it was too bad overall. Dragon films are thin on the ground to be honest, there's Dragonslayer (1981), Dragonworld (1994) prior to Dragonheart with Dungeons & Dragons (2000), Reign of Fire (2002) & Eargon (2007) afterwards & none of the films mentioned have been that good or done that well at the box-office. The script feels a bit uneven, while on the one hand you have this whimsical child like fantasy of a friendly talking Dragon there's the other side of the film with a peasant uprising which does get quite violent with necks being broken, people being stabbed, set on fire & one bloke is hit in the nuts with a huge battle axe (ouch) & the two distinctly different tones didn't sit together that well for me. Basically the violence is a little too strong for younger children while the silly talking friendly Dragon is a little childish for anyone over the age of ten. That's not to say Dragonheart isn't an enjoyable film for what it is because it is, it moves along at a decent enough pace, the mismatched partners Bowen & Draco surely have one of the bizarrest on screen buddy buddy relationships ever & it entertains but I didn't think the violence & childish fantasy sat well together & it's a little repetitive & predictable with an ending that goes on for too long, sure the Dragon dies but have an extended scene set to orchestral music with various star shining in the sky is just a bit too much. Dragonheart was made early in the days of CGI computer effects & you can see a lot of time & effort went into them & they hold up really well even now. The battle scenes & fights are good if a little predictable (the good guy always wins & the bad guy gets it) & as a period piece the costumes, sets & props all look the part. Draco the Dragon voiced by Sean Connery looks great, he moves convincingly, flies convincingly & definitely has a personality. In fact Dragonheart was nominated for a Best Visual Effects Oscar along with Twister (1996) but both deservedly lost out to Independence Day (1996). With a supposed budget of about $57,000,000 this had a lot of money spent on it & I would have though most of it was spent on the CGI effects, filmed on location in Slovakia. The acting is OK but nothing special, Pete Postlethwaite doesn't get much to do, Dennis Quid is somewhat bland, it's nice to see Brian Thompson in a Hollywood film while Sir John Gielgud has a voice cameo as King Arthur. Dragonheart is a solid enough fantasy adventure that may be too violent for youngsters while a bit too childish for adults, I thought it was good but nothing amazing overall. Followed by the straight to video sequel Dragonheart: A New Beginning (2000).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sean Connery as a Dragon. :)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this movie is fairly old but I really only just heard of it recently and seen it. I normally don't like dragon movies but I really did enjoy this one. My opinion there's just not that many good dragon movies out there. Which is kind of sad since I do love dragons and medieval times as a whole. This movie is kind of slow but I've found it's good to have patience. I found the acting wasn't half bad and the plot was fairly decent. Plus I think this movie had one of the first CGI dragons and I actually thought they didn't do too bad a job. I'd recommend it and say give it a chance. Seems to be a family friendly movie for the most part. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the best fantasy movie, but okay nonetheless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the very few fantasy films that hit the screen and even then it is not as high as a movie like Willow is (though I should point out that I originally wrote this review in 1996). In fact, it is quite a low fantasy movie with the exception of the dragon, which creates some of the high fantasy in this movie. Straight out, it is an enjoyable movie to watch, but it goes little beyond that. A knight is training a prince in the art of honour and chivalry, but the prince has better ideas. When he sees his father wounded severely in a peasant uprising, he does not help him, but rather rips the crown from his hand. It is this event that shows us that the prince is, in his heart, evil. Unfortunately, when his is wounded, he is taken to a Dragon for help. The dragon gives him half of his heart and the boy survives. Unfortunately, all pain that the prince (now King) feels is felt by the dragon. The king does not change his ways, and the knight thus blames the dragon. The movie hasn't got a straight plot, but it isn't twisted either. What it focuses on is the knight, who first seeks to kill the dragon, then befriends him, and then decides to destroy the king's power, only to become king himself. The movie does have a tragic feel to it, as we soon come to know that the dragon is going to die because of his compassion, but it is not the tragedy where we can see the character constantly degrade to a point where he will die. In fact, even though we know he is going to die, it is not because of his actions, but because of the actions of the antagonist, and though we see a minor flag that an act of compassion at the beginning will lead to his downfall, we do not know enough to want to warn him away from doing it. The theology in the movie is quite dodgy as well. Though human theology is not looked at, dragon theology is. The way the dragon reaches heaven is my doing noteworthy and honourable deeds. Unfortunately, if those deeds backfire then the dragon is in big trouble. As such there is no certainty and as such we can be as good as we like, but never be guaranteed because our acts of goodness might backfire. What Christ offers is assurance. There is no being good because no amount of good deeds can get us on the right side of God. In fact by doing pure good deeds we are saying that we are not happy with the way God does things and want to do it ourselves, and thus offending God. As such it is a vicious circle for we attempt to be good, but by being good we are being offensive, which is bad. As such being good does not work, but rather by trusting what God has already done. By dying he has given us the option of accepting that our goodness will never be good enough and thus take Jesus' goodness for ourselves, and his resurrection tells us that he had the authority to do it. As for the movie, it is okay, and pleasant to watch as a fantasy movie, but beyond that it is really not all that much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can someone say... GENIUS?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Miller (miller.jmiller.jason@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie that sins it? Literally, nothing. The acting is great, the storyline is phenomenal, the humor thrives, and the special effects do not disappoint. The storyline portrays a young Prince with a tyrannic father, who dies. The boy is injured to near death, and a dragon gives half his heart to the boy. The boy himself becomes a tyrant. A knight vows to kill all dragons until he kills the one who gave the heart. But, not all is what it seems... This is definitely a movie for those whom enjoy a good, hearty film with a moral at its center. It is even a good family film, depending on your parenting methods (which one should hope are decent and logical). If you need a movie to kick back and relax to, watch on a snowy or rainy day, or just because, this is a great movie. The storyline lacks no potential; utilizing all elements and keeping the audience's attention. The chosen actors for the characters was ingenious and well planned. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. I promise, if you approach this movie with a joyous attitude, or even a skeptical one, you will enjoy it. ~~Go forth and review movies~~
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood style medieval adventure fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hduck1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sickeningly mawkish story. Typical Hollywood. Clownish and idiotic dialog. An attempt to interject humor in an otherwise adventurous tale. Compare this production to the British series, Merlin. The latter had better dialog, better storyline, equally good special effects. The only drawbacks I found in Merlin were with regard to casting, but Colin Morgan made an ideal young Merlin for me. John Hurt's voice made a more believable dragon than Sean Connery's voice. These fantasies are fun to watch when they are well made. However, I am always aware that the dragon is the biblical symbol of Satan. Therefore to make a noble beast of the creature is mockery of the Bible. "Merlin" did not exactly make the dragon a good creature - without the control of a "dragonlord" it became entirely destructive. It seems ironic to make any kind of pact with a dragon; it is literally making a pact with the devil. But as I say, the fantasy is fun when well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great dragon flick with a good charm to it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, how I love Dragonheart. This was made during the dawn of CGI. After Terminator 2 and Jurassic Park pushed the boundaries of special effects to a whole new level, Universal decided to try something different with computer effects and storytelling. The result was this lovable film that has, dare I say it, a burning passion. The story of a dragon (Sean Connery) and a dragon slayer (Dennis Quaid) becoming friends and teaming up against a tyrannical king is unforgettable. This movie is just full of comedy, action, and drama and the cast, especially Sean Connery, deliver terrific performances. It's not often you see a dragon movie like this and with that, it should be commended. I give this movie a 7 for entertainment value and a fiery extra point for the effort in which this was made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Talking Dragon Makes This Movie Corny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    airwolf-121-720419
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I did enjoy this movie for what it is, I would have to say that this movie was corny. Corny because we have a friendly talking dragon voiced by Sean Connery. Plus, the acting of the evil boy king was just really cheesy in my opinion. Aren't dragons supposed to be mythical creatures we are supposed to fear? If so, then why are they portrayed as a cuddle bear we can share our most inner thoughts while other movies portray dragons as something to fear? The only reason why I am giving this movie a 3 is that Dennis Quaid is in this movie. While I also like Connery, his part just didn't sit well with me. So even the actors couldn't revive this very corny movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable with a sense of humour added in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like fantasy films and especially the ones set in medi evil times with dragons and sword fights and beautiful landscapes etc. That isn't to say all the ones that have these are necessarily good films but it is a world we can only imagine. Dragonheart starts off a little slow, but still interesting that sets up the plot of the film. Luckily it starts getting really enjoyable when the Dragon comes into it who becomes an ally of Bowen (Dennis Quaid) who is out to settle a personal vendetta against a Dragon who has turned a student of his into a corrupt ruler in his role as King Einon (David Thewlis in a very convincing role as an arrogant ruler). What makes this film appealing is the fact that the Dragon named Draco (voiced by Sean Connery) is given a lot of personality and hence is able to bond with Bowen. It adds a lot to the sense of humour and the film doesn't become too dark or a film that is based purely on revenge themes. The visual effects were also decent and for what this film is worth, it feels like a B grade film but looks like an A Grade film with the good performances, decent visuals and good cinematography of the landscapes. The production design is pretty impressive too. It still has flaws. The action scenes needed better music score to make it a bit more exciting and dramatic and the story itself is a bit clich&eacute; in some respects. Julie Christie doesn't have much to do in her role which is a shame considering she had a good presence in the beginning then was sort of here now and then later on. Dennis Quaid is convincing as a boorish Dragon Slayer earning a living as a slayer and is a likable character. What is also good is that there is no silly romantic subplot which I suspected would have been thrown in which would have made the plot even more clich&eacute; but it avoided that even though I thought there were going to be hints at it. So I was surprised to find myself enjoying this. Sometimes films like these that you can just watch and just have a good time are what you need when you don't want to think too much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece of Fantasy Storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omega
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dennis Quaid is Knight of the Old Code Bowen, a strong and grand hearted man that in hope of saving his fatally wounded pupil and future king Einon, takes him to the lair of a Dragon that, in the hope of making him a true king, unlike his father, gives him the life again by taking a part of his heart and putting it into him. Bowen, upon this action of benevolence, promises the Dragon his services, as the creature himself remembers him that Einon must stay true to his promise of being a good Ruler. As years pass, Einon reveals himself to be an even worse King than his father was, treating his reign like the worst kind of Tyrant would. Bowen, believing that the Dragon was the cause, declares vengeance on all Dragons, only to come at the situation that only one remained (precisely the one that gave half of his heart to Einon ). The two make an improbable alliance that would bring an advantage to both. DragonHeart has always been one of those memorable films that just never fail to amaze, with the feelings they are able to transmit to the viewer. One moment you laugh, the next you are broken in tears. Few films are able to do this to the viewer - And DragonHeart strikes as excellent in this. The film features a strong cast that pulls out exceptionally good performances - Dennis Quaid is of course a strong actor and highlights very well the nature of his character. One of the turning points of the film is the delusion of Bowen, that has lived all his life on his ideals, and training his pupil, is forced to see him exactly, or more like, worse than the last king, his father, was. Dina Meyer represents perfectly the brave, rebel woman Kara is. The most memorable human character though is without a doubt Brother Gilbert, played by the late Pete Postlethwaite (may he rest in peace), the comic relief of the film that never ceases to bring a smile. Sean Connery is the voice for the Dragon, Draco, who is at turn created through the use of Computer Graphics by the artists of Industrial Light & Magic, known for their work on films such as Jurassic Park, who never cease to do their job none less than amazing, as Draco still holds up very well today. Connery's voice perfectly fits the character and makes it even more memorable. Draco is a noble hearted, gentle figure and the best character of the film. His death is one of those moments in a film that you quite never forget, for its strength in presentation, tear shredding score and incredibly sad yet heart warming combination of image and words. DragonHeart is truly a beautiful, old school fantasy Masterpiece and deserves a lot of praising for what it is, and the humanitary message it represents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than those overrated 'The Lord of the Rings' films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Dragonheart' is strangely underrated. Considering the unbelievable popularity of 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy (even today), we could ask ourselves why 'Dragonheart' didn't reach half of that fame. However, being underrated has a good side, as most underrated and less known films are far superior than the eternally popular and overrated ones. 'Dragonheart' is an okay movie, worthy for dragon lovers. I am a dragon lover myself. Dragons fascinate me. They're such huge, fantastic and beautiful beasts. I wish dragons existed in real life. Draco the dragon is, without a doubt, the only really likable character in the movie. I don't care much about the others. The dragon is what makes this movie good enough. Without him, the movie would be nothing. The dragon is voiced by perhaps the most popular "James Bond" ever: Sean Connery. Bowen, the character portrayed by Dennis Quaid, is a good guy but undeniably arrogant and much self-proud and at the same time he's a bad guy for one reason: he kills all dragons because he believes that all dragons are evil. He wanted to kill Draco as well, but ends up forming a partnership and friendship with him and later realizes he's not evil. Draco was always a good dragon. He only killed those who wanted to harm him, in self-defense. What he didn't know was that giving half of his heart to Einon would be a terrible mistake. Einon falsely promised to be good and to follow the "old code" but in no time he showed what he really is: a brutal tyrant who only pretended to be Bowen's friend so that he could learn how to use the sword. The sad thing is that, in order to kill the bad guy, the dragon has to die as well. This happens because, as they share the same heart, they feel the same pains and all. Realizing this, the dragon doesn't just beg to be killed, he demands. Bowen doesn't have courage to do it at first and you can't blame him for that. That is a horrible thing to do. I'd like to know if there wasn't any other solution. You know, like, maybe the dragon could have found a way to recover the half of his heart that he gave to the villain. That way they wouldn't share the same pain and the evil guy could have been killed without the dragon having to die with him. Much of the filming occurred in the ancient ruins of Spi Castle, Slovakia. The result is beautiful sceneries and landscapes, perfect for an epic film. The action is set somewhere in the late 10th century in England, after the Saxons's conquest of that country. The dragon might have been created by computer, but he looks great and very real - so different from CGI "art". This level of perfection is comparable to the dinosaurs of 'Jurassic Park'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven but decent enough fantasy adventure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dragonheart is set during 948 A.D. & starts as a peasant uprising is defeated by evil King Freyne (Peter Hric) & his troops, in a show a strength King Freyne rides into their village to set it alight but it was a trap & King Freyne is killed in front of his teenage son Einon (Lee Oakes) who himself is badly injured. Einon's mother takes her son to a Dragon as a last resort in order to save his life, the Dragon gives Einon half of his own heart which saves the boy's life. Twelve years later & Einon (David Thewlis) has grown up to be just as much an evil tyrant as his father was who rules with brutality, his former friend, teacher & knight of the old order Bowen (Dennis Quaid) has turned Dragonslayer since he blames the Dragon's heart for polluting Einon & making him evil but decides to team up with a friendly Dragon he names Draco as well as feisty young woman Kara (Dina Meyer) who together lead a revolt against Einon, his troops & all he stands for... Directed by Rob Cohen this fantasy adventure is one of the few mainstream films featuring a Dragon & while it's nothing amazing I didn't think it was too bad overall. Dragon films are thin on the ground to be honest, there's Dragonslayer (1981), Dragonworld (1994) prior to Dragonheart with Dungeons & Dragons (2000), Reign of Fire (2002) & Eargon (2007) afterwards & none of the films mentioned have been that good or done that well at the box-office. The script feels a bit uneven, while on the one hand you have this whimsical child like fantasy of a friendly talking Dragon there's the other side of the film with a peasant uprising which does get quite violent with necks being broken, people being stabbed, set on fire & one bloke is hit in the nuts with a huge battle axe (ouch) & the two distinctly different tones didn't sit together that well for me. Basically the violence is a little too strong for younger children while the silly talking friendly Dragon is a little childish for anyone over the age of ten. That's not to say Dragonheart isn't an enjoyable film for what it is because it is, it moves along at a decent enough pace, the mismatched partners Bowen & Draco surely have one of the bizarrest on screen buddy buddy relationships ever & it entertains but I didn't think the violence & childish fantasy sat well together & it's a little repetitive & predictable with an ending that goes on for too long, sure the Dragon dies but have an extended scene set to orchestral music with various star shining in the sky is just a bit too much. Dragonheart was made early in the days of CGI computer effects & you can see a lot of time & effort went into them & they hold up really well even now. The battle scenes & fights are good if a little predictable (the good guy always wins & the bad guy gets it) & as a period piece the costumes, sets & props all look the part. Draco the Dragon voiced by Sean Connery looks great, he moves convincingly, flies convincingly & definitely has a personality. In fact Dragonheart was nominated for a Best Visual Effects Oscar along with Twister (1996) but both deservedly lost out to Independence Day (1996). With a supposed budget of about $57,000,000 this had a lot of money spent on it & I would have though most of it was spent on the CGI effects, filmed on location in Slovakia. The acting is OK but nothing special, Pete Postlethwaite doesn't get much to do, Dennis Quid is somewhat bland, it's nice to see Brian Thompson in a Hollywood film while Sir John Gielgud has a voice cameo as King Arthur. Dragonheart is a solid enough fantasy adventure that may be too violent for youngsters while a bit too childish for adults, I thought it was good but nothing amazing overall. Followed by the straight to video sequel Dragonheart: A New Beginning (2000).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sean Connery as a Dragon. :)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this movie is fairly old but I really only just heard of it recently and seen it. I normally don't like dragon movies but I really did enjoy this one. My opinion there's just not that many good dragon movies out there. Which is kind of sad since I do love dragons and medieval times as a whole. This movie is kind of slow but I've found it's good to have patience. I found the acting wasn't half bad and the plot was fairly decent. Plus I think this movie had one of the first CGI dragons and I actually thought they didn't do too bad a job. I'd recommend it and say give it a chance. Seems to be a family friendly movie for the most part. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the best fantasy movie, but okay nonetheless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the very few fantasy films that hit the screen and even then it is not as high as a movie like Willow is (though I should point out that I originally wrote this review in 1996). In fact, it is quite a low fantasy movie with the exception of the dragon, which creates some of the high fantasy in this movie. Straight out, it is an enjoyable movie to watch, but it goes little beyond that. A knight is training a prince in the art of honour and chivalry, but the prince has better ideas. When he sees his father wounded severely in a peasant uprising, he does not help him, but rather rips the crown from his hand. It is this event that shows us that the prince is, in his heart, evil. Unfortunately, when his is wounded, he is taken to a Dragon for help. The dragon gives him half of his heart and the boy survives. Unfortunately, all pain that the prince (now King) feels is felt by the dragon. The king does not change his ways, and the knight thus blames the dragon. The movie hasn't got a straight plot, but it isn't twisted either. What it focuses on is the knight, who first seeks to kill the dragon, then befriends him, and then decides to destroy the king's power, only to become king himself. The movie does have a tragic feel to it, as we soon come to know that the dragon is going to die because of his compassion, but it is not the tragedy where we can see the character constantly degrade to a point where he will die. In fact, even though we know he is going to die, it is not because of his actions, but because of the actions of the antagonist, and though we see a minor flag that an act of compassion at the beginning will lead to his downfall, we do not know enough to want to warn him away from doing it. The theology in the movie is quite dodgy as well. Though human theology is not looked at, dragon theology is. The way the dragon reaches heaven is my doing noteworthy and honourable deeds. Unfortunately, if those deeds backfire then the dragon is in big trouble. As such there is no certainty and as such we can be as good as we like, but never be guaranteed because our acts of goodness might backfire. What Christ offers is assurance. There is no being good because no amount of good deeds can get us on the right side of God. In fact by doing pure good deeds we are saying that we are not happy with the way God does things and want to do it ourselves, and thus offending God. As such it is a vicious circle for we attempt to be good, but by being good we are being offensive, which is bad. As such being good does not work, but rather by trusting what God has already done. By dying he has given us the option of accepting that our goodness will never be good enough and thus take Jesus' goodness for ourselves, and his resurrection tells us that he had the authority to do it. As for the movie, it is okay, and pleasant to watch as a fantasy movie, but beyond that it is really not all that much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can someone say... GENIUS?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Miller (miller.jmiller.jason@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie that sins it? Literally, nothing. The acting is great, the storyline is phenomenal, the humor thrives, and the special effects do not disappoint. The storyline portrays a young Prince with a tyrannic father, who dies. The boy is injured to near death, and a dragon gives half his heart to the boy. The boy himself becomes a tyrant. A knight vows to kill all dragons until he kills the one who gave the heart. But, not all is what it seems... This is definitely a movie for those whom enjoy a good, hearty film with a moral at its center. It is even a good family film, depending on your parenting methods (which one should hope are decent and logical). If you need a movie to kick back and relax to, watch on a snowy or rainy day, or just because, this is a great movie. The storyline lacks no potential; utilizing all elements and keeping the audience's attention. The chosen actors for the characters was ingenious and well planned. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. I promise, if you approach this movie with a joyous attitude, or even a skeptical one, you will enjoy it. ~~Go forth and review movies~~
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood style medieval adventure fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hduck1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sickeningly mawkish story. Typical Hollywood. Clownish and idiotic dialog. An attempt to interject humor in an otherwise adventurous tale. Compare this production to the British series, Merlin. The latter had better dialog, better storyline, equally good special effects. The only drawbacks I found in Merlin were with regard to casting, but Colin Morgan made an ideal young Merlin for me. John Hurt's voice made a more believable dragon than Sean Connery's voice. These fantasies are fun to watch when they are well made. However, I am always aware that the dragon is the biblical symbol of Satan. Therefore to make a noble beast of the creature is mockery of the Bible. "Merlin" did not exactly make the dragon a good creature - without the control of a "dragonlord" it became entirely destructive. It seems ironic to make any kind of pact with a dragon; it is literally making a pact with the devil. But as I say, the fantasy is fun when well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great dragon flick with a good charm to it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, how I love Dragonheart. This was made during the dawn of CGI. After Terminator 2 and Jurassic Park pushed the boundaries of special effects to a whole new level, Universal decided to try something different with computer effects and storytelling. The result was this lovable film that has, dare I say it, a burning passion. The story of a dragon (Sean Connery) and a dragon slayer (Dennis Quaid) becoming friends and teaming up against a tyrannical king is unforgettable. This movie is just full of comedy, action, and drama and the cast, especially Sean Connery, deliver terrific performances. It's not often you see a dragon movie like this and with that, it should be commended. I give this movie a 7 for entertainment value and a fiery extra point for the effort in which this was made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Talking Dragon Makes This Movie Corny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    airwolf-121-720419
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I did enjoy this movie for what it is, I would have to say that this movie was corny. Corny because we have a friendly talking dragon voiced by Sean Connery. Plus, the acting of the evil boy king was just really cheesy in my opinion. Aren't dragons supposed to be mythical creatures we are supposed to fear? If so, then why are they portrayed as a cuddle bear we can share our most inner thoughts while other movies portray dragons as something to fear? The only reason why I am giving this movie a 3 is that Dennis Quaid is in this movie. While I also like Connery, his part just didn't sit well with me. So even the actors couldn't revive this very corny movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable with a sense of humour added in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like fantasy films and especially the ones set in medi evil times with dragons and sword fights and beautiful landscapes etc. That isn't to say all the ones that have these are necessarily good films but it is a world we can only imagine. Dragonheart starts off a little slow, but still interesting that sets up the plot of the film. Luckily it starts getting really enjoyable when the Dragon comes into it who becomes an ally of Bowen (Dennis Quaid) who is out to settle a personal vendetta against a Dragon who has turned a student of his into a corrupt ruler in his role as King Einon (David Thewlis in a very convincing role as an arrogant ruler). What makes this film appealing is the fact that the Dragon named Draco (voiced by Sean Connery) is given a lot of personality and hence is able to bond with Bowen. It adds a lot to the sense of humour and the film doesn't become too dark or a film that is based purely on revenge themes. The visual effects were also decent and for what this film is worth, it feels like a B grade film but looks like an A Grade film with the good performances, decent visuals and good cinematography of the landscapes. The production design is pretty impressive too. It still has flaws. The action scenes needed better music score to make it a bit more exciting and dramatic and the story itself is a bit clich&eacute; in some respects. Julie Christie doesn't have much to do in her role which is a shame considering she had a good presence in the beginning then was sort of here now and then later on. Dennis Quaid is convincing as a boorish Dragon Slayer earning a living as a slayer and is a likable character. What is also good is that there is no silly romantic subplot which I suspected would have been thrown in which would have made the plot even more clich&eacute; but it avoided that even though I thought there were going to be hints at it. So I was surprised to find myself enjoying this. Sometimes films like these that you can just watch and just have a good time are what you need when you don't want to think too much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece of Fantasy Storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omega
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dennis Quaid is Knight of the Old Code Bowen, a strong and grand hearted man that in hope of saving his fatally wounded pupil and future king Einon, takes him to the lair of a Dragon that, in the hope of making him a true king, unlike his father, gives him the life again by taking a part of his heart and putting it into him. Bowen, upon this action of benevolence, promises the Dragon his services, as the creature himself remembers him that Einon must stay true to his promise of being a good Ruler. As years pass, Einon reveals himself to be an even worse King than his father was, treating his reign like the worst kind of Tyrant would. Bowen, believing that the Dragon was the cause, declares vengeance on all Dragons, only to come at the situation that only one remained (precisely the one that gave half of his heart to Einon ). The two make an improbable alliance that would bring an advantage to both. DragonHeart has always been one of those memorable films that just never fail to amaze, with the feelings they are able to transmit to the viewer. One moment you laugh, the next you are broken in tears. Few films are able to do this to the viewer - And DragonHeart strikes as excellent in this. The film features a strong cast that pulls out exceptionally good performances - Dennis Quaid is of course a strong actor and highlights very well the nature of his character. One of the turning points of the film is the delusion of Bowen, that has lived all his life on his ideals, and training his pupil, is forced to see him exactly, or more like, worse than the last king, his father, was. Dina Meyer represents perfectly the brave, rebel woman Kara is. The most memorable human character though is without a doubt Brother Gilbert, played by the late Pete Postlethwaite (may he rest in peace), the comic relief of the film that never ceases to bring a smile. Sean Connery is the voice for the Dragon, Draco, who is at turn created through the use of Computer Graphics by the artists of Industrial Light & Magic, known for their work on films such as Jurassic Park, who never cease to do their job none less than amazing, as Draco still holds up very well today. Connery's voice perfectly fits the character and makes it even more memorable. Draco is a noble hearted, gentle figure and the best character of the film. His death is one of those moments in a film that you quite never forget, for its strength in presentation, tear shredding score and incredibly sad yet heart warming combination of image and words. DragonHeart is truly a beautiful, old school fantasy Masterpiece and deserves a lot of praising for what it is, and the humanitary message it represents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than those overrated 'The Lord of the Rings' films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Dragonheart' is strangely underrated. Considering the unbelievable popularity of 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy (even today), we could ask ourselves why 'Dragonheart' didn't reach half of that fame. However, being underrated has a good side, as most underrated and less known films are far superior than the eternally popular and overrated ones. 'Dragonheart' is an okay movie, worthy for dragon lovers. I am a dragon lover myself. Dragons fascinate me. They're such huge, fantastic and beautiful beasts. I wish dragons existed in real life. Draco the dragon is, without a doubt, the only really likable character in the movie. I don't care much about the others. The dragon is what makes this movie good enough. Without him, the movie would be nothing. The dragon is voiced by perhaps the most popular "James Bond" ever: Sean Connery. Bowen, the character portrayed by Dennis Quaid, is a good guy but undeniably arrogant and much self-proud and at the same time he's a bad guy for one reason: he kills all dragons because he believes that all dragons are evil. He wanted to kill Draco as well, but ends up forming a partnership and friendship with him and later realizes he's not evil. Draco was always a good dragon. He only killed those who wanted to harm him, in self-defense. What he didn't know was that giving half of his heart to Einon would be a terrible mistake. Einon falsely promised to be good and to follow the "old code" but in no time he showed what he really is: a brutal tyrant who only pretended to be Bowen's friend so that he could learn how to use the sword. The sad thing is that, in order to kill the bad guy, the dragon has to die as well. This happens because, as they share the same heart, they feel the same pains and all. Realizing this, the dragon doesn't just beg to be killed, he demands. Bowen doesn't have courage to do it at first and you can't blame him for that. That is a horrible thing to do. I'd like to know if there wasn't any other solution. You know, like, maybe the dragon could have found a way to recover the half of his heart that he gave to the villain. That way they wouldn't share the same pain and the evil guy could have been killed without the dragon having to die with him. Much of the filming occurred in the ancient ruins of Spi Castle, Slovakia. The result is beautiful sceneries and landscapes, perfect for an epic film. The action is set somewhere in the late 10th century in England, after the Saxons's conquest of that country. The dragon might have been created by computer, but he looks great and very real - so different from CGI "art". This level of perfection is comparable to the dinosaurs of 'Jurassic Park'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven but decent enough fantasy adventure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dragonheart is set during 948 A.D. & starts as a peasant uprising is defeated by evil King Freyne (Peter Hric) & his troops, in a show a strength King Freyne rides into their village to set it alight but it was a trap & King Freyne is killed in front of his teenage son Einon (Lee Oakes) who himself is badly injured. Einon's mother takes her son to a Dragon as a last resort in order to save his life, the Dragon gives Einon half of his own heart which saves the boy's life. Twelve years later & Einon (David Thewlis) has grown up to be just as much an evil tyrant as his father was who rules with brutality, his former friend, teacher & knight of the old order Bowen (Dennis Quaid) has turned Dragonslayer since he blames the Dragon's heart for polluting Einon & making him evil but decides to team up with a friendly Dragon he names Draco as well as feisty young woman Kara (Dina Meyer) who together lead a revolt against Einon, his troops & all he stands for... Directed by Rob Cohen this fantasy adventure is one of the few mainstream films featuring a Dragon & while it's nothing amazing I didn't think it was too bad overall. Dragon films are thin on the ground to be honest, there's Dragonslayer (1981), Dragonworld (1994) prior to Dragonheart with Dungeons & Dragons (2000), Reign of Fire (2002) & Eargon (2007) afterwards & none of the films mentioned have been that good or done that well at the box-office. The script feels a bit uneven, while on the one hand you have this whimsical child like fantasy of a friendly talking Dragon there's the other side of the film with a peasant uprising which does get quite violent with necks being broken, people being stabbed, set on fire & one bloke is hit in the nuts with a huge battle axe (ouch) & the two distinctly different tones didn't sit together that well for me. Basically the violence is a little too strong for younger children while the silly talking friendly Dragon is a little childish for anyone over the age of ten. That's not to say Dragonheart isn't an enjoyable film for what it is because it is, it moves along at a decent enough pace, the mismatched partners Bowen & Draco surely have one of the bizarrest on screen buddy buddy relationships ever & it entertains but I didn't think the violence & childish fantasy sat well together & it's a little repetitive & predictable with an ending that goes on for too long, sure the Dragon dies but have an extended scene set to orchestral music with various star shining in the sky is just a bit too much. Dragonheart was made early in the days of CGI computer effects & you can see a lot of time & effort went into them & they hold up really well even now. The battle scenes & fights are good if a little predictable (the good guy always wins & the bad guy gets it) & as a period piece the costumes, sets & props all look the part. Draco the Dragon voiced by Sean Connery looks great, he moves convincingly, flies convincingly & definitely has a personality. In fact Dragonheart was nominated for a Best Visual Effects Oscar along with Twister (1996) but both deservedly lost out to Independence Day (1996). With a supposed budget of about $57,000,000 this had a lot of money spent on it & I would have though most of it was spent on the CGI effects, filmed on location in Slovakia. The acting is OK but nothing special, Pete Postlethwaite doesn't get much to do, Dennis Quid is somewhat bland, it's nice to see Brian Thompson in a Hollywood film while Sir John Gielgud has a voice cameo as King Arthur. Dragonheart is a solid enough fantasy adventure that may be too violent for youngsters while a bit too childish for adults, I thought it was good but nothing amazing overall. Followed by the straight to video sequel Dragonheart: A New Beginning (2000).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sean Connery as a Dragon. :)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this movie is fairly old but I really only just heard of it recently and seen it. I normally don't like dragon movies but I really did enjoy this one. My opinion there's just not that many good dragon movies out there. Which is kind of sad since I do love dragons and medieval times as a whole. This movie is kind of slow but I've found it's good to have patience. I found the acting wasn't half bad and the plot was fairly decent. Plus I think this movie had one of the first CGI dragons and I actually thought they didn't do too bad a job. I'd recommend it and say give it a chance. Seems to be a family friendly movie for the most part. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the best fantasy movie, but okay nonetheless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the very few fantasy films that hit the screen and even then it is not as high as a movie like Willow is (though I should point out that I originally wrote this review in 1996). In fact, it is quite a low fantasy movie with the exception of the dragon, which creates some of the high fantasy in this movie. Straight out, it is an enjoyable movie to watch, but it goes little beyond that. A knight is training a prince in the art of honour and chivalry, but the prince has better ideas. When he sees his father wounded severely in a peasant uprising, he does not help him, but rather rips the crown from his hand. It is this event that shows us that the prince is, in his heart, evil. Unfortunately, when his is wounded, he is taken to a Dragon for help. The dragon gives him half of his heart and the boy survives. Unfortunately, all pain that the prince (now King) feels is felt by the dragon. The king does not change his ways, and the knight thus blames the dragon. The movie hasn't got a straight plot, but it isn't twisted either. What it focuses on is the knight, who first seeks to kill the dragon, then befriends him, and then decides to destroy the king's power, only to become king himself. The movie does have a tragic feel to it, as we soon come to know that the dragon is going to die because of his compassion, but it is not the tragedy where we can see the character constantly degrade to a point where he will die. In fact, even though we know he is going to die, it is not because of his actions, but because of the actions of the antagonist, and though we see a minor flag that an act of compassion at the beginning will lead to his downfall, we do not know enough to want to warn him away from doing it. The theology in the movie is quite dodgy as well. Though human theology is not looked at, dragon theology is. The way the dragon reaches heaven is my doing noteworthy and honourable deeds. Unfortunately, if those deeds backfire then the dragon is in big trouble. As such there is no certainty and as such we can be as good as we like, but never be guaranteed because our acts of goodness might backfire. What Christ offers is assurance. There is no being good because no amount of good deeds can get us on the right side of God. In fact by doing pure good deeds we are saying that we are not happy with the way God does things and want to do it ourselves, and thus offending God. As such it is a vicious circle for we attempt to be good, but by being good we are being offensive, which is bad. As such being good does not work, but rather by trusting what God has already done. By dying he has given us the option of accepting that our goodness will never be good enough and thus take Jesus' goodness for ourselves, and his resurrection tells us that he had the authority to do it. As for the movie, it is okay, and pleasant to watch as a fantasy movie, but beyond that it is really not all that much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Can someone say... GENIUS?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Miller (miller.jmiller.jason@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie that sins it? Literally, nothing. The acting is great, the storyline is phenomenal, the humor thrives, and the special effects do not disappoint. The storyline portrays a young Prince with a tyrannic father, who dies. The boy is injured to near death, and a dragon gives half his heart to the boy. The boy himself becomes a tyrant. A knight vows to kill all dragons until he kills the one who gave the heart. But, not all is what it seems... This is definitely a movie for those whom enjoy a good, hearty film with a moral at its center. It is even a good family film, depending on your parenting methods (which one should hope are decent and logical). If you need a movie to kick back and relax to, watch on a snowy or rainy day, or just because, this is a great movie. The storyline lacks no potential; utilizing all elements and keeping the audience's attention. The chosen actors for the characters was ingenious and well planned. Whoever wrote the screenplay did an astounding job. I promise, if you approach this movie with a joyous attitude, or even a skeptical one, you will enjoy it. ~~Go forth and review movies~~
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood style medieval adventure fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hduck1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sickeningly mawkish story. Typical Hollywood. Clownish and idiotic dialog. An attempt to interject humor in an otherwise adventurous tale. Compare this production to the British series, Merlin. The latter had better dialog, better storyline, equally good special effects. The only drawbacks I found in Merlin were with regard to casting, but Colin Morgan made an ideal young Merlin for me. John Hurt's voice made a more believable dragon than Sean Connery's voice. These fantasies are fun to watch when they are well made. However, I am always aware that the dragon is the biblical symbol of Satan. Therefore to make a noble beast of the creature is mockery of the Bible. "Merlin" did not exactly make the dragon a good creature - without the control of a "dragonlord" it became entirely destructive. It seems ironic to make any kind of pact with a dragon; it is literally making a pact with the devil. But as I say, the fantasy is fun when well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great dragon flick with a good charm to it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kevinxirau
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, how I love Dragonheart. This was made during the dawn of CGI. After Terminator 2 and Jurassic Park pushed the boundaries of special effects to a whole new level, Universal decided to try something different with computer effects and storytelling. The result was this lovable film that has, dare I say it, a burning passion. The story of a dragon (Sean Connery) and a dragon slayer (Dennis Quaid) becoming friends and teaming up against a tyrannical king is unforgettable. This movie is just full of comedy, action, and drama and the cast, especially Sean Connery, deliver terrific performances. It's not often you see a dragon movie like this and with that, it should be commended. I give this movie a 7 for entertainment value and a fiery extra point for the effort in which this was made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Talking Dragon Makes This Movie Corny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    airwolf-121-720419
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I did enjoy this movie for what it is, I would have to say that this movie was corny. Corny because we have a friendly talking dragon voiced by Sean Connery. Plus, the acting of the evil boy king was just really cheesy in my opinion. Aren't dragons supposed to be mythical creatures we are supposed to fear? If so, then why are they portrayed as a cuddle bear we can share our most inner thoughts while other movies portray dragons as something to fear? The only reason why I am giving this movie a 3 is that Dennis Quaid is in this movie. While I also like Connery, his part just didn't sit well with me. So even the actors couldn't revive this very corny movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly enjoyable with a sense of humour added in
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like fantasy films and especially the ones set in medi evil times with dragons and sword fights and beautiful landscapes etc. That isn't to say all the ones that have these are necessarily good films but it is a world we can only imagine. Dragonheart starts off a little slow, but still interesting that sets up the plot of the film. Luckily it starts getting really enjoyable when the Dragon comes into it who becomes an ally of Bowen (Dennis Quaid) who is out to settle a personal vendetta against a Dragon who has turned a student of his into a corrupt ruler in his role as King Einon (David Thewlis in a very convincing role as an arrogant ruler). What makes this film appealing is the fact that the Dragon named Draco (voiced by Sean Connery) is given a lot of personality and hence is able to bond with Bowen. It adds a lot to the sense of humour and the film doesn't become too dark or a film that is based purely on revenge themes. The visual effects were also decent and for what this film is worth, it feels like a B grade film but looks like an A Grade film with the good performances, decent visuals and good cinematography of the landscapes. The production design is pretty impressive too. It still has flaws. The action scenes needed better music score to make it a bit more exciting and dramatic and the story itself is a bit clich&eacute; in some respects. Julie Christie doesn't have much to do in her role which is a shame considering she had a good presence in the beginning then was sort of here now and then later on. Dennis Quaid is convincing as a boorish Dragon Slayer earning a living as a slayer and is a likable character. What is also good is that there is no silly romantic subplot which I suspected would have been thrown in which would have made the plot even more clich&eacute; but it avoided that even though I thought there were going to be hints at it. So I was surprised to find myself enjoying this. Sometimes films like these that you can just watch and just have a good time are what you need when you don't want to think too much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece of Fantasy Storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Omega
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dennis Quaid is Knight of the Old Code Bowen, a strong and grand hearted man that in hope of saving his fatally wounded pupil and future king Einon, takes him to the lair of a Dragon that, in the hope of making him a true king, unlike his father, gives him the life again by taking a part of his heart and putting it into him. Bowen, upon this action of benevolence, promises the Dragon his services, as the creature himself remembers him that Einon must stay true to his promise of being a good Ruler. As years pass, Einon reveals himself to be an even worse King than his father was, treating his reign like the worst kind of Tyrant would. Bowen, believing that the Dragon was the cause, declares vengeance on all Dragons, only to come at the situation that only one remained (precisely the one that gave half of his heart to Einon ). The two make an improbable alliance that would bring an advantage to both. DragonHeart has always been one of those memorable films that just never fail to amaze, with the feelings they are able to transmit to the viewer. One moment you laugh, the next you are broken in tears. Few films are able to do this to the viewer - And DragonHeart strikes as excellent in this. The film features a strong cast that pulls out exceptionally good performances - Dennis Quaid is of course a strong actor and highlights very well the nature of his character. One of the turning points of the film is the delusion of Bowen, that has lived all his life on his ideals, and training his pupil, is forced to see him exactly, or more like, worse than the last king, his father, was. Dina Meyer represents perfectly the brave, rebel woman Kara is. The most memorable human character though is without a doubt Brother Gilbert, played by the late Pete Postlethwaite (may he rest in peace), the comic relief of the film that never ceases to bring a smile. Sean Connery is the voice for the Dragon, Draco, who is at turn created through the use of Computer Graphics by the artists of Industrial Light & Magic, known for their work on films such as Jurassic Park, who never cease to do their job none less than amazing, as Draco still holds up very well today. Connery's voice perfectly fits the character and makes it even more memorable. Draco is a noble hearted, gentle figure and the best character of the film. His death is one of those moments in a film that you quite never forget, for its strength in presentation, tear shredding score and incredibly sad yet heart warming combination of image and words. DragonHeart is truly a beautiful, old school fantasy Masterpiece and deserves a lot of praising for what it is, and the humanitary message it represents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than those overrated 'The Lord of the Rings' films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Atreyu_II
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Dragonheart' is strangely underrated. Considering the unbelievable popularity of 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy (even today), we could ask ourselves why 'Dragonheart' didn't reach half of that fame. However, being underrated has a good side, as most underrated and less known films are far superior than the eternally popular and overrated ones. 'Dragonheart' is an okay movie, worthy for dragon lovers. I am a dragon lover myself. Dragons fascinate me. They're such huge, fantastic and beautiful beasts. I wish dragons existed in real life. Draco the dragon is, without a doubt, the only really likable character in the movie. I don't care much about the others. The dragon is what makes this movie good enough. Without him, the movie would be nothing. The dragon is voiced by perhaps the most popular "James Bond" ever: Sean Connery. Bowen, the character portrayed by Dennis Quaid, is a good guy but undeniably arrogant and much self-proud and at the same time he's a bad guy for one reason: he kills all dragons because he believes that all dragons are evil. He wanted to kill Draco as well, but ends up forming a partnership and friendship with him and later realizes he's not evil. Draco was always a good dragon. He only killed those who wanted to harm him, in self-defense. What he didn't know was that giving half of his heart to Einon would be a terrible mistake. Einon falsely promised to be good and to follow the "old code" but in no time he showed what he really is: a brutal tyrant who only pretended to be Bowen's friend so that he could learn how to use the sword. The sad thing is that, in order to kill the bad guy, the dragon has to die as well. This happens because, as they share the same heart, they feel the same pains and all. Realizing this, the dragon doesn't just beg to be killed, he demands. Bowen doesn't have courage to do it at first and you can't blame him for that. That is a horrible thing to do. I'd like to know if there wasn't any other solution. You know, like, maybe the dragon could have found a way to recover the half of his heart that he gave to the villain. That way they wouldn't share the same pain and the evil guy could have been killed without the dragon having to die with him. Much of the filming occurred in the ancient ruins of Spi Castle, Slovakia. The result is beautiful sceneries and landscapes, perfect for an epic film. The action is set somewhere in the late 10th century in England, after the Saxons's conquest of that country. The dragon might have been created by computer, but he looks great and very real - so different from CGI "art". This level of perfection is comparable to the dinosaurs of 'Jurassic Park'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven but decent enough fantasy adventure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dragonheart is set during 948 A.D. & starts as a peasant uprising is defeated by evil King Freyne (Peter Hric) & his troops, in a show a strength King Freyne rides into their village to set it alight but it was a trap & King Freyne is killed in front of his teenage son Einon (Lee Oakes) who himself is badly injured. Einon's mother takes her son to a Dragon as a last resort in order to save his life, the Dragon gives Einon half of his own heart which saves the boy's life. Twelve years later & Einon (David Thewlis) has grown up to be just as much an evil tyrant as his father was who rules with brutality, his former friend, teacher & knight of the old order Bowen (Dennis Quaid) has turned Dragonslayer since he blames the Dragon's heart for polluting Einon & making him evil but decides to team up with a friendly Dragon he names Draco as well as feisty young woman Kara (Dina Meyer) who together lead a revolt against Einon, his troops & all he stands for... Directed by Rob Cohen this fantasy adventure is one of the few mainstream films featuring a Dragon & while it's nothing amazing I didn't think it was too bad overall. Dragon films are thin on the ground to be honest, there's Dragonslayer (1981), Dragonworld (1994) prior to Dragonheart with Dungeons & Dragons (2000), Reign of Fire (2002) & Eargon (2007) afterwards & none of the films mentioned have been that good or done that well at the box-office. The script feels a bit uneven, while on the one hand you have this whimsical child like fantasy of a friendly talking Dragon there's the other side of the film with a peasant uprising which does get quite violent with necks being broken, people being stabbed, set on fire & one bloke is hit in the nuts with a huge battle axe (ouch) & the two distinctly different tones didn't sit together that well for me. Basically the violence is a little too strong for younger children while the silly talking friendly Dragon is a little childish for anyone over the age of ten. That's not to say Dragonheart isn't an enjoyable film for what it is because it is, it moves along at a decent enough pace, the mismatched partners Bowen & Draco surely have one of the bizarrest on screen buddy buddy relationships ever & it entertains but I didn't think the violence & childish fantasy sat well together & it's a little repetitive & predictable with an ending that goes on for too long, sure the Dragon dies but have an extended scene set to orchestral music with various star shining in the sky is just a bit too much. Dragonheart was made early in the days of CGI computer effects & you can see a lot of time & effort went into them & they hold up really well even now. The battle scenes & fights are good if a little predictable (the good guy always wins & the bad guy gets it) & as a period piece the costumes, sets & props all look the part. Draco the Dragon voiced by Sean Connery looks great, he moves convincingly, flies convincingly & definitely has a personality. In fact Dragonheart was nominated for a Best Visual Effects Oscar along with Twister (1996) but both deservedly lost out to Independence Day (1996). With a supposed budget of about $57,000,000 this had a lot of money spent on it & I would have though most of it was spent on the CGI effects, filmed on location in Slovakia. The acting is OK but nothing special, Pete Postlethwaite doesn't get much to do, Dennis Quid is somewhat bland, it's nice to see Brian Thompson in a Hollywood film while Sir John Gielgud has a voice cameo as King Arthur. Dragonheart is a solid enough fantasy adventure that may be too violent for youngsters while a bit too childish for adults, I thought it was good but nothing amazing overall. Followed by the straight to video sequel Dragonheart: A New Beginning (2000).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sean Connery as a Dragon. :)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anna N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this movie is fairly old but I really only just heard of it recently and seen it. I normally don't like dragon movies but I really did enjoy this one. My opinion there's just not that many good dragon movies out there. Which is kind of sad since I do love dragons and medieval times as a whole. This movie is kind of slow but I've found it's good to have patience. I found the acting wasn't half bad and the plot was fairly decent. Plus I think this movie had one of the first CGI dragons and I actually thought they didn't do too bad a job. I'd recommend it and say give it a chance. Seems to be a family friendly movie for the most part. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
