<filme>
 <id>
  482
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0053291
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1959
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Quanto Mais Quente Melhor
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  When two musicians witness a mob hit, they flee the state in an all female band disguised as women, but further complications set in.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  When two Chicago musicians, Joe and Jerry, witness the the St. Valentine's Day massacre, they want to get out of town and get away from the gangster responsible, Spats Colombo. They're desperate to get a gig out of town but the only job they know of is in an all-girl band heading to Florida. They show up at the train station as Josephine and Daphne, the replacement saxophone and bass players. They certainly enjoy being around the girls, especially Sugar Kane Kowalczyk who sings and plays the ukulele. Joe in particular sets out to woo her while Jerry/Daphne is wooed by a millionaire, Osgood Fielding III. Mayhem ensues as the two men try to keep their true identities hidden and Spats Colombo and his crew show up for a meeting with several other crime lords.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   band
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   musician
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   witness
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   massacre
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   all girl band
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Billy Wilder
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Billy Wilder
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   I.A.L. Diamond
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Marilyn Monroe
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tony Curtis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jack Lemmon
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nell Ryder
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some Like It Hot is a movie about sex, but pretends to be about crime and greed. It's underlying cynicism is overruled when genuine emotion strikes the characters, blindsiding them. Tony Curtis' character thinks he only wants sex, and Marylin Monroe's character thinks she only wants money. They're both surprised to find that they end up desiring each other more. This has been my favourite movie since childhood, I used to watch it every week and could watch it a millions times over. My favourite character is Jack Lemmon as I think he's one of the best comedic actors of all time. My favourite scene is where Jack Lemmon dances the tango with his suitor, Osgood. He later daydreams about whether a honeymoon on the French Riviera or the more traditional Niagara Falls would be best, before he has to break the news to Osgood that he's a man, which leads to the best line in the movie: 'Well, Nobody's Perfect!'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The highly regarded Billy Wilder comedy Some Like It Hot relies on an original, really offbeat and audacious plot for the time (1959), where savoury and incredibly well written dialogues fly for two hours. The adventures of these two travesties are very enjoyable to follow, and the Curtis-Lemmon did a perfect job, a notch above Marylin Monroe even though she is coherent with her character. Overall, the comical potential has been well exploited, even if, due to the changes in mores, what seemed improbable and funny back then doesn't shock anymore. Moreover, the script sometimes goes through slow passages with endless scenes as the one on the boat, and one could question the purpose of the musical interludes as they appear more like promotional parts for Monroe. But, despite these few flaws, Some Like It Hot remains a sure bet in the comical genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder's Some Like It Hot is still among the greatest movie comedies, if not the greatest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only seen this movie once before on the late show when I lived in Jacksonville, FL, with my aunts. I remember thinking this was pretty funny. Now that I've watched this on DVD with my mom (who had never seen this before), it's even more funny than I remembered it. I mean, seeing Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon try to convincingly play women in order to escape some gangsters, especially in front of the actual females they're surrounded with, can be pretty funny since they don't really look anything similar to them but I guess the fact that many of them do drink might have been a factor. And then there's Marilyn Monroe, looking as luminous as one expects but also one of the most charismatic of actresses especially considering her off-screen troubles that seemed to affect everyone involved including director Billy Wilder. Wilder and I.A.L. Diamond's screenplay just cackles with such great lines. Oh, and I also loved Joe E. Brown's performance as the millionaire that falls for Lemmon's character. His seemed to be the best one here, even better than Lemmon's who was the only player to get an Oscar nomination. And while George Raft and Pat O'Brien played their typed roles of gangster and cop, they played them well enough to still deliver the goods. In summary, I'm not sure if I agree with the AFI listing this as No. 1 among great comedies, but Some Like It Hot is still one of the most entertaining of them, that's for sure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average in almost every way...don't stone me!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I am a student of Political history and could recite many a Marilyn Monroe fact or conspiracy theory to you, I had yet to see her in one of her iconic films. So finally I sat down to watch what is generally considered one of the greatest film comedies of all time. That is a lot to live up to and I didn't realize just how popular the film was until I logged on here to write this review. 8.4 on IMDb?! Now, please don't get me wrong...I enjoyed this movie. It was fun and wild and absolutely I can see how and why it pushed the limits back then. I'm not sure I have seen so many analogies and innuendos in one film. They were being shoved down your throat like a case of mistaken identity on Three's Company. The first analogy or clever innuendo is a chuckle and not much else but after the twentieth...it gets tired. The setting of 1929 makes some pretty intense action/gangster scenes even for the time. It was almost shocking to watch it now and that was kind of a neat mix to the comedy. Some of the comedic moments are almost dark in nature. I was surprised that I didn't really feel a lot of the humour had homophobic undertones which I thought would be a certainty. If anything, the very last gag in the film is almost pro-gay in some ways and it was definitely worth a laugh. Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon were so young!! Curtis was handsome and fun and delivered his comedic moments perfectly. Lemmon was quirky and fun and certainly has legendary comedic timing. The two of them together are just awesome. A buddy film like this requires great chemistry and there is nothing short in their chemistry together. They seem like a bit of an odd-couple but they work great together. The stunning beauty of Marilyn Monroe and her sheer raw charisma on screen cannot be denied. When she first appears and every subsequent appearance you are just mesmerized. She's actually a much actress that I anticipated and her role is fun and breezy and perfectly performed by her. The chemistry between her and Curtis and even her and Lemmon is lacking. I didn't feel nearly any sparks between her and Curtis and that's really unfortunate. Romance is an important part of the film and it doesn't really fit well. George Raft is the perfect cookie cutter gangster. He is nothing more or less than the stereotypical "Boss" we would expect from a gangster flick. Same for his crew as well. They could have been lifted right from Dick Tracey. Dave Barry was a great supporting actor and gave some great comedy as the angry but stumbling Beinstock. Joan Shawlee is also good as the band leader and mother hen Sweet Sue. I also really enjoyed the campy and fun character played by Joe E. Brown as the man who falls for Lemmon's Daphne. I have no doubt that to see the true brilliance behind the film you would have to look at from the perspective of 1959 films and the time period. The movie is set in 1929 and I couldn't help but notice the inconsistencies in the timing. Its small things but certain products that weren't available in 1929 (Cheese Whiz for one) or just certain dialect. Its a small thing but worth noting nonetheless. The comedy is definitely balanced out by the more violent scenes in the film so it almost turns out a darker comedy that doesn't always fit the slapstick tone and concept of the movie. It is a fun movie and certainly is a classic that shows up on many lists of being a top film. I don't necessarily agree with that but who am I to deny a film that has stood up to 50+ years. For me, it didn't floor me but it was entertaining. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic, charming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Linus (Linus_92@hotmail.se)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm usually not much for old comedies, although i have to say, this one was truly original, cheerful characters that created the comic impression throughout the movie, which made me grin all the way through. Tony Curtis is an entertaining actor to observe, pulling off three different characters in one movie is nothing more but impressive and shows that he is a very adjustable person. Marilyn Monroe who played 'Sugar Kane Kowalczyk', to me seemed to be very suitable for the character itself, she lived through the character as if it was a part of herself. Billy Wilder took such good care of this film, able to display excitement, love and comedy all together, the synchronization among all the cast on what could have been very chaotic couple of scenes if not done correctly, but manage to control this exceptionally. The shooting location and the backgrounds gave it a very comfortable awareness which made it feel like a cup of hot coco on a cold winter day. This classic comedy gives us a perspective about some of the joy and yet, the difficulty of being a women, it's displayed positively towards the audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cutting Edge, 1959
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No need to recap the plot nor echo consensus points. The movie is perfectly cast. The chemistry between Lemmon and Curtis is perfect. Add a wide-eyed Monroe and it's an outstanding comedy trifecta. Still, seeing the film again after first release, I wonder how much hilarity audiences of today find in the movie's sexual innuendo. After all, the premise was cutting-edge in 1959 when the word 'panties' in Anatomy of a Murder raised a ruckus with enforcers of the film code. In that same year, just watching from a theatre seat during the cross-dressing, plus the many innuendo scenes was like being a daring part of taboo-breaking. The bawdy subtext was a totally new experience in the commercial movies. Thus the amusement factor was heightened by novel comedic material, previously forbidden. But I wonder about today's younger audiences for whom the innuendo may even seem a little tame, given today's almost non-existent standards. In my little book, it's still a funny movie, thanks mainly to an expert cast, but hardly an all- time topper as it is in some ratings lists. Besides, it's the only comedy I can think of to work its way around not just one, but two, on-screen massacres!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good not great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Highly acclaimed as one of the best comedies in Hollywood history, Some Like It Hot has a neat comedic approach that was sure a topic on every gossiper's agenda in the late '50s. It's a funny little movie with an original storyline. Some Like It Hot utilizes it's beautiful costumes to their full potential, it's a beautiful film to look at it. The three stars are all very serviceable in their roles. Jack Lemon is the stand out owning the character and never looking back. Marilyn Monroe is deliciously sweet in the centerpiece of the film of beauty and sexuality. This is widely considered to be her career best, its a shame she missed an Oscar nomination for it. Tony Curtis does a fine job as well. My favorite scene is the legendary "I Wanna Be Loved By You" song lives up to the hype, it's a wonderful scene. My problem with Some Like It Hot is the lack of emotional investment I felt for the story or the characters. I didn't quite get the smacking wave of brilliance others have lived with Some Like It Hot. It's still a good movie, but I didn't think it was a great one. Rating: 7/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder shows his range, and proves again his writing chops
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy about cross-dressing is a surprising choice of subject matter for Billy Wilder, who is best known for his film noir morality tales. But his knack for multi-layered dialogue and sardonic humor work just as well here as in his more serious films. The premise of "Some Like it Hot" is absurd, and if there were no genuine laughs then the behavior of Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon's characters might easily come across as obnoxious and offensive. But there are laughs, and they come so rapidly and so often at the expense of the lead characters that these pitfalls are averted. Lemmon and Marilyn Monroe are so well cast that they are effectively playing themselves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandar_Wagner
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong I think this is a great movie. It's just that when AFI puts out a list of the 100 greatest comedies of all-time and this is #1 I have to disagree. It's the cross dressing comedy that started them all mix that with Marilyn Monroe and you got a classic. The problem I had with this so called masterpiece is that there were hardly any twists or turns along the way. Every time you thought something was going to happen, everything went find and by the time something actually happened, you just don't care anymore. Maybe that's the art, maybe I just don't get it but Some Like It Hot will always have be a little slice in history wither I like it or not!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is As Hot As ......We Need It......(Brilliant)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great Billy Wilder directs, writes, and has a say in the screenplay of one of the really great comedies. Some Like It Hot is up there in the best five comedies...ever made. Marilyn Munroe, Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon are superb as the three leads in this risqu&eacute; 1959 steam-roller. Wilder did everything to get up the noses of the censors, and was clever enough to get away with all of it. In 1959 men dressing and behaving like ladies...wearing ladies clothes...was dangerous ground to tread on. And the many sub-plots that this brought about were also "no go" areas. He succeeded just like the T.V. Classic Seinfeld...when they declared "not that there's anything wrong with that" when they did there great "sexual preference" episode. In the case of Some Like It Hot...we need to remember...this was 1959. Munroe was always difficult to work with...continually turning up late, and being obviously neurotic. In a famous B.B.C. talk show in the 1970s Curtis described Munroe as a "fruit cake". I am sure that was true, but she was wonderful in Some Like It Hot. The movie is a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nell Ryder
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some Like It Hot is a movie about sex, but pretends to be about crime and greed. It's underlying cynicism is overruled when genuine emotion strikes the characters, blindsiding them. Tony Curtis' character thinks he only wants sex, and Marylin Monroe's character thinks she only wants money. They're both surprised to find that they end up desiring each other more. This has been my favourite movie since childhood, I used to watch it every week and could watch it a millions times over. My favourite character is Jack Lemmon as I think he's one of the best comedic actors of all time. My favourite scene is where Jack Lemmon dances the tango with his suitor, Osgood. He later daydreams about whether a honeymoon on the French Riviera or the more traditional Niagara Falls would be best, before he has to break the news to Osgood that he's a man, which leads to the best line in the movie: 'Well, Nobody's Perfect!'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The highly regarded Billy Wilder comedy Some Like It Hot relies on an original, really offbeat and audacious plot for the time (1959), where savoury and incredibly well written dialogues fly for two hours. The adventures of these two travesties are very enjoyable to follow, and the Curtis-Lemmon did a perfect job, a notch above Marylin Monroe even though she is coherent with her character. Overall, the comical potential has been well exploited, even if, due to the changes in mores, what seemed improbable and funny back then doesn't shock anymore. Moreover, the script sometimes goes through slow passages with endless scenes as the one on the boat, and one could question the purpose of the musical interludes as they appear more like promotional parts for Monroe. But, despite these few flaws, Some Like It Hot remains a sure bet in the comical genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder's Some Like It Hot is still among the greatest movie comedies, if not the greatest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only seen this movie once before on the late show when I lived in Jacksonville, FL, with my aunts. I remember thinking this was pretty funny. Now that I've watched this on DVD with my mom (who had never seen this before), it's even more funny than I remembered it. I mean, seeing Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon try to convincingly play women in order to escape some gangsters, especially in front of the actual females they're surrounded with, can be pretty funny since they don't really look anything similar to them but I guess the fact that many of them do drink might have been a factor. And then there's Marilyn Monroe, looking as luminous as one expects but also one of the most charismatic of actresses especially considering her off-screen troubles that seemed to affect everyone involved including director Billy Wilder. Wilder and I.A.L. Diamond's screenplay just cackles with such great lines. Oh, and I also loved Joe E. Brown's performance as the millionaire that falls for Lemmon's character. His seemed to be the best one here, even better than Lemmon's who was the only player to get an Oscar nomination. And while George Raft and Pat O'Brien played their typed roles of gangster and cop, they played them well enough to still deliver the goods. In summary, I'm not sure if I agree with the AFI listing this as No. 1 among great comedies, but Some Like It Hot is still one of the most entertaining of them, that's for sure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average in almost every way...don't stone me!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I am a student of Political history and could recite many a Marilyn Monroe fact or conspiracy theory to you, I had yet to see her in one of her iconic films. So finally I sat down to watch what is generally considered one of the greatest film comedies of all time. That is a lot to live up to and I didn't realize just how popular the film was until I logged on here to write this review. 8.4 on IMDb?! Now, please don't get me wrong...I enjoyed this movie. It was fun and wild and absolutely I can see how and why it pushed the limits back then. I'm not sure I have seen so many analogies and innuendos in one film. They were being shoved down your throat like a case of mistaken identity on Three's Company. The first analogy or clever innuendo is a chuckle and not much else but after the twentieth...it gets tired. The setting of 1929 makes some pretty intense action/gangster scenes even for the time. It was almost shocking to watch it now and that was kind of a neat mix to the comedy. Some of the comedic moments are almost dark in nature. I was surprised that I didn't really feel a lot of the humour had homophobic undertones which I thought would be a certainty. If anything, the very last gag in the film is almost pro-gay in some ways and it was definitely worth a laugh. Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon were so young!! Curtis was handsome and fun and delivered his comedic moments perfectly. Lemmon was quirky and fun and certainly has legendary comedic timing. The two of them together are just awesome. A buddy film like this requires great chemistry and there is nothing short in their chemistry together. They seem like a bit of an odd-couple but they work great together. The stunning beauty of Marilyn Monroe and her sheer raw charisma on screen cannot be denied. When she first appears and every subsequent appearance you are just mesmerized. She's actually a much actress that I anticipated and her role is fun and breezy and perfectly performed by her. The chemistry between her and Curtis and even her and Lemmon is lacking. I didn't feel nearly any sparks between her and Curtis and that's really unfortunate. Romance is an important part of the film and it doesn't really fit well. George Raft is the perfect cookie cutter gangster. He is nothing more or less than the stereotypical "Boss" we would expect from a gangster flick. Same for his crew as well. They could have been lifted right from Dick Tracey. Dave Barry was a great supporting actor and gave some great comedy as the angry but stumbling Beinstock. Joan Shawlee is also good as the band leader and mother hen Sweet Sue. I also really enjoyed the campy and fun character played by Joe E. Brown as the man who falls for Lemmon's Daphne. I have no doubt that to see the true brilliance behind the film you would have to look at from the perspective of 1959 films and the time period. The movie is set in 1929 and I couldn't help but notice the inconsistencies in the timing. Its small things but certain products that weren't available in 1929 (Cheese Whiz for one) or just certain dialect. Its a small thing but worth noting nonetheless. The comedy is definitely balanced out by the more violent scenes in the film so it almost turns out a darker comedy that doesn't always fit the slapstick tone and concept of the movie. It is a fun movie and certainly is a classic that shows up on many lists of being a top film. I don't necessarily agree with that but who am I to deny a film that has stood up to 50+ years. For me, it didn't floor me but it was entertaining. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic, charming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Linus (Linus_92@hotmail.se)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm usually not much for old comedies, although i have to say, this one was truly original, cheerful characters that created the comic impression throughout the movie, which made me grin all the way through. Tony Curtis is an entertaining actor to observe, pulling off three different characters in one movie is nothing more but impressive and shows that he is a very adjustable person. Marilyn Monroe who played 'Sugar Kane Kowalczyk', to me seemed to be very suitable for the character itself, she lived through the character as if it was a part of herself. Billy Wilder took such good care of this film, able to display excitement, love and comedy all together, the synchronization among all the cast on what could have been very chaotic couple of scenes if not done correctly, but manage to control this exceptionally. The shooting location and the backgrounds gave it a very comfortable awareness which made it feel like a cup of hot coco on a cold winter day. This classic comedy gives us a perspective about some of the joy and yet, the difficulty of being a women, it's displayed positively towards the audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cutting Edge, 1959
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No need to recap the plot nor echo consensus points. The movie is perfectly cast. The chemistry between Lemmon and Curtis is perfect. Add a wide-eyed Monroe and it's an outstanding comedy trifecta. Still, seeing the film again after first release, I wonder how much hilarity audiences of today find in the movie's sexual innuendo. After all, the premise was cutting-edge in 1959 when the word 'panties' in Anatomy of a Murder raised a ruckus with enforcers of the film code. In that same year, just watching from a theatre seat during the cross-dressing, plus the many innuendo scenes was like being a daring part of taboo-breaking. The bawdy subtext was a totally new experience in the commercial movies. Thus the amusement factor was heightened by novel comedic material, previously forbidden. But I wonder about today's younger audiences for whom the innuendo may even seem a little tame, given today's almost non-existent standards. In my little book, it's still a funny movie, thanks mainly to an expert cast, but hardly an all- time topper as it is in some ratings lists. Besides, it's the only comedy I can think of to work its way around not just one, but two, on-screen massacres!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good not great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Highly acclaimed as one of the best comedies in Hollywood history, Some Like It Hot has a neat comedic approach that was sure a topic on every gossiper's agenda in the late '50s. It's a funny little movie with an original storyline. Some Like It Hot utilizes it's beautiful costumes to their full potential, it's a beautiful film to look at it. The three stars are all very serviceable in their roles. Jack Lemon is the stand out owning the character and never looking back. Marilyn Monroe is deliciously sweet in the centerpiece of the film of beauty and sexuality. This is widely considered to be her career best, its a shame she missed an Oscar nomination for it. Tony Curtis does a fine job as well. My favorite scene is the legendary "I Wanna Be Loved By You" song lives up to the hype, it's a wonderful scene. My problem with Some Like It Hot is the lack of emotional investment I felt for the story or the characters. I didn't quite get the smacking wave of brilliance others have lived with Some Like It Hot. It's still a good movie, but I didn't think it was a great one. Rating: 7/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder shows his range, and proves again his writing chops
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy about cross-dressing is a surprising choice of subject matter for Billy Wilder, who is best known for his film noir morality tales. But his knack for multi-layered dialogue and sardonic humor work just as well here as in his more serious films. The premise of "Some Like it Hot" is absurd, and if there were no genuine laughs then the behavior of Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon's characters might easily come across as obnoxious and offensive. But there are laughs, and they come so rapidly and so often at the expense of the lead characters that these pitfalls are averted. Lemmon and Marilyn Monroe are so well cast that they are effectively playing themselves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandar_Wagner
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong I think this is a great movie. It's just that when AFI puts out a list of the 100 greatest comedies of all-time and this is #1 I have to disagree. It's the cross dressing comedy that started them all mix that with Marilyn Monroe and you got a classic. The problem I had with this so called masterpiece is that there were hardly any twists or turns along the way. Every time you thought something was going to happen, everything went find and by the time something actually happened, you just don't care anymore. Maybe that's the art, maybe I just don't get it but Some Like It Hot will always have be a little slice in history wither I like it or not!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is As Hot As ......We Need It......(Brilliant)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great Billy Wilder directs, writes, and has a say in the screenplay of one of the really great comedies. Some Like It Hot is up there in the best five comedies...ever made. Marilyn Munroe, Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon are superb as the three leads in this risqu&eacute; 1959 steam-roller. Wilder did everything to get up the noses of the censors, and was clever enough to get away with all of it. In 1959 men dressing and behaving like ladies...wearing ladies clothes...was dangerous ground to tread on. And the many sub-plots that this brought about were also "no go" areas. He succeeded just like the T.V. Classic Seinfeld...when they declared "not that there's anything wrong with that" when they did there great "sexual preference" episode. In the case of Some Like It Hot...we need to remember...this was 1959. Munroe was always difficult to work with...continually turning up late, and being obviously neurotic. In a famous B.B.C. talk show in the 1970s Curtis described Munroe as a "fruit cake". I am sure that was true, but she was wonderful in Some Like It Hot. The movie is a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nell Ryder
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some Like It Hot is a movie about sex, but pretends to be about crime and greed. It's underlying cynicism is overruled when genuine emotion strikes the characters, blindsiding them. Tony Curtis' character thinks he only wants sex, and Marylin Monroe's character thinks she only wants money. They're both surprised to find that they end up desiring each other more. This has been my favourite movie since childhood, I used to watch it every week and could watch it a millions times over. My favourite character is Jack Lemmon as I think he's one of the best comedic actors of all time. My favourite scene is where Jack Lemmon dances the tango with his suitor, Osgood. He later daydreams about whether a honeymoon on the French Riviera or the more traditional Niagara Falls would be best, before he has to break the news to Osgood that he's a man, which leads to the best line in the movie: 'Well, Nobody's Perfect!'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The highly regarded Billy Wilder comedy Some Like It Hot relies on an original, really offbeat and audacious plot for the time (1959), where savoury and incredibly well written dialogues fly for two hours. The adventures of these two travesties are very enjoyable to follow, and the Curtis-Lemmon did a perfect job, a notch above Marylin Monroe even though she is coherent with her character. Overall, the comical potential has been well exploited, even if, due to the changes in mores, what seemed improbable and funny back then doesn't shock anymore. Moreover, the script sometimes goes through slow passages with endless scenes as the one on the boat, and one could question the purpose of the musical interludes as they appear more like promotional parts for Monroe. But, despite these few flaws, Some Like It Hot remains a sure bet in the comical genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder's Some Like It Hot is still among the greatest movie comedies, if not the greatest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only seen this movie once before on the late show when I lived in Jacksonville, FL, with my aunts. I remember thinking this was pretty funny. Now that I've watched this on DVD with my mom (who had never seen this before), it's even more funny than I remembered it. I mean, seeing Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon try to convincingly play women in order to escape some gangsters, especially in front of the actual females they're surrounded with, can be pretty funny since they don't really look anything similar to them but I guess the fact that many of them do drink might have been a factor. And then there's Marilyn Monroe, looking as luminous as one expects but also one of the most charismatic of actresses especially considering her off-screen troubles that seemed to affect everyone involved including director Billy Wilder. Wilder and I.A.L. Diamond's screenplay just cackles with such great lines. Oh, and I also loved Joe E. Brown's performance as the millionaire that falls for Lemmon's character. His seemed to be the best one here, even better than Lemmon's who was the only player to get an Oscar nomination. And while George Raft and Pat O'Brien played their typed roles of gangster and cop, they played them well enough to still deliver the goods. In summary, I'm not sure if I agree with the AFI listing this as No. 1 among great comedies, but Some Like It Hot is still one of the most entertaining of them, that's for sure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average in almost every way...don't stone me!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I am a student of Political history and could recite many a Marilyn Monroe fact or conspiracy theory to you, I had yet to see her in one of her iconic films. So finally I sat down to watch what is generally considered one of the greatest film comedies of all time. That is a lot to live up to and I didn't realize just how popular the film was until I logged on here to write this review. 8.4 on IMDb?! Now, please don't get me wrong...I enjoyed this movie. It was fun and wild and absolutely I can see how and why it pushed the limits back then. I'm not sure I have seen so many analogies and innuendos in one film. They were being shoved down your throat like a case of mistaken identity on Three's Company. The first analogy or clever innuendo is a chuckle and not much else but after the twentieth...it gets tired. The setting of 1929 makes some pretty intense action/gangster scenes even for the time. It was almost shocking to watch it now and that was kind of a neat mix to the comedy. Some of the comedic moments are almost dark in nature. I was surprised that I didn't really feel a lot of the humour had homophobic undertones which I thought would be a certainty. If anything, the very last gag in the film is almost pro-gay in some ways and it was definitely worth a laugh. Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon were so young!! Curtis was handsome and fun and delivered his comedic moments perfectly. Lemmon was quirky and fun and certainly has legendary comedic timing. The two of them together are just awesome. A buddy film like this requires great chemistry and there is nothing short in their chemistry together. They seem like a bit of an odd-couple but they work great together. The stunning beauty of Marilyn Monroe and her sheer raw charisma on screen cannot be denied. When she first appears and every subsequent appearance you are just mesmerized. She's actually a much actress that I anticipated and her role is fun and breezy and perfectly performed by her. The chemistry between her and Curtis and even her and Lemmon is lacking. I didn't feel nearly any sparks between her and Curtis and that's really unfortunate. Romance is an important part of the film and it doesn't really fit well. George Raft is the perfect cookie cutter gangster. He is nothing more or less than the stereotypical "Boss" we would expect from a gangster flick. Same for his crew as well. They could have been lifted right from Dick Tracey. Dave Barry was a great supporting actor and gave some great comedy as the angry but stumbling Beinstock. Joan Shawlee is also good as the band leader and mother hen Sweet Sue. I also really enjoyed the campy and fun character played by Joe E. Brown as the man who falls for Lemmon's Daphne. I have no doubt that to see the true brilliance behind the film you would have to look at from the perspective of 1959 films and the time period. The movie is set in 1929 and I couldn't help but notice the inconsistencies in the timing. Its small things but certain products that weren't available in 1929 (Cheese Whiz for one) or just certain dialect. Its a small thing but worth noting nonetheless. The comedy is definitely balanced out by the more violent scenes in the film so it almost turns out a darker comedy that doesn't always fit the slapstick tone and concept of the movie. It is a fun movie and certainly is a classic that shows up on many lists of being a top film. I don't necessarily agree with that but who am I to deny a film that has stood up to 50+ years. For me, it didn't floor me but it was entertaining. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic, charming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Linus (Linus_92@hotmail.se)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm usually not much for old comedies, although i have to say, this one was truly original, cheerful characters that created the comic impression throughout the movie, which made me grin all the way through. Tony Curtis is an entertaining actor to observe, pulling off three different characters in one movie is nothing more but impressive and shows that he is a very adjustable person. Marilyn Monroe who played 'Sugar Kane Kowalczyk', to me seemed to be very suitable for the character itself, she lived through the character as if it was a part of herself. Billy Wilder took such good care of this film, able to display excitement, love and comedy all together, the synchronization among all the cast on what could have been very chaotic couple of scenes if not done correctly, but manage to control this exceptionally. The shooting location and the backgrounds gave it a very comfortable awareness which made it feel like a cup of hot coco on a cold winter day. This classic comedy gives us a perspective about some of the joy and yet, the difficulty of being a women, it's displayed positively towards the audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cutting Edge, 1959
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No need to recap the plot nor echo consensus points. The movie is perfectly cast. The chemistry between Lemmon and Curtis is perfect. Add a wide-eyed Monroe and it's an outstanding comedy trifecta. Still, seeing the film again after first release, I wonder how much hilarity audiences of today find in the movie's sexual innuendo. After all, the premise was cutting-edge in 1959 when the word 'panties' in Anatomy of a Murder raised a ruckus with enforcers of the film code. In that same year, just watching from a theatre seat during the cross-dressing, plus the many innuendo scenes was like being a daring part of taboo-breaking. The bawdy subtext was a totally new experience in the commercial movies. Thus the amusement factor was heightened by novel comedic material, previously forbidden. But I wonder about today's younger audiences for whom the innuendo may even seem a little tame, given today's almost non-existent standards. In my little book, it's still a funny movie, thanks mainly to an expert cast, but hardly an all- time topper as it is in some ratings lists. Besides, it's the only comedy I can think of to work its way around not just one, but two, on-screen massacres!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good not great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Highly acclaimed as one of the best comedies in Hollywood history, Some Like It Hot has a neat comedic approach that was sure a topic on every gossiper's agenda in the late '50s. It's a funny little movie with an original storyline. Some Like It Hot utilizes it's beautiful costumes to their full potential, it's a beautiful film to look at it. The three stars are all very serviceable in their roles. Jack Lemon is the stand out owning the character and never looking back. Marilyn Monroe is deliciously sweet in the centerpiece of the film of beauty and sexuality. This is widely considered to be her career best, its a shame she missed an Oscar nomination for it. Tony Curtis does a fine job as well. My favorite scene is the legendary "I Wanna Be Loved By You" song lives up to the hype, it's a wonderful scene. My problem with Some Like It Hot is the lack of emotional investment I felt for the story or the characters. I didn't quite get the smacking wave of brilliance others have lived with Some Like It Hot. It's still a good movie, but I didn't think it was a great one. Rating: 7/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder shows his range, and proves again his writing chops
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy about cross-dressing is a surprising choice of subject matter for Billy Wilder, who is best known for his film noir morality tales. But his knack for multi-layered dialogue and sardonic humor work just as well here as in his more serious films. The premise of "Some Like it Hot" is absurd, and if there were no genuine laughs then the behavior of Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon's characters might easily come across as obnoxious and offensive. But there are laughs, and they come so rapidly and so often at the expense of the lead characters that these pitfalls are averted. Lemmon and Marilyn Monroe are so well cast that they are effectively playing themselves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandar_Wagner
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong I think this is a great movie. It's just that when AFI puts out a list of the 100 greatest comedies of all-time and this is #1 I have to disagree. It's the cross dressing comedy that started them all mix that with Marilyn Monroe and you got a classic. The problem I had with this so called masterpiece is that there were hardly any twists or turns along the way. Every time you thought something was going to happen, everything went find and by the time something actually happened, you just don't care anymore. Maybe that's the art, maybe I just don't get it but Some Like It Hot will always have be a little slice in history wither I like it or not!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is As Hot As ......We Need It......(Brilliant)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great Billy Wilder directs, writes, and has a say in the screenplay of one of the really great comedies. Some Like It Hot is up there in the best five comedies...ever made. Marilyn Munroe, Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon are superb as the three leads in this risqu&eacute; 1959 steam-roller. Wilder did everything to get up the noses of the censors, and was clever enough to get away with all of it. In 1959 men dressing and behaving like ladies...wearing ladies clothes...was dangerous ground to tread on. And the many sub-plots that this brought about were also "no go" areas. He succeeded just like the T.V. Classic Seinfeld...when they declared "not that there's anything wrong with that" when they did there great "sexual preference" episode. In the case of Some Like It Hot...we need to remember...this was 1959. Munroe was always difficult to work with...continually turning up late, and being obviously neurotic. In a famous B.B.C. talk show in the 1970s Curtis described Munroe as a "fruit cake". I am sure that was true, but she was wonderful in Some Like It Hot. The movie is a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nell Ryder
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some Like It Hot is a movie about sex, but pretends to be about crime and greed. It's underlying cynicism is overruled when genuine emotion strikes the characters, blindsiding them. Tony Curtis' character thinks he only wants sex, and Marylin Monroe's character thinks she only wants money. They're both surprised to find that they end up desiring each other more. This has been my favourite movie since childhood, I used to watch it every week and could watch it a millions times over. My favourite character is Jack Lemmon as I think he's one of the best comedic actors of all time. My favourite scene is where Jack Lemmon dances the tango with his suitor, Osgood. He later daydreams about whether a honeymoon on the French Riviera or the more traditional Niagara Falls would be best, before he has to break the news to Osgood that he's a man, which leads to the best line in the movie: 'Well, Nobody's Perfect!'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The highly regarded Billy Wilder comedy Some Like It Hot relies on an original, really offbeat and audacious plot for the time (1959), where savoury and incredibly well written dialogues fly for two hours. The adventures of these two travesties are very enjoyable to follow, and the Curtis-Lemmon did a perfect job, a notch above Marylin Monroe even though she is coherent with her character. Overall, the comical potential has been well exploited, even if, due to the changes in mores, what seemed improbable and funny back then doesn't shock anymore. Moreover, the script sometimes goes through slow passages with endless scenes as the one on the boat, and one could question the purpose of the musical interludes as they appear more like promotional parts for Monroe. But, despite these few flaws, Some Like It Hot remains a sure bet in the comical genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder's Some Like It Hot is still among the greatest movie comedies, if not the greatest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only seen this movie once before on the late show when I lived in Jacksonville, FL, with my aunts. I remember thinking this was pretty funny. Now that I've watched this on DVD with my mom (who had never seen this before), it's even more funny than I remembered it. I mean, seeing Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon try to convincingly play women in order to escape some gangsters, especially in front of the actual females they're surrounded with, can be pretty funny since they don't really look anything similar to them but I guess the fact that many of them do drink might have been a factor. And then there's Marilyn Monroe, looking as luminous as one expects but also one of the most charismatic of actresses especially considering her off-screen troubles that seemed to affect everyone involved including director Billy Wilder. Wilder and I.A.L. Diamond's screenplay just cackles with such great lines. Oh, and I also loved Joe E. Brown's performance as the millionaire that falls for Lemmon's character. His seemed to be the best one here, even better than Lemmon's who was the only player to get an Oscar nomination. And while George Raft and Pat O'Brien played their typed roles of gangster and cop, they played them well enough to still deliver the goods. In summary, I'm not sure if I agree with the AFI listing this as No. 1 among great comedies, but Some Like It Hot is still one of the most entertaining of them, that's for sure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average in almost every way...don't stone me!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I am a student of Political history and could recite many a Marilyn Monroe fact or conspiracy theory to you, I had yet to see her in one of her iconic films. So finally I sat down to watch what is generally considered one of the greatest film comedies of all time. That is a lot to live up to and I didn't realize just how popular the film was until I logged on here to write this review. 8.4 on IMDb?! Now, please don't get me wrong...I enjoyed this movie. It was fun and wild and absolutely I can see how and why it pushed the limits back then. I'm not sure I have seen so many analogies and innuendos in one film. They were being shoved down your throat like a case of mistaken identity on Three's Company. The first analogy or clever innuendo is a chuckle and not much else but after the twentieth...it gets tired. The setting of 1929 makes some pretty intense action/gangster scenes even for the time. It was almost shocking to watch it now and that was kind of a neat mix to the comedy. Some of the comedic moments are almost dark in nature. I was surprised that I didn't really feel a lot of the humour had homophobic undertones which I thought would be a certainty. If anything, the very last gag in the film is almost pro-gay in some ways and it was definitely worth a laugh. Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon were so young!! Curtis was handsome and fun and delivered his comedic moments perfectly. Lemmon was quirky and fun and certainly has legendary comedic timing. The two of them together are just awesome. A buddy film like this requires great chemistry and there is nothing short in their chemistry together. They seem like a bit of an odd-couple but they work great together. The stunning beauty of Marilyn Monroe and her sheer raw charisma on screen cannot be denied. When she first appears and every subsequent appearance you are just mesmerized. She's actually a much actress that I anticipated and her role is fun and breezy and perfectly performed by her. The chemistry between her and Curtis and even her and Lemmon is lacking. I didn't feel nearly any sparks between her and Curtis and that's really unfortunate. Romance is an important part of the film and it doesn't really fit well. George Raft is the perfect cookie cutter gangster. He is nothing more or less than the stereotypical "Boss" we would expect from a gangster flick. Same for his crew as well. They could have been lifted right from Dick Tracey. Dave Barry was a great supporting actor and gave some great comedy as the angry but stumbling Beinstock. Joan Shawlee is also good as the band leader and mother hen Sweet Sue. I also really enjoyed the campy and fun character played by Joe E. Brown as the man who falls for Lemmon's Daphne. I have no doubt that to see the true brilliance behind the film you would have to look at from the perspective of 1959 films and the time period. The movie is set in 1929 and I couldn't help but notice the inconsistencies in the timing. Its small things but certain products that weren't available in 1929 (Cheese Whiz for one) or just certain dialect. Its a small thing but worth noting nonetheless. The comedy is definitely balanced out by the more violent scenes in the film so it almost turns out a darker comedy that doesn't always fit the slapstick tone and concept of the movie. It is a fun movie and certainly is a classic that shows up on many lists of being a top film. I don't necessarily agree with that but who am I to deny a film that has stood up to 50+ years. For me, it didn't floor me but it was entertaining. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic, charming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Linus (Linus_92@hotmail.se)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm usually not much for old comedies, although i have to say, this one was truly original, cheerful characters that created the comic impression throughout the movie, which made me grin all the way through. Tony Curtis is an entertaining actor to observe, pulling off three different characters in one movie is nothing more but impressive and shows that he is a very adjustable person. Marilyn Monroe who played 'Sugar Kane Kowalczyk', to me seemed to be very suitable for the character itself, she lived through the character as if it was a part of herself. Billy Wilder took such good care of this film, able to display excitement, love and comedy all together, the synchronization among all the cast on what could have been very chaotic couple of scenes if not done correctly, but manage to control this exceptionally. The shooting location and the backgrounds gave it a very comfortable awareness which made it feel like a cup of hot coco on a cold winter day. This classic comedy gives us a perspective about some of the joy and yet, the difficulty of being a women, it's displayed positively towards the audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cutting Edge, 1959
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No need to recap the plot nor echo consensus points. The movie is perfectly cast. The chemistry between Lemmon and Curtis is perfect. Add a wide-eyed Monroe and it's an outstanding comedy trifecta. Still, seeing the film again after first release, I wonder how much hilarity audiences of today find in the movie's sexual innuendo. After all, the premise was cutting-edge in 1959 when the word 'panties' in Anatomy of a Murder raised a ruckus with enforcers of the film code. In that same year, just watching from a theatre seat during the cross-dressing, plus the many innuendo scenes was like being a daring part of taboo-breaking. The bawdy subtext was a totally new experience in the commercial movies. Thus the amusement factor was heightened by novel comedic material, previously forbidden. But I wonder about today's younger audiences for whom the innuendo may even seem a little tame, given today's almost non-existent standards. In my little book, it's still a funny movie, thanks mainly to an expert cast, but hardly an all- time topper as it is in some ratings lists. Besides, it's the only comedy I can think of to work its way around not just one, but two, on-screen massacres!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good not great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Highly acclaimed as one of the best comedies in Hollywood history, Some Like It Hot has a neat comedic approach that was sure a topic on every gossiper's agenda in the late '50s. It's a funny little movie with an original storyline. Some Like It Hot utilizes it's beautiful costumes to their full potential, it's a beautiful film to look at it. The three stars are all very serviceable in their roles. Jack Lemon is the stand out owning the character and never looking back. Marilyn Monroe is deliciously sweet in the centerpiece of the film of beauty and sexuality. This is widely considered to be her career best, its a shame she missed an Oscar nomination for it. Tony Curtis does a fine job as well. My favorite scene is the legendary "I Wanna Be Loved By You" song lives up to the hype, it's a wonderful scene. My problem with Some Like It Hot is the lack of emotional investment I felt for the story or the characters. I didn't quite get the smacking wave of brilliance others have lived with Some Like It Hot. It's still a good movie, but I didn't think it was a great one. Rating: 7/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder shows his range, and proves again his writing chops
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy about cross-dressing is a surprising choice of subject matter for Billy Wilder, who is best known for his film noir morality tales. But his knack for multi-layered dialogue and sardonic humor work just as well here as in his more serious films. The premise of "Some Like it Hot" is absurd, and if there were no genuine laughs then the behavior of Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon's characters might easily come across as obnoxious and offensive. But there are laughs, and they come so rapidly and so often at the expense of the lead characters that these pitfalls are averted. Lemmon and Marilyn Monroe are so well cast that they are effectively playing themselves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandar_Wagner
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong I think this is a great movie. It's just that when AFI puts out a list of the 100 greatest comedies of all-time and this is #1 I have to disagree. It's the cross dressing comedy that started them all mix that with Marilyn Monroe and you got a classic. The problem I had with this so called masterpiece is that there were hardly any twists or turns along the way. Every time you thought something was going to happen, everything went find and by the time something actually happened, you just don't care anymore. Maybe that's the art, maybe I just don't get it but Some Like It Hot will always have be a little slice in history wither I like it or not!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is As Hot As ......We Need It......(Brilliant)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great Billy Wilder directs, writes, and has a say in the screenplay of one of the really great comedies. Some Like It Hot is up there in the best five comedies...ever made. Marilyn Munroe, Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon are superb as the three leads in this risqu&eacute; 1959 steam-roller. Wilder did everything to get up the noses of the censors, and was clever enough to get away with all of it. In 1959 men dressing and behaving like ladies...wearing ladies clothes...was dangerous ground to tread on. And the many sub-plots that this brought about were also "no go" areas. He succeeded just like the T.V. Classic Seinfeld...when they declared "not that there's anything wrong with that" when they did there great "sexual preference" episode. In the case of Some Like It Hot...we need to remember...this was 1959. Munroe was always difficult to work with...continually turning up late, and being obviously neurotic. In a famous B.B.C. talk show in the 1970s Curtis described Munroe as a "fruit cake". I am sure that was true, but she was wonderful in Some Like It Hot. The movie is a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nell Ryder
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some Like It Hot is a movie about sex, but pretends to be about crime and greed. It's underlying cynicism is overruled when genuine emotion strikes the characters, blindsiding them. Tony Curtis' character thinks he only wants sex, and Marylin Monroe's character thinks she only wants money. They're both surprised to find that they end up desiring each other more. This has been my favourite movie since childhood, I used to watch it every week and could watch it a millions times over. My favourite character is Jack Lemmon as I think he's one of the best comedic actors of all time. My favourite scene is where Jack Lemmon dances the tango with his suitor, Osgood. He later daydreams about whether a honeymoon on the French Riviera or the more traditional Niagara Falls would be best, before he has to break the news to Osgood that he's a man, which leads to the best line in the movie: 'Well, Nobody's Perfect!'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The highly regarded Billy Wilder comedy Some Like It Hot relies on an original, really offbeat and audacious plot for the time (1959), where savoury and incredibly well written dialogues fly for two hours. The adventures of these two travesties are very enjoyable to follow, and the Curtis-Lemmon did a perfect job, a notch above Marylin Monroe even though she is coherent with her character. Overall, the comical potential has been well exploited, even if, due to the changes in mores, what seemed improbable and funny back then doesn't shock anymore. Moreover, the script sometimes goes through slow passages with endless scenes as the one on the boat, and one could question the purpose of the musical interludes as they appear more like promotional parts for Monroe. But, despite these few flaws, Some Like It Hot remains a sure bet in the comical genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder's Some Like It Hot is still among the greatest movie comedies, if not the greatest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only seen this movie once before on the late show when I lived in Jacksonville, FL, with my aunts. I remember thinking this was pretty funny. Now that I've watched this on DVD with my mom (who had never seen this before), it's even more funny than I remembered it. I mean, seeing Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon try to convincingly play women in order to escape some gangsters, especially in front of the actual females they're surrounded with, can be pretty funny since they don't really look anything similar to them but I guess the fact that many of them do drink might have been a factor. And then there's Marilyn Monroe, looking as luminous as one expects but also one of the most charismatic of actresses especially considering her off-screen troubles that seemed to affect everyone involved including director Billy Wilder. Wilder and I.A.L. Diamond's screenplay just cackles with such great lines. Oh, and I also loved Joe E. Brown's performance as the millionaire that falls for Lemmon's character. His seemed to be the best one here, even better than Lemmon's who was the only player to get an Oscar nomination. And while George Raft and Pat O'Brien played their typed roles of gangster and cop, they played them well enough to still deliver the goods. In summary, I'm not sure if I agree with the AFI listing this as No. 1 among great comedies, but Some Like It Hot is still one of the most entertaining of them, that's for sure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average in almost every way...don't stone me!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I am a student of Political history and could recite many a Marilyn Monroe fact or conspiracy theory to you, I had yet to see her in one of her iconic films. So finally I sat down to watch what is generally considered one of the greatest film comedies of all time. That is a lot to live up to and I didn't realize just how popular the film was until I logged on here to write this review. 8.4 on IMDb?! Now, please don't get me wrong...I enjoyed this movie. It was fun and wild and absolutely I can see how and why it pushed the limits back then. I'm not sure I have seen so many analogies and innuendos in one film. They were being shoved down your throat like a case of mistaken identity on Three's Company. The first analogy or clever innuendo is a chuckle and not much else but after the twentieth...it gets tired. The setting of 1929 makes some pretty intense action/gangster scenes even for the time. It was almost shocking to watch it now and that was kind of a neat mix to the comedy. Some of the comedic moments are almost dark in nature. I was surprised that I didn't really feel a lot of the humour had homophobic undertones which I thought would be a certainty. If anything, the very last gag in the film is almost pro-gay in some ways and it was definitely worth a laugh. Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon were so young!! Curtis was handsome and fun and delivered his comedic moments perfectly. Lemmon was quirky and fun and certainly has legendary comedic timing. The two of them together are just awesome. A buddy film like this requires great chemistry and there is nothing short in their chemistry together. They seem like a bit of an odd-couple but they work great together. The stunning beauty of Marilyn Monroe and her sheer raw charisma on screen cannot be denied. When she first appears and every subsequent appearance you are just mesmerized. She's actually a much actress that I anticipated and her role is fun and breezy and perfectly performed by her. The chemistry between her and Curtis and even her and Lemmon is lacking. I didn't feel nearly any sparks between her and Curtis and that's really unfortunate. Romance is an important part of the film and it doesn't really fit well. George Raft is the perfect cookie cutter gangster. He is nothing more or less than the stereotypical "Boss" we would expect from a gangster flick. Same for his crew as well. They could have been lifted right from Dick Tracey. Dave Barry was a great supporting actor and gave some great comedy as the angry but stumbling Beinstock. Joan Shawlee is also good as the band leader and mother hen Sweet Sue. I also really enjoyed the campy and fun character played by Joe E. Brown as the man who falls for Lemmon's Daphne. I have no doubt that to see the true brilliance behind the film you would have to look at from the perspective of 1959 films and the time period. The movie is set in 1929 and I couldn't help but notice the inconsistencies in the timing. Its small things but certain products that weren't available in 1929 (Cheese Whiz for one) or just certain dialect. Its a small thing but worth noting nonetheless. The comedy is definitely balanced out by the more violent scenes in the film so it almost turns out a darker comedy that doesn't always fit the slapstick tone and concept of the movie. It is a fun movie and certainly is a classic that shows up on many lists of being a top film. I don't necessarily agree with that but who am I to deny a film that has stood up to 50+ years. For me, it didn't floor me but it was entertaining. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic, charming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Linus (Linus_92@hotmail.se)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm usually not much for old comedies, although i have to say, this one was truly original, cheerful characters that created the comic impression throughout the movie, which made me grin all the way through. Tony Curtis is an entertaining actor to observe, pulling off three different characters in one movie is nothing more but impressive and shows that he is a very adjustable person. Marilyn Monroe who played 'Sugar Kane Kowalczyk', to me seemed to be very suitable for the character itself, she lived through the character as if it was a part of herself. Billy Wilder took such good care of this film, able to display excitement, love and comedy all together, the synchronization among all the cast on what could have been very chaotic couple of scenes if not done correctly, but manage to control this exceptionally. The shooting location and the backgrounds gave it a very comfortable awareness which made it feel like a cup of hot coco on a cold winter day. This classic comedy gives us a perspective about some of the joy and yet, the difficulty of being a women, it's displayed positively towards the audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cutting Edge, 1959
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No need to recap the plot nor echo consensus points. The movie is perfectly cast. The chemistry between Lemmon and Curtis is perfect. Add a wide-eyed Monroe and it's an outstanding comedy trifecta. Still, seeing the film again after first release, I wonder how much hilarity audiences of today find in the movie's sexual innuendo. After all, the premise was cutting-edge in 1959 when the word 'panties' in Anatomy of a Murder raised a ruckus with enforcers of the film code. In that same year, just watching from a theatre seat during the cross-dressing, plus the many innuendo scenes was like being a daring part of taboo-breaking. The bawdy subtext was a totally new experience in the commercial movies. Thus the amusement factor was heightened by novel comedic material, previously forbidden. But I wonder about today's younger audiences for whom the innuendo may even seem a little tame, given today's almost non-existent standards. In my little book, it's still a funny movie, thanks mainly to an expert cast, but hardly an all- time topper as it is in some ratings lists. Besides, it's the only comedy I can think of to work its way around not just one, but two, on-screen massacres!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good not great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Highly acclaimed as one of the best comedies in Hollywood history, Some Like It Hot has a neat comedic approach that was sure a topic on every gossiper's agenda in the late '50s. It's a funny little movie with an original storyline. Some Like It Hot utilizes it's beautiful costumes to their full potential, it's a beautiful film to look at it. The three stars are all very serviceable in their roles. Jack Lemon is the stand out owning the character and never looking back. Marilyn Monroe is deliciously sweet in the centerpiece of the film of beauty and sexuality. This is widely considered to be her career best, its a shame she missed an Oscar nomination for it. Tony Curtis does a fine job as well. My favorite scene is the legendary "I Wanna Be Loved By You" song lives up to the hype, it's a wonderful scene. My problem with Some Like It Hot is the lack of emotional investment I felt for the story or the characters. I didn't quite get the smacking wave of brilliance others have lived with Some Like It Hot. It's still a good movie, but I didn't think it was a great one. Rating: 7/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder shows his range, and proves again his writing chops
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy about cross-dressing is a surprising choice of subject matter for Billy Wilder, who is best known for his film noir morality tales. But his knack for multi-layered dialogue and sardonic humor work just as well here as in his more serious films. The premise of "Some Like it Hot" is absurd, and if there were no genuine laughs then the behavior of Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon's characters might easily come across as obnoxious and offensive. But there are laughs, and they come so rapidly and so often at the expense of the lead characters that these pitfalls are averted. Lemmon and Marilyn Monroe are so well cast that they are effectively playing themselves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandar_Wagner
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong I think this is a great movie. It's just that when AFI puts out a list of the 100 greatest comedies of all-time and this is #1 I have to disagree. It's the cross dressing comedy that started them all mix that with Marilyn Monroe and you got a classic. The problem I had with this so called masterpiece is that there were hardly any twists or turns along the way. Every time you thought something was going to happen, everything went find and by the time something actually happened, you just don't care anymore. Maybe that's the art, maybe I just don't get it but Some Like It Hot will always have be a little slice in history wither I like it or not!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is As Hot As ......We Need It......(Brilliant)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great Billy Wilder directs, writes, and has a say in the screenplay of one of the really great comedies. Some Like It Hot is up there in the best five comedies...ever made. Marilyn Munroe, Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon are superb as the three leads in this risqu&eacute; 1959 steam-roller. Wilder did everything to get up the noses of the censors, and was clever enough to get away with all of it. In 1959 men dressing and behaving like ladies...wearing ladies clothes...was dangerous ground to tread on. And the many sub-plots that this brought about were also "no go" areas. He succeeded just like the T.V. Classic Seinfeld...when they declared "not that there's anything wrong with that" when they did there great "sexual preference" episode. In the case of Some Like It Hot...we need to remember...this was 1959. Munroe was always difficult to work with...continually turning up late, and being obviously neurotic. In a famous B.B.C. talk show in the 1970s Curtis described Munroe as a "fruit cake". I am sure that was true, but she was wonderful in Some Like It Hot. The movie is a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nell Ryder
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some Like It Hot is a movie about sex, but pretends to be about crime and greed. It's underlying cynicism is overruled when genuine emotion strikes the characters, blindsiding them. Tony Curtis' character thinks he only wants sex, and Marylin Monroe's character thinks she only wants money. They're both surprised to find that they end up desiring each other more. This has been my favourite movie since childhood, I used to watch it every week and could watch it a millions times over. My favourite character is Jack Lemmon as I think he's one of the best comedic actors of all time. My favourite scene is where Jack Lemmon dances the tango with his suitor, Osgood. He later daydreams about whether a honeymoon on the French Riviera or the more traditional Niagara Falls would be best, before he has to break the news to Osgood that he's a man, which leads to the best line in the movie: 'Well, Nobody's Perfect!'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The highly regarded Billy Wilder comedy Some Like It Hot relies on an original, really offbeat and audacious plot for the time (1959), where savoury and incredibly well written dialogues fly for two hours. The adventures of these two travesties are very enjoyable to follow, and the Curtis-Lemmon did a perfect job, a notch above Marylin Monroe even though she is coherent with her character. Overall, the comical potential has been well exploited, even if, due to the changes in mores, what seemed improbable and funny back then doesn't shock anymore. Moreover, the script sometimes goes through slow passages with endless scenes as the one on the boat, and one could question the purpose of the musical interludes as they appear more like promotional parts for Monroe. But, despite these few flaws, Some Like It Hot remains a sure bet in the comical genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder's Some Like It Hot is still among the greatest movie comedies, if not the greatest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only seen this movie once before on the late show when I lived in Jacksonville, FL, with my aunts. I remember thinking this was pretty funny. Now that I've watched this on DVD with my mom (who had never seen this before), it's even more funny than I remembered it. I mean, seeing Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon try to convincingly play women in order to escape some gangsters, especially in front of the actual females they're surrounded with, can be pretty funny since they don't really look anything similar to them but I guess the fact that many of them do drink might have been a factor. And then there's Marilyn Monroe, looking as luminous as one expects but also one of the most charismatic of actresses especially considering her off-screen troubles that seemed to affect everyone involved including director Billy Wilder. Wilder and I.A.L. Diamond's screenplay just cackles with such great lines. Oh, and I also loved Joe E. Brown's performance as the millionaire that falls for Lemmon's character. His seemed to be the best one here, even better than Lemmon's who was the only player to get an Oscar nomination. And while George Raft and Pat O'Brien played their typed roles of gangster and cop, they played them well enough to still deliver the goods. In summary, I'm not sure if I agree with the AFI listing this as No. 1 among great comedies, but Some Like It Hot is still one of the most entertaining of them, that's for sure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average in almost every way...don't stone me!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I am a student of Political history and could recite many a Marilyn Monroe fact or conspiracy theory to you, I had yet to see her in one of her iconic films. So finally I sat down to watch what is generally considered one of the greatest film comedies of all time. That is a lot to live up to and I didn't realize just how popular the film was until I logged on here to write this review. 8.4 on IMDb?! Now, please don't get me wrong...I enjoyed this movie. It was fun and wild and absolutely I can see how and why it pushed the limits back then. I'm not sure I have seen so many analogies and innuendos in one film. They were being shoved down your throat like a case of mistaken identity on Three's Company. The first analogy or clever innuendo is a chuckle and not much else but after the twentieth...it gets tired. The setting of 1929 makes some pretty intense action/gangster scenes even for the time. It was almost shocking to watch it now and that was kind of a neat mix to the comedy. Some of the comedic moments are almost dark in nature. I was surprised that I didn't really feel a lot of the humour had homophobic undertones which I thought would be a certainty. If anything, the very last gag in the film is almost pro-gay in some ways and it was definitely worth a laugh. Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon were so young!! Curtis was handsome and fun and delivered his comedic moments perfectly. Lemmon was quirky and fun and certainly has legendary comedic timing. The two of them together are just awesome. A buddy film like this requires great chemistry and there is nothing short in their chemistry together. They seem like a bit of an odd-couple but they work great together. The stunning beauty of Marilyn Monroe and her sheer raw charisma on screen cannot be denied. When she first appears and every subsequent appearance you are just mesmerized. She's actually a much actress that I anticipated and her role is fun and breezy and perfectly performed by her. The chemistry between her and Curtis and even her and Lemmon is lacking. I didn't feel nearly any sparks between her and Curtis and that's really unfortunate. Romance is an important part of the film and it doesn't really fit well. George Raft is the perfect cookie cutter gangster. He is nothing more or less than the stereotypical "Boss" we would expect from a gangster flick. Same for his crew as well. They could have been lifted right from Dick Tracey. Dave Barry was a great supporting actor and gave some great comedy as the angry but stumbling Beinstock. Joan Shawlee is also good as the band leader and mother hen Sweet Sue. I also really enjoyed the campy and fun character played by Joe E. Brown as the man who falls for Lemmon's Daphne. I have no doubt that to see the true brilliance behind the film you would have to look at from the perspective of 1959 films and the time period. The movie is set in 1929 and I couldn't help but notice the inconsistencies in the timing. Its small things but certain products that weren't available in 1929 (Cheese Whiz for one) or just certain dialect. Its a small thing but worth noting nonetheless. The comedy is definitely balanced out by the more violent scenes in the film so it almost turns out a darker comedy that doesn't always fit the slapstick tone and concept of the movie. It is a fun movie and certainly is a classic that shows up on many lists of being a top film. I don't necessarily agree with that but who am I to deny a film that has stood up to 50+ years. For me, it didn't floor me but it was entertaining. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic, charming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Linus (Linus_92@hotmail.se)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm usually not much for old comedies, although i have to say, this one was truly original, cheerful characters that created the comic impression throughout the movie, which made me grin all the way through. Tony Curtis is an entertaining actor to observe, pulling off three different characters in one movie is nothing more but impressive and shows that he is a very adjustable person. Marilyn Monroe who played 'Sugar Kane Kowalczyk', to me seemed to be very suitable for the character itself, she lived through the character as if it was a part of herself. Billy Wilder took such good care of this film, able to display excitement, love and comedy all together, the synchronization among all the cast on what could have been very chaotic couple of scenes if not done correctly, but manage to control this exceptionally. The shooting location and the backgrounds gave it a very comfortable awareness which made it feel like a cup of hot coco on a cold winter day. This classic comedy gives us a perspective about some of the joy and yet, the difficulty of being a women, it's displayed positively towards the audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cutting Edge, 1959
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No need to recap the plot nor echo consensus points. The movie is perfectly cast. The chemistry between Lemmon and Curtis is perfect. Add a wide-eyed Monroe and it's an outstanding comedy trifecta. Still, seeing the film again after first release, I wonder how much hilarity audiences of today find in the movie's sexual innuendo. After all, the premise was cutting-edge in 1959 when the word 'panties' in Anatomy of a Murder raised a ruckus with enforcers of the film code. In that same year, just watching from a theatre seat during the cross-dressing, plus the many innuendo scenes was like being a daring part of taboo-breaking. The bawdy subtext was a totally new experience in the commercial movies. Thus the amusement factor was heightened by novel comedic material, previously forbidden. But I wonder about today's younger audiences for whom the innuendo may even seem a little tame, given today's almost non-existent standards. In my little book, it's still a funny movie, thanks mainly to an expert cast, but hardly an all- time topper as it is in some ratings lists. Besides, it's the only comedy I can think of to work its way around not just one, but two, on-screen massacres!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good not great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Highly acclaimed as one of the best comedies in Hollywood history, Some Like It Hot has a neat comedic approach that was sure a topic on every gossiper's agenda in the late '50s. It's a funny little movie with an original storyline. Some Like It Hot utilizes it's beautiful costumes to their full potential, it's a beautiful film to look at it. The three stars are all very serviceable in their roles. Jack Lemon is the stand out owning the character and never looking back. Marilyn Monroe is deliciously sweet in the centerpiece of the film of beauty and sexuality. This is widely considered to be her career best, its a shame she missed an Oscar nomination for it. Tony Curtis does a fine job as well. My favorite scene is the legendary "I Wanna Be Loved By You" song lives up to the hype, it's a wonderful scene. My problem with Some Like It Hot is the lack of emotional investment I felt for the story or the characters. I didn't quite get the smacking wave of brilliance others have lived with Some Like It Hot. It's still a good movie, but I didn't think it was a great one. Rating: 7/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder shows his range, and proves again his writing chops
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy about cross-dressing is a surprising choice of subject matter for Billy Wilder, who is best known for his film noir morality tales. But his knack for multi-layered dialogue and sardonic humor work just as well here as in his more serious films. The premise of "Some Like it Hot" is absurd, and if there were no genuine laughs then the behavior of Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon's characters might easily come across as obnoxious and offensive. But there are laughs, and they come so rapidly and so often at the expense of the lead characters that these pitfalls are averted. Lemmon and Marilyn Monroe are so well cast that they are effectively playing themselves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandar_Wagner
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong I think this is a great movie. It's just that when AFI puts out a list of the 100 greatest comedies of all-time and this is #1 I have to disagree. It's the cross dressing comedy that started them all mix that with Marilyn Monroe and you got a classic. The problem I had with this so called masterpiece is that there were hardly any twists or turns along the way. Every time you thought something was going to happen, everything went find and by the time something actually happened, you just don't care anymore. Maybe that's the art, maybe I just don't get it but Some Like It Hot will always have be a little slice in history wither I like it or not!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is As Hot As ......We Need It......(Brilliant)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great Billy Wilder directs, writes, and has a say in the screenplay of one of the really great comedies. Some Like It Hot is up there in the best five comedies...ever made. Marilyn Munroe, Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon are superb as the three leads in this risqu&eacute; 1959 steam-roller. Wilder did everything to get up the noses of the censors, and was clever enough to get away with all of it. In 1959 men dressing and behaving like ladies...wearing ladies clothes...was dangerous ground to tread on. And the many sub-plots that this brought about were also "no go" areas. He succeeded just like the T.V. Classic Seinfeld...when they declared "not that there's anything wrong with that" when they did there great "sexual preference" episode. In the case of Some Like It Hot...we need to remember...this was 1959. Munroe was always difficult to work with...continually turning up late, and being obviously neurotic. In a famous B.B.C. talk show in the 1970s Curtis described Munroe as a "fruit cake". I am sure that was true, but she was wonderful in Some Like It Hot. The movie is a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nell Ryder
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some Like It Hot is a movie about sex, but pretends to be about crime and greed. It's underlying cynicism is overruled when genuine emotion strikes the characters, blindsiding them. Tony Curtis' character thinks he only wants sex, and Marylin Monroe's character thinks she only wants money. They're both surprised to find that they end up desiring each other more. This has been my favourite movie since childhood, I used to watch it every week and could watch it a millions times over. My favourite character is Jack Lemmon as I think he's one of the best comedic actors of all time. My favourite scene is where Jack Lemmon dances the tango with his suitor, Osgood. He later daydreams about whether a honeymoon on the French Riviera or the more traditional Niagara Falls would be best, before he has to break the news to Osgood that he's a man, which leads to the best line in the movie: 'Well, Nobody's Perfect!'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The highly regarded Billy Wilder comedy Some Like It Hot relies on an original, really offbeat and audacious plot for the time (1959), where savoury and incredibly well written dialogues fly for two hours. The adventures of these two travesties are very enjoyable to follow, and the Curtis-Lemmon did a perfect job, a notch above Marylin Monroe even though she is coherent with her character. Overall, the comical potential has been well exploited, even if, due to the changes in mores, what seemed improbable and funny back then doesn't shock anymore. Moreover, the script sometimes goes through slow passages with endless scenes as the one on the boat, and one could question the purpose of the musical interludes as they appear more like promotional parts for Monroe. But, despite these few flaws, Some Like It Hot remains a sure bet in the comical genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder's Some Like It Hot is still among the greatest movie comedies, if not the greatest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only seen this movie once before on the late show when I lived in Jacksonville, FL, with my aunts. I remember thinking this was pretty funny. Now that I've watched this on DVD with my mom (who had never seen this before), it's even more funny than I remembered it. I mean, seeing Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon try to convincingly play women in order to escape some gangsters, especially in front of the actual females they're surrounded with, can be pretty funny since they don't really look anything similar to them but I guess the fact that many of them do drink might have been a factor. And then there's Marilyn Monroe, looking as luminous as one expects but also one of the most charismatic of actresses especially considering her off-screen troubles that seemed to affect everyone involved including director Billy Wilder. Wilder and I.A.L. Diamond's screenplay just cackles with such great lines. Oh, and I also loved Joe E. Brown's performance as the millionaire that falls for Lemmon's character. His seemed to be the best one here, even better than Lemmon's who was the only player to get an Oscar nomination. And while George Raft and Pat O'Brien played their typed roles of gangster and cop, they played them well enough to still deliver the goods. In summary, I'm not sure if I agree with the AFI listing this as No. 1 among great comedies, but Some Like It Hot is still one of the most entertaining of them, that's for sure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average in almost every way...don't stone me!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I am a student of Political history and could recite many a Marilyn Monroe fact or conspiracy theory to you, I had yet to see her in one of her iconic films. So finally I sat down to watch what is generally considered one of the greatest film comedies of all time. That is a lot to live up to and I didn't realize just how popular the film was until I logged on here to write this review. 8.4 on IMDb?! Now, please don't get me wrong...I enjoyed this movie. It was fun and wild and absolutely I can see how and why it pushed the limits back then. I'm not sure I have seen so many analogies and innuendos in one film. They were being shoved down your throat like a case of mistaken identity on Three's Company. The first analogy or clever innuendo is a chuckle and not much else but after the twentieth...it gets tired. The setting of 1929 makes some pretty intense action/gangster scenes even for the time. It was almost shocking to watch it now and that was kind of a neat mix to the comedy. Some of the comedic moments are almost dark in nature. I was surprised that I didn't really feel a lot of the humour had homophobic undertones which I thought would be a certainty. If anything, the very last gag in the film is almost pro-gay in some ways and it was definitely worth a laugh. Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon were so young!! Curtis was handsome and fun and delivered his comedic moments perfectly. Lemmon was quirky and fun and certainly has legendary comedic timing. The two of them together are just awesome. A buddy film like this requires great chemistry and there is nothing short in their chemistry together. They seem like a bit of an odd-couple but they work great together. The stunning beauty of Marilyn Monroe and her sheer raw charisma on screen cannot be denied. When she first appears and every subsequent appearance you are just mesmerized. She's actually a much actress that I anticipated and her role is fun and breezy and perfectly performed by her. The chemistry between her and Curtis and even her and Lemmon is lacking. I didn't feel nearly any sparks between her and Curtis and that's really unfortunate. Romance is an important part of the film and it doesn't really fit well. George Raft is the perfect cookie cutter gangster. He is nothing more or less than the stereotypical "Boss" we would expect from a gangster flick. Same for his crew as well. They could have been lifted right from Dick Tracey. Dave Barry was a great supporting actor and gave some great comedy as the angry but stumbling Beinstock. Joan Shawlee is also good as the band leader and mother hen Sweet Sue. I also really enjoyed the campy and fun character played by Joe E. Brown as the man who falls for Lemmon's Daphne. I have no doubt that to see the true brilliance behind the film you would have to look at from the perspective of 1959 films and the time period. The movie is set in 1929 and I couldn't help but notice the inconsistencies in the timing. Its small things but certain products that weren't available in 1929 (Cheese Whiz for one) or just certain dialect. Its a small thing but worth noting nonetheless. The comedy is definitely balanced out by the more violent scenes in the film so it almost turns out a darker comedy that doesn't always fit the slapstick tone and concept of the movie. It is a fun movie and certainly is a classic that shows up on many lists of being a top film. I don't necessarily agree with that but who am I to deny a film that has stood up to 50+ years. For me, it didn't floor me but it was entertaining. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic, charming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Linus (Linus_92@hotmail.se)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm usually not much for old comedies, although i have to say, this one was truly original, cheerful characters that created the comic impression throughout the movie, which made me grin all the way through. Tony Curtis is an entertaining actor to observe, pulling off three different characters in one movie is nothing more but impressive and shows that he is a very adjustable person. Marilyn Monroe who played 'Sugar Kane Kowalczyk', to me seemed to be very suitable for the character itself, she lived through the character as if it was a part of herself. Billy Wilder took such good care of this film, able to display excitement, love and comedy all together, the synchronization among all the cast on what could have been very chaotic couple of scenes if not done correctly, but manage to control this exceptionally. The shooting location and the backgrounds gave it a very comfortable awareness which made it feel like a cup of hot coco on a cold winter day. This classic comedy gives us a perspective about some of the joy and yet, the difficulty of being a women, it's displayed positively towards the audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cutting Edge, 1959
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No need to recap the plot nor echo consensus points. The movie is perfectly cast. The chemistry between Lemmon and Curtis is perfect. Add a wide-eyed Monroe and it's an outstanding comedy trifecta. Still, seeing the film again after first release, I wonder how much hilarity audiences of today find in the movie's sexual innuendo. After all, the premise was cutting-edge in 1959 when the word 'panties' in Anatomy of a Murder raised a ruckus with enforcers of the film code. In that same year, just watching from a theatre seat during the cross-dressing, plus the many innuendo scenes was like being a daring part of taboo-breaking. The bawdy subtext was a totally new experience in the commercial movies. Thus the amusement factor was heightened by novel comedic material, previously forbidden. But I wonder about today's younger audiences for whom the innuendo may even seem a little tame, given today's almost non-existent standards. In my little book, it's still a funny movie, thanks mainly to an expert cast, but hardly an all- time topper as it is in some ratings lists. Besides, it's the only comedy I can think of to work its way around not just one, but two, on-screen massacres!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good not great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Highly acclaimed as one of the best comedies in Hollywood history, Some Like It Hot has a neat comedic approach that was sure a topic on every gossiper's agenda in the late '50s. It's a funny little movie with an original storyline. Some Like It Hot utilizes it's beautiful costumes to their full potential, it's a beautiful film to look at it. The three stars are all very serviceable in their roles. Jack Lemon is the stand out owning the character and never looking back. Marilyn Monroe is deliciously sweet in the centerpiece of the film of beauty and sexuality. This is widely considered to be her career best, its a shame she missed an Oscar nomination for it. Tony Curtis does a fine job as well. My favorite scene is the legendary "I Wanna Be Loved By You" song lives up to the hype, it's a wonderful scene. My problem with Some Like It Hot is the lack of emotional investment I felt for the story or the characters. I didn't quite get the smacking wave of brilliance others have lived with Some Like It Hot. It's still a good movie, but I didn't think it was a great one. Rating: 7/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder shows his range, and proves again his writing chops
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy about cross-dressing is a surprising choice of subject matter for Billy Wilder, who is best known for his film noir morality tales. But his knack for multi-layered dialogue and sardonic humor work just as well here as in his more serious films. The premise of "Some Like it Hot" is absurd, and if there were no genuine laughs then the behavior of Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon's characters might easily come across as obnoxious and offensive. But there are laughs, and they come so rapidly and so often at the expense of the lead characters that these pitfalls are averted. Lemmon and Marilyn Monroe are so well cast that they are effectively playing themselves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandar_Wagner
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong I think this is a great movie. It's just that when AFI puts out a list of the 100 greatest comedies of all-time and this is #1 I have to disagree. It's the cross dressing comedy that started them all mix that with Marilyn Monroe and you got a classic. The problem I had with this so called masterpiece is that there were hardly any twists or turns along the way. Every time you thought something was going to happen, everything went find and by the time something actually happened, you just don't care anymore. Maybe that's the art, maybe I just don't get it but Some Like It Hot will always have be a little slice in history wither I like it or not!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is As Hot As ......We Need It......(Brilliant)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great Billy Wilder directs, writes, and has a say in the screenplay of one of the really great comedies. Some Like It Hot is up there in the best five comedies...ever made. Marilyn Munroe, Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon are superb as the three leads in this risqu&eacute; 1959 steam-roller. Wilder did everything to get up the noses of the censors, and was clever enough to get away with all of it. In 1959 men dressing and behaving like ladies...wearing ladies clothes...was dangerous ground to tread on. And the many sub-plots that this brought about were also "no go" areas. He succeeded just like the T.V. Classic Seinfeld...when they declared "not that there's anything wrong with that" when they did there great "sexual preference" episode. In the case of Some Like It Hot...we need to remember...this was 1959. Munroe was always difficult to work with...continually turning up late, and being obviously neurotic. In a famous B.B.C. talk show in the 1970s Curtis described Munroe as a "fruit cake". I am sure that was true, but she was wonderful in Some Like It Hot. The movie is a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nell Ryder
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some Like It Hot is a movie about sex, but pretends to be about crime and greed. It's underlying cynicism is overruled when genuine emotion strikes the characters, blindsiding them. Tony Curtis' character thinks he only wants sex, and Marylin Monroe's character thinks she only wants money. They're both surprised to find that they end up desiring each other more. This has been my favourite movie since childhood, I used to watch it every week and could watch it a millions times over. My favourite character is Jack Lemmon as I think he's one of the best comedic actors of all time. My favourite scene is where Jack Lemmon dances the tango with his suitor, Osgood. He later daydreams about whether a honeymoon on the French Riviera or the more traditional Niagara Falls would be best, before he has to break the news to Osgood that he's a man, which leads to the best line in the movie: 'Well, Nobody's Perfect!'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The highly regarded Billy Wilder comedy Some Like It Hot relies on an original, really offbeat and audacious plot for the time (1959), where savoury and incredibly well written dialogues fly for two hours. The adventures of these two travesties are very enjoyable to follow, and the Curtis-Lemmon did a perfect job, a notch above Marylin Monroe even though she is coherent with her character. Overall, the comical potential has been well exploited, even if, due to the changes in mores, what seemed improbable and funny back then doesn't shock anymore. Moreover, the script sometimes goes through slow passages with endless scenes as the one on the boat, and one could question the purpose of the musical interludes as they appear more like promotional parts for Monroe. But, despite these few flaws, Some Like It Hot remains a sure bet in the comical genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder's Some Like It Hot is still among the greatest movie comedies, if not the greatest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only seen this movie once before on the late show when I lived in Jacksonville, FL, with my aunts. I remember thinking this was pretty funny. Now that I've watched this on DVD with my mom (who had never seen this before), it's even more funny than I remembered it. I mean, seeing Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon try to convincingly play women in order to escape some gangsters, especially in front of the actual females they're surrounded with, can be pretty funny since they don't really look anything similar to them but I guess the fact that many of them do drink might have been a factor. And then there's Marilyn Monroe, looking as luminous as one expects but also one of the most charismatic of actresses especially considering her off-screen troubles that seemed to affect everyone involved including director Billy Wilder. Wilder and I.A.L. Diamond's screenplay just cackles with such great lines. Oh, and I also loved Joe E. Brown's performance as the millionaire that falls for Lemmon's character. His seemed to be the best one here, even better than Lemmon's who was the only player to get an Oscar nomination. And while George Raft and Pat O'Brien played their typed roles of gangster and cop, they played them well enough to still deliver the goods. In summary, I'm not sure if I agree with the AFI listing this as No. 1 among great comedies, but Some Like It Hot is still one of the most entertaining of them, that's for sure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average in almost every way...don't stone me!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I am a student of Political history and could recite many a Marilyn Monroe fact or conspiracy theory to you, I had yet to see her in one of her iconic films. So finally I sat down to watch what is generally considered one of the greatest film comedies of all time. That is a lot to live up to and I didn't realize just how popular the film was until I logged on here to write this review. 8.4 on IMDb?! Now, please don't get me wrong...I enjoyed this movie. It was fun and wild and absolutely I can see how and why it pushed the limits back then. I'm not sure I have seen so many analogies and innuendos in one film. They were being shoved down your throat like a case of mistaken identity on Three's Company. The first analogy or clever innuendo is a chuckle and not much else but after the twentieth...it gets tired. The setting of 1929 makes some pretty intense action/gangster scenes even for the time. It was almost shocking to watch it now and that was kind of a neat mix to the comedy. Some of the comedic moments are almost dark in nature. I was surprised that I didn't really feel a lot of the humour had homophobic undertones which I thought would be a certainty. If anything, the very last gag in the film is almost pro-gay in some ways and it was definitely worth a laugh. Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon were so young!! Curtis was handsome and fun and delivered his comedic moments perfectly. Lemmon was quirky and fun and certainly has legendary comedic timing. The two of them together are just awesome. A buddy film like this requires great chemistry and there is nothing short in their chemistry together. They seem like a bit of an odd-couple but they work great together. The stunning beauty of Marilyn Monroe and her sheer raw charisma on screen cannot be denied. When she first appears and every subsequent appearance you are just mesmerized. She's actually a much actress that I anticipated and her role is fun and breezy and perfectly performed by her. The chemistry between her and Curtis and even her and Lemmon is lacking. I didn't feel nearly any sparks between her and Curtis and that's really unfortunate. Romance is an important part of the film and it doesn't really fit well. George Raft is the perfect cookie cutter gangster. He is nothing more or less than the stereotypical "Boss" we would expect from a gangster flick. Same for his crew as well. They could have been lifted right from Dick Tracey. Dave Barry was a great supporting actor and gave some great comedy as the angry but stumbling Beinstock. Joan Shawlee is also good as the band leader and mother hen Sweet Sue. I also really enjoyed the campy and fun character played by Joe E. Brown as the man who falls for Lemmon's Daphne. I have no doubt that to see the true brilliance behind the film you would have to look at from the perspective of 1959 films and the time period. The movie is set in 1929 and I couldn't help but notice the inconsistencies in the timing. Its small things but certain products that weren't available in 1929 (Cheese Whiz for one) or just certain dialect. Its a small thing but worth noting nonetheless. The comedy is definitely balanced out by the more violent scenes in the film so it almost turns out a darker comedy that doesn't always fit the slapstick tone and concept of the movie. It is a fun movie and certainly is a classic that shows up on many lists of being a top film. I don't necessarily agree with that but who am I to deny a film that has stood up to 50+ years. For me, it didn't floor me but it was entertaining. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic, charming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Linus (Linus_92@hotmail.se)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm usually not much for old comedies, although i have to say, this one was truly original, cheerful characters that created the comic impression throughout the movie, which made me grin all the way through. Tony Curtis is an entertaining actor to observe, pulling off three different characters in one movie is nothing more but impressive and shows that he is a very adjustable person. Marilyn Monroe who played 'Sugar Kane Kowalczyk', to me seemed to be very suitable for the character itself, she lived through the character as if it was a part of herself. Billy Wilder took such good care of this film, able to display excitement, love and comedy all together, the synchronization among all the cast on what could have been very chaotic couple of scenes if not done correctly, but manage to control this exceptionally. The shooting location and the backgrounds gave it a very comfortable awareness which made it feel like a cup of hot coco on a cold winter day. This classic comedy gives us a perspective about some of the joy and yet, the difficulty of being a women, it's displayed positively towards the audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cutting Edge, 1959
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No need to recap the plot nor echo consensus points. The movie is perfectly cast. The chemistry between Lemmon and Curtis is perfect. Add a wide-eyed Monroe and it's an outstanding comedy trifecta. Still, seeing the film again after first release, I wonder how much hilarity audiences of today find in the movie's sexual innuendo. After all, the premise was cutting-edge in 1959 when the word 'panties' in Anatomy of a Murder raised a ruckus with enforcers of the film code. In that same year, just watching from a theatre seat during the cross-dressing, plus the many innuendo scenes was like being a daring part of taboo-breaking. The bawdy subtext was a totally new experience in the commercial movies. Thus the amusement factor was heightened by novel comedic material, previously forbidden. But I wonder about today's younger audiences for whom the innuendo may even seem a little tame, given today's almost non-existent standards. In my little book, it's still a funny movie, thanks mainly to an expert cast, but hardly an all- time topper as it is in some ratings lists. Besides, it's the only comedy I can think of to work its way around not just one, but two, on-screen massacres!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good not great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Highly acclaimed as one of the best comedies in Hollywood history, Some Like It Hot has a neat comedic approach that was sure a topic on every gossiper's agenda in the late '50s. It's a funny little movie with an original storyline. Some Like It Hot utilizes it's beautiful costumes to their full potential, it's a beautiful film to look at it. The three stars are all very serviceable in their roles. Jack Lemon is the stand out owning the character and never looking back. Marilyn Monroe is deliciously sweet in the centerpiece of the film of beauty and sexuality. This is widely considered to be her career best, its a shame she missed an Oscar nomination for it. Tony Curtis does a fine job as well. My favorite scene is the legendary "I Wanna Be Loved By You" song lives up to the hype, it's a wonderful scene. My problem with Some Like It Hot is the lack of emotional investment I felt for the story or the characters. I didn't quite get the smacking wave of brilliance others have lived with Some Like It Hot. It's still a good movie, but I didn't think it was a great one. Rating: 7/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder shows his range, and proves again his writing chops
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy about cross-dressing is a surprising choice of subject matter for Billy Wilder, who is best known for his film noir morality tales. But his knack for multi-layered dialogue and sardonic humor work just as well here as in his more serious films. The premise of "Some Like it Hot" is absurd, and if there were no genuine laughs then the behavior of Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon's characters might easily come across as obnoxious and offensive. But there are laughs, and they come so rapidly and so often at the expense of the lead characters that these pitfalls are averted. Lemmon and Marilyn Monroe are so well cast that they are effectively playing themselves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandar_Wagner
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong I think this is a great movie. It's just that when AFI puts out a list of the 100 greatest comedies of all-time and this is #1 I have to disagree. It's the cross dressing comedy that started them all mix that with Marilyn Monroe and you got a classic. The problem I had with this so called masterpiece is that there were hardly any twists or turns along the way. Every time you thought something was going to happen, everything went find and by the time something actually happened, you just don't care anymore. Maybe that's the art, maybe I just don't get it but Some Like It Hot will always have be a little slice in history wither I like it or not!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is As Hot As ......We Need It......(Brilliant)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great Billy Wilder directs, writes, and has a say in the screenplay of one of the really great comedies. Some Like It Hot is up there in the best five comedies...ever made. Marilyn Munroe, Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon are superb as the three leads in this risqu&eacute; 1959 steam-roller. Wilder did everything to get up the noses of the censors, and was clever enough to get away with all of it. In 1959 men dressing and behaving like ladies...wearing ladies clothes...was dangerous ground to tread on. And the many sub-plots that this brought about were also "no go" areas. He succeeded just like the T.V. Classic Seinfeld...when they declared "not that there's anything wrong with that" when they did there great "sexual preference" episode. In the case of Some Like It Hot...we need to remember...this was 1959. Munroe was always difficult to work with...continually turning up late, and being obviously neurotic. In a famous B.B.C. talk show in the 1970s Curtis described Munroe as a "fruit cake". I am sure that was true, but she was wonderful in Some Like It Hot. The movie is a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nell Ryder
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some Like It Hot is a movie about sex, but pretends to be about crime and greed. It's underlying cynicism is overruled when genuine emotion strikes the characters, blindsiding them. Tony Curtis' character thinks he only wants sex, and Marylin Monroe's character thinks she only wants money. They're both surprised to find that they end up desiring each other more. This has been my favourite movie since childhood, I used to watch it every week and could watch it a millions times over. My favourite character is Jack Lemmon as I think he's one of the best comedic actors of all time. My favourite scene is where Jack Lemmon dances the tango with his suitor, Osgood. He later daydreams about whether a honeymoon on the French Riviera or the more traditional Niagara Falls would be best, before he has to break the news to Osgood that he's a man, which leads to the best line in the movie: 'Well, Nobody's Perfect!'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The highly regarded Billy Wilder comedy Some Like It Hot relies on an original, really offbeat and audacious plot for the time (1959), where savoury and incredibly well written dialogues fly for two hours. The adventures of these two travesties are very enjoyable to follow, and the Curtis-Lemmon did a perfect job, a notch above Marylin Monroe even though she is coherent with her character. Overall, the comical potential has been well exploited, even if, due to the changes in mores, what seemed improbable and funny back then doesn't shock anymore. Moreover, the script sometimes goes through slow passages with endless scenes as the one on the boat, and one could question the purpose of the musical interludes as they appear more like promotional parts for Monroe. But, despite these few flaws, Some Like It Hot remains a sure bet in the comical genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder's Some Like It Hot is still among the greatest movie comedies, if not the greatest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only seen this movie once before on the late show when I lived in Jacksonville, FL, with my aunts. I remember thinking this was pretty funny. Now that I've watched this on DVD with my mom (who had never seen this before), it's even more funny than I remembered it. I mean, seeing Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon try to convincingly play women in order to escape some gangsters, especially in front of the actual females they're surrounded with, can be pretty funny since they don't really look anything similar to them but I guess the fact that many of them do drink might have been a factor. And then there's Marilyn Monroe, looking as luminous as one expects but also one of the most charismatic of actresses especially considering her off-screen troubles that seemed to affect everyone involved including director Billy Wilder. Wilder and I.A.L. Diamond's screenplay just cackles with such great lines. Oh, and I also loved Joe E. Brown's performance as the millionaire that falls for Lemmon's character. His seemed to be the best one here, even better than Lemmon's who was the only player to get an Oscar nomination. And while George Raft and Pat O'Brien played their typed roles of gangster and cop, they played them well enough to still deliver the goods. In summary, I'm not sure if I agree with the AFI listing this as No. 1 among great comedies, but Some Like It Hot is still one of the most entertaining of them, that's for sure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average in almost every way...don't stone me!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I am a student of Political history and could recite many a Marilyn Monroe fact or conspiracy theory to you, I had yet to see her in one of her iconic films. So finally I sat down to watch what is generally considered one of the greatest film comedies of all time. That is a lot to live up to and I didn't realize just how popular the film was until I logged on here to write this review. 8.4 on IMDb?! Now, please don't get me wrong...I enjoyed this movie. It was fun and wild and absolutely I can see how and why it pushed the limits back then. I'm not sure I have seen so many analogies and innuendos in one film. They were being shoved down your throat like a case of mistaken identity on Three's Company. The first analogy or clever innuendo is a chuckle and not much else but after the twentieth...it gets tired. The setting of 1929 makes some pretty intense action/gangster scenes even for the time. It was almost shocking to watch it now and that was kind of a neat mix to the comedy. Some of the comedic moments are almost dark in nature. I was surprised that I didn't really feel a lot of the humour had homophobic undertones which I thought would be a certainty. If anything, the very last gag in the film is almost pro-gay in some ways and it was definitely worth a laugh. Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon were so young!! Curtis was handsome and fun and delivered his comedic moments perfectly. Lemmon was quirky and fun and certainly has legendary comedic timing. The two of them together are just awesome. A buddy film like this requires great chemistry and there is nothing short in their chemistry together. They seem like a bit of an odd-couple but they work great together. The stunning beauty of Marilyn Monroe and her sheer raw charisma on screen cannot be denied. When she first appears and every subsequent appearance you are just mesmerized. She's actually a much actress that I anticipated and her role is fun and breezy and perfectly performed by her. The chemistry between her and Curtis and even her and Lemmon is lacking. I didn't feel nearly any sparks between her and Curtis and that's really unfortunate. Romance is an important part of the film and it doesn't really fit well. George Raft is the perfect cookie cutter gangster. He is nothing more or less than the stereotypical "Boss" we would expect from a gangster flick. Same for his crew as well. They could have been lifted right from Dick Tracey. Dave Barry was a great supporting actor and gave some great comedy as the angry but stumbling Beinstock. Joan Shawlee is also good as the band leader and mother hen Sweet Sue. I also really enjoyed the campy and fun character played by Joe E. Brown as the man who falls for Lemmon's Daphne. I have no doubt that to see the true brilliance behind the film you would have to look at from the perspective of 1959 films and the time period. The movie is set in 1929 and I couldn't help but notice the inconsistencies in the timing. Its small things but certain products that weren't available in 1929 (Cheese Whiz for one) or just certain dialect. Its a small thing but worth noting nonetheless. The comedy is definitely balanced out by the more violent scenes in the film so it almost turns out a darker comedy that doesn't always fit the slapstick tone and concept of the movie. It is a fun movie and certainly is a classic that shows up on many lists of being a top film. I don't necessarily agree with that but who am I to deny a film that has stood up to 50+ years. For me, it didn't floor me but it was entertaining. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic, charming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Linus (Linus_92@hotmail.se)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm usually not much for old comedies, although i have to say, this one was truly original, cheerful characters that created the comic impression throughout the movie, which made me grin all the way through. Tony Curtis is an entertaining actor to observe, pulling off three different characters in one movie is nothing more but impressive and shows that he is a very adjustable person. Marilyn Monroe who played 'Sugar Kane Kowalczyk', to me seemed to be very suitable for the character itself, she lived through the character as if it was a part of herself. Billy Wilder took such good care of this film, able to display excitement, love and comedy all together, the synchronization among all the cast on what could have been very chaotic couple of scenes if not done correctly, but manage to control this exceptionally. The shooting location and the backgrounds gave it a very comfortable awareness which made it feel like a cup of hot coco on a cold winter day. This classic comedy gives us a perspective about some of the joy and yet, the difficulty of being a women, it's displayed positively towards the audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cutting Edge, 1959
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No need to recap the plot nor echo consensus points. The movie is perfectly cast. The chemistry between Lemmon and Curtis is perfect. Add a wide-eyed Monroe and it's an outstanding comedy trifecta. Still, seeing the film again after first release, I wonder how much hilarity audiences of today find in the movie's sexual innuendo. After all, the premise was cutting-edge in 1959 when the word 'panties' in Anatomy of a Murder raised a ruckus with enforcers of the film code. In that same year, just watching from a theatre seat during the cross-dressing, plus the many innuendo scenes was like being a daring part of taboo-breaking. The bawdy subtext was a totally new experience in the commercial movies. Thus the amusement factor was heightened by novel comedic material, previously forbidden. But I wonder about today's younger audiences for whom the innuendo may even seem a little tame, given today's almost non-existent standards. In my little book, it's still a funny movie, thanks mainly to an expert cast, but hardly an all- time topper as it is in some ratings lists. Besides, it's the only comedy I can think of to work its way around not just one, but two, on-screen massacres!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good not great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Highly acclaimed as one of the best comedies in Hollywood history, Some Like It Hot has a neat comedic approach that was sure a topic on every gossiper's agenda in the late '50s. It's a funny little movie with an original storyline. Some Like It Hot utilizes it's beautiful costumes to their full potential, it's a beautiful film to look at it. The three stars are all very serviceable in their roles. Jack Lemon is the stand out owning the character and never looking back. Marilyn Monroe is deliciously sweet in the centerpiece of the film of beauty and sexuality. This is widely considered to be her career best, its a shame she missed an Oscar nomination for it. Tony Curtis does a fine job as well. My favorite scene is the legendary "I Wanna Be Loved By You" song lives up to the hype, it's a wonderful scene. My problem with Some Like It Hot is the lack of emotional investment I felt for the story or the characters. I didn't quite get the smacking wave of brilliance others have lived with Some Like It Hot. It's still a good movie, but I didn't think it was a great one. Rating: 7/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder shows his range, and proves again his writing chops
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy about cross-dressing is a surprising choice of subject matter for Billy Wilder, who is best known for his film noir morality tales. But his knack for multi-layered dialogue and sardonic humor work just as well here as in his more serious films. The premise of "Some Like it Hot" is absurd, and if there were no genuine laughs then the behavior of Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon's characters might easily come across as obnoxious and offensive. But there are laughs, and they come so rapidly and so often at the expense of the lead characters that these pitfalls are averted. Lemmon and Marilyn Monroe are so well cast that they are effectively playing themselves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandar_Wagner
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong I think this is a great movie. It's just that when AFI puts out a list of the 100 greatest comedies of all-time and this is #1 I have to disagree. It's the cross dressing comedy that started them all mix that with Marilyn Monroe and you got a classic. The problem I had with this so called masterpiece is that there were hardly any twists or turns along the way. Every time you thought something was going to happen, everything went find and by the time something actually happened, you just don't care anymore. Maybe that's the art, maybe I just don't get it but Some Like It Hot will always have be a little slice in history wither I like it or not!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is As Hot As ......We Need It......(Brilliant)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great Billy Wilder directs, writes, and has a say in the screenplay of one of the really great comedies. Some Like It Hot is up there in the best five comedies...ever made. Marilyn Munroe, Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon are superb as the three leads in this risqu&eacute; 1959 steam-roller. Wilder did everything to get up the noses of the censors, and was clever enough to get away with all of it. In 1959 men dressing and behaving like ladies...wearing ladies clothes...was dangerous ground to tread on. And the many sub-plots that this brought about were also "no go" areas. He succeeded just like the T.V. Classic Seinfeld...when they declared "not that there's anything wrong with that" when they did there great "sexual preference" episode. In the case of Some Like It Hot...we need to remember...this was 1959. Munroe was always difficult to work with...continually turning up late, and being obviously neurotic. In a famous B.B.C. talk show in the 1970s Curtis described Munroe as a "fruit cake". I am sure that was true, but she was wonderful in Some Like It Hot. The movie is a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nell Ryder
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some Like It Hot is a movie about sex, but pretends to be about crime and greed. It's underlying cynicism is overruled when genuine emotion strikes the characters, blindsiding them. Tony Curtis' character thinks he only wants sex, and Marylin Monroe's character thinks she only wants money. They're both surprised to find that they end up desiring each other more. This has been my favourite movie since childhood, I used to watch it every week and could watch it a millions times over. My favourite character is Jack Lemmon as I think he's one of the best comedic actors of all time. My favourite scene is where Jack Lemmon dances the tango with his suitor, Osgood. He later daydreams about whether a honeymoon on the French Riviera or the more traditional Niagara Falls would be best, before he has to break the news to Osgood that he's a man, which leads to the best line in the movie: 'Well, Nobody's Perfect!'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The highly regarded Billy Wilder comedy Some Like It Hot relies on an original, really offbeat and audacious plot for the time (1959), where savoury and incredibly well written dialogues fly for two hours. The adventures of these two travesties are very enjoyable to follow, and the Curtis-Lemmon did a perfect job, a notch above Marylin Monroe even though she is coherent with her character. Overall, the comical potential has been well exploited, even if, due to the changes in mores, what seemed improbable and funny back then doesn't shock anymore. Moreover, the script sometimes goes through slow passages with endless scenes as the one on the boat, and one could question the purpose of the musical interludes as they appear more like promotional parts for Monroe. But, despite these few flaws, Some Like It Hot remains a sure bet in the comical genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder's Some Like It Hot is still among the greatest movie comedies, if not the greatest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've only seen this movie once before on the late show when I lived in Jacksonville, FL, with my aunts. I remember thinking this was pretty funny. Now that I've watched this on DVD with my mom (who had never seen this before), it's even more funny than I remembered it. I mean, seeing Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon try to convincingly play women in order to escape some gangsters, especially in front of the actual females they're surrounded with, can be pretty funny since they don't really look anything similar to them but I guess the fact that many of them do drink might have been a factor. And then there's Marilyn Monroe, looking as luminous as one expects but also one of the most charismatic of actresses especially considering her off-screen troubles that seemed to affect everyone involved including director Billy Wilder. Wilder and I.A.L. Diamond's screenplay just cackles with such great lines. Oh, and I also loved Joe E. Brown's performance as the millionaire that falls for Lemmon's character. His seemed to be the best one here, even better than Lemmon's who was the only player to get an Oscar nomination. And while George Raft and Pat O'Brien played their typed roles of gangster and cop, they played them well enough to still deliver the goods. In summary, I'm not sure if I agree with the AFI listing this as No. 1 among great comedies, but Some Like It Hot is still one of the most entertaining of them, that's for sure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Average in almost every way...don't stone me!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I am a student of Political history and could recite many a Marilyn Monroe fact or conspiracy theory to you, I had yet to see her in one of her iconic films. So finally I sat down to watch what is generally considered one of the greatest film comedies of all time. That is a lot to live up to and I didn't realize just how popular the film was until I logged on here to write this review. 8.4 on IMDb?! Now, please don't get me wrong...I enjoyed this movie. It was fun and wild and absolutely I can see how and why it pushed the limits back then. I'm not sure I have seen so many analogies and innuendos in one film. They were being shoved down your throat like a case of mistaken identity on Three's Company. The first analogy or clever innuendo is a chuckle and not much else but after the twentieth...it gets tired. The setting of 1929 makes some pretty intense action/gangster scenes even for the time. It was almost shocking to watch it now and that was kind of a neat mix to the comedy. Some of the comedic moments are almost dark in nature. I was surprised that I didn't really feel a lot of the humour had homophobic undertones which I thought would be a certainty. If anything, the very last gag in the film is almost pro-gay in some ways and it was definitely worth a laugh. Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon were so young!! Curtis was handsome and fun and delivered his comedic moments perfectly. Lemmon was quirky and fun and certainly has legendary comedic timing. The two of them together are just awesome. A buddy film like this requires great chemistry and there is nothing short in their chemistry together. They seem like a bit of an odd-couple but they work great together. The stunning beauty of Marilyn Monroe and her sheer raw charisma on screen cannot be denied. When she first appears and every subsequent appearance you are just mesmerized. She's actually a much actress that I anticipated and her role is fun and breezy and perfectly performed by her. The chemistry between her and Curtis and even her and Lemmon is lacking. I didn't feel nearly any sparks between her and Curtis and that's really unfortunate. Romance is an important part of the film and it doesn't really fit well. George Raft is the perfect cookie cutter gangster. He is nothing more or less than the stereotypical "Boss" we would expect from a gangster flick. Same for his crew as well. They could have been lifted right from Dick Tracey. Dave Barry was a great supporting actor and gave some great comedy as the angry but stumbling Beinstock. Joan Shawlee is also good as the band leader and mother hen Sweet Sue. I also really enjoyed the campy and fun character played by Joe E. Brown as the man who falls for Lemmon's Daphne. I have no doubt that to see the true brilliance behind the film you would have to look at from the perspective of 1959 films and the time period. The movie is set in 1929 and I couldn't help but notice the inconsistencies in the timing. Its small things but certain products that weren't available in 1929 (Cheese Whiz for one) or just certain dialect. Its a small thing but worth noting nonetheless. The comedy is definitely balanced out by the more violent scenes in the film so it almost turns out a darker comedy that doesn't always fit the slapstick tone and concept of the movie. It is a fun movie and certainly is a classic that shows up on many lists of being a top film. I don't necessarily agree with that but who am I to deny a film that has stood up to 50+ years. For me, it didn't floor me but it was entertaining. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic, charming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Linus (Linus_92@hotmail.se)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm usually not much for old comedies, although i have to say, this one was truly original, cheerful characters that created the comic impression throughout the movie, which made me grin all the way through. Tony Curtis is an entertaining actor to observe, pulling off three different characters in one movie is nothing more but impressive and shows that he is a very adjustable person. Marilyn Monroe who played 'Sugar Kane Kowalczyk', to me seemed to be very suitable for the character itself, she lived through the character as if it was a part of herself. Billy Wilder took such good care of this film, able to display excitement, love and comedy all together, the synchronization among all the cast on what could have been very chaotic couple of scenes if not done correctly, but manage to control this exceptionally. The shooting location and the backgrounds gave it a very comfortable awareness which made it feel like a cup of hot coco on a cold winter day. This classic comedy gives us a perspective about some of the joy and yet, the difficulty of being a women, it's displayed positively towards the audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cutting Edge, 1959
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougdoepke
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No need to recap the plot nor echo consensus points. The movie is perfectly cast. The chemistry between Lemmon and Curtis is perfect. Add a wide-eyed Monroe and it's an outstanding comedy trifecta. Still, seeing the film again after first release, I wonder how much hilarity audiences of today find in the movie's sexual innuendo. After all, the premise was cutting-edge in 1959 when the word 'panties' in Anatomy of a Murder raised a ruckus with enforcers of the film code. In that same year, just watching from a theatre seat during the cross-dressing, plus the many innuendo scenes was like being a daring part of taboo-breaking. The bawdy subtext was a totally new experience in the commercial movies. Thus the amusement factor was heightened by novel comedic material, previously forbidden. But I wonder about today's younger audiences for whom the innuendo may even seem a little tame, given today's almost non-existent standards. In my little book, it's still a funny movie, thanks mainly to an expert cast, but hardly an all- time topper as it is in some ratings lists. Besides, it's the only comedy I can think of to work its way around not just one, but two, on-screen massacres!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good not great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Highly acclaimed as one of the best comedies in Hollywood history, Some Like It Hot has a neat comedic approach that was sure a topic on every gossiper's agenda in the late '50s. It's a funny little movie with an original storyline. Some Like It Hot utilizes it's beautiful costumes to their full potential, it's a beautiful film to look at it. The three stars are all very serviceable in their roles. Jack Lemon is the stand out owning the character and never looking back. Marilyn Monroe is deliciously sweet in the centerpiece of the film of beauty and sexuality. This is widely considered to be her career best, its a shame she missed an Oscar nomination for it. Tony Curtis does a fine job as well. My favorite scene is the legendary "I Wanna Be Loved By You" song lives up to the hype, it's a wonderful scene. My problem with Some Like It Hot is the lack of emotional investment I felt for the story or the characters. I didn't quite get the smacking wave of brilliance others have lived with Some Like It Hot. It's still a good movie, but I didn't think it was a great one. Rating: 7/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Billy Wilder shows his range, and proves again his writing chops
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy about cross-dressing is a surprising choice of subject matter for Billy Wilder, who is best known for his film noir morality tales. But his knack for multi-layered dialogue and sardonic humor work just as well here as in his more serious films. The premise of "Some Like it Hot" is absurd, and if there were no genuine laughs then the behavior of Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon's characters might easily come across as obnoxious and offensive. But there are laughs, and they come so rapidly and so often at the expense of the lead characters that these pitfalls are averted. Lemmon and Marilyn Monroe are so well cast that they are effectively playing themselves.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alexandar_Wagner
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't get me wrong I think this is a great movie. It's just that when AFI puts out a list of the 100 greatest comedies of all-time and this is #1 I have to disagree. It's the cross dressing comedy that started them all mix that with Marilyn Monroe and you got a classic. The problem I had with this so called masterpiece is that there were hardly any twists or turns along the way. Every time you thought something was going to happen, everything went find and by the time something actually happened, you just don't care anymore. Maybe that's the art, maybe I just don't get it but Some Like It Hot will always have be a little slice in history wither I like it or not!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is As Hot As ......We Need It......(Brilliant)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great Billy Wilder directs, writes, and has a say in the screenplay of one of the really great comedies. Some Like It Hot is up there in the best five comedies...ever made. Marilyn Munroe, Tony Curtis and Jack Lemmon are superb as the three leads in this risqu&eacute; 1959 steam-roller. Wilder did everything to get up the noses of the censors, and was clever enough to get away with all of it. In 1959 men dressing and behaving like ladies...wearing ladies clothes...was dangerous ground to tread on. And the many sub-plots that this brought about were also "no go" areas. He succeeded just like the T.V. Classic Seinfeld...when they declared "not that there's anything wrong with that" when they did there great "sexual preference" episode. In the case of Some Like It Hot...we need to remember...this was 1959. Munroe was always difficult to work with...continually turning up late, and being obviously neurotic. In a famous B.B.C. talk show in the 1970s Curtis described Munroe as a "fruit cake". I am sure that was true, but she was wonderful in Some Like It Hot. The movie is a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
