<filme>
 <id>
  484
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0033870
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1941
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Rel&iacute;quia Macabra (O Falc&atilde;o Malt&ecirc;s)
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A private detective takes on a case that involves him with three eccentric criminals, a gorgeous liar, and their quest for a priceless statuette.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Spade and Archer is the name of a San Francisco detective agency. That's for Sam Spade and Miles Archer. The two men are partners, but Sam doesn't like Miles much. A knockout, who goes by the name of Miss Wanderly, walks into their office; and by that night everything's changed. Miles is dead. And so is a man named Floyd Thursby. It seems Miss Wanderly is surrounded by dangerous men. There's Joel Cairo, who uses gardenia-scented calling cards. There's Kasper Gutman, with his enormous girth and feigned civility. Her only hope of protection comes from Sam, who is suspected by the police of one or the other murder. More murders are yet to come, and it will all be because of these dangerous men -- and their lust for a statuette of a bird: the Maltese Falcon.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Film-Noir
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   partner
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   detective
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   maltese falcon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   statuette
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Huston
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Huston
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Dashiell Hammett
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Humphrey Bogart
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mary Astor
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gladys George
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robbieasl
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A great classic, a great film, a great Bogart (Samuel Spade) in it, a great adaptation of the book. The film is generally a very faithful adaptation of the novel, although some scenes from the novel are not in the movie. It is a tribute to the "macho" image of the detective we have lost the past years. The film has a sense of humor the book lacks and an atmosphere that's hard to describe. A treasure that you could die for. A manly, unpredictable private detective with his own morality code. A crook smelling lavender (In the book. In the movie they say gardenias), a fat man and a breathtaking red-head, no one should trust. Those are the ingredients to the Dashiell Hammett story, which has been characterized as the best mystery novel ever written. (by Otto Penzler)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in fact, only pure masterpiece. one of admirable movies who gives soul of a novel and gives to public a form of special precious joy. a detective story, maybe the best, a magnificent cast and an unique director. but the basic ingredient remains the script, admirable at whole. because each character is just collection of nuances. because the white/black is used in splendid manner because the tension, the link between character, the music, the details are remarkable it is the film of Humprhey Bogart and, in same measure, the film of Sydney Greenstreet or Mary Astor. each of theme represents not exactly image of a type but puzzle of inspired science to expose the character specificity. and Peter Lorre is, definitely, Peter Lorre in one of his most splendid works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic Movie that Deserves the Position
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most famous movies ever made. Based on a book the movie was first made in 1931 and later remade in 1941 with Humphrey Bogart playing the detective Sam Spade. Most critics, including Bill Collins, directs us to focus on the characters in the movie because it is the characterization that makes this such a great movie. I agree to a point, but I think the whole issue of the Maltese Falcon makes this such a dark movie. The book upon which this movie is based is considered to be a change in direction with the way detective stories are made. Edgar Allen Poe was the creator of the detective story and it was developed by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, but their detectives were intelligent, honourable men. Sam Spade could be seen as one of the first "Down and Out detectives." The author of The Maltese Falcons describes private detectives as police officers who do not like to work with people but rather go it alone. These characters are more crooked and ruthless than police officers. It is no wonder that the police in The Maltese Falcon are somewhat cold towards Sam Spade. Spade works with fellow Detective Miles Archer and the movie opens with a young lady, O'Shannahey, hiring Spade and Archer to trail some guy who has stolen her sister from her. Suddenly Archer is shot and the movie starts into motion. The Maltese Falcon was a statuette that was stolen by pirates as it was being delivered to the King of Spain and it has supposedly surfaced in San-Fransisco. The movie is not a search for the falcon but rather people all wanting a piece of it. The fat man, who is the villain of the movie, wants the falcon and pays Spade a lot of money to get it. He doesn't want to part with his money and has his gunsel Wilma to dispose of Captain Jacobi and get the falcon. The harsh parts of the characters are revealed with the Fat Man willing to sell out Wilma, whom he claims to consider a son, to get the Falcon off of Sam Spade. And then there is O'Shannahey, a beautiful young lady who grabs Spade's heart, yet we know that Spade does not truly love this woman as we learn that he is having an affair with Archer's wife. O'Shannahey is not what we expect. At first she comes as an innocent woman who is looking for her sister but we find a web of lies and deceit surrounding her and the more we get entangled in the lies the more sinister O'Shannahey becomes. Spade is not a hero either, rather he is an anti-hero. He his selfish and cold, ready to betray his partner for a woman, and ready to betray his lover for his reputation. He slaps around Wilma and Cairo, treating them like little children. Spade is an arrogant, self-centered person and would rather look after himself than others. I think the ending of the Maltese Falcon is brilliant. I am one who looks more at the ending of a movie than the content because it is the ending that we are left with when we leave. The ending of the Maltese Falcon is not happy, nor is it sad. Rather we are just left knowing that life will go on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big gamble that paid off.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one was tougher than Bogart.No one was more sharp tongued than Bogart.No one had just the right retort more often than Bogart.No one had a stronger screen presence than Bogart.He commanded the screen every time he graced it.In this film,he was in the hands of a young upstart screenwriter directing his very first feature,a young man named John Huston.The studio was taking a gamble.George Raft even turned down the role of Sam Spade due to Huston's inexperience as a director.More Hollywood gambles probably fail than succeed,put this one paid of big dividends.Huston's direction was excellent,Bogey was awesome as always,and the supporting cast was top notch.Very worthy of it's classic status.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slightly above mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunznc
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After all the years of hype I was very disappointed after seeing this. The dialog is dull, the story is tripe, small ideas lead to nowhere, a scene starts to heat up and then turns abruptly and stalls. Surprisingly flat, no sparkle at all. The most interesting person in the entire film is Mary Astor. Her performance is the most complex but even her own story told by herself becomes a big question mark and is also dull just like everything else. With Sydney Greenstreet and Peter Lorre one would think that the they'd be seeing something similar to Casablanca which is far more entertaining that this. But even this trio cannot save this boring film. No, Shadow of a Doubt, Sorry Wrong Number, The Damned Don't Cry and Casablanca itself are much, much more entertaining than this. See it for Bogart's performance but not much here to brag about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional (though flawed) film with brilliant performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I had watched this movie a couple of times before, when I saw a documentary that talked about, I decided that perhaps I hadn't given it its full due. So I pulled the DVD off the shelf last evening and watched it again...after reading about it on Wikipedia for some background. In terms of plot, I don't think it's any masterpiece, although it is a good story. I would fault the movie somewhat because during the first half hour (of 101 minute film) you may find yourself struggling to grasp what the movie is really about (although, since I had seen it before and read about it, I knew...but I still think the first 30 minutes meanders around quite a bit with no clear destination, although that's not to say it's not intriguing. But then, things begin to fall into place and you have the development of a good mystery. In the end, you may reflect and say: wow! It's amazing how much they packed into 101 minutes! It's interesting how many references to homosexuality there are in this film...and that they got away with some of them. First, Peter Lorre's character is clearly effeminate, both with his behaviors and his gardenia scented calling cards. In an early scene, Bogart says to a male detective of his male partner, "What's your boyfriend getting at, Tom?" And later, when Bogart slaps a thug, "When you're slapped, you'll take it and like it." But the reason this film is sooooooo good is the acting. Although he had already been in films from 1928 - 1940, 1941 was really the year that Humphrey Bogart came into his own right as a true star, rather than a supporting actor. And it was in this film, in my view, that he showed what would be a fairly common theme throughout the rest of his career -- a good guy who was just a shade away from being a bad guy. As Sam Spade, that persona worked well, and continued to work well for Bogart in any number of pictures. The female lead -- Mary Astor -- is perfect here as a woman who is acting an evolving part in a never-ending comedy of errors; you can see she's not to be trusted, although superficially she seems highbrow, while underneath she's really a con. Gladys George, who surprisingly gets third billing, is rather irrelevant to the story as Bogart's partner's wife. I don't think how good Peter Lorre's role is here as an somewhat effeminate crook; in fact, I would say it's brilliant, and perhaps his best role. Barton MacLane is around as a detective, but his acting is always pretty static. Lee Patrick is enjoyable here as Bogart's secretary. Surprisingly way down at 7th billing is Sydney Greenstreet as "the fat man"; but this was his first film...and he turned it into a gem of a role with his evil giggling; interesting to watch his early scenes here where he is filmed sitting and you see him at an odd angle from the belly up. I've always thought that Ward Bond was an underrated actor. Here as a police detective he gets better screen time. Jerome Cowan, as Bogart's detective partner doesn't last long...killed off within minutes of the beginning of the film. Of special note here is Elisha Cook, as Wilmer, an effeminate gangster (?) who plays it too tough only to be put down repeatedly by Bogart...a very good role for him. Interestingly, John Hamilton is around as the DA (he later played Perry White in television's "Superman" series. And you have to watch carefully for the ship's captain, who turns out to be Walter Huston, director John Huston's father, in an uncredited cameo. The bottom line of this film is the old saying that there is no honor among thieves. But few films have ever portrayed that concept with such verve. Highly recommended...an exceptional (though flawed) film. Walter Huston as Captain Jacobi (uncredited)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt like I'd seen 'The Maltese Falcon' before, probably because as these things go it's pretty standard. A few dry quips, rapid fallings-in-love, double crosses, and characters pinging from hotel room to hotel room explaining the plot to each other while with every round of exposition it becomes less and less clear who did what to whom and why. I mean, it's fine but nothing special. It's worth watching for Humphrey Bogart, who is, as always, a magnetic screen presence, not the greatest actor in the world but a proper Movie Star. The highlight of the film for me, however, is the performance of Sydney Greenstreet, with his entertaining line in affable menace and a squeaky giggle that really tickled me. Solid stuff but nothing that really grabbed me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Determination solves a crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Maltese Falcon is about a detective who solves the crime of his partner's murder by dogged determination. The main plot is the solving of the crime (which ends in success), with a minor love interest subplot that ends in failure (the detective gives up the love interest after discovering she committed the murder). As a story The Maltese Falcon largely flatlines. The main plot moves from discovery to discovery but the turning points feel arbitrary and not meaningful. As the story unfolds, the detective unravels the back story of what the treasure is and how it got here. But the back story's revelation doesn't create much meaning for us or the protagonist as it mainly involves the secondary characters while our main character remains immovable and static. The main character untangles the sordid histories of these secondary characters to solve the crime, but we are left with a feeling of so what? In the end we get two somewhat moral triumphs: one, the detective solves the crime of his partner's murder despite the police messing up their investigation. But this moral victory feels empty since he and his dead partner's wife are lovers, which throws him off the moral high horse. The second is that he gives up his feelings for O'Shaughnessy and sends her to prison because he finds out she turns out to be the murderer. This moral dilemma also feels empty because: A) so he cheated on his dead partner's wife who was his lover to be with this new lover and then gives her up, how is that a moral victory? and B) The two of them only have 2 or 3 turning points to develop their relationship and their love doesn't have much to stand on. So the story is reduced to rely almost exclusively on a classic who dunnit throughline with some great actors who are unfortunately trying to breath life into empty cardboard box of characters. In other words, a big waste of time. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dashiell Hammett's "The Maltese Falcon" was a great book, but it really says something when the movie version is even more enjoyable. Well- written and directed by John Huston, there's a playfulness that comes through not only in the script, but in Humphrey Bogart's performance (who was a terrific pick for Sam Spade, by the way). It's what makes it more than just a top-notch detective story; it's an undeniable classic. Bogie's got the tough-guy act down to a T (hell, he makes it look easy), and Lee Patrick makes for a great scene foil for Bogart (she brings her own moxie to the proceedings). Peter Lorre and Sydney Greenstreet both excel at underhanded characters - Lorre, the slimy weasel and Greenstreet the refined wader of murky waters and smooth in a comical way (that chuckle is hilarious). The dialogue cracks like a whip, giving the ears a workout and making exposition scenes (dare I say it) exciting. "The Maltese Falcon" is more than a detective yarn and a film noir hallmark; it's just a consummate piece of classic Hollywood artistry. It's the sort of movie that leaves me hungry for more Bogey. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconaclastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is arguably the first Film-Noir. While it is a groundbreaking style of slick sensibilities, Camera Angles, and crisp Performances, the witty rhythmic Script is foremost the Star here. There is a surrealist, not a realism to the Dialog. A Pulped Up patter that can be found in the best Crime Fiction of Dashiell Hammett, Raymond Chandler, and James Cain. In real life People don't talk like that. "What do you want me to do, learn to stutter" answers Sam Spade. The Film is iconic Bogart and his supporters are along for the ride. He is in virtually every scene and it is his ship that the barnacles attach. Everything is dependent on the Character of Detective as he wanders through this wondering about what to do and who to do it to next. Undeniably infectious, things move at a rapid pace and is fascinating to watch. Not without flaws, such as a wordy, wondering Story and some stiffness. Still it is an important Movie, although it suffers from being Studio bound and some rather annoying, feathery Music. The end speech where Spade verbalizes his reasons for his actions is rather badly Written and Acted and almost doesn't fit with the sharpness that led us there. In short it feels tacked on and simplistic. But the rather weak ending is not enough to keep this from being a new slice of Cinema for the Forties and beyond. It is worth most of its relentless praise. There is a lot here to relish and only a few things that keep this from Greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robbieasl
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A great classic, a great film, a great Bogart (Samuel Spade) in it, a great adaptation of the book. The film is generally a very faithful adaptation of the novel, although some scenes from the novel are not in the movie. It is a tribute to the "macho" image of the detective we have lost the past years. The film has a sense of humor the book lacks and an atmosphere that's hard to describe. A treasure that you could die for. A manly, unpredictable private detective with his own morality code. A crook smelling lavender (In the book. In the movie they say gardenias), a fat man and a breathtaking red-head, no one should trust. Those are the ingredients to the Dashiell Hammett story, which has been characterized as the best mystery novel ever written. (by Otto Penzler)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in fact, only pure masterpiece. one of admirable movies who gives soul of a novel and gives to public a form of special precious joy. a detective story, maybe the best, a magnificent cast and an unique director. but the basic ingredient remains the script, admirable at whole. because each character is just collection of nuances. because the white/black is used in splendid manner because the tension, the link between character, the music, the details are remarkable it is the film of Humprhey Bogart and, in same measure, the film of Sydney Greenstreet or Mary Astor. each of theme represents not exactly image of a type but puzzle of inspired science to expose the character specificity. and Peter Lorre is, definitely, Peter Lorre in one of his most splendid works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic Movie that Deserves the Position
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most famous movies ever made. Based on a book the movie was first made in 1931 and later remade in 1941 with Humphrey Bogart playing the detective Sam Spade. Most critics, including Bill Collins, directs us to focus on the characters in the movie because it is the characterization that makes this such a great movie. I agree to a point, but I think the whole issue of the Maltese Falcon makes this such a dark movie. The book upon which this movie is based is considered to be a change in direction with the way detective stories are made. Edgar Allen Poe was the creator of the detective story and it was developed by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, but their detectives were intelligent, honourable men. Sam Spade could be seen as one of the first "Down and Out detectives." The author of The Maltese Falcons describes private detectives as police officers who do not like to work with people but rather go it alone. These characters are more crooked and ruthless than police officers. It is no wonder that the police in The Maltese Falcon are somewhat cold towards Sam Spade. Spade works with fellow Detective Miles Archer and the movie opens with a young lady, O'Shannahey, hiring Spade and Archer to trail some guy who has stolen her sister from her. Suddenly Archer is shot and the movie starts into motion. The Maltese Falcon was a statuette that was stolen by pirates as it was being delivered to the King of Spain and it has supposedly surfaced in San-Fransisco. The movie is not a search for the falcon but rather people all wanting a piece of it. The fat man, who is the villain of the movie, wants the falcon and pays Spade a lot of money to get it. He doesn't want to part with his money and has his gunsel Wilma to dispose of Captain Jacobi and get the falcon. The harsh parts of the characters are revealed with the Fat Man willing to sell out Wilma, whom he claims to consider a son, to get the Falcon off of Sam Spade. And then there is O'Shannahey, a beautiful young lady who grabs Spade's heart, yet we know that Spade does not truly love this woman as we learn that he is having an affair with Archer's wife. O'Shannahey is not what we expect. At first she comes as an innocent woman who is looking for her sister but we find a web of lies and deceit surrounding her and the more we get entangled in the lies the more sinister O'Shannahey becomes. Spade is not a hero either, rather he is an anti-hero. He his selfish and cold, ready to betray his partner for a woman, and ready to betray his lover for his reputation. He slaps around Wilma and Cairo, treating them like little children. Spade is an arrogant, self-centered person and would rather look after himself than others. I think the ending of the Maltese Falcon is brilliant. I am one who looks more at the ending of a movie than the content because it is the ending that we are left with when we leave. The ending of the Maltese Falcon is not happy, nor is it sad. Rather we are just left knowing that life will go on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big gamble that paid off.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one was tougher than Bogart.No one was more sharp tongued than Bogart.No one had just the right retort more often than Bogart.No one had a stronger screen presence than Bogart.He commanded the screen every time he graced it.In this film,he was in the hands of a young upstart screenwriter directing his very first feature,a young man named John Huston.The studio was taking a gamble.George Raft even turned down the role of Sam Spade due to Huston's inexperience as a director.More Hollywood gambles probably fail than succeed,put this one paid of big dividends.Huston's direction was excellent,Bogey was awesome as always,and the supporting cast was top notch.Very worthy of it's classic status.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slightly above mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunznc
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After all the years of hype I was very disappointed after seeing this. The dialog is dull, the story is tripe, small ideas lead to nowhere, a scene starts to heat up and then turns abruptly and stalls. Surprisingly flat, no sparkle at all. The most interesting person in the entire film is Mary Astor. Her performance is the most complex but even her own story told by herself becomes a big question mark and is also dull just like everything else. With Sydney Greenstreet and Peter Lorre one would think that the they'd be seeing something similar to Casablanca which is far more entertaining that this. But even this trio cannot save this boring film. No, Shadow of a Doubt, Sorry Wrong Number, The Damned Don't Cry and Casablanca itself are much, much more entertaining than this. See it for Bogart's performance but not much here to brag about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional (though flawed) film with brilliant performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I had watched this movie a couple of times before, when I saw a documentary that talked about, I decided that perhaps I hadn't given it its full due. So I pulled the DVD off the shelf last evening and watched it again...after reading about it on Wikipedia for some background. In terms of plot, I don't think it's any masterpiece, although it is a good story. I would fault the movie somewhat because during the first half hour (of 101 minute film) you may find yourself struggling to grasp what the movie is really about (although, since I had seen it before and read about it, I knew...but I still think the first 30 minutes meanders around quite a bit with no clear destination, although that's not to say it's not intriguing. But then, things begin to fall into place and you have the development of a good mystery. In the end, you may reflect and say: wow! It's amazing how much they packed into 101 minutes! It's interesting how many references to homosexuality there are in this film...and that they got away with some of them. First, Peter Lorre's character is clearly effeminate, both with his behaviors and his gardenia scented calling cards. In an early scene, Bogart says to a male detective of his male partner, "What's your boyfriend getting at, Tom?" And later, when Bogart slaps a thug, "When you're slapped, you'll take it and like it." But the reason this film is sooooooo good is the acting. Although he had already been in films from 1928 - 1940, 1941 was really the year that Humphrey Bogart came into his own right as a true star, rather than a supporting actor. And it was in this film, in my view, that he showed what would be a fairly common theme throughout the rest of his career -- a good guy who was just a shade away from being a bad guy. As Sam Spade, that persona worked well, and continued to work well for Bogart in any number of pictures. The female lead -- Mary Astor -- is perfect here as a woman who is acting an evolving part in a never-ending comedy of errors; you can see she's not to be trusted, although superficially she seems highbrow, while underneath she's really a con. Gladys George, who surprisingly gets third billing, is rather irrelevant to the story as Bogart's partner's wife. I don't think how good Peter Lorre's role is here as an somewhat effeminate crook; in fact, I would say it's brilliant, and perhaps his best role. Barton MacLane is around as a detective, but his acting is always pretty static. Lee Patrick is enjoyable here as Bogart's secretary. Surprisingly way down at 7th billing is Sydney Greenstreet as "the fat man"; but this was his first film...and he turned it into a gem of a role with his evil giggling; interesting to watch his early scenes here where he is filmed sitting and you see him at an odd angle from the belly up. I've always thought that Ward Bond was an underrated actor. Here as a police detective he gets better screen time. Jerome Cowan, as Bogart's detective partner doesn't last long...killed off within minutes of the beginning of the film. Of special note here is Elisha Cook, as Wilmer, an effeminate gangster (?) who plays it too tough only to be put down repeatedly by Bogart...a very good role for him. Interestingly, John Hamilton is around as the DA (he later played Perry White in television's "Superman" series. And you have to watch carefully for the ship's captain, who turns out to be Walter Huston, director John Huston's father, in an uncredited cameo. The bottom line of this film is the old saying that there is no honor among thieves. But few films have ever portrayed that concept with such verve. Highly recommended...an exceptional (though flawed) film. Walter Huston as Captain Jacobi (uncredited)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt like I'd seen 'The Maltese Falcon' before, probably because as these things go it's pretty standard. A few dry quips, rapid fallings-in-love, double crosses, and characters pinging from hotel room to hotel room explaining the plot to each other while with every round of exposition it becomes less and less clear who did what to whom and why. I mean, it's fine but nothing special. It's worth watching for Humphrey Bogart, who is, as always, a magnetic screen presence, not the greatest actor in the world but a proper Movie Star. The highlight of the film for me, however, is the performance of Sydney Greenstreet, with his entertaining line in affable menace and a squeaky giggle that really tickled me. Solid stuff but nothing that really grabbed me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Determination solves a crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Maltese Falcon is about a detective who solves the crime of his partner's murder by dogged determination. The main plot is the solving of the crime (which ends in success), with a minor love interest subplot that ends in failure (the detective gives up the love interest after discovering she committed the murder). As a story The Maltese Falcon largely flatlines. The main plot moves from discovery to discovery but the turning points feel arbitrary and not meaningful. As the story unfolds, the detective unravels the back story of what the treasure is and how it got here. But the back story's revelation doesn't create much meaning for us or the protagonist as it mainly involves the secondary characters while our main character remains immovable and static. The main character untangles the sordid histories of these secondary characters to solve the crime, but we are left with a feeling of so what? In the end we get two somewhat moral triumphs: one, the detective solves the crime of his partner's murder despite the police messing up their investigation. But this moral victory feels empty since he and his dead partner's wife are lovers, which throws him off the moral high horse. The second is that he gives up his feelings for O'Shaughnessy and sends her to prison because he finds out she turns out to be the murderer. This moral dilemma also feels empty because: A) so he cheated on his dead partner's wife who was his lover to be with this new lover and then gives her up, how is that a moral victory? and B) The two of them only have 2 or 3 turning points to develop their relationship and their love doesn't have much to stand on. So the story is reduced to rely almost exclusively on a classic who dunnit throughline with some great actors who are unfortunately trying to breath life into empty cardboard box of characters. In other words, a big waste of time. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dashiell Hammett's "The Maltese Falcon" was a great book, but it really says something when the movie version is even more enjoyable. Well- written and directed by John Huston, there's a playfulness that comes through not only in the script, but in Humphrey Bogart's performance (who was a terrific pick for Sam Spade, by the way). It's what makes it more than just a top-notch detective story; it's an undeniable classic. Bogie's got the tough-guy act down to a T (hell, he makes it look easy), and Lee Patrick makes for a great scene foil for Bogart (she brings her own moxie to the proceedings). Peter Lorre and Sydney Greenstreet both excel at underhanded characters - Lorre, the slimy weasel and Greenstreet the refined wader of murky waters and smooth in a comical way (that chuckle is hilarious). The dialogue cracks like a whip, giving the ears a workout and making exposition scenes (dare I say it) exciting. "The Maltese Falcon" is more than a detective yarn and a film noir hallmark; it's just a consummate piece of classic Hollywood artistry. It's the sort of movie that leaves me hungry for more Bogey. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconaclastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is arguably the first Film-Noir. While it is a groundbreaking style of slick sensibilities, Camera Angles, and crisp Performances, the witty rhythmic Script is foremost the Star here. There is a surrealist, not a realism to the Dialog. A Pulped Up patter that can be found in the best Crime Fiction of Dashiell Hammett, Raymond Chandler, and James Cain. In real life People don't talk like that. "What do you want me to do, learn to stutter" answers Sam Spade. The Film is iconic Bogart and his supporters are along for the ride. He is in virtually every scene and it is his ship that the barnacles attach. Everything is dependent on the Character of Detective as he wanders through this wondering about what to do and who to do it to next. Undeniably infectious, things move at a rapid pace and is fascinating to watch. Not without flaws, such as a wordy, wondering Story and some stiffness. Still it is an important Movie, although it suffers from being Studio bound and some rather annoying, feathery Music. The end speech where Spade verbalizes his reasons for his actions is rather badly Written and Acted and almost doesn't fit with the sharpness that led us there. In short it feels tacked on and simplistic. But the rather weak ending is not enough to keep this from being a new slice of Cinema for the Forties and beyond. It is worth most of its relentless praise. There is a lot here to relish and only a few things that keep this from Greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robbieasl
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A great classic, a great film, a great Bogart (Samuel Spade) in it, a great adaptation of the book. The film is generally a very faithful adaptation of the novel, although some scenes from the novel are not in the movie. It is a tribute to the "macho" image of the detective we have lost the past years. The film has a sense of humor the book lacks and an atmosphere that's hard to describe. A treasure that you could die for. A manly, unpredictable private detective with his own morality code. A crook smelling lavender (In the book. In the movie they say gardenias), a fat man and a breathtaking red-head, no one should trust. Those are the ingredients to the Dashiell Hammett story, which has been characterized as the best mystery novel ever written. (by Otto Penzler)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in fact, only pure masterpiece. one of admirable movies who gives soul of a novel and gives to public a form of special precious joy. a detective story, maybe the best, a magnificent cast and an unique director. but the basic ingredient remains the script, admirable at whole. because each character is just collection of nuances. because the white/black is used in splendid manner because the tension, the link between character, the music, the details are remarkable it is the film of Humprhey Bogart and, in same measure, the film of Sydney Greenstreet or Mary Astor. each of theme represents not exactly image of a type but puzzle of inspired science to expose the character specificity. and Peter Lorre is, definitely, Peter Lorre in one of his most splendid works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic Movie that Deserves the Position
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most famous movies ever made. Based on a book the movie was first made in 1931 and later remade in 1941 with Humphrey Bogart playing the detective Sam Spade. Most critics, including Bill Collins, directs us to focus on the characters in the movie because it is the characterization that makes this such a great movie. I agree to a point, but I think the whole issue of the Maltese Falcon makes this such a dark movie. The book upon which this movie is based is considered to be a change in direction with the way detective stories are made. Edgar Allen Poe was the creator of the detective story and it was developed by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, but their detectives were intelligent, honourable men. Sam Spade could be seen as one of the first "Down and Out detectives." The author of The Maltese Falcons describes private detectives as police officers who do not like to work with people but rather go it alone. These characters are more crooked and ruthless than police officers. It is no wonder that the police in The Maltese Falcon are somewhat cold towards Sam Spade. Spade works with fellow Detective Miles Archer and the movie opens with a young lady, O'Shannahey, hiring Spade and Archer to trail some guy who has stolen her sister from her. Suddenly Archer is shot and the movie starts into motion. The Maltese Falcon was a statuette that was stolen by pirates as it was being delivered to the King of Spain and it has supposedly surfaced in San-Fransisco. The movie is not a search for the falcon but rather people all wanting a piece of it. The fat man, who is the villain of the movie, wants the falcon and pays Spade a lot of money to get it. He doesn't want to part with his money and has his gunsel Wilma to dispose of Captain Jacobi and get the falcon. The harsh parts of the characters are revealed with the Fat Man willing to sell out Wilma, whom he claims to consider a son, to get the Falcon off of Sam Spade. And then there is O'Shannahey, a beautiful young lady who grabs Spade's heart, yet we know that Spade does not truly love this woman as we learn that he is having an affair with Archer's wife. O'Shannahey is not what we expect. At first she comes as an innocent woman who is looking for her sister but we find a web of lies and deceit surrounding her and the more we get entangled in the lies the more sinister O'Shannahey becomes. Spade is not a hero either, rather he is an anti-hero. He his selfish and cold, ready to betray his partner for a woman, and ready to betray his lover for his reputation. He slaps around Wilma and Cairo, treating them like little children. Spade is an arrogant, self-centered person and would rather look after himself than others. I think the ending of the Maltese Falcon is brilliant. I am one who looks more at the ending of a movie than the content because it is the ending that we are left with when we leave. The ending of the Maltese Falcon is not happy, nor is it sad. Rather we are just left knowing that life will go on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big gamble that paid off.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one was tougher than Bogart.No one was more sharp tongued than Bogart.No one had just the right retort more often than Bogart.No one had a stronger screen presence than Bogart.He commanded the screen every time he graced it.In this film,he was in the hands of a young upstart screenwriter directing his very first feature,a young man named John Huston.The studio was taking a gamble.George Raft even turned down the role of Sam Spade due to Huston's inexperience as a director.More Hollywood gambles probably fail than succeed,put this one paid of big dividends.Huston's direction was excellent,Bogey was awesome as always,and the supporting cast was top notch.Very worthy of it's classic status.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slightly above mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunznc
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After all the years of hype I was very disappointed after seeing this. The dialog is dull, the story is tripe, small ideas lead to nowhere, a scene starts to heat up and then turns abruptly and stalls. Surprisingly flat, no sparkle at all. The most interesting person in the entire film is Mary Astor. Her performance is the most complex but even her own story told by herself becomes a big question mark and is also dull just like everything else. With Sydney Greenstreet and Peter Lorre one would think that the they'd be seeing something similar to Casablanca which is far more entertaining that this. But even this trio cannot save this boring film. No, Shadow of a Doubt, Sorry Wrong Number, The Damned Don't Cry and Casablanca itself are much, much more entertaining than this. See it for Bogart's performance but not much here to brag about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional (though flawed) film with brilliant performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I had watched this movie a couple of times before, when I saw a documentary that talked about, I decided that perhaps I hadn't given it its full due. So I pulled the DVD off the shelf last evening and watched it again...after reading about it on Wikipedia for some background. In terms of plot, I don't think it's any masterpiece, although it is a good story. I would fault the movie somewhat because during the first half hour (of 101 minute film) you may find yourself struggling to grasp what the movie is really about (although, since I had seen it before and read about it, I knew...but I still think the first 30 minutes meanders around quite a bit with no clear destination, although that's not to say it's not intriguing. But then, things begin to fall into place and you have the development of a good mystery. In the end, you may reflect and say: wow! It's amazing how much they packed into 101 minutes! It's interesting how many references to homosexuality there are in this film...and that they got away with some of them. First, Peter Lorre's character is clearly effeminate, both with his behaviors and his gardenia scented calling cards. In an early scene, Bogart says to a male detective of his male partner, "What's your boyfriend getting at, Tom?" And later, when Bogart slaps a thug, "When you're slapped, you'll take it and like it." But the reason this film is sooooooo good is the acting. Although he had already been in films from 1928 - 1940, 1941 was really the year that Humphrey Bogart came into his own right as a true star, rather than a supporting actor. And it was in this film, in my view, that he showed what would be a fairly common theme throughout the rest of his career -- a good guy who was just a shade away from being a bad guy. As Sam Spade, that persona worked well, and continued to work well for Bogart in any number of pictures. The female lead -- Mary Astor -- is perfect here as a woman who is acting an evolving part in a never-ending comedy of errors; you can see she's not to be trusted, although superficially she seems highbrow, while underneath she's really a con. Gladys George, who surprisingly gets third billing, is rather irrelevant to the story as Bogart's partner's wife. I don't think how good Peter Lorre's role is here as an somewhat effeminate crook; in fact, I would say it's brilliant, and perhaps his best role. Barton MacLane is around as a detective, but his acting is always pretty static. Lee Patrick is enjoyable here as Bogart's secretary. Surprisingly way down at 7th billing is Sydney Greenstreet as "the fat man"; but this was his first film...and he turned it into a gem of a role with his evil giggling; interesting to watch his early scenes here where he is filmed sitting and you see him at an odd angle from the belly up. I've always thought that Ward Bond was an underrated actor. Here as a police detective he gets better screen time. Jerome Cowan, as Bogart's detective partner doesn't last long...killed off within minutes of the beginning of the film. Of special note here is Elisha Cook, as Wilmer, an effeminate gangster (?) who plays it too tough only to be put down repeatedly by Bogart...a very good role for him. Interestingly, John Hamilton is around as the DA (he later played Perry White in television's "Superman" series. And you have to watch carefully for the ship's captain, who turns out to be Walter Huston, director John Huston's father, in an uncredited cameo. The bottom line of this film is the old saying that there is no honor among thieves. But few films have ever portrayed that concept with such verve. Highly recommended...an exceptional (though flawed) film. Walter Huston as Captain Jacobi (uncredited)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt like I'd seen 'The Maltese Falcon' before, probably because as these things go it's pretty standard. A few dry quips, rapid fallings-in-love, double crosses, and characters pinging from hotel room to hotel room explaining the plot to each other while with every round of exposition it becomes less and less clear who did what to whom and why. I mean, it's fine but nothing special. It's worth watching for Humphrey Bogart, who is, as always, a magnetic screen presence, not the greatest actor in the world but a proper Movie Star. The highlight of the film for me, however, is the performance of Sydney Greenstreet, with his entertaining line in affable menace and a squeaky giggle that really tickled me. Solid stuff but nothing that really grabbed me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Determination solves a crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Maltese Falcon is about a detective who solves the crime of his partner's murder by dogged determination. The main plot is the solving of the crime (which ends in success), with a minor love interest subplot that ends in failure (the detective gives up the love interest after discovering she committed the murder). As a story The Maltese Falcon largely flatlines. The main plot moves from discovery to discovery but the turning points feel arbitrary and not meaningful. As the story unfolds, the detective unravels the back story of what the treasure is and how it got here. But the back story's revelation doesn't create much meaning for us or the protagonist as it mainly involves the secondary characters while our main character remains immovable and static. The main character untangles the sordid histories of these secondary characters to solve the crime, but we are left with a feeling of so what? In the end we get two somewhat moral triumphs: one, the detective solves the crime of his partner's murder despite the police messing up their investigation. But this moral victory feels empty since he and his dead partner's wife are lovers, which throws him off the moral high horse. The second is that he gives up his feelings for O'Shaughnessy and sends her to prison because he finds out she turns out to be the murderer. This moral dilemma also feels empty because: A) so he cheated on his dead partner's wife who was his lover to be with this new lover and then gives her up, how is that a moral victory? and B) The two of them only have 2 or 3 turning points to develop their relationship and their love doesn't have much to stand on. So the story is reduced to rely almost exclusively on a classic who dunnit throughline with some great actors who are unfortunately trying to breath life into empty cardboard box of characters. In other words, a big waste of time. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dashiell Hammett's "The Maltese Falcon" was a great book, but it really says something when the movie version is even more enjoyable. Well- written and directed by John Huston, there's a playfulness that comes through not only in the script, but in Humphrey Bogart's performance (who was a terrific pick for Sam Spade, by the way). It's what makes it more than just a top-notch detective story; it's an undeniable classic. Bogie's got the tough-guy act down to a T (hell, he makes it look easy), and Lee Patrick makes for a great scene foil for Bogart (she brings her own moxie to the proceedings). Peter Lorre and Sydney Greenstreet both excel at underhanded characters - Lorre, the slimy weasel and Greenstreet the refined wader of murky waters and smooth in a comical way (that chuckle is hilarious). The dialogue cracks like a whip, giving the ears a workout and making exposition scenes (dare I say it) exciting. "The Maltese Falcon" is more than a detective yarn and a film noir hallmark; it's just a consummate piece of classic Hollywood artistry. It's the sort of movie that leaves me hungry for more Bogey. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconaclastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is arguably the first Film-Noir. While it is a groundbreaking style of slick sensibilities, Camera Angles, and crisp Performances, the witty rhythmic Script is foremost the Star here. There is a surrealist, not a realism to the Dialog. A Pulped Up patter that can be found in the best Crime Fiction of Dashiell Hammett, Raymond Chandler, and James Cain. In real life People don't talk like that. "What do you want me to do, learn to stutter" answers Sam Spade. The Film is iconic Bogart and his supporters are along for the ride. He is in virtually every scene and it is his ship that the barnacles attach. Everything is dependent on the Character of Detective as he wanders through this wondering about what to do and who to do it to next. Undeniably infectious, things move at a rapid pace and is fascinating to watch. Not without flaws, such as a wordy, wondering Story and some stiffness. Still it is an important Movie, although it suffers from being Studio bound and some rather annoying, feathery Music. The end speech where Spade verbalizes his reasons for his actions is rather badly Written and Acted and almost doesn't fit with the sharpness that led us there. In short it feels tacked on and simplistic. But the rather weak ending is not enough to keep this from being a new slice of Cinema for the Forties and beyond. It is worth most of its relentless praise. There is a lot here to relish and only a few things that keep this from Greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robbieasl
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A great classic, a great film, a great Bogart (Samuel Spade) in it, a great adaptation of the book. The film is generally a very faithful adaptation of the novel, although some scenes from the novel are not in the movie. It is a tribute to the "macho" image of the detective we have lost the past years. The film has a sense of humor the book lacks and an atmosphere that's hard to describe. A treasure that you could die for. A manly, unpredictable private detective with his own morality code. A crook smelling lavender (In the book. In the movie they say gardenias), a fat man and a breathtaking red-head, no one should trust. Those are the ingredients to the Dashiell Hammett story, which has been characterized as the best mystery novel ever written. (by Otto Penzler)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in fact, only pure masterpiece. one of admirable movies who gives soul of a novel and gives to public a form of special precious joy. a detective story, maybe the best, a magnificent cast and an unique director. but the basic ingredient remains the script, admirable at whole. because each character is just collection of nuances. because the white/black is used in splendid manner because the tension, the link between character, the music, the details are remarkable it is the film of Humprhey Bogart and, in same measure, the film of Sydney Greenstreet or Mary Astor. each of theme represents not exactly image of a type but puzzle of inspired science to expose the character specificity. and Peter Lorre is, definitely, Peter Lorre in one of his most splendid works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic Movie that Deserves the Position
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most famous movies ever made. Based on a book the movie was first made in 1931 and later remade in 1941 with Humphrey Bogart playing the detective Sam Spade. Most critics, including Bill Collins, directs us to focus on the characters in the movie because it is the characterization that makes this such a great movie. I agree to a point, but I think the whole issue of the Maltese Falcon makes this such a dark movie. The book upon which this movie is based is considered to be a change in direction with the way detective stories are made. Edgar Allen Poe was the creator of the detective story and it was developed by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, but their detectives were intelligent, honourable men. Sam Spade could be seen as one of the first "Down and Out detectives." The author of The Maltese Falcons describes private detectives as police officers who do not like to work with people but rather go it alone. These characters are more crooked and ruthless than police officers. It is no wonder that the police in The Maltese Falcon are somewhat cold towards Sam Spade. Spade works with fellow Detective Miles Archer and the movie opens with a young lady, O'Shannahey, hiring Spade and Archer to trail some guy who has stolen her sister from her. Suddenly Archer is shot and the movie starts into motion. The Maltese Falcon was a statuette that was stolen by pirates as it was being delivered to the King of Spain and it has supposedly surfaced in San-Fransisco. The movie is not a search for the falcon but rather people all wanting a piece of it. The fat man, who is the villain of the movie, wants the falcon and pays Spade a lot of money to get it. He doesn't want to part with his money and has his gunsel Wilma to dispose of Captain Jacobi and get the falcon. The harsh parts of the characters are revealed with the Fat Man willing to sell out Wilma, whom he claims to consider a son, to get the Falcon off of Sam Spade. And then there is O'Shannahey, a beautiful young lady who grabs Spade's heart, yet we know that Spade does not truly love this woman as we learn that he is having an affair with Archer's wife. O'Shannahey is not what we expect. At first she comes as an innocent woman who is looking for her sister but we find a web of lies and deceit surrounding her and the more we get entangled in the lies the more sinister O'Shannahey becomes. Spade is not a hero either, rather he is an anti-hero. He his selfish and cold, ready to betray his partner for a woman, and ready to betray his lover for his reputation. He slaps around Wilma and Cairo, treating them like little children. Spade is an arrogant, self-centered person and would rather look after himself than others. I think the ending of the Maltese Falcon is brilliant. I am one who looks more at the ending of a movie than the content because it is the ending that we are left with when we leave. The ending of the Maltese Falcon is not happy, nor is it sad. Rather we are just left knowing that life will go on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big gamble that paid off.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one was tougher than Bogart.No one was more sharp tongued than Bogart.No one had just the right retort more often than Bogart.No one had a stronger screen presence than Bogart.He commanded the screen every time he graced it.In this film,he was in the hands of a young upstart screenwriter directing his very first feature,a young man named John Huston.The studio was taking a gamble.George Raft even turned down the role of Sam Spade due to Huston's inexperience as a director.More Hollywood gambles probably fail than succeed,put this one paid of big dividends.Huston's direction was excellent,Bogey was awesome as always,and the supporting cast was top notch.Very worthy of it's classic status.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slightly above mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunznc
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After all the years of hype I was very disappointed after seeing this. The dialog is dull, the story is tripe, small ideas lead to nowhere, a scene starts to heat up and then turns abruptly and stalls. Surprisingly flat, no sparkle at all. The most interesting person in the entire film is Mary Astor. Her performance is the most complex but even her own story told by herself becomes a big question mark and is also dull just like everything else. With Sydney Greenstreet and Peter Lorre one would think that the they'd be seeing something similar to Casablanca which is far more entertaining that this. But even this trio cannot save this boring film. No, Shadow of a Doubt, Sorry Wrong Number, The Damned Don't Cry and Casablanca itself are much, much more entertaining than this. See it for Bogart's performance but not much here to brag about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional (though flawed) film with brilliant performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I had watched this movie a couple of times before, when I saw a documentary that talked about, I decided that perhaps I hadn't given it its full due. So I pulled the DVD off the shelf last evening and watched it again...after reading about it on Wikipedia for some background. In terms of plot, I don't think it's any masterpiece, although it is a good story. I would fault the movie somewhat because during the first half hour (of 101 minute film) you may find yourself struggling to grasp what the movie is really about (although, since I had seen it before and read about it, I knew...but I still think the first 30 minutes meanders around quite a bit with no clear destination, although that's not to say it's not intriguing. But then, things begin to fall into place and you have the development of a good mystery. In the end, you may reflect and say: wow! It's amazing how much they packed into 101 minutes! It's interesting how many references to homosexuality there are in this film...and that they got away with some of them. First, Peter Lorre's character is clearly effeminate, both with his behaviors and his gardenia scented calling cards. In an early scene, Bogart says to a male detective of his male partner, "What's your boyfriend getting at, Tom?" And later, when Bogart slaps a thug, "When you're slapped, you'll take it and like it." But the reason this film is sooooooo good is the acting. Although he had already been in films from 1928 - 1940, 1941 was really the year that Humphrey Bogart came into his own right as a true star, rather than a supporting actor. And it was in this film, in my view, that he showed what would be a fairly common theme throughout the rest of his career -- a good guy who was just a shade away from being a bad guy. As Sam Spade, that persona worked well, and continued to work well for Bogart in any number of pictures. The female lead -- Mary Astor -- is perfect here as a woman who is acting an evolving part in a never-ending comedy of errors; you can see she's not to be trusted, although superficially she seems highbrow, while underneath she's really a con. Gladys George, who surprisingly gets third billing, is rather irrelevant to the story as Bogart's partner's wife. I don't think how good Peter Lorre's role is here as an somewhat effeminate crook; in fact, I would say it's brilliant, and perhaps his best role. Barton MacLane is around as a detective, but his acting is always pretty static. Lee Patrick is enjoyable here as Bogart's secretary. Surprisingly way down at 7th billing is Sydney Greenstreet as "the fat man"; but this was his first film...and he turned it into a gem of a role with his evil giggling; interesting to watch his early scenes here where he is filmed sitting and you see him at an odd angle from the belly up. I've always thought that Ward Bond was an underrated actor. Here as a police detective he gets better screen time. Jerome Cowan, as Bogart's detective partner doesn't last long...killed off within minutes of the beginning of the film. Of special note here is Elisha Cook, as Wilmer, an effeminate gangster (?) who plays it too tough only to be put down repeatedly by Bogart...a very good role for him. Interestingly, John Hamilton is around as the DA (he later played Perry White in television's "Superman" series. And you have to watch carefully for the ship's captain, who turns out to be Walter Huston, director John Huston's father, in an uncredited cameo. The bottom line of this film is the old saying that there is no honor among thieves. But few films have ever portrayed that concept with such verve. Highly recommended...an exceptional (though flawed) film. Walter Huston as Captain Jacobi (uncredited)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt like I'd seen 'The Maltese Falcon' before, probably because as these things go it's pretty standard. A few dry quips, rapid fallings-in-love, double crosses, and characters pinging from hotel room to hotel room explaining the plot to each other while with every round of exposition it becomes less and less clear who did what to whom and why. I mean, it's fine but nothing special. It's worth watching for Humphrey Bogart, who is, as always, a magnetic screen presence, not the greatest actor in the world but a proper Movie Star. The highlight of the film for me, however, is the performance of Sydney Greenstreet, with his entertaining line in affable menace and a squeaky giggle that really tickled me. Solid stuff but nothing that really grabbed me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Determination solves a crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Maltese Falcon is about a detective who solves the crime of his partner's murder by dogged determination. The main plot is the solving of the crime (which ends in success), with a minor love interest subplot that ends in failure (the detective gives up the love interest after discovering she committed the murder). As a story The Maltese Falcon largely flatlines. The main plot moves from discovery to discovery but the turning points feel arbitrary and not meaningful. As the story unfolds, the detective unravels the back story of what the treasure is and how it got here. But the back story's revelation doesn't create much meaning for us or the protagonist as it mainly involves the secondary characters while our main character remains immovable and static. The main character untangles the sordid histories of these secondary characters to solve the crime, but we are left with a feeling of so what? In the end we get two somewhat moral triumphs: one, the detective solves the crime of his partner's murder despite the police messing up their investigation. But this moral victory feels empty since he and his dead partner's wife are lovers, which throws him off the moral high horse. The second is that he gives up his feelings for O'Shaughnessy and sends her to prison because he finds out she turns out to be the murderer. This moral dilemma also feels empty because: A) so he cheated on his dead partner's wife who was his lover to be with this new lover and then gives her up, how is that a moral victory? and B) The two of them only have 2 or 3 turning points to develop their relationship and their love doesn't have much to stand on. So the story is reduced to rely almost exclusively on a classic who dunnit throughline with some great actors who are unfortunately trying to breath life into empty cardboard box of characters. In other words, a big waste of time. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dashiell Hammett's "The Maltese Falcon" was a great book, but it really says something when the movie version is even more enjoyable. Well- written and directed by John Huston, there's a playfulness that comes through not only in the script, but in Humphrey Bogart's performance (who was a terrific pick for Sam Spade, by the way). It's what makes it more than just a top-notch detective story; it's an undeniable classic. Bogie's got the tough-guy act down to a T (hell, he makes it look easy), and Lee Patrick makes for a great scene foil for Bogart (she brings her own moxie to the proceedings). Peter Lorre and Sydney Greenstreet both excel at underhanded characters - Lorre, the slimy weasel and Greenstreet the refined wader of murky waters and smooth in a comical way (that chuckle is hilarious). The dialogue cracks like a whip, giving the ears a workout and making exposition scenes (dare I say it) exciting. "The Maltese Falcon" is more than a detective yarn and a film noir hallmark; it's just a consummate piece of classic Hollywood artistry. It's the sort of movie that leaves me hungry for more Bogey. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconaclastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is arguably the first Film-Noir. While it is a groundbreaking style of slick sensibilities, Camera Angles, and crisp Performances, the witty rhythmic Script is foremost the Star here. There is a surrealist, not a realism to the Dialog. A Pulped Up patter that can be found in the best Crime Fiction of Dashiell Hammett, Raymond Chandler, and James Cain. In real life People don't talk like that. "What do you want me to do, learn to stutter" answers Sam Spade. The Film is iconic Bogart and his supporters are along for the ride. He is in virtually every scene and it is his ship that the barnacles attach. Everything is dependent on the Character of Detective as he wanders through this wondering about what to do and who to do it to next. Undeniably infectious, things move at a rapid pace and is fascinating to watch. Not without flaws, such as a wordy, wondering Story and some stiffness. Still it is an important Movie, although it suffers from being Studio bound and some rather annoying, feathery Music. The end speech where Spade verbalizes his reasons for his actions is rather badly Written and Acted and almost doesn't fit with the sharpness that led us there. In short it feels tacked on and simplistic. But the rather weak ending is not enough to keep this from being a new slice of Cinema for the Forties and beyond. It is worth most of its relentless praise. There is a lot here to relish and only a few things that keep this from Greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robbieasl
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A great classic, a great film, a great Bogart (Samuel Spade) in it, a great adaptation of the book. The film is generally a very faithful adaptation of the novel, although some scenes from the novel are not in the movie. It is a tribute to the "macho" image of the detective we have lost the past years. The film has a sense of humor the book lacks and an atmosphere that's hard to describe. A treasure that you could die for. A manly, unpredictable private detective with his own morality code. A crook smelling lavender (In the book. In the movie they say gardenias), a fat man and a breathtaking red-head, no one should trust. Those are the ingredients to the Dashiell Hammett story, which has been characterized as the best mystery novel ever written. (by Otto Penzler)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in fact, only pure masterpiece. one of admirable movies who gives soul of a novel and gives to public a form of special precious joy. a detective story, maybe the best, a magnificent cast and an unique director. but the basic ingredient remains the script, admirable at whole. because each character is just collection of nuances. because the white/black is used in splendid manner because the tension, the link between character, the music, the details are remarkable it is the film of Humprhey Bogart and, in same measure, the film of Sydney Greenstreet or Mary Astor. each of theme represents not exactly image of a type but puzzle of inspired science to expose the character specificity. and Peter Lorre is, definitely, Peter Lorre in one of his most splendid works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic Movie that Deserves the Position
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most famous movies ever made. Based on a book the movie was first made in 1931 and later remade in 1941 with Humphrey Bogart playing the detective Sam Spade. Most critics, including Bill Collins, directs us to focus on the characters in the movie because it is the characterization that makes this such a great movie. I agree to a point, but I think the whole issue of the Maltese Falcon makes this such a dark movie. The book upon which this movie is based is considered to be a change in direction with the way detective stories are made. Edgar Allen Poe was the creator of the detective story and it was developed by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, but their detectives were intelligent, honourable men. Sam Spade could be seen as one of the first "Down and Out detectives." The author of The Maltese Falcons describes private detectives as police officers who do not like to work with people but rather go it alone. These characters are more crooked and ruthless than police officers. It is no wonder that the police in The Maltese Falcon are somewhat cold towards Sam Spade. Spade works with fellow Detective Miles Archer and the movie opens with a young lady, O'Shannahey, hiring Spade and Archer to trail some guy who has stolen her sister from her. Suddenly Archer is shot and the movie starts into motion. The Maltese Falcon was a statuette that was stolen by pirates as it was being delivered to the King of Spain and it has supposedly surfaced in San-Fransisco. The movie is not a search for the falcon but rather people all wanting a piece of it. The fat man, who is the villain of the movie, wants the falcon and pays Spade a lot of money to get it. He doesn't want to part with his money and has his gunsel Wilma to dispose of Captain Jacobi and get the falcon. The harsh parts of the characters are revealed with the Fat Man willing to sell out Wilma, whom he claims to consider a son, to get the Falcon off of Sam Spade. And then there is O'Shannahey, a beautiful young lady who grabs Spade's heart, yet we know that Spade does not truly love this woman as we learn that he is having an affair with Archer's wife. O'Shannahey is not what we expect. At first she comes as an innocent woman who is looking for her sister but we find a web of lies and deceit surrounding her and the more we get entangled in the lies the more sinister O'Shannahey becomes. Spade is not a hero either, rather he is an anti-hero. He his selfish and cold, ready to betray his partner for a woman, and ready to betray his lover for his reputation. He slaps around Wilma and Cairo, treating them like little children. Spade is an arrogant, self-centered person and would rather look after himself than others. I think the ending of the Maltese Falcon is brilliant. I am one who looks more at the ending of a movie than the content because it is the ending that we are left with when we leave. The ending of the Maltese Falcon is not happy, nor is it sad. Rather we are just left knowing that life will go on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big gamble that paid off.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one was tougher than Bogart.No one was more sharp tongued than Bogart.No one had just the right retort more often than Bogart.No one had a stronger screen presence than Bogart.He commanded the screen every time he graced it.In this film,he was in the hands of a young upstart screenwriter directing his very first feature,a young man named John Huston.The studio was taking a gamble.George Raft even turned down the role of Sam Spade due to Huston's inexperience as a director.More Hollywood gambles probably fail than succeed,put this one paid of big dividends.Huston's direction was excellent,Bogey was awesome as always,and the supporting cast was top notch.Very worthy of it's classic status.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slightly above mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunznc
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After all the years of hype I was very disappointed after seeing this. The dialog is dull, the story is tripe, small ideas lead to nowhere, a scene starts to heat up and then turns abruptly and stalls. Surprisingly flat, no sparkle at all. The most interesting person in the entire film is Mary Astor. Her performance is the most complex but even her own story told by herself becomes a big question mark and is also dull just like everything else. With Sydney Greenstreet and Peter Lorre one would think that the they'd be seeing something similar to Casablanca which is far more entertaining that this. But even this trio cannot save this boring film. No, Shadow of a Doubt, Sorry Wrong Number, The Damned Don't Cry and Casablanca itself are much, much more entertaining than this. See it for Bogart's performance but not much here to brag about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional (though flawed) film with brilliant performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I had watched this movie a couple of times before, when I saw a documentary that talked about, I decided that perhaps I hadn't given it its full due. So I pulled the DVD off the shelf last evening and watched it again...after reading about it on Wikipedia for some background. In terms of plot, I don't think it's any masterpiece, although it is a good story. I would fault the movie somewhat because during the first half hour (of 101 minute film) you may find yourself struggling to grasp what the movie is really about (although, since I had seen it before and read about it, I knew...but I still think the first 30 minutes meanders around quite a bit with no clear destination, although that's not to say it's not intriguing. But then, things begin to fall into place and you have the development of a good mystery. In the end, you may reflect and say: wow! It's amazing how much they packed into 101 minutes! It's interesting how many references to homosexuality there are in this film...and that they got away with some of them. First, Peter Lorre's character is clearly effeminate, both with his behaviors and his gardenia scented calling cards. In an early scene, Bogart says to a male detective of his male partner, "What's your boyfriend getting at, Tom?" And later, when Bogart slaps a thug, "When you're slapped, you'll take it and like it." But the reason this film is sooooooo good is the acting. Although he had already been in films from 1928 - 1940, 1941 was really the year that Humphrey Bogart came into his own right as a true star, rather than a supporting actor. And it was in this film, in my view, that he showed what would be a fairly common theme throughout the rest of his career -- a good guy who was just a shade away from being a bad guy. As Sam Spade, that persona worked well, and continued to work well for Bogart in any number of pictures. The female lead -- Mary Astor -- is perfect here as a woman who is acting an evolving part in a never-ending comedy of errors; you can see she's not to be trusted, although superficially she seems highbrow, while underneath she's really a con. Gladys George, who surprisingly gets third billing, is rather irrelevant to the story as Bogart's partner's wife. I don't think how good Peter Lorre's role is here as an somewhat effeminate crook; in fact, I would say it's brilliant, and perhaps his best role. Barton MacLane is around as a detective, but his acting is always pretty static. Lee Patrick is enjoyable here as Bogart's secretary. Surprisingly way down at 7th billing is Sydney Greenstreet as "the fat man"; but this was his first film...and he turned it into a gem of a role with his evil giggling; interesting to watch his early scenes here where he is filmed sitting and you see him at an odd angle from the belly up. I've always thought that Ward Bond was an underrated actor. Here as a police detective he gets better screen time. Jerome Cowan, as Bogart's detective partner doesn't last long...killed off within minutes of the beginning of the film. Of special note here is Elisha Cook, as Wilmer, an effeminate gangster (?) who plays it too tough only to be put down repeatedly by Bogart...a very good role for him. Interestingly, John Hamilton is around as the DA (he later played Perry White in television's "Superman" series. And you have to watch carefully for the ship's captain, who turns out to be Walter Huston, director John Huston's father, in an uncredited cameo. The bottom line of this film is the old saying that there is no honor among thieves. But few films have ever portrayed that concept with such verve. Highly recommended...an exceptional (though flawed) film. Walter Huston as Captain Jacobi (uncredited)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt like I'd seen 'The Maltese Falcon' before, probably because as these things go it's pretty standard. A few dry quips, rapid fallings-in-love, double crosses, and characters pinging from hotel room to hotel room explaining the plot to each other while with every round of exposition it becomes less and less clear who did what to whom and why. I mean, it's fine but nothing special. It's worth watching for Humphrey Bogart, who is, as always, a magnetic screen presence, not the greatest actor in the world but a proper Movie Star. The highlight of the film for me, however, is the performance of Sydney Greenstreet, with his entertaining line in affable menace and a squeaky giggle that really tickled me. Solid stuff but nothing that really grabbed me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Determination solves a crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Maltese Falcon is about a detective who solves the crime of his partner's murder by dogged determination. The main plot is the solving of the crime (which ends in success), with a minor love interest subplot that ends in failure (the detective gives up the love interest after discovering she committed the murder). As a story The Maltese Falcon largely flatlines. The main plot moves from discovery to discovery but the turning points feel arbitrary and not meaningful. As the story unfolds, the detective unravels the back story of what the treasure is and how it got here. But the back story's revelation doesn't create much meaning for us or the protagonist as it mainly involves the secondary characters while our main character remains immovable and static. The main character untangles the sordid histories of these secondary characters to solve the crime, but we are left with a feeling of so what? In the end we get two somewhat moral triumphs: one, the detective solves the crime of his partner's murder despite the police messing up their investigation. But this moral victory feels empty since he and his dead partner's wife are lovers, which throws him off the moral high horse. The second is that he gives up his feelings for O'Shaughnessy and sends her to prison because he finds out she turns out to be the murderer. This moral dilemma also feels empty because: A) so he cheated on his dead partner's wife who was his lover to be with this new lover and then gives her up, how is that a moral victory? and B) The two of them only have 2 or 3 turning points to develop their relationship and their love doesn't have much to stand on. So the story is reduced to rely almost exclusively on a classic who dunnit throughline with some great actors who are unfortunately trying to breath life into empty cardboard box of characters. In other words, a big waste of time. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dashiell Hammett's "The Maltese Falcon" was a great book, but it really says something when the movie version is even more enjoyable. Well- written and directed by John Huston, there's a playfulness that comes through not only in the script, but in Humphrey Bogart's performance (who was a terrific pick for Sam Spade, by the way). It's what makes it more than just a top-notch detective story; it's an undeniable classic. Bogie's got the tough-guy act down to a T (hell, he makes it look easy), and Lee Patrick makes for a great scene foil for Bogart (she brings her own moxie to the proceedings). Peter Lorre and Sydney Greenstreet both excel at underhanded characters - Lorre, the slimy weasel and Greenstreet the refined wader of murky waters and smooth in a comical way (that chuckle is hilarious). The dialogue cracks like a whip, giving the ears a workout and making exposition scenes (dare I say it) exciting. "The Maltese Falcon" is more than a detective yarn and a film noir hallmark; it's just a consummate piece of classic Hollywood artistry. It's the sort of movie that leaves me hungry for more Bogey. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconaclastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is arguably the first Film-Noir. While it is a groundbreaking style of slick sensibilities, Camera Angles, and crisp Performances, the witty rhythmic Script is foremost the Star here. There is a surrealist, not a realism to the Dialog. A Pulped Up patter that can be found in the best Crime Fiction of Dashiell Hammett, Raymond Chandler, and James Cain. In real life People don't talk like that. "What do you want me to do, learn to stutter" answers Sam Spade. The Film is iconic Bogart and his supporters are along for the ride. He is in virtually every scene and it is his ship that the barnacles attach. Everything is dependent on the Character of Detective as he wanders through this wondering about what to do and who to do it to next. Undeniably infectious, things move at a rapid pace and is fascinating to watch. Not without flaws, such as a wordy, wondering Story and some stiffness. Still it is an important Movie, although it suffers from being Studio bound and some rather annoying, feathery Music. The end speech where Spade verbalizes his reasons for his actions is rather badly Written and Acted and almost doesn't fit with the sharpness that led us there. In short it feels tacked on and simplistic. But the rather weak ending is not enough to keep this from being a new slice of Cinema for the Forties and beyond. It is worth most of its relentless praise. There is a lot here to relish and only a few things that keep this from Greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robbieasl
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A great classic, a great film, a great Bogart (Samuel Spade) in it, a great adaptation of the book. The film is generally a very faithful adaptation of the novel, although some scenes from the novel are not in the movie. It is a tribute to the "macho" image of the detective we have lost the past years. The film has a sense of humor the book lacks and an atmosphere that's hard to describe. A treasure that you could die for. A manly, unpredictable private detective with his own morality code. A crook smelling lavender (In the book. In the movie they say gardenias), a fat man and a breathtaking red-head, no one should trust. Those are the ingredients to the Dashiell Hammett story, which has been characterized as the best mystery novel ever written. (by Otto Penzler)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in fact, only pure masterpiece. one of admirable movies who gives soul of a novel and gives to public a form of special precious joy. a detective story, maybe the best, a magnificent cast and an unique director. but the basic ingredient remains the script, admirable at whole. because each character is just collection of nuances. because the white/black is used in splendid manner because the tension, the link between character, the music, the details are remarkable it is the film of Humprhey Bogart and, in same measure, the film of Sydney Greenstreet or Mary Astor. each of theme represents not exactly image of a type but puzzle of inspired science to expose the character specificity. and Peter Lorre is, definitely, Peter Lorre in one of his most splendid works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic Movie that Deserves the Position
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most famous movies ever made. Based on a book the movie was first made in 1931 and later remade in 1941 with Humphrey Bogart playing the detective Sam Spade. Most critics, including Bill Collins, directs us to focus on the characters in the movie because it is the characterization that makes this such a great movie. I agree to a point, but I think the whole issue of the Maltese Falcon makes this such a dark movie. The book upon which this movie is based is considered to be a change in direction with the way detective stories are made. Edgar Allen Poe was the creator of the detective story and it was developed by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, but their detectives were intelligent, honourable men. Sam Spade could be seen as one of the first "Down and Out detectives." The author of The Maltese Falcons describes private detectives as police officers who do not like to work with people but rather go it alone. These characters are more crooked and ruthless than police officers. It is no wonder that the police in The Maltese Falcon are somewhat cold towards Sam Spade. Spade works with fellow Detective Miles Archer and the movie opens with a young lady, O'Shannahey, hiring Spade and Archer to trail some guy who has stolen her sister from her. Suddenly Archer is shot and the movie starts into motion. The Maltese Falcon was a statuette that was stolen by pirates as it was being delivered to the King of Spain and it has supposedly surfaced in San-Fransisco. The movie is not a search for the falcon but rather people all wanting a piece of it. The fat man, who is the villain of the movie, wants the falcon and pays Spade a lot of money to get it. He doesn't want to part with his money and has his gunsel Wilma to dispose of Captain Jacobi and get the falcon. The harsh parts of the characters are revealed with the Fat Man willing to sell out Wilma, whom he claims to consider a son, to get the Falcon off of Sam Spade. And then there is O'Shannahey, a beautiful young lady who grabs Spade's heart, yet we know that Spade does not truly love this woman as we learn that he is having an affair with Archer's wife. O'Shannahey is not what we expect. At first she comes as an innocent woman who is looking for her sister but we find a web of lies and deceit surrounding her and the more we get entangled in the lies the more sinister O'Shannahey becomes. Spade is not a hero either, rather he is an anti-hero. He his selfish and cold, ready to betray his partner for a woman, and ready to betray his lover for his reputation. He slaps around Wilma and Cairo, treating them like little children. Spade is an arrogant, self-centered person and would rather look after himself than others. I think the ending of the Maltese Falcon is brilliant. I am one who looks more at the ending of a movie than the content because it is the ending that we are left with when we leave. The ending of the Maltese Falcon is not happy, nor is it sad. Rather we are just left knowing that life will go on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big gamble that paid off.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one was tougher than Bogart.No one was more sharp tongued than Bogart.No one had just the right retort more often than Bogart.No one had a stronger screen presence than Bogart.He commanded the screen every time he graced it.In this film,he was in the hands of a young upstart screenwriter directing his very first feature,a young man named John Huston.The studio was taking a gamble.George Raft even turned down the role of Sam Spade due to Huston's inexperience as a director.More Hollywood gambles probably fail than succeed,put this one paid of big dividends.Huston's direction was excellent,Bogey was awesome as always,and the supporting cast was top notch.Very worthy of it's classic status.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slightly above mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunznc
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After all the years of hype I was very disappointed after seeing this. The dialog is dull, the story is tripe, small ideas lead to nowhere, a scene starts to heat up and then turns abruptly and stalls. Surprisingly flat, no sparkle at all. The most interesting person in the entire film is Mary Astor. Her performance is the most complex but even her own story told by herself becomes a big question mark and is also dull just like everything else. With Sydney Greenstreet and Peter Lorre one would think that the they'd be seeing something similar to Casablanca which is far more entertaining that this. But even this trio cannot save this boring film. No, Shadow of a Doubt, Sorry Wrong Number, The Damned Don't Cry and Casablanca itself are much, much more entertaining than this. See it for Bogart's performance but not much here to brag about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional (though flawed) film with brilliant performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I had watched this movie a couple of times before, when I saw a documentary that talked about, I decided that perhaps I hadn't given it its full due. So I pulled the DVD off the shelf last evening and watched it again...after reading about it on Wikipedia for some background. In terms of plot, I don't think it's any masterpiece, although it is a good story. I would fault the movie somewhat because during the first half hour (of 101 minute film) you may find yourself struggling to grasp what the movie is really about (although, since I had seen it before and read about it, I knew...but I still think the first 30 minutes meanders around quite a bit with no clear destination, although that's not to say it's not intriguing. But then, things begin to fall into place and you have the development of a good mystery. In the end, you may reflect and say: wow! It's amazing how much they packed into 101 minutes! It's interesting how many references to homosexuality there are in this film...and that they got away with some of them. First, Peter Lorre's character is clearly effeminate, both with his behaviors and his gardenia scented calling cards. In an early scene, Bogart says to a male detective of his male partner, "What's your boyfriend getting at, Tom?" And later, when Bogart slaps a thug, "When you're slapped, you'll take it and like it." But the reason this film is sooooooo good is the acting. Although he had already been in films from 1928 - 1940, 1941 was really the year that Humphrey Bogart came into his own right as a true star, rather than a supporting actor. And it was in this film, in my view, that he showed what would be a fairly common theme throughout the rest of his career -- a good guy who was just a shade away from being a bad guy. As Sam Spade, that persona worked well, and continued to work well for Bogart in any number of pictures. The female lead -- Mary Astor -- is perfect here as a woman who is acting an evolving part in a never-ending comedy of errors; you can see she's not to be trusted, although superficially she seems highbrow, while underneath she's really a con. Gladys George, who surprisingly gets third billing, is rather irrelevant to the story as Bogart's partner's wife. I don't think how good Peter Lorre's role is here as an somewhat effeminate crook; in fact, I would say it's brilliant, and perhaps his best role. Barton MacLane is around as a detective, but his acting is always pretty static. Lee Patrick is enjoyable here as Bogart's secretary. Surprisingly way down at 7th billing is Sydney Greenstreet as "the fat man"; but this was his first film...and he turned it into a gem of a role with his evil giggling; interesting to watch his early scenes here where he is filmed sitting and you see him at an odd angle from the belly up. I've always thought that Ward Bond was an underrated actor. Here as a police detective he gets better screen time. Jerome Cowan, as Bogart's detective partner doesn't last long...killed off within minutes of the beginning of the film. Of special note here is Elisha Cook, as Wilmer, an effeminate gangster (?) who plays it too tough only to be put down repeatedly by Bogart...a very good role for him. Interestingly, John Hamilton is around as the DA (he later played Perry White in television's "Superman" series. And you have to watch carefully for the ship's captain, who turns out to be Walter Huston, director John Huston's father, in an uncredited cameo. The bottom line of this film is the old saying that there is no honor among thieves. But few films have ever portrayed that concept with such verve. Highly recommended...an exceptional (though flawed) film. Walter Huston as Captain Jacobi (uncredited)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt like I'd seen 'The Maltese Falcon' before, probably because as these things go it's pretty standard. A few dry quips, rapid fallings-in-love, double crosses, and characters pinging from hotel room to hotel room explaining the plot to each other while with every round of exposition it becomes less and less clear who did what to whom and why. I mean, it's fine but nothing special. It's worth watching for Humphrey Bogart, who is, as always, a magnetic screen presence, not the greatest actor in the world but a proper Movie Star. The highlight of the film for me, however, is the performance of Sydney Greenstreet, with his entertaining line in affable menace and a squeaky giggle that really tickled me. Solid stuff but nothing that really grabbed me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Determination solves a crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Maltese Falcon is about a detective who solves the crime of his partner's murder by dogged determination. The main plot is the solving of the crime (which ends in success), with a minor love interest subplot that ends in failure (the detective gives up the love interest after discovering she committed the murder). As a story The Maltese Falcon largely flatlines. The main plot moves from discovery to discovery but the turning points feel arbitrary and not meaningful. As the story unfolds, the detective unravels the back story of what the treasure is and how it got here. But the back story's revelation doesn't create much meaning for us or the protagonist as it mainly involves the secondary characters while our main character remains immovable and static. The main character untangles the sordid histories of these secondary characters to solve the crime, but we are left with a feeling of so what? In the end we get two somewhat moral triumphs: one, the detective solves the crime of his partner's murder despite the police messing up their investigation. But this moral victory feels empty since he and his dead partner's wife are lovers, which throws him off the moral high horse. The second is that he gives up his feelings for O'Shaughnessy and sends her to prison because he finds out she turns out to be the murderer. This moral dilemma also feels empty because: A) so he cheated on his dead partner's wife who was his lover to be with this new lover and then gives her up, how is that a moral victory? and B) The two of them only have 2 or 3 turning points to develop their relationship and their love doesn't have much to stand on. So the story is reduced to rely almost exclusively on a classic who dunnit throughline with some great actors who are unfortunately trying to breath life into empty cardboard box of characters. In other words, a big waste of time. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dashiell Hammett's "The Maltese Falcon" was a great book, but it really says something when the movie version is even more enjoyable. Well- written and directed by John Huston, there's a playfulness that comes through not only in the script, but in Humphrey Bogart's performance (who was a terrific pick for Sam Spade, by the way). It's what makes it more than just a top-notch detective story; it's an undeniable classic. Bogie's got the tough-guy act down to a T (hell, he makes it look easy), and Lee Patrick makes for a great scene foil for Bogart (she brings her own moxie to the proceedings). Peter Lorre and Sydney Greenstreet both excel at underhanded characters - Lorre, the slimy weasel and Greenstreet the refined wader of murky waters and smooth in a comical way (that chuckle is hilarious). The dialogue cracks like a whip, giving the ears a workout and making exposition scenes (dare I say it) exciting. "The Maltese Falcon" is more than a detective yarn and a film noir hallmark; it's just a consummate piece of classic Hollywood artistry. It's the sort of movie that leaves me hungry for more Bogey. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconaclastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is arguably the first Film-Noir. While it is a groundbreaking style of slick sensibilities, Camera Angles, and crisp Performances, the witty rhythmic Script is foremost the Star here. There is a surrealist, not a realism to the Dialog. A Pulped Up patter that can be found in the best Crime Fiction of Dashiell Hammett, Raymond Chandler, and James Cain. In real life People don't talk like that. "What do you want me to do, learn to stutter" answers Sam Spade. The Film is iconic Bogart and his supporters are along for the ride. He is in virtually every scene and it is his ship that the barnacles attach. Everything is dependent on the Character of Detective as he wanders through this wondering about what to do and who to do it to next. Undeniably infectious, things move at a rapid pace and is fascinating to watch. Not without flaws, such as a wordy, wondering Story and some stiffness. Still it is an important Movie, although it suffers from being Studio bound and some rather annoying, feathery Music. The end speech where Spade verbalizes his reasons for his actions is rather badly Written and Acted and almost doesn't fit with the sharpness that led us there. In short it feels tacked on and simplistic. But the rather weak ending is not enough to keep this from being a new slice of Cinema for the Forties and beyond. It is worth most of its relentless praise. There is a lot here to relish and only a few things that keep this from Greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robbieasl
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A great classic, a great film, a great Bogart (Samuel Spade) in it, a great adaptation of the book. The film is generally a very faithful adaptation of the novel, although some scenes from the novel are not in the movie. It is a tribute to the "macho" image of the detective we have lost the past years. The film has a sense of humor the book lacks and an atmosphere that's hard to describe. A treasure that you could die for. A manly, unpredictable private detective with his own morality code. A crook smelling lavender (In the book. In the movie they say gardenias), a fat man and a breathtaking red-head, no one should trust. Those are the ingredients to the Dashiell Hammett story, which has been characterized as the best mystery novel ever written. (by Otto Penzler)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in fact, only pure masterpiece. one of admirable movies who gives soul of a novel and gives to public a form of special precious joy. a detective story, maybe the best, a magnificent cast and an unique director. but the basic ingredient remains the script, admirable at whole. because each character is just collection of nuances. because the white/black is used in splendid manner because the tension, the link between character, the music, the details are remarkable it is the film of Humprhey Bogart and, in same measure, the film of Sydney Greenstreet or Mary Astor. each of theme represents not exactly image of a type but puzzle of inspired science to expose the character specificity. and Peter Lorre is, definitely, Peter Lorre in one of his most splendid works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic Movie that Deserves the Position
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most famous movies ever made. Based on a book the movie was first made in 1931 and later remade in 1941 with Humphrey Bogart playing the detective Sam Spade. Most critics, including Bill Collins, directs us to focus on the characters in the movie because it is the characterization that makes this such a great movie. I agree to a point, but I think the whole issue of the Maltese Falcon makes this such a dark movie. The book upon which this movie is based is considered to be a change in direction with the way detective stories are made. Edgar Allen Poe was the creator of the detective story and it was developed by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, but their detectives were intelligent, honourable men. Sam Spade could be seen as one of the first "Down and Out detectives." The author of The Maltese Falcons describes private detectives as police officers who do not like to work with people but rather go it alone. These characters are more crooked and ruthless than police officers. It is no wonder that the police in The Maltese Falcon are somewhat cold towards Sam Spade. Spade works with fellow Detective Miles Archer and the movie opens with a young lady, O'Shannahey, hiring Spade and Archer to trail some guy who has stolen her sister from her. Suddenly Archer is shot and the movie starts into motion. The Maltese Falcon was a statuette that was stolen by pirates as it was being delivered to the King of Spain and it has supposedly surfaced in San-Fransisco. The movie is not a search for the falcon but rather people all wanting a piece of it. The fat man, who is the villain of the movie, wants the falcon and pays Spade a lot of money to get it. He doesn't want to part with his money and has his gunsel Wilma to dispose of Captain Jacobi and get the falcon. The harsh parts of the characters are revealed with the Fat Man willing to sell out Wilma, whom he claims to consider a son, to get the Falcon off of Sam Spade. And then there is O'Shannahey, a beautiful young lady who grabs Spade's heart, yet we know that Spade does not truly love this woman as we learn that he is having an affair with Archer's wife. O'Shannahey is not what we expect. At first she comes as an innocent woman who is looking for her sister but we find a web of lies and deceit surrounding her and the more we get entangled in the lies the more sinister O'Shannahey becomes. Spade is not a hero either, rather he is an anti-hero. He his selfish and cold, ready to betray his partner for a woman, and ready to betray his lover for his reputation. He slaps around Wilma and Cairo, treating them like little children. Spade is an arrogant, self-centered person and would rather look after himself than others. I think the ending of the Maltese Falcon is brilliant. I am one who looks more at the ending of a movie than the content because it is the ending that we are left with when we leave. The ending of the Maltese Falcon is not happy, nor is it sad. Rather we are just left knowing that life will go on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big gamble that paid off.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one was tougher than Bogart.No one was more sharp tongued than Bogart.No one had just the right retort more often than Bogart.No one had a stronger screen presence than Bogart.He commanded the screen every time he graced it.In this film,he was in the hands of a young upstart screenwriter directing his very first feature,a young man named John Huston.The studio was taking a gamble.George Raft even turned down the role of Sam Spade due to Huston's inexperience as a director.More Hollywood gambles probably fail than succeed,put this one paid of big dividends.Huston's direction was excellent,Bogey was awesome as always,and the supporting cast was top notch.Very worthy of it's classic status.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slightly above mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunznc
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After all the years of hype I was very disappointed after seeing this. The dialog is dull, the story is tripe, small ideas lead to nowhere, a scene starts to heat up and then turns abruptly and stalls. Surprisingly flat, no sparkle at all. The most interesting person in the entire film is Mary Astor. Her performance is the most complex but even her own story told by herself becomes a big question mark and is also dull just like everything else. With Sydney Greenstreet and Peter Lorre one would think that the they'd be seeing something similar to Casablanca which is far more entertaining that this. But even this trio cannot save this boring film. No, Shadow of a Doubt, Sorry Wrong Number, The Damned Don't Cry and Casablanca itself are much, much more entertaining than this. See it for Bogart's performance but not much here to brag about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional (though flawed) film with brilliant performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I had watched this movie a couple of times before, when I saw a documentary that talked about, I decided that perhaps I hadn't given it its full due. So I pulled the DVD off the shelf last evening and watched it again...after reading about it on Wikipedia for some background. In terms of plot, I don't think it's any masterpiece, although it is a good story. I would fault the movie somewhat because during the first half hour (of 101 minute film) you may find yourself struggling to grasp what the movie is really about (although, since I had seen it before and read about it, I knew...but I still think the first 30 minutes meanders around quite a bit with no clear destination, although that's not to say it's not intriguing. But then, things begin to fall into place and you have the development of a good mystery. In the end, you may reflect and say: wow! It's amazing how much they packed into 101 minutes! It's interesting how many references to homosexuality there are in this film...and that they got away with some of them. First, Peter Lorre's character is clearly effeminate, both with his behaviors and his gardenia scented calling cards. In an early scene, Bogart says to a male detective of his male partner, "What's your boyfriend getting at, Tom?" And later, when Bogart slaps a thug, "When you're slapped, you'll take it and like it." But the reason this film is sooooooo good is the acting. Although he had already been in films from 1928 - 1940, 1941 was really the year that Humphrey Bogart came into his own right as a true star, rather than a supporting actor. And it was in this film, in my view, that he showed what would be a fairly common theme throughout the rest of his career -- a good guy who was just a shade away from being a bad guy. As Sam Spade, that persona worked well, and continued to work well for Bogart in any number of pictures. The female lead -- Mary Astor -- is perfect here as a woman who is acting an evolving part in a never-ending comedy of errors; you can see she's not to be trusted, although superficially she seems highbrow, while underneath she's really a con. Gladys George, who surprisingly gets third billing, is rather irrelevant to the story as Bogart's partner's wife. I don't think how good Peter Lorre's role is here as an somewhat effeminate crook; in fact, I would say it's brilliant, and perhaps his best role. Barton MacLane is around as a detective, but his acting is always pretty static. Lee Patrick is enjoyable here as Bogart's secretary. Surprisingly way down at 7th billing is Sydney Greenstreet as "the fat man"; but this was his first film...and he turned it into a gem of a role with his evil giggling; interesting to watch his early scenes here where he is filmed sitting and you see him at an odd angle from the belly up. I've always thought that Ward Bond was an underrated actor. Here as a police detective he gets better screen time. Jerome Cowan, as Bogart's detective partner doesn't last long...killed off within minutes of the beginning of the film. Of special note here is Elisha Cook, as Wilmer, an effeminate gangster (?) who plays it too tough only to be put down repeatedly by Bogart...a very good role for him. Interestingly, John Hamilton is around as the DA (he later played Perry White in television's "Superman" series. And you have to watch carefully for the ship's captain, who turns out to be Walter Huston, director John Huston's father, in an uncredited cameo. The bottom line of this film is the old saying that there is no honor among thieves. But few films have ever portrayed that concept with such verve. Highly recommended...an exceptional (though flawed) film. Walter Huston as Captain Jacobi (uncredited)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt like I'd seen 'The Maltese Falcon' before, probably because as these things go it's pretty standard. A few dry quips, rapid fallings-in-love, double crosses, and characters pinging from hotel room to hotel room explaining the plot to each other while with every round of exposition it becomes less and less clear who did what to whom and why. I mean, it's fine but nothing special. It's worth watching for Humphrey Bogart, who is, as always, a magnetic screen presence, not the greatest actor in the world but a proper Movie Star. The highlight of the film for me, however, is the performance of Sydney Greenstreet, with his entertaining line in affable menace and a squeaky giggle that really tickled me. Solid stuff but nothing that really grabbed me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Determination solves a crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Maltese Falcon is about a detective who solves the crime of his partner's murder by dogged determination. The main plot is the solving of the crime (which ends in success), with a minor love interest subplot that ends in failure (the detective gives up the love interest after discovering she committed the murder). As a story The Maltese Falcon largely flatlines. The main plot moves from discovery to discovery but the turning points feel arbitrary and not meaningful. As the story unfolds, the detective unravels the back story of what the treasure is and how it got here. But the back story's revelation doesn't create much meaning for us or the protagonist as it mainly involves the secondary characters while our main character remains immovable and static. The main character untangles the sordid histories of these secondary characters to solve the crime, but we are left with a feeling of so what? In the end we get two somewhat moral triumphs: one, the detective solves the crime of his partner's murder despite the police messing up their investigation. But this moral victory feels empty since he and his dead partner's wife are lovers, which throws him off the moral high horse. The second is that he gives up his feelings for O'Shaughnessy and sends her to prison because he finds out she turns out to be the murderer. This moral dilemma also feels empty because: A) so he cheated on his dead partner's wife who was his lover to be with this new lover and then gives her up, how is that a moral victory? and B) The two of them only have 2 or 3 turning points to develop their relationship and their love doesn't have much to stand on. So the story is reduced to rely almost exclusively on a classic who dunnit throughline with some great actors who are unfortunately trying to breath life into empty cardboard box of characters. In other words, a big waste of time. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dashiell Hammett's "The Maltese Falcon" was a great book, but it really says something when the movie version is even more enjoyable. Well- written and directed by John Huston, there's a playfulness that comes through not only in the script, but in Humphrey Bogart's performance (who was a terrific pick for Sam Spade, by the way). It's what makes it more than just a top-notch detective story; it's an undeniable classic. Bogie's got the tough-guy act down to a T (hell, he makes it look easy), and Lee Patrick makes for a great scene foil for Bogart (she brings her own moxie to the proceedings). Peter Lorre and Sydney Greenstreet both excel at underhanded characters - Lorre, the slimy weasel and Greenstreet the refined wader of murky waters and smooth in a comical way (that chuckle is hilarious). The dialogue cracks like a whip, giving the ears a workout and making exposition scenes (dare I say it) exciting. "The Maltese Falcon" is more than a detective yarn and a film noir hallmark; it's just a consummate piece of classic Hollywood artistry. It's the sort of movie that leaves me hungry for more Bogey. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconaclastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is arguably the first Film-Noir. While it is a groundbreaking style of slick sensibilities, Camera Angles, and crisp Performances, the witty rhythmic Script is foremost the Star here. There is a surrealist, not a realism to the Dialog. A Pulped Up patter that can be found in the best Crime Fiction of Dashiell Hammett, Raymond Chandler, and James Cain. In real life People don't talk like that. "What do you want me to do, learn to stutter" answers Sam Spade. The Film is iconic Bogart and his supporters are along for the ride. He is in virtually every scene and it is his ship that the barnacles attach. Everything is dependent on the Character of Detective as he wanders through this wondering about what to do and who to do it to next. Undeniably infectious, things move at a rapid pace and is fascinating to watch. Not without flaws, such as a wordy, wondering Story and some stiffness. Still it is an important Movie, although it suffers from being Studio bound and some rather annoying, feathery Music. The end speech where Spade verbalizes his reasons for his actions is rather badly Written and Acted and almost doesn't fit with the sharpness that led us there. In short it feels tacked on and simplistic. But the rather weak ending is not enough to keep this from being a new slice of Cinema for the Forties and beyond. It is worth most of its relentless praise. There is a lot here to relish and only a few things that keep this from Greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robbieasl
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A great classic, a great film, a great Bogart (Samuel Spade) in it, a great adaptation of the book. The film is generally a very faithful adaptation of the novel, although some scenes from the novel are not in the movie. It is a tribute to the "macho" image of the detective we have lost the past years. The film has a sense of humor the book lacks and an atmosphere that's hard to describe. A treasure that you could die for. A manly, unpredictable private detective with his own morality code. A crook smelling lavender (In the book. In the movie they say gardenias), a fat man and a breathtaking red-head, no one should trust. Those are the ingredients to the Dashiell Hammett story, which has been characterized as the best mystery novel ever written. (by Otto Penzler)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in fact, only pure masterpiece. one of admirable movies who gives soul of a novel and gives to public a form of special precious joy. a detective story, maybe the best, a magnificent cast and an unique director. but the basic ingredient remains the script, admirable at whole. because each character is just collection of nuances. because the white/black is used in splendid manner because the tension, the link between character, the music, the details are remarkable it is the film of Humprhey Bogart and, in same measure, the film of Sydney Greenstreet or Mary Astor. each of theme represents not exactly image of a type but puzzle of inspired science to expose the character specificity. and Peter Lorre is, definitely, Peter Lorre in one of his most splendid works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic Movie that Deserves the Position
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most famous movies ever made. Based on a book the movie was first made in 1931 and later remade in 1941 with Humphrey Bogart playing the detective Sam Spade. Most critics, including Bill Collins, directs us to focus on the characters in the movie because it is the characterization that makes this such a great movie. I agree to a point, but I think the whole issue of the Maltese Falcon makes this such a dark movie. The book upon which this movie is based is considered to be a change in direction with the way detective stories are made. Edgar Allen Poe was the creator of the detective story and it was developed by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, but their detectives were intelligent, honourable men. Sam Spade could be seen as one of the first "Down and Out detectives." The author of The Maltese Falcons describes private detectives as police officers who do not like to work with people but rather go it alone. These characters are more crooked and ruthless than police officers. It is no wonder that the police in The Maltese Falcon are somewhat cold towards Sam Spade. Spade works with fellow Detective Miles Archer and the movie opens with a young lady, O'Shannahey, hiring Spade and Archer to trail some guy who has stolen her sister from her. Suddenly Archer is shot and the movie starts into motion. The Maltese Falcon was a statuette that was stolen by pirates as it was being delivered to the King of Spain and it has supposedly surfaced in San-Fransisco. The movie is not a search for the falcon but rather people all wanting a piece of it. The fat man, who is the villain of the movie, wants the falcon and pays Spade a lot of money to get it. He doesn't want to part with his money and has his gunsel Wilma to dispose of Captain Jacobi and get the falcon. The harsh parts of the characters are revealed with the Fat Man willing to sell out Wilma, whom he claims to consider a son, to get the Falcon off of Sam Spade. And then there is O'Shannahey, a beautiful young lady who grabs Spade's heart, yet we know that Spade does not truly love this woman as we learn that he is having an affair with Archer's wife. O'Shannahey is not what we expect. At first she comes as an innocent woman who is looking for her sister but we find a web of lies and deceit surrounding her and the more we get entangled in the lies the more sinister O'Shannahey becomes. Spade is not a hero either, rather he is an anti-hero. He his selfish and cold, ready to betray his partner for a woman, and ready to betray his lover for his reputation. He slaps around Wilma and Cairo, treating them like little children. Spade is an arrogant, self-centered person and would rather look after himself than others. I think the ending of the Maltese Falcon is brilliant. I am one who looks more at the ending of a movie than the content because it is the ending that we are left with when we leave. The ending of the Maltese Falcon is not happy, nor is it sad. Rather we are just left knowing that life will go on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big gamble that paid off.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one was tougher than Bogart.No one was more sharp tongued than Bogart.No one had just the right retort more often than Bogart.No one had a stronger screen presence than Bogart.He commanded the screen every time he graced it.In this film,he was in the hands of a young upstart screenwriter directing his very first feature,a young man named John Huston.The studio was taking a gamble.George Raft even turned down the role of Sam Spade due to Huston's inexperience as a director.More Hollywood gambles probably fail than succeed,put this one paid of big dividends.Huston's direction was excellent,Bogey was awesome as always,and the supporting cast was top notch.Very worthy of it's classic status.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slightly above mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunznc
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After all the years of hype I was very disappointed after seeing this. The dialog is dull, the story is tripe, small ideas lead to nowhere, a scene starts to heat up and then turns abruptly and stalls. Surprisingly flat, no sparkle at all. The most interesting person in the entire film is Mary Astor. Her performance is the most complex but even her own story told by herself becomes a big question mark and is also dull just like everything else. With Sydney Greenstreet and Peter Lorre one would think that the they'd be seeing something similar to Casablanca which is far more entertaining that this. But even this trio cannot save this boring film. No, Shadow of a Doubt, Sorry Wrong Number, The Damned Don't Cry and Casablanca itself are much, much more entertaining than this. See it for Bogart's performance but not much here to brag about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional (though flawed) film with brilliant performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I had watched this movie a couple of times before, when I saw a documentary that talked about, I decided that perhaps I hadn't given it its full due. So I pulled the DVD off the shelf last evening and watched it again...after reading about it on Wikipedia for some background. In terms of plot, I don't think it's any masterpiece, although it is a good story. I would fault the movie somewhat because during the first half hour (of 101 minute film) you may find yourself struggling to grasp what the movie is really about (although, since I had seen it before and read about it, I knew...but I still think the first 30 minutes meanders around quite a bit with no clear destination, although that's not to say it's not intriguing. But then, things begin to fall into place and you have the development of a good mystery. In the end, you may reflect and say: wow! It's amazing how much they packed into 101 minutes! It's interesting how many references to homosexuality there are in this film...and that they got away with some of them. First, Peter Lorre's character is clearly effeminate, both with his behaviors and his gardenia scented calling cards. In an early scene, Bogart says to a male detective of his male partner, "What's your boyfriend getting at, Tom?" And later, when Bogart slaps a thug, "When you're slapped, you'll take it and like it." But the reason this film is sooooooo good is the acting. Although he had already been in films from 1928 - 1940, 1941 was really the year that Humphrey Bogart came into his own right as a true star, rather than a supporting actor. And it was in this film, in my view, that he showed what would be a fairly common theme throughout the rest of his career -- a good guy who was just a shade away from being a bad guy. As Sam Spade, that persona worked well, and continued to work well for Bogart in any number of pictures. The female lead -- Mary Astor -- is perfect here as a woman who is acting an evolving part in a never-ending comedy of errors; you can see she's not to be trusted, although superficially she seems highbrow, while underneath she's really a con. Gladys George, who surprisingly gets third billing, is rather irrelevant to the story as Bogart's partner's wife. I don't think how good Peter Lorre's role is here as an somewhat effeminate crook; in fact, I would say it's brilliant, and perhaps his best role. Barton MacLane is around as a detective, but his acting is always pretty static. Lee Patrick is enjoyable here as Bogart's secretary. Surprisingly way down at 7th billing is Sydney Greenstreet as "the fat man"; but this was his first film...and he turned it into a gem of a role with his evil giggling; interesting to watch his early scenes here where he is filmed sitting and you see him at an odd angle from the belly up. I've always thought that Ward Bond was an underrated actor. Here as a police detective he gets better screen time. Jerome Cowan, as Bogart's detective partner doesn't last long...killed off within minutes of the beginning of the film. Of special note here is Elisha Cook, as Wilmer, an effeminate gangster (?) who plays it too tough only to be put down repeatedly by Bogart...a very good role for him. Interestingly, John Hamilton is around as the DA (he later played Perry White in television's "Superman" series. And you have to watch carefully for the ship's captain, who turns out to be Walter Huston, director John Huston's father, in an uncredited cameo. The bottom line of this film is the old saying that there is no honor among thieves. But few films have ever portrayed that concept with such verve. Highly recommended...an exceptional (though flawed) film. Walter Huston as Captain Jacobi (uncredited)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt like I'd seen 'The Maltese Falcon' before, probably because as these things go it's pretty standard. A few dry quips, rapid fallings-in-love, double crosses, and characters pinging from hotel room to hotel room explaining the plot to each other while with every round of exposition it becomes less and less clear who did what to whom and why. I mean, it's fine but nothing special. It's worth watching for Humphrey Bogart, who is, as always, a magnetic screen presence, not the greatest actor in the world but a proper Movie Star. The highlight of the film for me, however, is the performance of Sydney Greenstreet, with his entertaining line in affable menace and a squeaky giggle that really tickled me. Solid stuff but nothing that really grabbed me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Determination solves a crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Maltese Falcon is about a detective who solves the crime of his partner's murder by dogged determination. The main plot is the solving of the crime (which ends in success), with a minor love interest subplot that ends in failure (the detective gives up the love interest after discovering she committed the murder). As a story The Maltese Falcon largely flatlines. The main plot moves from discovery to discovery but the turning points feel arbitrary and not meaningful. As the story unfolds, the detective unravels the back story of what the treasure is and how it got here. But the back story's revelation doesn't create much meaning for us or the protagonist as it mainly involves the secondary characters while our main character remains immovable and static. The main character untangles the sordid histories of these secondary characters to solve the crime, but we are left with a feeling of so what? In the end we get two somewhat moral triumphs: one, the detective solves the crime of his partner's murder despite the police messing up their investigation. But this moral victory feels empty since he and his dead partner's wife are lovers, which throws him off the moral high horse. The second is that he gives up his feelings for O'Shaughnessy and sends her to prison because he finds out she turns out to be the murderer. This moral dilemma also feels empty because: A) so he cheated on his dead partner's wife who was his lover to be with this new lover and then gives her up, how is that a moral victory? and B) The two of them only have 2 or 3 turning points to develop their relationship and their love doesn't have much to stand on. So the story is reduced to rely almost exclusively on a classic who dunnit throughline with some great actors who are unfortunately trying to breath life into empty cardboard box of characters. In other words, a big waste of time. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dashiell Hammett's "The Maltese Falcon" was a great book, but it really says something when the movie version is even more enjoyable. Well- written and directed by John Huston, there's a playfulness that comes through not only in the script, but in Humphrey Bogart's performance (who was a terrific pick for Sam Spade, by the way). It's what makes it more than just a top-notch detective story; it's an undeniable classic. Bogie's got the tough-guy act down to a T (hell, he makes it look easy), and Lee Patrick makes for a great scene foil for Bogart (she brings her own moxie to the proceedings). Peter Lorre and Sydney Greenstreet both excel at underhanded characters - Lorre, the slimy weasel and Greenstreet the refined wader of murky waters and smooth in a comical way (that chuckle is hilarious). The dialogue cracks like a whip, giving the ears a workout and making exposition scenes (dare I say it) exciting. "The Maltese Falcon" is more than a detective yarn and a film noir hallmark; it's just a consummate piece of classic Hollywood artistry. It's the sort of movie that leaves me hungry for more Bogey. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconaclastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is arguably the first Film-Noir. While it is a groundbreaking style of slick sensibilities, Camera Angles, and crisp Performances, the witty rhythmic Script is foremost the Star here. There is a surrealist, not a realism to the Dialog. A Pulped Up patter that can be found in the best Crime Fiction of Dashiell Hammett, Raymond Chandler, and James Cain. In real life People don't talk like that. "What do you want me to do, learn to stutter" answers Sam Spade. The Film is iconic Bogart and his supporters are along for the ride. He is in virtually every scene and it is his ship that the barnacles attach. Everything is dependent on the Character of Detective as he wanders through this wondering about what to do and who to do it to next. Undeniably infectious, things move at a rapid pace and is fascinating to watch. Not without flaws, such as a wordy, wondering Story and some stiffness. Still it is an important Movie, although it suffers from being Studio bound and some rather annoying, feathery Music. The end speech where Spade verbalizes his reasons for his actions is rather badly Written and Acted and almost doesn't fit with the sharpness that led us there. In short it feels tacked on and simplistic. But the rather weak ending is not enough to keep this from being a new slice of Cinema for the Forties and beyond. It is worth most of its relentless praise. There is a lot here to relish and only a few things that keep this from Greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robbieasl
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A great classic, a great film, a great Bogart (Samuel Spade) in it, a great adaptation of the book. The film is generally a very faithful adaptation of the novel, although some scenes from the novel are not in the movie. It is a tribute to the "macho" image of the detective we have lost the past years. The film has a sense of humor the book lacks and an atmosphere that's hard to describe. A treasure that you could die for. A manly, unpredictable private detective with his own morality code. A crook smelling lavender (In the book. In the movie they say gardenias), a fat man and a breathtaking red-head, no one should trust. Those are the ingredients to the Dashiell Hammett story, which has been characterized as the best mystery novel ever written. (by Otto Penzler)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in fact, only pure masterpiece. one of admirable movies who gives soul of a novel and gives to public a form of special precious joy. a detective story, maybe the best, a magnificent cast and an unique director. but the basic ingredient remains the script, admirable at whole. because each character is just collection of nuances. because the white/black is used in splendid manner because the tension, the link between character, the music, the details are remarkable it is the film of Humprhey Bogart and, in same measure, the film of Sydney Greenstreet or Mary Astor. each of theme represents not exactly image of a type but puzzle of inspired science to expose the character specificity. and Peter Lorre is, definitely, Peter Lorre in one of his most splendid works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic Movie that Deserves the Position
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most famous movies ever made. Based on a book the movie was first made in 1931 and later remade in 1941 with Humphrey Bogart playing the detective Sam Spade. Most critics, including Bill Collins, directs us to focus on the characters in the movie because it is the characterization that makes this such a great movie. I agree to a point, but I think the whole issue of the Maltese Falcon makes this such a dark movie. The book upon which this movie is based is considered to be a change in direction with the way detective stories are made. Edgar Allen Poe was the creator of the detective story and it was developed by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, but their detectives were intelligent, honourable men. Sam Spade could be seen as one of the first "Down and Out detectives." The author of The Maltese Falcons describes private detectives as police officers who do not like to work with people but rather go it alone. These characters are more crooked and ruthless than police officers. It is no wonder that the police in The Maltese Falcon are somewhat cold towards Sam Spade. Spade works with fellow Detective Miles Archer and the movie opens with a young lady, O'Shannahey, hiring Spade and Archer to trail some guy who has stolen her sister from her. Suddenly Archer is shot and the movie starts into motion. The Maltese Falcon was a statuette that was stolen by pirates as it was being delivered to the King of Spain and it has supposedly surfaced in San-Fransisco. The movie is not a search for the falcon but rather people all wanting a piece of it. The fat man, who is the villain of the movie, wants the falcon and pays Spade a lot of money to get it. He doesn't want to part with his money and has his gunsel Wilma to dispose of Captain Jacobi and get the falcon. The harsh parts of the characters are revealed with the Fat Man willing to sell out Wilma, whom he claims to consider a son, to get the Falcon off of Sam Spade. And then there is O'Shannahey, a beautiful young lady who grabs Spade's heart, yet we know that Spade does not truly love this woman as we learn that he is having an affair with Archer's wife. O'Shannahey is not what we expect. At first she comes as an innocent woman who is looking for her sister but we find a web of lies and deceit surrounding her and the more we get entangled in the lies the more sinister O'Shannahey becomes. Spade is not a hero either, rather he is an anti-hero. He his selfish and cold, ready to betray his partner for a woman, and ready to betray his lover for his reputation. He slaps around Wilma and Cairo, treating them like little children. Spade is an arrogant, self-centered person and would rather look after himself than others. I think the ending of the Maltese Falcon is brilliant. I am one who looks more at the ending of a movie than the content because it is the ending that we are left with when we leave. The ending of the Maltese Falcon is not happy, nor is it sad. Rather we are just left knowing that life will go on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big gamble that paid off.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one was tougher than Bogart.No one was more sharp tongued than Bogart.No one had just the right retort more often than Bogart.No one had a stronger screen presence than Bogart.He commanded the screen every time he graced it.In this film,he was in the hands of a young upstart screenwriter directing his very first feature,a young man named John Huston.The studio was taking a gamble.George Raft even turned down the role of Sam Spade due to Huston's inexperience as a director.More Hollywood gambles probably fail than succeed,put this one paid of big dividends.Huston's direction was excellent,Bogey was awesome as always,and the supporting cast was top notch.Very worthy of it's classic status.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slightly above mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunznc
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After all the years of hype I was very disappointed after seeing this. The dialog is dull, the story is tripe, small ideas lead to nowhere, a scene starts to heat up and then turns abruptly and stalls. Surprisingly flat, no sparkle at all. The most interesting person in the entire film is Mary Astor. Her performance is the most complex but even her own story told by herself becomes a big question mark and is also dull just like everything else. With Sydney Greenstreet and Peter Lorre one would think that the they'd be seeing something similar to Casablanca which is far more entertaining that this. But even this trio cannot save this boring film. No, Shadow of a Doubt, Sorry Wrong Number, The Damned Don't Cry and Casablanca itself are much, much more entertaining than this. See it for Bogart's performance but not much here to brag about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional (though flawed) film with brilliant performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I had watched this movie a couple of times before, when I saw a documentary that talked about, I decided that perhaps I hadn't given it its full due. So I pulled the DVD off the shelf last evening and watched it again...after reading about it on Wikipedia for some background. In terms of plot, I don't think it's any masterpiece, although it is a good story. I would fault the movie somewhat because during the first half hour (of 101 minute film) you may find yourself struggling to grasp what the movie is really about (although, since I had seen it before and read about it, I knew...but I still think the first 30 minutes meanders around quite a bit with no clear destination, although that's not to say it's not intriguing. But then, things begin to fall into place and you have the development of a good mystery. In the end, you may reflect and say: wow! It's amazing how much they packed into 101 minutes! It's interesting how many references to homosexuality there are in this film...and that they got away with some of them. First, Peter Lorre's character is clearly effeminate, both with his behaviors and his gardenia scented calling cards. In an early scene, Bogart says to a male detective of his male partner, "What's your boyfriend getting at, Tom?" And later, when Bogart slaps a thug, "When you're slapped, you'll take it and like it." But the reason this film is sooooooo good is the acting. Although he had already been in films from 1928 - 1940, 1941 was really the year that Humphrey Bogart came into his own right as a true star, rather than a supporting actor. And it was in this film, in my view, that he showed what would be a fairly common theme throughout the rest of his career -- a good guy who was just a shade away from being a bad guy. As Sam Spade, that persona worked well, and continued to work well for Bogart in any number of pictures. The female lead -- Mary Astor -- is perfect here as a woman who is acting an evolving part in a never-ending comedy of errors; you can see she's not to be trusted, although superficially she seems highbrow, while underneath she's really a con. Gladys George, who surprisingly gets third billing, is rather irrelevant to the story as Bogart's partner's wife. I don't think how good Peter Lorre's role is here as an somewhat effeminate crook; in fact, I would say it's brilliant, and perhaps his best role. Barton MacLane is around as a detective, but his acting is always pretty static. Lee Patrick is enjoyable here as Bogart's secretary. Surprisingly way down at 7th billing is Sydney Greenstreet as "the fat man"; but this was his first film...and he turned it into a gem of a role with his evil giggling; interesting to watch his early scenes here where he is filmed sitting and you see him at an odd angle from the belly up. I've always thought that Ward Bond was an underrated actor. Here as a police detective he gets better screen time. Jerome Cowan, as Bogart's detective partner doesn't last long...killed off within minutes of the beginning of the film. Of special note here is Elisha Cook, as Wilmer, an effeminate gangster (?) who plays it too tough only to be put down repeatedly by Bogart...a very good role for him. Interestingly, John Hamilton is around as the DA (he later played Perry White in television's "Superman" series. And you have to watch carefully for the ship's captain, who turns out to be Walter Huston, director John Huston's father, in an uncredited cameo. The bottom line of this film is the old saying that there is no honor among thieves. But few films have ever portrayed that concept with such verve. Highly recommended...an exceptional (though flawed) film. Walter Huston as Captain Jacobi (uncredited)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt like I'd seen 'The Maltese Falcon' before, probably because as these things go it's pretty standard. A few dry quips, rapid fallings-in-love, double crosses, and characters pinging from hotel room to hotel room explaining the plot to each other while with every round of exposition it becomes less and less clear who did what to whom and why. I mean, it's fine but nothing special. It's worth watching for Humphrey Bogart, who is, as always, a magnetic screen presence, not the greatest actor in the world but a proper Movie Star. The highlight of the film for me, however, is the performance of Sydney Greenstreet, with his entertaining line in affable menace and a squeaky giggle that really tickled me. Solid stuff but nothing that really grabbed me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Determination solves a crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Maltese Falcon is about a detective who solves the crime of his partner's murder by dogged determination. The main plot is the solving of the crime (which ends in success), with a minor love interest subplot that ends in failure (the detective gives up the love interest after discovering she committed the murder). As a story The Maltese Falcon largely flatlines. The main plot moves from discovery to discovery but the turning points feel arbitrary and not meaningful. As the story unfolds, the detective unravels the back story of what the treasure is and how it got here. But the back story's revelation doesn't create much meaning for us or the protagonist as it mainly involves the secondary characters while our main character remains immovable and static. The main character untangles the sordid histories of these secondary characters to solve the crime, but we are left with a feeling of so what? In the end we get two somewhat moral triumphs: one, the detective solves the crime of his partner's murder despite the police messing up their investigation. But this moral victory feels empty since he and his dead partner's wife are lovers, which throws him off the moral high horse. The second is that he gives up his feelings for O'Shaughnessy and sends her to prison because he finds out she turns out to be the murderer. This moral dilemma also feels empty because: A) so he cheated on his dead partner's wife who was his lover to be with this new lover and then gives her up, how is that a moral victory? and B) The two of them only have 2 or 3 turning points to develop their relationship and their love doesn't have much to stand on. So the story is reduced to rely almost exclusively on a classic who dunnit throughline with some great actors who are unfortunately trying to breath life into empty cardboard box of characters. In other words, a big waste of time. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dashiell Hammett's "The Maltese Falcon" was a great book, but it really says something when the movie version is even more enjoyable. Well- written and directed by John Huston, there's a playfulness that comes through not only in the script, but in Humphrey Bogart's performance (who was a terrific pick for Sam Spade, by the way). It's what makes it more than just a top-notch detective story; it's an undeniable classic. Bogie's got the tough-guy act down to a T (hell, he makes it look easy), and Lee Patrick makes for a great scene foil for Bogart (she brings her own moxie to the proceedings). Peter Lorre and Sydney Greenstreet both excel at underhanded characters - Lorre, the slimy weasel and Greenstreet the refined wader of murky waters and smooth in a comical way (that chuckle is hilarious). The dialogue cracks like a whip, giving the ears a workout and making exposition scenes (dare I say it) exciting. "The Maltese Falcon" is more than a detective yarn and a film noir hallmark; it's just a consummate piece of classic Hollywood artistry. It's the sort of movie that leaves me hungry for more Bogey. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconaclastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is arguably the first Film-Noir. While it is a groundbreaking style of slick sensibilities, Camera Angles, and crisp Performances, the witty rhythmic Script is foremost the Star here. There is a surrealist, not a realism to the Dialog. A Pulped Up patter that can be found in the best Crime Fiction of Dashiell Hammett, Raymond Chandler, and James Cain. In real life People don't talk like that. "What do you want me to do, learn to stutter" answers Sam Spade. The Film is iconic Bogart and his supporters are along for the ride. He is in virtually every scene and it is his ship that the barnacles attach. Everything is dependent on the Character of Detective as he wanders through this wondering about what to do and who to do it to next. Undeniably infectious, things move at a rapid pace and is fascinating to watch. Not without flaws, such as a wordy, wondering Story and some stiffness. Still it is an important Movie, although it suffers from being Studio bound and some rather annoying, feathery Music. The end speech where Spade verbalizes his reasons for his actions is rather badly Written and Acted and almost doesn't fit with the sharpness that led us there. In short it feels tacked on and simplistic. But the rather weak ending is not enough to keep this from being a new slice of Cinema for the Forties and beyond. It is worth most of its relentless praise. There is a lot here to relish and only a few things that keep this from Greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robbieasl
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A great classic, a great film, a great Bogart (Samuel Spade) in it, a great adaptation of the book. The film is generally a very faithful adaptation of the novel, although some scenes from the novel are not in the movie. It is a tribute to the "macho" image of the detective we have lost the past years. The film has a sense of humor the book lacks and an atmosphere that's hard to describe. A treasure that you could die for. A manly, unpredictable private detective with his own morality code. A crook smelling lavender (In the book. In the movie they say gardenias), a fat man and a breathtaking red-head, no one should trust. Those are the ingredients to the Dashiell Hammett story, which has been characterized as the best mystery novel ever written. (by Otto Penzler)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    memorable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in fact, only pure masterpiece. one of admirable movies who gives soul of a novel and gives to public a form of special precious joy. a detective story, maybe the best, a magnificent cast and an unique director. but the basic ingredient remains the script, admirable at whole. because each character is just collection of nuances. because the white/black is used in splendid manner because the tension, the link between character, the music, the details are remarkable it is the film of Humprhey Bogart and, in same measure, the film of Sydney Greenstreet or Mary Astor. each of theme represents not exactly image of a type but puzzle of inspired science to expose the character specificity. and Peter Lorre is, definitely, Peter Lorre in one of his most splendid works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic Movie that Deserves the Position
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most famous movies ever made. Based on a book the movie was first made in 1931 and later remade in 1941 with Humphrey Bogart playing the detective Sam Spade. Most critics, including Bill Collins, directs us to focus on the characters in the movie because it is the characterization that makes this such a great movie. I agree to a point, but I think the whole issue of the Maltese Falcon makes this such a dark movie. The book upon which this movie is based is considered to be a change in direction with the way detective stories are made. Edgar Allen Poe was the creator of the detective story and it was developed by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, but their detectives were intelligent, honourable men. Sam Spade could be seen as one of the first "Down and Out detectives." The author of The Maltese Falcons describes private detectives as police officers who do not like to work with people but rather go it alone. These characters are more crooked and ruthless than police officers. It is no wonder that the police in The Maltese Falcon are somewhat cold towards Sam Spade. Spade works with fellow Detective Miles Archer and the movie opens with a young lady, O'Shannahey, hiring Spade and Archer to trail some guy who has stolen her sister from her. Suddenly Archer is shot and the movie starts into motion. The Maltese Falcon was a statuette that was stolen by pirates as it was being delivered to the King of Spain and it has supposedly surfaced in San-Fransisco. The movie is not a search for the falcon but rather people all wanting a piece of it. The fat man, who is the villain of the movie, wants the falcon and pays Spade a lot of money to get it. He doesn't want to part with his money and has his gunsel Wilma to dispose of Captain Jacobi and get the falcon. The harsh parts of the characters are revealed with the Fat Man willing to sell out Wilma, whom he claims to consider a son, to get the Falcon off of Sam Spade. And then there is O'Shannahey, a beautiful young lady who grabs Spade's heart, yet we know that Spade does not truly love this woman as we learn that he is having an affair with Archer's wife. O'Shannahey is not what we expect. At first she comes as an innocent woman who is looking for her sister but we find a web of lies and deceit surrounding her and the more we get entangled in the lies the more sinister O'Shannahey becomes. Spade is not a hero either, rather he is an anti-hero. He his selfish and cold, ready to betray his partner for a woman, and ready to betray his lover for his reputation. He slaps around Wilma and Cairo, treating them like little children. Spade is an arrogant, self-centered person and would rather look after himself than others. I think the ending of the Maltese Falcon is brilliant. I am one who looks more at the ending of a movie than the content because it is the ending that we are left with when we leave. The ending of the Maltese Falcon is not happy, nor is it sad. Rather we are just left knowing that life will go on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big gamble that paid off.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No one was tougher than Bogart.No one was more sharp tongued than Bogart.No one had just the right retort more often than Bogart.No one had a stronger screen presence than Bogart.He commanded the screen every time he graced it.In this film,he was in the hands of a young upstart screenwriter directing his very first feature,a young man named John Huston.The studio was taking a gamble.George Raft even turned down the role of Sam Spade due to Huston's inexperience as a director.More Hollywood gambles probably fail than succeed,put this one paid of big dividends.Huston's direction was excellent,Bogey was awesome as always,and the supporting cast was top notch.Very worthy of it's classic status.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slightly above mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunznc
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After all the years of hype I was very disappointed after seeing this. The dialog is dull, the story is tripe, small ideas lead to nowhere, a scene starts to heat up and then turns abruptly and stalls. Surprisingly flat, no sparkle at all. The most interesting person in the entire film is Mary Astor. Her performance is the most complex but even her own story told by herself becomes a big question mark and is also dull just like everything else. With Sydney Greenstreet and Peter Lorre one would think that the they'd be seeing something similar to Casablanca which is far more entertaining that this. But even this trio cannot save this boring film. No, Shadow of a Doubt, Sorry Wrong Number, The Damned Don't Cry and Casablanca itself are much, much more entertaining than this. See it for Bogart's performance but not much here to brag about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional (though flawed) film with brilliant performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I had watched this movie a couple of times before, when I saw a documentary that talked about, I decided that perhaps I hadn't given it its full due. So I pulled the DVD off the shelf last evening and watched it again...after reading about it on Wikipedia for some background. In terms of plot, I don't think it's any masterpiece, although it is a good story. I would fault the movie somewhat because during the first half hour (of 101 minute film) you may find yourself struggling to grasp what the movie is really about (although, since I had seen it before and read about it, I knew...but I still think the first 30 minutes meanders around quite a bit with no clear destination, although that's not to say it's not intriguing. But then, things begin to fall into place and you have the development of a good mystery. In the end, you may reflect and say: wow! It's amazing how much they packed into 101 minutes! It's interesting how many references to homosexuality there are in this film...and that they got away with some of them. First, Peter Lorre's character is clearly effeminate, both with his behaviors and his gardenia scented calling cards. In an early scene, Bogart says to a male detective of his male partner, "What's your boyfriend getting at, Tom?" And later, when Bogart slaps a thug, "When you're slapped, you'll take it and like it." But the reason this film is sooooooo good is the acting. Although he had already been in films from 1928 - 1940, 1941 was really the year that Humphrey Bogart came into his own right as a true star, rather than a supporting actor. And it was in this film, in my view, that he showed what would be a fairly common theme throughout the rest of his career -- a good guy who was just a shade away from being a bad guy. As Sam Spade, that persona worked well, and continued to work well for Bogart in any number of pictures. The female lead -- Mary Astor -- is perfect here as a woman who is acting an evolving part in a never-ending comedy of errors; you can see she's not to be trusted, although superficially she seems highbrow, while underneath she's really a con. Gladys George, who surprisingly gets third billing, is rather irrelevant to the story as Bogart's partner's wife. I don't think how good Peter Lorre's role is here as an somewhat effeminate crook; in fact, I would say it's brilliant, and perhaps his best role. Barton MacLane is around as a detective, but his acting is always pretty static. Lee Patrick is enjoyable here as Bogart's secretary. Surprisingly way down at 7th billing is Sydney Greenstreet as "the fat man"; but this was his first film...and he turned it into a gem of a role with his evil giggling; interesting to watch his early scenes here where he is filmed sitting and you see him at an odd angle from the belly up. I've always thought that Ward Bond was an underrated actor. Here as a police detective he gets better screen time. Jerome Cowan, as Bogart's detective partner doesn't last long...killed off within minutes of the beginning of the film. Of special note here is Elisha Cook, as Wilmer, an effeminate gangster (?) who plays it too tough only to be put down repeatedly by Bogart...a very good role for him. Interestingly, John Hamilton is around as the DA (he later played Perry White in television's "Superman" series. And you have to watch carefully for the ship's captain, who turns out to be Walter Huston, director John Huston's father, in an uncredited cameo. The bottom line of this film is the old saying that there is no honor among thieves. But few films have ever portrayed that concept with such verve. Highly recommended...an exceptional (though flawed) film. Walter Huston as Captain Jacobi (uncredited)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt like I'd seen 'The Maltese Falcon' before, probably because as these things go it's pretty standard. A few dry quips, rapid fallings-in-love, double crosses, and characters pinging from hotel room to hotel room explaining the plot to each other while with every round of exposition it becomes less and less clear who did what to whom and why. I mean, it's fine but nothing special. It's worth watching for Humphrey Bogart, who is, as always, a magnetic screen presence, not the greatest actor in the world but a proper Movie Star. The highlight of the film for me, however, is the performance of Sydney Greenstreet, with his entertaining line in affable menace and a squeaky giggle that really tickled me. Solid stuff but nothing that really grabbed me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Determination solves a crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Maltese Falcon is about a detective who solves the crime of his partner's murder by dogged determination. The main plot is the solving of the crime (which ends in success), with a minor love interest subplot that ends in failure (the detective gives up the love interest after discovering she committed the murder). As a story The Maltese Falcon largely flatlines. The main plot moves from discovery to discovery but the turning points feel arbitrary and not meaningful. As the story unfolds, the detective unravels the back story of what the treasure is and how it got here. But the back story's revelation doesn't create much meaning for us or the protagonist as it mainly involves the secondary characters while our main character remains immovable and static. The main character untangles the sordid histories of these secondary characters to solve the crime, but we are left with a feeling of so what? In the end we get two somewhat moral triumphs: one, the detective solves the crime of his partner's murder despite the police messing up their investigation. But this moral victory feels empty since he and his dead partner's wife are lovers, which throws him off the moral high horse. The second is that he gives up his feelings for O'Shaughnessy and sends her to prison because he finds out she turns out to be the murderer. This moral dilemma also feels empty because: A) so he cheated on his dead partner's wife who was his lover to be with this new lover and then gives her up, how is that a moral victory? and B) The two of them only have 2 or 3 turning points to develop their relationship and their love doesn't have much to stand on. So the story is reduced to rely almost exclusively on a classic who dunnit throughline with some great actors who are unfortunately trying to breath life into empty cardboard box of characters. In other words, a big waste of time. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dashiell Hammett's "The Maltese Falcon" was a great book, but it really says something when the movie version is even more enjoyable. Well- written and directed by John Huston, there's a playfulness that comes through not only in the script, but in Humphrey Bogart's performance (who was a terrific pick for Sam Spade, by the way). It's what makes it more than just a top-notch detective story; it's an undeniable classic. Bogie's got the tough-guy act down to a T (hell, he makes it look easy), and Lee Patrick makes for a great scene foil for Bogart (she brings her own moxie to the proceedings). Peter Lorre and Sydney Greenstreet both excel at underhanded characters - Lorre, the slimy weasel and Greenstreet the refined wader of murky waters and smooth in a comical way (that chuckle is hilarious). The dialogue cracks like a whip, giving the ears a workout and making exposition scenes (dare I say it) exciting. "The Maltese Falcon" is more than a detective yarn and a film noir hallmark; it's just a consummate piece of classic Hollywood artistry. It's the sort of movie that leaves me hungry for more Bogey. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconaclastic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is arguably the first Film-Noir. While it is a groundbreaking style of slick sensibilities, Camera Angles, and crisp Performances, the witty rhythmic Script is foremost the Star here. There is a surrealist, not a realism to the Dialog. A Pulped Up patter that can be found in the best Crime Fiction of Dashiell Hammett, Raymond Chandler, and James Cain. In real life People don't talk like that. "What do you want me to do, learn to stutter" answers Sam Spade. The Film is iconic Bogart and his supporters are along for the ride. He is in virtually every scene and it is his ship that the barnacles attach. Everything is dependent on the Character of Detective as he wanders through this wondering about what to do and who to do it to next. Undeniably infectious, things move at a rapid pace and is fascinating to watch. Not without flaws, such as a wordy, wondering Story and some stiffness. Still it is an important Movie, although it suffers from being Studio bound and some rather annoying, feathery Music. The end speech where Spade verbalizes his reasons for his actions is rather badly Written and Acted and almost doesn't fit with the sharpness that led us there. In short it feels tacked on and simplistic. But the rather weak ending is not enough to keep this from being a new slice of Cinema for the Forties and beyond. It is worth most of its relentless praise. There is a lot here to relish and only a few things that keep this from Greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
