<filme>
 <id>
  485
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0058385
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1964
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Minha Bela Dama
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A misogynistic and snobbish phonetics professor agrees to a wager that he can take a flower girl and make her presentable in high society.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Gloriously witty adaptation of the Broadway musical about Professor Henry Higgins, who takes a bet from Colonel Pickering that he can transform unrefined, dirty Cockney flower girl Eliza Doolittle into a lady, and fool everyone into thinking she really is one, too! He does, and thus young aristocrat Freddy Eynsford-Hill falls madly in love with her. But when Higgins takes all the credit and forgets to acknowledge her efforts, Eliza angrily leaves him for Freddy, and suddenly Higgins realizes he's grown accustomed to her face and can't really live without it.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Musical
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   flower girl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wager
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   professor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   high society
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   colonel
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   George Cukor
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Alan Jay Lerner
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   George Bernard Shaw
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Audrey Hepburn
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rex Harrison
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Stanley Holloway
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit song after hit song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every song in this musical is a hit. Rex Harrison is at his Rex Harrisoniest, and Audrey Hepburn reveals layer after layer of Eliza Doolittle. The costumes are brilliant, particularly in the artfully- staged, hilarious scene at the racetrack. Stanley Holloway, who played Eliza's ne'er-do-well father on Broadway before bringing the role to the screen, steals his scenes. This movie earned every bit of its Best Picture Oscar and remains one of the best movie musicals of all time. Though the movie deals with the touchy subjects of class and gender and does not pull its punches, it is not mean-spirited and does not run too much afoul of modern sensibilities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic. or little more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I confess- Audrey Hepburn is one of my favorite actresses. so, it is difficult to not love this film. smart, charming, almost touching, full of great performances, it is adorable more than a classic. songs, adaptation, costumes - all is perfect. and each new meeting is a pure delight. sure, hypothesis of Julie Andrews as Eliza is present. but not for long time because Hepburn does a splendid work and the levels of metamorphose of poor young girl in a brilliant lady is credible and fascinating. sure, the axis remains Rex Harrison and this fact is obvious. but , like in case of each good movie, the flavor after its end is essential. in this case it is not only entertainment but drops of special beauty who covers small imperfections and gives a very nice feeling of life joy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alyssa Black (Aly200)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'My Fair Lady' originated on Broadway in 1957 and was a huge successful when released. This film adaption was released in 1964 without the original star in the female lead (Julie Andrews was to star in 'Mary Poppins' and that year won the Best Actress Oscar for her portrayal). But Audrey Hepburn shines in this film as the fiery-spirited cockney flower girl Eliza Doolittle (her singing was dubbed by Marni Nixon)opposite Rex Harrison's Henry Higgins (the role he originated on Broadway). The two actors are perfect foils for each other as the student and tutor who clash over the social graces that Eliza must learn in order to be a lady. This musical is quite underrated because of Hepburn's performance as opposed to Julie Andrews' in the original production. I think that it's a matter of interpretation; both actresses have their styles and play the character in her own way. This is one of Audrey's finest performance since her performance as Holly Golightly in 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could somehow be better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zoe Yac
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Audrey Hepburn is simply stunning in this movie - as in most. Only drag is that she did not actually sing her songs in the movie. Also, the poor quality of the majority of songs is quite disappointing. The story is just superb, though. But who is to thank for that? Anyways, I give it a 7/10 because of the very solid overall cast, some quite remembering songs - by far the most outstanding of them being "I Could Have Danced All Night" -, the thought out lead characters (but actually only them, since the supporting roles were rather shallow. At least the part of Pickering could be exhausted in a more interesting way, although it is hinted at at the end of the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What flair, my lady!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical adaptation of a tale of love between a book-learned pedagogue and a flower-selling prodigy bonded through phonetics. The movie is a melange of mellifluous songs, male chauvinism and a maiden who undergoes a paradigm shift in her speech and charisma. I love the scene in which people are busy with their daily chores and the frame freezes, then the camera zooms out and another set of people move around and then it freezes and another set of people move around. And all the people in the 3 sets of the frame move around in a haphazard manner. I beg your pardon lovers of literature, I haven't read the play by George Bernard Shaw nor have i heard about it before watching the film. Professor Higgins takes Eliza as a disciple to experiment on after Col. Pickering throws a challenge that he couldn't make a duchess out of a flower-seller. Professor Higgins, an expert in Phonetics, is a celibate and often looks down on women. He provides her luxury and at the same time forces her to try and try till she enunciates the words correctly. After several exhaustive sessions, Higgins makes her perceive what they're trying to do to her and his words do the miracle. She speaks flawlessly and with a rich and refined voice. Higgins takes her to a horse race, a place where Eliza could interact with the blue-blooded. She does well in the beginning but slowly she starts uttering innuendos and senseless idioms that Higgins and Pickering try to cover up with illogical explanations. Things go back to round one when she screams in enjoyment in the language of the slum-dwellers. Higgins gives her rigorous training and his efforts bear fruit in a matter of time. She draws the attention of several people and a princess showers encomiums on her charisma. Higgins is lauded for his efforts by his fellowmen but they fail to understand Eliza's efforts too; all that she had to endure to become a subject of Higgins' achievement. She leaves the house in agony and swears to never return again. Higgins realizes they are in-execrable but takes time to confess it and comes to him after his long-due confession.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mobility with Music ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Oscar for best picture of 1964 went to this musical. It was very hard to understand Audrey Hepburn at the beginning of the film with that cockneyed accent. She came into the role as the picture progressed and she became a lady. This is basically a story of class warfare set to music without the violence of Oscar winner "West Side Story." Rex Harrison won the best actor here and although he gave a good performance as speech professor Henry Higgins, am sure the other nominees were better. He certainly looked down on the gutter snipe Hepburn, but as the picture went by he certainly grew accustomed to her face. After he makes her a lady and she is a success at the ball, Hepburn, as Eliza, is at the crossroad of her life. What shall become of her? Will someone please explain to me why Gladys Cooper was nominated for best supporting actress here? Her part was next to nothing and she added zilch to the picture. Cooper was far more magnificent in her other nominations some 20 years before- "The Song of Bernadette," and "Now, Voyager." She missed a 1958 supporting bid for "Separate Tables." Harrison mouthed the words beautifully to the music of the songs given to him. That was an achievement in itself. The picture proved without doubt that upward social mobility is possible. The film may also be described as a Cinderella like-tale. After all, our girl in rags wound up with a gem as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rags to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dichoi-197-207907
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Fair Lady is an unlikely musical of beloved songs and characters. Romance, refreshing comedy, and unexpected satire weave through this wonderful film that retains a great deal of George Bernard Shaw's "Pygmalion" (1912) which was itself inspired by Ovid's Metamorphosis. Even though it is one of the most loved romances, no one ever gets kissed. No nudity, no sex, not even a declaration of love. The story celebrates not romance but intelligence. The story involves a meeting of two egos outside a lavish London theater: linguist Henry Higgins (Rex Harrison) and flower girl Eliza Doolittle (Audrey Hepburn). Eliza is a common Cockney flower girl who is plucked from the Covent Garden and transformed into a "lady" by Higgins. It is difficult to discuss George Cukor's 1964 film as it actually exists because of the gossip that muddles it greatness. Many viewers would rather discuss the film that was not made, the one that would have starred Julie Andrews who made the role of Eliza her own on the stage. Casting Audrey Hepburn was an insult to a then little-known Andrews because the studio head Jack L. Warner chose Hepburn for her greater box appeal. Furthermore, Hepburn did not sing her own songs but was instead dubbed by the talented Marni Nixon. This dubbing became quite notorious, so much so that although My Fair Lady was nominated for twelve Oscars and won eight, Hepburn was not even nominated for best actress. Ironically, Andrews won the Best Actress Award for "Mary Poppins," while Hepburn was snubbed by the Academy. Let us step back and take another look at the controversy. Indeed, Hepburn did not sing her own songs. However, the dubbing of singing voices was very common at the time, and Nixon herself dubbed other actresses such as Deborah Kerr and Natalie Wood. Even actors who did sing their own songs lip-synced to their own pre-recorded dubs. The fact that Hepburn did not do her own singing only makes her success, which is that she did her own acting. What Hepburn did for the role was to make you care about Eliza and to believe in her transformation. Even if she did not sing her part, Hepburn still delivered a dazzling performance because of her ability to make us believe. My Fair Lady drew its dialogue from Shaw's "Pygmalion," which is more challenging than most other musicals. The dialogue was not only embedded with well-honed wit and satire but required Eliza to transition accents from Cockney to the Queen's English. Hepburn does this with flawless technique and confidence in a performance with palpable passion. The audience is given reasons to care about her character. We can relate to her, feel for what happens to her, and rejoice when things go her way. Throughout the film, Hepburn, who is so tenderly waiflike, brings a poignancy to her scenes that is magical. Not only does My Fair Lady feature an involving story with compelling characters, but there is not a dud to be found on the list of more than a dozen toe-tapping numbers. The best-known song from the film, "I Could Have Danced All Night," is familiar to almost everyone  even though who have not seen the movie. This is a testament to the brilliant marriage of dialogue and lyric in the film as seen in a poor smitten character named Freddy. Many people despise musicals because of the preposterous way characters pause mid-sentence and suddenly burst into song. Freddy avoids these predictable scenes, singing "On the Street Where You Live" with a childlike candor compared with other more emotional characters. Apart from the marvels of its words and music, My Fair Lady is a visual triumph laced with elegance. Cukor made exquisite use of Cecil Beaton who designed the production, the sets, and the costumes. Many extras are dressed in whites, blacks, and greys, creating a backdrop for Higgins in his brown tweed suit and Eliza, who has a touch of red in her dress. The story expresses endless optimism through the d&eacute;cor of Higgins' home, which is packed with the latest mechanical gadgets for teaching people how to speak better. The unusually remote camera stays well back from the action with relatively few close-ups, allowing the audience to see as much of the luxurious sets as possible. The audience can unmistakably see that this is a movie into which a world of care and effort was invested. What distinguished My Fair Lady above all is that it actually says something meaningful. In a film of quick words, unforgettable music, and outstanding images, it analyzes the socialist attack on the British class system. By dramatizing how superiority and success was inherited, not earned, through Eliza's escape from the lower class system, My Fair Lady becomes a great entertainment as well as a great influence. The impact it had on the creation of feminism and class- consciousness through the mid-1900s is still not sufficiently appreciated. It was a revolutionary message in England at the time, and it is still thought-provoking. Not only do people not make movies like this anymore  they simply cannot. The movie industry seems to no longer be interested in musicals about adults, much less adults with ideas. Few film genres are as magical as musicals, and few musicals are as intelligent and joyous as My Fair Lady. It is both notable and marvelous that the film stays so true to the original material and does not cave in to a schmaltzy rewritten happy ending. It remains an open question to the audience whether Eliza stays to listen to what he says next. If these two are ever to fall in love, it will be with their heads, instead of their hearts. This movie is a classic not because a group of film experts have labeled it as such, but because it has been, and always will be, a pure joy to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey Hepburn is, and always will be, Eliza Doolittle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I have the highest respect for Julie Andrews, I think the producers made the right choice in Audrey Hepburn. Andrews has the clear advantage of an extraordinarily fine voice, so she could have done her own singing, as she did in the London cast recording. But I have trouble seeing Andrews as the ideal for the Eliza Doolittle character over the full scope of the movie. What My Fair Lady is about is the story of Pygmalion, the play by George Bernard Shaw, but also the earlier Greek legend of the sculptor who created the image of his perfect woman out of stone, so beautiful that she came alive. So the end result must be a very high ideal of perfection, grace and beauty. Now Julie Andrews is no slouch in those departments, but she lacks the extraordinary other-worldliness that Audrey Hepburn was renown for. When Hepburn played a real princess in her first starring role in Roman Holiday, she was absolutely convincing. She made the transformation from caterpillar to butterfly in Sabrina. So when Eliza goes to the royal ball and everyone thinks the former flower girl is a princess going incognito, it is heartbreakingly believable. Eliza truly has been transformed into the ideal of perfection and beauty. As much as I admire Andrews, I can't quite imagine her being as convincing in that scene. Some say Andrews earned the part for her portrayal of the role on stage, and that she got a raw deal. If that had been the end of her career, I would be inclined to agree. But look at the wonderful, dream roles she has had since, particularly the immortal Sound of Music, in which she was perfectly cast. I think being miscast can be as bad or worse than no role at all. While Andrews certainly would not have been a disaster, I think she might have been a slight disappointment. There is a big difference between a portrayal on stage, in which the audience is more willing to suspend disbelief, and on film, where every pore is five feet tall. That is probably why the wonderful, but aging, Mary Martin didn't get many film roles. Andrews might not have been as convincing an Eliza on film as she was on stage. I see some posters calling My Fair Lady an American production. Just a reminder: Hepburn was not American. She was British-Dutch-Belgian. And while she came from a rich family, she grew up in starvation poverty while in Holland during World War II, which may have given her the depth to play such a range of roles, from the flower girl to princesses. I'm not saying Hepburn's portrayal of Eliza is perfect. I grew up with Hepburn as Eliza, and she inhabits the role, in my mind. But as an adult, with the closer examination of being able to watch the DVD version an infinite number of times, I do see some weaknesses in her portrayal. I doubt most people would see these in the first or second viewing. A more troubling question is whether Hepburn should have done her own singing. She had a good singing voice, and could have done a good job. You can hear her singing Moon River in Breakfast at Tiffany's. The ultimate reason they dubbed her may have been Rex Harrison and Stanley Holloway. They are trying to make a musical, and most of the stars can't actually sing. To have a weak singing performance from Hepburn would have been too much. Marni Nixon could be counted on for a skilled voice match. (BTW, Nixon finally appears on screen in Sound of Music, as a nun commenting on Maria -- Andrews.) Problem solved. As to shortening some numbers, hey, this is a musical! The music is what it's about. I've seen too many musicals where they feel compelled to cut and cut to speed things up, shorten the movie. In South Pacific, the movie version cuts the "Wash That Man Right Out of my Hair" number down to one verse, and they really wrecked it. Brigadoon cut everything down to the minimum, and took all the wind out of the sails. With a musical, if you want to tell a story and have lots of music, you have got to make the film longer than the average non-musical; it's a big mistake to cut out parts of the story, or truncate the musical numbers. And as to the sets, the lesson I have derived from looking at many musicals is that you do not want a set that is too realistic. A musical is by nature a fantasy, because real people don't go breaking into song and dance in daily life. You need sets that are beautiful, but not entirely realistic. The 1962 remake of State Fair by Mel Ferrer, Hepburn's husband, was a disaster, and one reason was it was filmed very realistically. Guys and Dolls is perhaps the best example of non- realism, because the story was a fable, and the sets were almost like giant illustrations from a children's book. On the other hand, the movie version should not, generally, look too much like a Broadway play. Now, let's see, what would the My Fair Lady look like if the sets were a brutally realistic depiction of Edwardian London? We're talking real slums, with real horse manure. Save the realism for non-musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll make a queen of that barbarous wretch"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicsoncall
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the pros and cons of this film, and as an outsider looking in, my advantage perhaps is that I don't know a whole lot about George Bernard Shaw, Pygmalion, Broadway musicals and Audrey Hepburn's dubbed voice as a singing Eliza Doolittle. So coming in cold, and not particularly a fan of movie musicals, I'd have to say this was watchable enough, though at almost three hours, I WAS getting antsy after the two hour mark. I realize that fans and critics will bring their own prejudices to bear in regard to the casting and staging of the story, but that aside, and with no particular horse in the race, I'd have to say that this was entertaining enough for the kind of picture I generally don't go out of the way for. My mission is to watch and review each of the movies that appeared on the American Film Institute's original 1997 list of Best One Hundred Movies of All Time. So with a clinical approach and an open mind, I'm not predisposed one way or the other to like or dislike a picture I would have passed on otherwise. So now I've seen it, it passes muster as an entertaining film, and my movie viewing experience is that much more well rounded. With a little bit of luck, you might enjoy it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply delightful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't necessarily have to be into musical to be taken in by this charming film. All I can say is that I wish there would be more musical movies like this. It's a movie with such a pleasant and joyful atmosphere to it, even though the story of course also takes some dramatic turns. But this is what musicals should all be about; simply have a good time watching it and let it be a feast for your eyes and ears. The entire movie does feel and look very stagy but in this case that really isn't a complaint. It simply suits the movie well and makes it part of the reason why this is such perfect light entertainment to watch. Besides, it is a good looking movie as well, with all of its grand sets and nice costume design. But what is a musical without any good music. And luckily this movie does really has some good and pleasant songs in it, performed nicely by its cast, though not always its original cast. Audrey Hepburn still got dubbed for instance, which was also really apparent in some of the songs. Rex Harrison on the other hand does all of the singing himself and his style of singing and acting fits the character and songs very well. Yes, all of the acting in general is very impressive in this movie as well. I had seen Rex Harrison in a couple of movies before but he never impressed me as much as he did with his role in this movie. Also Audrey Hepburn surprised me. I have always loved her but I never realized how incredible versatile as an actress she actually was until I saw her in this movie. She basically plays two different characters in this. She is both very convincing as the foul mounted girl from the streets and as the sophisticated, uppercases lady. You probably won't even recognize her at first, until she slowly starts to transform into the lovely beautiful young woman, we also all remember Audrey Hepburn as. The story and characters within this movie are definitely not all without its flaws but in this case all the story wanted was to deliver a simple, light and enjoyable movie for everybody of all ages, sexes and ethnicities to enjoy. And I think they most definitely did not fail with this. At least the Academy Awards also agree with me, since the movie received 8 Oscar's, including the most important ones for best director and best picture of the year. It also eventually would turn out to be the only Oscar legendary director George Cukor received. Simply a movie to enjoy. 9/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit song after hit song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every song in this musical is a hit. Rex Harrison is at his Rex Harrisoniest, and Audrey Hepburn reveals layer after layer of Eliza Doolittle. The costumes are brilliant, particularly in the artfully- staged, hilarious scene at the racetrack. Stanley Holloway, who played Eliza's ne'er-do-well father on Broadway before bringing the role to the screen, steals his scenes. This movie earned every bit of its Best Picture Oscar and remains one of the best movie musicals of all time. Though the movie deals with the touchy subjects of class and gender and does not pull its punches, it is not mean-spirited and does not run too much afoul of modern sensibilities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic. or little more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I confess- Audrey Hepburn is one of my favorite actresses. so, it is difficult to not love this film. smart, charming, almost touching, full of great performances, it is adorable more than a classic. songs, adaptation, costumes - all is perfect. and each new meeting is a pure delight. sure, hypothesis of Julie Andrews as Eliza is present. but not for long time because Hepburn does a splendid work and the levels of metamorphose of poor young girl in a brilliant lady is credible and fascinating. sure, the axis remains Rex Harrison and this fact is obvious. but , like in case of each good movie, the flavor after its end is essential. in this case it is not only entertainment but drops of special beauty who covers small imperfections and gives a very nice feeling of life joy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alyssa Black (Aly200)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'My Fair Lady' originated on Broadway in 1957 and was a huge successful when released. This film adaption was released in 1964 without the original star in the female lead (Julie Andrews was to star in 'Mary Poppins' and that year won the Best Actress Oscar for her portrayal). But Audrey Hepburn shines in this film as the fiery-spirited cockney flower girl Eliza Doolittle (her singing was dubbed by Marni Nixon)opposite Rex Harrison's Henry Higgins (the role he originated on Broadway). The two actors are perfect foils for each other as the student and tutor who clash over the social graces that Eliza must learn in order to be a lady. This musical is quite underrated because of Hepburn's performance as opposed to Julie Andrews' in the original production. I think that it's a matter of interpretation; both actresses have their styles and play the character in her own way. This is one of Audrey's finest performance since her performance as Holly Golightly in 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could somehow be better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zoe Yac
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Audrey Hepburn is simply stunning in this movie - as in most. Only drag is that she did not actually sing her songs in the movie. Also, the poor quality of the majority of songs is quite disappointing. The story is just superb, though. But who is to thank for that? Anyways, I give it a 7/10 because of the very solid overall cast, some quite remembering songs - by far the most outstanding of them being "I Could Have Danced All Night" -, the thought out lead characters (but actually only them, since the supporting roles were rather shallow. At least the part of Pickering could be exhausted in a more interesting way, although it is hinted at at the end of the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What flair, my lady!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical adaptation of a tale of love between a book-learned pedagogue and a flower-selling prodigy bonded through phonetics. The movie is a melange of mellifluous songs, male chauvinism and a maiden who undergoes a paradigm shift in her speech and charisma. I love the scene in which people are busy with their daily chores and the frame freezes, then the camera zooms out and another set of people move around and then it freezes and another set of people move around. And all the people in the 3 sets of the frame move around in a haphazard manner. I beg your pardon lovers of literature, I haven't read the play by George Bernard Shaw nor have i heard about it before watching the film. Professor Higgins takes Eliza as a disciple to experiment on after Col. Pickering throws a challenge that he couldn't make a duchess out of a flower-seller. Professor Higgins, an expert in Phonetics, is a celibate and often looks down on women. He provides her luxury and at the same time forces her to try and try till she enunciates the words correctly. After several exhaustive sessions, Higgins makes her perceive what they're trying to do to her and his words do the miracle. She speaks flawlessly and with a rich and refined voice. Higgins takes her to a horse race, a place where Eliza could interact with the blue-blooded. She does well in the beginning but slowly she starts uttering innuendos and senseless idioms that Higgins and Pickering try to cover up with illogical explanations. Things go back to round one when she screams in enjoyment in the language of the slum-dwellers. Higgins gives her rigorous training and his efforts bear fruit in a matter of time. She draws the attention of several people and a princess showers encomiums on her charisma. Higgins is lauded for his efforts by his fellowmen but they fail to understand Eliza's efforts too; all that she had to endure to become a subject of Higgins' achievement. She leaves the house in agony and swears to never return again. Higgins realizes they are in-execrable but takes time to confess it and comes to him after his long-due confession.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mobility with Music ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Oscar for best picture of 1964 went to this musical. It was very hard to understand Audrey Hepburn at the beginning of the film with that cockneyed accent. She came into the role as the picture progressed and she became a lady. This is basically a story of class warfare set to music without the violence of Oscar winner "West Side Story." Rex Harrison won the best actor here and although he gave a good performance as speech professor Henry Higgins, am sure the other nominees were better. He certainly looked down on the gutter snipe Hepburn, but as the picture went by he certainly grew accustomed to her face. After he makes her a lady and she is a success at the ball, Hepburn, as Eliza, is at the crossroad of her life. What shall become of her? Will someone please explain to me why Gladys Cooper was nominated for best supporting actress here? Her part was next to nothing and she added zilch to the picture. Cooper was far more magnificent in her other nominations some 20 years before- "The Song of Bernadette," and "Now, Voyager." She missed a 1958 supporting bid for "Separate Tables." Harrison mouthed the words beautifully to the music of the songs given to him. That was an achievement in itself. The picture proved without doubt that upward social mobility is possible. The film may also be described as a Cinderella like-tale. After all, our girl in rags wound up with a gem as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rags to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dichoi-197-207907
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Fair Lady is an unlikely musical of beloved songs and characters. Romance, refreshing comedy, and unexpected satire weave through this wonderful film that retains a great deal of George Bernard Shaw's "Pygmalion" (1912) which was itself inspired by Ovid's Metamorphosis. Even though it is one of the most loved romances, no one ever gets kissed. No nudity, no sex, not even a declaration of love. The story celebrates not romance but intelligence. The story involves a meeting of two egos outside a lavish London theater: linguist Henry Higgins (Rex Harrison) and flower girl Eliza Doolittle (Audrey Hepburn). Eliza is a common Cockney flower girl who is plucked from the Covent Garden and transformed into a "lady" by Higgins. It is difficult to discuss George Cukor's 1964 film as it actually exists because of the gossip that muddles it greatness. Many viewers would rather discuss the film that was not made, the one that would have starred Julie Andrews who made the role of Eliza her own on the stage. Casting Audrey Hepburn was an insult to a then little-known Andrews because the studio head Jack L. Warner chose Hepburn for her greater box appeal. Furthermore, Hepburn did not sing her own songs but was instead dubbed by the talented Marni Nixon. This dubbing became quite notorious, so much so that although My Fair Lady was nominated for twelve Oscars and won eight, Hepburn was not even nominated for best actress. Ironically, Andrews won the Best Actress Award for "Mary Poppins," while Hepburn was snubbed by the Academy. Let us step back and take another look at the controversy. Indeed, Hepburn did not sing her own songs. However, the dubbing of singing voices was very common at the time, and Nixon herself dubbed other actresses such as Deborah Kerr and Natalie Wood. Even actors who did sing their own songs lip-synced to their own pre-recorded dubs. The fact that Hepburn did not do her own singing only makes her success, which is that she did her own acting. What Hepburn did for the role was to make you care about Eliza and to believe in her transformation. Even if she did not sing her part, Hepburn still delivered a dazzling performance because of her ability to make us believe. My Fair Lady drew its dialogue from Shaw's "Pygmalion," which is more challenging than most other musicals. The dialogue was not only embedded with well-honed wit and satire but required Eliza to transition accents from Cockney to the Queen's English. Hepburn does this with flawless technique and confidence in a performance with palpable passion. The audience is given reasons to care about her character. We can relate to her, feel for what happens to her, and rejoice when things go her way. Throughout the film, Hepburn, who is so tenderly waiflike, brings a poignancy to her scenes that is magical. Not only does My Fair Lady feature an involving story with compelling characters, but there is not a dud to be found on the list of more than a dozen toe-tapping numbers. The best-known song from the film, "I Could Have Danced All Night," is familiar to almost everyone  even though who have not seen the movie. This is a testament to the brilliant marriage of dialogue and lyric in the film as seen in a poor smitten character named Freddy. Many people despise musicals because of the preposterous way characters pause mid-sentence and suddenly burst into song. Freddy avoids these predictable scenes, singing "On the Street Where You Live" with a childlike candor compared with other more emotional characters. Apart from the marvels of its words and music, My Fair Lady is a visual triumph laced with elegance. Cukor made exquisite use of Cecil Beaton who designed the production, the sets, and the costumes. Many extras are dressed in whites, blacks, and greys, creating a backdrop for Higgins in his brown tweed suit and Eliza, who has a touch of red in her dress. The story expresses endless optimism through the d&eacute;cor of Higgins' home, which is packed with the latest mechanical gadgets for teaching people how to speak better. The unusually remote camera stays well back from the action with relatively few close-ups, allowing the audience to see as much of the luxurious sets as possible. The audience can unmistakably see that this is a movie into which a world of care and effort was invested. What distinguished My Fair Lady above all is that it actually says something meaningful. In a film of quick words, unforgettable music, and outstanding images, it analyzes the socialist attack on the British class system. By dramatizing how superiority and success was inherited, not earned, through Eliza's escape from the lower class system, My Fair Lady becomes a great entertainment as well as a great influence. The impact it had on the creation of feminism and class- consciousness through the mid-1900s is still not sufficiently appreciated. It was a revolutionary message in England at the time, and it is still thought-provoking. Not only do people not make movies like this anymore  they simply cannot. The movie industry seems to no longer be interested in musicals about adults, much less adults with ideas. Few film genres are as magical as musicals, and few musicals are as intelligent and joyous as My Fair Lady. It is both notable and marvelous that the film stays so true to the original material and does not cave in to a schmaltzy rewritten happy ending. It remains an open question to the audience whether Eliza stays to listen to what he says next. If these two are ever to fall in love, it will be with their heads, instead of their hearts. This movie is a classic not because a group of film experts have labeled it as such, but because it has been, and always will be, a pure joy to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey Hepburn is, and always will be, Eliza Doolittle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I have the highest respect for Julie Andrews, I think the producers made the right choice in Audrey Hepburn. Andrews has the clear advantage of an extraordinarily fine voice, so she could have done her own singing, as she did in the London cast recording. But I have trouble seeing Andrews as the ideal for the Eliza Doolittle character over the full scope of the movie. What My Fair Lady is about is the story of Pygmalion, the play by George Bernard Shaw, but also the earlier Greek legend of the sculptor who created the image of his perfect woman out of stone, so beautiful that she came alive. So the end result must be a very high ideal of perfection, grace and beauty. Now Julie Andrews is no slouch in those departments, but she lacks the extraordinary other-worldliness that Audrey Hepburn was renown for. When Hepburn played a real princess in her first starring role in Roman Holiday, she was absolutely convincing. She made the transformation from caterpillar to butterfly in Sabrina. So when Eliza goes to the royal ball and everyone thinks the former flower girl is a princess going incognito, it is heartbreakingly believable. Eliza truly has been transformed into the ideal of perfection and beauty. As much as I admire Andrews, I can't quite imagine her being as convincing in that scene. Some say Andrews earned the part for her portrayal of the role on stage, and that she got a raw deal. If that had been the end of her career, I would be inclined to agree. But look at the wonderful, dream roles she has had since, particularly the immortal Sound of Music, in which she was perfectly cast. I think being miscast can be as bad or worse than no role at all. While Andrews certainly would not have been a disaster, I think she might have been a slight disappointment. There is a big difference between a portrayal on stage, in which the audience is more willing to suspend disbelief, and on film, where every pore is five feet tall. That is probably why the wonderful, but aging, Mary Martin didn't get many film roles. Andrews might not have been as convincing an Eliza on film as she was on stage. I see some posters calling My Fair Lady an American production. Just a reminder: Hepburn was not American. She was British-Dutch-Belgian. And while she came from a rich family, she grew up in starvation poverty while in Holland during World War II, which may have given her the depth to play such a range of roles, from the flower girl to princesses. I'm not saying Hepburn's portrayal of Eliza is perfect. I grew up with Hepburn as Eliza, and she inhabits the role, in my mind. But as an adult, with the closer examination of being able to watch the DVD version an infinite number of times, I do see some weaknesses in her portrayal. I doubt most people would see these in the first or second viewing. A more troubling question is whether Hepburn should have done her own singing. She had a good singing voice, and could have done a good job. You can hear her singing Moon River in Breakfast at Tiffany's. The ultimate reason they dubbed her may have been Rex Harrison and Stanley Holloway. They are trying to make a musical, and most of the stars can't actually sing. To have a weak singing performance from Hepburn would have been too much. Marni Nixon could be counted on for a skilled voice match. (BTW, Nixon finally appears on screen in Sound of Music, as a nun commenting on Maria -- Andrews.) Problem solved. As to shortening some numbers, hey, this is a musical! The music is what it's about. I've seen too many musicals where they feel compelled to cut and cut to speed things up, shorten the movie. In South Pacific, the movie version cuts the "Wash That Man Right Out of my Hair" number down to one verse, and they really wrecked it. Brigadoon cut everything down to the minimum, and took all the wind out of the sails. With a musical, if you want to tell a story and have lots of music, you have got to make the film longer than the average non-musical; it's a big mistake to cut out parts of the story, or truncate the musical numbers. And as to the sets, the lesson I have derived from looking at many musicals is that you do not want a set that is too realistic. A musical is by nature a fantasy, because real people don't go breaking into song and dance in daily life. You need sets that are beautiful, but not entirely realistic. The 1962 remake of State Fair by Mel Ferrer, Hepburn's husband, was a disaster, and one reason was it was filmed very realistically. Guys and Dolls is perhaps the best example of non- realism, because the story was a fable, and the sets were almost like giant illustrations from a children's book. On the other hand, the movie version should not, generally, look too much like a Broadway play. Now, let's see, what would the My Fair Lady look like if the sets were a brutally realistic depiction of Edwardian London? We're talking real slums, with real horse manure. Save the realism for non-musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll make a queen of that barbarous wretch"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicsoncall
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the pros and cons of this film, and as an outsider looking in, my advantage perhaps is that I don't know a whole lot about George Bernard Shaw, Pygmalion, Broadway musicals and Audrey Hepburn's dubbed voice as a singing Eliza Doolittle. So coming in cold, and not particularly a fan of movie musicals, I'd have to say this was watchable enough, though at almost three hours, I WAS getting antsy after the two hour mark. I realize that fans and critics will bring their own prejudices to bear in regard to the casting and staging of the story, but that aside, and with no particular horse in the race, I'd have to say that this was entertaining enough for the kind of picture I generally don't go out of the way for. My mission is to watch and review each of the movies that appeared on the American Film Institute's original 1997 list of Best One Hundred Movies of All Time. So with a clinical approach and an open mind, I'm not predisposed one way or the other to like or dislike a picture I would have passed on otherwise. So now I've seen it, it passes muster as an entertaining film, and my movie viewing experience is that much more well rounded. With a little bit of luck, you might enjoy it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply delightful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't necessarily have to be into musical to be taken in by this charming film. All I can say is that I wish there would be more musical movies like this. It's a movie with such a pleasant and joyful atmosphere to it, even though the story of course also takes some dramatic turns. But this is what musicals should all be about; simply have a good time watching it and let it be a feast for your eyes and ears. The entire movie does feel and look very stagy but in this case that really isn't a complaint. It simply suits the movie well and makes it part of the reason why this is such perfect light entertainment to watch. Besides, it is a good looking movie as well, with all of its grand sets and nice costume design. But what is a musical without any good music. And luckily this movie does really has some good and pleasant songs in it, performed nicely by its cast, though not always its original cast. Audrey Hepburn still got dubbed for instance, which was also really apparent in some of the songs. Rex Harrison on the other hand does all of the singing himself and his style of singing and acting fits the character and songs very well. Yes, all of the acting in general is very impressive in this movie as well. I had seen Rex Harrison in a couple of movies before but he never impressed me as much as he did with his role in this movie. Also Audrey Hepburn surprised me. I have always loved her but I never realized how incredible versatile as an actress she actually was until I saw her in this movie. She basically plays two different characters in this. She is both very convincing as the foul mounted girl from the streets and as the sophisticated, uppercases lady. You probably won't even recognize her at first, until she slowly starts to transform into the lovely beautiful young woman, we also all remember Audrey Hepburn as. The story and characters within this movie are definitely not all without its flaws but in this case all the story wanted was to deliver a simple, light and enjoyable movie for everybody of all ages, sexes and ethnicities to enjoy. And I think they most definitely did not fail with this. At least the Academy Awards also agree with me, since the movie received 8 Oscar's, including the most important ones for best director and best picture of the year. It also eventually would turn out to be the only Oscar legendary director George Cukor received. Simply a movie to enjoy. 9/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit song after hit song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every song in this musical is a hit. Rex Harrison is at his Rex Harrisoniest, and Audrey Hepburn reveals layer after layer of Eliza Doolittle. The costumes are brilliant, particularly in the artfully- staged, hilarious scene at the racetrack. Stanley Holloway, who played Eliza's ne'er-do-well father on Broadway before bringing the role to the screen, steals his scenes. This movie earned every bit of its Best Picture Oscar and remains one of the best movie musicals of all time. Though the movie deals with the touchy subjects of class and gender and does not pull its punches, it is not mean-spirited and does not run too much afoul of modern sensibilities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic. or little more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I confess- Audrey Hepburn is one of my favorite actresses. so, it is difficult to not love this film. smart, charming, almost touching, full of great performances, it is adorable more than a classic. songs, adaptation, costumes - all is perfect. and each new meeting is a pure delight. sure, hypothesis of Julie Andrews as Eliza is present. but not for long time because Hepburn does a splendid work and the levels of metamorphose of poor young girl in a brilliant lady is credible and fascinating. sure, the axis remains Rex Harrison and this fact is obvious. but , like in case of each good movie, the flavor after its end is essential. in this case it is not only entertainment but drops of special beauty who covers small imperfections and gives a very nice feeling of life joy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alyssa Black (Aly200)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'My Fair Lady' originated on Broadway in 1957 and was a huge successful when released. This film adaption was released in 1964 without the original star in the female lead (Julie Andrews was to star in 'Mary Poppins' and that year won the Best Actress Oscar for her portrayal). But Audrey Hepburn shines in this film as the fiery-spirited cockney flower girl Eliza Doolittle (her singing was dubbed by Marni Nixon)opposite Rex Harrison's Henry Higgins (the role he originated on Broadway). The two actors are perfect foils for each other as the student and tutor who clash over the social graces that Eliza must learn in order to be a lady. This musical is quite underrated because of Hepburn's performance as opposed to Julie Andrews' in the original production. I think that it's a matter of interpretation; both actresses have their styles and play the character in her own way. This is one of Audrey's finest performance since her performance as Holly Golightly in 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could somehow be better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zoe Yac
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Audrey Hepburn is simply stunning in this movie - as in most. Only drag is that she did not actually sing her songs in the movie. Also, the poor quality of the majority of songs is quite disappointing. The story is just superb, though. But who is to thank for that? Anyways, I give it a 7/10 because of the very solid overall cast, some quite remembering songs - by far the most outstanding of them being "I Could Have Danced All Night" -, the thought out lead characters (but actually only them, since the supporting roles were rather shallow. At least the part of Pickering could be exhausted in a more interesting way, although it is hinted at at the end of the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What flair, my lady!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical adaptation of a tale of love between a book-learned pedagogue and a flower-selling prodigy bonded through phonetics. The movie is a melange of mellifluous songs, male chauvinism and a maiden who undergoes a paradigm shift in her speech and charisma. I love the scene in which people are busy with their daily chores and the frame freezes, then the camera zooms out and another set of people move around and then it freezes and another set of people move around. And all the people in the 3 sets of the frame move around in a haphazard manner. I beg your pardon lovers of literature, I haven't read the play by George Bernard Shaw nor have i heard about it before watching the film. Professor Higgins takes Eliza as a disciple to experiment on after Col. Pickering throws a challenge that he couldn't make a duchess out of a flower-seller. Professor Higgins, an expert in Phonetics, is a celibate and often looks down on women. He provides her luxury and at the same time forces her to try and try till she enunciates the words correctly. After several exhaustive sessions, Higgins makes her perceive what they're trying to do to her and his words do the miracle. She speaks flawlessly and with a rich and refined voice. Higgins takes her to a horse race, a place where Eliza could interact with the blue-blooded. She does well in the beginning but slowly she starts uttering innuendos and senseless idioms that Higgins and Pickering try to cover up with illogical explanations. Things go back to round one when she screams in enjoyment in the language of the slum-dwellers. Higgins gives her rigorous training and his efforts bear fruit in a matter of time. She draws the attention of several people and a princess showers encomiums on her charisma. Higgins is lauded for his efforts by his fellowmen but they fail to understand Eliza's efforts too; all that she had to endure to become a subject of Higgins' achievement. She leaves the house in agony and swears to never return again. Higgins realizes they are in-execrable but takes time to confess it and comes to him after his long-due confession.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mobility with Music ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Oscar for best picture of 1964 went to this musical. It was very hard to understand Audrey Hepburn at the beginning of the film with that cockneyed accent. She came into the role as the picture progressed and she became a lady. This is basically a story of class warfare set to music without the violence of Oscar winner "West Side Story." Rex Harrison won the best actor here and although he gave a good performance as speech professor Henry Higgins, am sure the other nominees were better. He certainly looked down on the gutter snipe Hepburn, but as the picture went by he certainly grew accustomed to her face. After he makes her a lady and she is a success at the ball, Hepburn, as Eliza, is at the crossroad of her life. What shall become of her? Will someone please explain to me why Gladys Cooper was nominated for best supporting actress here? Her part was next to nothing and she added zilch to the picture. Cooper was far more magnificent in her other nominations some 20 years before- "The Song of Bernadette," and "Now, Voyager." She missed a 1958 supporting bid for "Separate Tables." Harrison mouthed the words beautifully to the music of the songs given to him. That was an achievement in itself. The picture proved without doubt that upward social mobility is possible. The film may also be described as a Cinderella like-tale. After all, our girl in rags wound up with a gem as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rags to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dichoi-197-207907
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Fair Lady is an unlikely musical of beloved songs and characters. Romance, refreshing comedy, and unexpected satire weave through this wonderful film that retains a great deal of George Bernard Shaw's "Pygmalion" (1912) which was itself inspired by Ovid's Metamorphosis. Even though it is one of the most loved romances, no one ever gets kissed. No nudity, no sex, not even a declaration of love. The story celebrates not romance but intelligence. The story involves a meeting of two egos outside a lavish London theater: linguist Henry Higgins (Rex Harrison) and flower girl Eliza Doolittle (Audrey Hepburn). Eliza is a common Cockney flower girl who is plucked from the Covent Garden and transformed into a "lady" by Higgins. It is difficult to discuss George Cukor's 1964 film as it actually exists because of the gossip that muddles it greatness. Many viewers would rather discuss the film that was not made, the one that would have starred Julie Andrews who made the role of Eliza her own on the stage. Casting Audrey Hepburn was an insult to a then little-known Andrews because the studio head Jack L. Warner chose Hepburn for her greater box appeal. Furthermore, Hepburn did not sing her own songs but was instead dubbed by the talented Marni Nixon. This dubbing became quite notorious, so much so that although My Fair Lady was nominated for twelve Oscars and won eight, Hepburn was not even nominated for best actress. Ironically, Andrews won the Best Actress Award for "Mary Poppins," while Hepburn was snubbed by the Academy. Let us step back and take another look at the controversy. Indeed, Hepburn did not sing her own songs. However, the dubbing of singing voices was very common at the time, and Nixon herself dubbed other actresses such as Deborah Kerr and Natalie Wood. Even actors who did sing their own songs lip-synced to their own pre-recorded dubs. The fact that Hepburn did not do her own singing only makes her success, which is that she did her own acting. What Hepburn did for the role was to make you care about Eliza and to believe in her transformation. Even if she did not sing her part, Hepburn still delivered a dazzling performance because of her ability to make us believe. My Fair Lady drew its dialogue from Shaw's "Pygmalion," which is more challenging than most other musicals. The dialogue was not only embedded with well-honed wit and satire but required Eliza to transition accents from Cockney to the Queen's English. Hepburn does this with flawless technique and confidence in a performance with palpable passion. The audience is given reasons to care about her character. We can relate to her, feel for what happens to her, and rejoice when things go her way. Throughout the film, Hepburn, who is so tenderly waiflike, brings a poignancy to her scenes that is magical. Not only does My Fair Lady feature an involving story with compelling characters, but there is not a dud to be found on the list of more than a dozen toe-tapping numbers. The best-known song from the film, "I Could Have Danced All Night," is familiar to almost everyone  even though who have not seen the movie. This is a testament to the brilliant marriage of dialogue and lyric in the film as seen in a poor smitten character named Freddy. Many people despise musicals because of the preposterous way characters pause mid-sentence and suddenly burst into song. Freddy avoids these predictable scenes, singing "On the Street Where You Live" with a childlike candor compared with other more emotional characters. Apart from the marvels of its words and music, My Fair Lady is a visual triumph laced with elegance. Cukor made exquisite use of Cecil Beaton who designed the production, the sets, and the costumes. Many extras are dressed in whites, blacks, and greys, creating a backdrop for Higgins in his brown tweed suit and Eliza, who has a touch of red in her dress. The story expresses endless optimism through the d&eacute;cor of Higgins' home, which is packed with the latest mechanical gadgets for teaching people how to speak better. The unusually remote camera stays well back from the action with relatively few close-ups, allowing the audience to see as much of the luxurious sets as possible. The audience can unmistakably see that this is a movie into which a world of care and effort was invested. What distinguished My Fair Lady above all is that it actually says something meaningful. In a film of quick words, unforgettable music, and outstanding images, it analyzes the socialist attack on the British class system. By dramatizing how superiority and success was inherited, not earned, through Eliza's escape from the lower class system, My Fair Lady becomes a great entertainment as well as a great influence. The impact it had on the creation of feminism and class- consciousness through the mid-1900s is still not sufficiently appreciated. It was a revolutionary message in England at the time, and it is still thought-provoking. Not only do people not make movies like this anymore  they simply cannot. The movie industry seems to no longer be interested in musicals about adults, much less adults with ideas. Few film genres are as magical as musicals, and few musicals are as intelligent and joyous as My Fair Lady. It is both notable and marvelous that the film stays so true to the original material and does not cave in to a schmaltzy rewritten happy ending. It remains an open question to the audience whether Eliza stays to listen to what he says next. If these two are ever to fall in love, it will be with their heads, instead of their hearts. This movie is a classic not because a group of film experts have labeled it as such, but because it has been, and always will be, a pure joy to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey Hepburn is, and always will be, Eliza Doolittle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I have the highest respect for Julie Andrews, I think the producers made the right choice in Audrey Hepburn. Andrews has the clear advantage of an extraordinarily fine voice, so she could have done her own singing, as she did in the London cast recording. But I have trouble seeing Andrews as the ideal for the Eliza Doolittle character over the full scope of the movie. What My Fair Lady is about is the story of Pygmalion, the play by George Bernard Shaw, but also the earlier Greek legend of the sculptor who created the image of his perfect woman out of stone, so beautiful that she came alive. So the end result must be a very high ideal of perfection, grace and beauty. Now Julie Andrews is no slouch in those departments, but she lacks the extraordinary other-worldliness that Audrey Hepburn was renown for. When Hepburn played a real princess in her first starring role in Roman Holiday, she was absolutely convincing. She made the transformation from caterpillar to butterfly in Sabrina. So when Eliza goes to the royal ball and everyone thinks the former flower girl is a princess going incognito, it is heartbreakingly believable. Eliza truly has been transformed into the ideal of perfection and beauty. As much as I admire Andrews, I can't quite imagine her being as convincing in that scene. Some say Andrews earned the part for her portrayal of the role on stage, and that she got a raw deal. If that had been the end of her career, I would be inclined to agree. But look at the wonderful, dream roles she has had since, particularly the immortal Sound of Music, in which she was perfectly cast. I think being miscast can be as bad or worse than no role at all. While Andrews certainly would not have been a disaster, I think she might have been a slight disappointment. There is a big difference between a portrayal on stage, in which the audience is more willing to suspend disbelief, and on film, where every pore is five feet tall. That is probably why the wonderful, but aging, Mary Martin didn't get many film roles. Andrews might not have been as convincing an Eliza on film as she was on stage. I see some posters calling My Fair Lady an American production. Just a reminder: Hepburn was not American. She was British-Dutch-Belgian. And while she came from a rich family, she grew up in starvation poverty while in Holland during World War II, which may have given her the depth to play such a range of roles, from the flower girl to princesses. I'm not saying Hepburn's portrayal of Eliza is perfect. I grew up with Hepburn as Eliza, and she inhabits the role, in my mind. But as an adult, with the closer examination of being able to watch the DVD version an infinite number of times, I do see some weaknesses in her portrayal. I doubt most people would see these in the first or second viewing. A more troubling question is whether Hepburn should have done her own singing. She had a good singing voice, and could have done a good job. You can hear her singing Moon River in Breakfast at Tiffany's. The ultimate reason they dubbed her may have been Rex Harrison and Stanley Holloway. They are trying to make a musical, and most of the stars can't actually sing. To have a weak singing performance from Hepburn would have been too much. Marni Nixon could be counted on for a skilled voice match. (BTW, Nixon finally appears on screen in Sound of Music, as a nun commenting on Maria -- Andrews.) Problem solved. As to shortening some numbers, hey, this is a musical! The music is what it's about. I've seen too many musicals where they feel compelled to cut and cut to speed things up, shorten the movie. In South Pacific, the movie version cuts the "Wash That Man Right Out of my Hair" number down to one verse, and they really wrecked it. Brigadoon cut everything down to the minimum, and took all the wind out of the sails. With a musical, if you want to tell a story and have lots of music, you have got to make the film longer than the average non-musical; it's a big mistake to cut out parts of the story, or truncate the musical numbers. And as to the sets, the lesson I have derived from looking at many musicals is that you do not want a set that is too realistic. A musical is by nature a fantasy, because real people don't go breaking into song and dance in daily life. You need sets that are beautiful, but not entirely realistic. The 1962 remake of State Fair by Mel Ferrer, Hepburn's husband, was a disaster, and one reason was it was filmed very realistically. Guys and Dolls is perhaps the best example of non- realism, because the story was a fable, and the sets were almost like giant illustrations from a children's book. On the other hand, the movie version should not, generally, look too much like a Broadway play. Now, let's see, what would the My Fair Lady look like if the sets were a brutally realistic depiction of Edwardian London? We're talking real slums, with real horse manure. Save the realism for non-musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll make a queen of that barbarous wretch"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicsoncall
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the pros and cons of this film, and as an outsider looking in, my advantage perhaps is that I don't know a whole lot about George Bernard Shaw, Pygmalion, Broadway musicals and Audrey Hepburn's dubbed voice as a singing Eliza Doolittle. So coming in cold, and not particularly a fan of movie musicals, I'd have to say this was watchable enough, though at almost three hours, I WAS getting antsy after the two hour mark. I realize that fans and critics will bring their own prejudices to bear in regard to the casting and staging of the story, but that aside, and with no particular horse in the race, I'd have to say that this was entertaining enough for the kind of picture I generally don't go out of the way for. My mission is to watch and review each of the movies that appeared on the American Film Institute's original 1997 list of Best One Hundred Movies of All Time. So with a clinical approach and an open mind, I'm not predisposed one way or the other to like or dislike a picture I would have passed on otherwise. So now I've seen it, it passes muster as an entertaining film, and my movie viewing experience is that much more well rounded. With a little bit of luck, you might enjoy it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply delightful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't necessarily have to be into musical to be taken in by this charming film. All I can say is that I wish there would be more musical movies like this. It's a movie with such a pleasant and joyful atmosphere to it, even though the story of course also takes some dramatic turns. But this is what musicals should all be about; simply have a good time watching it and let it be a feast for your eyes and ears. The entire movie does feel and look very stagy but in this case that really isn't a complaint. It simply suits the movie well and makes it part of the reason why this is such perfect light entertainment to watch. Besides, it is a good looking movie as well, with all of its grand sets and nice costume design. But what is a musical without any good music. And luckily this movie does really has some good and pleasant songs in it, performed nicely by its cast, though not always its original cast. Audrey Hepburn still got dubbed for instance, which was also really apparent in some of the songs. Rex Harrison on the other hand does all of the singing himself and his style of singing and acting fits the character and songs very well. Yes, all of the acting in general is very impressive in this movie as well. I had seen Rex Harrison in a couple of movies before but he never impressed me as much as he did with his role in this movie. Also Audrey Hepburn surprised me. I have always loved her but I never realized how incredible versatile as an actress she actually was until I saw her in this movie. She basically plays two different characters in this. She is both very convincing as the foul mounted girl from the streets and as the sophisticated, uppercases lady. You probably won't even recognize her at first, until she slowly starts to transform into the lovely beautiful young woman, we also all remember Audrey Hepburn as. The story and characters within this movie are definitely not all without its flaws but in this case all the story wanted was to deliver a simple, light and enjoyable movie for everybody of all ages, sexes and ethnicities to enjoy. And I think they most definitely did not fail with this. At least the Academy Awards also agree with me, since the movie received 8 Oscar's, including the most important ones for best director and best picture of the year. It also eventually would turn out to be the only Oscar legendary director George Cukor received. Simply a movie to enjoy. 9/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit song after hit song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every song in this musical is a hit. Rex Harrison is at his Rex Harrisoniest, and Audrey Hepburn reveals layer after layer of Eliza Doolittle. The costumes are brilliant, particularly in the artfully- staged, hilarious scene at the racetrack. Stanley Holloway, who played Eliza's ne'er-do-well father on Broadway before bringing the role to the screen, steals his scenes. This movie earned every bit of its Best Picture Oscar and remains one of the best movie musicals of all time. Though the movie deals with the touchy subjects of class and gender and does not pull its punches, it is not mean-spirited and does not run too much afoul of modern sensibilities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic. or little more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I confess- Audrey Hepburn is one of my favorite actresses. so, it is difficult to not love this film. smart, charming, almost touching, full of great performances, it is adorable more than a classic. songs, adaptation, costumes - all is perfect. and each new meeting is a pure delight. sure, hypothesis of Julie Andrews as Eliza is present. but not for long time because Hepburn does a splendid work and the levels of metamorphose of poor young girl in a brilliant lady is credible and fascinating. sure, the axis remains Rex Harrison and this fact is obvious. but , like in case of each good movie, the flavor after its end is essential. in this case it is not only entertainment but drops of special beauty who covers small imperfections and gives a very nice feeling of life joy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alyssa Black (Aly200)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'My Fair Lady' originated on Broadway in 1957 and was a huge successful when released. This film adaption was released in 1964 without the original star in the female lead (Julie Andrews was to star in 'Mary Poppins' and that year won the Best Actress Oscar for her portrayal). But Audrey Hepburn shines in this film as the fiery-spirited cockney flower girl Eliza Doolittle (her singing was dubbed by Marni Nixon)opposite Rex Harrison's Henry Higgins (the role he originated on Broadway). The two actors are perfect foils for each other as the student and tutor who clash over the social graces that Eliza must learn in order to be a lady. This musical is quite underrated because of Hepburn's performance as opposed to Julie Andrews' in the original production. I think that it's a matter of interpretation; both actresses have their styles and play the character in her own way. This is one of Audrey's finest performance since her performance as Holly Golightly in 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could somehow be better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zoe Yac
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Audrey Hepburn is simply stunning in this movie - as in most. Only drag is that she did not actually sing her songs in the movie. Also, the poor quality of the majority of songs is quite disappointing. The story is just superb, though. But who is to thank for that? Anyways, I give it a 7/10 because of the very solid overall cast, some quite remembering songs - by far the most outstanding of them being "I Could Have Danced All Night" -, the thought out lead characters (but actually only them, since the supporting roles were rather shallow. At least the part of Pickering could be exhausted in a more interesting way, although it is hinted at at the end of the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What flair, my lady!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical adaptation of a tale of love between a book-learned pedagogue and a flower-selling prodigy bonded through phonetics. The movie is a melange of mellifluous songs, male chauvinism and a maiden who undergoes a paradigm shift in her speech and charisma. I love the scene in which people are busy with their daily chores and the frame freezes, then the camera zooms out and another set of people move around and then it freezes and another set of people move around. And all the people in the 3 sets of the frame move around in a haphazard manner. I beg your pardon lovers of literature, I haven't read the play by George Bernard Shaw nor have i heard about it before watching the film. Professor Higgins takes Eliza as a disciple to experiment on after Col. Pickering throws a challenge that he couldn't make a duchess out of a flower-seller. Professor Higgins, an expert in Phonetics, is a celibate and often looks down on women. He provides her luxury and at the same time forces her to try and try till she enunciates the words correctly. After several exhaustive sessions, Higgins makes her perceive what they're trying to do to her and his words do the miracle. She speaks flawlessly and with a rich and refined voice. Higgins takes her to a horse race, a place where Eliza could interact with the blue-blooded. She does well in the beginning but slowly she starts uttering innuendos and senseless idioms that Higgins and Pickering try to cover up with illogical explanations. Things go back to round one when she screams in enjoyment in the language of the slum-dwellers. Higgins gives her rigorous training and his efforts bear fruit in a matter of time. She draws the attention of several people and a princess showers encomiums on her charisma. Higgins is lauded for his efforts by his fellowmen but they fail to understand Eliza's efforts too; all that she had to endure to become a subject of Higgins' achievement. She leaves the house in agony and swears to never return again. Higgins realizes they are in-execrable but takes time to confess it and comes to him after his long-due confession.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mobility with Music ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Oscar for best picture of 1964 went to this musical. It was very hard to understand Audrey Hepburn at the beginning of the film with that cockneyed accent. She came into the role as the picture progressed and she became a lady. This is basically a story of class warfare set to music without the violence of Oscar winner "West Side Story." Rex Harrison won the best actor here and although he gave a good performance as speech professor Henry Higgins, am sure the other nominees were better. He certainly looked down on the gutter snipe Hepburn, but as the picture went by he certainly grew accustomed to her face. After he makes her a lady and she is a success at the ball, Hepburn, as Eliza, is at the crossroad of her life. What shall become of her? Will someone please explain to me why Gladys Cooper was nominated for best supporting actress here? Her part was next to nothing and she added zilch to the picture. Cooper was far more magnificent in her other nominations some 20 years before- "The Song of Bernadette," and "Now, Voyager." She missed a 1958 supporting bid for "Separate Tables." Harrison mouthed the words beautifully to the music of the songs given to him. That was an achievement in itself. The picture proved without doubt that upward social mobility is possible. The film may also be described as a Cinderella like-tale. After all, our girl in rags wound up with a gem as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rags to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dichoi-197-207907
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Fair Lady is an unlikely musical of beloved songs and characters. Romance, refreshing comedy, and unexpected satire weave through this wonderful film that retains a great deal of George Bernard Shaw's "Pygmalion" (1912) which was itself inspired by Ovid's Metamorphosis. Even though it is one of the most loved romances, no one ever gets kissed. No nudity, no sex, not even a declaration of love. The story celebrates not romance but intelligence. The story involves a meeting of two egos outside a lavish London theater: linguist Henry Higgins (Rex Harrison) and flower girl Eliza Doolittle (Audrey Hepburn). Eliza is a common Cockney flower girl who is plucked from the Covent Garden and transformed into a "lady" by Higgins. It is difficult to discuss George Cukor's 1964 film as it actually exists because of the gossip that muddles it greatness. Many viewers would rather discuss the film that was not made, the one that would have starred Julie Andrews who made the role of Eliza her own on the stage. Casting Audrey Hepburn was an insult to a then little-known Andrews because the studio head Jack L. Warner chose Hepburn for her greater box appeal. Furthermore, Hepburn did not sing her own songs but was instead dubbed by the talented Marni Nixon. This dubbing became quite notorious, so much so that although My Fair Lady was nominated for twelve Oscars and won eight, Hepburn was not even nominated for best actress. Ironically, Andrews won the Best Actress Award for "Mary Poppins," while Hepburn was snubbed by the Academy. Let us step back and take another look at the controversy. Indeed, Hepburn did not sing her own songs. However, the dubbing of singing voices was very common at the time, and Nixon herself dubbed other actresses such as Deborah Kerr and Natalie Wood. Even actors who did sing their own songs lip-synced to their own pre-recorded dubs. The fact that Hepburn did not do her own singing only makes her success, which is that she did her own acting. What Hepburn did for the role was to make you care about Eliza and to believe in her transformation. Even if she did not sing her part, Hepburn still delivered a dazzling performance because of her ability to make us believe. My Fair Lady drew its dialogue from Shaw's "Pygmalion," which is more challenging than most other musicals. The dialogue was not only embedded with well-honed wit and satire but required Eliza to transition accents from Cockney to the Queen's English. Hepburn does this with flawless technique and confidence in a performance with palpable passion. The audience is given reasons to care about her character. We can relate to her, feel for what happens to her, and rejoice when things go her way. Throughout the film, Hepburn, who is so tenderly waiflike, brings a poignancy to her scenes that is magical. Not only does My Fair Lady feature an involving story with compelling characters, but there is not a dud to be found on the list of more than a dozen toe-tapping numbers. The best-known song from the film, "I Could Have Danced All Night," is familiar to almost everyone  even though who have not seen the movie. This is a testament to the brilliant marriage of dialogue and lyric in the film as seen in a poor smitten character named Freddy. Many people despise musicals because of the preposterous way characters pause mid-sentence and suddenly burst into song. Freddy avoids these predictable scenes, singing "On the Street Where You Live" with a childlike candor compared with other more emotional characters. Apart from the marvels of its words and music, My Fair Lady is a visual triumph laced with elegance. Cukor made exquisite use of Cecil Beaton who designed the production, the sets, and the costumes. Many extras are dressed in whites, blacks, and greys, creating a backdrop for Higgins in his brown tweed suit and Eliza, who has a touch of red in her dress. The story expresses endless optimism through the d&eacute;cor of Higgins' home, which is packed with the latest mechanical gadgets for teaching people how to speak better. The unusually remote camera stays well back from the action with relatively few close-ups, allowing the audience to see as much of the luxurious sets as possible. The audience can unmistakably see that this is a movie into which a world of care and effort was invested. What distinguished My Fair Lady above all is that it actually says something meaningful. In a film of quick words, unforgettable music, and outstanding images, it analyzes the socialist attack on the British class system. By dramatizing how superiority and success was inherited, not earned, through Eliza's escape from the lower class system, My Fair Lady becomes a great entertainment as well as a great influence. The impact it had on the creation of feminism and class- consciousness through the mid-1900s is still not sufficiently appreciated. It was a revolutionary message in England at the time, and it is still thought-provoking. Not only do people not make movies like this anymore  they simply cannot. The movie industry seems to no longer be interested in musicals about adults, much less adults with ideas. Few film genres are as magical as musicals, and few musicals are as intelligent and joyous as My Fair Lady. It is both notable and marvelous that the film stays so true to the original material and does not cave in to a schmaltzy rewritten happy ending. It remains an open question to the audience whether Eliza stays to listen to what he says next. If these two are ever to fall in love, it will be with their heads, instead of their hearts. This movie is a classic not because a group of film experts have labeled it as such, but because it has been, and always will be, a pure joy to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey Hepburn is, and always will be, Eliza Doolittle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I have the highest respect for Julie Andrews, I think the producers made the right choice in Audrey Hepburn. Andrews has the clear advantage of an extraordinarily fine voice, so she could have done her own singing, as she did in the London cast recording. But I have trouble seeing Andrews as the ideal for the Eliza Doolittle character over the full scope of the movie. What My Fair Lady is about is the story of Pygmalion, the play by George Bernard Shaw, but also the earlier Greek legend of the sculptor who created the image of his perfect woman out of stone, so beautiful that she came alive. So the end result must be a very high ideal of perfection, grace and beauty. Now Julie Andrews is no slouch in those departments, but she lacks the extraordinary other-worldliness that Audrey Hepburn was renown for. When Hepburn played a real princess in her first starring role in Roman Holiday, she was absolutely convincing. She made the transformation from caterpillar to butterfly in Sabrina. So when Eliza goes to the royal ball and everyone thinks the former flower girl is a princess going incognito, it is heartbreakingly believable. Eliza truly has been transformed into the ideal of perfection and beauty. As much as I admire Andrews, I can't quite imagine her being as convincing in that scene. Some say Andrews earned the part for her portrayal of the role on stage, and that she got a raw deal. If that had been the end of her career, I would be inclined to agree. But look at the wonderful, dream roles she has had since, particularly the immortal Sound of Music, in which she was perfectly cast. I think being miscast can be as bad or worse than no role at all. While Andrews certainly would not have been a disaster, I think she might have been a slight disappointment. There is a big difference between a portrayal on stage, in which the audience is more willing to suspend disbelief, and on film, where every pore is five feet tall. That is probably why the wonderful, but aging, Mary Martin didn't get many film roles. Andrews might not have been as convincing an Eliza on film as she was on stage. I see some posters calling My Fair Lady an American production. Just a reminder: Hepburn was not American. She was British-Dutch-Belgian. And while she came from a rich family, she grew up in starvation poverty while in Holland during World War II, which may have given her the depth to play such a range of roles, from the flower girl to princesses. I'm not saying Hepburn's portrayal of Eliza is perfect. I grew up with Hepburn as Eliza, and she inhabits the role, in my mind. But as an adult, with the closer examination of being able to watch the DVD version an infinite number of times, I do see some weaknesses in her portrayal. I doubt most people would see these in the first or second viewing. A more troubling question is whether Hepburn should have done her own singing. She had a good singing voice, and could have done a good job. You can hear her singing Moon River in Breakfast at Tiffany's. The ultimate reason they dubbed her may have been Rex Harrison and Stanley Holloway. They are trying to make a musical, and most of the stars can't actually sing. To have a weak singing performance from Hepburn would have been too much. Marni Nixon could be counted on for a skilled voice match. (BTW, Nixon finally appears on screen in Sound of Music, as a nun commenting on Maria -- Andrews.) Problem solved. As to shortening some numbers, hey, this is a musical! The music is what it's about. I've seen too many musicals where they feel compelled to cut and cut to speed things up, shorten the movie. In South Pacific, the movie version cuts the "Wash That Man Right Out of my Hair" number down to one verse, and they really wrecked it. Brigadoon cut everything down to the minimum, and took all the wind out of the sails. With a musical, if you want to tell a story and have lots of music, you have got to make the film longer than the average non-musical; it's a big mistake to cut out parts of the story, or truncate the musical numbers. And as to the sets, the lesson I have derived from looking at many musicals is that you do not want a set that is too realistic. A musical is by nature a fantasy, because real people don't go breaking into song and dance in daily life. You need sets that are beautiful, but not entirely realistic. The 1962 remake of State Fair by Mel Ferrer, Hepburn's husband, was a disaster, and one reason was it was filmed very realistically. Guys and Dolls is perhaps the best example of non- realism, because the story was a fable, and the sets were almost like giant illustrations from a children's book. On the other hand, the movie version should not, generally, look too much like a Broadway play. Now, let's see, what would the My Fair Lady look like if the sets were a brutally realistic depiction of Edwardian London? We're talking real slums, with real horse manure. Save the realism for non-musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll make a queen of that barbarous wretch"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicsoncall
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the pros and cons of this film, and as an outsider looking in, my advantage perhaps is that I don't know a whole lot about George Bernard Shaw, Pygmalion, Broadway musicals and Audrey Hepburn's dubbed voice as a singing Eliza Doolittle. So coming in cold, and not particularly a fan of movie musicals, I'd have to say this was watchable enough, though at almost three hours, I WAS getting antsy after the two hour mark. I realize that fans and critics will bring their own prejudices to bear in regard to the casting and staging of the story, but that aside, and with no particular horse in the race, I'd have to say that this was entertaining enough for the kind of picture I generally don't go out of the way for. My mission is to watch and review each of the movies that appeared on the American Film Institute's original 1997 list of Best One Hundred Movies of All Time. So with a clinical approach and an open mind, I'm not predisposed one way or the other to like or dislike a picture I would have passed on otherwise. So now I've seen it, it passes muster as an entertaining film, and my movie viewing experience is that much more well rounded. With a little bit of luck, you might enjoy it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply delightful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't necessarily have to be into musical to be taken in by this charming film. All I can say is that I wish there would be more musical movies like this. It's a movie with such a pleasant and joyful atmosphere to it, even though the story of course also takes some dramatic turns. But this is what musicals should all be about; simply have a good time watching it and let it be a feast for your eyes and ears. The entire movie does feel and look very stagy but in this case that really isn't a complaint. It simply suits the movie well and makes it part of the reason why this is such perfect light entertainment to watch. Besides, it is a good looking movie as well, with all of its grand sets and nice costume design. But what is a musical without any good music. And luckily this movie does really has some good and pleasant songs in it, performed nicely by its cast, though not always its original cast. Audrey Hepburn still got dubbed for instance, which was also really apparent in some of the songs. Rex Harrison on the other hand does all of the singing himself and his style of singing and acting fits the character and songs very well. Yes, all of the acting in general is very impressive in this movie as well. I had seen Rex Harrison in a couple of movies before but he never impressed me as much as he did with his role in this movie. Also Audrey Hepburn surprised me. I have always loved her but I never realized how incredible versatile as an actress she actually was until I saw her in this movie. She basically plays two different characters in this. She is both very convincing as the foul mounted girl from the streets and as the sophisticated, uppercases lady. You probably won't even recognize her at first, until she slowly starts to transform into the lovely beautiful young woman, we also all remember Audrey Hepburn as. The story and characters within this movie are definitely not all without its flaws but in this case all the story wanted was to deliver a simple, light and enjoyable movie for everybody of all ages, sexes and ethnicities to enjoy. And I think they most definitely did not fail with this. At least the Academy Awards also agree with me, since the movie received 8 Oscar's, including the most important ones for best director and best picture of the year. It also eventually would turn out to be the only Oscar legendary director George Cukor received. Simply a movie to enjoy. 9/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit song after hit song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every song in this musical is a hit. Rex Harrison is at his Rex Harrisoniest, and Audrey Hepburn reveals layer after layer of Eliza Doolittle. The costumes are brilliant, particularly in the artfully- staged, hilarious scene at the racetrack. Stanley Holloway, who played Eliza's ne'er-do-well father on Broadway before bringing the role to the screen, steals his scenes. This movie earned every bit of its Best Picture Oscar and remains one of the best movie musicals of all time. Though the movie deals with the touchy subjects of class and gender and does not pull its punches, it is not mean-spirited and does not run too much afoul of modern sensibilities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic. or little more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I confess- Audrey Hepburn is one of my favorite actresses. so, it is difficult to not love this film. smart, charming, almost touching, full of great performances, it is adorable more than a classic. songs, adaptation, costumes - all is perfect. and each new meeting is a pure delight. sure, hypothesis of Julie Andrews as Eliza is present. but not for long time because Hepburn does a splendid work and the levels of metamorphose of poor young girl in a brilliant lady is credible and fascinating. sure, the axis remains Rex Harrison and this fact is obvious. but , like in case of each good movie, the flavor after its end is essential. in this case it is not only entertainment but drops of special beauty who covers small imperfections and gives a very nice feeling of life joy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alyssa Black (Aly200)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'My Fair Lady' originated on Broadway in 1957 and was a huge successful when released. This film adaption was released in 1964 without the original star in the female lead (Julie Andrews was to star in 'Mary Poppins' and that year won the Best Actress Oscar for her portrayal). But Audrey Hepburn shines in this film as the fiery-spirited cockney flower girl Eliza Doolittle (her singing was dubbed by Marni Nixon)opposite Rex Harrison's Henry Higgins (the role he originated on Broadway). The two actors are perfect foils for each other as the student and tutor who clash over the social graces that Eliza must learn in order to be a lady. This musical is quite underrated because of Hepburn's performance as opposed to Julie Andrews' in the original production. I think that it's a matter of interpretation; both actresses have their styles and play the character in her own way. This is one of Audrey's finest performance since her performance as Holly Golightly in 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could somehow be better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zoe Yac
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Audrey Hepburn is simply stunning in this movie - as in most. Only drag is that she did not actually sing her songs in the movie. Also, the poor quality of the majority of songs is quite disappointing. The story is just superb, though. But who is to thank for that? Anyways, I give it a 7/10 because of the very solid overall cast, some quite remembering songs - by far the most outstanding of them being "I Could Have Danced All Night" -, the thought out lead characters (but actually only them, since the supporting roles were rather shallow. At least the part of Pickering could be exhausted in a more interesting way, although it is hinted at at the end of the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What flair, my lady!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical adaptation of a tale of love between a book-learned pedagogue and a flower-selling prodigy bonded through phonetics. The movie is a melange of mellifluous songs, male chauvinism and a maiden who undergoes a paradigm shift in her speech and charisma. I love the scene in which people are busy with their daily chores and the frame freezes, then the camera zooms out and another set of people move around and then it freezes and another set of people move around. And all the people in the 3 sets of the frame move around in a haphazard manner. I beg your pardon lovers of literature, I haven't read the play by George Bernard Shaw nor have i heard about it before watching the film. Professor Higgins takes Eliza as a disciple to experiment on after Col. Pickering throws a challenge that he couldn't make a duchess out of a flower-seller. Professor Higgins, an expert in Phonetics, is a celibate and often looks down on women. He provides her luxury and at the same time forces her to try and try till she enunciates the words correctly. After several exhaustive sessions, Higgins makes her perceive what they're trying to do to her and his words do the miracle. She speaks flawlessly and with a rich and refined voice. Higgins takes her to a horse race, a place where Eliza could interact with the blue-blooded. She does well in the beginning but slowly she starts uttering innuendos and senseless idioms that Higgins and Pickering try to cover up with illogical explanations. Things go back to round one when she screams in enjoyment in the language of the slum-dwellers. Higgins gives her rigorous training and his efforts bear fruit in a matter of time. She draws the attention of several people and a princess showers encomiums on her charisma. Higgins is lauded for his efforts by his fellowmen but they fail to understand Eliza's efforts too; all that she had to endure to become a subject of Higgins' achievement. She leaves the house in agony and swears to never return again. Higgins realizes they are in-execrable but takes time to confess it and comes to him after his long-due confession.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mobility with Music ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Oscar for best picture of 1964 went to this musical. It was very hard to understand Audrey Hepburn at the beginning of the film with that cockneyed accent. She came into the role as the picture progressed and she became a lady. This is basically a story of class warfare set to music without the violence of Oscar winner "West Side Story." Rex Harrison won the best actor here and although he gave a good performance as speech professor Henry Higgins, am sure the other nominees were better. He certainly looked down on the gutter snipe Hepburn, but as the picture went by he certainly grew accustomed to her face. After he makes her a lady and she is a success at the ball, Hepburn, as Eliza, is at the crossroad of her life. What shall become of her? Will someone please explain to me why Gladys Cooper was nominated for best supporting actress here? Her part was next to nothing and she added zilch to the picture. Cooper was far more magnificent in her other nominations some 20 years before- "The Song of Bernadette," and "Now, Voyager." She missed a 1958 supporting bid for "Separate Tables." Harrison mouthed the words beautifully to the music of the songs given to him. That was an achievement in itself. The picture proved without doubt that upward social mobility is possible. The film may also be described as a Cinderella like-tale. After all, our girl in rags wound up with a gem as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rags to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dichoi-197-207907
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Fair Lady is an unlikely musical of beloved songs and characters. Romance, refreshing comedy, and unexpected satire weave through this wonderful film that retains a great deal of George Bernard Shaw's "Pygmalion" (1912) which was itself inspired by Ovid's Metamorphosis. Even though it is one of the most loved romances, no one ever gets kissed. No nudity, no sex, not even a declaration of love. The story celebrates not romance but intelligence. The story involves a meeting of two egos outside a lavish London theater: linguist Henry Higgins (Rex Harrison) and flower girl Eliza Doolittle (Audrey Hepburn). Eliza is a common Cockney flower girl who is plucked from the Covent Garden and transformed into a "lady" by Higgins. It is difficult to discuss George Cukor's 1964 film as it actually exists because of the gossip that muddles it greatness. Many viewers would rather discuss the film that was not made, the one that would have starred Julie Andrews who made the role of Eliza her own on the stage. Casting Audrey Hepburn was an insult to a then little-known Andrews because the studio head Jack L. Warner chose Hepburn for her greater box appeal. Furthermore, Hepburn did not sing her own songs but was instead dubbed by the talented Marni Nixon. This dubbing became quite notorious, so much so that although My Fair Lady was nominated for twelve Oscars and won eight, Hepburn was not even nominated for best actress. Ironically, Andrews won the Best Actress Award for "Mary Poppins," while Hepburn was snubbed by the Academy. Let us step back and take another look at the controversy. Indeed, Hepburn did not sing her own songs. However, the dubbing of singing voices was very common at the time, and Nixon herself dubbed other actresses such as Deborah Kerr and Natalie Wood. Even actors who did sing their own songs lip-synced to their own pre-recorded dubs. The fact that Hepburn did not do her own singing only makes her success, which is that she did her own acting. What Hepburn did for the role was to make you care about Eliza and to believe in her transformation. Even if she did not sing her part, Hepburn still delivered a dazzling performance because of her ability to make us believe. My Fair Lady drew its dialogue from Shaw's "Pygmalion," which is more challenging than most other musicals. The dialogue was not only embedded with well-honed wit and satire but required Eliza to transition accents from Cockney to the Queen's English. Hepburn does this with flawless technique and confidence in a performance with palpable passion. The audience is given reasons to care about her character. We can relate to her, feel for what happens to her, and rejoice when things go her way. Throughout the film, Hepburn, who is so tenderly waiflike, brings a poignancy to her scenes that is magical. Not only does My Fair Lady feature an involving story with compelling characters, but there is not a dud to be found on the list of more than a dozen toe-tapping numbers. The best-known song from the film, "I Could Have Danced All Night," is familiar to almost everyone  even though who have not seen the movie. This is a testament to the brilliant marriage of dialogue and lyric in the film as seen in a poor smitten character named Freddy. Many people despise musicals because of the preposterous way characters pause mid-sentence and suddenly burst into song. Freddy avoids these predictable scenes, singing "On the Street Where You Live" with a childlike candor compared with other more emotional characters. Apart from the marvels of its words and music, My Fair Lady is a visual triumph laced with elegance. Cukor made exquisite use of Cecil Beaton who designed the production, the sets, and the costumes. Many extras are dressed in whites, blacks, and greys, creating a backdrop for Higgins in his brown tweed suit and Eliza, who has a touch of red in her dress. The story expresses endless optimism through the d&eacute;cor of Higgins' home, which is packed with the latest mechanical gadgets for teaching people how to speak better. The unusually remote camera stays well back from the action with relatively few close-ups, allowing the audience to see as much of the luxurious sets as possible. The audience can unmistakably see that this is a movie into which a world of care and effort was invested. What distinguished My Fair Lady above all is that it actually says something meaningful. In a film of quick words, unforgettable music, and outstanding images, it analyzes the socialist attack on the British class system. By dramatizing how superiority and success was inherited, not earned, through Eliza's escape from the lower class system, My Fair Lady becomes a great entertainment as well as a great influence. The impact it had on the creation of feminism and class- consciousness through the mid-1900s is still not sufficiently appreciated. It was a revolutionary message in England at the time, and it is still thought-provoking. Not only do people not make movies like this anymore  they simply cannot. The movie industry seems to no longer be interested in musicals about adults, much less adults with ideas. Few film genres are as magical as musicals, and few musicals are as intelligent and joyous as My Fair Lady. It is both notable and marvelous that the film stays so true to the original material and does not cave in to a schmaltzy rewritten happy ending. It remains an open question to the audience whether Eliza stays to listen to what he says next. If these two are ever to fall in love, it will be with their heads, instead of their hearts. This movie is a classic not because a group of film experts have labeled it as such, but because it has been, and always will be, a pure joy to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey Hepburn is, and always will be, Eliza Doolittle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I have the highest respect for Julie Andrews, I think the producers made the right choice in Audrey Hepburn. Andrews has the clear advantage of an extraordinarily fine voice, so she could have done her own singing, as she did in the London cast recording. But I have trouble seeing Andrews as the ideal for the Eliza Doolittle character over the full scope of the movie. What My Fair Lady is about is the story of Pygmalion, the play by George Bernard Shaw, but also the earlier Greek legend of the sculptor who created the image of his perfect woman out of stone, so beautiful that she came alive. So the end result must be a very high ideal of perfection, grace and beauty. Now Julie Andrews is no slouch in those departments, but she lacks the extraordinary other-worldliness that Audrey Hepburn was renown for. When Hepburn played a real princess in her first starring role in Roman Holiday, she was absolutely convincing. She made the transformation from caterpillar to butterfly in Sabrina. So when Eliza goes to the royal ball and everyone thinks the former flower girl is a princess going incognito, it is heartbreakingly believable. Eliza truly has been transformed into the ideal of perfection and beauty. As much as I admire Andrews, I can't quite imagine her being as convincing in that scene. Some say Andrews earned the part for her portrayal of the role on stage, and that she got a raw deal. If that had been the end of her career, I would be inclined to agree. But look at the wonderful, dream roles she has had since, particularly the immortal Sound of Music, in which she was perfectly cast. I think being miscast can be as bad or worse than no role at all. While Andrews certainly would not have been a disaster, I think she might have been a slight disappointment. There is a big difference between a portrayal on stage, in which the audience is more willing to suspend disbelief, and on film, where every pore is five feet tall. That is probably why the wonderful, but aging, Mary Martin didn't get many film roles. Andrews might not have been as convincing an Eliza on film as she was on stage. I see some posters calling My Fair Lady an American production. Just a reminder: Hepburn was not American. She was British-Dutch-Belgian. And while she came from a rich family, she grew up in starvation poverty while in Holland during World War II, which may have given her the depth to play such a range of roles, from the flower girl to princesses. I'm not saying Hepburn's portrayal of Eliza is perfect. I grew up with Hepburn as Eliza, and she inhabits the role, in my mind. But as an adult, with the closer examination of being able to watch the DVD version an infinite number of times, I do see some weaknesses in her portrayal. I doubt most people would see these in the first or second viewing. A more troubling question is whether Hepburn should have done her own singing. She had a good singing voice, and could have done a good job. You can hear her singing Moon River in Breakfast at Tiffany's. The ultimate reason they dubbed her may have been Rex Harrison and Stanley Holloway. They are trying to make a musical, and most of the stars can't actually sing. To have a weak singing performance from Hepburn would have been too much. Marni Nixon could be counted on for a skilled voice match. (BTW, Nixon finally appears on screen in Sound of Music, as a nun commenting on Maria -- Andrews.) Problem solved. As to shortening some numbers, hey, this is a musical! The music is what it's about. I've seen too many musicals where they feel compelled to cut and cut to speed things up, shorten the movie. In South Pacific, the movie version cuts the "Wash That Man Right Out of my Hair" number down to one verse, and they really wrecked it. Brigadoon cut everything down to the minimum, and took all the wind out of the sails. With a musical, if you want to tell a story and have lots of music, you have got to make the film longer than the average non-musical; it's a big mistake to cut out parts of the story, or truncate the musical numbers. And as to the sets, the lesson I have derived from looking at many musicals is that you do not want a set that is too realistic. A musical is by nature a fantasy, because real people don't go breaking into song and dance in daily life. You need sets that are beautiful, but not entirely realistic. The 1962 remake of State Fair by Mel Ferrer, Hepburn's husband, was a disaster, and one reason was it was filmed very realistically. Guys and Dolls is perhaps the best example of non- realism, because the story was a fable, and the sets were almost like giant illustrations from a children's book. On the other hand, the movie version should not, generally, look too much like a Broadway play. Now, let's see, what would the My Fair Lady look like if the sets were a brutally realistic depiction of Edwardian London? We're talking real slums, with real horse manure. Save the realism for non-musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll make a queen of that barbarous wretch"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicsoncall
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the pros and cons of this film, and as an outsider looking in, my advantage perhaps is that I don't know a whole lot about George Bernard Shaw, Pygmalion, Broadway musicals and Audrey Hepburn's dubbed voice as a singing Eliza Doolittle. So coming in cold, and not particularly a fan of movie musicals, I'd have to say this was watchable enough, though at almost three hours, I WAS getting antsy after the two hour mark. I realize that fans and critics will bring their own prejudices to bear in regard to the casting and staging of the story, but that aside, and with no particular horse in the race, I'd have to say that this was entertaining enough for the kind of picture I generally don't go out of the way for. My mission is to watch and review each of the movies that appeared on the American Film Institute's original 1997 list of Best One Hundred Movies of All Time. So with a clinical approach and an open mind, I'm not predisposed one way or the other to like or dislike a picture I would have passed on otherwise. So now I've seen it, it passes muster as an entertaining film, and my movie viewing experience is that much more well rounded. With a little bit of luck, you might enjoy it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply delightful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't necessarily have to be into musical to be taken in by this charming film. All I can say is that I wish there would be more musical movies like this. It's a movie with such a pleasant and joyful atmosphere to it, even though the story of course also takes some dramatic turns. But this is what musicals should all be about; simply have a good time watching it and let it be a feast for your eyes and ears. The entire movie does feel and look very stagy but in this case that really isn't a complaint. It simply suits the movie well and makes it part of the reason why this is such perfect light entertainment to watch. Besides, it is a good looking movie as well, with all of its grand sets and nice costume design. But what is a musical without any good music. And luckily this movie does really has some good and pleasant songs in it, performed nicely by its cast, though not always its original cast. Audrey Hepburn still got dubbed for instance, which was also really apparent in some of the songs. Rex Harrison on the other hand does all of the singing himself and his style of singing and acting fits the character and songs very well. Yes, all of the acting in general is very impressive in this movie as well. I had seen Rex Harrison in a couple of movies before but he never impressed me as much as he did with his role in this movie. Also Audrey Hepburn surprised me. I have always loved her but I never realized how incredible versatile as an actress she actually was until I saw her in this movie. She basically plays two different characters in this. She is both very convincing as the foul mounted girl from the streets and as the sophisticated, uppercases lady. You probably won't even recognize her at first, until she slowly starts to transform into the lovely beautiful young woman, we also all remember Audrey Hepburn as. The story and characters within this movie are definitely not all without its flaws but in this case all the story wanted was to deliver a simple, light and enjoyable movie for everybody of all ages, sexes and ethnicities to enjoy. And I think they most definitely did not fail with this. At least the Academy Awards also agree with me, since the movie received 8 Oscar's, including the most important ones for best director and best picture of the year. It also eventually would turn out to be the only Oscar legendary director George Cukor received. Simply a movie to enjoy. 9/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit song after hit song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every song in this musical is a hit. Rex Harrison is at his Rex Harrisoniest, and Audrey Hepburn reveals layer after layer of Eliza Doolittle. The costumes are brilliant, particularly in the artfully- staged, hilarious scene at the racetrack. Stanley Holloway, who played Eliza's ne'er-do-well father on Broadway before bringing the role to the screen, steals his scenes. This movie earned every bit of its Best Picture Oscar and remains one of the best movie musicals of all time. Though the movie deals with the touchy subjects of class and gender and does not pull its punches, it is not mean-spirited and does not run too much afoul of modern sensibilities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic. or little more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I confess- Audrey Hepburn is one of my favorite actresses. so, it is difficult to not love this film. smart, charming, almost touching, full of great performances, it is adorable more than a classic. songs, adaptation, costumes - all is perfect. and each new meeting is a pure delight. sure, hypothesis of Julie Andrews as Eliza is present. but not for long time because Hepburn does a splendid work and the levels of metamorphose of poor young girl in a brilliant lady is credible and fascinating. sure, the axis remains Rex Harrison and this fact is obvious. but , like in case of each good movie, the flavor after its end is essential. in this case it is not only entertainment but drops of special beauty who covers small imperfections and gives a very nice feeling of life joy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alyssa Black (Aly200)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'My Fair Lady' originated on Broadway in 1957 and was a huge successful when released. This film adaption was released in 1964 without the original star in the female lead (Julie Andrews was to star in 'Mary Poppins' and that year won the Best Actress Oscar for her portrayal). But Audrey Hepburn shines in this film as the fiery-spirited cockney flower girl Eliza Doolittle (her singing was dubbed by Marni Nixon)opposite Rex Harrison's Henry Higgins (the role he originated on Broadway). The two actors are perfect foils for each other as the student and tutor who clash over the social graces that Eliza must learn in order to be a lady. This musical is quite underrated because of Hepburn's performance as opposed to Julie Andrews' in the original production. I think that it's a matter of interpretation; both actresses have their styles and play the character in her own way. This is one of Audrey's finest performance since her performance as Holly Golightly in 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could somehow be better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zoe Yac
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Audrey Hepburn is simply stunning in this movie - as in most. Only drag is that she did not actually sing her songs in the movie. Also, the poor quality of the majority of songs is quite disappointing. The story is just superb, though. But who is to thank for that? Anyways, I give it a 7/10 because of the very solid overall cast, some quite remembering songs - by far the most outstanding of them being "I Could Have Danced All Night" -, the thought out lead characters (but actually only them, since the supporting roles were rather shallow. At least the part of Pickering could be exhausted in a more interesting way, although it is hinted at at the end of the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What flair, my lady!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical adaptation of a tale of love between a book-learned pedagogue and a flower-selling prodigy bonded through phonetics. The movie is a melange of mellifluous songs, male chauvinism and a maiden who undergoes a paradigm shift in her speech and charisma. I love the scene in which people are busy with their daily chores and the frame freezes, then the camera zooms out and another set of people move around and then it freezes and another set of people move around. And all the people in the 3 sets of the frame move around in a haphazard manner. I beg your pardon lovers of literature, I haven't read the play by George Bernard Shaw nor have i heard about it before watching the film. Professor Higgins takes Eliza as a disciple to experiment on after Col. Pickering throws a challenge that he couldn't make a duchess out of a flower-seller. Professor Higgins, an expert in Phonetics, is a celibate and often looks down on women. He provides her luxury and at the same time forces her to try and try till she enunciates the words correctly. After several exhaustive sessions, Higgins makes her perceive what they're trying to do to her and his words do the miracle. She speaks flawlessly and with a rich and refined voice. Higgins takes her to a horse race, a place where Eliza could interact with the blue-blooded. She does well in the beginning but slowly she starts uttering innuendos and senseless idioms that Higgins and Pickering try to cover up with illogical explanations. Things go back to round one when she screams in enjoyment in the language of the slum-dwellers. Higgins gives her rigorous training and his efforts bear fruit in a matter of time. She draws the attention of several people and a princess showers encomiums on her charisma. Higgins is lauded for his efforts by his fellowmen but they fail to understand Eliza's efforts too; all that she had to endure to become a subject of Higgins' achievement. She leaves the house in agony and swears to never return again. Higgins realizes they are in-execrable but takes time to confess it and comes to him after his long-due confession.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mobility with Music ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Oscar for best picture of 1964 went to this musical. It was very hard to understand Audrey Hepburn at the beginning of the film with that cockneyed accent. She came into the role as the picture progressed and she became a lady. This is basically a story of class warfare set to music without the violence of Oscar winner "West Side Story." Rex Harrison won the best actor here and although he gave a good performance as speech professor Henry Higgins, am sure the other nominees were better. He certainly looked down on the gutter snipe Hepburn, but as the picture went by he certainly grew accustomed to her face. After he makes her a lady and she is a success at the ball, Hepburn, as Eliza, is at the crossroad of her life. What shall become of her? Will someone please explain to me why Gladys Cooper was nominated for best supporting actress here? Her part was next to nothing and she added zilch to the picture. Cooper was far more magnificent in her other nominations some 20 years before- "The Song of Bernadette," and "Now, Voyager." She missed a 1958 supporting bid for "Separate Tables." Harrison mouthed the words beautifully to the music of the songs given to him. That was an achievement in itself. The picture proved without doubt that upward social mobility is possible. The film may also be described as a Cinderella like-tale. After all, our girl in rags wound up with a gem as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rags to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dichoi-197-207907
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Fair Lady is an unlikely musical of beloved songs and characters. Romance, refreshing comedy, and unexpected satire weave through this wonderful film that retains a great deal of George Bernard Shaw's "Pygmalion" (1912) which was itself inspired by Ovid's Metamorphosis. Even though it is one of the most loved romances, no one ever gets kissed. No nudity, no sex, not even a declaration of love. The story celebrates not romance but intelligence. The story involves a meeting of two egos outside a lavish London theater: linguist Henry Higgins (Rex Harrison) and flower girl Eliza Doolittle (Audrey Hepburn). Eliza is a common Cockney flower girl who is plucked from the Covent Garden and transformed into a "lady" by Higgins. It is difficult to discuss George Cukor's 1964 film as it actually exists because of the gossip that muddles it greatness. Many viewers would rather discuss the film that was not made, the one that would have starred Julie Andrews who made the role of Eliza her own on the stage. Casting Audrey Hepburn was an insult to a then little-known Andrews because the studio head Jack L. Warner chose Hepburn for her greater box appeal. Furthermore, Hepburn did not sing her own songs but was instead dubbed by the talented Marni Nixon. This dubbing became quite notorious, so much so that although My Fair Lady was nominated for twelve Oscars and won eight, Hepburn was not even nominated for best actress. Ironically, Andrews won the Best Actress Award for "Mary Poppins," while Hepburn was snubbed by the Academy. Let us step back and take another look at the controversy. Indeed, Hepburn did not sing her own songs. However, the dubbing of singing voices was very common at the time, and Nixon herself dubbed other actresses such as Deborah Kerr and Natalie Wood. Even actors who did sing their own songs lip-synced to their own pre-recorded dubs. The fact that Hepburn did not do her own singing only makes her success, which is that she did her own acting. What Hepburn did for the role was to make you care about Eliza and to believe in her transformation. Even if she did not sing her part, Hepburn still delivered a dazzling performance because of her ability to make us believe. My Fair Lady drew its dialogue from Shaw's "Pygmalion," which is more challenging than most other musicals. The dialogue was not only embedded with well-honed wit and satire but required Eliza to transition accents from Cockney to the Queen's English. Hepburn does this with flawless technique and confidence in a performance with palpable passion. The audience is given reasons to care about her character. We can relate to her, feel for what happens to her, and rejoice when things go her way. Throughout the film, Hepburn, who is so tenderly waiflike, brings a poignancy to her scenes that is magical. Not only does My Fair Lady feature an involving story with compelling characters, but there is not a dud to be found on the list of more than a dozen toe-tapping numbers. The best-known song from the film, "I Could Have Danced All Night," is familiar to almost everyone  even though who have not seen the movie. This is a testament to the brilliant marriage of dialogue and lyric in the film as seen in a poor smitten character named Freddy. Many people despise musicals because of the preposterous way characters pause mid-sentence and suddenly burst into song. Freddy avoids these predictable scenes, singing "On the Street Where You Live" with a childlike candor compared with other more emotional characters. Apart from the marvels of its words and music, My Fair Lady is a visual triumph laced with elegance. Cukor made exquisite use of Cecil Beaton who designed the production, the sets, and the costumes. Many extras are dressed in whites, blacks, and greys, creating a backdrop for Higgins in his brown tweed suit and Eliza, who has a touch of red in her dress. The story expresses endless optimism through the d&eacute;cor of Higgins' home, which is packed with the latest mechanical gadgets for teaching people how to speak better. The unusually remote camera stays well back from the action with relatively few close-ups, allowing the audience to see as much of the luxurious sets as possible. The audience can unmistakably see that this is a movie into which a world of care and effort was invested. What distinguished My Fair Lady above all is that it actually says something meaningful. In a film of quick words, unforgettable music, and outstanding images, it analyzes the socialist attack on the British class system. By dramatizing how superiority and success was inherited, not earned, through Eliza's escape from the lower class system, My Fair Lady becomes a great entertainment as well as a great influence. The impact it had on the creation of feminism and class- consciousness through the mid-1900s is still not sufficiently appreciated. It was a revolutionary message in England at the time, and it is still thought-provoking. Not only do people not make movies like this anymore  they simply cannot. The movie industry seems to no longer be interested in musicals about adults, much less adults with ideas. Few film genres are as magical as musicals, and few musicals are as intelligent and joyous as My Fair Lady. It is both notable and marvelous that the film stays so true to the original material and does not cave in to a schmaltzy rewritten happy ending. It remains an open question to the audience whether Eliza stays to listen to what he says next. If these two are ever to fall in love, it will be with their heads, instead of their hearts. This movie is a classic not because a group of film experts have labeled it as such, but because it has been, and always will be, a pure joy to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey Hepburn is, and always will be, Eliza Doolittle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I have the highest respect for Julie Andrews, I think the producers made the right choice in Audrey Hepburn. Andrews has the clear advantage of an extraordinarily fine voice, so she could have done her own singing, as she did in the London cast recording. But I have trouble seeing Andrews as the ideal for the Eliza Doolittle character over the full scope of the movie. What My Fair Lady is about is the story of Pygmalion, the play by George Bernard Shaw, but also the earlier Greek legend of the sculptor who created the image of his perfect woman out of stone, so beautiful that she came alive. So the end result must be a very high ideal of perfection, grace and beauty. Now Julie Andrews is no slouch in those departments, but she lacks the extraordinary other-worldliness that Audrey Hepburn was renown for. When Hepburn played a real princess in her first starring role in Roman Holiday, she was absolutely convincing. She made the transformation from caterpillar to butterfly in Sabrina. So when Eliza goes to the royal ball and everyone thinks the former flower girl is a princess going incognito, it is heartbreakingly believable. Eliza truly has been transformed into the ideal of perfection and beauty. As much as I admire Andrews, I can't quite imagine her being as convincing in that scene. Some say Andrews earned the part for her portrayal of the role on stage, and that she got a raw deal. If that had been the end of her career, I would be inclined to agree. But look at the wonderful, dream roles she has had since, particularly the immortal Sound of Music, in which she was perfectly cast. I think being miscast can be as bad or worse than no role at all. While Andrews certainly would not have been a disaster, I think she might have been a slight disappointment. There is a big difference between a portrayal on stage, in which the audience is more willing to suspend disbelief, and on film, where every pore is five feet tall. That is probably why the wonderful, but aging, Mary Martin didn't get many film roles. Andrews might not have been as convincing an Eliza on film as she was on stage. I see some posters calling My Fair Lady an American production. Just a reminder: Hepburn was not American. She was British-Dutch-Belgian. And while she came from a rich family, she grew up in starvation poverty while in Holland during World War II, which may have given her the depth to play such a range of roles, from the flower girl to princesses. I'm not saying Hepburn's portrayal of Eliza is perfect. I grew up with Hepburn as Eliza, and she inhabits the role, in my mind. But as an adult, with the closer examination of being able to watch the DVD version an infinite number of times, I do see some weaknesses in her portrayal. I doubt most people would see these in the first or second viewing. A more troubling question is whether Hepburn should have done her own singing. She had a good singing voice, and could have done a good job. You can hear her singing Moon River in Breakfast at Tiffany's. The ultimate reason they dubbed her may have been Rex Harrison and Stanley Holloway. They are trying to make a musical, and most of the stars can't actually sing. To have a weak singing performance from Hepburn would have been too much. Marni Nixon could be counted on for a skilled voice match. (BTW, Nixon finally appears on screen in Sound of Music, as a nun commenting on Maria -- Andrews.) Problem solved. As to shortening some numbers, hey, this is a musical! The music is what it's about. I've seen too many musicals where they feel compelled to cut and cut to speed things up, shorten the movie. In South Pacific, the movie version cuts the "Wash That Man Right Out of my Hair" number down to one verse, and they really wrecked it. Brigadoon cut everything down to the minimum, and took all the wind out of the sails. With a musical, if you want to tell a story and have lots of music, you have got to make the film longer than the average non-musical; it's a big mistake to cut out parts of the story, or truncate the musical numbers. And as to the sets, the lesson I have derived from looking at many musicals is that you do not want a set that is too realistic. A musical is by nature a fantasy, because real people don't go breaking into song and dance in daily life. You need sets that are beautiful, but not entirely realistic. The 1962 remake of State Fair by Mel Ferrer, Hepburn's husband, was a disaster, and one reason was it was filmed very realistically. Guys and Dolls is perhaps the best example of non- realism, because the story was a fable, and the sets were almost like giant illustrations from a children's book. On the other hand, the movie version should not, generally, look too much like a Broadway play. Now, let's see, what would the My Fair Lady look like if the sets were a brutally realistic depiction of Edwardian London? We're talking real slums, with real horse manure. Save the realism for non-musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll make a queen of that barbarous wretch"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicsoncall
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the pros and cons of this film, and as an outsider looking in, my advantage perhaps is that I don't know a whole lot about George Bernard Shaw, Pygmalion, Broadway musicals and Audrey Hepburn's dubbed voice as a singing Eliza Doolittle. So coming in cold, and not particularly a fan of movie musicals, I'd have to say this was watchable enough, though at almost three hours, I WAS getting antsy after the two hour mark. I realize that fans and critics will bring their own prejudices to bear in regard to the casting and staging of the story, but that aside, and with no particular horse in the race, I'd have to say that this was entertaining enough for the kind of picture I generally don't go out of the way for. My mission is to watch and review each of the movies that appeared on the American Film Institute's original 1997 list of Best One Hundred Movies of All Time. So with a clinical approach and an open mind, I'm not predisposed one way or the other to like or dislike a picture I would have passed on otherwise. So now I've seen it, it passes muster as an entertaining film, and my movie viewing experience is that much more well rounded. With a little bit of luck, you might enjoy it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply delightful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't necessarily have to be into musical to be taken in by this charming film. All I can say is that I wish there would be more musical movies like this. It's a movie with such a pleasant and joyful atmosphere to it, even though the story of course also takes some dramatic turns. But this is what musicals should all be about; simply have a good time watching it and let it be a feast for your eyes and ears. The entire movie does feel and look very stagy but in this case that really isn't a complaint. It simply suits the movie well and makes it part of the reason why this is such perfect light entertainment to watch. Besides, it is a good looking movie as well, with all of its grand sets and nice costume design. But what is a musical without any good music. And luckily this movie does really has some good and pleasant songs in it, performed nicely by its cast, though not always its original cast. Audrey Hepburn still got dubbed for instance, which was also really apparent in some of the songs. Rex Harrison on the other hand does all of the singing himself and his style of singing and acting fits the character and songs very well. Yes, all of the acting in general is very impressive in this movie as well. I had seen Rex Harrison in a couple of movies before but he never impressed me as much as he did with his role in this movie. Also Audrey Hepburn surprised me. I have always loved her but I never realized how incredible versatile as an actress she actually was until I saw her in this movie. She basically plays two different characters in this. She is both very convincing as the foul mounted girl from the streets and as the sophisticated, uppercases lady. You probably won't even recognize her at first, until she slowly starts to transform into the lovely beautiful young woman, we also all remember Audrey Hepburn as. The story and characters within this movie are definitely not all without its flaws but in this case all the story wanted was to deliver a simple, light and enjoyable movie for everybody of all ages, sexes and ethnicities to enjoy. And I think they most definitely did not fail with this. At least the Academy Awards also agree with me, since the movie received 8 Oscar's, including the most important ones for best director and best picture of the year. It also eventually would turn out to be the only Oscar legendary director George Cukor received. Simply a movie to enjoy. 9/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit song after hit song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every song in this musical is a hit. Rex Harrison is at his Rex Harrisoniest, and Audrey Hepburn reveals layer after layer of Eliza Doolittle. The costumes are brilliant, particularly in the artfully- staged, hilarious scene at the racetrack. Stanley Holloway, who played Eliza's ne'er-do-well father on Broadway before bringing the role to the screen, steals his scenes. This movie earned every bit of its Best Picture Oscar and remains one of the best movie musicals of all time. Though the movie deals with the touchy subjects of class and gender and does not pull its punches, it is not mean-spirited and does not run too much afoul of modern sensibilities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic. or little more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I confess- Audrey Hepburn is one of my favorite actresses. so, it is difficult to not love this film. smart, charming, almost touching, full of great performances, it is adorable more than a classic. songs, adaptation, costumes - all is perfect. and each new meeting is a pure delight. sure, hypothesis of Julie Andrews as Eliza is present. but not for long time because Hepburn does a splendid work and the levels of metamorphose of poor young girl in a brilliant lady is credible and fascinating. sure, the axis remains Rex Harrison and this fact is obvious. but , like in case of each good movie, the flavor after its end is essential. in this case it is not only entertainment but drops of special beauty who covers small imperfections and gives a very nice feeling of life joy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alyssa Black (Aly200)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'My Fair Lady' originated on Broadway in 1957 and was a huge successful when released. This film adaption was released in 1964 without the original star in the female lead (Julie Andrews was to star in 'Mary Poppins' and that year won the Best Actress Oscar for her portrayal). But Audrey Hepburn shines in this film as the fiery-spirited cockney flower girl Eliza Doolittle (her singing was dubbed by Marni Nixon)opposite Rex Harrison's Henry Higgins (the role he originated on Broadway). The two actors are perfect foils for each other as the student and tutor who clash over the social graces that Eliza must learn in order to be a lady. This musical is quite underrated because of Hepburn's performance as opposed to Julie Andrews' in the original production. I think that it's a matter of interpretation; both actresses have their styles and play the character in her own way. This is one of Audrey's finest performance since her performance as Holly Golightly in 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could somehow be better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zoe Yac
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Audrey Hepburn is simply stunning in this movie - as in most. Only drag is that she did not actually sing her songs in the movie. Also, the poor quality of the majority of songs is quite disappointing. The story is just superb, though. But who is to thank for that? Anyways, I give it a 7/10 because of the very solid overall cast, some quite remembering songs - by far the most outstanding of them being "I Could Have Danced All Night" -, the thought out lead characters (but actually only them, since the supporting roles were rather shallow. At least the part of Pickering could be exhausted in a more interesting way, although it is hinted at at the end of the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What flair, my lady!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical adaptation of a tale of love between a book-learned pedagogue and a flower-selling prodigy bonded through phonetics. The movie is a melange of mellifluous songs, male chauvinism and a maiden who undergoes a paradigm shift in her speech and charisma. I love the scene in which people are busy with their daily chores and the frame freezes, then the camera zooms out and another set of people move around and then it freezes and another set of people move around. And all the people in the 3 sets of the frame move around in a haphazard manner. I beg your pardon lovers of literature, I haven't read the play by George Bernard Shaw nor have i heard about it before watching the film. Professor Higgins takes Eliza as a disciple to experiment on after Col. Pickering throws a challenge that he couldn't make a duchess out of a flower-seller. Professor Higgins, an expert in Phonetics, is a celibate and often looks down on women. He provides her luxury and at the same time forces her to try and try till she enunciates the words correctly. After several exhaustive sessions, Higgins makes her perceive what they're trying to do to her and his words do the miracle. She speaks flawlessly and with a rich and refined voice. Higgins takes her to a horse race, a place where Eliza could interact with the blue-blooded. She does well in the beginning but slowly she starts uttering innuendos and senseless idioms that Higgins and Pickering try to cover up with illogical explanations. Things go back to round one when she screams in enjoyment in the language of the slum-dwellers. Higgins gives her rigorous training and his efforts bear fruit in a matter of time. She draws the attention of several people and a princess showers encomiums on her charisma. Higgins is lauded for his efforts by his fellowmen but they fail to understand Eliza's efforts too; all that she had to endure to become a subject of Higgins' achievement. She leaves the house in agony and swears to never return again. Higgins realizes they are in-execrable but takes time to confess it and comes to him after his long-due confession.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mobility with Music ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Oscar for best picture of 1964 went to this musical. It was very hard to understand Audrey Hepburn at the beginning of the film with that cockneyed accent. She came into the role as the picture progressed and she became a lady. This is basically a story of class warfare set to music without the violence of Oscar winner "West Side Story." Rex Harrison won the best actor here and although he gave a good performance as speech professor Henry Higgins, am sure the other nominees were better. He certainly looked down on the gutter snipe Hepburn, but as the picture went by he certainly grew accustomed to her face. After he makes her a lady and she is a success at the ball, Hepburn, as Eliza, is at the crossroad of her life. What shall become of her? Will someone please explain to me why Gladys Cooper was nominated for best supporting actress here? Her part was next to nothing and she added zilch to the picture. Cooper was far more magnificent in her other nominations some 20 years before- "The Song of Bernadette," and "Now, Voyager." She missed a 1958 supporting bid for "Separate Tables." Harrison mouthed the words beautifully to the music of the songs given to him. That was an achievement in itself. The picture proved without doubt that upward social mobility is possible. The film may also be described as a Cinderella like-tale. After all, our girl in rags wound up with a gem as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rags to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dichoi-197-207907
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Fair Lady is an unlikely musical of beloved songs and characters. Romance, refreshing comedy, and unexpected satire weave through this wonderful film that retains a great deal of George Bernard Shaw's "Pygmalion" (1912) which was itself inspired by Ovid's Metamorphosis. Even though it is one of the most loved romances, no one ever gets kissed. No nudity, no sex, not even a declaration of love. The story celebrates not romance but intelligence. The story involves a meeting of two egos outside a lavish London theater: linguist Henry Higgins (Rex Harrison) and flower girl Eliza Doolittle (Audrey Hepburn). Eliza is a common Cockney flower girl who is plucked from the Covent Garden and transformed into a "lady" by Higgins. It is difficult to discuss George Cukor's 1964 film as it actually exists because of the gossip that muddles it greatness. Many viewers would rather discuss the film that was not made, the one that would have starred Julie Andrews who made the role of Eliza her own on the stage. Casting Audrey Hepburn was an insult to a then little-known Andrews because the studio head Jack L. Warner chose Hepburn for her greater box appeal. Furthermore, Hepburn did not sing her own songs but was instead dubbed by the talented Marni Nixon. This dubbing became quite notorious, so much so that although My Fair Lady was nominated for twelve Oscars and won eight, Hepburn was not even nominated for best actress. Ironically, Andrews won the Best Actress Award for "Mary Poppins," while Hepburn was snubbed by the Academy. Let us step back and take another look at the controversy. Indeed, Hepburn did not sing her own songs. However, the dubbing of singing voices was very common at the time, and Nixon herself dubbed other actresses such as Deborah Kerr and Natalie Wood. Even actors who did sing their own songs lip-synced to their own pre-recorded dubs. The fact that Hepburn did not do her own singing only makes her success, which is that she did her own acting. What Hepburn did for the role was to make you care about Eliza and to believe in her transformation. Even if she did not sing her part, Hepburn still delivered a dazzling performance because of her ability to make us believe. My Fair Lady drew its dialogue from Shaw's "Pygmalion," which is more challenging than most other musicals. The dialogue was not only embedded with well-honed wit and satire but required Eliza to transition accents from Cockney to the Queen's English. Hepburn does this with flawless technique and confidence in a performance with palpable passion. The audience is given reasons to care about her character. We can relate to her, feel for what happens to her, and rejoice when things go her way. Throughout the film, Hepburn, who is so tenderly waiflike, brings a poignancy to her scenes that is magical. Not only does My Fair Lady feature an involving story with compelling characters, but there is not a dud to be found on the list of more than a dozen toe-tapping numbers. The best-known song from the film, "I Could Have Danced All Night," is familiar to almost everyone  even though who have not seen the movie. This is a testament to the brilliant marriage of dialogue and lyric in the film as seen in a poor smitten character named Freddy. Many people despise musicals because of the preposterous way characters pause mid-sentence and suddenly burst into song. Freddy avoids these predictable scenes, singing "On the Street Where You Live" with a childlike candor compared with other more emotional characters. Apart from the marvels of its words and music, My Fair Lady is a visual triumph laced with elegance. Cukor made exquisite use of Cecil Beaton who designed the production, the sets, and the costumes. Many extras are dressed in whites, blacks, and greys, creating a backdrop for Higgins in his brown tweed suit and Eliza, who has a touch of red in her dress. The story expresses endless optimism through the d&eacute;cor of Higgins' home, which is packed with the latest mechanical gadgets for teaching people how to speak better. The unusually remote camera stays well back from the action with relatively few close-ups, allowing the audience to see as much of the luxurious sets as possible. The audience can unmistakably see that this is a movie into which a world of care and effort was invested. What distinguished My Fair Lady above all is that it actually says something meaningful. In a film of quick words, unforgettable music, and outstanding images, it analyzes the socialist attack on the British class system. By dramatizing how superiority and success was inherited, not earned, through Eliza's escape from the lower class system, My Fair Lady becomes a great entertainment as well as a great influence. The impact it had on the creation of feminism and class- consciousness through the mid-1900s is still not sufficiently appreciated. It was a revolutionary message in England at the time, and it is still thought-provoking. Not only do people not make movies like this anymore  they simply cannot. The movie industry seems to no longer be interested in musicals about adults, much less adults with ideas. Few film genres are as magical as musicals, and few musicals are as intelligent and joyous as My Fair Lady. It is both notable and marvelous that the film stays so true to the original material and does not cave in to a schmaltzy rewritten happy ending. It remains an open question to the audience whether Eliza stays to listen to what he says next. If these two are ever to fall in love, it will be with their heads, instead of their hearts. This movie is a classic not because a group of film experts have labeled it as such, but because it has been, and always will be, a pure joy to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey Hepburn is, and always will be, Eliza Doolittle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I have the highest respect for Julie Andrews, I think the producers made the right choice in Audrey Hepburn. Andrews has the clear advantage of an extraordinarily fine voice, so she could have done her own singing, as she did in the London cast recording. But I have trouble seeing Andrews as the ideal for the Eliza Doolittle character over the full scope of the movie. What My Fair Lady is about is the story of Pygmalion, the play by George Bernard Shaw, but also the earlier Greek legend of the sculptor who created the image of his perfect woman out of stone, so beautiful that she came alive. So the end result must be a very high ideal of perfection, grace and beauty. Now Julie Andrews is no slouch in those departments, but she lacks the extraordinary other-worldliness that Audrey Hepburn was renown for. When Hepburn played a real princess in her first starring role in Roman Holiday, she was absolutely convincing. She made the transformation from caterpillar to butterfly in Sabrina. So when Eliza goes to the royal ball and everyone thinks the former flower girl is a princess going incognito, it is heartbreakingly believable. Eliza truly has been transformed into the ideal of perfection and beauty. As much as I admire Andrews, I can't quite imagine her being as convincing in that scene. Some say Andrews earned the part for her portrayal of the role on stage, and that she got a raw deal. If that had been the end of her career, I would be inclined to agree. But look at the wonderful, dream roles she has had since, particularly the immortal Sound of Music, in which she was perfectly cast. I think being miscast can be as bad or worse than no role at all. While Andrews certainly would not have been a disaster, I think she might have been a slight disappointment. There is a big difference between a portrayal on stage, in which the audience is more willing to suspend disbelief, and on film, where every pore is five feet tall. That is probably why the wonderful, but aging, Mary Martin didn't get many film roles. Andrews might not have been as convincing an Eliza on film as she was on stage. I see some posters calling My Fair Lady an American production. Just a reminder: Hepburn was not American. She was British-Dutch-Belgian. And while she came from a rich family, she grew up in starvation poverty while in Holland during World War II, which may have given her the depth to play such a range of roles, from the flower girl to princesses. I'm not saying Hepburn's portrayal of Eliza is perfect. I grew up with Hepburn as Eliza, and she inhabits the role, in my mind. But as an adult, with the closer examination of being able to watch the DVD version an infinite number of times, I do see some weaknesses in her portrayal. I doubt most people would see these in the first or second viewing. A more troubling question is whether Hepburn should have done her own singing. She had a good singing voice, and could have done a good job. You can hear her singing Moon River in Breakfast at Tiffany's. The ultimate reason they dubbed her may have been Rex Harrison and Stanley Holloway. They are trying to make a musical, and most of the stars can't actually sing. To have a weak singing performance from Hepburn would have been too much. Marni Nixon could be counted on for a skilled voice match. (BTW, Nixon finally appears on screen in Sound of Music, as a nun commenting on Maria -- Andrews.) Problem solved. As to shortening some numbers, hey, this is a musical! The music is what it's about. I've seen too many musicals where they feel compelled to cut and cut to speed things up, shorten the movie. In South Pacific, the movie version cuts the "Wash That Man Right Out of my Hair" number down to one verse, and they really wrecked it. Brigadoon cut everything down to the minimum, and took all the wind out of the sails. With a musical, if you want to tell a story and have lots of music, you have got to make the film longer than the average non-musical; it's a big mistake to cut out parts of the story, or truncate the musical numbers. And as to the sets, the lesson I have derived from looking at many musicals is that you do not want a set that is too realistic. A musical is by nature a fantasy, because real people don't go breaking into song and dance in daily life. You need sets that are beautiful, but not entirely realistic. The 1962 remake of State Fair by Mel Ferrer, Hepburn's husband, was a disaster, and one reason was it was filmed very realistically. Guys and Dolls is perhaps the best example of non- realism, because the story was a fable, and the sets were almost like giant illustrations from a children's book. On the other hand, the movie version should not, generally, look too much like a Broadway play. Now, let's see, what would the My Fair Lady look like if the sets were a brutally realistic depiction of Edwardian London? We're talking real slums, with real horse manure. Save the realism for non-musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll make a queen of that barbarous wretch"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicsoncall
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the pros and cons of this film, and as an outsider looking in, my advantage perhaps is that I don't know a whole lot about George Bernard Shaw, Pygmalion, Broadway musicals and Audrey Hepburn's dubbed voice as a singing Eliza Doolittle. So coming in cold, and not particularly a fan of movie musicals, I'd have to say this was watchable enough, though at almost three hours, I WAS getting antsy after the two hour mark. I realize that fans and critics will bring their own prejudices to bear in regard to the casting and staging of the story, but that aside, and with no particular horse in the race, I'd have to say that this was entertaining enough for the kind of picture I generally don't go out of the way for. My mission is to watch and review each of the movies that appeared on the American Film Institute's original 1997 list of Best One Hundred Movies of All Time. So with a clinical approach and an open mind, I'm not predisposed one way or the other to like or dislike a picture I would have passed on otherwise. So now I've seen it, it passes muster as an entertaining film, and my movie viewing experience is that much more well rounded. With a little bit of luck, you might enjoy it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply delightful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't necessarily have to be into musical to be taken in by this charming film. All I can say is that I wish there would be more musical movies like this. It's a movie with such a pleasant and joyful atmosphere to it, even though the story of course also takes some dramatic turns. But this is what musicals should all be about; simply have a good time watching it and let it be a feast for your eyes and ears. The entire movie does feel and look very stagy but in this case that really isn't a complaint. It simply suits the movie well and makes it part of the reason why this is such perfect light entertainment to watch. Besides, it is a good looking movie as well, with all of its grand sets and nice costume design. But what is a musical without any good music. And luckily this movie does really has some good and pleasant songs in it, performed nicely by its cast, though not always its original cast. Audrey Hepburn still got dubbed for instance, which was also really apparent in some of the songs. Rex Harrison on the other hand does all of the singing himself and his style of singing and acting fits the character and songs very well. Yes, all of the acting in general is very impressive in this movie as well. I had seen Rex Harrison in a couple of movies before but he never impressed me as much as he did with his role in this movie. Also Audrey Hepburn surprised me. I have always loved her but I never realized how incredible versatile as an actress she actually was until I saw her in this movie. She basically plays two different characters in this. She is both very convincing as the foul mounted girl from the streets and as the sophisticated, uppercases lady. You probably won't even recognize her at first, until she slowly starts to transform into the lovely beautiful young woman, we also all remember Audrey Hepburn as. The story and characters within this movie are definitely not all without its flaws but in this case all the story wanted was to deliver a simple, light and enjoyable movie for everybody of all ages, sexes and ethnicities to enjoy. And I think they most definitely did not fail with this. At least the Academy Awards also agree with me, since the movie received 8 Oscar's, including the most important ones for best director and best picture of the year. It also eventually would turn out to be the only Oscar legendary director George Cukor received. Simply a movie to enjoy. 9/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit song after hit song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every song in this musical is a hit. Rex Harrison is at his Rex Harrisoniest, and Audrey Hepburn reveals layer after layer of Eliza Doolittle. The costumes are brilliant, particularly in the artfully- staged, hilarious scene at the racetrack. Stanley Holloway, who played Eliza's ne'er-do-well father on Broadway before bringing the role to the screen, steals his scenes. This movie earned every bit of its Best Picture Oscar and remains one of the best movie musicals of all time. Though the movie deals with the touchy subjects of class and gender and does not pull its punches, it is not mean-spirited and does not run too much afoul of modern sensibilities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic. or little more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I confess- Audrey Hepburn is one of my favorite actresses. so, it is difficult to not love this film. smart, charming, almost touching, full of great performances, it is adorable more than a classic. songs, adaptation, costumes - all is perfect. and each new meeting is a pure delight. sure, hypothesis of Julie Andrews as Eliza is present. but not for long time because Hepburn does a splendid work and the levels of metamorphose of poor young girl in a brilliant lady is credible and fascinating. sure, the axis remains Rex Harrison and this fact is obvious. but , like in case of each good movie, the flavor after its end is essential. in this case it is not only entertainment but drops of special beauty who covers small imperfections and gives a very nice feeling of life joy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alyssa Black (Aly200)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'My Fair Lady' originated on Broadway in 1957 and was a huge successful when released. This film adaption was released in 1964 without the original star in the female lead (Julie Andrews was to star in 'Mary Poppins' and that year won the Best Actress Oscar for her portrayal). But Audrey Hepburn shines in this film as the fiery-spirited cockney flower girl Eliza Doolittle (her singing was dubbed by Marni Nixon)opposite Rex Harrison's Henry Higgins (the role he originated on Broadway). The two actors are perfect foils for each other as the student and tutor who clash over the social graces that Eliza must learn in order to be a lady. This musical is quite underrated because of Hepburn's performance as opposed to Julie Andrews' in the original production. I think that it's a matter of interpretation; both actresses have their styles and play the character in her own way. This is one of Audrey's finest performance since her performance as Holly Golightly in 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could somehow be better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zoe Yac
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Audrey Hepburn is simply stunning in this movie - as in most. Only drag is that she did not actually sing her songs in the movie. Also, the poor quality of the majority of songs is quite disappointing. The story is just superb, though. But who is to thank for that? Anyways, I give it a 7/10 because of the very solid overall cast, some quite remembering songs - by far the most outstanding of them being "I Could Have Danced All Night" -, the thought out lead characters (but actually only them, since the supporting roles were rather shallow. At least the part of Pickering could be exhausted in a more interesting way, although it is hinted at at the end of the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What flair, my lady!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical adaptation of a tale of love between a book-learned pedagogue and a flower-selling prodigy bonded through phonetics. The movie is a melange of mellifluous songs, male chauvinism and a maiden who undergoes a paradigm shift in her speech and charisma. I love the scene in which people are busy with their daily chores and the frame freezes, then the camera zooms out and another set of people move around and then it freezes and another set of people move around. And all the people in the 3 sets of the frame move around in a haphazard manner. I beg your pardon lovers of literature, I haven't read the play by George Bernard Shaw nor have i heard about it before watching the film. Professor Higgins takes Eliza as a disciple to experiment on after Col. Pickering throws a challenge that he couldn't make a duchess out of a flower-seller. Professor Higgins, an expert in Phonetics, is a celibate and often looks down on women. He provides her luxury and at the same time forces her to try and try till she enunciates the words correctly. After several exhaustive sessions, Higgins makes her perceive what they're trying to do to her and his words do the miracle. She speaks flawlessly and with a rich and refined voice. Higgins takes her to a horse race, a place where Eliza could interact with the blue-blooded. She does well in the beginning but slowly she starts uttering innuendos and senseless idioms that Higgins and Pickering try to cover up with illogical explanations. Things go back to round one when she screams in enjoyment in the language of the slum-dwellers. Higgins gives her rigorous training and his efforts bear fruit in a matter of time. She draws the attention of several people and a princess showers encomiums on her charisma. Higgins is lauded for his efforts by his fellowmen but they fail to understand Eliza's efforts too; all that she had to endure to become a subject of Higgins' achievement. She leaves the house in agony and swears to never return again. Higgins realizes they are in-execrable but takes time to confess it and comes to him after his long-due confession.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mobility with Music ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Oscar for best picture of 1964 went to this musical. It was very hard to understand Audrey Hepburn at the beginning of the film with that cockneyed accent. She came into the role as the picture progressed and she became a lady. This is basically a story of class warfare set to music without the violence of Oscar winner "West Side Story." Rex Harrison won the best actor here and although he gave a good performance as speech professor Henry Higgins, am sure the other nominees were better. He certainly looked down on the gutter snipe Hepburn, but as the picture went by he certainly grew accustomed to her face. After he makes her a lady and she is a success at the ball, Hepburn, as Eliza, is at the crossroad of her life. What shall become of her? Will someone please explain to me why Gladys Cooper was nominated for best supporting actress here? Her part was next to nothing and she added zilch to the picture. Cooper was far more magnificent in her other nominations some 20 years before- "The Song of Bernadette," and "Now, Voyager." She missed a 1958 supporting bid for "Separate Tables." Harrison mouthed the words beautifully to the music of the songs given to him. That was an achievement in itself. The picture proved without doubt that upward social mobility is possible. The film may also be described as a Cinderella like-tale. After all, our girl in rags wound up with a gem as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rags to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dichoi-197-207907
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Fair Lady is an unlikely musical of beloved songs and characters. Romance, refreshing comedy, and unexpected satire weave through this wonderful film that retains a great deal of George Bernard Shaw's "Pygmalion" (1912) which was itself inspired by Ovid's Metamorphosis. Even though it is one of the most loved romances, no one ever gets kissed. No nudity, no sex, not even a declaration of love. The story celebrates not romance but intelligence. The story involves a meeting of two egos outside a lavish London theater: linguist Henry Higgins (Rex Harrison) and flower girl Eliza Doolittle (Audrey Hepburn). Eliza is a common Cockney flower girl who is plucked from the Covent Garden and transformed into a "lady" by Higgins. It is difficult to discuss George Cukor's 1964 film as it actually exists because of the gossip that muddles it greatness. Many viewers would rather discuss the film that was not made, the one that would have starred Julie Andrews who made the role of Eliza her own on the stage. Casting Audrey Hepburn was an insult to a then little-known Andrews because the studio head Jack L. Warner chose Hepburn for her greater box appeal. Furthermore, Hepburn did not sing her own songs but was instead dubbed by the talented Marni Nixon. This dubbing became quite notorious, so much so that although My Fair Lady was nominated for twelve Oscars and won eight, Hepburn was not even nominated for best actress. Ironically, Andrews won the Best Actress Award for "Mary Poppins," while Hepburn was snubbed by the Academy. Let us step back and take another look at the controversy. Indeed, Hepburn did not sing her own songs. However, the dubbing of singing voices was very common at the time, and Nixon herself dubbed other actresses such as Deborah Kerr and Natalie Wood. Even actors who did sing their own songs lip-synced to their own pre-recorded dubs. The fact that Hepburn did not do her own singing only makes her success, which is that she did her own acting. What Hepburn did for the role was to make you care about Eliza and to believe in her transformation. Even if she did not sing her part, Hepburn still delivered a dazzling performance because of her ability to make us believe. My Fair Lady drew its dialogue from Shaw's "Pygmalion," which is more challenging than most other musicals. The dialogue was not only embedded with well-honed wit and satire but required Eliza to transition accents from Cockney to the Queen's English. Hepburn does this with flawless technique and confidence in a performance with palpable passion. The audience is given reasons to care about her character. We can relate to her, feel for what happens to her, and rejoice when things go her way. Throughout the film, Hepburn, who is so tenderly waiflike, brings a poignancy to her scenes that is magical. Not only does My Fair Lady feature an involving story with compelling characters, but there is not a dud to be found on the list of more than a dozen toe-tapping numbers. The best-known song from the film, "I Could Have Danced All Night," is familiar to almost everyone  even though who have not seen the movie. This is a testament to the brilliant marriage of dialogue and lyric in the film as seen in a poor smitten character named Freddy. Many people despise musicals because of the preposterous way characters pause mid-sentence and suddenly burst into song. Freddy avoids these predictable scenes, singing "On the Street Where You Live" with a childlike candor compared with other more emotional characters. Apart from the marvels of its words and music, My Fair Lady is a visual triumph laced with elegance. Cukor made exquisite use of Cecil Beaton who designed the production, the sets, and the costumes. Many extras are dressed in whites, blacks, and greys, creating a backdrop for Higgins in his brown tweed suit and Eliza, who has a touch of red in her dress. The story expresses endless optimism through the d&eacute;cor of Higgins' home, which is packed with the latest mechanical gadgets for teaching people how to speak better. The unusually remote camera stays well back from the action with relatively few close-ups, allowing the audience to see as much of the luxurious sets as possible. The audience can unmistakably see that this is a movie into which a world of care and effort was invested. What distinguished My Fair Lady above all is that it actually says something meaningful. In a film of quick words, unforgettable music, and outstanding images, it analyzes the socialist attack on the British class system. By dramatizing how superiority and success was inherited, not earned, through Eliza's escape from the lower class system, My Fair Lady becomes a great entertainment as well as a great influence. The impact it had on the creation of feminism and class- consciousness through the mid-1900s is still not sufficiently appreciated. It was a revolutionary message in England at the time, and it is still thought-provoking. Not only do people not make movies like this anymore  they simply cannot. The movie industry seems to no longer be interested in musicals about adults, much less adults with ideas. Few film genres are as magical as musicals, and few musicals are as intelligent and joyous as My Fair Lady. It is both notable and marvelous that the film stays so true to the original material and does not cave in to a schmaltzy rewritten happy ending. It remains an open question to the audience whether Eliza stays to listen to what he says next. If these two are ever to fall in love, it will be with their heads, instead of their hearts. This movie is a classic not because a group of film experts have labeled it as such, but because it has been, and always will be, a pure joy to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey Hepburn is, and always will be, Eliza Doolittle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I have the highest respect for Julie Andrews, I think the producers made the right choice in Audrey Hepburn. Andrews has the clear advantage of an extraordinarily fine voice, so she could have done her own singing, as she did in the London cast recording. But I have trouble seeing Andrews as the ideal for the Eliza Doolittle character over the full scope of the movie. What My Fair Lady is about is the story of Pygmalion, the play by George Bernard Shaw, but also the earlier Greek legend of the sculptor who created the image of his perfect woman out of stone, so beautiful that she came alive. So the end result must be a very high ideal of perfection, grace and beauty. Now Julie Andrews is no slouch in those departments, but she lacks the extraordinary other-worldliness that Audrey Hepburn was renown for. When Hepburn played a real princess in her first starring role in Roman Holiday, she was absolutely convincing. She made the transformation from caterpillar to butterfly in Sabrina. So when Eliza goes to the royal ball and everyone thinks the former flower girl is a princess going incognito, it is heartbreakingly believable. Eliza truly has been transformed into the ideal of perfection and beauty. As much as I admire Andrews, I can't quite imagine her being as convincing in that scene. Some say Andrews earned the part for her portrayal of the role on stage, and that she got a raw deal. If that had been the end of her career, I would be inclined to agree. But look at the wonderful, dream roles she has had since, particularly the immortal Sound of Music, in which she was perfectly cast. I think being miscast can be as bad or worse than no role at all. While Andrews certainly would not have been a disaster, I think she might have been a slight disappointment. There is a big difference between a portrayal on stage, in which the audience is more willing to suspend disbelief, and on film, where every pore is five feet tall. That is probably why the wonderful, but aging, Mary Martin didn't get many film roles. Andrews might not have been as convincing an Eliza on film as she was on stage. I see some posters calling My Fair Lady an American production. Just a reminder: Hepburn was not American. She was British-Dutch-Belgian. And while she came from a rich family, she grew up in starvation poverty while in Holland during World War II, which may have given her the depth to play such a range of roles, from the flower girl to princesses. I'm not saying Hepburn's portrayal of Eliza is perfect. I grew up with Hepburn as Eliza, and she inhabits the role, in my mind. But as an adult, with the closer examination of being able to watch the DVD version an infinite number of times, I do see some weaknesses in her portrayal. I doubt most people would see these in the first or second viewing. A more troubling question is whether Hepburn should have done her own singing. She had a good singing voice, and could have done a good job. You can hear her singing Moon River in Breakfast at Tiffany's. The ultimate reason they dubbed her may have been Rex Harrison and Stanley Holloway. They are trying to make a musical, and most of the stars can't actually sing. To have a weak singing performance from Hepburn would have been too much. Marni Nixon could be counted on for a skilled voice match. (BTW, Nixon finally appears on screen in Sound of Music, as a nun commenting on Maria -- Andrews.) Problem solved. As to shortening some numbers, hey, this is a musical! The music is what it's about. I've seen too many musicals where they feel compelled to cut and cut to speed things up, shorten the movie. In South Pacific, the movie version cuts the "Wash That Man Right Out of my Hair" number down to one verse, and they really wrecked it. Brigadoon cut everything down to the minimum, and took all the wind out of the sails. With a musical, if you want to tell a story and have lots of music, you have got to make the film longer than the average non-musical; it's a big mistake to cut out parts of the story, or truncate the musical numbers. And as to the sets, the lesson I have derived from looking at many musicals is that you do not want a set that is too realistic. A musical is by nature a fantasy, because real people don't go breaking into song and dance in daily life. You need sets that are beautiful, but not entirely realistic. The 1962 remake of State Fair by Mel Ferrer, Hepburn's husband, was a disaster, and one reason was it was filmed very realistically. Guys and Dolls is perhaps the best example of non- realism, because the story was a fable, and the sets were almost like giant illustrations from a children's book. On the other hand, the movie version should not, generally, look too much like a Broadway play. Now, let's see, what would the My Fair Lady look like if the sets were a brutally realistic depiction of Edwardian London? We're talking real slums, with real horse manure. Save the realism for non-musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll make a queen of that barbarous wretch"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicsoncall
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the pros and cons of this film, and as an outsider looking in, my advantage perhaps is that I don't know a whole lot about George Bernard Shaw, Pygmalion, Broadway musicals and Audrey Hepburn's dubbed voice as a singing Eliza Doolittle. So coming in cold, and not particularly a fan of movie musicals, I'd have to say this was watchable enough, though at almost three hours, I WAS getting antsy after the two hour mark. I realize that fans and critics will bring their own prejudices to bear in regard to the casting and staging of the story, but that aside, and with no particular horse in the race, I'd have to say that this was entertaining enough for the kind of picture I generally don't go out of the way for. My mission is to watch and review each of the movies that appeared on the American Film Institute's original 1997 list of Best One Hundred Movies of All Time. So with a clinical approach and an open mind, I'm not predisposed one way or the other to like or dislike a picture I would have passed on otherwise. So now I've seen it, it passes muster as an entertaining film, and my movie viewing experience is that much more well rounded. With a little bit of luck, you might enjoy it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply delightful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't necessarily have to be into musical to be taken in by this charming film. All I can say is that I wish there would be more musical movies like this. It's a movie with such a pleasant and joyful atmosphere to it, even though the story of course also takes some dramatic turns. But this is what musicals should all be about; simply have a good time watching it and let it be a feast for your eyes and ears. The entire movie does feel and look very stagy but in this case that really isn't a complaint. It simply suits the movie well and makes it part of the reason why this is such perfect light entertainment to watch. Besides, it is a good looking movie as well, with all of its grand sets and nice costume design. But what is a musical without any good music. And luckily this movie does really has some good and pleasant songs in it, performed nicely by its cast, though not always its original cast. Audrey Hepburn still got dubbed for instance, which was also really apparent in some of the songs. Rex Harrison on the other hand does all of the singing himself and his style of singing and acting fits the character and songs very well. Yes, all of the acting in general is very impressive in this movie as well. I had seen Rex Harrison in a couple of movies before but he never impressed me as much as he did with his role in this movie. Also Audrey Hepburn surprised me. I have always loved her but I never realized how incredible versatile as an actress she actually was until I saw her in this movie. She basically plays two different characters in this. She is both very convincing as the foul mounted girl from the streets and as the sophisticated, uppercases lady. You probably won't even recognize her at first, until she slowly starts to transform into the lovely beautiful young woman, we also all remember Audrey Hepburn as. The story and characters within this movie are definitely not all without its flaws but in this case all the story wanted was to deliver a simple, light and enjoyable movie for everybody of all ages, sexes and ethnicities to enjoy. And I think they most definitely did not fail with this. At least the Academy Awards also agree with me, since the movie received 8 Oscar's, including the most important ones for best director and best picture of the year. It also eventually would turn out to be the only Oscar legendary director George Cukor received. Simply a movie to enjoy. 9/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit song after hit song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every song in this musical is a hit. Rex Harrison is at his Rex Harrisoniest, and Audrey Hepburn reveals layer after layer of Eliza Doolittle. The costumes are brilliant, particularly in the artfully- staged, hilarious scene at the racetrack. Stanley Holloway, who played Eliza's ne'er-do-well father on Broadway before bringing the role to the screen, steals his scenes. This movie earned every bit of its Best Picture Oscar and remains one of the best movie musicals of all time. Though the movie deals with the touchy subjects of class and gender and does not pull its punches, it is not mean-spirited and does not run too much afoul of modern sensibilities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic. or little more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I confess- Audrey Hepburn is one of my favorite actresses. so, it is difficult to not love this film. smart, charming, almost touching, full of great performances, it is adorable more than a classic. songs, adaptation, costumes - all is perfect. and each new meeting is a pure delight. sure, hypothesis of Julie Andrews as Eliza is present. but not for long time because Hepburn does a splendid work and the levels of metamorphose of poor young girl in a brilliant lady is credible and fascinating. sure, the axis remains Rex Harrison and this fact is obvious. but , like in case of each good movie, the flavor after its end is essential. in this case it is not only entertainment but drops of special beauty who covers small imperfections and gives a very nice feeling of life joy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alyssa Black (Aly200)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'My Fair Lady' originated on Broadway in 1957 and was a huge successful when released. This film adaption was released in 1964 without the original star in the female lead (Julie Andrews was to star in 'Mary Poppins' and that year won the Best Actress Oscar for her portrayal). But Audrey Hepburn shines in this film as the fiery-spirited cockney flower girl Eliza Doolittle (her singing was dubbed by Marni Nixon)opposite Rex Harrison's Henry Higgins (the role he originated on Broadway). The two actors are perfect foils for each other as the student and tutor who clash over the social graces that Eliza must learn in order to be a lady. This musical is quite underrated because of Hepburn's performance as opposed to Julie Andrews' in the original production. I think that it's a matter of interpretation; both actresses have their styles and play the character in her own way. This is one of Audrey's finest performance since her performance as Holly Golightly in 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could somehow be better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zoe Yac
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Audrey Hepburn is simply stunning in this movie - as in most. Only drag is that she did not actually sing her songs in the movie. Also, the poor quality of the majority of songs is quite disappointing. The story is just superb, though. But who is to thank for that? Anyways, I give it a 7/10 because of the very solid overall cast, some quite remembering songs - by far the most outstanding of them being "I Could Have Danced All Night" -, the thought out lead characters (but actually only them, since the supporting roles were rather shallow. At least the part of Pickering could be exhausted in a more interesting way, although it is hinted at at the end of the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What flair, my lady!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical adaptation of a tale of love between a book-learned pedagogue and a flower-selling prodigy bonded through phonetics. The movie is a melange of mellifluous songs, male chauvinism and a maiden who undergoes a paradigm shift in her speech and charisma. I love the scene in which people are busy with their daily chores and the frame freezes, then the camera zooms out and another set of people move around and then it freezes and another set of people move around. And all the people in the 3 sets of the frame move around in a haphazard manner. I beg your pardon lovers of literature, I haven't read the play by George Bernard Shaw nor have i heard about it before watching the film. Professor Higgins takes Eliza as a disciple to experiment on after Col. Pickering throws a challenge that he couldn't make a duchess out of a flower-seller. Professor Higgins, an expert in Phonetics, is a celibate and often looks down on women. He provides her luxury and at the same time forces her to try and try till she enunciates the words correctly. After several exhaustive sessions, Higgins makes her perceive what they're trying to do to her and his words do the miracle. She speaks flawlessly and with a rich and refined voice. Higgins takes her to a horse race, a place where Eliza could interact with the blue-blooded. She does well in the beginning but slowly she starts uttering innuendos and senseless idioms that Higgins and Pickering try to cover up with illogical explanations. Things go back to round one when she screams in enjoyment in the language of the slum-dwellers. Higgins gives her rigorous training and his efforts bear fruit in a matter of time. She draws the attention of several people and a princess showers encomiums on her charisma. Higgins is lauded for his efforts by his fellowmen but they fail to understand Eliza's efforts too; all that she had to endure to become a subject of Higgins' achievement. She leaves the house in agony and swears to never return again. Higgins realizes they are in-execrable but takes time to confess it and comes to him after his long-due confession.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mobility with Music ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Oscar for best picture of 1964 went to this musical. It was very hard to understand Audrey Hepburn at the beginning of the film with that cockneyed accent. She came into the role as the picture progressed and she became a lady. This is basically a story of class warfare set to music without the violence of Oscar winner "West Side Story." Rex Harrison won the best actor here and although he gave a good performance as speech professor Henry Higgins, am sure the other nominees were better. He certainly looked down on the gutter snipe Hepburn, but as the picture went by he certainly grew accustomed to her face. After he makes her a lady and she is a success at the ball, Hepburn, as Eliza, is at the crossroad of her life. What shall become of her? Will someone please explain to me why Gladys Cooper was nominated for best supporting actress here? Her part was next to nothing and she added zilch to the picture. Cooper was far more magnificent in her other nominations some 20 years before- "The Song of Bernadette," and "Now, Voyager." She missed a 1958 supporting bid for "Separate Tables." Harrison mouthed the words beautifully to the music of the songs given to him. That was an achievement in itself. The picture proved without doubt that upward social mobility is possible. The film may also be described as a Cinderella like-tale. After all, our girl in rags wound up with a gem as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rags to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dichoi-197-207907
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Fair Lady is an unlikely musical of beloved songs and characters. Romance, refreshing comedy, and unexpected satire weave through this wonderful film that retains a great deal of George Bernard Shaw's "Pygmalion" (1912) which was itself inspired by Ovid's Metamorphosis. Even though it is one of the most loved romances, no one ever gets kissed. No nudity, no sex, not even a declaration of love. The story celebrates not romance but intelligence. The story involves a meeting of two egos outside a lavish London theater: linguist Henry Higgins (Rex Harrison) and flower girl Eliza Doolittle (Audrey Hepburn). Eliza is a common Cockney flower girl who is plucked from the Covent Garden and transformed into a "lady" by Higgins. It is difficult to discuss George Cukor's 1964 film as it actually exists because of the gossip that muddles it greatness. Many viewers would rather discuss the film that was not made, the one that would have starred Julie Andrews who made the role of Eliza her own on the stage. Casting Audrey Hepburn was an insult to a then little-known Andrews because the studio head Jack L. Warner chose Hepburn for her greater box appeal. Furthermore, Hepburn did not sing her own songs but was instead dubbed by the talented Marni Nixon. This dubbing became quite notorious, so much so that although My Fair Lady was nominated for twelve Oscars and won eight, Hepburn was not even nominated for best actress. Ironically, Andrews won the Best Actress Award for "Mary Poppins," while Hepburn was snubbed by the Academy. Let us step back and take another look at the controversy. Indeed, Hepburn did not sing her own songs. However, the dubbing of singing voices was very common at the time, and Nixon herself dubbed other actresses such as Deborah Kerr and Natalie Wood. Even actors who did sing their own songs lip-synced to their own pre-recorded dubs. The fact that Hepburn did not do her own singing only makes her success, which is that she did her own acting. What Hepburn did for the role was to make you care about Eliza and to believe in her transformation. Even if she did not sing her part, Hepburn still delivered a dazzling performance because of her ability to make us believe. My Fair Lady drew its dialogue from Shaw's "Pygmalion," which is more challenging than most other musicals. The dialogue was not only embedded with well-honed wit and satire but required Eliza to transition accents from Cockney to the Queen's English. Hepburn does this with flawless technique and confidence in a performance with palpable passion. The audience is given reasons to care about her character. We can relate to her, feel for what happens to her, and rejoice when things go her way. Throughout the film, Hepburn, who is so tenderly waiflike, brings a poignancy to her scenes that is magical. Not only does My Fair Lady feature an involving story with compelling characters, but there is not a dud to be found on the list of more than a dozen toe-tapping numbers. The best-known song from the film, "I Could Have Danced All Night," is familiar to almost everyone  even though who have not seen the movie. This is a testament to the brilliant marriage of dialogue and lyric in the film as seen in a poor smitten character named Freddy. Many people despise musicals because of the preposterous way characters pause mid-sentence and suddenly burst into song. Freddy avoids these predictable scenes, singing "On the Street Where You Live" with a childlike candor compared with other more emotional characters. Apart from the marvels of its words and music, My Fair Lady is a visual triumph laced with elegance. Cukor made exquisite use of Cecil Beaton who designed the production, the sets, and the costumes. Many extras are dressed in whites, blacks, and greys, creating a backdrop for Higgins in his brown tweed suit and Eliza, who has a touch of red in her dress. The story expresses endless optimism through the d&eacute;cor of Higgins' home, which is packed with the latest mechanical gadgets for teaching people how to speak better. The unusually remote camera stays well back from the action with relatively few close-ups, allowing the audience to see as much of the luxurious sets as possible. The audience can unmistakably see that this is a movie into which a world of care and effort was invested. What distinguished My Fair Lady above all is that it actually says something meaningful. In a film of quick words, unforgettable music, and outstanding images, it analyzes the socialist attack on the British class system. By dramatizing how superiority and success was inherited, not earned, through Eliza's escape from the lower class system, My Fair Lady becomes a great entertainment as well as a great influence. The impact it had on the creation of feminism and class- consciousness through the mid-1900s is still not sufficiently appreciated. It was a revolutionary message in England at the time, and it is still thought-provoking. Not only do people not make movies like this anymore  they simply cannot. The movie industry seems to no longer be interested in musicals about adults, much less adults with ideas. Few film genres are as magical as musicals, and few musicals are as intelligent and joyous as My Fair Lady. It is both notable and marvelous that the film stays so true to the original material and does not cave in to a schmaltzy rewritten happy ending. It remains an open question to the audience whether Eliza stays to listen to what he says next. If these two are ever to fall in love, it will be with their heads, instead of their hearts. This movie is a classic not because a group of film experts have labeled it as such, but because it has been, and always will be, a pure joy to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey Hepburn is, and always will be, Eliza Doolittle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I have the highest respect for Julie Andrews, I think the producers made the right choice in Audrey Hepburn. Andrews has the clear advantage of an extraordinarily fine voice, so she could have done her own singing, as she did in the London cast recording. But I have trouble seeing Andrews as the ideal for the Eliza Doolittle character over the full scope of the movie. What My Fair Lady is about is the story of Pygmalion, the play by George Bernard Shaw, but also the earlier Greek legend of the sculptor who created the image of his perfect woman out of stone, so beautiful that she came alive. So the end result must be a very high ideal of perfection, grace and beauty. Now Julie Andrews is no slouch in those departments, but she lacks the extraordinary other-worldliness that Audrey Hepburn was renown for. When Hepburn played a real princess in her first starring role in Roman Holiday, she was absolutely convincing. She made the transformation from caterpillar to butterfly in Sabrina. So when Eliza goes to the royal ball and everyone thinks the former flower girl is a princess going incognito, it is heartbreakingly believable. Eliza truly has been transformed into the ideal of perfection and beauty. As much as I admire Andrews, I can't quite imagine her being as convincing in that scene. Some say Andrews earned the part for her portrayal of the role on stage, and that she got a raw deal. If that had been the end of her career, I would be inclined to agree. But look at the wonderful, dream roles she has had since, particularly the immortal Sound of Music, in which she was perfectly cast. I think being miscast can be as bad or worse than no role at all. While Andrews certainly would not have been a disaster, I think she might have been a slight disappointment. There is a big difference between a portrayal on stage, in which the audience is more willing to suspend disbelief, and on film, where every pore is five feet tall. That is probably why the wonderful, but aging, Mary Martin didn't get many film roles. Andrews might not have been as convincing an Eliza on film as she was on stage. I see some posters calling My Fair Lady an American production. Just a reminder: Hepburn was not American. She was British-Dutch-Belgian. And while she came from a rich family, she grew up in starvation poverty while in Holland during World War II, which may have given her the depth to play such a range of roles, from the flower girl to princesses. I'm not saying Hepburn's portrayal of Eliza is perfect. I grew up with Hepburn as Eliza, and she inhabits the role, in my mind. But as an adult, with the closer examination of being able to watch the DVD version an infinite number of times, I do see some weaknesses in her portrayal. I doubt most people would see these in the first or second viewing. A more troubling question is whether Hepburn should have done her own singing. She had a good singing voice, and could have done a good job. You can hear her singing Moon River in Breakfast at Tiffany's. The ultimate reason they dubbed her may have been Rex Harrison and Stanley Holloway. They are trying to make a musical, and most of the stars can't actually sing. To have a weak singing performance from Hepburn would have been too much. Marni Nixon could be counted on for a skilled voice match. (BTW, Nixon finally appears on screen in Sound of Music, as a nun commenting on Maria -- Andrews.) Problem solved. As to shortening some numbers, hey, this is a musical! The music is what it's about. I've seen too many musicals where they feel compelled to cut and cut to speed things up, shorten the movie. In South Pacific, the movie version cuts the "Wash That Man Right Out of my Hair" number down to one verse, and they really wrecked it. Brigadoon cut everything down to the minimum, and took all the wind out of the sails. With a musical, if you want to tell a story and have lots of music, you have got to make the film longer than the average non-musical; it's a big mistake to cut out parts of the story, or truncate the musical numbers. And as to the sets, the lesson I have derived from looking at many musicals is that you do not want a set that is too realistic. A musical is by nature a fantasy, because real people don't go breaking into song and dance in daily life. You need sets that are beautiful, but not entirely realistic. The 1962 remake of State Fair by Mel Ferrer, Hepburn's husband, was a disaster, and one reason was it was filmed very realistically. Guys and Dolls is perhaps the best example of non- realism, because the story was a fable, and the sets were almost like giant illustrations from a children's book. On the other hand, the movie version should not, generally, look too much like a Broadway play. Now, let's see, what would the My Fair Lady look like if the sets were a brutally realistic depiction of Edwardian London? We're talking real slums, with real horse manure. Save the realism for non-musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll make a queen of that barbarous wretch"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicsoncall
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the pros and cons of this film, and as an outsider looking in, my advantage perhaps is that I don't know a whole lot about George Bernard Shaw, Pygmalion, Broadway musicals and Audrey Hepburn's dubbed voice as a singing Eliza Doolittle. So coming in cold, and not particularly a fan of movie musicals, I'd have to say this was watchable enough, though at almost three hours, I WAS getting antsy after the two hour mark. I realize that fans and critics will bring their own prejudices to bear in regard to the casting and staging of the story, but that aside, and with no particular horse in the race, I'd have to say that this was entertaining enough for the kind of picture I generally don't go out of the way for. My mission is to watch and review each of the movies that appeared on the American Film Institute's original 1997 list of Best One Hundred Movies of All Time. So with a clinical approach and an open mind, I'm not predisposed one way or the other to like or dislike a picture I would have passed on otherwise. So now I've seen it, it passes muster as an entertaining film, and my movie viewing experience is that much more well rounded. With a little bit of luck, you might enjoy it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply delightful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't necessarily have to be into musical to be taken in by this charming film. All I can say is that I wish there would be more musical movies like this. It's a movie with such a pleasant and joyful atmosphere to it, even though the story of course also takes some dramatic turns. But this is what musicals should all be about; simply have a good time watching it and let it be a feast for your eyes and ears. The entire movie does feel and look very stagy but in this case that really isn't a complaint. It simply suits the movie well and makes it part of the reason why this is such perfect light entertainment to watch. Besides, it is a good looking movie as well, with all of its grand sets and nice costume design. But what is a musical without any good music. And luckily this movie does really has some good and pleasant songs in it, performed nicely by its cast, though not always its original cast. Audrey Hepburn still got dubbed for instance, which was also really apparent in some of the songs. Rex Harrison on the other hand does all of the singing himself and his style of singing and acting fits the character and songs very well. Yes, all of the acting in general is very impressive in this movie as well. I had seen Rex Harrison in a couple of movies before but he never impressed me as much as he did with his role in this movie. Also Audrey Hepburn surprised me. I have always loved her but I never realized how incredible versatile as an actress she actually was until I saw her in this movie. She basically plays two different characters in this. She is both very convincing as the foul mounted girl from the streets and as the sophisticated, uppercases lady. You probably won't even recognize her at first, until she slowly starts to transform into the lovely beautiful young woman, we also all remember Audrey Hepburn as. The story and characters within this movie are definitely not all without its flaws but in this case all the story wanted was to deliver a simple, light and enjoyable movie for everybody of all ages, sexes and ethnicities to enjoy. And I think they most definitely did not fail with this. At least the Academy Awards also agree with me, since the movie received 8 Oscar's, including the most important ones for best director and best picture of the year. It also eventually would turn out to be the only Oscar legendary director George Cukor received. Simply a movie to enjoy. 9/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit song after hit song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every song in this musical is a hit. Rex Harrison is at his Rex Harrisoniest, and Audrey Hepburn reveals layer after layer of Eliza Doolittle. The costumes are brilliant, particularly in the artfully- staged, hilarious scene at the racetrack. Stanley Holloway, who played Eliza's ne'er-do-well father on Broadway before bringing the role to the screen, steals his scenes. This movie earned every bit of its Best Picture Oscar and remains one of the best movie musicals of all time. Though the movie deals with the touchy subjects of class and gender and does not pull its punches, it is not mean-spirited and does not run too much afoul of modern sensibilities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic. or little more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I confess- Audrey Hepburn is one of my favorite actresses. so, it is difficult to not love this film. smart, charming, almost touching, full of great performances, it is adorable more than a classic. songs, adaptation, costumes - all is perfect. and each new meeting is a pure delight. sure, hypothesis of Julie Andrews as Eliza is present. but not for long time because Hepburn does a splendid work and the levels of metamorphose of poor young girl in a brilliant lady is credible and fascinating. sure, the axis remains Rex Harrison and this fact is obvious. but , like in case of each good movie, the flavor after its end is essential. in this case it is not only entertainment but drops of special beauty who covers small imperfections and gives a very nice feeling of life joy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alyssa Black (Aly200)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'My Fair Lady' originated on Broadway in 1957 and was a huge successful when released. This film adaption was released in 1964 without the original star in the female lead (Julie Andrews was to star in 'Mary Poppins' and that year won the Best Actress Oscar for her portrayal). But Audrey Hepburn shines in this film as the fiery-spirited cockney flower girl Eliza Doolittle (her singing was dubbed by Marni Nixon)opposite Rex Harrison's Henry Higgins (the role he originated on Broadway). The two actors are perfect foils for each other as the student and tutor who clash over the social graces that Eliza must learn in order to be a lady. This musical is quite underrated because of Hepburn's performance as opposed to Julie Andrews' in the original production. I think that it's a matter of interpretation; both actresses have their styles and play the character in her own way. This is one of Audrey's finest performance since her performance as Holly Golightly in 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could somehow be better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zoe Yac
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Audrey Hepburn is simply stunning in this movie - as in most. Only drag is that she did not actually sing her songs in the movie. Also, the poor quality of the majority of songs is quite disappointing. The story is just superb, though. But who is to thank for that? Anyways, I give it a 7/10 because of the very solid overall cast, some quite remembering songs - by far the most outstanding of them being "I Could Have Danced All Night" -, the thought out lead characters (but actually only them, since the supporting roles were rather shallow. At least the part of Pickering could be exhausted in a more interesting way, although it is hinted at at the end of the movie).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What flair, my lady!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical adaptation of a tale of love between a book-learned pedagogue and a flower-selling prodigy bonded through phonetics. The movie is a melange of mellifluous songs, male chauvinism and a maiden who undergoes a paradigm shift in her speech and charisma. I love the scene in which people are busy with their daily chores and the frame freezes, then the camera zooms out and another set of people move around and then it freezes and another set of people move around. And all the people in the 3 sets of the frame move around in a haphazard manner. I beg your pardon lovers of literature, I haven't read the play by George Bernard Shaw nor have i heard about it before watching the film. Professor Higgins takes Eliza as a disciple to experiment on after Col. Pickering throws a challenge that he couldn't make a duchess out of a flower-seller. Professor Higgins, an expert in Phonetics, is a celibate and often looks down on women. He provides her luxury and at the same time forces her to try and try till she enunciates the words correctly. After several exhaustive sessions, Higgins makes her perceive what they're trying to do to her and his words do the miracle. She speaks flawlessly and with a rich and refined voice. Higgins takes her to a horse race, a place where Eliza could interact with the blue-blooded. She does well in the beginning but slowly she starts uttering innuendos and senseless idioms that Higgins and Pickering try to cover up with illogical explanations. Things go back to round one when she screams in enjoyment in the language of the slum-dwellers. Higgins gives her rigorous training and his efforts bear fruit in a matter of time. She draws the attention of several people and a princess showers encomiums on her charisma. Higgins is lauded for his efforts by his fellowmen but they fail to understand Eliza's efforts too; all that she had to endure to become a subject of Higgins' achievement. She leaves the house in agony and swears to never return again. Higgins realizes they are in-execrable but takes time to confess it and comes to him after his long-due confession.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mobility with Music ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Oscar for best picture of 1964 went to this musical. It was very hard to understand Audrey Hepburn at the beginning of the film with that cockneyed accent. She came into the role as the picture progressed and she became a lady. This is basically a story of class warfare set to music without the violence of Oscar winner "West Side Story." Rex Harrison won the best actor here and although he gave a good performance as speech professor Henry Higgins, am sure the other nominees were better. He certainly looked down on the gutter snipe Hepburn, but as the picture went by he certainly grew accustomed to her face. After he makes her a lady and she is a success at the ball, Hepburn, as Eliza, is at the crossroad of her life. What shall become of her? Will someone please explain to me why Gladys Cooper was nominated for best supporting actress here? Her part was next to nothing and she added zilch to the picture. Cooper was far more magnificent in her other nominations some 20 years before- "The Song of Bernadette," and "Now, Voyager." She missed a 1958 supporting bid for "Separate Tables." Harrison mouthed the words beautifully to the music of the songs given to him. That was an achievement in itself. The picture proved without doubt that upward social mobility is possible. The film may also be described as a Cinderella like-tale. After all, our girl in rags wound up with a gem as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Rags to Riches
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dichoi-197-207907
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Fair Lady is an unlikely musical of beloved songs and characters. Romance, refreshing comedy, and unexpected satire weave through this wonderful film that retains a great deal of George Bernard Shaw's "Pygmalion" (1912) which was itself inspired by Ovid's Metamorphosis. Even though it is one of the most loved romances, no one ever gets kissed. No nudity, no sex, not even a declaration of love. The story celebrates not romance but intelligence. The story involves a meeting of two egos outside a lavish London theater: linguist Henry Higgins (Rex Harrison) and flower girl Eliza Doolittle (Audrey Hepburn). Eliza is a common Cockney flower girl who is plucked from the Covent Garden and transformed into a "lady" by Higgins. It is difficult to discuss George Cukor's 1964 film as it actually exists because of the gossip that muddles it greatness. Many viewers would rather discuss the film that was not made, the one that would have starred Julie Andrews who made the role of Eliza her own on the stage. Casting Audrey Hepburn was an insult to a then little-known Andrews because the studio head Jack L. Warner chose Hepburn for her greater box appeal. Furthermore, Hepburn did not sing her own songs but was instead dubbed by the talented Marni Nixon. This dubbing became quite notorious, so much so that although My Fair Lady was nominated for twelve Oscars and won eight, Hepburn was not even nominated for best actress. Ironically, Andrews won the Best Actress Award for "Mary Poppins," while Hepburn was snubbed by the Academy. Let us step back and take another look at the controversy. Indeed, Hepburn did not sing her own songs. However, the dubbing of singing voices was very common at the time, and Nixon herself dubbed other actresses such as Deborah Kerr and Natalie Wood. Even actors who did sing their own songs lip-synced to their own pre-recorded dubs. The fact that Hepburn did not do her own singing only makes her success, which is that she did her own acting. What Hepburn did for the role was to make you care about Eliza and to believe in her transformation. Even if she did not sing her part, Hepburn still delivered a dazzling performance because of her ability to make us believe. My Fair Lady drew its dialogue from Shaw's "Pygmalion," which is more challenging than most other musicals. The dialogue was not only embedded with well-honed wit and satire but required Eliza to transition accents from Cockney to the Queen's English. Hepburn does this with flawless technique and confidence in a performance with palpable passion. The audience is given reasons to care about her character. We can relate to her, feel for what happens to her, and rejoice when things go her way. Throughout the film, Hepburn, who is so tenderly waiflike, brings a poignancy to her scenes that is magical. Not only does My Fair Lady feature an involving story with compelling characters, but there is not a dud to be found on the list of more than a dozen toe-tapping numbers. The best-known song from the film, "I Could Have Danced All Night," is familiar to almost everyone  even though who have not seen the movie. This is a testament to the brilliant marriage of dialogue and lyric in the film as seen in a poor smitten character named Freddy. Many people despise musicals because of the preposterous way characters pause mid-sentence and suddenly burst into song. Freddy avoids these predictable scenes, singing "On the Street Where You Live" with a childlike candor compared with other more emotional characters. Apart from the marvels of its words and music, My Fair Lady is a visual triumph laced with elegance. Cukor made exquisite use of Cecil Beaton who designed the production, the sets, and the costumes. Many extras are dressed in whites, blacks, and greys, creating a backdrop for Higgins in his brown tweed suit and Eliza, who has a touch of red in her dress. The story expresses endless optimism through the d&eacute;cor of Higgins' home, which is packed with the latest mechanical gadgets for teaching people how to speak better. The unusually remote camera stays well back from the action with relatively few close-ups, allowing the audience to see as much of the luxurious sets as possible. The audience can unmistakably see that this is a movie into which a world of care and effort was invested. What distinguished My Fair Lady above all is that it actually says something meaningful. In a film of quick words, unforgettable music, and outstanding images, it analyzes the socialist attack on the British class system. By dramatizing how superiority and success was inherited, not earned, through Eliza's escape from the lower class system, My Fair Lady becomes a great entertainment as well as a great influence. The impact it had on the creation of feminism and class- consciousness through the mid-1900s is still not sufficiently appreciated. It was a revolutionary message in England at the time, and it is still thought-provoking. Not only do people not make movies like this anymore  they simply cannot. The movie industry seems to no longer be interested in musicals about adults, much less adults with ideas. Few film genres are as magical as musicals, and few musicals are as intelligent and joyous as My Fair Lady. It is both notable and marvelous that the film stays so true to the original material and does not cave in to a schmaltzy rewritten happy ending. It remains an open question to the audience whether Eliza stays to listen to what he says next. If these two are ever to fall in love, it will be with their heads, instead of their hearts. This movie is a classic not because a group of film experts have labeled it as such, but because it has been, and always will be, a pure joy to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey Hepburn is, and always will be, Eliza Doolittle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I have the highest respect for Julie Andrews, I think the producers made the right choice in Audrey Hepburn. Andrews has the clear advantage of an extraordinarily fine voice, so she could have done her own singing, as she did in the London cast recording. But I have trouble seeing Andrews as the ideal for the Eliza Doolittle character over the full scope of the movie. What My Fair Lady is about is the story of Pygmalion, the play by George Bernard Shaw, but also the earlier Greek legend of the sculptor who created the image of his perfect woman out of stone, so beautiful that she came alive. So the end result must be a very high ideal of perfection, grace and beauty. Now Julie Andrews is no slouch in those departments, but she lacks the extraordinary other-worldliness that Audrey Hepburn was renown for. When Hepburn played a real princess in her first starring role in Roman Holiday, she was absolutely convincing. She made the transformation from caterpillar to butterfly in Sabrina. So when Eliza goes to the royal ball and everyone thinks the former flower girl is a princess going incognito, it is heartbreakingly believable. Eliza truly has been transformed into the ideal of perfection and beauty. As much as I admire Andrews, I can't quite imagine her being as convincing in that scene. Some say Andrews earned the part for her portrayal of the role on stage, and that she got a raw deal. If that had been the end of her career, I would be inclined to agree. But look at the wonderful, dream roles she has had since, particularly the immortal Sound of Music, in which she was perfectly cast. I think being miscast can be as bad or worse than no role at all. While Andrews certainly would not have been a disaster, I think she might have been a slight disappointment. There is a big difference between a portrayal on stage, in which the audience is more willing to suspend disbelief, and on film, where every pore is five feet tall. That is probably why the wonderful, but aging, Mary Martin didn't get many film roles. Andrews might not have been as convincing an Eliza on film as she was on stage. I see some posters calling My Fair Lady an American production. Just a reminder: Hepburn was not American. She was British-Dutch-Belgian. And while she came from a rich family, she grew up in starvation poverty while in Holland during World War II, which may have given her the depth to play such a range of roles, from the flower girl to princesses. I'm not saying Hepburn's portrayal of Eliza is perfect. I grew up with Hepburn as Eliza, and she inhabits the role, in my mind. But as an adult, with the closer examination of being able to watch the DVD version an infinite number of times, I do see some weaknesses in her portrayal. I doubt most people would see these in the first or second viewing. A more troubling question is whether Hepburn should have done her own singing. She had a good singing voice, and could have done a good job. You can hear her singing Moon River in Breakfast at Tiffany's. The ultimate reason they dubbed her may have been Rex Harrison and Stanley Holloway. They are trying to make a musical, and most of the stars can't actually sing. To have a weak singing performance from Hepburn would have been too much. Marni Nixon could be counted on for a skilled voice match. (BTW, Nixon finally appears on screen in Sound of Music, as a nun commenting on Maria -- Andrews.) Problem solved. As to shortening some numbers, hey, this is a musical! The music is what it's about. I've seen too many musicals where they feel compelled to cut and cut to speed things up, shorten the movie. In South Pacific, the movie version cuts the "Wash That Man Right Out of my Hair" number down to one verse, and they really wrecked it. Brigadoon cut everything down to the minimum, and took all the wind out of the sails. With a musical, if you want to tell a story and have lots of music, you have got to make the film longer than the average non-musical; it's a big mistake to cut out parts of the story, or truncate the musical numbers. And as to the sets, the lesson I have derived from looking at many musicals is that you do not want a set that is too realistic. A musical is by nature a fantasy, because real people don't go breaking into song and dance in daily life. You need sets that are beautiful, but not entirely realistic. The 1962 remake of State Fair by Mel Ferrer, Hepburn's husband, was a disaster, and one reason was it was filmed very realistically. Guys and Dolls is perhaps the best example of non- realism, because the story was a fable, and the sets were almost like giant illustrations from a children's book. On the other hand, the movie version should not, generally, look too much like a Broadway play. Now, let's see, what would the My Fair Lady look like if the sets were a brutally realistic depiction of Edwardian London? We're talking real slums, with real horse manure. Save the realism for non-musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I'll make a queen of that barbarous wretch"!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicsoncall
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the pros and cons of this film, and as an outsider looking in, my advantage perhaps is that I don't know a whole lot about George Bernard Shaw, Pygmalion, Broadway musicals and Audrey Hepburn's dubbed voice as a singing Eliza Doolittle. So coming in cold, and not particularly a fan of movie musicals, I'd have to say this was watchable enough, though at almost three hours, I WAS getting antsy after the two hour mark. I realize that fans and critics will bring their own prejudices to bear in regard to the casting and staging of the story, but that aside, and with no particular horse in the race, I'd have to say that this was entertaining enough for the kind of picture I generally don't go out of the way for. My mission is to watch and review each of the movies that appeared on the American Film Institute's original 1997 list of Best One Hundred Movies of All Time. So with a clinical approach and an open mind, I'm not predisposed one way or the other to like or dislike a picture I would have passed on otherwise. So now I've seen it, it passes muster as an entertaining film, and my movie viewing experience is that much more well rounded. With a little bit of luck, you might enjoy it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply delightful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't necessarily have to be into musical to be taken in by this charming film. All I can say is that I wish there would be more musical movies like this. It's a movie with such a pleasant and joyful atmosphere to it, even though the story of course also takes some dramatic turns. But this is what musicals should all be about; simply have a good time watching it and let it be a feast for your eyes and ears. The entire movie does feel and look very stagy but in this case that really isn't a complaint. It simply suits the movie well and makes it part of the reason why this is such perfect light entertainment to watch. Besides, it is a good looking movie as well, with all of its grand sets and nice costume design. But what is a musical without any good music. And luckily this movie does really has some good and pleasant songs in it, performed nicely by its cast, though not always its original cast. Audrey Hepburn still got dubbed for instance, which was also really apparent in some of the songs. Rex Harrison on the other hand does all of the singing himself and his style of singing and acting fits the character and songs very well. Yes, all of the acting in general is very impressive in this movie as well. I had seen Rex Harrison in a couple of movies before but he never impressed me as much as he did with his role in this movie. Also Audrey Hepburn surprised me. I have always loved her but I never realized how incredible versatile as an actress she actually was until I saw her in this movie. She basically plays two different characters in this. She is both very convincing as the foul mounted girl from the streets and as the sophisticated, uppercases lady. You probably won't even recognize her at first, until she slowly starts to transform into the lovely beautiful young woman, we also all remember Audrey Hepburn as. The story and characters within this movie are definitely not all without its flaws but in this case all the story wanted was to deliver a simple, light and enjoyable movie for everybody of all ages, sexes and ethnicities to enjoy. And I think they most definitely did not fail with this. At least the Academy Awards also agree with me, since the movie received 8 Oscar's, including the most important ones for best director and best picture of the year. It also eventually would turn out to be the only Oscar legendary director George Cukor received. Simply a movie to enjoy. 9/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
