<filme>
 <id>
  491
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0029843
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1938
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  As Aventuras de Robin Hood
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  When Prince John and the Norman Lords begin oppressing the Saxon masses in King Richard's absence, a Saxon lord fights back as the outlaw leader of a rebel guerrilla army.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Sir Robin of Locksley, defender of downtrodden Saxons, runs afoul of Norman authority and is forced to turn outlaw. With his band of Merry Men, he robs from the rich, gives to the poor and still has time to woo the lovely Maid Marian, and foil the cruel Sir Guy of Gisbourne, and keep the nefarious Prince John off the throne.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   prince
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   saxon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   king
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   norman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   outlaw
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Michael Curtiz
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   William Keighley
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Norman Reilly Raine
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Seton I. Miller
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Errol Flynn
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Olivia de Havilland
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Basil Rathbone
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep, still the best version of the Robin Hood legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For my money, one of the great adventure movies, "The Adventures of Robin Hood" thrills with ease. Errol Flynn is the master swashbuckler in the title role (dude makes it look easy) and he just makes you want to go out and find some bad guys to sword fight. Basil Rathbone and Claude Rains both make for terrific bad guys, while Olivia de Havilland is flat-out gorgeous. The fight scenes are well-choreographed, Korngold's score is grandly stirring, and the whole thing is imbued with Technicolor warmth. Classic! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The glory of Errol Flynn, Olivia deHavilland, & Technicolor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the earlier days of television, on Sunday nights we always had to watch "Walt Disney's Wonderful World Of Color". Well, this isn't a Disney film, but it is a wonderful world of Technicolor! In the restored version now on DVD, the color is stunning. You might say, "And a bit overdone", and you would be correct. But it's still color film to savor. Without any question, Errol Flynn's performance here is one of the most iconic in American film history. He is at his peak, and while he made quite a few fine films after this one, none had the luster of this film. And, this is one of the biggest productions made by Warner Brothers in this era, far different than its typical second class musicals (as compared to MGM) and black-and-white gangster pics. In contrast, Olivia DeHavilland's finest and most notable film performance was still a year away -- "Gone With The Wind". Nevertheless, DeHavilland is ravishingly beautiful here. And, keep in mind that the horse she rides became Trigger shortly after this film was made, when Roy Rogers purchased him. Basil Rathbone, who seemed to usually play villains on the screen (except for his stint as Sherlock Holmes), is excellent here, and was every bit as good as swordsman as depicted; here he plays Sir Guy of Gisbourne. Claude Rains as the evil Prince John who is attempting to usurp his brother's throne, does well, although this is so different than all of his other roles. As always, barrel-bellied Eugene Palette with his husky voice is interesting, here as Friar Tuck. Alan Hale Sr. is simply perfect as Little John, and this is just one of many screen appearances he made as Flynn's "pal". Herbert Mundin is fine as one of the merry men; sadly, at age 40, he was killed just a year later in an auto accident. Melville Cooper and Una O'Connor provide comic relief, the former as the Sheriff of Nottingham, and the latter as a lady in waiting. As far as the story, it, too, is excellent, with a few raised eyebrows. Would Robin Hood have been so dumb to put himself in a situation where he would almost certainly be at a strategic disadvantage and be captured (the archery contest)? I think not. In the deluxe DVD pack now available, there's an excellent documentary about the making of the film, as well as another about the history of Technicolor. Quite fascinating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A merrier Robin than Costner and Crowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When reviewing old movies like 1938's "The Adventures of Robin Hood", the reviewer must decide whether to critique the movie based on the era in which it was released or solely upon one's modern viewing experience. I'm going to largely review this classic version of Robin Hood according to the latter. I do like Errol Flynn in the title roll. He exudes such a joie de vivre ("joy of living") in contrast to Costner's dour performance and Crowe's dead serious approach. Flynn's rendition comes across as a Medieval superhero with superhuman nonchalance and bravery, not to mention fighting skills. One sequence shows Robin Hood taking on a whole castle of armed foes and easily escaping. I have no problem with this -- superheroes are great -- but it does mark the film as more of a Medieval fantasy rather than a quasi-realistic historical picture. Olivia de Havilland is also great as Maid Marion. She has a lovely face and such a winsome spirit. The pompous villains are excellent as well. As for Robin's merry men, they're serviceable. The film is very colorful and energetic, but sometimes the dialogue comes across so rehearsed. The characters speak so quickly and without inflection that it often doesn't even register what they said until a few seconds after they speak. Maybe it's just the way actors delivered their lines back then but, regardless, this'll strike modern viewers as bad filmmaking and acting. One scene is very eye-rolling -- when Marion comes into Robin's camp in Sherwood forest and his merry men start dancing hand-in-hand. Alrighty then. As far as the score goes, I'm sure it was fine for 1938, but for modern listeners it's verging on atrocious. Still, it's surprising how much "The Adventures of Robin Hood" holds up and remains entertaining. It's a great film when you want a pleasant flash from the past. But it doesn't hold a candle to more modern Medieval films, like "Tristan & Isolde" and "Black Death". And Costner and Crowe's more realistic versions are all-around better, even while they're less vibrant. But, again, the 1938 version is great when you're in the mood for a more energetic and colorful viewing experience. The film runs 102 minutes and was shot in California (they do a pretty good job of trying to make Southern California look like England). GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (richard@berrong.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how many times I've watched this movie. Certainly every time I've seen it on TV. As with any great work of art, once you get the plot down pat and don't have to focus on it anymore, you can take a certain distance and start to study the art with which the work was put together. That's where I am with "The Adventures of Robin Hood." Every time I see it, I marvel at some different aspect of its creation, such as the brilliant use of a great film score, or the use of Technicolor. (Yes, modern movies about the Medieval Ages are probably historically more accurate with their drab colors, but "The Adventures of Robin Hood" wasn't aspiring to be a history class film strip.) This evening, as I watched it again, I wondered about the extent to which its plot was meant to be read as commentary on contemporary world politics. It was made in 1938, after all, by which time Hitler had annexed several lands, in particular Austria, and driven many Jews out of Germany. By 1938 Hollywood had become something of a refugee camp for Jewish artists who had fled from Germany and then Austria. To what extent was this story of another invader, the Normans, and their unjust treatment of those whom they conquered, the Saxons, meant to be read as a commentary on what had just happened to Austria in March of 1938?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the child uncredited cast members
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Earl Faneuf
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Edward Earle Marsh was still alive, I met him in Las Vegas. He was an amazing man who was involved with Classical music, Many films (standard and porn) and numerous TV shows. His scrap book was amazing. He told me how he had been one of the small children in the forest when Errol and Olivia were talking. No speaking part. Just one of the children sitting on the ground. I just thought it would be nice to add his name to the cast since no one has done so over the years. I have always loved this film. It is one of my favorites from that time period. I would certainly recommend it to anyone who wants a wonderful family film that is full of great acting, and very well written dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Classic Robin Hood Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Prince John (Claude Rains) and the Norman Lords begin oppressing the Saxon masses in King Richard's absence, a Saxon lord (Errol Flynn) fights back as the outlaw leader of a rebel guerrilla army. I suppose the "modern classic" version of Robin Hood would be the Kevin Costner version, which is a great film in its own right. But the all-time classic Robin Hood is Errol Flynn. Indeed, is Flynn today known for much beyond this role? He easily surpassed Douglas Fairbanks. What makes this film a classic is not only the Technicolor (which shows off some very vibrant and interesting wardrobes), but the wardrobes themselves (which were clearly the inspiration behind "Men and Tights") and the general whimsical nature of the film. Despite being about rebellion and a prince who torments his own people, it has a very upbeat feel to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still fresh 70-odd years on
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films which have iconic value to their young audiences - King Kong, Star Wars, The Matrix all leap to mind. Harryhausen's Jason And The Argonauts was mine, and the classic Errol Flynn The Adventures Of Robin Hood was my Dad's. And I can see why. Looking back at this 1938 film from the distance of 2012, it remains fresh, exciting, good humoured, full of action, bright, zesty and incredibly colourful. I would venture a guess that the use of Technicolor in this film had the same sort of impact on the cinema-going public that the 3D in Avatar did. If I was going to criticise, I would mention that the acting tends to reflect the often hammy style of the time, particularly for the supporting cast, but this is a minor quibble. This film remains as entertaining now as it was in 1938, and it was so entertaining in those days that my Dad saw it 5 times in one day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Historical Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a marvelously engaging flick. Everything seemed to come together in Warner's 1938 colorful story of Robin Hood, the 13th-century legendary outlaw who robbed from the rich only in order to give to the poor. Flynn was at his peak in 1938, terribly handsome without being in the least effete. And he was physically graceful enough to suggest competence in acrobatics and swordplay. Olivia De Havilland as Maid Marion is stunning -- vulnerable, alarmed, brave, sexy. The purity of her features isn't plastered over with an impasto of elaborate make up. Claude Raines is perfect as the sardonic and slimy fratricidal brother. And Basil Rathbone is here in his villainous mode (Mr. Murdstone, etc.), evil and grounded. His swordplay was convincing because he studied the art and became quite good; not competition level but he knew what he was about. Comedy relief is provided by some of the supporting players. William Keighley began directing but his work wasn't considered zippy enough so he was replaced by the redoubtable Michael Curtiz and -- Sire, he hesitates not to undercrank the camera and accelerate the action, nor does he pause before ripping off the shadows of swashbucklers on the castle walls, right out of silent movies with Douglas Fairbanks. The dialog is properly stilted and there are a few slightly surreal lines. Rathbone admonishes the sheriff. "You couldn't catch him if he sat in your lap shooting arrows at a crow!" Who thought THAT up? It's all an intensely hued fairy tale of course, done in gorgeous new three-strip Technicolor. Eric Wolfgang Korngold's score is delightfully bombastic. Historically, by the time the Robin Hood stories became popular, there was little friction between Norman and Saxon. People knew their places. The Normans were on top and ate "pork" (from French), while the Saxons did the farm work and raised "swine" (Germanic). Maid Marion didn't enter the stories until later. Fun, action, and the studio system at its best. Catch it if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnkim
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never seen this film or perhaps are of a certain age and consider this too old for you then you are missing a classic. This film does not desire to be nor is it historically correct. What it is, is simply a wonderful entertainment playing the Robin Hood legend in full. Every character is rich and the adventure you are invited to follow is wonderful. Errol Flynn is at his physical and romantic best. De Havilland is perfect as the demure yet quietly sensual Maid Marion, and as to Basil Rathbone! What a wonderful villain he portrays. Please younger film buffs see this film and enjoy it as it plays. You are in for a real treat and a fantastic adventure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Hood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dane (dane11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I need to tell you, I am a fan of Robin Hood. I read the stories of Robin Hood as a child/young adult. I've watched every Robin Hood movie and TV Show (TV Show's in re-runs, with the exception of When Things Were Rotten). Robin Hood is a character who is worthy of legend. He is a character that few can really compare to. And, after seeing Errol Flynn in green tights and cap, I realized, there would never be another Robin Hood. The Adventures of Robin Hood, from Warner Brothers in glorious Technicolor is a visual masterpiece. From the green forests to the dark, castle of the would-be King, Prince John, the colors and textures really come to life. The excellent direction by Michael Curtiz allows the film to fire on all cylinders. But it is the character of Robin, portrayed by Flynn with a great smile and amazing athleticism that really wins over the viewer. We cannot deny that Flynn's smile will win over the heart of Maid Marian. Nor do we doubt when he casts his smile on his victims that they too would be overwhelmed by his charm and style. Flynn's Robin Hood is not threatening. Flynn's Robin Hood comes across as happy and carefree, fighting for what he believes in. When the time comes for Robin to be serious and fight it out with his enemies, we are equally drawn in, ready to believe that we're watching the greatest hero/anti-hero ever imagined. No hero is complete without a great adversary. For Robin, his enemy has always been the Sheriff of Nottingham, but here we have, Sir Guy of Gisbourne, perfectly portrayed by Basil Rathbone. Naturally, Sir Guy takes his orders from Prince John, the great Claude Rains showing a slightly feminine side of a would-be-king. Prince John's associates are all evil and conniving, the Sheriff of Nottingham is played for laughs by Melville Cooper, allowing Sir Guy to be the really bad guy that hates Robin Hood. There is too much about this movie to like -- Robin's "Merry Men" are robustly and warmly portrayed by Alan Hale, Patrick Knowles and Eugene Palette as Little John, Will Scarlet and Friar Tuck, respectively. The glorious Technicolor vision of Sherwood Forest and the complete cast of characters that includes the Una O'Connor in a fun role as Maid Marian's guardian. There is humor and action and, of course, romance as only old Hollywood could make it. Michael Curtiz deftly moves between humor and action with an amazing style so the view hardly notices the difference. I've watched Douglas Fairbanks, Kevin Costner and Patrick Bergin try their hand at the character, I've watched the old TV series, the Disney cartoon and Mel Brooks satirical "Robin Hood: Men in Tights", right down to Ridley Scott's great retelling of the story with Russel Crowe. None of these compare to Errol Flynn in the Adventures of Robin Hood. Costner was way too wooden to be a true swashbuckler. Bergin was a little too uptight to be interesting. The TV show was... well, it was a 1950's TV show... Even Richard Lester's "Robin and Marian" falls a little short, though Connery is great as an older Robin Hood, complete with a winning, fun-loving smile. Flynn was fun and adventurous. We believe he could split the other archer's arrow. We believe that he could win the heart of Maid Marian and that his men would gladly follow him in to the Lion's den. We cheered for him because he was fun and he looked upon everything with a grin. We believe that he will protect the throne for good King Richard and save all of England, because we see that spark in his eyes telling us nothing is impossible. I'm a huge fan of Robin Hood. If the old stories of Robin Hood did not make me a fan, Errol Flynn did. There will never be another Robin Hood to compare with what Flynn brought to the screen. If you're checking out the Kevin Costner Robin Hood or the Russel Crowe version, take a look at what Flynn did first and you will be amazed by what you see. Allow yourself to go back in time and meet this man who was charming and fun and so full of life that all would gladly follow him. You too will become a fan of Robin Hood -- and probably a fan of Errol Flynn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep, still the best version of the Robin Hood legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For my money, one of the great adventure movies, "The Adventures of Robin Hood" thrills with ease. Errol Flynn is the master swashbuckler in the title role (dude makes it look easy) and he just makes you want to go out and find some bad guys to sword fight. Basil Rathbone and Claude Rains both make for terrific bad guys, while Olivia de Havilland is flat-out gorgeous. The fight scenes are well-choreographed, Korngold's score is grandly stirring, and the whole thing is imbued with Technicolor warmth. Classic! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The glory of Errol Flynn, Olivia deHavilland, & Technicolor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the earlier days of television, on Sunday nights we always had to watch "Walt Disney's Wonderful World Of Color". Well, this isn't a Disney film, but it is a wonderful world of Technicolor! In the restored version now on DVD, the color is stunning. You might say, "And a bit overdone", and you would be correct. But it's still color film to savor. Without any question, Errol Flynn's performance here is one of the most iconic in American film history. He is at his peak, and while he made quite a few fine films after this one, none had the luster of this film. And, this is one of the biggest productions made by Warner Brothers in this era, far different than its typical second class musicals (as compared to MGM) and black-and-white gangster pics. In contrast, Olivia DeHavilland's finest and most notable film performance was still a year away -- "Gone With The Wind". Nevertheless, DeHavilland is ravishingly beautiful here. And, keep in mind that the horse she rides became Trigger shortly after this film was made, when Roy Rogers purchased him. Basil Rathbone, who seemed to usually play villains on the screen (except for his stint as Sherlock Holmes), is excellent here, and was every bit as good as swordsman as depicted; here he plays Sir Guy of Gisbourne. Claude Rains as the evil Prince John who is attempting to usurp his brother's throne, does well, although this is so different than all of his other roles. As always, barrel-bellied Eugene Palette with his husky voice is interesting, here as Friar Tuck. Alan Hale Sr. is simply perfect as Little John, and this is just one of many screen appearances he made as Flynn's "pal". Herbert Mundin is fine as one of the merry men; sadly, at age 40, he was killed just a year later in an auto accident. Melville Cooper and Una O'Connor provide comic relief, the former as the Sheriff of Nottingham, and the latter as a lady in waiting. As far as the story, it, too, is excellent, with a few raised eyebrows. Would Robin Hood have been so dumb to put himself in a situation where he would almost certainly be at a strategic disadvantage and be captured (the archery contest)? I think not. In the deluxe DVD pack now available, there's an excellent documentary about the making of the film, as well as another about the history of Technicolor. Quite fascinating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A merrier Robin than Costner and Crowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When reviewing old movies like 1938's "The Adventures of Robin Hood", the reviewer must decide whether to critique the movie based on the era in which it was released or solely upon one's modern viewing experience. I'm going to largely review this classic version of Robin Hood according to the latter. I do like Errol Flynn in the title roll. He exudes such a joie de vivre ("joy of living") in contrast to Costner's dour performance and Crowe's dead serious approach. Flynn's rendition comes across as a Medieval superhero with superhuman nonchalance and bravery, not to mention fighting skills. One sequence shows Robin Hood taking on a whole castle of armed foes and easily escaping. I have no problem with this -- superheroes are great -- but it does mark the film as more of a Medieval fantasy rather than a quasi-realistic historical picture. Olivia de Havilland is also great as Maid Marion. She has a lovely face and such a winsome spirit. The pompous villains are excellent as well. As for Robin's merry men, they're serviceable. The film is very colorful and energetic, but sometimes the dialogue comes across so rehearsed. The characters speak so quickly and without inflection that it often doesn't even register what they said until a few seconds after they speak. Maybe it's just the way actors delivered their lines back then but, regardless, this'll strike modern viewers as bad filmmaking and acting. One scene is very eye-rolling -- when Marion comes into Robin's camp in Sherwood forest and his merry men start dancing hand-in-hand. Alrighty then. As far as the score goes, I'm sure it was fine for 1938, but for modern listeners it's verging on atrocious. Still, it's surprising how much "The Adventures of Robin Hood" holds up and remains entertaining. It's a great film when you want a pleasant flash from the past. But it doesn't hold a candle to more modern Medieval films, like "Tristan & Isolde" and "Black Death". And Costner and Crowe's more realistic versions are all-around better, even while they're less vibrant. But, again, the 1938 version is great when you're in the mood for a more energetic and colorful viewing experience. The film runs 102 minutes and was shot in California (they do a pretty good job of trying to make Southern California look like England). GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (richard@berrong.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how many times I've watched this movie. Certainly every time I've seen it on TV. As with any great work of art, once you get the plot down pat and don't have to focus on it anymore, you can take a certain distance and start to study the art with which the work was put together. That's where I am with "The Adventures of Robin Hood." Every time I see it, I marvel at some different aspect of its creation, such as the brilliant use of a great film score, or the use of Technicolor. (Yes, modern movies about the Medieval Ages are probably historically more accurate with their drab colors, but "The Adventures of Robin Hood" wasn't aspiring to be a history class film strip.) This evening, as I watched it again, I wondered about the extent to which its plot was meant to be read as commentary on contemporary world politics. It was made in 1938, after all, by which time Hitler had annexed several lands, in particular Austria, and driven many Jews out of Germany. By 1938 Hollywood had become something of a refugee camp for Jewish artists who had fled from Germany and then Austria. To what extent was this story of another invader, the Normans, and their unjust treatment of those whom they conquered, the Saxons, meant to be read as a commentary on what had just happened to Austria in March of 1938?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the child uncredited cast members
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Earl Faneuf
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Edward Earle Marsh was still alive, I met him in Las Vegas. He was an amazing man who was involved with Classical music, Many films (standard and porn) and numerous TV shows. His scrap book was amazing. He told me how he had been one of the small children in the forest when Errol and Olivia were talking. No speaking part. Just one of the children sitting on the ground. I just thought it would be nice to add his name to the cast since no one has done so over the years. I have always loved this film. It is one of my favorites from that time period. I would certainly recommend it to anyone who wants a wonderful family film that is full of great acting, and very well written dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Classic Robin Hood Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Prince John (Claude Rains) and the Norman Lords begin oppressing the Saxon masses in King Richard's absence, a Saxon lord (Errol Flynn) fights back as the outlaw leader of a rebel guerrilla army. I suppose the "modern classic" version of Robin Hood would be the Kevin Costner version, which is a great film in its own right. But the all-time classic Robin Hood is Errol Flynn. Indeed, is Flynn today known for much beyond this role? He easily surpassed Douglas Fairbanks. What makes this film a classic is not only the Technicolor (which shows off some very vibrant and interesting wardrobes), but the wardrobes themselves (which were clearly the inspiration behind "Men and Tights") and the general whimsical nature of the film. Despite being about rebellion and a prince who torments his own people, it has a very upbeat feel to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still fresh 70-odd years on
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films which have iconic value to their young audiences - King Kong, Star Wars, The Matrix all leap to mind. Harryhausen's Jason And The Argonauts was mine, and the classic Errol Flynn The Adventures Of Robin Hood was my Dad's. And I can see why. Looking back at this 1938 film from the distance of 2012, it remains fresh, exciting, good humoured, full of action, bright, zesty and incredibly colourful. I would venture a guess that the use of Technicolor in this film had the same sort of impact on the cinema-going public that the 3D in Avatar did. If I was going to criticise, I would mention that the acting tends to reflect the often hammy style of the time, particularly for the supporting cast, but this is a minor quibble. This film remains as entertaining now as it was in 1938, and it was so entertaining in those days that my Dad saw it 5 times in one day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Historical Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a marvelously engaging flick. Everything seemed to come together in Warner's 1938 colorful story of Robin Hood, the 13th-century legendary outlaw who robbed from the rich only in order to give to the poor. Flynn was at his peak in 1938, terribly handsome without being in the least effete. And he was physically graceful enough to suggest competence in acrobatics and swordplay. Olivia De Havilland as Maid Marion is stunning -- vulnerable, alarmed, brave, sexy. The purity of her features isn't plastered over with an impasto of elaborate make up. Claude Raines is perfect as the sardonic and slimy fratricidal brother. And Basil Rathbone is here in his villainous mode (Mr. Murdstone, etc.), evil and grounded. His swordplay was convincing because he studied the art and became quite good; not competition level but he knew what he was about. Comedy relief is provided by some of the supporting players. William Keighley began directing but his work wasn't considered zippy enough so he was replaced by the redoubtable Michael Curtiz and -- Sire, he hesitates not to undercrank the camera and accelerate the action, nor does he pause before ripping off the shadows of swashbucklers on the castle walls, right out of silent movies with Douglas Fairbanks. The dialog is properly stilted and there are a few slightly surreal lines. Rathbone admonishes the sheriff. "You couldn't catch him if he sat in your lap shooting arrows at a crow!" Who thought THAT up? It's all an intensely hued fairy tale of course, done in gorgeous new three-strip Technicolor. Eric Wolfgang Korngold's score is delightfully bombastic. Historically, by the time the Robin Hood stories became popular, there was little friction between Norman and Saxon. People knew their places. The Normans were on top and ate "pork" (from French), while the Saxons did the farm work and raised "swine" (Germanic). Maid Marion didn't enter the stories until later. Fun, action, and the studio system at its best. Catch it if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnkim
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never seen this film or perhaps are of a certain age and consider this too old for you then you are missing a classic. This film does not desire to be nor is it historically correct. What it is, is simply a wonderful entertainment playing the Robin Hood legend in full. Every character is rich and the adventure you are invited to follow is wonderful. Errol Flynn is at his physical and romantic best. De Havilland is perfect as the demure yet quietly sensual Maid Marion, and as to Basil Rathbone! What a wonderful villain he portrays. Please younger film buffs see this film and enjoy it as it plays. You are in for a real treat and a fantastic adventure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Hood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dane (dane11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I need to tell you, I am a fan of Robin Hood. I read the stories of Robin Hood as a child/young adult. I've watched every Robin Hood movie and TV Show (TV Show's in re-runs, with the exception of When Things Were Rotten). Robin Hood is a character who is worthy of legend. He is a character that few can really compare to. And, after seeing Errol Flynn in green tights and cap, I realized, there would never be another Robin Hood. The Adventures of Robin Hood, from Warner Brothers in glorious Technicolor is a visual masterpiece. From the green forests to the dark, castle of the would-be King, Prince John, the colors and textures really come to life. The excellent direction by Michael Curtiz allows the film to fire on all cylinders. But it is the character of Robin, portrayed by Flynn with a great smile and amazing athleticism that really wins over the viewer. We cannot deny that Flynn's smile will win over the heart of Maid Marian. Nor do we doubt when he casts his smile on his victims that they too would be overwhelmed by his charm and style. Flynn's Robin Hood is not threatening. Flynn's Robin Hood comes across as happy and carefree, fighting for what he believes in. When the time comes for Robin to be serious and fight it out with his enemies, we are equally drawn in, ready to believe that we're watching the greatest hero/anti-hero ever imagined. No hero is complete without a great adversary. For Robin, his enemy has always been the Sheriff of Nottingham, but here we have, Sir Guy of Gisbourne, perfectly portrayed by Basil Rathbone. Naturally, Sir Guy takes his orders from Prince John, the great Claude Rains showing a slightly feminine side of a would-be-king. Prince John's associates are all evil and conniving, the Sheriff of Nottingham is played for laughs by Melville Cooper, allowing Sir Guy to be the really bad guy that hates Robin Hood. There is too much about this movie to like -- Robin's "Merry Men" are robustly and warmly portrayed by Alan Hale, Patrick Knowles and Eugene Palette as Little John, Will Scarlet and Friar Tuck, respectively. The glorious Technicolor vision of Sherwood Forest and the complete cast of characters that includes the Una O'Connor in a fun role as Maid Marian's guardian. There is humor and action and, of course, romance as only old Hollywood could make it. Michael Curtiz deftly moves between humor and action with an amazing style so the view hardly notices the difference. I've watched Douglas Fairbanks, Kevin Costner and Patrick Bergin try their hand at the character, I've watched the old TV series, the Disney cartoon and Mel Brooks satirical "Robin Hood: Men in Tights", right down to Ridley Scott's great retelling of the story with Russel Crowe. None of these compare to Errol Flynn in the Adventures of Robin Hood. Costner was way too wooden to be a true swashbuckler. Bergin was a little too uptight to be interesting. The TV show was... well, it was a 1950's TV show... Even Richard Lester's "Robin and Marian" falls a little short, though Connery is great as an older Robin Hood, complete with a winning, fun-loving smile. Flynn was fun and adventurous. We believe he could split the other archer's arrow. We believe that he could win the heart of Maid Marian and that his men would gladly follow him in to the Lion's den. We cheered for him because he was fun and he looked upon everything with a grin. We believe that he will protect the throne for good King Richard and save all of England, because we see that spark in his eyes telling us nothing is impossible. I'm a huge fan of Robin Hood. If the old stories of Robin Hood did not make me a fan, Errol Flynn did. There will never be another Robin Hood to compare with what Flynn brought to the screen. If you're checking out the Kevin Costner Robin Hood or the Russel Crowe version, take a look at what Flynn did first and you will be amazed by what you see. Allow yourself to go back in time and meet this man who was charming and fun and so full of life that all would gladly follow him. You too will become a fan of Robin Hood -- and probably a fan of Errol Flynn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep, still the best version of the Robin Hood legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For my money, one of the great adventure movies, "The Adventures of Robin Hood" thrills with ease. Errol Flynn is the master swashbuckler in the title role (dude makes it look easy) and he just makes you want to go out and find some bad guys to sword fight. Basil Rathbone and Claude Rains both make for terrific bad guys, while Olivia de Havilland is flat-out gorgeous. The fight scenes are well-choreographed, Korngold's score is grandly stirring, and the whole thing is imbued with Technicolor warmth. Classic! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The glory of Errol Flynn, Olivia deHavilland, & Technicolor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the earlier days of television, on Sunday nights we always had to watch "Walt Disney's Wonderful World Of Color". Well, this isn't a Disney film, but it is a wonderful world of Technicolor! In the restored version now on DVD, the color is stunning. You might say, "And a bit overdone", and you would be correct. But it's still color film to savor. Without any question, Errol Flynn's performance here is one of the most iconic in American film history. He is at his peak, and while he made quite a few fine films after this one, none had the luster of this film. And, this is one of the biggest productions made by Warner Brothers in this era, far different than its typical second class musicals (as compared to MGM) and black-and-white gangster pics. In contrast, Olivia DeHavilland's finest and most notable film performance was still a year away -- "Gone With The Wind". Nevertheless, DeHavilland is ravishingly beautiful here. And, keep in mind that the horse she rides became Trigger shortly after this film was made, when Roy Rogers purchased him. Basil Rathbone, who seemed to usually play villains on the screen (except for his stint as Sherlock Holmes), is excellent here, and was every bit as good as swordsman as depicted; here he plays Sir Guy of Gisbourne. Claude Rains as the evil Prince John who is attempting to usurp his brother's throne, does well, although this is so different than all of his other roles. As always, barrel-bellied Eugene Palette with his husky voice is interesting, here as Friar Tuck. Alan Hale Sr. is simply perfect as Little John, and this is just one of many screen appearances he made as Flynn's "pal". Herbert Mundin is fine as one of the merry men; sadly, at age 40, he was killed just a year later in an auto accident. Melville Cooper and Una O'Connor provide comic relief, the former as the Sheriff of Nottingham, and the latter as a lady in waiting. As far as the story, it, too, is excellent, with a few raised eyebrows. Would Robin Hood have been so dumb to put himself in a situation where he would almost certainly be at a strategic disadvantage and be captured (the archery contest)? I think not. In the deluxe DVD pack now available, there's an excellent documentary about the making of the film, as well as another about the history of Technicolor. Quite fascinating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A merrier Robin than Costner and Crowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When reviewing old movies like 1938's "The Adventures of Robin Hood", the reviewer must decide whether to critique the movie based on the era in which it was released or solely upon one's modern viewing experience. I'm going to largely review this classic version of Robin Hood according to the latter. I do like Errol Flynn in the title roll. He exudes such a joie de vivre ("joy of living") in contrast to Costner's dour performance and Crowe's dead serious approach. Flynn's rendition comes across as a Medieval superhero with superhuman nonchalance and bravery, not to mention fighting skills. One sequence shows Robin Hood taking on a whole castle of armed foes and easily escaping. I have no problem with this -- superheroes are great -- but it does mark the film as more of a Medieval fantasy rather than a quasi-realistic historical picture. Olivia de Havilland is also great as Maid Marion. She has a lovely face and such a winsome spirit. The pompous villains are excellent as well. As for Robin's merry men, they're serviceable. The film is very colorful and energetic, but sometimes the dialogue comes across so rehearsed. The characters speak so quickly and without inflection that it often doesn't even register what they said until a few seconds after they speak. Maybe it's just the way actors delivered their lines back then but, regardless, this'll strike modern viewers as bad filmmaking and acting. One scene is very eye-rolling -- when Marion comes into Robin's camp in Sherwood forest and his merry men start dancing hand-in-hand. Alrighty then. As far as the score goes, I'm sure it was fine for 1938, but for modern listeners it's verging on atrocious. Still, it's surprising how much "The Adventures of Robin Hood" holds up and remains entertaining. It's a great film when you want a pleasant flash from the past. But it doesn't hold a candle to more modern Medieval films, like "Tristan & Isolde" and "Black Death". And Costner and Crowe's more realistic versions are all-around better, even while they're less vibrant. But, again, the 1938 version is great when you're in the mood for a more energetic and colorful viewing experience. The film runs 102 minutes and was shot in California (they do a pretty good job of trying to make Southern California look like England). GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (richard@berrong.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how many times I've watched this movie. Certainly every time I've seen it on TV. As with any great work of art, once you get the plot down pat and don't have to focus on it anymore, you can take a certain distance and start to study the art with which the work was put together. That's where I am with "The Adventures of Robin Hood." Every time I see it, I marvel at some different aspect of its creation, such as the brilliant use of a great film score, or the use of Technicolor. (Yes, modern movies about the Medieval Ages are probably historically more accurate with their drab colors, but "The Adventures of Robin Hood" wasn't aspiring to be a history class film strip.) This evening, as I watched it again, I wondered about the extent to which its plot was meant to be read as commentary on contemporary world politics. It was made in 1938, after all, by which time Hitler had annexed several lands, in particular Austria, and driven many Jews out of Germany. By 1938 Hollywood had become something of a refugee camp for Jewish artists who had fled from Germany and then Austria. To what extent was this story of another invader, the Normans, and their unjust treatment of those whom they conquered, the Saxons, meant to be read as a commentary on what had just happened to Austria in March of 1938?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the child uncredited cast members
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Earl Faneuf
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Edward Earle Marsh was still alive, I met him in Las Vegas. He was an amazing man who was involved with Classical music, Many films (standard and porn) and numerous TV shows. His scrap book was amazing. He told me how he had been one of the small children in the forest when Errol and Olivia were talking. No speaking part. Just one of the children sitting on the ground. I just thought it would be nice to add his name to the cast since no one has done so over the years. I have always loved this film. It is one of my favorites from that time period. I would certainly recommend it to anyone who wants a wonderful family film that is full of great acting, and very well written dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Classic Robin Hood Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Prince John (Claude Rains) and the Norman Lords begin oppressing the Saxon masses in King Richard's absence, a Saxon lord (Errol Flynn) fights back as the outlaw leader of a rebel guerrilla army. I suppose the "modern classic" version of Robin Hood would be the Kevin Costner version, which is a great film in its own right. But the all-time classic Robin Hood is Errol Flynn. Indeed, is Flynn today known for much beyond this role? He easily surpassed Douglas Fairbanks. What makes this film a classic is not only the Technicolor (which shows off some very vibrant and interesting wardrobes), but the wardrobes themselves (which were clearly the inspiration behind "Men and Tights") and the general whimsical nature of the film. Despite being about rebellion and a prince who torments his own people, it has a very upbeat feel to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still fresh 70-odd years on
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films which have iconic value to their young audiences - King Kong, Star Wars, The Matrix all leap to mind. Harryhausen's Jason And The Argonauts was mine, and the classic Errol Flynn The Adventures Of Robin Hood was my Dad's. And I can see why. Looking back at this 1938 film from the distance of 2012, it remains fresh, exciting, good humoured, full of action, bright, zesty and incredibly colourful. I would venture a guess that the use of Technicolor in this film had the same sort of impact on the cinema-going public that the 3D in Avatar did. If I was going to criticise, I would mention that the acting tends to reflect the often hammy style of the time, particularly for the supporting cast, but this is a minor quibble. This film remains as entertaining now as it was in 1938, and it was so entertaining in those days that my Dad saw it 5 times in one day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Historical Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a marvelously engaging flick. Everything seemed to come together in Warner's 1938 colorful story of Robin Hood, the 13th-century legendary outlaw who robbed from the rich only in order to give to the poor. Flynn was at his peak in 1938, terribly handsome without being in the least effete. And he was physically graceful enough to suggest competence in acrobatics and swordplay. Olivia De Havilland as Maid Marion is stunning -- vulnerable, alarmed, brave, sexy. The purity of her features isn't plastered over with an impasto of elaborate make up. Claude Raines is perfect as the sardonic and slimy fratricidal brother. And Basil Rathbone is here in his villainous mode (Mr. Murdstone, etc.), evil and grounded. His swordplay was convincing because he studied the art and became quite good; not competition level but he knew what he was about. Comedy relief is provided by some of the supporting players. William Keighley began directing but his work wasn't considered zippy enough so he was replaced by the redoubtable Michael Curtiz and -- Sire, he hesitates not to undercrank the camera and accelerate the action, nor does he pause before ripping off the shadows of swashbucklers on the castle walls, right out of silent movies with Douglas Fairbanks. The dialog is properly stilted and there are a few slightly surreal lines. Rathbone admonishes the sheriff. "You couldn't catch him if he sat in your lap shooting arrows at a crow!" Who thought THAT up? It's all an intensely hued fairy tale of course, done in gorgeous new three-strip Technicolor. Eric Wolfgang Korngold's score is delightfully bombastic. Historically, by the time the Robin Hood stories became popular, there was little friction between Norman and Saxon. People knew their places. The Normans were on top and ate "pork" (from French), while the Saxons did the farm work and raised "swine" (Germanic). Maid Marion didn't enter the stories until later. Fun, action, and the studio system at its best. Catch it if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnkim
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never seen this film or perhaps are of a certain age and consider this too old for you then you are missing a classic. This film does not desire to be nor is it historically correct. What it is, is simply a wonderful entertainment playing the Robin Hood legend in full. Every character is rich and the adventure you are invited to follow is wonderful. Errol Flynn is at his physical and romantic best. De Havilland is perfect as the demure yet quietly sensual Maid Marion, and as to Basil Rathbone! What a wonderful villain he portrays. Please younger film buffs see this film and enjoy it as it plays. You are in for a real treat and a fantastic adventure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Hood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dane (dane11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I need to tell you, I am a fan of Robin Hood. I read the stories of Robin Hood as a child/young adult. I've watched every Robin Hood movie and TV Show (TV Show's in re-runs, with the exception of When Things Were Rotten). Robin Hood is a character who is worthy of legend. He is a character that few can really compare to. And, after seeing Errol Flynn in green tights and cap, I realized, there would never be another Robin Hood. The Adventures of Robin Hood, from Warner Brothers in glorious Technicolor is a visual masterpiece. From the green forests to the dark, castle of the would-be King, Prince John, the colors and textures really come to life. The excellent direction by Michael Curtiz allows the film to fire on all cylinders. But it is the character of Robin, portrayed by Flynn with a great smile and amazing athleticism that really wins over the viewer. We cannot deny that Flynn's smile will win over the heart of Maid Marian. Nor do we doubt when he casts his smile on his victims that they too would be overwhelmed by his charm and style. Flynn's Robin Hood is not threatening. Flynn's Robin Hood comes across as happy and carefree, fighting for what he believes in. When the time comes for Robin to be serious and fight it out with his enemies, we are equally drawn in, ready to believe that we're watching the greatest hero/anti-hero ever imagined. No hero is complete without a great adversary. For Robin, his enemy has always been the Sheriff of Nottingham, but here we have, Sir Guy of Gisbourne, perfectly portrayed by Basil Rathbone. Naturally, Sir Guy takes his orders from Prince John, the great Claude Rains showing a slightly feminine side of a would-be-king. Prince John's associates are all evil and conniving, the Sheriff of Nottingham is played for laughs by Melville Cooper, allowing Sir Guy to be the really bad guy that hates Robin Hood. There is too much about this movie to like -- Robin's "Merry Men" are robustly and warmly portrayed by Alan Hale, Patrick Knowles and Eugene Palette as Little John, Will Scarlet and Friar Tuck, respectively. The glorious Technicolor vision of Sherwood Forest and the complete cast of characters that includes the Una O'Connor in a fun role as Maid Marian's guardian. There is humor and action and, of course, romance as only old Hollywood could make it. Michael Curtiz deftly moves between humor and action with an amazing style so the view hardly notices the difference. I've watched Douglas Fairbanks, Kevin Costner and Patrick Bergin try their hand at the character, I've watched the old TV series, the Disney cartoon and Mel Brooks satirical "Robin Hood: Men in Tights", right down to Ridley Scott's great retelling of the story with Russel Crowe. None of these compare to Errol Flynn in the Adventures of Robin Hood. Costner was way too wooden to be a true swashbuckler. Bergin was a little too uptight to be interesting. The TV show was... well, it was a 1950's TV show... Even Richard Lester's "Robin and Marian" falls a little short, though Connery is great as an older Robin Hood, complete with a winning, fun-loving smile. Flynn was fun and adventurous. We believe he could split the other archer's arrow. We believe that he could win the heart of Maid Marian and that his men would gladly follow him in to the Lion's den. We cheered for him because he was fun and he looked upon everything with a grin. We believe that he will protect the throne for good King Richard and save all of England, because we see that spark in his eyes telling us nothing is impossible. I'm a huge fan of Robin Hood. If the old stories of Robin Hood did not make me a fan, Errol Flynn did. There will never be another Robin Hood to compare with what Flynn brought to the screen. If you're checking out the Kevin Costner Robin Hood or the Russel Crowe version, take a look at what Flynn did first and you will be amazed by what you see. Allow yourself to go back in time and meet this man who was charming and fun and so full of life that all would gladly follow him. You too will become a fan of Robin Hood -- and probably a fan of Errol Flynn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep, still the best version of the Robin Hood legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For my money, one of the great adventure movies, "The Adventures of Robin Hood" thrills with ease. Errol Flynn is the master swashbuckler in the title role (dude makes it look easy) and he just makes you want to go out and find some bad guys to sword fight. Basil Rathbone and Claude Rains both make for terrific bad guys, while Olivia de Havilland is flat-out gorgeous. The fight scenes are well-choreographed, Korngold's score is grandly stirring, and the whole thing is imbued with Technicolor warmth. Classic! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The glory of Errol Flynn, Olivia deHavilland, & Technicolor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the earlier days of television, on Sunday nights we always had to watch "Walt Disney's Wonderful World Of Color". Well, this isn't a Disney film, but it is a wonderful world of Technicolor! In the restored version now on DVD, the color is stunning. You might say, "And a bit overdone", and you would be correct. But it's still color film to savor. Without any question, Errol Flynn's performance here is one of the most iconic in American film history. He is at his peak, and while he made quite a few fine films after this one, none had the luster of this film. And, this is one of the biggest productions made by Warner Brothers in this era, far different than its typical second class musicals (as compared to MGM) and black-and-white gangster pics. In contrast, Olivia DeHavilland's finest and most notable film performance was still a year away -- "Gone With The Wind". Nevertheless, DeHavilland is ravishingly beautiful here. And, keep in mind that the horse she rides became Trigger shortly after this film was made, when Roy Rogers purchased him. Basil Rathbone, who seemed to usually play villains on the screen (except for his stint as Sherlock Holmes), is excellent here, and was every bit as good as swordsman as depicted; here he plays Sir Guy of Gisbourne. Claude Rains as the evil Prince John who is attempting to usurp his brother's throne, does well, although this is so different than all of his other roles. As always, barrel-bellied Eugene Palette with his husky voice is interesting, here as Friar Tuck. Alan Hale Sr. is simply perfect as Little John, and this is just one of many screen appearances he made as Flynn's "pal". Herbert Mundin is fine as one of the merry men; sadly, at age 40, he was killed just a year later in an auto accident. Melville Cooper and Una O'Connor provide comic relief, the former as the Sheriff of Nottingham, and the latter as a lady in waiting. As far as the story, it, too, is excellent, with a few raised eyebrows. Would Robin Hood have been so dumb to put himself in a situation where he would almost certainly be at a strategic disadvantage and be captured (the archery contest)? I think not. In the deluxe DVD pack now available, there's an excellent documentary about the making of the film, as well as another about the history of Technicolor. Quite fascinating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A merrier Robin than Costner and Crowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When reviewing old movies like 1938's "The Adventures of Robin Hood", the reviewer must decide whether to critique the movie based on the era in which it was released or solely upon one's modern viewing experience. I'm going to largely review this classic version of Robin Hood according to the latter. I do like Errol Flynn in the title roll. He exudes such a joie de vivre ("joy of living") in contrast to Costner's dour performance and Crowe's dead serious approach. Flynn's rendition comes across as a Medieval superhero with superhuman nonchalance and bravery, not to mention fighting skills. One sequence shows Robin Hood taking on a whole castle of armed foes and easily escaping. I have no problem with this -- superheroes are great -- but it does mark the film as more of a Medieval fantasy rather than a quasi-realistic historical picture. Olivia de Havilland is also great as Maid Marion. She has a lovely face and such a winsome spirit. The pompous villains are excellent as well. As for Robin's merry men, they're serviceable. The film is very colorful and energetic, but sometimes the dialogue comes across so rehearsed. The characters speak so quickly and without inflection that it often doesn't even register what they said until a few seconds after they speak. Maybe it's just the way actors delivered their lines back then but, regardless, this'll strike modern viewers as bad filmmaking and acting. One scene is very eye-rolling -- when Marion comes into Robin's camp in Sherwood forest and his merry men start dancing hand-in-hand. Alrighty then. As far as the score goes, I'm sure it was fine for 1938, but for modern listeners it's verging on atrocious. Still, it's surprising how much "The Adventures of Robin Hood" holds up and remains entertaining. It's a great film when you want a pleasant flash from the past. But it doesn't hold a candle to more modern Medieval films, like "Tristan & Isolde" and "Black Death". And Costner and Crowe's more realistic versions are all-around better, even while they're less vibrant. But, again, the 1938 version is great when you're in the mood for a more energetic and colorful viewing experience. The film runs 102 minutes and was shot in California (they do a pretty good job of trying to make Southern California look like England). GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (richard@berrong.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how many times I've watched this movie. Certainly every time I've seen it on TV. As with any great work of art, once you get the plot down pat and don't have to focus on it anymore, you can take a certain distance and start to study the art with which the work was put together. That's where I am with "The Adventures of Robin Hood." Every time I see it, I marvel at some different aspect of its creation, such as the brilliant use of a great film score, or the use of Technicolor. (Yes, modern movies about the Medieval Ages are probably historically more accurate with their drab colors, but "The Adventures of Robin Hood" wasn't aspiring to be a history class film strip.) This evening, as I watched it again, I wondered about the extent to which its plot was meant to be read as commentary on contemporary world politics. It was made in 1938, after all, by which time Hitler had annexed several lands, in particular Austria, and driven many Jews out of Germany. By 1938 Hollywood had become something of a refugee camp for Jewish artists who had fled from Germany and then Austria. To what extent was this story of another invader, the Normans, and their unjust treatment of those whom they conquered, the Saxons, meant to be read as a commentary on what had just happened to Austria in March of 1938?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the child uncredited cast members
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Earl Faneuf
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Edward Earle Marsh was still alive, I met him in Las Vegas. He was an amazing man who was involved with Classical music, Many films (standard and porn) and numerous TV shows. His scrap book was amazing. He told me how he had been one of the small children in the forest when Errol and Olivia were talking. No speaking part. Just one of the children sitting on the ground. I just thought it would be nice to add his name to the cast since no one has done so over the years. I have always loved this film. It is one of my favorites from that time period. I would certainly recommend it to anyone who wants a wonderful family film that is full of great acting, and very well written dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Classic Robin Hood Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Prince John (Claude Rains) and the Norman Lords begin oppressing the Saxon masses in King Richard's absence, a Saxon lord (Errol Flynn) fights back as the outlaw leader of a rebel guerrilla army. I suppose the "modern classic" version of Robin Hood would be the Kevin Costner version, which is a great film in its own right. But the all-time classic Robin Hood is Errol Flynn. Indeed, is Flynn today known for much beyond this role? He easily surpassed Douglas Fairbanks. What makes this film a classic is not only the Technicolor (which shows off some very vibrant and interesting wardrobes), but the wardrobes themselves (which were clearly the inspiration behind "Men and Tights") and the general whimsical nature of the film. Despite being about rebellion and a prince who torments his own people, it has a very upbeat feel to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still fresh 70-odd years on
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films which have iconic value to their young audiences - King Kong, Star Wars, The Matrix all leap to mind. Harryhausen's Jason And The Argonauts was mine, and the classic Errol Flynn The Adventures Of Robin Hood was my Dad's. And I can see why. Looking back at this 1938 film from the distance of 2012, it remains fresh, exciting, good humoured, full of action, bright, zesty and incredibly colourful. I would venture a guess that the use of Technicolor in this film had the same sort of impact on the cinema-going public that the 3D in Avatar did. If I was going to criticise, I would mention that the acting tends to reflect the often hammy style of the time, particularly for the supporting cast, but this is a minor quibble. This film remains as entertaining now as it was in 1938, and it was so entertaining in those days that my Dad saw it 5 times in one day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Historical Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a marvelously engaging flick. Everything seemed to come together in Warner's 1938 colorful story of Robin Hood, the 13th-century legendary outlaw who robbed from the rich only in order to give to the poor. Flynn was at his peak in 1938, terribly handsome without being in the least effete. And he was physically graceful enough to suggest competence in acrobatics and swordplay. Olivia De Havilland as Maid Marion is stunning -- vulnerable, alarmed, brave, sexy. The purity of her features isn't plastered over with an impasto of elaborate make up. Claude Raines is perfect as the sardonic and slimy fratricidal brother. And Basil Rathbone is here in his villainous mode (Mr. Murdstone, etc.), evil and grounded. His swordplay was convincing because he studied the art and became quite good; not competition level but he knew what he was about. Comedy relief is provided by some of the supporting players. William Keighley began directing but his work wasn't considered zippy enough so he was replaced by the redoubtable Michael Curtiz and -- Sire, he hesitates not to undercrank the camera and accelerate the action, nor does he pause before ripping off the shadows of swashbucklers on the castle walls, right out of silent movies with Douglas Fairbanks. The dialog is properly stilted and there are a few slightly surreal lines. Rathbone admonishes the sheriff. "You couldn't catch him if he sat in your lap shooting arrows at a crow!" Who thought THAT up? It's all an intensely hued fairy tale of course, done in gorgeous new three-strip Technicolor. Eric Wolfgang Korngold's score is delightfully bombastic. Historically, by the time the Robin Hood stories became popular, there was little friction between Norman and Saxon. People knew their places. The Normans were on top and ate "pork" (from French), while the Saxons did the farm work and raised "swine" (Germanic). Maid Marion didn't enter the stories until later. Fun, action, and the studio system at its best. Catch it if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnkim
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never seen this film or perhaps are of a certain age and consider this too old for you then you are missing a classic. This film does not desire to be nor is it historically correct. What it is, is simply a wonderful entertainment playing the Robin Hood legend in full. Every character is rich and the adventure you are invited to follow is wonderful. Errol Flynn is at his physical and romantic best. De Havilland is perfect as the demure yet quietly sensual Maid Marion, and as to Basil Rathbone! What a wonderful villain he portrays. Please younger film buffs see this film and enjoy it as it plays. You are in for a real treat and a fantastic adventure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Hood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dane (dane11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I need to tell you, I am a fan of Robin Hood. I read the stories of Robin Hood as a child/young adult. I've watched every Robin Hood movie and TV Show (TV Show's in re-runs, with the exception of When Things Were Rotten). Robin Hood is a character who is worthy of legend. He is a character that few can really compare to. And, after seeing Errol Flynn in green tights and cap, I realized, there would never be another Robin Hood. The Adventures of Robin Hood, from Warner Brothers in glorious Technicolor is a visual masterpiece. From the green forests to the dark, castle of the would-be King, Prince John, the colors and textures really come to life. The excellent direction by Michael Curtiz allows the film to fire on all cylinders. But it is the character of Robin, portrayed by Flynn with a great smile and amazing athleticism that really wins over the viewer. We cannot deny that Flynn's smile will win over the heart of Maid Marian. Nor do we doubt when he casts his smile on his victims that they too would be overwhelmed by his charm and style. Flynn's Robin Hood is not threatening. Flynn's Robin Hood comes across as happy and carefree, fighting for what he believes in. When the time comes for Robin to be serious and fight it out with his enemies, we are equally drawn in, ready to believe that we're watching the greatest hero/anti-hero ever imagined. No hero is complete without a great adversary. For Robin, his enemy has always been the Sheriff of Nottingham, but here we have, Sir Guy of Gisbourne, perfectly portrayed by Basil Rathbone. Naturally, Sir Guy takes his orders from Prince John, the great Claude Rains showing a slightly feminine side of a would-be-king. Prince John's associates are all evil and conniving, the Sheriff of Nottingham is played for laughs by Melville Cooper, allowing Sir Guy to be the really bad guy that hates Robin Hood. There is too much about this movie to like -- Robin's "Merry Men" are robustly and warmly portrayed by Alan Hale, Patrick Knowles and Eugene Palette as Little John, Will Scarlet and Friar Tuck, respectively. The glorious Technicolor vision of Sherwood Forest and the complete cast of characters that includes the Una O'Connor in a fun role as Maid Marian's guardian. There is humor and action and, of course, romance as only old Hollywood could make it. Michael Curtiz deftly moves between humor and action with an amazing style so the view hardly notices the difference. I've watched Douglas Fairbanks, Kevin Costner and Patrick Bergin try their hand at the character, I've watched the old TV series, the Disney cartoon and Mel Brooks satirical "Robin Hood: Men in Tights", right down to Ridley Scott's great retelling of the story with Russel Crowe. None of these compare to Errol Flynn in the Adventures of Robin Hood. Costner was way too wooden to be a true swashbuckler. Bergin was a little too uptight to be interesting. The TV show was... well, it was a 1950's TV show... Even Richard Lester's "Robin and Marian" falls a little short, though Connery is great as an older Robin Hood, complete with a winning, fun-loving smile. Flynn was fun and adventurous. We believe he could split the other archer's arrow. We believe that he could win the heart of Maid Marian and that his men would gladly follow him in to the Lion's den. We cheered for him because he was fun and he looked upon everything with a grin. We believe that he will protect the throne for good King Richard and save all of England, because we see that spark in his eyes telling us nothing is impossible. I'm a huge fan of Robin Hood. If the old stories of Robin Hood did not make me a fan, Errol Flynn did. There will never be another Robin Hood to compare with what Flynn brought to the screen. If you're checking out the Kevin Costner Robin Hood or the Russel Crowe version, take a look at what Flynn did first and you will be amazed by what you see. Allow yourself to go back in time and meet this man who was charming and fun and so full of life that all would gladly follow him. You too will become a fan of Robin Hood -- and probably a fan of Errol Flynn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep, still the best version of the Robin Hood legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For my money, one of the great adventure movies, "The Adventures of Robin Hood" thrills with ease. Errol Flynn is the master swashbuckler in the title role (dude makes it look easy) and he just makes you want to go out and find some bad guys to sword fight. Basil Rathbone and Claude Rains both make for terrific bad guys, while Olivia de Havilland is flat-out gorgeous. The fight scenes are well-choreographed, Korngold's score is grandly stirring, and the whole thing is imbued with Technicolor warmth. Classic! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The glory of Errol Flynn, Olivia deHavilland, & Technicolor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the earlier days of television, on Sunday nights we always had to watch "Walt Disney's Wonderful World Of Color". Well, this isn't a Disney film, but it is a wonderful world of Technicolor! In the restored version now on DVD, the color is stunning. You might say, "And a bit overdone", and you would be correct. But it's still color film to savor. Without any question, Errol Flynn's performance here is one of the most iconic in American film history. He is at his peak, and while he made quite a few fine films after this one, none had the luster of this film. And, this is one of the biggest productions made by Warner Brothers in this era, far different than its typical second class musicals (as compared to MGM) and black-and-white gangster pics. In contrast, Olivia DeHavilland's finest and most notable film performance was still a year away -- "Gone With The Wind". Nevertheless, DeHavilland is ravishingly beautiful here. And, keep in mind that the horse she rides became Trigger shortly after this film was made, when Roy Rogers purchased him. Basil Rathbone, who seemed to usually play villains on the screen (except for his stint as Sherlock Holmes), is excellent here, and was every bit as good as swordsman as depicted; here he plays Sir Guy of Gisbourne. Claude Rains as the evil Prince John who is attempting to usurp his brother's throne, does well, although this is so different than all of his other roles. As always, barrel-bellied Eugene Palette with his husky voice is interesting, here as Friar Tuck. Alan Hale Sr. is simply perfect as Little John, and this is just one of many screen appearances he made as Flynn's "pal". Herbert Mundin is fine as one of the merry men; sadly, at age 40, he was killed just a year later in an auto accident. Melville Cooper and Una O'Connor provide comic relief, the former as the Sheriff of Nottingham, and the latter as a lady in waiting. As far as the story, it, too, is excellent, with a few raised eyebrows. Would Robin Hood have been so dumb to put himself in a situation where he would almost certainly be at a strategic disadvantage and be captured (the archery contest)? I think not. In the deluxe DVD pack now available, there's an excellent documentary about the making of the film, as well as another about the history of Technicolor. Quite fascinating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A merrier Robin than Costner and Crowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When reviewing old movies like 1938's "The Adventures of Robin Hood", the reviewer must decide whether to critique the movie based on the era in which it was released or solely upon one's modern viewing experience. I'm going to largely review this classic version of Robin Hood according to the latter. I do like Errol Flynn in the title roll. He exudes such a joie de vivre ("joy of living") in contrast to Costner's dour performance and Crowe's dead serious approach. Flynn's rendition comes across as a Medieval superhero with superhuman nonchalance and bravery, not to mention fighting skills. One sequence shows Robin Hood taking on a whole castle of armed foes and easily escaping. I have no problem with this -- superheroes are great -- but it does mark the film as more of a Medieval fantasy rather than a quasi-realistic historical picture. Olivia de Havilland is also great as Maid Marion. She has a lovely face and such a winsome spirit. The pompous villains are excellent as well. As for Robin's merry men, they're serviceable. The film is very colorful and energetic, but sometimes the dialogue comes across so rehearsed. The characters speak so quickly and without inflection that it often doesn't even register what they said until a few seconds after they speak. Maybe it's just the way actors delivered their lines back then but, regardless, this'll strike modern viewers as bad filmmaking and acting. One scene is very eye-rolling -- when Marion comes into Robin's camp in Sherwood forest and his merry men start dancing hand-in-hand. Alrighty then. As far as the score goes, I'm sure it was fine for 1938, but for modern listeners it's verging on atrocious. Still, it's surprising how much "The Adventures of Robin Hood" holds up and remains entertaining. It's a great film when you want a pleasant flash from the past. But it doesn't hold a candle to more modern Medieval films, like "Tristan & Isolde" and "Black Death". And Costner and Crowe's more realistic versions are all-around better, even while they're less vibrant. But, again, the 1938 version is great when you're in the mood for a more energetic and colorful viewing experience. The film runs 102 minutes and was shot in California (they do a pretty good job of trying to make Southern California look like England). GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (richard@berrong.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how many times I've watched this movie. Certainly every time I've seen it on TV. As with any great work of art, once you get the plot down pat and don't have to focus on it anymore, you can take a certain distance and start to study the art with which the work was put together. That's where I am with "The Adventures of Robin Hood." Every time I see it, I marvel at some different aspect of its creation, such as the brilliant use of a great film score, or the use of Technicolor. (Yes, modern movies about the Medieval Ages are probably historically more accurate with their drab colors, but "The Adventures of Robin Hood" wasn't aspiring to be a history class film strip.) This evening, as I watched it again, I wondered about the extent to which its plot was meant to be read as commentary on contemporary world politics. It was made in 1938, after all, by which time Hitler had annexed several lands, in particular Austria, and driven many Jews out of Germany. By 1938 Hollywood had become something of a refugee camp for Jewish artists who had fled from Germany and then Austria. To what extent was this story of another invader, the Normans, and their unjust treatment of those whom they conquered, the Saxons, meant to be read as a commentary on what had just happened to Austria in March of 1938?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the child uncredited cast members
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Earl Faneuf
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Edward Earle Marsh was still alive, I met him in Las Vegas. He was an amazing man who was involved with Classical music, Many films (standard and porn) and numerous TV shows. His scrap book was amazing. He told me how he had been one of the small children in the forest when Errol and Olivia were talking. No speaking part. Just one of the children sitting on the ground. I just thought it would be nice to add his name to the cast since no one has done so over the years. I have always loved this film. It is one of my favorites from that time period. I would certainly recommend it to anyone who wants a wonderful family film that is full of great acting, and very well written dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Classic Robin Hood Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Prince John (Claude Rains) and the Norman Lords begin oppressing the Saxon masses in King Richard's absence, a Saxon lord (Errol Flynn) fights back as the outlaw leader of a rebel guerrilla army. I suppose the "modern classic" version of Robin Hood would be the Kevin Costner version, which is a great film in its own right. But the all-time classic Robin Hood is Errol Flynn. Indeed, is Flynn today known for much beyond this role? He easily surpassed Douglas Fairbanks. What makes this film a classic is not only the Technicolor (which shows off some very vibrant and interesting wardrobes), but the wardrobes themselves (which were clearly the inspiration behind "Men and Tights") and the general whimsical nature of the film. Despite being about rebellion and a prince who torments his own people, it has a very upbeat feel to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still fresh 70-odd years on
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films which have iconic value to their young audiences - King Kong, Star Wars, The Matrix all leap to mind. Harryhausen's Jason And The Argonauts was mine, and the classic Errol Flynn The Adventures Of Robin Hood was my Dad's. And I can see why. Looking back at this 1938 film from the distance of 2012, it remains fresh, exciting, good humoured, full of action, bright, zesty and incredibly colourful. I would venture a guess that the use of Technicolor in this film had the same sort of impact on the cinema-going public that the 3D in Avatar did. If I was going to criticise, I would mention that the acting tends to reflect the often hammy style of the time, particularly for the supporting cast, but this is a minor quibble. This film remains as entertaining now as it was in 1938, and it was so entertaining in those days that my Dad saw it 5 times in one day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Historical Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a marvelously engaging flick. Everything seemed to come together in Warner's 1938 colorful story of Robin Hood, the 13th-century legendary outlaw who robbed from the rich only in order to give to the poor. Flynn was at his peak in 1938, terribly handsome without being in the least effete. And he was physically graceful enough to suggest competence in acrobatics and swordplay. Olivia De Havilland as Maid Marion is stunning -- vulnerable, alarmed, brave, sexy. The purity of her features isn't plastered over with an impasto of elaborate make up. Claude Raines is perfect as the sardonic and slimy fratricidal brother. And Basil Rathbone is here in his villainous mode (Mr. Murdstone, etc.), evil and grounded. His swordplay was convincing because he studied the art and became quite good; not competition level but he knew what he was about. Comedy relief is provided by some of the supporting players. William Keighley began directing but his work wasn't considered zippy enough so he was replaced by the redoubtable Michael Curtiz and -- Sire, he hesitates not to undercrank the camera and accelerate the action, nor does he pause before ripping off the shadows of swashbucklers on the castle walls, right out of silent movies with Douglas Fairbanks. The dialog is properly stilted and there are a few slightly surreal lines. Rathbone admonishes the sheriff. "You couldn't catch him if he sat in your lap shooting arrows at a crow!" Who thought THAT up? It's all an intensely hued fairy tale of course, done in gorgeous new three-strip Technicolor. Eric Wolfgang Korngold's score is delightfully bombastic. Historically, by the time the Robin Hood stories became popular, there was little friction between Norman and Saxon. People knew their places. The Normans were on top and ate "pork" (from French), while the Saxons did the farm work and raised "swine" (Germanic). Maid Marion didn't enter the stories until later. Fun, action, and the studio system at its best. Catch it if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnkim
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never seen this film or perhaps are of a certain age and consider this too old for you then you are missing a classic. This film does not desire to be nor is it historically correct. What it is, is simply a wonderful entertainment playing the Robin Hood legend in full. Every character is rich and the adventure you are invited to follow is wonderful. Errol Flynn is at his physical and romantic best. De Havilland is perfect as the demure yet quietly sensual Maid Marion, and as to Basil Rathbone! What a wonderful villain he portrays. Please younger film buffs see this film and enjoy it as it plays. You are in for a real treat and a fantastic adventure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Hood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dane (dane11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I need to tell you, I am a fan of Robin Hood. I read the stories of Robin Hood as a child/young adult. I've watched every Robin Hood movie and TV Show (TV Show's in re-runs, with the exception of When Things Were Rotten). Robin Hood is a character who is worthy of legend. He is a character that few can really compare to. And, after seeing Errol Flynn in green tights and cap, I realized, there would never be another Robin Hood. The Adventures of Robin Hood, from Warner Brothers in glorious Technicolor is a visual masterpiece. From the green forests to the dark, castle of the would-be King, Prince John, the colors and textures really come to life. The excellent direction by Michael Curtiz allows the film to fire on all cylinders. But it is the character of Robin, portrayed by Flynn with a great smile and amazing athleticism that really wins over the viewer. We cannot deny that Flynn's smile will win over the heart of Maid Marian. Nor do we doubt when he casts his smile on his victims that they too would be overwhelmed by his charm and style. Flynn's Robin Hood is not threatening. Flynn's Robin Hood comes across as happy and carefree, fighting for what he believes in. When the time comes for Robin to be serious and fight it out with his enemies, we are equally drawn in, ready to believe that we're watching the greatest hero/anti-hero ever imagined. No hero is complete without a great adversary. For Robin, his enemy has always been the Sheriff of Nottingham, but here we have, Sir Guy of Gisbourne, perfectly portrayed by Basil Rathbone. Naturally, Sir Guy takes his orders from Prince John, the great Claude Rains showing a slightly feminine side of a would-be-king. Prince John's associates are all evil and conniving, the Sheriff of Nottingham is played for laughs by Melville Cooper, allowing Sir Guy to be the really bad guy that hates Robin Hood. There is too much about this movie to like -- Robin's "Merry Men" are robustly and warmly portrayed by Alan Hale, Patrick Knowles and Eugene Palette as Little John, Will Scarlet and Friar Tuck, respectively. The glorious Technicolor vision of Sherwood Forest and the complete cast of characters that includes the Una O'Connor in a fun role as Maid Marian's guardian. There is humor and action and, of course, romance as only old Hollywood could make it. Michael Curtiz deftly moves between humor and action with an amazing style so the view hardly notices the difference. I've watched Douglas Fairbanks, Kevin Costner and Patrick Bergin try their hand at the character, I've watched the old TV series, the Disney cartoon and Mel Brooks satirical "Robin Hood: Men in Tights", right down to Ridley Scott's great retelling of the story with Russel Crowe. None of these compare to Errol Flynn in the Adventures of Robin Hood. Costner was way too wooden to be a true swashbuckler. Bergin was a little too uptight to be interesting. The TV show was... well, it was a 1950's TV show... Even Richard Lester's "Robin and Marian" falls a little short, though Connery is great as an older Robin Hood, complete with a winning, fun-loving smile. Flynn was fun and adventurous. We believe he could split the other archer's arrow. We believe that he could win the heart of Maid Marian and that his men would gladly follow him in to the Lion's den. We cheered for him because he was fun and he looked upon everything with a grin. We believe that he will protect the throne for good King Richard and save all of England, because we see that spark in his eyes telling us nothing is impossible. I'm a huge fan of Robin Hood. If the old stories of Robin Hood did not make me a fan, Errol Flynn did. There will never be another Robin Hood to compare with what Flynn brought to the screen. If you're checking out the Kevin Costner Robin Hood or the Russel Crowe version, take a look at what Flynn did first and you will be amazed by what you see. Allow yourself to go back in time and meet this man who was charming and fun and so full of life that all would gladly follow him. You too will become a fan of Robin Hood -- and probably a fan of Errol Flynn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep, still the best version of the Robin Hood legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For my money, one of the great adventure movies, "The Adventures of Robin Hood" thrills with ease. Errol Flynn is the master swashbuckler in the title role (dude makes it look easy) and he just makes you want to go out and find some bad guys to sword fight. Basil Rathbone and Claude Rains both make for terrific bad guys, while Olivia de Havilland is flat-out gorgeous. The fight scenes are well-choreographed, Korngold's score is grandly stirring, and the whole thing is imbued with Technicolor warmth. Classic! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The glory of Errol Flynn, Olivia deHavilland, & Technicolor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the earlier days of television, on Sunday nights we always had to watch "Walt Disney's Wonderful World Of Color". Well, this isn't a Disney film, but it is a wonderful world of Technicolor! In the restored version now on DVD, the color is stunning. You might say, "And a bit overdone", and you would be correct. But it's still color film to savor. Without any question, Errol Flynn's performance here is one of the most iconic in American film history. He is at his peak, and while he made quite a few fine films after this one, none had the luster of this film. And, this is one of the biggest productions made by Warner Brothers in this era, far different than its typical second class musicals (as compared to MGM) and black-and-white gangster pics. In contrast, Olivia DeHavilland's finest and most notable film performance was still a year away -- "Gone With The Wind". Nevertheless, DeHavilland is ravishingly beautiful here. And, keep in mind that the horse she rides became Trigger shortly after this film was made, when Roy Rogers purchased him. Basil Rathbone, who seemed to usually play villains on the screen (except for his stint as Sherlock Holmes), is excellent here, and was every bit as good as swordsman as depicted; here he plays Sir Guy of Gisbourne. Claude Rains as the evil Prince John who is attempting to usurp his brother's throne, does well, although this is so different than all of his other roles. As always, barrel-bellied Eugene Palette with his husky voice is interesting, here as Friar Tuck. Alan Hale Sr. is simply perfect as Little John, and this is just one of many screen appearances he made as Flynn's "pal". Herbert Mundin is fine as one of the merry men; sadly, at age 40, he was killed just a year later in an auto accident. Melville Cooper and Una O'Connor provide comic relief, the former as the Sheriff of Nottingham, and the latter as a lady in waiting. As far as the story, it, too, is excellent, with a few raised eyebrows. Would Robin Hood have been so dumb to put himself in a situation where he would almost certainly be at a strategic disadvantage and be captured (the archery contest)? I think not. In the deluxe DVD pack now available, there's an excellent documentary about the making of the film, as well as another about the history of Technicolor. Quite fascinating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A merrier Robin than Costner and Crowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When reviewing old movies like 1938's "The Adventures of Robin Hood", the reviewer must decide whether to critique the movie based on the era in which it was released or solely upon one's modern viewing experience. I'm going to largely review this classic version of Robin Hood according to the latter. I do like Errol Flynn in the title roll. He exudes such a joie de vivre ("joy of living") in contrast to Costner's dour performance and Crowe's dead serious approach. Flynn's rendition comes across as a Medieval superhero with superhuman nonchalance and bravery, not to mention fighting skills. One sequence shows Robin Hood taking on a whole castle of armed foes and easily escaping. I have no problem with this -- superheroes are great -- but it does mark the film as more of a Medieval fantasy rather than a quasi-realistic historical picture. Olivia de Havilland is also great as Maid Marion. She has a lovely face and such a winsome spirit. The pompous villains are excellent as well. As for Robin's merry men, they're serviceable. The film is very colorful and energetic, but sometimes the dialogue comes across so rehearsed. The characters speak so quickly and without inflection that it often doesn't even register what they said until a few seconds after they speak. Maybe it's just the way actors delivered their lines back then but, regardless, this'll strike modern viewers as bad filmmaking and acting. One scene is very eye-rolling -- when Marion comes into Robin's camp in Sherwood forest and his merry men start dancing hand-in-hand. Alrighty then. As far as the score goes, I'm sure it was fine for 1938, but for modern listeners it's verging on atrocious. Still, it's surprising how much "The Adventures of Robin Hood" holds up and remains entertaining. It's a great film when you want a pleasant flash from the past. But it doesn't hold a candle to more modern Medieval films, like "Tristan & Isolde" and "Black Death". And Costner and Crowe's more realistic versions are all-around better, even while they're less vibrant. But, again, the 1938 version is great when you're in the mood for a more energetic and colorful viewing experience. The film runs 102 minutes and was shot in California (they do a pretty good job of trying to make Southern California look like England). GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (richard@berrong.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how many times I've watched this movie. Certainly every time I've seen it on TV. As with any great work of art, once you get the plot down pat and don't have to focus on it anymore, you can take a certain distance and start to study the art with which the work was put together. That's where I am with "The Adventures of Robin Hood." Every time I see it, I marvel at some different aspect of its creation, such as the brilliant use of a great film score, or the use of Technicolor. (Yes, modern movies about the Medieval Ages are probably historically more accurate with their drab colors, but "The Adventures of Robin Hood" wasn't aspiring to be a history class film strip.) This evening, as I watched it again, I wondered about the extent to which its plot was meant to be read as commentary on contemporary world politics. It was made in 1938, after all, by which time Hitler had annexed several lands, in particular Austria, and driven many Jews out of Germany. By 1938 Hollywood had become something of a refugee camp for Jewish artists who had fled from Germany and then Austria. To what extent was this story of another invader, the Normans, and their unjust treatment of those whom they conquered, the Saxons, meant to be read as a commentary on what had just happened to Austria in March of 1938?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the child uncredited cast members
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Earl Faneuf
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Edward Earle Marsh was still alive, I met him in Las Vegas. He was an amazing man who was involved with Classical music, Many films (standard and porn) and numerous TV shows. His scrap book was amazing. He told me how he had been one of the small children in the forest when Errol and Olivia were talking. No speaking part. Just one of the children sitting on the ground. I just thought it would be nice to add his name to the cast since no one has done so over the years. I have always loved this film. It is one of my favorites from that time period. I would certainly recommend it to anyone who wants a wonderful family film that is full of great acting, and very well written dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Classic Robin Hood Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Prince John (Claude Rains) and the Norman Lords begin oppressing the Saxon masses in King Richard's absence, a Saxon lord (Errol Flynn) fights back as the outlaw leader of a rebel guerrilla army. I suppose the "modern classic" version of Robin Hood would be the Kevin Costner version, which is a great film in its own right. But the all-time classic Robin Hood is Errol Flynn. Indeed, is Flynn today known for much beyond this role? He easily surpassed Douglas Fairbanks. What makes this film a classic is not only the Technicolor (which shows off some very vibrant and interesting wardrobes), but the wardrobes themselves (which were clearly the inspiration behind "Men and Tights") and the general whimsical nature of the film. Despite being about rebellion and a prince who torments his own people, it has a very upbeat feel to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still fresh 70-odd years on
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films which have iconic value to their young audiences - King Kong, Star Wars, The Matrix all leap to mind. Harryhausen's Jason And The Argonauts was mine, and the classic Errol Flynn The Adventures Of Robin Hood was my Dad's. And I can see why. Looking back at this 1938 film from the distance of 2012, it remains fresh, exciting, good humoured, full of action, bright, zesty and incredibly colourful. I would venture a guess that the use of Technicolor in this film had the same sort of impact on the cinema-going public that the 3D in Avatar did. If I was going to criticise, I would mention that the acting tends to reflect the often hammy style of the time, particularly for the supporting cast, but this is a minor quibble. This film remains as entertaining now as it was in 1938, and it was so entertaining in those days that my Dad saw it 5 times in one day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Historical Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a marvelously engaging flick. Everything seemed to come together in Warner's 1938 colorful story of Robin Hood, the 13th-century legendary outlaw who robbed from the rich only in order to give to the poor. Flynn was at his peak in 1938, terribly handsome without being in the least effete. And he was physically graceful enough to suggest competence in acrobatics and swordplay. Olivia De Havilland as Maid Marion is stunning -- vulnerable, alarmed, brave, sexy. The purity of her features isn't plastered over with an impasto of elaborate make up. Claude Raines is perfect as the sardonic and slimy fratricidal brother. And Basil Rathbone is here in his villainous mode (Mr. Murdstone, etc.), evil and grounded. His swordplay was convincing because he studied the art and became quite good; not competition level but he knew what he was about. Comedy relief is provided by some of the supporting players. William Keighley began directing but his work wasn't considered zippy enough so he was replaced by the redoubtable Michael Curtiz and -- Sire, he hesitates not to undercrank the camera and accelerate the action, nor does he pause before ripping off the shadows of swashbucklers on the castle walls, right out of silent movies with Douglas Fairbanks. The dialog is properly stilted and there are a few slightly surreal lines. Rathbone admonishes the sheriff. "You couldn't catch him if he sat in your lap shooting arrows at a crow!" Who thought THAT up? It's all an intensely hued fairy tale of course, done in gorgeous new three-strip Technicolor. Eric Wolfgang Korngold's score is delightfully bombastic. Historically, by the time the Robin Hood stories became popular, there was little friction between Norman and Saxon. People knew their places. The Normans were on top and ate "pork" (from French), while the Saxons did the farm work and raised "swine" (Germanic). Maid Marion didn't enter the stories until later. Fun, action, and the studio system at its best. Catch it if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnkim
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never seen this film or perhaps are of a certain age and consider this too old for you then you are missing a classic. This film does not desire to be nor is it historically correct. What it is, is simply a wonderful entertainment playing the Robin Hood legend in full. Every character is rich and the adventure you are invited to follow is wonderful. Errol Flynn is at his physical and romantic best. De Havilland is perfect as the demure yet quietly sensual Maid Marion, and as to Basil Rathbone! What a wonderful villain he portrays. Please younger film buffs see this film and enjoy it as it plays. You are in for a real treat and a fantastic adventure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Hood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dane (dane11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I need to tell you, I am a fan of Robin Hood. I read the stories of Robin Hood as a child/young adult. I've watched every Robin Hood movie and TV Show (TV Show's in re-runs, with the exception of When Things Were Rotten). Robin Hood is a character who is worthy of legend. He is a character that few can really compare to. And, after seeing Errol Flynn in green tights and cap, I realized, there would never be another Robin Hood. The Adventures of Robin Hood, from Warner Brothers in glorious Technicolor is a visual masterpiece. From the green forests to the dark, castle of the would-be King, Prince John, the colors and textures really come to life. The excellent direction by Michael Curtiz allows the film to fire on all cylinders. But it is the character of Robin, portrayed by Flynn with a great smile and amazing athleticism that really wins over the viewer. We cannot deny that Flynn's smile will win over the heart of Maid Marian. Nor do we doubt when he casts his smile on his victims that they too would be overwhelmed by his charm and style. Flynn's Robin Hood is not threatening. Flynn's Robin Hood comes across as happy and carefree, fighting for what he believes in. When the time comes for Robin to be serious and fight it out with his enemies, we are equally drawn in, ready to believe that we're watching the greatest hero/anti-hero ever imagined. No hero is complete without a great adversary. For Robin, his enemy has always been the Sheriff of Nottingham, but here we have, Sir Guy of Gisbourne, perfectly portrayed by Basil Rathbone. Naturally, Sir Guy takes his orders from Prince John, the great Claude Rains showing a slightly feminine side of a would-be-king. Prince John's associates are all evil and conniving, the Sheriff of Nottingham is played for laughs by Melville Cooper, allowing Sir Guy to be the really bad guy that hates Robin Hood. There is too much about this movie to like -- Robin's "Merry Men" are robustly and warmly portrayed by Alan Hale, Patrick Knowles and Eugene Palette as Little John, Will Scarlet and Friar Tuck, respectively. The glorious Technicolor vision of Sherwood Forest and the complete cast of characters that includes the Una O'Connor in a fun role as Maid Marian's guardian. There is humor and action and, of course, romance as only old Hollywood could make it. Michael Curtiz deftly moves between humor and action with an amazing style so the view hardly notices the difference. I've watched Douglas Fairbanks, Kevin Costner and Patrick Bergin try their hand at the character, I've watched the old TV series, the Disney cartoon and Mel Brooks satirical "Robin Hood: Men in Tights", right down to Ridley Scott's great retelling of the story with Russel Crowe. None of these compare to Errol Flynn in the Adventures of Robin Hood. Costner was way too wooden to be a true swashbuckler. Bergin was a little too uptight to be interesting. The TV show was... well, it was a 1950's TV show... Even Richard Lester's "Robin and Marian" falls a little short, though Connery is great as an older Robin Hood, complete with a winning, fun-loving smile. Flynn was fun and adventurous. We believe he could split the other archer's arrow. We believe that he could win the heart of Maid Marian and that his men would gladly follow him in to the Lion's den. We cheered for him because he was fun and he looked upon everything with a grin. We believe that he will protect the throne for good King Richard and save all of England, because we see that spark in his eyes telling us nothing is impossible. I'm a huge fan of Robin Hood. If the old stories of Robin Hood did not make me a fan, Errol Flynn did. There will never be another Robin Hood to compare with what Flynn brought to the screen. If you're checking out the Kevin Costner Robin Hood or the Russel Crowe version, take a look at what Flynn did first and you will be amazed by what you see. Allow yourself to go back in time and meet this man who was charming and fun and so full of life that all would gladly follow him. You too will become a fan of Robin Hood -- and probably a fan of Errol Flynn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep, still the best version of the Robin Hood legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For my money, one of the great adventure movies, "The Adventures of Robin Hood" thrills with ease. Errol Flynn is the master swashbuckler in the title role (dude makes it look easy) and he just makes you want to go out and find some bad guys to sword fight. Basil Rathbone and Claude Rains both make for terrific bad guys, while Olivia de Havilland is flat-out gorgeous. The fight scenes are well-choreographed, Korngold's score is grandly stirring, and the whole thing is imbued with Technicolor warmth. Classic! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The glory of Errol Flynn, Olivia deHavilland, & Technicolor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the earlier days of television, on Sunday nights we always had to watch "Walt Disney's Wonderful World Of Color". Well, this isn't a Disney film, but it is a wonderful world of Technicolor! In the restored version now on DVD, the color is stunning. You might say, "And a bit overdone", and you would be correct. But it's still color film to savor. Without any question, Errol Flynn's performance here is one of the most iconic in American film history. He is at his peak, and while he made quite a few fine films after this one, none had the luster of this film. And, this is one of the biggest productions made by Warner Brothers in this era, far different than its typical second class musicals (as compared to MGM) and black-and-white gangster pics. In contrast, Olivia DeHavilland's finest and most notable film performance was still a year away -- "Gone With The Wind". Nevertheless, DeHavilland is ravishingly beautiful here. And, keep in mind that the horse she rides became Trigger shortly after this film was made, when Roy Rogers purchased him. Basil Rathbone, who seemed to usually play villains on the screen (except for his stint as Sherlock Holmes), is excellent here, and was every bit as good as swordsman as depicted; here he plays Sir Guy of Gisbourne. Claude Rains as the evil Prince John who is attempting to usurp his brother's throne, does well, although this is so different than all of his other roles. As always, barrel-bellied Eugene Palette with his husky voice is interesting, here as Friar Tuck. Alan Hale Sr. is simply perfect as Little John, and this is just one of many screen appearances he made as Flynn's "pal". Herbert Mundin is fine as one of the merry men; sadly, at age 40, he was killed just a year later in an auto accident. Melville Cooper and Una O'Connor provide comic relief, the former as the Sheriff of Nottingham, and the latter as a lady in waiting. As far as the story, it, too, is excellent, with a few raised eyebrows. Would Robin Hood have been so dumb to put himself in a situation where he would almost certainly be at a strategic disadvantage and be captured (the archery contest)? I think not. In the deluxe DVD pack now available, there's an excellent documentary about the making of the film, as well as another about the history of Technicolor. Quite fascinating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A merrier Robin than Costner and Crowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When reviewing old movies like 1938's "The Adventures of Robin Hood", the reviewer must decide whether to critique the movie based on the era in which it was released or solely upon one's modern viewing experience. I'm going to largely review this classic version of Robin Hood according to the latter. I do like Errol Flynn in the title roll. He exudes such a joie de vivre ("joy of living") in contrast to Costner's dour performance and Crowe's dead serious approach. Flynn's rendition comes across as a Medieval superhero with superhuman nonchalance and bravery, not to mention fighting skills. One sequence shows Robin Hood taking on a whole castle of armed foes and easily escaping. I have no problem with this -- superheroes are great -- but it does mark the film as more of a Medieval fantasy rather than a quasi-realistic historical picture. Olivia de Havilland is also great as Maid Marion. She has a lovely face and such a winsome spirit. The pompous villains are excellent as well. As for Robin's merry men, they're serviceable. The film is very colorful and energetic, but sometimes the dialogue comes across so rehearsed. The characters speak so quickly and without inflection that it often doesn't even register what they said until a few seconds after they speak. Maybe it's just the way actors delivered their lines back then but, regardless, this'll strike modern viewers as bad filmmaking and acting. One scene is very eye-rolling -- when Marion comes into Robin's camp in Sherwood forest and his merry men start dancing hand-in-hand. Alrighty then. As far as the score goes, I'm sure it was fine for 1938, but for modern listeners it's verging on atrocious. Still, it's surprising how much "The Adventures of Robin Hood" holds up and remains entertaining. It's a great film when you want a pleasant flash from the past. But it doesn't hold a candle to more modern Medieval films, like "Tristan & Isolde" and "Black Death". And Costner and Crowe's more realistic versions are all-around better, even while they're less vibrant. But, again, the 1938 version is great when you're in the mood for a more energetic and colorful viewing experience. The film runs 102 minutes and was shot in California (they do a pretty good job of trying to make Southern California look like England). GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (richard@berrong.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how many times I've watched this movie. Certainly every time I've seen it on TV. As with any great work of art, once you get the plot down pat and don't have to focus on it anymore, you can take a certain distance and start to study the art with which the work was put together. That's where I am with "The Adventures of Robin Hood." Every time I see it, I marvel at some different aspect of its creation, such as the brilliant use of a great film score, or the use of Technicolor. (Yes, modern movies about the Medieval Ages are probably historically more accurate with their drab colors, but "The Adventures of Robin Hood" wasn't aspiring to be a history class film strip.) This evening, as I watched it again, I wondered about the extent to which its plot was meant to be read as commentary on contemporary world politics. It was made in 1938, after all, by which time Hitler had annexed several lands, in particular Austria, and driven many Jews out of Germany. By 1938 Hollywood had become something of a refugee camp for Jewish artists who had fled from Germany and then Austria. To what extent was this story of another invader, the Normans, and their unjust treatment of those whom they conquered, the Saxons, meant to be read as a commentary on what had just happened to Austria in March of 1938?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the child uncredited cast members
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Earl Faneuf
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Edward Earle Marsh was still alive, I met him in Las Vegas. He was an amazing man who was involved with Classical music, Many films (standard and porn) and numerous TV shows. His scrap book was amazing. He told me how he had been one of the small children in the forest when Errol and Olivia were talking. No speaking part. Just one of the children sitting on the ground. I just thought it would be nice to add his name to the cast since no one has done so over the years. I have always loved this film. It is one of my favorites from that time period. I would certainly recommend it to anyone who wants a wonderful family film that is full of great acting, and very well written dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Classic Robin Hood Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Prince John (Claude Rains) and the Norman Lords begin oppressing the Saxon masses in King Richard's absence, a Saxon lord (Errol Flynn) fights back as the outlaw leader of a rebel guerrilla army. I suppose the "modern classic" version of Robin Hood would be the Kevin Costner version, which is a great film in its own right. But the all-time classic Robin Hood is Errol Flynn. Indeed, is Flynn today known for much beyond this role? He easily surpassed Douglas Fairbanks. What makes this film a classic is not only the Technicolor (which shows off some very vibrant and interesting wardrobes), but the wardrobes themselves (which were clearly the inspiration behind "Men and Tights") and the general whimsical nature of the film. Despite being about rebellion and a prince who torments his own people, it has a very upbeat feel to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still fresh 70-odd years on
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films which have iconic value to their young audiences - King Kong, Star Wars, The Matrix all leap to mind. Harryhausen's Jason And The Argonauts was mine, and the classic Errol Flynn The Adventures Of Robin Hood was my Dad's. And I can see why. Looking back at this 1938 film from the distance of 2012, it remains fresh, exciting, good humoured, full of action, bright, zesty and incredibly colourful. I would venture a guess that the use of Technicolor in this film had the same sort of impact on the cinema-going public that the 3D in Avatar did. If I was going to criticise, I would mention that the acting tends to reflect the often hammy style of the time, particularly for the supporting cast, but this is a minor quibble. This film remains as entertaining now as it was in 1938, and it was so entertaining in those days that my Dad saw it 5 times in one day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Historical Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a marvelously engaging flick. Everything seemed to come together in Warner's 1938 colorful story of Robin Hood, the 13th-century legendary outlaw who robbed from the rich only in order to give to the poor. Flynn was at his peak in 1938, terribly handsome without being in the least effete. And he was physically graceful enough to suggest competence in acrobatics and swordplay. Olivia De Havilland as Maid Marion is stunning -- vulnerable, alarmed, brave, sexy. The purity of her features isn't plastered over with an impasto of elaborate make up. Claude Raines is perfect as the sardonic and slimy fratricidal brother. And Basil Rathbone is here in his villainous mode (Mr. Murdstone, etc.), evil and grounded. His swordplay was convincing because he studied the art and became quite good; not competition level but he knew what he was about. Comedy relief is provided by some of the supporting players. William Keighley began directing but his work wasn't considered zippy enough so he was replaced by the redoubtable Michael Curtiz and -- Sire, he hesitates not to undercrank the camera and accelerate the action, nor does he pause before ripping off the shadows of swashbucklers on the castle walls, right out of silent movies with Douglas Fairbanks. The dialog is properly stilted and there are a few slightly surreal lines. Rathbone admonishes the sheriff. "You couldn't catch him if he sat in your lap shooting arrows at a crow!" Who thought THAT up? It's all an intensely hued fairy tale of course, done in gorgeous new three-strip Technicolor. Eric Wolfgang Korngold's score is delightfully bombastic. Historically, by the time the Robin Hood stories became popular, there was little friction between Norman and Saxon. People knew their places. The Normans were on top and ate "pork" (from French), while the Saxons did the farm work and raised "swine" (Germanic). Maid Marion didn't enter the stories until later. Fun, action, and the studio system at its best. Catch it if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnkim
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never seen this film or perhaps are of a certain age and consider this too old for you then you are missing a classic. This film does not desire to be nor is it historically correct. What it is, is simply a wonderful entertainment playing the Robin Hood legend in full. Every character is rich and the adventure you are invited to follow is wonderful. Errol Flynn is at his physical and romantic best. De Havilland is perfect as the demure yet quietly sensual Maid Marion, and as to Basil Rathbone! What a wonderful villain he portrays. Please younger film buffs see this film and enjoy it as it plays. You are in for a real treat and a fantastic adventure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Hood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dane (dane11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I need to tell you, I am a fan of Robin Hood. I read the stories of Robin Hood as a child/young adult. I've watched every Robin Hood movie and TV Show (TV Show's in re-runs, with the exception of When Things Were Rotten). Robin Hood is a character who is worthy of legend. He is a character that few can really compare to. And, after seeing Errol Flynn in green tights and cap, I realized, there would never be another Robin Hood. The Adventures of Robin Hood, from Warner Brothers in glorious Technicolor is a visual masterpiece. From the green forests to the dark, castle of the would-be King, Prince John, the colors and textures really come to life. The excellent direction by Michael Curtiz allows the film to fire on all cylinders. But it is the character of Robin, portrayed by Flynn with a great smile and amazing athleticism that really wins over the viewer. We cannot deny that Flynn's smile will win over the heart of Maid Marian. Nor do we doubt when he casts his smile on his victims that they too would be overwhelmed by his charm and style. Flynn's Robin Hood is not threatening. Flynn's Robin Hood comes across as happy and carefree, fighting for what he believes in. When the time comes for Robin to be serious and fight it out with his enemies, we are equally drawn in, ready to believe that we're watching the greatest hero/anti-hero ever imagined. No hero is complete without a great adversary. For Robin, his enemy has always been the Sheriff of Nottingham, but here we have, Sir Guy of Gisbourne, perfectly portrayed by Basil Rathbone. Naturally, Sir Guy takes his orders from Prince John, the great Claude Rains showing a slightly feminine side of a would-be-king. Prince John's associates are all evil and conniving, the Sheriff of Nottingham is played for laughs by Melville Cooper, allowing Sir Guy to be the really bad guy that hates Robin Hood. There is too much about this movie to like -- Robin's "Merry Men" are robustly and warmly portrayed by Alan Hale, Patrick Knowles and Eugene Palette as Little John, Will Scarlet and Friar Tuck, respectively. The glorious Technicolor vision of Sherwood Forest and the complete cast of characters that includes the Una O'Connor in a fun role as Maid Marian's guardian. There is humor and action and, of course, romance as only old Hollywood could make it. Michael Curtiz deftly moves between humor and action with an amazing style so the view hardly notices the difference. I've watched Douglas Fairbanks, Kevin Costner and Patrick Bergin try their hand at the character, I've watched the old TV series, the Disney cartoon and Mel Brooks satirical "Robin Hood: Men in Tights", right down to Ridley Scott's great retelling of the story with Russel Crowe. None of these compare to Errol Flynn in the Adventures of Robin Hood. Costner was way too wooden to be a true swashbuckler. Bergin was a little too uptight to be interesting. The TV show was... well, it was a 1950's TV show... Even Richard Lester's "Robin and Marian" falls a little short, though Connery is great as an older Robin Hood, complete with a winning, fun-loving smile. Flynn was fun and adventurous. We believe he could split the other archer's arrow. We believe that he could win the heart of Maid Marian and that his men would gladly follow him in to the Lion's den. We cheered for him because he was fun and he looked upon everything with a grin. We believe that he will protect the throne for good King Richard and save all of England, because we see that spark in his eyes telling us nothing is impossible. I'm a huge fan of Robin Hood. If the old stories of Robin Hood did not make me a fan, Errol Flynn did. There will never be another Robin Hood to compare with what Flynn brought to the screen. If you're checking out the Kevin Costner Robin Hood or the Russel Crowe version, take a look at what Flynn did first and you will be amazed by what you see. Allow yourself to go back in time and meet this man who was charming and fun and so full of life that all would gladly follow him. You too will become a fan of Robin Hood -- and probably a fan of Errol Flynn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep, still the best version of the Robin Hood legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For my money, one of the great adventure movies, "The Adventures of Robin Hood" thrills with ease. Errol Flynn is the master swashbuckler in the title role (dude makes it look easy) and he just makes you want to go out and find some bad guys to sword fight. Basil Rathbone and Claude Rains both make for terrific bad guys, while Olivia de Havilland is flat-out gorgeous. The fight scenes are well-choreographed, Korngold's score is grandly stirring, and the whole thing is imbued with Technicolor warmth. Classic! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The glory of Errol Flynn, Olivia deHavilland, & Technicolor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the earlier days of television, on Sunday nights we always had to watch "Walt Disney's Wonderful World Of Color". Well, this isn't a Disney film, but it is a wonderful world of Technicolor! In the restored version now on DVD, the color is stunning. You might say, "And a bit overdone", and you would be correct. But it's still color film to savor. Without any question, Errol Flynn's performance here is one of the most iconic in American film history. He is at his peak, and while he made quite a few fine films after this one, none had the luster of this film. And, this is one of the biggest productions made by Warner Brothers in this era, far different than its typical second class musicals (as compared to MGM) and black-and-white gangster pics. In contrast, Olivia DeHavilland's finest and most notable film performance was still a year away -- "Gone With The Wind". Nevertheless, DeHavilland is ravishingly beautiful here. And, keep in mind that the horse she rides became Trigger shortly after this film was made, when Roy Rogers purchased him. Basil Rathbone, who seemed to usually play villains on the screen (except for his stint as Sherlock Holmes), is excellent here, and was every bit as good as swordsman as depicted; here he plays Sir Guy of Gisbourne. Claude Rains as the evil Prince John who is attempting to usurp his brother's throne, does well, although this is so different than all of his other roles. As always, barrel-bellied Eugene Palette with his husky voice is interesting, here as Friar Tuck. Alan Hale Sr. is simply perfect as Little John, and this is just one of many screen appearances he made as Flynn's "pal". Herbert Mundin is fine as one of the merry men; sadly, at age 40, he was killed just a year later in an auto accident. Melville Cooper and Una O'Connor provide comic relief, the former as the Sheriff of Nottingham, and the latter as a lady in waiting. As far as the story, it, too, is excellent, with a few raised eyebrows. Would Robin Hood have been so dumb to put himself in a situation where he would almost certainly be at a strategic disadvantage and be captured (the archery contest)? I think not. In the deluxe DVD pack now available, there's an excellent documentary about the making of the film, as well as another about the history of Technicolor. Quite fascinating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A merrier Robin than Costner and Crowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When reviewing old movies like 1938's "The Adventures of Robin Hood", the reviewer must decide whether to critique the movie based on the era in which it was released or solely upon one's modern viewing experience. I'm going to largely review this classic version of Robin Hood according to the latter. I do like Errol Flynn in the title roll. He exudes such a joie de vivre ("joy of living") in contrast to Costner's dour performance and Crowe's dead serious approach. Flynn's rendition comes across as a Medieval superhero with superhuman nonchalance and bravery, not to mention fighting skills. One sequence shows Robin Hood taking on a whole castle of armed foes and easily escaping. I have no problem with this -- superheroes are great -- but it does mark the film as more of a Medieval fantasy rather than a quasi-realistic historical picture. Olivia de Havilland is also great as Maid Marion. She has a lovely face and such a winsome spirit. The pompous villains are excellent as well. As for Robin's merry men, they're serviceable. The film is very colorful and energetic, but sometimes the dialogue comes across so rehearsed. The characters speak so quickly and without inflection that it often doesn't even register what they said until a few seconds after they speak. Maybe it's just the way actors delivered their lines back then but, regardless, this'll strike modern viewers as bad filmmaking and acting. One scene is very eye-rolling -- when Marion comes into Robin's camp in Sherwood forest and his merry men start dancing hand-in-hand. Alrighty then. As far as the score goes, I'm sure it was fine for 1938, but for modern listeners it's verging on atrocious. Still, it's surprising how much "The Adventures of Robin Hood" holds up and remains entertaining. It's a great film when you want a pleasant flash from the past. But it doesn't hold a candle to more modern Medieval films, like "Tristan & Isolde" and "Black Death". And Costner and Crowe's more realistic versions are all-around better, even while they're less vibrant. But, again, the 1938 version is great when you're in the mood for a more energetic and colorful viewing experience. The film runs 102 minutes and was shot in California (they do a pretty good job of trying to make Southern California look like England). GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (richard@berrong.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how many times I've watched this movie. Certainly every time I've seen it on TV. As with any great work of art, once you get the plot down pat and don't have to focus on it anymore, you can take a certain distance and start to study the art with which the work was put together. That's where I am with "The Adventures of Robin Hood." Every time I see it, I marvel at some different aspect of its creation, such as the brilliant use of a great film score, or the use of Technicolor. (Yes, modern movies about the Medieval Ages are probably historically more accurate with their drab colors, but "The Adventures of Robin Hood" wasn't aspiring to be a history class film strip.) This evening, as I watched it again, I wondered about the extent to which its plot was meant to be read as commentary on contemporary world politics. It was made in 1938, after all, by which time Hitler had annexed several lands, in particular Austria, and driven many Jews out of Germany. By 1938 Hollywood had become something of a refugee camp for Jewish artists who had fled from Germany and then Austria. To what extent was this story of another invader, the Normans, and their unjust treatment of those whom they conquered, the Saxons, meant to be read as a commentary on what had just happened to Austria in March of 1938?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the child uncredited cast members
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Earl Faneuf
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Edward Earle Marsh was still alive, I met him in Las Vegas. He was an amazing man who was involved with Classical music, Many films (standard and porn) and numerous TV shows. His scrap book was amazing. He told me how he had been one of the small children in the forest when Errol and Olivia were talking. No speaking part. Just one of the children sitting on the ground. I just thought it would be nice to add his name to the cast since no one has done so over the years. I have always loved this film. It is one of my favorites from that time period. I would certainly recommend it to anyone who wants a wonderful family film that is full of great acting, and very well written dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Classic Robin Hood Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Prince John (Claude Rains) and the Norman Lords begin oppressing the Saxon masses in King Richard's absence, a Saxon lord (Errol Flynn) fights back as the outlaw leader of a rebel guerrilla army. I suppose the "modern classic" version of Robin Hood would be the Kevin Costner version, which is a great film in its own right. But the all-time classic Robin Hood is Errol Flynn. Indeed, is Flynn today known for much beyond this role? He easily surpassed Douglas Fairbanks. What makes this film a classic is not only the Technicolor (which shows off some very vibrant and interesting wardrobes), but the wardrobes themselves (which were clearly the inspiration behind "Men and Tights") and the general whimsical nature of the film. Despite being about rebellion and a prince who torments his own people, it has a very upbeat feel to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still fresh 70-odd years on
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films which have iconic value to their young audiences - King Kong, Star Wars, The Matrix all leap to mind. Harryhausen's Jason And The Argonauts was mine, and the classic Errol Flynn The Adventures Of Robin Hood was my Dad's. And I can see why. Looking back at this 1938 film from the distance of 2012, it remains fresh, exciting, good humoured, full of action, bright, zesty and incredibly colourful. I would venture a guess that the use of Technicolor in this film had the same sort of impact on the cinema-going public that the 3D in Avatar did. If I was going to criticise, I would mention that the acting tends to reflect the often hammy style of the time, particularly for the supporting cast, but this is a minor quibble. This film remains as entertaining now as it was in 1938, and it was so entertaining in those days that my Dad saw it 5 times in one day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Historical Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a marvelously engaging flick. Everything seemed to come together in Warner's 1938 colorful story of Robin Hood, the 13th-century legendary outlaw who robbed from the rich only in order to give to the poor. Flynn was at his peak in 1938, terribly handsome without being in the least effete. And he was physically graceful enough to suggest competence in acrobatics and swordplay. Olivia De Havilland as Maid Marion is stunning -- vulnerable, alarmed, brave, sexy. The purity of her features isn't plastered over with an impasto of elaborate make up. Claude Raines is perfect as the sardonic and slimy fratricidal brother. And Basil Rathbone is here in his villainous mode (Mr. Murdstone, etc.), evil and grounded. His swordplay was convincing because he studied the art and became quite good; not competition level but he knew what he was about. Comedy relief is provided by some of the supporting players. William Keighley began directing but his work wasn't considered zippy enough so he was replaced by the redoubtable Michael Curtiz and -- Sire, he hesitates not to undercrank the camera and accelerate the action, nor does he pause before ripping off the shadows of swashbucklers on the castle walls, right out of silent movies with Douglas Fairbanks. The dialog is properly stilted and there are a few slightly surreal lines. Rathbone admonishes the sheriff. "You couldn't catch him if he sat in your lap shooting arrows at a crow!" Who thought THAT up? It's all an intensely hued fairy tale of course, done in gorgeous new three-strip Technicolor. Eric Wolfgang Korngold's score is delightfully bombastic. Historically, by the time the Robin Hood stories became popular, there was little friction between Norman and Saxon. People knew their places. The Normans were on top and ate "pork" (from French), while the Saxons did the farm work and raised "swine" (Germanic). Maid Marion didn't enter the stories until later. Fun, action, and the studio system at its best. Catch it if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnkim
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never seen this film or perhaps are of a certain age and consider this too old for you then you are missing a classic. This film does not desire to be nor is it historically correct. What it is, is simply a wonderful entertainment playing the Robin Hood legend in full. Every character is rich and the adventure you are invited to follow is wonderful. Errol Flynn is at his physical and romantic best. De Havilland is perfect as the demure yet quietly sensual Maid Marion, and as to Basil Rathbone! What a wonderful villain he portrays. Please younger film buffs see this film and enjoy it as it plays. You are in for a real treat and a fantastic adventure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Hood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dane (dane11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I need to tell you, I am a fan of Robin Hood. I read the stories of Robin Hood as a child/young adult. I've watched every Robin Hood movie and TV Show (TV Show's in re-runs, with the exception of When Things Were Rotten). Robin Hood is a character who is worthy of legend. He is a character that few can really compare to. And, after seeing Errol Flynn in green tights and cap, I realized, there would never be another Robin Hood. The Adventures of Robin Hood, from Warner Brothers in glorious Technicolor is a visual masterpiece. From the green forests to the dark, castle of the would-be King, Prince John, the colors and textures really come to life. The excellent direction by Michael Curtiz allows the film to fire on all cylinders. But it is the character of Robin, portrayed by Flynn with a great smile and amazing athleticism that really wins over the viewer. We cannot deny that Flynn's smile will win over the heart of Maid Marian. Nor do we doubt when he casts his smile on his victims that they too would be overwhelmed by his charm and style. Flynn's Robin Hood is not threatening. Flynn's Robin Hood comes across as happy and carefree, fighting for what he believes in. When the time comes for Robin to be serious and fight it out with his enemies, we are equally drawn in, ready to believe that we're watching the greatest hero/anti-hero ever imagined. No hero is complete without a great adversary. For Robin, his enemy has always been the Sheriff of Nottingham, but here we have, Sir Guy of Gisbourne, perfectly portrayed by Basil Rathbone. Naturally, Sir Guy takes his orders from Prince John, the great Claude Rains showing a slightly feminine side of a would-be-king. Prince John's associates are all evil and conniving, the Sheriff of Nottingham is played for laughs by Melville Cooper, allowing Sir Guy to be the really bad guy that hates Robin Hood. There is too much about this movie to like -- Robin's "Merry Men" are robustly and warmly portrayed by Alan Hale, Patrick Knowles and Eugene Palette as Little John, Will Scarlet and Friar Tuck, respectively. The glorious Technicolor vision of Sherwood Forest and the complete cast of characters that includes the Una O'Connor in a fun role as Maid Marian's guardian. There is humor and action and, of course, romance as only old Hollywood could make it. Michael Curtiz deftly moves between humor and action with an amazing style so the view hardly notices the difference. I've watched Douglas Fairbanks, Kevin Costner and Patrick Bergin try their hand at the character, I've watched the old TV series, the Disney cartoon and Mel Brooks satirical "Robin Hood: Men in Tights", right down to Ridley Scott's great retelling of the story with Russel Crowe. None of these compare to Errol Flynn in the Adventures of Robin Hood. Costner was way too wooden to be a true swashbuckler. Bergin was a little too uptight to be interesting. The TV show was... well, it was a 1950's TV show... Even Richard Lester's "Robin and Marian" falls a little short, though Connery is great as an older Robin Hood, complete with a winning, fun-loving smile. Flynn was fun and adventurous. We believe he could split the other archer's arrow. We believe that he could win the heart of Maid Marian and that his men would gladly follow him in to the Lion's den. We cheered for him because he was fun and he looked upon everything with a grin. We believe that he will protect the throne for good King Richard and save all of England, because we see that spark in his eyes telling us nothing is impossible. I'm a huge fan of Robin Hood. If the old stories of Robin Hood did not make me a fan, Errol Flynn did. There will never be another Robin Hood to compare with what Flynn brought to the screen. If you're checking out the Kevin Costner Robin Hood or the Russel Crowe version, take a look at what Flynn did first and you will be amazed by what you see. Allow yourself to go back in time and meet this man who was charming and fun and so full of life that all would gladly follow him. You too will become a fan of Robin Hood -- and probably a fan of Errol Flynn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep, still the best version of the Robin Hood legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For my money, one of the great adventure movies, "The Adventures of Robin Hood" thrills with ease. Errol Flynn is the master swashbuckler in the title role (dude makes it look easy) and he just makes you want to go out and find some bad guys to sword fight. Basil Rathbone and Claude Rains both make for terrific bad guys, while Olivia de Havilland is flat-out gorgeous. The fight scenes are well-choreographed, Korngold's score is grandly stirring, and the whole thing is imbued with Technicolor warmth. Classic! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The glory of Errol Flynn, Olivia deHavilland, & Technicolor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the earlier days of television, on Sunday nights we always had to watch "Walt Disney's Wonderful World Of Color". Well, this isn't a Disney film, but it is a wonderful world of Technicolor! In the restored version now on DVD, the color is stunning. You might say, "And a bit overdone", and you would be correct. But it's still color film to savor. Without any question, Errol Flynn's performance here is one of the most iconic in American film history. He is at his peak, and while he made quite a few fine films after this one, none had the luster of this film. And, this is one of the biggest productions made by Warner Brothers in this era, far different than its typical second class musicals (as compared to MGM) and black-and-white gangster pics. In contrast, Olivia DeHavilland's finest and most notable film performance was still a year away -- "Gone With The Wind". Nevertheless, DeHavilland is ravishingly beautiful here. And, keep in mind that the horse she rides became Trigger shortly after this film was made, when Roy Rogers purchased him. Basil Rathbone, who seemed to usually play villains on the screen (except for his stint as Sherlock Holmes), is excellent here, and was every bit as good as swordsman as depicted; here he plays Sir Guy of Gisbourne. Claude Rains as the evil Prince John who is attempting to usurp his brother's throne, does well, although this is so different than all of his other roles. As always, barrel-bellied Eugene Palette with his husky voice is interesting, here as Friar Tuck. Alan Hale Sr. is simply perfect as Little John, and this is just one of many screen appearances he made as Flynn's "pal". Herbert Mundin is fine as one of the merry men; sadly, at age 40, he was killed just a year later in an auto accident. Melville Cooper and Una O'Connor provide comic relief, the former as the Sheriff of Nottingham, and the latter as a lady in waiting. As far as the story, it, too, is excellent, with a few raised eyebrows. Would Robin Hood have been so dumb to put himself in a situation where he would almost certainly be at a strategic disadvantage and be captured (the archery contest)? I think not. In the deluxe DVD pack now available, there's an excellent documentary about the making of the film, as well as another about the history of Technicolor. Quite fascinating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A merrier Robin than Costner and Crowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When reviewing old movies like 1938's "The Adventures of Robin Hood", the reviewer must decide whether to critique the movie based on the era in which it was released or solely upon one's modern viewing experience. I'm going to largely review this classic version of Robin Hood according to the latter. I do like Errol Flynn in the title roll. He exudes such a joie de vivre ("joy of living") in contrast to Costner's dour performance and Crowe's dead serious approach. Flynn's rendition comes across as a Medieval superhero with superhuman nonchalance and bravery, not to mention fighting skills. One sequence shows Robin Hood taking on a whole castle of armed foes and easily escaping. I have no problem with this -- superheroes are great -- but it does mark the film as more of a Medieval fantasy rather than a quasi-realistic historical picture. Olivia de Havilland is also great as Maid Marion. She has a lovely face and such a winsome spirit. The pompous villains are excellent as well. As for Robin's merry men, they're serviceable. The film is very colorful and energetic, but sometimes the dialogue comes across so rehearsed. The characters speak so quickly and without inflection that it often doesn't even register what they said until a few seconds after they speak. Maybe it's just the way actors delivered their lines back then but, regardless, this'll strike modern viewers as bad filmmaking and acting. One scene is very eye-rolling -- when Marion comes into Robin's camp in Sherwood forest and his merry men start dancing hand-in-hand. Alrighty then. As far as the score goes, I'm sure it was fine for 1938, but for modern listeners it's verging on atrocious. Still, it's surprising how much "The Adventures of Robin Hood" holds up and remains entertaining. It's a great film when you want a pleasant flash from the past. But it doesn't hold a candle to more modern Medieval films, like "Tristan & Isolde" and "Black Death". And Costner and Crowe's more realistic versions are all-around better, even while they're less vibrant. But, again, the 1938 version is great when you're in the mood for a more energetic and colorful viewing experience. The film runs 102 minutes and was shot in California (they do a pretty good job of trying to make Southern California look like England). GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (richard@berrong.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how many times I've watched this movie. Certainly every time I've seen it on TV. As with any great work of art, once you get the plot down pat and don't have to focus on it anymore, you can take a certain distance and start to study the art with which the work was put together. That's where I am with "The Adventures of Robin Hood." Every time I see it, I marvel at some different aspect of its creation, such as the brilliant use of a great film score, or the use of Technicolor. (Yes, modern movies about the Medieval Ages are probably historically more accurate with their drab colors, but "The Adventures of Robin Hood" wasn't aspiring to be a history class film strip.) This evening, as I watched it again, I wondered about the extent to which its plot was meant to be read as commentary on contemporary world politics. It was made in 1938, after all, by which time Hitler had annexed several lands, in particular Austria, and driven many Jews out of Germany. By 1938 Hollywood had become something of a refugee camp for Jewish artists who had fled from Germany and then Austria. To what extent was this story of another invader, the Normans, and their unjust treatment of those whom they conquered, the Saxons, meant to be read as a commentary on what had just happened to Austria in March of 1938?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the child uncredited cast members
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Earl Faneuf
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Edward Earle Marsh was still alive, I met him in Las Vegas. He was an amazing man who was involved with Classical music, Many films (standard and porn) and numerous TV shows. His scrap book was amazing. He told me how he had been one of the small children in the forest when Errol and Olivia were talking. No speaking part. Just one of the children sitting on the ground. I just thought it would be nice to add his name to the cast since no one has done so over the years. I have always loved this film. It is one of my favorites from that time period. I would certainly recommend it to anyone who wants a wonderful family film that is full of great acting, and very well written dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Classic Robin Hood Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Prince John (Claude Rains) and the Norman Lords begin oppressing the Saxon masses in King Richard's absence, a Saxon lord (Errol Flynn) fights back as the outlaw leader of a rebel guerrilla army. I suppose the "modern classic" version of Robin Hood would be the Kevin Costner version, which is a great film in its own right. But the all-time classic Robin Hood is Errol Flynn. Indeed, is Flynn today known for much beyond this role? He easily surpassed Douglas Fairbanks. What makes this film a classic is not only the Technicolor (which shows off some very vibrant and interesting wardrobes), but the wardrobes themselves (which were clearly the inspiration behind "Men and Tights") and the general whimsical nature of the film. Despite being about rebellion and a prince who torments his own people, it has a very upbeat feel to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still fresh 70-odd years on
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films which have iconic value to their young audiences - King Kong, Star Wars, The Matrix all leap to mind. Harryhausen's Jason And The Argonauts was mine, and the classic Errol Flynn The Adventures Of Robin Hood was my Dad's. And I can see why. Looking back at this 1938 film from the distance of 2012, it remains fresh, exciting, good humoured, full of action, bright, zesty and incredibly colourful. I would venture a guess that the use of Technicolor in this film had the same sort of impact on the cinema-going public that the 3D in Avatar did. If I was going to criticise, I would mention that the acting tends to reflect the often hammy style of the time, particularly for the supporting cast, but this is a minor quibble. This film remains as entertaining now as it was in 1938, and it was so entertaining in those days that my Dad saw it 5 times in one day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Historical Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a marvelously engaging flick. Everything seemed to come together in Warner's 1938 colorful story of Robin Hood, the 13th-century legendary outlaw who robbed from the rich only in order to give to the poor. Flynn was at his peak in 1938, terribly handsome without being in the least effete. And he was physically graceful enough to suggest competence in acrobatics and swordplay. Olivia De Havilland as Maid Marion is stunning -- vulnerable, alarmed, brave, sexy. The purity of her features isn't plastered over with an impasto of elaborate make up. Claude Raines is perfect as the sardonic and slimy fratricidal brother. And Basil Rathbone is here in his villainous mode (Mr. Murdstone, etc.), evil and grounded. His swordplay was convincing because he studied the art and became quite good; not competition level but he knew what he was about. Comedy relief is provided by some of the supporting players. William Keighley began directing but his work wasn't considered zippy enough so he was replaced by the redoubtable Michael Curtiz and -- Sire, he hesitates not to undercrank the camera and accelerate the action, nor does he pause before ripping off the shadows of swashbucklers on the castle walls, right out of silent movies with Douglas Fairbanks. The dialog is properly stilted and there are a few slightly surreal lines. Rathbone admonishes the sheriff. "You couldn't catch him if he sat in your lap shooting arrows at a crow!" Who thought THAT up? It's all an intensely hued fairy tale of course, done in gorgeous new three-strip Technicolor. Eric Wolfgang Korngold's score is delightfully bombastic. Historically, by the time the Robin Hood stories became popular, there was little friction between Norman and Saxon. People knew their places. The Normans were on top and ate "pork" (from French), while the Saxons did the farm work and raised "swine" (Germanic). Maid Marion didn't enter the stories until later. Fun, action, and the studio system at its best. Catch it if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnkim
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never seen this film or perhaps are of a certain age and consider this too old for you then you are missing a classic. This film does not desire to be nor is it historically correct. What it is, is simply a wonderful entertainment playing the Robin Hood legend in full. Every character is rich and the adventure you are invited to follow is wonderful. Errol Flynn is at his physical and romantic best. De Havilland is perfect as the demure yet quietly sensual Maid Marion, and as to Basil Rathbone! What a wonderful villain he portrays. Please younger film buffs see this film and enjoy it as it plays. You are in for a real treat and a fantastic adventure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Hood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dane (dane11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I need to tell you, I am a fan of Robin Hood. I read the stories of Robin Hood as a child/young adult. I've watched every Robin Hood movie and TV Show (TV Show's in re-runs, with the exception of When Things Were Rotten). Robin Hood is a character who is worthy of legend. He is a character that few can really compare to. And, after seeing Errol Flynn in green tights and cap, I realized, there would never be another Robin Hood. The Adventures of Robin Hood, from Warner Brothers in glorious Technicolor is a visual masterpiece. From the green forests to the dark, castle of the would-be King, Prince John, the colors and textures really come to life. The excellent direction by Michael Curtiz allows the film to fire on all cylinders. But it is the character of Robin, portrayed by Flynn with a great smile and amazing athleticism that really wins over the viewer. We cannot deny that Flynn's smile will win over the heart of Maid Marian. Nor do we doubt when he casts his smile on his victims that they too would be overwhelmed by his charm and style. Flynn's Robin Hood is not threatening. Flynn's Robin Hood comes across as happy and carefree, fighting for what he believes in. When the time comes for Robin to be serious and fight it out with his enemies, we are equally drawn in, ready to believe that we're watching the greatest hero/anti-hero ever imagined. No hero is complete without a great adversary. For Robin, his enemy has always been the Sheriff of Nottingham, but here we have, Sir Guy of Gisbourne, perfectly portrayed by Basil Rathbone. Naturally, Sir Guy takes his orders from Prince John, the great Claude Rains showing a slightly feminine side of a would-be-king. Prince John's associates are all evil and conniving, the Sheriff of Nottingham is played for laughs by Melville Cooper, allowing Sir Guy to be the really bad guy that hates Robin Hood. There is too much about this movie to like -- Robin's "Merry Men" are robustly and warmly portrayed by Alan Hale, Patrick Knowles and Eugene Palette as Little John, Will Scarlet and Friar Tuck, respectively. The glorious Technicolor vision of Sherwood Forest and the complete cast of characters that includes the Una O'Connor in a fun role as Maid Marian's guardian. There is humor and action and, of course, romance as only old Hollywood could make it. Michael Curtiz deftly moves between humor and action with an amazing style so the view hardly notices the difference. I've watched Douglas Fairbanks, Kevin Costner and Patrick Bergin try their hand at the character, I've watched the old TV series, the Disney cartoon and Mel Brooks satirical "Robin Hood: Men in Tights", right down to Ridley Scott's great retelling of the story with Russel Crowe. None of these compare to Errol Flynn in the Adventures of Robin Hood. Costner was way too wooden to be a true swashbuckler. Bergin was a little too uptight to be interesting. The TV show was... well, it was a 1950's TV show... Even Richard Lester's "Robin and Marian" falls a little short, though Connery is great as an older Robin Hood, complete with a winning, fun-loving smile. Flynn was fun and adventurous. We believe he could split the other archer's arrow. We believe that he could win the heart of Maid Marian and that his men would gladly follow him in to the Lion's den. We cheered for him because he was fun and he looked upon everything with a grin. We believe that he will protect the throne for good King Richard and save all of England, because we see that spark in his eyes telling us nothing is impossible. I'm a huge fan of Robin Hood. If the old stories of Robin Hood did not make me a fan, Errol Flynn did. There will never be another Robin Hood to compare with what Flynn brought to the screen. If you're checking out the Kevin Costner Robin Hood or the Russel Crowe version, take a look at what Flynn did first and you will be amazed by what you see. Allow yourself to go back in time and meet this man who was charming and fun and so full of life that all would gladly follow him. You too will become a fan of Robin Hood -- and probably a fan of Errol Flynn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep, still the best version of the Robin Hood legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr-Fusion
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For my money, one of the great adventure movies, "The Adventures of Robin Hood" thrills with ease. Errol Flynn is the master swashbuckler in the title role (dude makes it look easy) and he just makes you want to go out and find some bad guys to sword fight. Basil Rathbone and Claude Rains both make for terrific bad guys, while Olivia de Havilland is flat-out gorgeous. The fight scenes are well-choreographed, Korngold's score is grandly stirring, and the whole thing is imbued with Technicolor warmth. Classic! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The glory of Errol Flynn, Olivia deHavilland, & Technicolor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the earlier days of television, on Sunday nights we always had to watch "Walt Disney's Wonderful World Of Color". Well, this isn't a Disney film, but it is a wonderful world of Technicolor! In the restored version now on DVD, the color is stunning. You might say, "And a bit overdone", and you would be correct. But it's still color film to savor. Without any question, Errol Flynn's performance here is one of the most iconic in American film history. He is at his peak, and while he made quite a few fine films after this one, none had the luster of this film. And, this is one of the biggest productions made by Warner Brothers in this era, far different than its typical second class musicals (as compared to MGM) and black-and-white gangster pics. In contrast, Olivia DeHavilland's finest and most notable film performance was still a year away -- "Gone With The Wind". Nevertheless, DeHavilland is ravishingly beautiful here. And, keep in mind that the horse she rides became Trigger shortly after this film was made, when Roy Rogers purchased him. Basil Rathbone, who seemed to usually play villains on the screen (except for his stint as Sherlock Holmes), is excellent here, and was every bit as good as swordsman as depicted; here he plays Sir Guy of Gisbourne. Claude Rains as the evil Prince John who is attempting to usurp his brother's throne, does well, although this is so different than all of his other roles. As always, barrel-bellied Eugene Palette with his husky voice is interesting, here as Friar Tuck. Alan Hale Sr. is simply perfect as Little John, and this is just one of many screen appearances he made as Flynn's "pal". Herbert Mundin is fine as one of the merry men; sadly, at age 40, he was killed just a year later in an auto accident. Melville Cooper and Una O'Connor provide comic relief, the former as the Sheriff of Nottingham, and the latter as a lady in waiting. As far as the story, it, too, is excellent, with a few raised eyebrows. Would Robin Hood have been so dumb to put himself in a situation where he would almost certainly be at a strategic disadvantage and be captured (the archery contest)? I think not. In the deluxe DVD pack now available, there's an excellent documentary about the making of the film, as well as another about the history of Technicolor. Quite fascinating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A merrier Robin than Costner and Crowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When reviewing old movies like 1938's "The Adventures of Robin Hood", the reviewer must decide whether to critique the movie based on the era in which it was released or solely upon one's modern viewing experience. I'm going to largely review this classic version of Robin Hood according to the latter. I do like Errol Flynn in the title roll. He exudes such a joie de vivre ("joy of living") in contrast to Costner's dour performance and Crowe's dead serious approach. Flynn's rendition comes across as a Medieval superhero with superhuman nonchalance and bravery, not to mention fighting skills. One sequence shows Robin Hood taking on a whole castle of armed foes and easily escaping. I have no problem with this -- superheroes are great -- but it does mark the film as more of a Medieval fantasy rather than a quasi-realistic historical picture. Olivia de Havilland is also great as Maid Marion. She has a lovely face and such a winsome spirit. The pompous villains are excellent as well. As for Robin's merry men, they're serviceable. The film is very colorful and energetic, but sometimes the dialogue comes across so rehearsed. The characters speak so quickly and without inflection that it often doesn't even register what they said until a few seconds after they speak. Maybe it's just the way actors delivered their lines back then but, regardless, this'll strike modern viewers as bad filmmaking and acting. One scene is very eye-rolling -- when Marion comes into Robin's camp in Sherwood forest and his merry men start dancing hand-in-hand. Alrighty then. As far as the score goes, I'm sure it was fine for 1938, but for modern listeners it's verging on atrocious. Still, it's surprising how much "The Adventures of Robin Hood" holds up and remains entertaining. It's a great film when you want a pleasant flash from the past. But it doesn't hold a candle to more modern Medieval films, like "Tristan & Isolde" and "Black Death". And Costner and Crowe's more realistic versions are all-around better, even while they're less vibrant. But, again, the 1938 version is great when you're in the mood for a more energetic and colorful viewing experience. The film runs 102 minutes and was shot in California (they do a pretty good job of trying to make Southern California look like England). GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (richard@berrong.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how many times I've watched this movie. Certainly every time I've seen it on TV. As with any great work of art, once you get the plot down pat and don't have to focus on it anymore, you can take a certain distance and start to study the art with which the work was put together. That's where I am with "The Adventures of Robin Hood." Every time I see it, I marvel at some different aspect of its creation, such as the brilliant use of a great film score, or the use of Technicolor. (Yes, modern movies about the Medieval Ages are probably historically more accurate with their drab colors, but "The Adventures of Robin Hood" wasn't aspiring to be a history class film strip.) This evening, as I watched it again, I wondered about the extent to which its plot was meant to be read as commentary on contemporary world politics. It was made in 1938, after all, by which time Hitler had annexed several lands, in particular Austria, and driven many Jews out of Germany. By 1938 Hollywood had become something of a refugee camp for Jewish artists who had fled from Germany and then Austria. To what extent was this story of another invader, the Normans, and their unjust treatment of those whom they conquered, the Saxons, meant to be read as a commentary on what had just happened to Austria in March of 1938?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the child uncredited cast members
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Earl Faneuf
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Edward Earle Marsh was still alive, I met him in Las Vegas. He was an amazing man who was involved with Classical music, Many films (standard and porn) and numerous TV shows. His scrap book was amazing. He told me how he had been one of the small children in the forest when Errol and Olivia were talking. No speaking part. Just one of the children sitting on the ground. I just thought it would be nice to add his name to the cast since no one has done so over the years. I have always loved this film. It is one of my favorites from that time period. I would certainly recommend it to anyone who wants a wonderful family film that is full of great acting, and very well written dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Classic Robin Hood Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Prince John (Claude Rains) and the Norman Lords begin oppressing the Saxon masses in King Richard's absence, a Saxon lord (Errol Flynn) fights back as the outlaw leader of a rebel guerrilla army. I suppose the "modern classic" version of Robin Hood would be the Kevin Costner version, which is a great film in its own right. But the all-time classic Robin Hood is Errol Flynn. Indeed, is Flynn today known for much beyond this role? He easily surpassed Douglas Fairbanks. What makes this film a classic is not only the Technicolor (which shows off some very vibrant and interesting wardrobes), but the wardrobes themselves (which were clearly the inspiration behind "Men and Tights") and the general whimsical nature of the film. Despite being about rebellion and a prince who torments his own people, it has a very upbeat feel to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still fresh 70-odd years on
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films which have iconic value to their young audiences - King Kong, Star Wars, The Matrix all leap to mind. Harryhausen's Jason And The Argonauts was mine, and the classic Errol Flynn The Adventures Of Robin Hood was my Dad's. And I can see why. Looking back at this 1938 film from the distance of 2012, it remains fresh, exciting, good humoured, full of action, bright, zesty and incredibly colourful. I would venture a guess that the use of Technicolor in this film had the same sort of impact on the cinema-going public that the 3D in Avatar did. If I was going to criticise, I would mention that the acting tends to reflect the often hammy style of the time, particularly for the supporting cast, but this is a minor quibble. This film remains as entertaining now as it was in 1938, and it was so entertaining in those days that my Dad saw it 5 times in one day!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Historical Adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a marvelously engaging flick. Everything seemed to come together in Warner's 1938 colorful story of Robin Hood, the 13th-century legendary outlaw who robbed from the rich only in order to give to the poor. Flynn was at his peak in 1938, terribly handsome without being in the least effete. And he was physically graceful enough to suggest competence in acrobatics and swordplay. Olivia De Havilland as Maid Marion is stunning -- vulnerable, alarmed, brave, sexy. The purity of her features isn't plastered over with an impasto of elaborate make up. Claude Raines is perfect as the sardonic and slimy fratricidal brother. And Basil Rathbone is here in his villainous mode (Mr. Murdstone, etc.), evil and grounded. His swordplay was convincing because he studied the art and became quite good; not competition level but he knew what he was about. Comedy relief is provided by some of the supporting players. William Keighley began directing but his work wasn't considered zippy enough so he was replaced by the redoubtable Michael Curtiz and -- Sire, he hesitates not to undercrank the camera and accelerate the action, nor does he pause before ripping off the shadows of swashbucklers on the castle walls, right out of silent movies with Douglas Fairbanks. The dialog is properly stilted and there are a few slightly surreal lines. Rathbone admonishes the sheriff. "You couldn't catch him if he sat in your lap shooting arrows at a crow!" Who thought THAT up? It's all an intensely hued fairy tale of course, done in gorgeous new three-strip Technicolor. Eric Wolfgang Korngold's score is delightfully bombastic. Historically, by the time the Robin Hood stories became popular, there was little friction between Norman and Saxon. People knew their places. The Normans were on top and ate "pork" (from French), while the Saxons did the farm work and raised "swine" (Germanic). Maid Marion didn't enter the stories until later. Fun, action, and the studio system at its best. Catch it if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mnkim
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never seen this film or perhaps are of a certain age and consider this too old for you then you are missing a classic. This film does not desire to be nor is it historically correct. What it is, is simply a wonderful entertainment playing the Robin Hood legend in full. Every character is rich and the adventure you are invited to follow is wonderful. Errol Flynn is at his physical and romantic best. De Havilland is perfect as the demure yet quietly sensual Maid Marion, and as to Basil Rathbone! What a wonderful villain he portrays. Please younger film buffs see this film and enjoy it as it plays. You are in for a real treat and a fantastic adventure!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Perfect Hood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dane (dane11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I need to tell you, I am a fan of Robin Hood. I read the stories of Robin Hood as a child/young adult. I've watched every Robin Hood movie and TV Show (TV Show's in re-runs, with the exception of When Things Were Rotten). Robin Hood is a character who is worthy of legend. He is a character that few can really compare to. And, after seeing Errol Flynn in green tights and cap, I realized, there would never be another Robin Hood. The Adventures of Robin Hood, from Warner Brothers in glorious Technicolor is a visual masterpiece. From the green forests to the dark, castle of the would-be King, Prince John, the colors and textures really come to life. The excellent direction by Michael Curtiz allows the film to fire on all cylinders. But it is the character of Robin, portrayed by Flynn with a great smile and amazing athleticism that really wins over the viewer. We cannot deny that Flynn's smile will win over the heart of Maid Marian. Nor do we doubt when he casts his smile on his victims that they too would be overwhelmed by his charm and style. Flynn's Robin Hood is not threatening. Flynn's Robin Hood comes across as happy and carefree, fighting for what he believes in. When the time comes for Robin to be serious and fight it out with his enemies, we are equally drawn in, ready to believe that we're watching the greatest hero/anti-hero ever imagined. No hero is complete without a great adversary. For Robin, his enemy has always been the Sheriff of Nottingham, but here we have, Sir Guy of Gisbourne, perfectly portrayed by Basil Rathbone. Naturally, Sir Guy takes his orders from Prince John, the great Claude Rains showing a slightly feminine side of a would-be-king. Prince John's associates are all evil and conniving, the Sheriff of Nottingham is played for laughs by Melville Cooper, allowing Sir Guy to be the really bad guy that hates Robin Hood. There is too much about this movie to like -- Robin's "Merry Men" are robustly and warmly portrayed by Alan Hale, Patrick Knowles and Eugene Palette as Little John, Will Scarlet and Friar Tuck, respectively. The glorious Technicolor vision of Sherwood Forest and the complete cast of characters that includes the Una O'Connor in a fun role as Maid Marian's guardian. There is humor and action and, of course, romance as only old Hollywood could make it. Michael Curtiz deftly moves between humor and action with an amazing style so the view hardly notices the difference. I've watched Douglas Fairbanks, Kevin Costner and Patrick Bergin try their hand at the character, I've watched the old TV series, the Disney cartoon and Mel Brooks satirical "Robin Hood: Men in Tights", right down to Ridley Scott's great retelling of the story with Russel Crowe. None of these compare to Errol Flynn in the Adventures of Robin Hood. Costner was way too wooden to be a true swashbuckler. Bergin was a little too uptight to be interesting. The TV show was... well, it was a 1950's TV show... Even Richard Lester's "Robin and Marian" falls a little short, though Connery is great as an older Robin Hood, complete with a winning, fun-loving smile. Flynn was fun and adventurous. We believe he could split the other archer's arrow. We believe that he could win the heart of Maid Marian and that his men would gladly follow him in to the Lion's den. We cheered for him because he was fun and he looked upon everything with a grin. We believe that he will protect the throne for good King Richard and save all of England, because we see that spark in his eyes telling us nothing is impossible. I'm a huge fan of Robin Hood. If the old stories of Robin Hood did not make me a fan, Errol Flynn did. There will never be another Robin Hood to compare with what Flynn brought to the screen. If you're checking out the Kevin Costner Robin Hood or the Russel Crowe version, take a look at what Flynn did first and you will be amazed by what you see. Allow yourself to go back in time and meet this man who was charming and fun and so full of life that all would gladly follow him. You too will become a fan of Robin Hood -- and probably a fan of Errol Flynn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
