<filme>
 <id>
  495
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0048960
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1956
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Volta ao Mundo em 80 Dias
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Adaptation of Jules Verne's novel about a Victorian Englishman who bets that with the new steamships and railways he can do what the title says.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Phileas Fogg accepts a challenge from his fellow members at the Reform Club and sets of prove that you can travel around the world in a mind-boggling 80 days. He sets off by train to Paris with his new valet Passepartout but then is forced to continue the trip by balloon arriving next in Spain where Passepartout has an interesting encounter in the bullfighting ring. They finally make their way across the Mediterranean and through the Suez canal, arriving in Bombay two days ahead of schedule. They board the train for Calcutta where they find there is a 50 mile gap midway. The break in their journey proved eventful as they rescue an Indian princess, Aouda, who is about to be forced to commit suttee - throwing herself on her dead husband's funeral pyre. They make to Calcutta and on to Siam and the Honk Kong. Throughout the voyage, they are followed by a detective, Mr. Fix, who is convinced that Fogg is the thief responsible for the recent &pound;55,000 theft at the bank of England. In Honk ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bet
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   travel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   train
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   england
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   journey
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Michael Anderson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   James Poe
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   John Farrow
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   David Niven
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Cantinflas
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Finlay Currie
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable once
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    implaxible
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stuck it out but was reminded that the previous time I saw it I had decided that I did not ever need to see it again. But this time it was in HD! Random comments: This was obviously made for the Cinerama (Todd-AO) screen, with the many travelogue scenes that are pretty but now read like a demonstration reel for a new (1950s) projection feature at Disney World. Many "look out the window, stock shot" sequences. OK, so they weren't stock shots but it sure felt like it. IMDb says that at the time, Cantinflas was the highest-paid movie star in world. Apparently popular everywhere but the U.S. I did not find him particularly engaging or appealing. There is nary a bit of humor or tension in the whole film. Each crisis is instantly solved by either money or a simple "Land Ho!". In fact, some sequences drag on way too long, specifically the ones in Spain. (Maybe for the Cantinflas audience?) There is a bullfighting sequence that goes on for nearly 15 minutes where absolutely nothing is at stake and the movie stops completely dead. It was startling to go from the cinematic location shots to the obvious backlot first unit stuff. For such an "epic", it felt quite claustrophobic. I liked and recognized many of the cameos. Apparently this was the film that started that trend. The music was lush and wonderful, and the end title sequence was quite engaging (a Saul Bass production). This version had the Edward R. Murrow intro which I had not seen before, and the Intermission, Entracte, and Exit Music, all of which I quite like in an epic film event. I kept mentally comparing this to some of the other big event films around the time, especially It's A Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World and The Great Race, both of which I enjoyed much more. One thing that made me laugh is that one Indian fell off his horse three times. It may have been three angles of the same shot. I did find it interesting that Fogg used a telescope much like the antique one I found I have. Now I wonder just how old it is?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great but All Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Saw this as a kid in school. Really liked it but really thought that David Niven was way too cold as a fish. And that Niven's Phileas Fogg though he is that way in the novel. Until Fogg showed some emotion when he and his valet Passepartout, rescued Shirley McClaine's Auoda from the fire. But still despite Niven IMHO who was the weak link in the movie. Loved Catlinflas as Passepartout. In the novel, he is French but in the movie, he is Spanish. He was big in Mexico until his death but wished he made it in America. Oh well! Still the movie had great scenery and really great all-star cast. This is where the term "cameo appearance" was coined. Michael Todd the producer of the film would die in a plane crash a year or so after the movie won the Oscar for best pic for 1956. He also was married to Liz Taylor at the time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A monument to the death of Hollywood's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Todd was a promoter. He was a man with the talent for carrying out the colossal hype, someone who could sell the proverbial refrigerator to an Eskimo. He certainly displayed his genius in this glut of scenery, costumes and extras, selling this mess of a movie to the public in 1956. This film is so charmless, so humorless, such a depiction of stereotypes and clich&eacute;s, and not less egregious, a squandering and misappropriation of acting talent. David Niven holds his own, but he single-handedly can't sustain the whole show. The talented Shirley MacLaine stands around wondering what she's doing and how she got roped into agreeing to be part of the cast. As to how Todd could have lured name stars to take on cameos, is a mystery to me. Maybe people such as Frank Sinatra and Marlene Dieterich had nothing better to do that day? Possibly the wide screen Todd A-O process engulfed viewers and glued them into their theatre seats where they watched like spellbound captives back in 1956, but today, there is absolutely nothing to recommend this movie. If nothing else, this movie stands as a testimonial to Hollywood's desperate bid to lure 1950s audiences away from their TV sets and back into the movie theatre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie has more than a handful of cast and wonderful cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is movie that goes on for 2 hours and keeps you wanting more, for the journey had beautiful scenery and nice international cast. The movie stared David Niven as Fogg and Cantinflas as Passepartout. Both characters being contradictory, Fogg is a gentleman, well-dressed, well-spoken, and extremely punctual, whereas Passepartout was the comic relief in the movie, he loved women and was a jack of all trade, their union boasted of talents and wits that saw them through the entire journey. This adventure film was produced by Michael Todd and is based on a novel of the same name by Jules Verne. Well comparing this to the 2004 remake that had Jackie Chan and Steve Coogan is going to be difficult as some of the attributes of Passepartout were given to Fogg making you lose respect for Fogg himself and the 1956 version is far different in the adventures embarked upon by the two compared to those in the 2004 version. The movie was actually filmed in 75 days and the cast including extras totaled 68,894 people and 7,959 animals. The wardrobe department spent $410,000 to provide 74,685 costumes and 36,092 trinkets. This movie packed a punch as the producers visited every country that Fogg and Passepartout passed through. The plot is about an English man in 1872 who is a member of the Reform Club, his name is Phileas Fogg (David Niven) he claims he can circumnavigate the world in eighty days. This made the other member of the Club view his claim as a bogus statement so he makes a &pound;20,000 wager (equal to over &pound;1,000,000 today) with several members of the Reform Club. The wager states that he will arrive back within 80 days before 8:45 pm. Together with his resourceful valet, Passepartout (Cantinflas), Fogg sets out on his journey which saw him save a princess, battle Indians, and as he was on his journey was named the chief suspect of stolen &pound;55,000 (equal to over &pound;3,000,000 today) from the Bank of England. This movie's wonderful cinematography was done by Lionel Lindon who won an Academy award for his work and he was involved in the photography of The Alfred Hitchcock Hour. The movie won five Academy awards, beating out critically acclaimed films like Friendly Persuasion, The Ten Commandments, Giant, and The King and I. The wins were Best Picture, Best Cinematography, Best Film Editing, Best Music and Best Writing, Best Screenplay, Adapted. This is a movie that is fun to watch and captivating to see. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am the true Kimi Gee, love hot air balloon rides
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgeouskimi
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually took a hot air balloon ride, so yes. I give this film a 10. Just to think a film from the 1950s could be so popular, Around the World in 80 Days, from the 1950s... Kimi Gee, being that I did the hot air balloon ride, probably almost made what was so exciting seem more. Why did this film get so popular? Maybe because I also went on a hot air balloon ride. What an adventure, going around the world, not knowing whether the wind would blow you to some remote island in the middle of no where or whether you would land somewhere popular that people had heard about your adventure... now I am in Guam. I tried the ride... and will try again one day... come on, it's just a balloon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good entertainment, although it drags at places.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rueiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First, I saw the Spanish cartoon adaptation in the mid-1980s, which can be quite nice for a kid's first introduction to Verne's legendary tale. Then I read the novel when I was ten years old, and later I saw this movie on TV on a Saturday afternoon.I loved it. Years later, I bought a VHS copy, and only two years ago I got the restored DVD edition, which comes with a lot of material some of which is interesting and the rest is a load of nonsense they added up just to have an excuse to produce a two-disc set. The restored movie runs for 174 minutes against the 160 or so of the old VHS. The newly added sequences are the intermission and exit music segments and some action shots previously edited that have been put back. I have to say that I find the film quite slow at times, with some sequences (the Melies "Journey to the Moon", the balloon voyage, the Spanish episode and the attack of the Sioux unnecessarily overlong and quite boring. Still, I also have to say that the film shines as to production values and its faithfulness to Verne's novel except for the balloon and the Spanish adventures. And some members of the cast are just right for their roles; I can not imagine anyone else but David Niven as Phileas Fogg, and Bobby Newton is likable as inspector Fix. But then Cantinflas, with all his natural skills for mimicry and his ability to talk like a gun-machine without saying anything solid, is a bit out of place here, since he talks Spanish at times instead of French, which is the nationality his character is supposed to be. And Shirley MacLaine,fresh from "The Trouble with Harry", seems to have been passing by when Mike Todd spotted her and immediately pulled out his chequebook and signed her in on the spot. But then, as a consolation, some of the cameos are a real delight: Coward, Gielgud,Boyer, Dietrich, Gingold, Mills... And it is John Carradine the one who stills every scene he is in, as the bullying, cigar-smoker, vulgarian Yank. He is very funny, and brings the best laughs in the film. Anyway, despite of its flaws and of being unnecessarily overlong, this film still is one of my favourite adventure epics of all time. I haven't seen the Jackie Chan - Steve Coogan remake, nor I intend to. Call me old-fashioned if you like, but I believe that in the old days movies looked much nicer and less fake than they do today courtesy of the CGI rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A beautiful, fun spectacle-- but only when watched as its creator intended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that suffers when viewed on a small screen. Made during a time when television posed a huge threat to the film industry, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a spectacle if there ever was one, a showcase of gorgeous cinematography and production values which can be appreciated nowhere else but in the theater. The acting and story were obviously of lesser importance than all the visuals. David Niven does a good job playing the quintessential British gentleman, and Cantinflas gives the most memorable performance as his comedic servant. The only lacking performance is given by Shirley MacLaine as Aouda, not only because she looks nothing like she's from India, but because she's uninteresting and never brings her character to life. There's also dozens of cameos sprinkled throughout, which are fun to look for if you're familiar with classic Hollywood personalities. For those who don't mind style over substance, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a treat indeed. If you're not one of those people, then hold off unless you ever get to see it on the big screen, where one can most appreciate all the film has to offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1956: Disney Verne and Todd Verne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    reisen55
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time has dulled my memory of this film. Bought the restored DVD a few weeks ago and began watching it last night. And it is one of those odd films that was great in 1956 when travel was new and the audience unsophisticated. What struck me today is now simple it really is. Some locations, London, Paris and Spain are gorgeous, plus local to Europe. The music is grand, and it works like a charm. As soon as the film departs Spain, we enter (a) Hollywood backlot sets and (b) traveloge territory where all too long we are treated to gorgeous, and dull, camera shots of distant countries while Niven and Company are off screen. Only Europe and America are really used in real-time sets. The rest is amazingly artificial. Now, I love Cantinflas who is a wonderful clone of Chaplin in this film - blood cousin to the Tramp. Niven is precise and perfect. MacClaine is rather wasted and dear Robert Newton is a treasure. Victor Young's score is ideal. BUT SINCE WE ARE on Verne in 1956, turn the page to 20,000 LEAGUES UNDER THE SEA and we have Verne done RIGHT!!! Disney's best action film ever, and far superior to Todd's globe trotting epic. So watch this 1956 memory with some careful planning. Be prepared, your memory may be better off to keep without spoiling it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It comes off like a 9-hour travelogue, but maybe it's something you may want to see once.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I watched "Around the World in Eighty Days" tonight, I noticde that it is a beautiful and spectacular film. The first time I tried seeing it was on a 25" TV--this time it's on a 58" one and the beauty is much more obvious. Too bad I couldn't have seen this on the big screen using the amazing 70mm cameras. And, if they brought it back to the theaters, I might be tempted to see it that way--even though the film does have many shortcomings. I've got to be honest here, I tried watching this film years ago and gave up on it. The only reason I am watching it through to the end now is that I would like to eventually see all the Best Picture winners--even the incredibly overblown ones. This brings me to a pet peeve I have. I HATE films that feature a bazillion cameos. I find that often the plethora of stars tend to get in the way of the story and often soak up a huge portion of the budget--leaving precious little for writing. Some of the stars in the film are very international in flavor and I never would have recognized them the first time I tried to see this movie 25 years ago. Now, after having seen and reviewed a ridiculous number of films, I was actually excited by some of these casting decisions. Catinflas, though completely unknown in America did some marvelous little comedies in Mexico--and he is the other reason I chose to try watching the movie again. I was to see Fernandel (who also made many wonderful films--in France and Italy). But, I was also maddened because his cameo as a hack driver was so short and unfunny--completely wasting his wonderful comedic talents. And this trend continued for several more of the cameo--wonderful actors who really have nothing to do and are pretty much wasted. At least 30 minutes could have and should have been cut from the film. I am NOT against long films...if they are well-paced. Too many times in this movie, however, scenes just unfold way too slowly--such as when the balloon is going over the Alps. A VERY LONG period of nice music and shots of the balloon are shown--when it really seemed interminably long. This reminded me of the major problem with "Star Trek: The Motion Picture"--too many unnecessarily long shots which killed the film's momentum. The bullfighting scene is also one that goes on and on and on and could have been 1/3 as long. Many other such examples followed. So is it a great film? No. I agree with another reviewer who felt the movie got an Oscar for Best Picture simply because it was such a spectacle--not because it was especially good. It's one of the weaker Best Picture films of the era, in my opinion. However, I must give the film its due. The movie is beautiful in every way--great costumes, amazing locations and sets, breathtaking cinematography and a scope that cannot really be matched. But, it is also very, very , very long with poor pacing, suffers from an overuse and wasting of cameos and just isn't that interesting. Catinflas was a very gifted and funny man--here you don't get a great sense of that at all. Likewise, David Niven was a very fine actor--but here he's more like set dressing and you don't get to see him at his best. Before I conclude, let's talk about the cameos. With all the many cameos, why did they pick Shirley MacLaine to play an Indian princess?! Talk about bizarre casting! And why have Frank Sinatra in a cameo that takes two seconds and he just turns and smiles at the camera?! I don't get it. And what was with John Carradine?! Even for him he over-acted horribly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adventure, Colorful and Long.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lots of money, effort, and publicity on display in this story of an fastidious British gentleman, David Niven, who manages to use the technology of the Victorian era to travel, well, around the world in 80 days, with sidekick Cantinflas, and picking up Princess Shirley MacLaine along the way. Producer Michael Todd put everything he had into it. It was a tremendous splash at the time using a special projective technique, plenty of music that went into a best-selling album, and the face of every recognizable actor of every nationality imaginable. There are theatrical knights in abundance. Let's see. There's Sir John Gielgud, Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sir John Mills, and Sir Frank Sinatra. Now, fifty-six years after its release, it's hard to see what all the fuss was about. It's BIG of course, but it more or less had to be. What was happening in 1955 to the movie industry? It was being replaced by television and studios were desperate for novelty, something the audience couldn't find on their small black and white sets at home -- in this case, a MAGNIFICOLOR extravaganza in TODD-A-OMG-VISION! Look -- there's Marlene Dietrich! And that's the guy, what's his name, the sergeant from that John Ford cavalry movie! Gosh! The problem with the flick is that it's really designed to elicit gasps from a family audience. Not laughs, not thrills, not clenched teeth. You're supposed to sit back as at a travelogue and marvel at the sights of a Spanish bullfight, in which a clumsy Cantinflas taunts a bull while trying to hold his pants up (ha ha), and a painted elephant in India, and all kinds of definitely retrograde stereotypes -- bullfights, flamenco dancers (good ones), thugee, suttee, jabbering Chinese, bowing Japanese, a steamboat that has to destroy itself to provide its own fuel, hostile American Indians attacking a train, a rescue by the cavalry. It all must have been thrilling if you'd never seen it before, but in order not to have seen it before you'd have to be no more than fifteen years old. There are some smiles. Here's the one that got to me. The opening scene is in one of those stuffy, tradition-ridden English gentleman's clubs. The figures are mostly motionless. The gentlemen sit playing whist or reading newspapers. No one is speaking. A cat pads through the room. And one gentleman complains to a steward, "Can't you stop that animal from stomping around?" I wish there had been more jokes or physical gags. I wish it wouldn't depend so heavily on a viewer's ability to be astounded by all the production values and the innumerable cameos. Want to see a more entertaining movie along the same lines? See "The Great Race."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable once
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    implaxible
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stuck it out but was reminded that the previous time I saw it I had decided that I did not ever need to see it again. But this time it was in HD! Random comments: This was obviously made for the Cinerama (Todd-AO) screen, with the many travelogue scenes that are pretty but now read like a demonstration reel for a new (1950s) projection feature at Disney World. Many "look out the window, stock shot" sequences. OK, so they weren't stock shots but it sure felt like it. IMDb says that at the time, Cantinflas was the highest-paid movie star in world. Apparently popular everywhere but the U.S. I did not find him particularly engaging or appealing. There is nary a bit of humor or tension in the whole film. Each crisis is instantly solved by either money or a simple "Land Ho!". In fact, some sequences drag on way too long, specifically the ones in Spain. (Maybe for the Cantinflas audience?) There is a bullfighting sequence that goes on for nearly 15 minutes where absolutely nothing is at stake and the movie stops completely dead. It was startling to go from the cinematic location shots to the obvious backlot first unit stuff. For such an "epic", it felt quite claustrophobic. I liked and recognized many of the cameos. Apparently this was the film that started that trend. The music was lush and wonderful, and the end title sequence was quite engaging (a Saul Bass production). This version had the Edward R. Murrow intro which I had not seen before, and the Intermission, Entracte, and Exit Music, all of which I quite like in an epic film event. I kept mentally comparing this to some of the other big event films around the time, especially It's A Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World and The Great Race, both of which I enjoyed much more. One thing that made me laugh is that one Indian fell off his horse three times. It may have been three angles of the same shot. I did find it interesting that Fogg used a telescope much like the antique one I found I have. Now I wonder just how old it is?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great but All Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Saw this as a kid in school. Really liked it but really thought that David Niven was way too cold as a fish. And that Niven's Phileas Fogg though he is that way in the novel. Until Fogg showed some emotion when he and his valet Passepartout, rescued Shirley McClaine's Auoda from the fire. But still despite Niven IMHO who was the weak link in the movie. Loved Catlinflas as Passepartout. In the novel, he is French but in the movie, he is Spanish. He was big in Mexico until his death but wished he made it in America. Oh well! Still the movie had great scenery and really great all-star cast. This is where the term "cameo appearance" was coined. Michael Todd the producer of the film would die in a plane crash a year or so after the movie won the Oscar for best pic for 1956. He also was married to Liz Taylor at the time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A monument to the death of Hollywood's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Todd was a promoter. He was a man with the talent for carrying out the colossal hype, someone who could sell the proverbial refrigerator to an Eskimo. He certainly displayed his genius in this glut of scenery, costumes and extras, selling this mess of a movie to the public in 1956. This film is so charmless, so humorless, such a depiction of stereotypes and clich&eacute;s, and not less egregious, a squandering and misappropriation of acting talent. David Niven holds his own, but he single-handedly can't sustain the whole show. The talented Shirley MacLaine stands around wondering what she's doing and how she got roped into agreeing to be part of the cast. As to how Todd could have lured name stars to take on cameos, is a mystery to me. Maybe people such as Frank Sinatra and Marlene Dieterich had nothing better to do that day? Possibly the wide screen Todd A-O process engulfed viewers and glued them into their theatre seats where they watched like spellbound captives back in 1956, but today, there is absolutely nothing to recommend this movie. If nothing else, this movie stands as a testimonial to Hollywood's desperate bid to lure 1950s audiences away from their TV sets and back into the movie theatre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie has more than a handful of cast and wonderful cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is movie that goes on for 2 hours and keeps you wanting more, for the journey had beautiful scenery and nice international cast. The movie stared David Niven as Fogg and Cantinflas as Passepartout. Both characters being contradictory, Fogg is a gentleman, well-dressed, well-spoken, and extremely punctual, whereas Passepartout was the comic relief in the movie, he loved women and was a jack of all trade, their union boasted of talents and wits that saw them through the entire journey. This adventure film was produced by Michael Todd and is based on a novel of the same name by Jules Verne. Well comparing this to the 2004 remake that had Jackie Chan and Steve Coogan is going to be difficult as some of the attributes of Passepartout were given to Fogg making you lose respect for Fogg himself and the 1956 version is far different in the adventures embarked upon by the two compared to those in the 2004 version. The movie was actually filmed in 75 days and the cast including extras totaled 68,894 people and 7,959 animals. The wardrobe department spent $410,000 to provide 74,685 costumes and 36,092 trinkets. This movie packed a punch as the producers visited every country that Fogg and Passepartout passed through. The plot is about an English man in 1872 who is a member of the Reform Club, his name is Phileas Fogg (David Niven) he claims he can circumnavigate the world in eighty days. This made the other member of the Club view his claim as a bogus statement so he makes a &pound;20,000 wager (equal to over &pound;1,000,000 today) with several members of the Reform Club. The wager states that he will arrive back within 80 days before 8:45 pm. Together with his resourceful valet, Passepartout (Cantinflas), Fogg sets out on his journey which saw him save a princess, battle Indians, and as he was on his journey was named the chief suspect of stolen &pound;55,000 (equal to over &pound;3,000,000 today) from the Bank of England. This movie's wonderful cinematography was done by Lionel Lindon who won an Academy award for his work and he was involved in the photography of The Alfred Hitchcock Hour. The movie won five Academy awards, beating out critically acclaimed films like Friendly Persuasion, The Ten Commandments, Giant, and The King and I. The wins were Best Picture, Best Cinematography, Best Film Editing, Best Music and Best Writing, Best Screenplay, Adapted. This is a movie that is fun to watch and captivating to see. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am the true Kimi Gee, love hot air balloon rides
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgeouskimi
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually took a hot air balloon ride, so yes. I give this film a 10. Just to think a film from the 1950s could be so popular, Around the World in 80 Days, from the 1950s... Kimi Gee, being that I did the hot air balloon ride, probably almost made what was so exciting seem more. Why did this film get so popular? Maybe because I also went on a hot air balloon ride. What an adventure, going around the world, not knowing whether the wind would blow you to some remote island in the middle of no where or whether you would land somewhere popular that people had heard about your adventure... now I am in Guam. I tried the ride... and will try again one day... come on, it's just a balloon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good entertainment, although it drags at places.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rueiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First, I saw the Spanish cartoon adaptation in the mid-1980s, which can be quite nice for a kid's first introduction to Verne's legendary tale. Then I read the novel when I was ten years old, and later I saw this movie on TV on a Saturday afternoon.I loved it. Years later, I bought a VHS copy, and only two years ago I got the restored DVD edition, which comes with a lot of material some of which is interesting and the rest is a load of nonsense they added up just to have an excuse to produce a two-disc set. The restored movie runs for 174 minutes against the 160 or so of the old VHS. The newly added sequences are the intermission and exit music segments and some action shots previously edited that have been put back. I have to say that I find the film quite slow at times, with some sequences (the Melies "Journey to the Moon", the balloon voyage, the Spanish episode and the attack of the Sioux unnecessarily overlong and quite boring. Still, I also have to say that the film shines as to production values and its faithfulness to Verne's novel except for the balloon and the Spanish adventures. And some members of the cast are just right for their roles; I can not imagine anyone else but David Niven as Phileas Fogg, and Bobby Newton is likable as inspector Fix. But then Cantinflas, with all his natural skills for mimicry and his ability to talk like a gun-machine without saying anything solid, is a bit out of place here, since he talks Spanish at times instead of French, which is the nationality his character is supposed to be. And Shirley MacLaine,fresh from "The Trouble with Harry", seems to have been passing by when Mike Todd spotted her and immediately pulled out his chequebook and signed her in on the spot. But then, as a consolation, some of the cameos are a real delight: Coward, Gielgud,Boyer, Dietrich, Gingold, Mills... And it is John Carradine the one who stills every scene he is in, as the bullying, cigar-smoker, vulgarian Yank. He is very funny, and brings the best laughs in the film. Anyway, despite of its flaws and of being unnecessarily overlong, this film still is one of my favourite adventure epics of all time. I haven't seen the Jackie Chan - Steve Coogan remake, nor I intend to. Call me old-fashioned if you like, but I believe that in the old days movies looked much nicer and less fake than they do today courtesy of the CGI rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A beautiful, fun spectacle-- but only when watched as its creator intended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that suffers when viewed on a small screen. Made during a time when television posed a huge threat to the film industry, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a spectacle if there ever was one, a showcase of gorgeous cinematography and production values which can be appreciated nowhere else but in the theater. The acting and story were obviously of lesser importance than all the visuals. David Niven does a good job playing the quintessential British gentleman, and Cantinflas gives the most memorable performance as his comedic servant. The only lacking performance is given by Shirley MacLaine as Aouda, not only because she looks nothing like she's from India, but because she's uninteresting and never brings her character to life. There's also dozens of cameos sprinkled throughout, which are fun to look for if you're familiar with classic Hollywood personalities. For those who don't mind style over substance, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a treat indeed. If you're not one of those people, then hold off unless you ever get to see it on the big screen, where one can most appreciate all the film has to offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1956: Disney Verne and Todd Verne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    reisen55
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time has dulled my memory of this film. Bought the restored DVD a few weeks ago and began watching it last night. And it is one of those odd films that was great in 1956 when travel was new and the audience unsophisticated. What struck me today is now simple it really is. Some locations, London, Paris and Spain are gorgeous, plus local to Europe. The music is grand, and it works like a charm. As soon as the film departs Spain, we enter (a) Hollywood backlot sets and (b) traveloge territory where all too long we are treated to gorgeous, and dull, camera shots of distant countries while Niven and Company are off screen. Only Europe and America are really used in real-time sets. The rest is amazingly artificial. Now, I love Cantinflas who is a wonderful clone of Chaplin in this film - blood cousin to the Tramp. Niven is precise and perfect. MacClaine is rather wasted and dear Robert Newton is a treasure. Victor Young's score is ideal. BUT SINCE WE ARE on Verne in 1956, turn the page to 20,000 LEAGUES UNDER THE SEA and we have Verne done RIGHT!!! Disney's best action film ever, and far superior to Todd's globe trotting epic. So watch this 1956 memory with some careful planning. Be prepared, your memory may be better off to keep without spoiling it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It comes off like a 9-hour travelogue, but maybe it's something you may want to see once.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I watched "Around the World in Eighty Days" tonight, I noticde that it is a beautiful and spectacular film. The first time I tried seeing it was on a 25" TV--this time it's on a 58" one and the beauty is much more obvious. Too bad I couldn't have seen this on the big screen using the amazing 70mm cameras. And, if they brought it back to the theaters, I might be tempted to see it that way--even though the film does have many shortcomings. I've got to be honest here, I tried watching this film years ago and gave up on it. The only reason I am watching it through to the end now is that I would like to eventually see all the Best Picture winners--even the incredibly overblown ones. This brings me to a pet peeve I have. I HATE films that feature a bazillion cameos. I find that often the plethora of stars tend to get in the way of the story and often soak up a huge portion of the budget--leaving precious little for writing. Some of the stars in the film are very international in flavor and I never would have recognized them the first time I tried to see this movie 25 years ago. Now, after having seen and reviewed a ridiculous number of films, I was actually excited by some of these casting decisions. Catinflas, though completely unknown in America did some marvelous little comedies in Mexico--and he is the other reason I chose to try watching the movie again. I was to see Fernandel (who also made many wonderful films--in France and Italy). But, I was also maddened because his cameo as a hack driver was so short and unfunny--completely wasting his wonderful comedic talents. And this trend continued for several more of the cameo--wonderful actors who really have nothing to do and are pretty much wasted. At least 30 minutes could have and should have been cut from the film. I am NOT against long films...if they are well-paced. Too many times in this movie, however, scenes just unfold way too slowly--such as when the balloon is going over the Alps. A VERY LONG period of nice music and shots of the balloon are shown--when it really seemed interminably long. This reminded me of the major problem with "Star Trek: The Motion Picture"--too many unnecessarily long shots which killed the film's momentum. The bullfighting scene is also one that goes on and on and on and could have been 1/3 as long. Many other such examples followed. So is it a great film? No. I agree with another reviewer who felt the movie got an Oscar for Best Picture simply because it was such a spectacle--not because it was especially good. It's one of the weaker Best Picture films of the era, in my opinion. However, I must give the film its due. The movie is beautiful in every way--great costumes, amazing locations and sets, breathtaking cinematography and a scope that cannot really be matched. But, it is also very, very , very long with poor pacing, suffers from an overuse and wasting of cameos and just isn't that interesting. Catinflas was a very gifted and funny man--here you don't get a great sense of that at all. Likewise, David Niven was a very fine actor--but here he's more like set dressing and you don't get to see him at his best. Before I conclude, let's talk about the cameos. With all the many cameos, why did they pick Shirley MacLaine to play an Indian princess?! Talk about bizarre casting! And why have Frank Sinatra in a cameo that takes two seconds and he just turns and smiles at the camera?! I don't get it. And what was with John Carradine?! Even for him he over-acted horribly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adventure, Colorful and Long.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lots of money, effort, and publicity on display in this story of an fastidious British gentleman, David Niven, who manages to use the technology of the Victorian era to travel, well, around the world in 80 days, with sidekick Cantinflas, and picking up Princess Shirley MacLaine along the way. Producer Michael Todd put everything he had into it. It was a tremendous splash at the time using a special projective technique, plenty of music that went into a best-selling album, and the face of every recognizable actor of every nationality imaginable. There are theatrical knights in abundance. Let's see. There's Sir John Gielgud, Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sir John Mills, and Sir Frank Sinatra. Now, fifty-six years after its release, it's hard to see what all the fuss was about. It's BIG of course, but it more or less had to be. What was happening in 1955 to the movie industry? It was being replaced by television and studios were desperate for novelty, something the audience couldn't find on their small black and white sets at home -- in this case, a MAGNIFICOLOR extravaganza in TODD-A-OMG-VISION! Look -- there's Marlene Dietrich! And that's the guy, what's his name, the sergeant from that John Ford cavalry movie! Gosh! The problem with the flick is that it's really designed to elicit gasps from a family audience. Not laughs, not thrills, not clenched teeth. You're supposed to sit back as at a travelogue and marvel at the sights of a Spanish bullfight, in which a clumsy Cantinflas taunts a bull while trying to hold his pants up (ha ha), and a painted elephant in India, and all kinds of definitely retrograde stereotypes -- bullfights, flamenco dancers (good ones), thugee, suttee, jabbering Chinese, bowing Japanese, a steamboat that has to destroy itself to provide its own fuel, hostile American Indians attacking a train, a rescue by the cavalry. It all must have been thrilling if you'd never seen it before, but in order not to have seen it before you'd have to be no more than fifteen years old. There are some smiles. Here's the one that got to me. The opening scene is in one of those stuffy, tradition-ridden English gentleman's clubs. The figures are mostly motionless. The gentlemen sit playing whist or reading newspapers. No one is speaking. A cat pads through the room. And one gentleman complains to a steward, "Can't you stop that animal from stomping around?" I wish there had been more jokes or physical gags. I wish it wouldn't depend so heavily on a viewer's ability to be astounded by all the production values and the innumerable cameos. Want to see a more entertaining movie along the same lines? See "The Great Race."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable once
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    implaxible
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stuck it out but was reminded that the previous time I saw it I had decided that I did not ever need to see it again. But this time it was in HD! Random comments: This was obviously made for the Cinerama (Todd-AO) screen, with the many travelogue scenes that are pretty but now read like a demonstration reel for a new (1950s) projection feature at Disney World. Many "look out the window, stock shot" sequences. OK, so they weren't stock shots but it sure felt like it. IMDb says that at the time, Cantinflas was the highest-paid movie star in world. Apparently popular everywhere but the U.S. I did not find him particularly engaging or appealing. There is nary a bit of humor or tension in the whole film. Each crisis is instantly solved by either money or a simple "Land Ho!". In fact, some sequences drag on way too long, specifically the ones in Spain. (Maybe for the Cantinflas audience?) There is a bullfighting sequence that goes on for nearly 15 minutes where absolutely nothing is at stake and the movie stops completely dead. It was startling to go from the cinematic location shots to the obvious backlot first unit stuff. For such an "epic", it felt quite claustrophobic. I liked and recognized many of the cameos. Apparently this was the film that started that trend. The music was lush and wonderful, and the end title sequence was quite engaging (a Saul Bass production). This version had the Edward R. Murrow intro which I had not seen before, and the Intermission, Entracte, and Exit Music, all of which I quite like in an epic film event. I kept mentally comparing this to some of the other big event films around the time, especially It's A Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World and The Great Race, both of which I enjoyed much more. One thing that made me laugh is that one Indian fell off his horse three times. It may have been three angles of the same shot. I did find it interesting that Fogg used a telescope much like the antique one I found I have. Now I wonder just how old it is?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great but All Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Saw this as a kid in school. Really liked it but really thought that David Niven was way too cold as a fish. And that Niven's Phileas Fogg though he is that way in the novel. Until Fogg showed some emotion when he and his valet Passepartout, rescued Shirley McClaine's Auoda from the fire. But still despite Niven IMHO who was the weak link in the movie. Loved Catlinflas as Passepartout. In the novel, he is French but in the movie, he is Spanish. He was big in Mexico until his death but wished he made it in America. Oh well! Still the movie had great scenery and really great all-star cast. This is where the term "cameo appearance" was coined. Michael Todd the producer of the film would die in a plane crash a year or so after the movie won the Oscar for best pic for 1956. He also was married to Liz Taylor at the time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A monument to the death of Hollywood's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Todd was a promoter. He was a man with the talent for carrying out the colossal hype, someone who could sell the proverbial refrigerator to an Eskimo. He certainly displayed his genius in this glut of scenery, costumes and extras, selling this mess of a movie to the public in 1956. This film is so charmless, so humorless, such a depiction of stereotypes and clich&eacute;s, and not less egregious, a squandering and misappropriation of acting talent. David Niven holds his own, but he single-handedly can't sustain the whole show. The talented Shirley MacLaine stands around wondering what she's doing and how she got roped into agreeing to be part of the cast. As to how Todd could have lured name stars to take on cameos, is a mystery to me. Maybe people such as Frank Sinatra and Marlene Dieterich had nothing better to do that day? Possibly the wide screen Todd A-O process engulfed viewers and glued them into their theatre seats where they watched like spellbound captives back in 1956, but today, there is absolutely nothing to recommend this movie. If nothing else, this movie stands as a testimonial to Hollywood's desperate bid to lure 1950s audiences away from their TV sets and back into the movie theatre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie has more than a handful of cast and wonderful cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is movie that goes on for 2 hours and keeps you wanting more, for the journey had beautiful scenery and nice international cast. The movie stared David Niven as Fogg and Cantinflas as Passepartout. Both characters being contradictory, Fogg is a gentleman, well-dressed, well-spoken, and extremely punctual, whereas Passepartout was the comic relief in the movie, he loved women and was a jack of all trade, their union boasted of talents and wits that saw them through the entire journey. This adventure film was produced by Michael Todd and is based on a novel of the same name by Jules Verne. Well comparing this to the 2004 remake that had Jackie Chan and Steve Coogan is going to be difficult as some of the attributes of Passepartout were given to Fogg making you lose respect for Fogg himself and the 1956 version is far different in the adventures embarked upon by the two compared to those in the 2004 version. The movie was actually filmed in 75 days and the cast including extras totaled 68,894 people and 7,959 animals. The wardrobe department spent $410,000 to provide 74,685 costumes and 36,092 trinkets. This movie packed a punch as the producers visited every country that Fogg and Passepartout passed through. The plot is about an English man in 1872 who is a member of the Reform Club, his name is Phileas Fogg (David Niven) he claims he can circumnavigate the world in eighty days. This made the other member of the Club view his claim as a bogus statement so he makes a &pound;20,000 wager (equal to over &pound;1,000,000 today) with several members of the Reform Club. The wager states that he will arrive back within 80 days before 8:45 pm. Together with his resourceful valet, Passepartout (Cantinflas), Fogg sets out on his journey which saw him save a princess, battle Indians, and as he was on his journey was named the chief suspect of stolen &pound;55,000 (equal to over &pound;3,000,000 today) from the Bank of England. This movie's wonderful cinematography was done by Lionel Lindon who won an Academy award for his work and he was involved in the photography of The Alfred Hitchcock Hour. The movie won five Academy awards, beating out critically acclaimed films like Friendly Persuasion, The Ten Commandments, Giant, and The King and I. The wins were Best Picture, Best Cinematography, Best Film Editing, Best Music and Best Writing, Best Screenplay, Adapted. This is a movie that is fun to watch and captivating to see. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am the true Kimi Gee, love hot air balloon rides
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgeouskimi
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually took a hot air balloon ride, so yes. I give this film a 10. Just to think a film from the 1950s could be so popular, Around the World in 80 Days, from the 1950s... Kimi Gee, being that I did the hot air balloon ride, probably almost made what was so exciting seem more. Why did this film get so popular? Maybe because I also went on a hot air balloon ride. What an adventure, going around the world, not knowing whether the wind would blow you to some remote island in the middle of no where or whether you would land somewhere popular that people had heard about your adventure... now I am in Guam. I tried the ride... and will try again one day... come on, it's just a balloon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good entertainment, although it drags at places.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rueiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First, I saw the Spanish cartoon adaptation in the mid-1980s, which can be quite nice for a kid's first introduction to Verne's legendary tale. Then I read the novel when I was ten years old, and later I saw this movie on TV on a Saturday afternoon.I loved it. Years later, I bought a VHS copy, and only two years ago I got the restored DVD edition, which comes with a lot of material some of which is interesting and the rest is a load of nonsense they added up just to have an excuse to produce a two-disc set. The restored movie runs for 174 minutes against the 160 or so of the old VHS. The newly added sequences are the intermission and exit music segments and some action shots previously edited that have been put back. I have to say that I find the film quite slow at times, with some sequences (the Melies "Journey to the Moon", the balloon voyage, the Spanish episode and the attack of the Sioux unnecessarily overlong and quite boring. Still, I also have to say that the film shines as to production values and its faithfulness to Verne's novel except for the balloon and the Spanish adventures. And some members of the cast are just right for their roles; I can not imagine anyone else but David Niven as Phileas Fogg, and Bobby Newton is likable as inspector Fix. But then Cantinflas, with all his natural skills for mimicry and his ability to talk like a gun-machine without saying anything solid, is a bit out of place here, since he talks Spanish at times instead of French, which is the nationality his character is supposed to be. And Shirley MacLaine,fresh from "The Trouble with Harry", seems to have been passing by when Mike Todd spotted her and immediately pulled out his chequebook and signed her in on the spot. But then, as a consolation, some of the cameos are a real delight: Coward, Gielgud,Boyer, Dietrich, Gingold, Mills... And it is John Carradine the one who stills every scene he is in, as the bullying, cigar-smoker, vulgarian Yank. He is very funny, and brings the best laughs in the film. Anyway, despite of its flaws and of being unnecessarily overlong, this film still is one of my favourite adventure epics of all time. I haven't seen the Jackie Chan - Steve Coogan remake, nor I intend to. Call me old-fashioned if you like, but I believe that in the old days movies looked much nicer and less fake than they do today courtesy of the CGI rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A beautiful, fun spectacle-- but only when watched as its creator intended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that suffers when viewed on a small screen. Made during a time when television posed a huge threat to the film industry, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a spectacle if there ever was one, a showcase of gorgeous cinematography and production values which can be appreciated nowhere else but in the theater. The acting and story were obviously of lesser importance than all the visuals. David Niven does a good job playing the quintessential British gentleman, and Cantinflas gives the most memorable performance as his comedic servant. The only lacking performance is given by Shirley MacLaine as Aouda, not only because she looks nothing like she's from India, but because she's uninteresting and never brings her character to life. There's also dozens of cameos sprinkled throughout, which are fun to look for if you're familiar with classic Hollywood personalities. For those who don't mind style over substance, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a treat indeed. If you're not one of those people, then hold off unless you ever get to see it on the big screen, where one can most appreciate all the film has to offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1956: Disney Verne and Todd Verne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    reisen55
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time has dulled my memory of this film. Bought the restored DVD a few weeks ago and began watching it last night. And it is one of those odd films that was great in 1956 when travel was new and the audience unsophisticated. What struck me today is now simple it really is. Some locations, London, Paris and Spain are gorgeous, plus local to Europe. The music is grand, and it works like a charm. As soon as the film departs Spain, we enter (a) Hollywood backlot sets and (b) traveloge territory where all too long we are treated to gorgeous, and dull, camera shots of distant countries while Niven and Company are off screen. Only Europe and America are really used in real-time sets. The rest is amazingly artificial. Now, I love Cantinflas who is a wonderful clone of Chaplin in this film - blood cousin to the Tramp. Niven is precise and perfect. MacClaine is rather wasted and dear Robert Newton is a treasure. Victor Young's score is ideal. BUT SINCE WE ARE on Verne in 1956, turn the page to 20,000 LEAGUES UNDER THE SEA and we have Verne done RIGHT!!! Disney's best action film ever, and far superior to Todd's globe trotting epic. So watch this 1956 memory with some careful planning. Be prepared, your memory may be better off to keep without spoiling it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It comes off like a 9-hour travelogue, but maybe it's something you may want to see once.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I watched "Around the World in Eighty Days" tonight, I noticde that it is a beautiful and spectacular film. The first time I tried seeing it was on a 25" TV--this time it's on a 58" one and the beauty is much more obvious. Too bad I couldn't have seen this on the big screen using the amazing 70mm cameras. And, if they brought it back to the theaters, I might be tempted to see it that way--even though the film does have many shortcomings. I've got to be honest here, I tried watching this film years ago and gave up on it. The only reason I am watching it through to the end now is that I would like to eventually see all the Best Picture winners--even the incredibly overblown ones. This brings me to a pet peeve I have. I HATE films that feature a bazillion cameos. I find that often the plethora of stars tend to get in the way of the story and often soak up a huge portion of the budget--leaving precious little for writing. Some of the stars in the film are very international in flavor and I never would have recognized them the first time I tried to see this movie 25 years ago. Now, after having seen and reviewed a ridiculous number of films, I was actually excited by some of these casting decisions. Catinflas, though completely unknown in America did some marvelous little comedies in Mexico--and he is the other reason I chose to try watching the movie again. I was to see Fernandel (who also made many wonderful films--in France and Italy). But, I was also maddened because his cameo as a hack driver was so short and unfunny--completely wasting his wonderful comedic talents. And this trend continued for several more of the cameo--wonderful actors who really have nothing to do and are pretty much wasted. At least 30 minutes could have and should have been cut from the film. I am NOT against long films...if they are well-paced. Too many times in this movie, however, scenes just unfold way too slowly--such as when the balloon is going over the Alps. A VERY LONG period of nice music and shots of the balloon are shown--when it really seemed interminably long. This reminded me of the major problem with "Star Trek: The Motion Picture"--too many unnecessarily long shots which killed the film's momentum. The bullfighting scene is also one that goes on and on and on and could have been 1/3 as long. Many other such examples followed. So is it a great film? No. I agree with another reviewer who felt the movie got an Oscar for Best Picture simply because it was such a spectacle--not because it was especially good. It's one of the weaker Best Picture films of the era, in my opinion. However, I must give the film its due. The movie is beautiful in every way--great costumes, amazing locations and sets, breathtaking cinematography and a scope that cannot really be matched. But, it is also very, very , very long with poor pacing, suffers from an overuse and wasting of cameos and just isn't that interesting. Catinflas was a very gifted and funny man--here you don't get a great sense of that at all. Likewise, David Niven was a very fine actor--but here he's more like set dressing and you don't get to see him at his best. Before I conclude, let's talk about the cameos. With all the many cameos, why did they pick Shirley MacLaine to play an Indian princess?! Talk about bizarre casting! And why have Frank Sinatra in a cameo that takes two seconds and he just turns and smiles at the camera?! I don't get it. And what was with John Carradine?! Even for him he over-acted horribly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adventure, Colorful and Long.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lots of money, effort, and publicity on display in this story of an fastidious British gentleman, David Niven, who manages to use the technology of the Victorian era to travel, well, around the world in 80 days, with sidekick Cantinflas, and picking up Princess Shirley MacLaine along the way. Producer Michael Todd put everything he had into it. It was a tremendous splash at the time using a special projective technique, plenty of music that went into a best-selling album, and the face of every recognizable actor of every nationality imaginable. There are theatrical knights in abundance. Let's see. There's Sir John Gielgud, Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sir John Mills, and Sir Frank Sinatra. Now, fifty-six years after its release, it's hard to see what all the fuss was about. It's BIG of course, but it more or less had to be. What was happening in 1955 to the movie industry? It was being replaced by television and studios were desperate for novelty, something the audience couldn't find on their small black and white sets at home -- in this case, a MAGNIFICOLOR extravaganza in TODD-A-OMG-VISION! Look -- there's Marlene Dietrich! And that's the guy, what's his name, the sergeant from that John Ford cavalry movie! Gosh! The problem with the flick is that it's really designed to elicit gasps from a family audience. Not laughs, not thrills, not clenched teeth. You're supposed to sit back as at a travelogue and marvel at the sights of a Spanish bullfight, in which a clumsy Cantinflas taunts a bull while trying to hold his pants up (ha ha), and a painted elephant in India, and all kinds of definitely retrograde stereotypes -- bullfights, flamenco dancers (good ones), thugee, suttee, jabbering Chinese, bowing Japanese, a steamboat that has to destroy itself to provide its own fuel, hostile American Indians attacking a train, a rescue by the cavalry. It all must have been thrilling if you'd never seen it before, but in order not to have seen it before you'd have to be no more than fifteen years old. There are some smiles. Here's the one that got to me. The opening scene is in one of those stuffy, tradition-ridden English gentleman's clubs. The figures are mostly motionless. The gentlemen sit playing whist or reading newspapers. No one is speaking. A cat pads through the room. And one gentleman complains to a steward, "Can't you stop that animal from stomping around?" I wish there had been more jokes or physical gags. I wish it wouldn't depend so heavily on a viewer's ability to be astounded by all the production values and the innumerable cameos. Want to see a more entertaining movie along the same lines? See "The Great Race."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable once
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    implaxible
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stuck it out but was reminded that the previous time I saw it I had decided that I did not ever need to see it again. But this time it was in HD! Random comments: This was obviously made for the Cinerama (Todd-AO) screen, with the many travelogue scenes that are pretty but now read like a demonstration reel for a new (1950s) projection feature at Disney World. Many "look out the window, stock shot" sequences. OK, so they weren't stock shots but it sure felt like it. IMDb says that at the time, Cantinflas was the highest-paid movie star in world. Apparently popular everywhere but the U.S. I did not find him particularly engaging or appealing. There is nary a bit of humor or tension in the whole film. Each crisis is instantly solved by either money or a simple "Land Ho!". In fact, some sequences drag on way too long, specifically the ones in Spain. (Maybe for the Cantinflas audience?) There is a bullfighting sequence that goes on for nearly 15 minutes where absolutely nothing is at stake and the movie stops completely dead. It was startling to go from the cinematic location shots to the obvious backlot first unit stuff. For such an "epic", it felt quite claustrophobic. I liked and recognized many of the cameos. Apparently this was the film that started that trend. The music was lush and wonderful, and the end title sequence was quite engaging (a Saul Bass production). This version had the Edward R. Murrow intro which I had not seen before, and the Intermission, Entracte, and Exit Music, all of which I quite like in an epic film event. I kept mentally comparing this to some of the other big event films around the time, especially It's A Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World and The Great Race, both of which I enjoyed much more. One thing that made me laugh is that one Indian fell off his horse three times. It may have been three angles of the same shot. I did find it interesting that Fogg used a telescope much like the antique one I found I have. Now I wonder just how old it is?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great but All Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Saw this as a kid in school. Really liked it but really thought that David Niven was way too cold as a fish. And that Niven's Phileas Fogg though he is that way in the novel. Until Fogg showed some emotion when he and his valet Passepartout, rescued Shirley McClaine's Auoda from the fire. But still despite Niven IMHO who was the weak link in the movie. Loved Catlinflas as Passepartout. In the novel, he is French but in the movie, he is Spanish. He was big in Mexico until his death but wished he made it in America. Oh well! Still the movie had great scenery and really great all-star cast. This is where the term "cameo appearance" was coined. Michael Todd the producer of the film would die in a plane crash a year or so after the movie won the Oscar for best pic for 1956. He also was married to Liz Taylor at the time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A monument to the death of Hollywood's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Todd was a promoter. He was a man with the talent for carrying out the colossal hype, someone who could sell the proverbial refrigerator to an Eskimo. He certainly displayed his genius in this glut of scenery, costumes and extras, selling this mess of a movie to the public in 1956. This film is so charmless, so humorless, such a depiction of stereotypes and clich&eacute;s, and not less egregious, a squandering and misappropriation of acting talent. David Niven holds his own, but he single-handedly can't sustain the whole show. The talented Shirley MacLaine stands around wondering what she's doing and how she got roped into agreeing to be part of the cast. As to how Todd could have lured name stars to take on cameos, is a mystery to me. Maybe people such as Frank Sinatra and Marlene Dieterich had nothing better to do that day? Possibly the wide screen Todd A-O process engulfed viewers and glued them into their theatre seats where they watched like spellbound captives back in 1956, but today, there is absolutely nothing to recommend this movie. If nothing else, this movie stands as a testimonial to Hollywood's desperate bid to lure 1950s audiences away from their TV sets and back into the movie theatre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie has more than a handful of cast and wonderful cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is movie that goes on for 2 hours and keeps you wanting more, for the journey had beautiful scenery and nice international cast. The movie stared David Niven as Fogg and Cantinflas as Passepartout. Both characters being contradictory, Fogg is a gentleman, well-dressed, well-spoken, and extremely punctual, whereas Passepartout was the comic relief in the movie, he loved women and was a jack of all trade, their union boasted of talents and wits that saw them through the entire journey. This adventure film was produced by Michael Todd and is based on a novel of the same name by Jules Verne. Well comparing this to the 2004 remake that had Jackie Chan and Steve Coogan is going to be difficult as some of the attributes of Passepartout were given to Fogg making you lose respect for Fogg himself and the 1956 version is far different in the adventures embarked upon by the two compared to those in the 2004 version. The movie was actually filmed in 75 days and the cast including extras totaled 68,894 people and 7,959 animals. The wardrobe department spent $410,000 to provide 74,685 costumes and 36,092 trinkets. This movie packed a punch as the producers visited every country that Fogg and Passepartout passed through. The plot is about an English man in 1872 who is a member of the Reform Club, his name is Phileas Fogg (David Niven) he claims he can circumnavigate the world in eighty days. This made the other member of the Club view his claim as a bogus statement so he makes a &pound;20,000 wager (equal to over &pound;1,000,000 today) with several members of the Reform Club. The wager states that he will arrive back within 80 days before 8:45 pm. Together with his resourceful valet, Passepartout (Cantinflas), Fogg sets out on his journey which saw him save a princess, battle Indians, and as he was on his journey was named the chief suspect of stolen &pound;55,000 (equal to over &pound;3,000,000 today) from the Bank of England. This movie's wonderful cinematography was done by Lionel Lindon who won an Academy award for his work and he was involved in the photography of The Alfred Hitchcock Hour. The movie won five Academy awards, beating out critically acclaimed films like Friendly Persuasion, The Ten Commandments, Giant, and The King and I. The wins were Best Picture, Best Cinematography, Best Film Editing, Best Music and Best Writing, Best Screenplay, Adapted. This is a movie that is fun to watch and captivating to see. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am the true Kimi Gee, love hot air balloon rides
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgeouskimi
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually took a hot air balloon ride, so yes. I give this film a 10. Just to think a film from the 1950s could be so popular, Around the World in 80 Days, from the 1950s... Kimi Gee, being that I did the hot air balloon ride, probably almost made what was so exciting seem more. Why did this film get so popular? Maybe because I also went on a hot air balloon ride. What an adventure, going around the world, not knowing whether the wind would blow you to some remote island in the middle of no where or whether you would land somewhere popular that people had heard about your adventure... now I am in Guam. I tried the ride... and will try again one day... come on, it's just a balloon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good entertainment, although it drags at places.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rueiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First, I saw the Spanish cartoon adaptation in the mid-1980s, which can be quite nice for a kid's first introduction to Verne's legendary tale. Then I read the novel when I was ten years old, and later I saw this movie on TV on a Saturday afternoon.I loved it. Years later, I bought a VHS copy, and only two years ago I got the restored DVD edition, which comes with a lot of material some of which is interesting and the rest is a load of nonsense they added up just to have an excuse to produce a two-disc set. The restored movie runs for 174 minutes against the 160 or so of the old VHS. The newly added sequences are the intermission and exit music segments and some action shots previously edited that have been put back. I have to say that I find the film quite slow at times, with some sequences (the Melies "Journey to the Moon", the balloon voyage, the Spanish episode and the attack of the Sioux unnecessarily overlong and quite boring. Still, I also have to say that the film shines as to production values and its faithfulness to Verne's novel except for the balloon and the Spanish adventures. And some members of the cast are just right for their roles; I can not imagine anyone else but David Niven as Phileas Fogg, and Bobby Newton is likable as inspector Fix. But then Cantinflas, with all his natural skills for mimicry and his ability to talk like a gun-machine without saying anything solid, is a bit out of place here, since he talks Spanish at times instead of French, which is the nationality his character is supposed to be. And Shirley MacLaine,fresh from "The Trouble with Harry", seems to have been passing by when Mike Todd spotted her and immediately pulled out his chequebook and signed her in on the spot. But then, as a consolation, some of the cameos are a real delight: Coward, Gielgud,Boyer, Dietrich, Gingold, Mills... And it is John Carradine the one who stills every scene he is in, as the bullying, cigar-smoker, vulgarian Yank. He is very funny, and brings the best laughs in the film. Anyway, despite of its flaws and of being unnecessarily overlong, this film still is one of my favourite adventure epics of all time. I haven't seen the Jackie Chan - Steve Coogan remake, nor I intend to. Call me old-fashioned if you like, but I believe that in the old days movies looked much nicer and less fake than they do today courtesy of the CGI rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A beautiful, fun spectacle-- but only when watched as its creator intended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that suffers when viewed on a small screen. Made during a time when television posed a huge threat to the film industry, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a spectacle if there ever was one, a showcase of gorgeous cinematography and production values which can be appreciated nowhere else but in the theater. The acting and story were obviously of lesser importance than all the visuals. David Niven does a good job playing the quintessential British gentleman, and Cantinflas gives the most memorable performance as his comedic servant. The only lacking performance is given by Shirley MacLaine as Aouda, not only because she looks nothing like she's from India, but because she's uninteresting and never brings her character to life. There's also dozens of cameos sprinkled throughout, which are fun to look for if you're familiar with classic Hollywood personalities. For those who don't mind style over substance, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a treat indeed. If you're not one of those people, then hold off unless you ever get to see it on the big screen, where one can most appreciate all the film has to offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1956: Disney Verne and Todd Verne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    reisen55
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time has dulled my memory of this film. Bought the restored DVD a few weeks ago and began watching it last night. And it is one of those odd films that was great in 1956 when travel was new and the audience unsophisticated. What struck me today is now simple it really is. Some locations, London, Paris and Spain are gorgeous, plus local to Europe. The music is grand, and it works like a charm. As soon as the film departs Spain, we enter (a) Hollywood backlot sets and (b) traveloge territory where all too long we are treated to gorgeous, and dull, camera shots of distant countries while Niven and Company are off screen. Only Europe and America are really used in real-time sets. The rest is amazingly artificial. Now, I love Cantinflas who is a wonderful clone of Chaplin in this film - blood cousin to the Tramp. Niven is precise and perfect. MacClaine is rather wasted and dear Robert Newton is a treasure. Victor Young's score is ideal. BUT SINCE WE ARE on Verne in 1956, turn the page to 20,000 LEAGUES UNDER THE SEA and we have Verne done RIGHT!!! Disney's best action film ever, and far superior to Todd's globe trotting epic. So watch this 1956 memory with some careful planning. Be prepared, your memory may be better off to keep without spoiling it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It comes off like a 9-hour travelogue, but maybe it's something you may want to see once.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I watched "Around the World in Eighty Days" tonight, I noticde that it is a beautiful and spectacular film. The first time I tried seeing it was on a 25" TV--this time it's on a 58" one and the beauty is much more obvious. Too bad I couldn't have seen this on the big screen using the amazing 70mm cameras. And, if they brought it back to the theaters, I might be tempted to see it that way--even though the film does have many shortcomings. I've got to be honest here, I tried watching this film years ago and gave up on it. The only reason I am watching it through to the end now is that I would like to eventually see all the Best Picture winners--even the incredibly overblown ones. This brings me to a pet peeve I have. I HATE films that feature a bazillion cameos. I find that often the plethora of stars tend to get in the way of the story and often soak up a huge portion of the budget--leaving precious little for writing. Some of the stars in the film are very international in flavor and I never would have recognized them the first time I tried to see this movie 25 years ago. Now, after having seen and reviewed a ridiculous number of films, I was actually excited by some of these casting decisions. Catinflas, though completely unknown in America did some marvelous little comedies in Mexico--and he is the other reason I chose to try watching the movie again. I was to see Fernandel (who also made many wonderful films--in France and Italy). But, I was also maddened because his cameo as a hack driver was so short and unfunny--completely wasting his wonderful comedic talents. And this trend continued for several more of the cameo--wonderful actors who really have nothing to do and are pretty much wasted. At least 30 minutes could have and should have been cut from the film. I am NOT against long films...if they are well-paced. Too many times in this movie, however, scenes just unfold way too slowly--such as when the balloon is going over the Alps. A VERY LONG period of nice music and shots of the balloon are shown--when it really seemed interminably long. This reminded me of the major problem with "Star Trek: The Motion Picture"--too many unnecessarily long shots which killed the film's momentum. The bullfighting scene is also one that goes on and on and on and could have been 1/3 as long. Many other such examples followed. So is it a great film? No. I agree with another reviewer who felt the movie got an Oscar for Best Picture simply because it was such a spectacle--not because it was especially good. It's one of the weaker Best Picture films of the era, in my opinion. However, I must give the film its due. The movie is beautiful in every way--great costumes, amazing locations and sets, breathtaking cinematography and a scope that cannot really be matched. But, it is also very, very , very long with poor pacing, suffers from an overuse and wasting of cameos and just isn't that interesting. Catinflas was a very gifted and funny man--here you don't get a great sense of that at all. Likewise, David Niven was a very fine actor--but here he's more like set dressing and you don't get to see him at his best. Before I conclude, let's talk about the cameos. With all the many cameos, why did they pick Shirley MacLaine to play an Indian princess?! Talk about bizarre casting! And why have Frank Sinatra in a cameo that takes two seconds and he just turns and smiles at the camera?! I don't get it. And what was with John Carradine?! Even for him he over-acted horribly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adventure, Colorful and Long.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lots of money, effort, and publicity on display in this story of an fastidious British gentleman, David Niven, who manages to use the technology of the Victorian era to travel, well, around the world in 80 days, with sidekick Cantinflas, and picking up Princess Shirley MacLaine along the way. Producer Michael Todd put everything he had into it. It was a tremendous splash at the time using a special projective technique, plenty of music that went into a best-selling album, and the face of every recognizable actor of every nationality imaginable. There are theatrical knights in abundance. Let's see. There's Sir John Gielgud, Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sir John Mills, and Sir Frank Sinatra. Now, fifty-six years after its release, it's hard to see what all the fuss was about. It's BIG of course, but it more or less had to be. What was happening in 1955 to the movie industry? It was being replaced by television and studios were desperate for novelty, something the audience couldn't find on their small black and white sets at home -- in this case, a MAGNIFICOLOR extravaganza in TODD-A-OMG-VISION! Look -- there's Marlene Dietrich! And that's the guy, what's his name, the sergeant from that John Ford cavalry movie! Gosh! The problem with the flick is that it's really designed to elicit gasps from a family audience. Not laughs, not thrills, not clenched teeth. You're supposed to sit back as at a travelogue and marvel at the sights of a Spanish bullfight, in which a clumsy Cantinflas taunts a bull while trying to hold his pants up (ha ha), and a painted elephant in India, and all kinds of definitely retrograde stereotypes -- bullfights, flamenco dancers (good ones), thugee, suttee, jabbering Chinese, bowing Japanese, a steamboat that has to destroy itself to provide its own fuel, hostile American Indians attacking a train, a rescue by the cavalry. It all must have been thrilling if you'd never seen it before, but in order not to have seen it before you'd have to be no more than fifteen years old. There are some smiles. Here's the one that got to me. The opening scene is in one of those stuffy, tradition-ridden English gentleman's clubs. The figures are mostly motionless. The gentlemen sit playing whist or reading newspapers. No one is speaking. A cat pads through the room. And one gentleman complains to a steward, "Can't you stop that animal from stomping around?" I wish there had been more jokes or physical gags. I wish it wouldn't depend so heavily on a viewer's ability to be astounded by all the production values and the innumerable cameos. Want to see a more entertaining movie along the same lines? See "The Great Race."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable once
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    implaxible
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stuck it out but was reminded that the previous time I saw it I had decided that I did not ever need to see it again. But this time it was in HD! Random comments: This was obviously made for the Cinerama (Todd-AO) screen, with the many travelogue scenes that are pretty but now read like a demonstration reel for a new (1950s) projection feature at Disney World. Many "look out the window, stock shot" sequences. OK, so they weren't stock shots but it sure felt like it. IMDb says that at the time, Cantinflas was the highest-paid movie star in world. Apparently popular everywhere but the U.S. I did not find him particularly engaging or appealing. There is nary a bit of humor or tension in the whole film. Each crisis is instantly solved by either money or a simple "Land Ho!". In fact, some sequences drag on way too long, specifically the ones in Spain. (Maybe for the Cantinflas audience?) There is a bullfighting sequence that goes on for nearly 15 minutes where absolutely nothing is at stake and the movie stops completely dead. It was startling to go from the cinematic location shots to the obvious backlot first unit stuff. For such an "epic", it felt quite claustrophobic. I liked and recognized many of the cameos. Apparently this was the film that started that trend. The music was lush and wonderful, and the end title sequence was quite engaging (a Saul Bass production). This version had the Edward R. Murrow intro which I had not seen before, and the Intermission, Entracte, and Exit Music, all of which I quite like in an epic film event. I kept mentally comparing this to some of the other big event films around the time, especially It's A Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World and The Great Race, both of which I enjoyed much more. One thing that made me laugh is that one Indian fell off his horse three times. It may have been three angles of the same shot. I did find it interesting that Fogg used a telescope much like the antique one I found I have. Now I wonder just how old it is?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great but All Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Saw this as a kid in school. Really liked it but really thought that David Niven was way too cold as a fish. And that Niven's Phileas Fogg though he is that way in the novel. Until Fogg showed some emotion when he and his valet Passepartout, rescued Shirley McClaine's Auoda from the fire. But still despite Niven IMHO who was the weak link in the movie. Loved Catlinflas as Passepartout. In the novel, he is French but in the movie, he is Spanish. He was big in Mexico until his death but wished he made it in America. Oh well! Still the movie had great scenery and really great all-star cast. This is where the term "cameo appearance" was coined. Michael Todd the producer of the film would die in a plane crash a year or so after the movie won the Oscar for best pic for 1956. He also was married to Liz Taylor at the time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A monument to the death of Hollywood's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Todd was a promoter. He was a man with the talent for carrying out the colossal hype, someone who could sell the proverbial refrigerator to an Eskimo. He certainly displayed his genius in this glut of scenery, costumes and extras, selling this mess of a movie to the public in 1956. This film is so charmless, so humorless, such a depiction of stereotypes and clich&eacute;s, and not less egregious, a squandering and misappropriation of acting talent. David Niven holds his own, but he single-handedly can't sustain the whole show. The talented Shirley MacLaine stands around wondering what she's doing and how she got roped into agreeing to be part of the cast. As to how Todd could have lured name stars to take on cameos, is a mystery to me. Maybe people such as Frank Sinatra and Marlene Dieterich had nothing better to do that day? Possibly the wide screen Todd A-O process engulfed viewers and glued them into their theatre seats where they watched like spellbound captives back in 1956, but today, there is absolutely nothing to recommend this movie. If nothing else, this movie stands as a testimonial to Hollywood's desperate bid to lure 1950s audiences away from their TV sets and back into the movie theatre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie has more than a handful of cast and wonderful cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is movie that goes on for 2 hours and keeps you wanting more, for the journey had beautiful scenery and nice international cast. The movie stared David Niven as Fogg and Cantinflas as Passepartout. Both characters being contradictory, Fogg is a gentleman, well-dressed, well-spoken, and extremely punctual, whereas Passepartout was the comic relief in the movie, he loved women and was a jack of all trade, their union boasted of talents and wits that saw them through the entire journey. This adventure film was produced by Michael Todd and is based on a novel of the same name by Jules Verne. Well comparing this to the 2004 remake that had Jackie Chan and Steve Coogan is going to be difficult as some of the attributes of Passepartout were given to Fogg making you lose respect for Fogg himself and the 1956 version is far different in the adventures embarked upon by the two compared to those in the 2004 version. The movie was actually filmed in 75 days and the cast including extras totaled 68,894 people and 7,959 animals. The wardrobe department spent $410,000 to provide 74,685 costumes and 36,092 trinkets. This movie packed a punch as the producers visited every country that Fogg and Passepartout passed through. The plot is about an English man in 1872 who is a member of the Reform Club, his name is Phileas Fogg (David Niven) he claims he can circumnavigate the world in eighty days. This made the other member of the Club view his claim as a bogus statement so he makes a &pound;20,000 wager (equal to over &pound;1,000,000 today) with several members of the Reform Club. The wager states that he will arrive back within 80 days before 8:45 pm. Together with his resourceful valet, Passepartout (Cantinflas), Fogg sets out on his journey which saw him save a princess, battle Indians, and as he was on his journey was named the chief suspect of stolen &pound;55,000 (equal to over &pound;3,000,000 today) from the Bank of England. This movie's wonderful cinematography was done by Lionel Lindon who won an Academy award for his work and he was involved in the photography of The Alfred Hitchcock Hour. The movie won five Academy awards, beating out critically acclaimed films like Friendly Persuasion, The Ten Commandments, Giant, and The King and I. The wins were Best Picture, Best Cinematography, Best Film Editing, Best Music and Best Writing, Best Screenplay, Adapted. This is a movie that is fun to watch and captivating to see. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am the true Kimi Gee, love hot air balloon rides
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgeouskimi
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually took a hot air balloon ride, so yes. I give this film a 10. Just to think a film from the 1950s could be so popular, Around the World in 80 Days, from the 1950s... Kimi Gee, being that I did the hot air balloon ride, probably almost made what was so exciting seem more. Why did this film get so popular? Maybe because I also went on a hot air balloon ride. What an adventure, going around the world, not knowing whether the wind would blow you to some remote island in the middle of no where or whether you would land somewhere popular that people had heard about your adventure... now I am in Guam. I tried the ride... and will try again one day... come on, it's just a balloon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good entertainment, although it drags at places.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rueiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First, I saw the Spanish cartoon adaptation in the mid-1980s, which can be quite nice for a kid's first introduction to Verne's legendary tale. Then I read the novel when I was ten years old, and later I saw this movie on TV on a Saturday afternoon.I loved it. Years later, I bought a VHS copy, and only two years ago I got the restored DVD edition, which comes with a lot of material some of which is interesting and the rest is a load of nonsense they added up just to have an excuse to produce a two-disc set. The restored movie runs for 174 minutes against the 160 or so of the old VHS. The newly added sequences are the intermission and exit music segments and some action shots previously edited that have been put back. I have to say that I find the film quite slow at times, with some sequences (the Melies "Journey to the Moon", the balloon voyage, the Spanish episode and the attack of the Sioux unnecessarily overlong and quite boring. Still, I also have to say that the film shines as to production values and its faithfulness to Verne's novel except for the balloon and the Spanish adventures. And some members of the cast are just right for their roles; I can not imagine anyone else but David Niven as Phileas Fogg, and Bobby Newton is likable as inspector Fix. But then Cantinflas, with all his natural skills for mimicry and his ability to talk like a gun-machine without saying anything solid, is a bit out of place here, since he talks Spanish at times instead of French, which is the nationality his character is supposed to be. And Shirley MacLaine,fresh from "The Trouble with Harry", seems to have been passing by when Mike Todd spotted her and immediately pulled out his chequebook and signed her in on the spot. But then, as a consolation, some of the cameos are a real delight: Coward, Gielgud,Boyer, Dietrich, Gingold, Mills... And it is John Carradine the one who stills every scene he is in, as the bullying, cigar-smoker, vulgarian Yank. He is very funny, and brings the best laughs in the film. Anyway, despite of its flaws and of being unnecessarily overlong, this film still is one of my favourite adventure epics of all time. I haven't seen the Jackie Chan - Steve Coogan remake, nor I intend to. Call me old-fashioned if you like, but I believe that in the old days movies looked much nicer and less fake than they do today courtesy of the CGI rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A beautiful, fun spectacle-- but only when watched as its creator intended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that suffers when viewed on a small screen. Made during a time when television posed a huge threat to the film industry, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a spectacle if there ever was one, a showcase of gorgeous cinematography and production values which can be appreciated nowhere else but in the theater. The acting and story were obviously of lesser importance than all the visuals. David Niven does a good job playing the quintessential British gentleman, and Cantinflas gives the most memorable performance as his comedic servant. The only lacking performance is given by Shirley MacLaine as Aouda, not only because she looks nothing like she's from India, but because she's uninteresting and never brings her character to life. There's also dozens of cameos sprinkled throughout, which are fun to look for if you're familiar with classic Hollywood personalities. For those who don't mind style over substance, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a treat indeed. If you're not one of those people, then hold off unless you ever get to see it on the big screen, where one can most appreciate all the film has to offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1956: Disney Verne and Todd Verne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    reisen55
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time has dulled my memory of this film. Bought the restored DVD a few weeks ago and began watching it last night. And it is one of those odd films that was great in 1956 when travel was new and the audience unsophisticated. What struck me today is now simple it really is. Some locations, London, Paris and Spain are gorgeous, plus local to Europe. The music is grand, and it works like a charm. As soon as the film departs Spain, we enter (a) Hollywood backlot sets and (b) traveloge territory where all too long we are treated to gorgeous, and dull, camera shots of distant countries while Niven and Company are off screen. Only Europe and America are really used in real-time sets. The rest is amazingly artificial. Now, I love Cantinflas who is a wonderful clone of Chaplin in this film - blood cousin to the Tramp. Niven is precise and perfect. MacClaine is rather wasted and dear Robert Newton is a treasure. Victor Young's score is ideal. BUT SINCE WE ARE on Verne in 1956, turn the page to 20,000 LEAGUES UNDER THE SEA and we have Verne done RIGHT!!! Disney's best action film ever, and far superior to Todd's globe trotting epic. So watch this 1956 memory with some careful planning. Be prepared, your memory may be better off to keep without spoiling it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It comes off like a 9-hour travelogue, but maybe it's something you may want to see once.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I watched "Around the World in Eighty Days" tonight, I noticde that it is a beautiful and spectacular film. The first time I tried seeing it was on a 25" TV--this time it's on a 58" one and the beauty is much more obvious. Too bad I couldn't have seen this on the big screen using the amazing 70mm cameras. And, if they brought it back to the theaters, I might be tempted to see it that way--even though the film does have many shortcomings. I've got to be honest here, I tried watching this film years ago and gave up on it. The only reason I am watching it through to the end now is that I would like to eventually see all the Best Picture winners--even the incredibly overblown ones. This brings me to a pet peeve I have. I HATE films that feature a bazillion cameos. I find that often the plethora of stars tend to get in the way of the story and often soak up a huge portion of the budget--leaving precious little for writing. Some of the stars in the film are very international in flavor and I never would have recognized them the first time I tried to see this movie 25 years ago. Now, after having seen and reviewed a ridiculous number of films, I was actually excited by some of these casting decisions. Catinflas, though completely unknown in America did some marvelous little comedies in Mexico--and he is the other reason I chose to try watching the movie again. I was to see Fernandel (who also made many wonderful films--in France and Italy). But, I was also maddened because his cameo as a hack driver was so short and unfunny--completely wasting his wonderful comedic talents. And this trend continued for several more of the cameo--wonderful actors who really have nothing to do and are pretty much wasted. At least 30 minutes could have and should have been cut from the film. I am NOT against long films...if they are well-paced. Too many times in this movie, however, scenes just unfold way too slowly--such as when the balloon is going over the Alps. A VERY LONG period of nice music and shots of the balloon are shown--when it really seemed interminably long. This reminded me of the major problem with "Star Trek: The Motion Picture"--too many unnecessarily long shots which killed the film's momentum. The bullfighting scene is also one that goes on and on and on and could have been 1/3 as long. Many other such examples followed. So is it a great film? No. I agree with another reviewer who felt the movie got an Oscar for Best Picture simply because it was such a spectacle--not because it was especially good. It's one of the weaker Best Picture films of the era, in my opinion. However, I must give the film its due. The movie is beautiful in every way--great costumes, amazing locations and sets, breathtaking cinematography and a scope that cannot really be matched. But, it is also very, very , very long with poor pacing, suffers from an overuse and wasting of cameos and just isn't that interesting. Catinflas was a very gifted and funny man--here you don't get a great sense of that at all. Likewise, David Niven was a very fine actor--but here he's more like set dressing and you don't get to see him at his best. Before I conclude, let's talk about the cameos. With all the many cameos, why did they pick Shirley MacLaine to play an Indian princess?! Talk about bizarre casting! And why have Frank Sinatra in a cameo that takes two seconds and he just turns and smiles at the camera?! I don't get it. And what was with John Carradine?! Even for him he over-acted horribly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adventure, Colorful and Long.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lots of money, effort, and publicity on display in this story of an fastidious British gentleman, David Niven, who manages to use the technology of the Victorian era to travel, well, around the world in 80 days, with sidekick Cantinflas, and picking up Princess Shirley MacLaine along the way. Producer Michael Todd put everything he had into it. It was a tremendous splash at the time using a special projective technique, plenty of music that went into a best-selling album, and the face of every recognizable actor of every nationality imaginable. There are theatrical knights in abundance. Let's see. There's Sir John Gielgud, Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sir John Mills, and Sir Frank Sinatra. Now, fifty-six years after its release, it's hard to see what all the fuss was about. It's BIG of course, but it more or less had to be. What was happening in 1955 to the movie industry? It was being replaced by television and studios were desperate for novelty, something the audience couldn't find on their small black and white sets at home -- in this case, a MAGNIFICOLOR extravaganza in TODD-A-OMG-VISION! Look -- there's Marlene Dietrich! And that's the guy, what's his name, the sergeant from that John Ford cavalry movie! Gosh! The problem with the flick is that it's really designed to elicit gasps from a family audience. Not laughs, not thrills, not clenched teeth. You're supposed to sit back as at a travelogue and marvel at the sights of a Spanish bullfight, in which a clumsy Cantinflas taunts a bull while trying to hold his pants up (ha ha), and a painted elephant in India, and all kinds of definitely retrograde stereotypes -- bullfights, flamenco dancers (good ones), thugee, suttee, jabbering Chinese, bowing Japanese, a steamboat that has to destroy itself to provide its own fuel, hostile American Indians attacking a train, a rescue by the cavalry. It all must have been thrilling if you'd never seen it before, but in order not to have seen it before you'd have to be no more than fifteen years old. There are some smiles. Here's the one that got to me. The opening scene is in one of those stuffy, tradition-ridden English gentleman's clubs. The figures are mostly motionless. The gentlemen sit playing whist or reading newspapers. No one is speaking. A cat pads through the room. And one gentleman complains to a steward, "Can't you stop that animal from stomping around?" I wish there had been more jokes or physical gags. I wish it wouldn't depend so heavily on a viewer's ability to be astounded by all the production values and the innumerable cameos. Want to see a more entertaining movie along the same lines? See "The Great Race."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable once
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    implaxible
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stuck it out but was reminded that the previous time I saw it I had decided that I did not ever need to see it again. But this time it was in HD! Random comments: This was obviously made for the Cinerama (Todd-AO) screen, with the many travelogue scenes that are pretty but now read like a demonstration reel for a new (1950s) projection feature at Disney World. Many "look out the window, stock shot" sequences. OK, so they weren't stock shots but it sure felt like it. IMDb says that at the time, Cantinflas was the highest-paid movie star in world. Apparently popular everywhere but the U.S. I did not find him particularly engaging or appealing. There is nary a bit of humor or tension in the whole film. Each crisis is instantly solved by either money or a simple "Land Ho!". In fact, some sequences drag on way too long, specifically the ones in Spain. (Maybe for the Cantinflas audience?) There is a bullfighting sequence that goes on for nearly 15 minutes where absolutely nothing is at stake and the movie stops completely dead. It was startling to go from the cinematic location shots to the obvious backlot first unit stuff. For such an "epic", it felt quite claustrophobic. I liked and recognized many of the cameos. Apparently this was the film that started that trend. The music was lush and wonderful, and the end title sequence was quite engaging (a Saul Bass production). This version had the Edward R. Murrow intro which I had not seen before, and the Intermission, Entracte, and Exit Music, all of which I quite like in an epic film event. I kept mentally comparing this to some of the other big event films around the time, especially It's A Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World and The Great Race, both of which I enjoyed much more. One thing that made me laugh is that one Indian fell off his horse three times. It may have been three angles of the same shot. I did find it interesting that Fogg used a telescope much like the antique one I found I have. Now I wonder just how old it is?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great but All Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Saw this as a kid in school. Really liked it but really thought that David Niven was way too cold as a fish. And that Niven's Phileas Fogg though he is that way in the novel. Until Fogg showed some emotion when he and his valet Passepartout, rescued Shirley McClaine's Auoda from the fire. But still despite Niven IMHO who was the weak link in the movie. Loved Catlinflas as Passepartout. In the novel, he is French but in the movie, he is Spanish. He was big in Mexico until his death but wished he made it in America. Oh well! Still the movie had great scenery and really great all-star cast. This is where the term "cameo appearance" was coined. Michael Todd the producer of the film would die in a plane crash a year or so after the movie won the Oscar for best pic for 1956. He also was married to Liz Taylor at the time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A monument to the death of Hollywood's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Todd was a promoter. He was a man with the talent for carrying out the colossal hype, someone who could sell the proverbial refrigerator to an Eskimo. He certainly displayed his genius in this glut of scenery, costumes and extras, selling this mess of a movie to the public in 1956. This film is so charmless, so humorless, such a depiction of stereotypes and clich&eacute;s, and not less egregious, a squandering and misappropriation of acting talent. David Niven holds his own, but he single-handedly can't sustain the whole show. The talented Shirley MacLaine stands around wondering what she's doing and how she got roped into agreeing to be part of the cast. As to how Todd could have lured name stars to take on cameos, is a mystery to me. Maybe people such as Frank Sinatra and Marlene Dieterich had nothing better to do that day? Possibly the wide screen Todd A-O process engulfed viewers and glued them into their theatre seats where they watched like spellbound captives back in 1956, but today, there is absolutely nothing to recommend this movie. If nothing else, this movie stands as a testimonial to Hollywood's desperate bid to lure 1950s audiences away from their TV sets and back into the movie theatre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie has more than a handful of cast and wonderful cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is movie that goes on for 2 hours and keeps you wanting more, for the journey had beautiful scenery and nice international cast. The movie stared David Niven as Fogg and Cantinflas as Passepartout. Both characters being contradictory, Fogg is a gentleman, well-dressed, well-spoken, and extremely punctual, whereas Passepartout was the comic relief in the movie, he loved women and was a jack of all trade, their union boasted of talents and wits that saw them through the entire journey. This adventure film was produced by Michael Todd and is based on a novel of the same name by Jules Verne. Well comparing this to the 2004 remake that had Jackie Chan and Steve Coogan is going to be difficult as some of the attributes of Passepartout were given to Fogg making you lose respect for Fogg himself and the 1956 version is far different in the adventures embarked upon by the two compared to those in the 2004 version. The movie was actually filmed in 75 days and the cast including extras totaled 68,894 people and 7,959 animals. The wardrobe department spent $410,000 to provide 74,685 costumes and 36,092 trinkets. This movie packed a punch as the producers visited every country that Fogg and Passepartout passed through. The plot is about an English man in 1872 who is a member of the Reform Club, his name is Phileas Fogg (David Niven) he claims he can circumnavigate the world in eighty days. This made the other member of the Club view his claim as a bogus statement so he makes a &pound;20,000 wager (equal to over &pound;1,000,000 today) with several members of the Reform Club. The wager states that he will arrive back within 80 days before 8:45 pm. Together with his resourceful valet, Passepartout (Cantinflas), Fogg sets out on his journey which saw him save a princess, battle Indians, and as he was on his journey was named the chief suspect of stolen &pound;55,000 (equal to over &pound;3,000,000 today) from the Bank of England. This movie's wonderful cinematography was done by Lionel Lindon who won an Academy award for his work and he was involved in the photography of The Alfred Hitchcock Hour. The movie won five Academy awards, beating out critically acclaimed films like Friendly Persuasion, The Ten Commandments, Giant, and The King and I. The wins were Best Picture, Best Cinematography, Best Film Editing, Best Music and Best Writing, Best Screenplay, Adapted. This is a movie that is fun to watch and captivating to see. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am the true Kimi Gee, love hot air balloon rides
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgeouskimi
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually took a hot air balloon ride, so yes. I give this film a 10. Just to think a film from the 1950s could be so popular, Around the World in 80 Days, from the 1950s... Kimi Gee, being that I did the hot air balloon ride, probably almost made what was so exciting seem more. Why did this film get so popular? Maybe because I also went on a hot air balloon ride. What an adventure, going around the world, not knowing whether the wind would blow you to some remote island in the middle of no where or whether you would land somewhere popular that people had heard about your adventure... now I am in Guam. I tried the ride... and will try again one day... come on, it's just a balloon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good entertainment, although it drags at places.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rueiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First, I saw the Spanish cartoon adaptation in the mid-1980s, which can be quite nice for a kid's first introduction to Verne's legendary tale. Then I read the novel when I was ten years old, and later I saw this movie on TV on a Saturday afternoon.I loved it. Years later, I bought a VHS copy, and only two years ago I got the restored DVD edition, which comes with a lot of material some of which is interesting and the rest is a load of nonsense they added up just to have an excuse to produce a two-disc set. The restored movie runs for 174 minutes against the 160 or so of the old VHS. The newly added sequences are the intermission and exit music segments and some action shots previously edited that have been put back. I have to say that I find the film quite slow at times, with some sequences (the Melies "Journey to the Moon", the balloon voyage, the Spanish episode and the attack of the Sioux unnecessarily overlong and quite boring. Still, I also have to say that the film shines as to production values and its faithfulness to Verne's novel except for the balloon and the Spanish adventures. And some members of the cast are just right for their roles; I can not imagine anyone else but David Niven as Phileas Fogg, and Bobby Newton is likable as inspector Fix. But then Cantinflas, with all his natural skills for mimicry and his ability to talk like a gun-machine without saying anything solid, is a bit out of place here, since he talks Spanish at times instead of French, which is the nationality his character is supposed to be. And Shirley MacLaine,fresh from "The Trouble with Harry", seems to have been passing by when Mike Todd spotted her and immediately pulled out his chequebook and signed her in on the spot. But then, as a consolation, some of the cameos are a real delight: Coward, Gielgud,Boyer, Dietrich, Gingold, Mills... And it is John Carradine the one who stills every scene he is in, as the bullying, cigar-smoker, vulgarian Yank. He is very funny, and brings the best laughs in the film. Anyway, despite of its flaws and of being unnecessarily overlong, this film still is one of my favourite adventure epics of all time. I haven't seen the Jackie Chan - Steve Coogan remake, nor I intend to. Call me old-fashioned if you like, but I believe that in the old days movies looked much nicer and less fake than they do today courtesy of the CGI rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A beautiful, fun spectacle-- but only when watched as its creator intended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that suffers when viewed on a small screen. Made during a time when television posed a huge threat to the film industry, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a spectacle if there ever was one, a showcase of gorgeous cinematography and production values which can be appreciated nowhere else but in the theater. The acting and story were obviously of lesser importance than all the visuals. David Niven does a good job playing the quintessential British gentleman, and Cantinflas gives the most memorable performance as his comedic servant. The only lacking performance is given by Shirley MacLaine as Aouda, not only because she looks nothing like she's from India, but because she's uninteresting and never brings her character to life. There's also dozens of cameos sprinkled throughout, which are fun to look for if you're familiar with classic Hollywood personalities. For those who don't mind style over substance, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a treat indeed. If you're not one of those people, then hold off unless you ever get to see it on the big screen, where one can most appreciate all the film has to offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1956: Disney Verne and Todd Verne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    reisen55
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time has dulled my memory of this film. Bought the restored DVD a few weeks ago and began watching it last night. And it is one of those odd films that was great in 1956 when travel was new and the audience unsophisticated. What struck me today is now simple it really is. Some locations, London, Paris and Spain are gorgeous, plus local to Europe. The music is grand, and it works like a charm. As soon as the film departs Spain, we enter (a) Hollywood backlot sets and (b) traveloge territory where all too long we are treated to gorgeous, and dull, camera shots of distant countries while Niven and Company are off screen. Only Europe and America are really used in real-time sets. The rest is amazingly artificial. Now, I love Cantinflas who is a wonderful clone of Chaplin in this film - blood cousin to the Tramp. Niven is precise and perfect. MacClaine is rather wasted and dear Robert Newton is a treasure. Victor Young's score is ideal. BUT SINCE WE ARE on Verne in 1956, turn the page to 20,000 LEAGUES UNDER THE SEA and we have Verne done RIGHT!!! Disney's best action film ever, and far superior to Todd's globe trotting epic. So watch this 1956 memory with some careful planning. Be prepared, your memory may be better off to keep without spoiling it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It comes off like a 9-hour travelogue, but maybe it's something you may want to see once.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I watched "Around the World in Eighty Days" tonight, I noticde that it is a beautiful and spectacular film. The first time I tried seeing it was on a 25" TV--this time it's on a 58" one and the beauty is much more obvious. Too bad I couldn't have seen this on the big screen using the amazing 70mm cameras. And, if they brought it back to the theaters, I might be tempted to see it that way--even though the film does have many shortcomings. I've got to be honest here, I tried watching this film years ago and gave up on it. The only reason I am watching it through to the end now is that I would like to eventually see all the Best Picture winners--even the incredibly overblown ones. This brings me to a pet peeve I have. I HATE films that feature a bazillion cameos. I find that often the plethora of stars tend to get in the way of the story and often soak up a huge portion of the budget--leaving precious little for writing. Some of the stars in the film are very international in flavor and I never would have recognized them the first time I tried to see this movie 25 years ago. Now, after having seen and reviewed a ridiculous number of films, I was actually excited by some of these casting decisions. Catinflas, though completely unknown in America did some marvelous little comedies in Mexico--and he is the other reason I chose to try watching the movie again. I was to see Fernandel (who also made many wonderful films--in France and Italy). But, I was also maddened because his cameo as a hack driver was so short and unfunny--completely wasting his wonderful comedic talents. And this trend continued for several more of the cameo--wonderful actors who really have nothing to do and are pretty much wasted. At least 30 minutes could have and should have been cut from the film. I am NOT against long films...if they are well-paced. Too many times in this movie, however, scenes just unfold way too slowly--such as when the balloon is going over the Alps. A VERY LONG period of nice music and shots of the balloon are shown--when it really seemed interminably long. This reminded me of the major problem with "Star Trek: The Motion Picture"--too many unnecessarily long shots which killed the film's momentum. The bullfighting scene is also one that goes on and on and on and could have been 1/3 as long. Many other such examples followed. So is it a great film? No. I agree with another reviewer who felt the movie got an Oscar for Best Picture simply because it was such a spectacle--not because it was especially good. It's one of the weaker Best Picture films of the era, in my opinion. However, I must give the film its due. The movie is beautiful in every way--great costumes, amazing locations and sets, breathtaking cinematography and a scope that cannot really be matched. But, it is also very, very , very long with poor pacing, suffers from an overuse and wasting of cameos and just isn't that interesting. Catinflas was a very gifted and funny man--here you don't get a great sense of that at all. Likewise, David Niven was a very fine actor--but here he's more like set dressing and you don't get to see him at his best. Before I conclude, let's talk about the cameos. With all the many cameos, why did they pick Shirley MacLaine to play an Indian princess?! Talk about bizarre casting! And why have Frank Sinatra in a cameo that takes two seconds and he just turns and smiles at the camera?! I don't get it. And what was with John Carradine?! Even for him he over-acted horribly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adventure, Colorful and Long.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lots of money, effort, and publicity on display in this story of an fastidious British gentleman, David Niven, who manages to use the technology of the Victorian era to travel, well, around the world in 80 days, with sidekick Cantinflas, and picking up Princess Shirley MacLaine along the way. Producer Michael Todd put everything he had into it. It was a tremendous splash at the time using a special projective technique, plenty of music that went into a best-selling album, and the face of every recognizable actor of every nationality imaginable. There are theatrical knights in abundance. Let's see. There's Sir John Gielgud, Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sir John Mills, and Sir Frank Sinatra. Now, fifty-six years after its release, it's hard to see what all the fuss was about. It's BIG of course, but it more or less had to be. What was happening in 1955 to the movie industry? It was being replaced by television and studios were desperate for novelty, something the audience couldn't find on their small black and white sets at home -- in this case, a MAGNIFICOLOR extravaganza in TODD-A-OMG-VISION! Look -- there's Marlene Dietrich! And that's the guy, what's his name, the sergeant from that John Ford cavalry movie! Gosh! The problem with the flick is that it's really designed to elicit gasps from a family audience. Not laughs, not thrills, not clenched teeth. You're supposed to sit back as at a travelogue and marvel at the sights of a Spanish bullfight, in which a clumsy Cantinflas taunts a bull while trying to hold his pants up (ha ha), and a painted elephant in India, and all kinds of definitely retrograde stereotypes -- bullfights, flamenco dancers (good ones), thugee, suttee, jabbering Chinese, bowing Japanese, a steamboat that has to destroy itself to provide its own fuel, hostile American Indians attacking a train, a rescue by the cavalry. It all must have been thrilling if you'd never seen it before, but in order not to have seen it before you'd have to be no more than fifteen years old. There are some smiles. Here's the one that got to me. The opening scene is in one of those stuffy, tradition-ridden English gentleman's clubs. The figures are mostly motionless. The gentlemen sit playing whist or reading newspapers. No one is speaking. A cat pads through the room. And one gentleman complains to a steward, "Can't you stop that animal from stomping around?" I wish there had been more jokes or physical gags. I wish it wouldn't depend so heavily on a viewer's ability to be astounded by all the production values and the innumerable cameos. Want to see a more entertaining movie along the same lines? See "The Great Race."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable once
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    implaxible
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stuck it out but was reminded that the previous time I saw it I had decided that I did not ever need to see it again. But this time it was in HD! Random comments: This was obviously made for the Cinerama (Todd-AO) screen, with the many travelogue scenes that are pretty but now read like a demonstration reel for a new (1950s) projection feature at Disney World. Many "look out the window, stock shot" sequences. OK, so they weren't stock shots but it sure felt like it. IMDb says that at the time, Cantinflas was the highest-paid movie star in world. Apparently popular everywhere but the U.S. I did not find him particularly engaging or appealing. There is nary a bit of humor or tension in the whole film. Each crisis is instantly solved by either money or a simple "Land Ho!". In fact, some sequences drag on way too long, specifically the ones in Spain. (Maybe for the Cantinflas audience?) There is a bullfighting sequence that goes on for nearly 15 minutes where absolutely nothing is at stake and the movie stops completely dead. It was startling to go from the cinematic location shots to the obvious backlot first unit stuff. For such an "epic", it felt quite claustrophobic. I liked and recognized many of the cameos. Apparently this was the film that started that trend. The music was lush and wonderful, and the end title sequence was quite engaging (a Saul Bass production). This version had the Edward R. Murrow intro which I had not seen before, and the Intermission, Entracte, and Exit Music, all of which I quite like in an epic film event. I kept mentally comparing this to some of the other big event films around the time, especially It's A Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World and The Great Race, both of which I enjoyed much more. One thing that made me laugh is that one Indian fell off his horse three times. It may have been three angles of the same shot. I did find it interesting that Fogg used a telescope much like the antique one I found I have. Now I wonder just how old it is?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great but All Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Saw this as a kid in school. Really liked it but really thought that David Niven was way too cold as a fish. And that Niven's Phileas Fogg though he is that way in the novel. Until Fogg showed some emotion when he and his valet Passepartout, rescued Shirley McClaine's Auoda from the fire. But still despite Niven IMHO who was the weak link in the movie. Loved Catlinflas as Passepartout. In the novel, he is French but in the movie, he is Spanish. He was big in Mexico until his death but wished he made it in America. Oh well! Still the movie had great scenery and really great all-star cast. This is where the term "cameo appearance" was coined. Michael Todd the producer of the film would die in a plane crash a year or so after the movie won the Oscar for best pic for 1956. He also was married to Liz Taylor at the time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A monument to the death of Hollywood's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Todd was a promoter. He was a man with the talent for carrying out the colossal hype, someone who could sell the proverbial refrigerator to an Eskimo. He certainly displayed his genius in this glut of scenery, costumes and extras, selling this mess of a movie to the public in 1956. This film is so charmless, so humorless, such a depiction of stereotypes and clich&eacute;s, and not less egregious, a squandering and misappropriation of acting talent. David Niven holds his own, but he single-handedly can't sustain the whole show. The talented Shirley MacLaine stands around wondering what she's doing and how she got roped into agreeing to be part of the cast. As to how Todd could have lured name stars to take on cameos, is a mystery to me. Maybe people such as Frank Sinatra and Marlene Dieterich had nothing better to do that day? Possibly the wide screen Todd A-O process engulfed viewers and glued them into their theatre seats where they watched like spellbound captives back in 1956, but today, there is absolutely nothing to recommend this movie. If nothing else, this movie stands as a testimonial to Hollywood's desperate bid to lure 1950s audiences away from their TV sets and back into the movie theatre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie has more than a handful of cast and wonderful cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is movie that goes on for 2 hours and keeps you wanting more, for the journey had beautiful scenery and nice international cast. The movie stared David Niven as Fogg and Cantinflas as Passepartout. Both characters being contradictory, Fogg is a gentleman, well-dressed, well-spoken, and extremely punctual, whereas Passepartout was the comic relief in the movie, he loved women and was a jack of all trade, their union boasted of talents and wits that saw them through the entire journey. This adventure film was produced by Michael Todd and is based on a novel of the same name by Jules Verne. Well comparing this to the 2004 remake that had Jackie Chan and Steve Coogan is going to be difficult as some of the attributes of Passepartout were given to Fogg making you lose respect for Fogg himself and the 1956 version is far different in the adventures embarked upon by the two compared to those in the 2004 version. The movie was actually filmed in 75 days and the cast including extras totaled 68,894 people and 7,959 animals. The wardrobe department spent $410,000 to provide 74,685 costumes and 36,092 trinkets. This movie packed a punch as the producers visited every country that Fogg and Passepartout passed through. The plot is about an English man in 1872 who is a member of the Reform Club, his name is Phileas Fogg (David Niven) he claims he can circumnavigate the world in eighty days. This made the other member of the Club view his claim as a bogus statement so he makes a &pound;20,000 wager (equal to over &pound;1,000,000 today) with several members of the Reform Club. The wager states that he will arrive back within 80 days before 8:45 pm. Together with his resourceful valet, Passepartout (Cantinflas), Fogg sets out on his journey which saw him save a princess, battle Indians, and as he was on his journey was named the chief suspect of stolen &pound;55,000 (equal to over &pound;3,000,000 today) from the Bank of England. This movie's wonderful cinematography was done by Lionel Lindon who won an Academy award for his work and he was involved in the photography of The Alfred Hitchcock Hour. The movie won five Academy awards, beating out critically acclaimed films like Friendly Persuasion, The Ten Commandments, Giant, and The King and I. The wins were Best Picture, Best Cinematography, Best Film Editing, Best Music and Best Writing, Best Screenplay, Adapted. This is a movie that is fun to watch and captivating to see. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am the true Kimi Gee, love hot air balloon rides
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgeouskimi
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually took a hot air balloon ride, so yes. I give this film a 10. Just to think a film from the 1950s could be so popular, Around the World in 80 Days, from the 1950s... Kimi Gee, being that I did the hot air balloon ride, probably almost made what was so exciting seem more. Why did this film get so popular? Maybe because I also went on a hot air balloon ride. What an adventure, going around the world, not knowing whether the wind would blow you to some remote island in the middle of no where or whether you would land somewhere popular that people had heard about your adventure... now I am in Guam. I tried the ride... and will try again one day... come on, it's just a balloon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good entertainment, although it drags at places.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rueiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First, I saw the Spanish cartoon adaptation in the mid-1980s, which can be quite nice for a kid's first introduction to Verne's legendary tale. Then I read the novel when I was ten years old, and later I saw this movie on TV on a Saturday afternoon.I loved it. Years later, I bought a VHS copy, and only two years ago I got the restored DVD edition, which comes with a lot of material some of which is interesting and the rest is a load of nonsense they added up just to have an excuse to produce a two-disc set. The restored movie runs for 174 minutes against the 160 or so of the old VHS. The newly added sequences are the intermission and exit music segments and some action shots previously edited that have been put back. I have to say that I find the film quite slow at times, with some sequences (the Melies "Journey to the Moon", the balloon voyage, the Spanish episode and the attack of the Sioux unnecessarily overlong and quite boring. Still, I also have to say that the film shines as to production values and its faithfulness to Verne's novel except for the balloon and the Spanish adventures. And some members of the cast are just right for their roles; I can not imagine anyone else but David Niven as Phileas Fogg, and Bobby Newton is likable as inspector Fix. But then Cantinflas, with all his natural skills for mimicry and his ability to talk like a gun-machine without saying anything solid, is a bit out of place here, since he talks Spanish at times instead of French, which is the nationality his character is supposed to be. And Shirley MacLaine,fresh from "The Trouble with Harry", seems to have been passing by when Mike Todd spotted her and immediately pulled out his chequebook and signed her in on the spot. But then, as a consolation, some of the cameos are a real delight: Coward, Gielgud,Boyer, Dietrich, Gingold, Mills... And it is John Carradine the one who stills every scene he is in, as the bullying, cigar-smoker, vulgarian Yank. He is very funny, and brings the best laughs in the film. Anyway, despite of its flaws and of being unnecessarily overlong, this film still is one of my favourite adventure epics of all time. I haven't seen the Jackie Chan - Steve Coogan remake, nor I intend to. Call me old-fashioned if you like, but I believe that in the old days movies looked much nicer and less fake than they do today courtesy of the CGI rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A beautiful, fun spectacle-- but only when watched as its creator intended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that suffers when viewed on a small screen. Made during a time when television posed a huge threat to the film industry, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a spectacle if there ever was one, a showcase of gorgeous cinematography and production values which can be appreciated nowhere else but in the theater. The acting and story were obviously of lesser importance than all the visuals. David Niven does a good job playing the quintessential British gentleman, and Cantinflas gives the most memorable performance as his comedic servant. The only lacking performance is given by Shirley MacLaine as Aouda, not only because she looks nothing like she's from India, but because she's uninteresting and never brings her character to life. There's also dozens of cameos sprinkled throughout, which are fun to look for if you're familiar with classic Hollywood personalities. For those who don't mind style over substance, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a treat indeed. If you're not one of those people, then hold off unless you ever get to see it on the big screen, where one can most appreciate all the film has to offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1956: Disney Verne and Todd Verne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    reisen55
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time has dulled my memory of this film. Bought the restored DVD a few weeks ago and began watching it last night. And it is one of those odd films that was great in 1956 when travel was new and the audience unsophisticated. What struck me today is now simple it really is. Some locations, London, Paris and Spain are gorgeous, plus local to Europe. The music is grand, and it works like a charm. As soon as the film departs Spain, we enter (a) Hollywood backlot sets and (b) traveloge territory where all too long we are treated to gorgeous, and dull, camera shots of distant countries while Niven and Company are off screen. Only Europe and America are really used in real-time sets. The rest is amazingly artificial. Now, I love Cantinflas who is a wonderful clone of Chaplin in this film - blood cousin to the Tramp. Niven is precise and perfect. MacClaine is rather wasted and dear Robert Newton is a treasure. Victor Young's score is ideal. BUT SINCE WE ARE on Verne in 1956, turn the page to 20,000 LEAGUES UNDER THE SEA and we have Verne done RIGHT!!! Disney's best action film ever, and far superior to Todd's globe trotting epic. So watch this 1956 memory with some careful planning. Be prepared, your memory may be better off to keep without spoiling it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It comes off like a 9-hour travelogue, but maybe it's something you may want to see once.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I watched "Around the World in Eighty Days" tonight, I noticde that it is a beautiful and spectacular film. The first time I tried seeing it was on a 25" TV--this time it's on a 58" one and the beauty is much more obvious. Too bad I couldn't have seen this on the big screen using the amazing 70mm cameras. And, if they brought it back to the theaters, I might be tempted to see it that way--even though the film does have many shortcomings. I've got to be honest here, I tried watching this film years ago and gave up on it. The only reason I am watching it through to the end now is that I would like to eventually see all the Best Picture winners--even the incredibly overblown ones. This brings me to a pet peeve I have. I HATE films that feature a bazillion cameos. I find that often the plethora of stars tend to get in the way of the story and often soak up a huge portion of the budget--leaving precious little for writing. Some of the stars in the film are very international in flavor and I never would have recognized them the first time I tried to see this movie 25 years ago. Now, after having seen and reviewed a ridiculous number of films, I was actually excited by some of these casting decisions. Catinflas, though completely unknown in America did some marvelous little comedies in Mexico--and he is the other reason I chose to try watching the movie again. I was to see Fernandel (who also made many wonderful films--in France and Italy). But, I was also maddened because his cameo as a hack driver was so short and unfunny--completely wasting his wonderful comedic talents. And this trend continued for several more of the cameo--wonderful actors who really have nothing to do and are pretty much wasted. At least 30 minutes could have and should have been cut from the film. I am NOT against long films...if they are well-paced. Too many times in this movie, however, scenes just unfold way too slowly--such as when the balloon is going over the Alps. A VERY LONG period of nice music and shots of the balloon are shown--when it really seemed interminably long. This reminded me of the major problem with "Star Trek: The Motion Picture"--too many unnecessarily long shots which killed the film's momentum. The bullfighting scene is also one that goes on and on and on and could have been 1/3 as long. Many other such examples followed. So is it a great film? No. I agree with another reviewer who felt the movie got an Oscar for Best Picture simply because it was such a spectacle--not because it was especially good. It's one of the weaker Best Picture films of the era, in my opinion. However, I must give the film its due. The movie is beautiful in every way--great costumes, amazing locations and sets, breathtaking cinematography and a scope that cannot really be matched. But, it is also very, very , very long with poor pacing, suffers from an overuse and wasting of cameos and just isn't that interesting. Catinflas was a very gifted and funny man--here you don't get a great sense of that at all. Likewise, David Niven was a very fine actor--but here he's more like set dressing and you don't get to see him at his best. Before I conclude, let's talk about the cameos. With all the many cameos, why did they pick Shirley MacLaine to play an Indian princess?! Talk about bizarre casting! And why have Frank Sinatra in a cameo that takes two seconds and he just turns and smiles at the camera?! I don't get it. And what was with John Carradine?! Even for him he over-acted horribly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adventure, Colorful and Long.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lots of money, effort, and publicity on display in this story of an fastidious British gentleman, David Niven, who manages to use the technology of the Victorian era to travel, well, around the world in 80 days, with sidekick Cantinflas, and picking up Princess Shirley MacLaine along the way. Producer Michael Todd put everything he had into it. It was a tremendous splash at the time using a special projective technique, plenty of music that went into a best-selling album, and the face of every recognizable actor of every nationality imaginable. There are theatrical knights in abundance. Let's see. There's Sir John Gielgud, Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sir John Mills, and Sir Frank Sinatra. Now, fifty-six years after its release, it's hard to see what all the fuss was about. It's BIG of course, but it more or less had to be. What was happening in 1955 to the movie industry? It was being replaced by television and studios were desperate for novelty, something the audience couldn't find on their small black and white sets at home -- in this case, a MAGNIFICOLOR extravaganza in TODD-A-OMG-VISION! Look -- there's Marlene Dietrich! And that's the guy, what's his name, the sergeant from that John Ford cavalry movie! Gosh! The problem with the flick is that it's really designed to elicit gasps from a family audience. Not laughs, not thrills, not clenched teeth. You're supposed to sit back as at a travelogue and marvel at the sights of a Spanish bullfight, in which a clumsy Cantinflas taunts a bull while trying to hold his pants up (ha ha), and a painted elephant in India, and all kinds of definitely retrograde stereotypes -- bullfights, flamenco dancers (good ones), thugee, suttee, jabbering Chinese, bowing Japanese, a steamboat that has to destroy itself to provide its own fuel, hostile American Indians attacking a train, a rescue by the cavalry. It all must have been thrilling if you'd never seen it before, but in order not to have seen it before you'd have to be no more than fifteen years old. There are some smiles. Here's the one that got to me. The opening scene is in one of those stuffy, tradition-ridden English gentleman's clubs. The figures are mostly motionless. The gentlemen sit playing whist or reading newspapers. No one is speaking. A cat pads through the room. And one gentleman complains to a steward, "Can't you stop that animal from stomping around?" I wish there had been more jokes or physical gags. I wish it wouldn't depend so heavily on a viewer's ability to be astounded by all the production values and the innumerable cameos. Want to see a more entertaining movie along the same lines? See "The Great Race."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable once
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    implaxible
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stuck it out but was reminded that the previous time I saw it I had decided that I did not ever need to see it again. But this time it was in HD! Random comments: This was obviously made for the Cinerama (Todd-AO) screen, with the many travelogue scenes that are pretty but now read like a demonstration reel for a new (1950s) projection feature at Disney World. Many "look out the window, stock shot" sequences. OK, so they weren't stock shots but it sure felt like it. IMDb says that at the time, Cantinflas was the highest-paid movie star in world. Apparently popular everywhere but the U.S. I did not find him particularly engaging or appealing. There is nary a bit of humor or tension in the whole film. Each crisis is instantly solved by either money or a simple "Land Ho!". In fact, some sequences drag on way too long, specifically the ones in Spain. (Maybe for the Cantinflas audience?) There is a bullfighting sequence that goes on for nearly 15 minutes where absolutely nothing is at stake and the movie stops completely dead. It was startling to go from the cinematic location shots to the obvious backlot first unit stuff. For such an "epic", it felt quite claustrophobic. I liked and recognized many of the cameos. Apparently this was the film that started that trend. The music was lush and wonderful, and the end title sequence was quite engaging (a Saul Bass production). This version had the Edward R. Murrow intro which I had not seen before, and the Intermission, Entracte, and Exit Music, all of which I quite like in an epic film event. I kept mentally comparing this to some of the other big event films around the time, especially It's A Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World and The Great Race, both of which I enjoyed much more. One thing that made me laugh is that one Indian fell off his horse three times. It may have been three angles of the same shot. I did find it interesting that Fogg used a telescope much like the antique one I found I have. Now I wonder just how old it is?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great but All Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Saw this as a kid in school. Really liked it but really thought that David Niven was way too cold as a fish. And that Niven's Phileas Fogg though he is that way in the novel. Until Fogg showed some emotion when he and his valet Passepartout, rescued Shirley McClaine's Auoda from the fire. But still despite Niven IMHO who was the weak link in the movie. Loved Catlinflas as Passepartout. In the novel, he is French but in the movie, he is Spanish. He was big in Mexico until his death but wished he made it in America. Oh well! Still the movie had great scenery and really great all-star cast. This is where the term "cameo appearance" was coined. Michael Todd the producer of the film would die in a plane crash a year or so after the movie won the Oscar for best pic for 1956. He also was married to Liz Taylor at the time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A monument to the death of Hollywood's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Todd was a promoter. He was a man with the talent for carrying out the colossal hype, someone who could sell the proverbial refrigerator to an Eskimo. He certainly displayed his genius in this glut of scenery, costumes and extras, selling this mess of a movie to the public in 1956. This film is so charmless, so humorless, such a depiction of stereotypes and clich&eacute;s, and not less egregious, a squandering and misappropriation of acting talent. David Niven holds his own, but he single-handedly can't sustain the whole show. The talented Shirley MacLaine stands around wondering what she's doing and how she got roped into agreeing to be part of the cast. As to how Todd could have lured name stars to take on cameos, is a mystery to me. Maybe people such as Frank Sinatra and Marlene Dieterich had nothing better to do that day? Possibly the wide screen Todd A-O process engulfed viewers and glued them into their theatre seats where they watched like spellbound captives back in 1956, but today, there is absolutely nothing to recommend this movie. If nothing else, this movie stands as a testimonial to Hollywood's desperate bid to lure 1950s audiences away from their TV sets and back into the movie theatre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie has more than a handful of cast and wonderful cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is movie that goes on for 2 hours and keeps you wanting more, for the journey had beautiful scenery and nice international cast. The movie stared David Niven as Fogg and Cantinflas as Passepartout. Both characters being contradictory, Fogg is a gentleman, well-dressed, well-spoken, and extremely punctual, whereas Passepartout was the comic relief in the movie, he loved women and was a jack of all trade, their union boasted of talents and wits that saw them through the entire journey. This adventure film was produced by Michael Todd and is based on a novel of the same name by Jules Verne. Well comparing this to the 2004 remake that had Jackie Chan and Steve Coogan is going to be difficult as some of the attributes of Passepartout were given to Fogg making you lose respect for Fogg himself and the 1956 version is far different in the adventures embarked upon by the two compared to those in the 2004 version. The movie was actually filmed in 75 days and the cast including extras totaled 68,894 people and 7,959 animals. The wardrobe department spent $410,000 to provide 74,685 costumes and 36,092 trinkets. This movie packed a punch as the producers visited every country that Fogg and Passepartout passed through. The plot is about an English man in 1872 who is a member of the Reform Club, his name is Phileas Fogg (David Niven) he claims he can circumnavigate the world in eighty days. This made the other member of the Club view his claim as a bogus statement so he makes a &pound;20,000 wager (equal to over &pound;1,000,000 today) with several members of the Reform Club. The wager states that he will arrive back within 80 days before 8:45 pm. Together with his resourceful valet, Passepartout (Cantinflas), Fogg sets out on his journey which saw him save a princess, battle Indians, and as he was on his journey was named the chief suspect of stolen &pound;55,000 (equal to over &pound;3,000,000 today) from the Bank of England. This movie's wonderful cinematography was done by Lionel Lindon who won an Academy award for his work and he was involved in the photography of The Alfred Hitchcock Hour. The movie won five Academy awards, beating out critically acclaimed films like Friendly Persuasion, The Ten Commandments, Giant, and The King and I. The wins were Best Picture, Best Cinematography, Best Film Editing, Best Music and Best Writing, Best Screenplay, Adapted. This is a movie that is fun to watch and captivating to see. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am the true Kimi Gee, love hot air balloon rides
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgeouskimi
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually took a hot air balloon ride, so yes. I give this film a 10. Just to think a film from the 1950s could be so popular, Around the World in 80 Days, from the 1950s... Kimi Gee, being that I did the hot air balloon ride, probably almost made what was so exciting seem more. Why did this film get so popular? Maybe because I also went on a hot air balloon ride. What an adventure, going around the world, not knowing whether the wind would blow you to some remote island in the middle of no where or whether you would land somewhere popular that people had heard about your adventure... now I am in Guam. I tried the ride... and will try again one day... come on, it's just a balloon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good entertainment, although it drags at places.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rueiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First, I saw the Spanish cartoon adaptation in the mid-1980s, which can be quite nice for a kid's first introduction to Verne's legendary tale. Then I read the novel when I was ten years old, and later I saw this movie on TV on a Saturday afternoon.I loved it. Years later, I bought a VHS copy, and only two years ago I got the restored DVD edition, which comes with a lot of material some of which is interesting and the rest is a load of nonsense they added up just to have an excuse to produce a two-disc set. The restored movie runs for 174 minutes against the 160 or so of the old VHS. The newly added sequences are the intermission and exit music segments and some action shots previously edited that have been put back. I have to say that I find the film quite slow at times, with some sequences (the Melies "Journey to the Moon", the balloon voyage, the Spanish episode and the attack of the Sioux unnecessarily overlong and quite boring. Still, I also have to say that the film shines as to production values and its faithfulness to Verne's novel except for the balloon and the Spanish adventures. And some members of the cast are just right for their roles; I can not imagine anyone else but David Niven as Phileas Fogg, and Bobby Newton is likable as inspector Fix. But then Cantinflas, with all his natural skills for mimicry and his ability to talk like a gun-machine without saying anything solid, is a bit out of place here, since he talks Spanish at times instead of French, which is the nationality his character is supposed to be. And Shirley MacLaine,fresh from "The Trouble with Harry", seems to have been passing by when Mike Todd spotted her and immediately pulled out his chequebook and signed her in on the spot. But then, as a consolation, some of the cameos are a real delight: Coward, Gielgud,Boyer, Dietrich, Gingold, Mills... And it is John Carradine the one who stills every scene he is in, as the bullying, cigar-smoker, vulgarian Yank. He is very funny, and brings the best laughs in the film. Anyway, despite of its flaws and of being unnecessarily overlong, this film still is one of my favourite adventure epics of all time. I haven't seen the Jackie Chan - Steve Coogan remake, nor I intend to. Call me old-fashioned if you like, but I believe that in the old days movies looked much nicer and less fake than they do today courtesy of the CGI rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A beautiful, fun spectacle-- but only when watched as its creator intended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that suffers when viewed on a small screen. Made during a time when television posed a huge threat to the film industry, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a spectacle if there ever was one, a showcase of gorgeous cinematography and production values which can be appreciated nowhere else but in the theater. The acting and story were obviously of lesser importance than all the visuals. David Niven does a good job playing the quintessential British gentleman, and Cantinflas gives the most memorable performance as his comedic servant. The only lacking performance is given by Shirley MacLaine as Aouda, not only because she looks nothing like she's from India, but because she's uninteresting and never brings her character to life. There's also dozens of cameos sprinkled throughout, which are fun to look for if you're familiar with classic Hollywood personalities. For those who don't mind style over substance, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a treat indeed. If you're not one of those people, then hold off unless you ever get to see it on the big screen, where one can most appreciate all the film has to offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1956: Disney Verne and Todd Verne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    reisen55
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time has dulled my memory of this film. Bought the restored DVD a few weeks ago and began watching it last night. And it is one of those odd films that was great in 1956 when travel was new and the audience unsophisticated. What struck me today is now simple it really is. Some locations, London, Paris and Spain are gorgeous, plus local to Europe. The music is grand, and it works like a charm. As soon as the film departs Spain, we enter (a) Hollywood backlot sets and (b) traveloge territory where all too long we are treated to gorgeous, and dull, camera shots of distant countries while Niven and Company are off screen. Only Europe and America are really used in real-time sets. The rest is amazingly artificial. Now, I love Cantinflas who is a wonderful clone of Chaplin in this film - blood cousin to the Tramp. Niven is precise and perfect. MacClaine is rather wasted and dear Robert Newton is a treasure. Victor Young's score is ideal. BUT SINCE WE ARE on Verne in 1956, turn the page to 20,000 LEAGUES UNDER THE SEA and we have Verne done RIGHT!!! Disney's best action film ever, and far superior to Todd's globe trotting epic. So watch this 1956 memory with some careful planning. Be prepared, your memory may be better off to keep without spoiling it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It comes off like a 9-hour travelogue, but maybe it's something you may want to see once.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I watched "Around the World in Eighty Days" tonight, I noticde that it is a beautiful and spectacular film. The first time I tried seeing it was on a 25" TV--this time it's on a 58" one and the beauty is much more obvious. Too bad I couldn't have seen this on the big screen using the amazing 70mm cameras. And, if they brought it back to the theaters, I might be tempted to see it that way--even though the film does have many shortcomings. I've got to be honest here, I tried watching this film years ago and gave up on it. The only reason I am watching it through to the end now is that I would like to eventually see all the Best Picture winners--even the incredibly overblown ones. This brings me to a pet peeve I have. I HATE films that feature a bazillion cameos. I find that often the plethora of stars tend to get in the way of the story and often soak up a huge portion of the budget--leaving precious little for writing. Some of the stars in the film are very international in flavor and I never would have recognized them the first time I tried to see this movie 25 years ago. Now, after having seen and reviewed a ridiculous number of films, I was actually excited by some of these casting decisions. Catinflas, though completely unknown in America did some marvelous little comedies in Mexico--and he is the other reason I chose to try watching the movie again. I was to see Fernandel (who also made many wonderful films--in France and Italy). But, I was also maddened because his cameo as a hack driver was so short and unfunny--completely wasting his wonderful comedic talents. And this trend continued for several more of the cameo--wonderful actors who really have nothing to do and are pretty much wasted. At least 30 minutes could have and should have been cut from the film. I am NOT against long films...if they are well-paced. Too many times in this movie, however, scenes just unfold way too slowly--such as when the balloon is going over the Alps. A VERY LONG period of nice music and shots of the balloon are shown--when it really seemed interminably long. This reminded me of the major problem with "Star Trek: The Motion Picture"--too many unnecessarily long shots which killed the film's momentum. The bullfighting scene is also one that goes on and on and on and could have been 1/3 as long. Many other such examples followed. So is it a great film? No. I agree with another reviewer who felt the movie got an Oscar for Best Picture simply because it was such a spectacle--not because it was especially good. It's one of the weaker Best Picture films of the era, in my opinion. However, I must give the film its due. The movie is beautiful in every way--great costumes, amazing locations and sets, breathtaking cinematography and a scope that cannot really be matched. But, it is also very, very , very long with poor pacing, suffers from an overuse and wasting of cameos and just isn't that interesting. Catinflas was a very gifted and funny man--here you don't get a great sense of that at all. Likewise, David Niven was a very fine actor--but here he's more like set dressing and you don't get to see him at his best. Before I conclude, let's talk about the cameos. With all the many cameos, why did they pick Shirley MacLaine to play an Indian princess?! Talk about bizarre casting! And why have Frank Sinatra in a cameo that takes two seconds and he just turns and smiles at the camera?! I don't get it. And what was with John Carradine?! Even for him he over-acted horribly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adventure, Colorful and Long.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lots of money, effort, and publicity on display in this story of an fastidious British gentleman, David Niven, who manages to use the technology of the Victorian era to travel, well, around the world in 80 days, with sidekick Cantinflas, and picking up Princess Shirley MacLaine along the way. Producer Michael Todd put everything he had into it. It was a tremendous splash at the time using a special projective technique, plenty of music that went into a best-selling album, and the face of every recognizable actor of every nationality imaginable. There are theatrical knights in abundance. Let's see. There's Sir John Gielgud, Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sir John Mills, and Sir Frank Sinatra. Now, fifty-six years after its release, it's hard to see what all the fuss was about. It's BIG of course, but it more or less had to be. What was happening in 1955 to the movie industry? It was being replaced by television and studios were desperate for novelty, something the audience couldn't find on their small black and white sets at home -- in this case, a MAGNIFICOLOR extravaganza in TODD-A-OMG-VISION! Look -- there's Marlene Dietrich! And that's the guy, what's his name, the sergeant from that John Ford cavalry movie! Gosh! The problem with the flick is that it's really designed to elicit gasps from a family audience. Not laughs, not thrills, not clenched teeth. You're supposed to sit back as at a travelogue and marvel at the sights of a Spanish bullfight, in which a clumsy Cantinflas taunts a bull while trying to hold his pants up (ha ha), and a painted elephant in India, and all kinds of definitely retrograde stereotypes -- bullfights, flamenco dancers (good ones), thugee, suttee, jabbering Chinese, bowing Japanese, a steamboat that has to destroy itself to provide its own fuel, hostile American Indians attacking a train, a rescue by the cavalry. It all must have been thrilling if you'd never seen it before, but in order not to have seen it before you'd have to be no more than fifteen years old. There are some smiles. Here's the one that got to me. The opening scene is in one of those stuffy, tradition-ridden English gentleman's clubs. The figures are mostly motionless. The gentlemen sit playing whist or reading newspapers. No one is speaking. A cat pads through the room. And one gentleman complains to a steward, "Can't you stop that animal from stomping around?" I wish there had been more jokes or physical gags. I wish it wouldn't depend so heavily on a viewer's ability to be astounded by all the production values and the innumerable cameos. Want to see a more entertaining movie along the same lines? See "The Great Race."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable once
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    implaxible
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stuck it out but was reminded that the previous time I saw it I had decided that I did not ever need to see it again. But this time it was in HD! Random comments: This was obviously made for the Cinerama (Todd-AO) screen, with the many travelogue scenes that are pretty but now read like a demonstration reel for a new (1950s) projection feature at Disney World. Many "look out the window, stock shot" sequences. OK, so they weren't stock shots but it sure felt like it. IMDb says that at the time, Cantinflas was the highest-paid movie star in world. Apparently popular everywhere but the U.S. I did not find him particularly engaging or appealing. There is nary a bit of humor or tension in the whole film. Each crisis is instantly solved by either money or a simple "Land Ho!". In fact, some sequences drag on way too long, specifically the ones in Spain. (Maybe for the Cantinflas audience?) There is a bullfighting sequence that goes on for nearly 15 minutes where absolutely nothing is at stake and the movie stops completely dead. It was startling to go from the cinematic location shots to the obvious backlot first unit stuff. For such an "epic", it felt quite claustrophobic. I liked and recognized many of the cameos. Apparently this was the film that started that trend. The music was lush and wonderful, and the end title sequence was quite engaging (a Saul Bass production). This version had the Edward R. Murrow intro which I had not seen before, and the Intermission, Entracte, and Exit Music, all of which I quite like in an epic film event. I kept mentally comparing this to some of the other big event films around the time, especially It's A Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World and The Great Race, both of which I enjoyed much more. One thing that made me laugh is that one Indian fell off his horse three times. It may have been three angles of the same shot. I did find it interesting that Fogg used a telescope much like the antique one I found I have. Now I wonder just how old it is?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great but All Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Saw this as a kid in school. Really liked it but really thought that David Niven was way too cold as a fish. And that Niven's Phileas Fogg though he is that way in the novel. Until Fogg showed some emotion when he and his valet Passepartout, rescued Shirley McClaine's Auoda from the fire. But still despite Niven IMHO who was the weak link in the movie. Loved Catlinflas as Passepartout. In the novel, he is French but in the movie, he is Spanish. He was big in Mexico until his death but wished he made it in America. Oh well! Still the movie had great scenery and really great all-star cast. This is where the term "cameo appearance" was coined. Michael Todd the producer of the film would die in a plane crash a year or so after the movie won the Oscar for best pic for 1956. He also was married to Liz Taylor at the time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A monument to the death of Hollywood's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Todd was a promoter. He was a man with the talent for carrying out the colossal hype, someone who could sell the proverbial refrigerator to an Eskimo. He certainly displayed his genius in this glut of scenery, costumes and extras, selling this mess of a movie to the public in 1956. This film is so charmless, so humorless, such a depiction of stereotypes and clich&eacute;s, and not less egregious, a squandering and misappropriation of acting talent. David Niven holds his own, but he single-handedly can't sustain the whole show. The talented Shirley MacLaine stands around wondering what she's doing and how she got roped into agreeing to be part of the cast. As to how Todd could have lured name stars to take on cameos, is a mystery to me. Maybe people such as Frank Sinatra and Marlene Dieterich had nothing better to do that day? Possibly the wide screen Todd A-O process engulfed viewers and glued them into their theatre seats where they watched like spellbound captives back in 1956, but today, there is absolutely nothing to recommend this movie. If nothing else, this movie stands as a testimonial to Hollywood's desperate bid to lure 1950s audiences away from their TV sets and back into the movie theatre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie has more than a handful of cast and wonderful cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is movie that goes on for 2 hours and keeps you wanting more, for the journey had beautiful scenery and nice international cast. The movie stared David Niven as Fogg and Cantinflas as Passepartout. Both characters being contradictory, Fogg is a gentleman, well-dressed, well-spoken, and extremely punctual, whereas Passepartout was the comic relief in the movie, he loved women and was a jack of all trade, their union boasted of talents and wits that saw them through the entire journey. This adventure film was produced by Michael Todd and is based on a novel of the same name by Jules Verne. Well comparing this to the 2004 remake that had Jackie Chan and Steve Coogan is going to be difficult as some of the attributes of Passepartout were given to Fogg making you lose respect for Fogg himself and the 1956 version is far different in the adventures embarked upon by the two compared to those in the 2004 version. The movie was actually filmed in 75 days and the cast including extras totaled 68,894 people and 7,959 animals. The wardrobe department spent $410,000 to provide 74,685 costumes and 36,092 trinkets. This movie packed a punch as the producers visited every country that Fogg and Passepartout passed through. The plot is about an English man in 1872 who is a member of the Reform Club, his name is Phileas Fogg (David Niven) he claims he can circumnavigate the world in eighty days. This made the other member of the Club view his claim as a bogus statement so he makes a &pound;20,000 wager (equal to over &pound;1,000,000 today) with several members of the Reform Club. The wager states that he will arrive back within 80 days before 8:45 pm. Together with his resourceful valet, Passepartout (Cantinflas), Fogg sets out on his journey which saw him save a princess, battle Indians, and as he was on his journey was named the chief suspect of stolen &pound;55,000 (equal to over &pound;3,000,000 today) from the Bank of England. This movie's wonderful cinematography was done by Lionel Lindon who won an Academy award for his work and he was involved in the photography of The Alfred Hitchcock Hour. The movie won five Academy awards, beating out critically acclaimed films like Friendly Persuasion, The Ten Commandments, Giant, and The King and I. The wins were Best Picture, Best Cinematography, Best Film Editing, Best Music and Best Writing, Best Screenplay, Adapted. This is a movie that is fun to watch and captivating to see. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am the true Kimi Gee, love hot air balloon rides
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgeouskimi
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually took a hot air balloon ride, so yes. I give this film a 10. Just to think a film from the 1950s could be so popular, Around the World in 80 Days, from the 1950s... Kimi Gee, being that I did the hot air balloon ride, probably almost made what was so exciting seem more. Why did this film get so popular? Maybe because I also went on a hot air balloon ride. What an adventure, going around the world, not knowing whether the wind would blow you to some remote island in the middle of no where or whether you would land somewhere popular that people had heard about your adventure... now I am in Guam. I tried the ride... and will try again one day... come on, it's just a balloon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good entertainment, although it drags at places.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rueiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First, I saw the Spanish cartoon adaptation in the mid-1980s, which can be quite nice for a kid's first introduction to Verne's legendary tale. Then I read the novel when I was ten years old, and later I saw this movie on TV on a Saturday afternoon.I loved it. Years later, I bought a VHS copy, and only two years ago I got the restored DVD edition, which comes with a lot of material some of which is interesting and the rest is a load of nonsense they added up just to have an excuse to produce a two-disc set. The restored movie runs for 174 minutes against the 160 or so of the old VHS. The newly added sequences are the intermission and exit music segments and some action shots previously edited that have been put back. I have to say that I find the film quite slow at times, with some sequences (the Melies "Journey to the Moon", the balloon voyage, the Spanish episode and the attack of the Sioux unnecessarily overlong and quite boring. Still, I also have to say that the film shines as to production values and its faithfulness to Verne's novel except for the balloon and the Spanish adventures. And some members of the cast are just right for their roles; I can not imagine anyone else but David Niven as Phileas Fogg, and Bobby Newton is likable as inspector Fix. But then Cantinflas, with all his natural skills for mimicry and his ability to talk like a gun-machine without saying anything solid, is a bit out of place here, since he talks Spanish at times instead of French, which is the nationality his character is supposed to be. And Shirley MacLaine,fresh from "The Trouble with Harry", seems to have been passing by when Mike Todd spotted her and immediately pulled out his chequebook and signed her in on the spot. But then, as a consolation, some of the cameos are a real delight: Coward, Gielgud,Boyer, Dietrich, Gingold, Mills... And it is John Carradine the one who stills every scene he is in, as the bullying, cigar-smoker, vulgarian Yank. He is very funny, and brings the best laughs in the film. Anyway, despite of its flaws and of being unnecessarily overlong, this film still is one of my favourite adventure epics of all time. I haven't seen the Jackie Chan - Steve Coogan remake, nor I intend to. Call me old-fashioned if you like, but I believe that in the old days movies looked much nicer and less fake than they do today courtesy of the CGI rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A beautiful, fun spectacle-- but only when watched as its creator intended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that suffers when viewed on a small screen. Made during a time when television posed a huge threat to the film industry, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a spectacle if there ever was one, a showcase of gorgeous cinematography and production values which can be appreciated nowhere else but in the theater. The acting and story were obviously of lesser importance than all the visuals. David Niven does a good job playing the quintessential British gentleman, and Cantinflas gives the most memorable performance as his comedic servant. The only lacking performance is given by Shirley MacLaine as Aouda, not only because she looks nothing like she's from India, but because she's uninteresting and never brings her character to life. There's also dozens of cameos sprinkled throughout, which are fun to look for if you're familiar with classic Hollywood personalities. For those who don't mind style over substance, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a treat indeed. If you're not one of those people, then hold off unless you ever get to see it on the big screen, where one can most appreciate all the film has to offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1956: Disney Verne and Todd Verne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    reisen55
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time has dulled my memory of this film. Bought the restored DVD a few weeks ago and began watching it last night. And it is one of those odd films that was great in 1956 when travel was new and the audience unsophisticated. What struck me today is now simple it really is. Some locations, London, Paris and Spain are gorgeous, plus local to Europe. The music is grand, and it works like a charm. As soon as the film departs Spain, we enter (a) Hollywood backlot sets and (b) traveloge territory where all too long we are treated to gorgeous, and dull, camera shots of distant countries while Niven and Company are off screen. Only Europe and America are really used in real-time sets. The rest is amazingly artificial. Now, I love Cantinflas who is a wonderful clone of Chaplin in this film - blood cousin to the Tramp. Niven is precise and perfect. MacClaine is rather wasted and dear Robert Newton is a treasure. Victor Young's score is ideal. BUT SINCE WE ARE on Verne in 1956, turn the page to 20,000 LEAGUES UNDER THE SEA and we have Verne done RIGHT!!! Disney's best action film ever, and far superior to Todd's globe trotting epic. So watch this 1956 memory with some careful planning. Be prepared, your memory may be better off to keep without spoiling it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It comes off like a 9-hour travelogue, but maybe it's something you may want to see once.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I watched "Around the World in Eighty Days" tonight, I noticde that it is a beautiful and spectacular film. The first time I tried seeing it was on a 25" TV--this time it's on a 58" one and the beauty is much more obvious. Too bad I couldn't have seen this on the big screen using the amazing 70mm cameras. And, if they brought it back to the theaters, I might be tempted to see it that way--even though the film does have many shortcomings. I've got to be honest here, I tried watching this film years ago and gave up on it. The only reason I am watching it through to the end now is that I would like to eventually see all the Best Picture winners--even the incredibly overblown ones. This brings me to a pet peeve I have. I HATE films that feature a bazillion cameos. I find that often the plethora of stars tend to get in the way of the story and often soak up a huge portion of the budget--leaving precious little for writing. Some of the stars in the film are very international in flavor and I never would have recognized them the first time I tried to see this movie 25 years ago. Now, after having seen and reviewed a ridiculous number of films, I was actually excited by some of these casting decisions. Catinflas, though completely unknown in America did some marvelous little comedies in Mexico--and he is the other reason I chose to try watching the movie again. I was to see Fernandel (who also made many wonderful films--in France and Italy). But, I was also maddened because his cameo as a hack driver was so short and unfunny--completely wasting his wonderful comedic talents. And this trend continued for several more of the cameo--wonderful actors who really have nothing to do and are pretty much wasted. At least 30 minutes could have and should have been cut from the film. I am NOT against long films...if they are well-paced. Too many times in this movie, however, scenes just unfold way too slowly--such as when the balloon is going over the Alps. A VERY LONG period of nice music and shots of the balloon are shown--when it really seemed interminably long. This reminded me of the major problem with "Star Trek: The Motion Picture"--too many unnecessarily long shots which killed the film's momentum. The bullfighting scene is also one that goes on and on and on and could have been 1/3 as long. Many other such examples followed. So is it a great film? No. I agree with another reviewer who felt the movie got an Oscar for Best Picture simply because it was such a spectacle--not because it was especially good. It's one of the weaker Best Picture films of the era, in my opinion. However, I must give the film its due. The movie is beautiful in every way--great costumes, amazing locations and sets, breathtaking cinematography and a scope that cannot really be matched. But, it is also very, very , very long with poor pacing, suffers from an overuse and wasting of cameos and just isn't that interesting. Catinflas was a very gifted and funny man--here you don't get a great sense of that at all. Likewise, David Niven was a very fine actor--but here he's more like set dressing and you don't get to see him at his best. Before I conclude, let's talk about the cameos. With all the many cameos, why did they pick Shirley MacLaine to play an Indian princess?! Talk about bizarre casting! And why have Frank Sinatra in a cameo that takes two seconds and he just turns and smiles at the camera?! I don't get it. And what was with John Carradine?! Even for him he over-acted horribly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adventure, Colorful and Long.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lots of money, effort, and publicity on display in this story of an fastidious British gentleman, David Niven, who manages to use the technology of the Victorian era to travel, well, around the world in 80 days, with sidekick Cantinflas, and picking up Princess Shirley MacLaine along the way. Producer Michael Todd put everything he had into it. It was a tremendous splash at the time using a special projective technique, plenty of music that went into a best-selling album, and the face of every recognizable actor of every nationality imaginable. There are theatrical knights in abundance. Let's see. There's Sir John Gielgud, Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sir John Mills, and Sir Frank Sinatra. Now, fifty-six years after its release, it's hard to see what all the fuss was about. It's BIG of course, but it more or less had to be. What was happening in 1955 to the movie industry? It was being replaced by television and studios were desperate for novelty, something the audience couldn't find on their small black and white sets at home -- in this case, a MAGNIFICOLOR extravaganza in TODD-A-OMG-VISION! Look -- there's Marlene Dietrich! And that's the guy, what's his name, the sergeant from that John Ford cavalry movie! Gosh! The problem with the flick is that it's really designed to elicit gasps from a family audience. Not laughs, not thrills, not clenched teeth. You're supposed to sit back as at a travelogue and marvel at the sights of a Spanish bullfight, in which a clumsy Cantinflas taunts a bull while trying to hold his pants up (ha ha), and a painted elephant in India, and all kinds of definitely retrograde stereotypes -- bullfights, flamenco dancers (good ones), thugee, suttee, jabbering Chinese, bowing Japanese, a steamboat that has to destroy itself to provide its own fuel, hostile American Indians attacking a train, a rescue by the cavalry. It all must have been thrilling if you'd never seen it before, but in order not to have seen it before you'd have to be no more than fifteen years old. There are some smiles. Here's the one that got to me. The opening scene is in one of those stuffy, tradition-ridden English gentleman's clubs. The figures are mostly motionless. The gentlemen sit playing whist or reading newspapers. No one is speaking. A cat pads through the room. And one gentleman complains to a steward, "Can't you stop that animal from stomping around?" I wish there had been more jokes or physical gags. I wish it wouldn't depend so heavily on a viewer's ability to be astounded by all the production values and the innumerable cameos. Want to see a more entertaining movie along the same lines? See "The Great Race."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable once
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    implaxible
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stuck it out but was reminded that the previous time I saw it I had decided that I did not ever need to see it again. But this time it was in HD! Random comments: This was obviously made for the Cinerama (Todd-AO) screen, with the many travelogue scenes that are pretty but now read like a demonstration reel for a new (1950s) projection feature at Disney World. Many "look out the window, stock shot" sequences. OK, so they weren't stock shots but it sure felt like it. IMDb says that at the time, Cantinflas was the highest-paid movie star in world. Apparently popular everywhere but the U.S. I did not find him particularly engaging or appealing. There is nary a bit of humor or tension in the whole film. Each crisis is instantly solved by either money or a simple "Land Ho!". In fact, some sequences drag on way too long, specifically the ones in Spain. (Maybe for the Cantinflas audience?) There is a bullfighting sequence that goes on for nearly 15 minutes where absolutely nothing is at stake and the movie stops completely dead. It was startling to go from the cinematic location shots to the obvious backlot first unit stuff. For such an "epic", it felt quite claustrophobic. I liked and recognized many of the cameos. Apparently this was the film that started that trend. The music was lush and wonderful, and the end title sequence was quite engaging (a Saul Bass production). This version had the Edward R. Murrow intro which I had not seen before, and the Intermission, Entracte, and Exit Music, all of which I quite like in an epic film event. I kept mentally comparing this to some of the other big event films around the time, especially It's A Mad, Mad, Mad, Mad World and The Great Race, both of which I enjoyed much more. One thing that made me laugh is that one Indian fell off his horse three times. It may have been three angles of the same shot. I did find it interesting that Fogg used a telescope much like the antique one I found I have. Now I wonder just how old it is?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great but All Awesome!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Saw this as a kid in school. Really liked it but really thought that David Niven was way too cold as a fish. And that Niven's Phileas Fogg though he is that way in the novel. Until Fogg showed some emotion when he and his valet Passepartout, rescued Shirley McClaine's Auoda from the fire. But still despite Niven IMHO who was the weak link in the movie. Loved Catlinflas as Passepartout. In the novel, he is French but in the movie, he is Spanish. He was big in Mexico until his death but wished he made it in America. Oh well! Still the movie had great scenery and really great all-star cast. This is where the term "cameo appearance" was coined. Michael Todd the producer of the film would die in a plane crash a year or so after the movie won the Oscar for best pic for 1956. He also was married to Liz Taylor at the time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A monument to the death of Hollywood's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Applause Meter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Todd was a promoter. He was a man with the talent for carrying out the colossal hype, someone who could sell the proverbial refrigerator to an Eskimo. He certainly displayed his genius in this glut of scenery, costumes and extras, selling this mess of a movie to the public in 1956. This film is so charmless, so humorless, such a depiction of stereotypes and clich&eacute;s, and not less egregious, a squandering and misappropriation of acting talent. David Niven holds his own, but he single-handedly can't sustain the whole show. The talented Shirley MacLaine stands around wondering what she's doing and how she got roped into agreeing to be part of the cast. As to how Todd could have lured name stars to take on cameos, is a mystery to me. Maybe people such as Frank Sinatra and Marlene Dieterich had nothing better to do that day? Possibly the wide screen Todd A-O process engulfed viewers and glued them into their theatre seats where they watched like spellbound captives back in 1956, but today, there is absolutely nothing to recommend this movie. If nothing else, this movie stands as a testimonial to Hollywood's desperate bid to lure 1950s audiences away from their TV sets and back into the movie theatre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    this movie has more than a handful of cast and wonderful cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is movie that goes on for 2 hours and keeps you wanting more, for the journey had beautiful scenery and nice international cast. The movie stared David Niven as Fogg and Cantinflas as Passepartout. Both characters being contradictory, Fogg is a gentleman, well-dressed, well-spoken, and extremely punctual, whereas Passepartout was the comic relief in the movie, he loved women and was a jack of all trade, their union boasted of talents and wits that saw them through the entire journey. This adventure film was produced by Michael Todd and is based on a novel of the same name by Jules Verne. Well comparing this to the 2004 remake that had Jackie Chan and Steve Coogan is going to be difficult as some of the attributes of Passepartout were given to Fogg making you lose respect for Fogg himself and the 1956 version is far different in the adventures embarked upon by the two compared to those in the 2004 version. The movie was actually filmed in 75 days and the cast including extras totaled 68,894 people and 7,959 animals. The wardrobe department spent $410,000 to provide 74,685 costumes and 36,092 trinkets. This movie packed a punch as the producers visited every country that Fogg and Passepartout passed through. The plot is about an English man in 1872 who is a member of the Reform Club, his name is Phileas Fogg (David Niven) he claims he can circumnavigate the world in eighty days. This made the other member of the Club view his claim as a bogus statement so he makes a &pound;20,000 wager (equal to over &pound;1,000,000 today) with several members of the Reform Club. The wager states that he will arrive back within 80 days before 8:45 pm. Together with his resourceful valet, Passepartout (Cantinflas), Fogg sets out on his journey which saw him save a princess, battle Indians, and as he was on his journey was named the chief suspect of stolen &pound;55,000 (equal to over &pound;3,000,000 today) from the Bank of England. This movie's wonderful cinematography was done by Lionel Lindon who won an Academy award for his work and he was involved in the photography of The Alfred Hitchcock Hour. The movie won five Academy awards, beating out critically acclaimed films like Friendly Persuasion, The Ten Commandments, Giant, and The King and I. The wins were Best Picture, Best Cinematography, Best Film Editing, Best Music and Best Writing, Best Screenplay, Adapted. This is a movie that is fun to watch and captivating to see. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am the true Kimi Gee, love hot air balloon rides
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgeouskimi
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually took a hot air balloon ride, so yes. I give this film a 10. Just to think a film from the 1950s could be so popular, Around the World in 80 Days, from the 1950s... Kimi Gee, being that I did the hot air balloon ride, probably almost made what was so exciting seem more. Why did this film get so popular? Maybe because I also went on a hot air balloon ride. What an adventure, going around the world, not knowing whether the wind would blow you to some remote island in the middle of no where or whether you would land somewhere popular that people had heard about your adventure... now I am in Guam. I tried the ride... and will try again one day... come on, it's just a balloon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good entertainment, although it drags at places.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rueiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First, I saw the Spanish cartoon adaptation in the mid-1980s, which can be quite nice for a kid's first introduction to Verne's legendary tale. Then I read the novel when I was ten years old, and later I saw this movie on TV on a Saturday afternoon.I loved it. Years later, I bought a VHS copy, and only two years ago I got the restored DVD edition, which comes with a lot of material some of which is interesting and the rest is a load of nonsense they added up just to have an excuse to produce a two-disc set. The restored movie runs for 174 minutes against the 160 or so of the old VHS. The newly added sequences are the intermission and exit music segments and some action shots previously edited that have been put back. I have to say that I find the film quite slow at times, with some sequences (the Melies "Journey to the Moon", the balloon voyage, the Spanish episode and the attack of the Sioux unnecessarily overlong and quite boring. Still, I also have to say that the film shines as to production values and its faithfulness to Verne's novel except for the balloon and the Spanish adventures. And some members of the cast are just right for their roles; I can not imagine anyone else but David Niven as Phileas Fogg, and Bobby Newton is likable as inspector Fix. But then Cantinflas, with all his natural skills for mimicry and his ability to talk like a gun-machine without saying anything solid, is a bit out of place here, since he talks Spanish at times instead of French, which is the nationality his character is supposed to be. And Shirley MacLaine,fresh from "The Trouble with Harry", seems to have been passing by when Mike Todd spotted her and immediately pulled out his chequebook and signed her in on the spot. But then, as a consolation, some of the cameos are a real delight: Coward, Gielgud,Boyer, Dietrich, Gingold, Mills... And it is John Carradine the one who stills every scene he is in, as the bullying, cigar-smoker, vulgarian Yank. He is very funny, and brings the best laughs in the film. Anyway, despite of its flaws and of being unnecessarily overlong, this film still is one of my favourite adventure epics of all time. I haven't seen the Jackie Chan - Steve Coogan remake, nor I intend to. Call me old-fashioned if you like, but I believe that in the old days movies looked much nicer and less fake than they do today courtesy of the CGI rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A beautiful, fun spectacle-- but only when watched as its creator intended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that suffers when viewed on a small screen. Made during a time when television posed a huge threat to the film industry, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a spectacle if there ever was one, a showcase of gorgeous cinematography and production values which can be appreciated nowhere else but in the theater. The acting and story were obviously of lesser importance than all the visuals. David Niven does a good job playing the quintessential British gentleman, and Cantinflas gives the most memorable performance as his comedic servant. The only lacking performance is given by Shirley MacLaine as Aouda, not only because she looks nothing like she's from India, but because she's uninteresting and never brings her character to life. There's also dozens of cameos sprinkled throughout, which are fun to look for if you're familiar with classic Hollywood personalities. For those who don't mind style over substance, "Around the World in 80 Days" is a treat indeed. If you're not one of those people, then hold off unless you ever get to see it on the big screen, where one can most appreciate all the film has to offer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    1956: Disney Verne and Todd Verne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    reisen55
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time has dulled my memory of this film. Bought the restored DVD a few weeks ago and began watching it last night. And it is one of those odd films that was great in 1956 when travel was new and the audience unsophisticated. What struck me today is now simple it really is. Some locations, London, Paris and Spain are gorgeous, plus local to Europe. The music is grand, and it works like a charm. As soon as the film departs Spain, we enter (a) Hollywood backlot sets and (b) traveloge territory where all too long we are treated to gorgeous, and dull, camera shots of distant countries while Niven and Company are off screen. Only Europe and America are really used in real-time sets. The rest is amazingly artificial. Now, I love Cantinflas who is a wonderful clone of Chaplin in this film - blood cousin to the Tramp. Niven is precise and perfect. MacClaine is rather wasted and dear Robert Newton is a treasure. Victor Young's score is ideal. BUT SINCE WE ARE on Verne in 1956, turn the page to 20,000 LEAGUES UNDER THE SEA and we have Verne done RIGHT!!! Disney's best action film ever, and far superior to Todd's globe trotting epic. So watch this 1956 memory with some careful planning. Be prepared, your memory may be better off to keep without spoiling it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It comes off like a 9-hour travelogue, but maybe it's something you may want to see once.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I watched "Around the World in Eighty Days" tonight, I noticde that it is a beautiful and spectacular film. The first time I tried seeing it was on a 25" TV--this time it's on a 58" one and the beauty is much more obvious. Too bad I couldn't have seen this on the big screen using the amazing 70mm cameras. And, if they brought it back to the theaters, I might be tempted to see it that way--even though the film does have many shortcomings. I've got to be honest here, I tried watching this film years ago and gave up on it. The only reason I am watching it through to the end now is that I would like to eventually see all the Best Picture winners--even the incredibly overblown ones. This brings me to a pet peeve I have. I HATE films that feature a bazillion cameos. I find that often the plethora of stars tend to get in the way of the story and often soak up a huge portion of the budget--leaving precious little for writing. Some of the stars in the film are very international in flavor and I never would have recognized them the first time I tried to see this movie 25 years ago. Now, after having seen and reviewed a ridiculous number of films, I was actually excited by some of these casting decisions. Catinflas, though completely unknown in America did some marvelous little comedies in Mexico--and he is the other reason I chose to try watching the movie again. I was to see Fernandel (who also made many wonderful films--in France and Italy). But, I was also maddened because his cameo as a hack driver was so short and unfunny--completely wasting his wonderful comedic talents. And this trend continued for several more of the cameo--wonderful actors who really have nothing to do and are pretty much wasted. At least 30 minutes could have and should have been cut from the film. I am NOT against long films...if they are well-paced. Too many times in this movie, however, scenes just unfold way too slowly--such as when the balloon is going over the Alps. A VERY LONG period of nice music and shots of the balloon are shown--when it really seemed interminably long. This reminded me of the major problem with "Star Trek: The Motion Picture"--too many unnecessarily long shots which killed the film's momentum. The bullfighting scene is also one that goes on and on and on and could have been 1/3 as long. Many other such examples followed. So is it a great film? No. I agree with another reviewer who felt the movie got an Oscar for Best Picture simply because it was such a spectacle--not because it was especially good. It's one of the weaker Best Picture films of the era, in my opinion. However, I must give the film its due. The movie is beautiful in every way--great costumes, amazing locations and sets, breathtaking cinematography and a scope that cannot really be matched. But, it is also very, very , very long with poor pacing, suffers from an overuse and wasting of cameos and just isn't that interesting. Catinflas was a very gifted and funny man--here you don't get a great sense of that at all. Likewise, David Niven was a very fine actor--but here he's more like set dressing and you don't get to see him at his best. Before I conclude, let's talk about the cameos. With all the many cameos, why did they pick Shirley MacLaine to play an Indian princess?! Talk about bizarre casting! And why have Frank Sinatra in a cameo that takes two seconds and he just turns and smiles at the camera?! I don't get it. And what was with John Carradine?! Even for him he over-acted horribly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adventure, Colorful and Long.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lots of money, effort, and publicity on display in this story of an fastidious British gentleman, David Niven, who manages to use the technology of the Victorian era to travel, well, around the world in 80 days, with sidekick Cantinflas, and picking up Princess Shirley MacLaine along the way. Producer Michael Todd put everything he had into it. It was a tremendous splash at the time using a special projective technique, plenty of music that went into a best-selling album, and the face of every recognizable actor of every nationality imaginable. There are theatrical knights in abundance. Let's see. There's Sir John Gielgud, Sir Cedric Hardwicke, Sir John Mills, and Sir Frank Sinatra. Now, fifty-six years after its release, it's hard to see what all the fuss was about. It's BIG of course, but it more or less had to be. What was happening in 1955 to the movie industry? It was being replaced by television and studios were desperate for novelty, something the audience couldn't find on their small black and white sets at home -- in this case, a MAGNIFICOLOR extravaganza in TODD-A-OMG-VISION! Look -- there's Marlene Dietrich! And that's the guy, what's his name, the sergeant from that John Ford cavalry movie! Gosh! The problem with the flick is that it's really designed to elicit gasps from a family audience. Not laughs, not thrills, not clenched teeth. You're supposed to sit back as at a travelogue and marvel at the sights of a Spanish bullfight, in which a clumsy Cantinflas taunts a bull while trying to hold his pants up (ha ha), and a painted elephant in India, and all kinds of definitely retrograde stereotypes -- bullfights, flamenco dancers (good ones), thugee, suttee, jabbering Chinese, bowing Japanese, a steamboat that has to destroy itself to provide its own fuel, hostile American Indians attacking a train, a rescue by the cavalry. It all must have been thrilling if you'd never seen it before, but in order not to have seen it before you'd have to be no more than fifteen years old. There are some smiles. Here's the one that got to me. The opening scene is in one of those stuffy, tradition-ridden English gentleman's clubs. The figures are mostly motionless. The gentlemen sit playing whist or reading newspapers. No one is speaking. A cat pads through the room. And one gentleman complains to a steward, "Can't you stop that animal from stomping around?" I wish there had been more jokes or physical gags. I wish it wouldn't depend so heavily on a viewer's ability to be astounded by all the production values and the innumerable cameos. Want to see a more entertaining movie along the same lines? See "The Great Race."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
