<filme>
 <id>
  50
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0076759
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1977
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Guerra nas Estrelas
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Luke Skywalker joins forces with a Jedi Knight, a cocky pilot, a wookiee and two droids to save the universe from the Empire's world-destroying battle-station, while also attempting to rescue Princess Leia from the evil Darth Vader.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Part IV in George Lucas' epic, Star Wars: A New Hope opens with a Rebel ship being boarded by the tyrannical Darth Vader. The plot then follows the life of a simple farm boy, Luke Skywalker, as he and his newly met allies (Han Solo, Chewbacca, Obi-Wan Kenobi, C-3PO, R2-D2) attempt to rescue a Rebel leader, Princess Leia, from the clutches of the Empire. The conclusion is culminated as the Rebels, including Skywalker and flying ace Wedge Antilles make an attack on the Empire's most powerful and ominous weapon, the Death Star.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   empire
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   planet
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   galaxy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   princess
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   rescue
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   George Lucas
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   George Lucas
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Mark Hamill
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Harrison Ford
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Carrie Fisher
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Feat of Imagination, Fantasy & Creativity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ingredients that made Star Wars a revolution of its time are clearly noticeable, without a doubt, but the visual encapsulation of this sci-fi saga has aged pretty badly & today looks like an unintentionally funny ride than a masterpiece adventure. Still, at its core, Star Wars is a cinematic feat of imagination, fantasy & creativity that hypnotized an entire generation with its freshly envisioned & awe-inspiring world, gripping story, first-rate adventure & celebrated characters. It may not look as dazzling & groundbreaking today as it was in its time but its vast influences can be seen in plethora of sci-fi space fantasies, even today. Nicely crafted by George Lucas & introducing a sweeping visual effects, greatly influenced from Stanley Kubrick's 2001: A Space Odyssey, the outer surface of Star Wars may have degraded with time but the core hasn't aged a day, resulting in it making an impact in the sci-fi genre, blockbuster filmmaking & marketing, even today & hopefully for few more decades.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not just a great movie. It's important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story happened 'A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away'. The galaxy is under dictatorship. Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) is part of the rebellion but is capture by the evil Darth Vader. Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) the young hero, Han Solo (Harrison Ford) the brigand, and the wise master Ben Obi-Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) must together rescue the princess. The characters are icons pulled from classic storytelling. George Lucas was able to assemble such iconic characters into a well told story. Rarely is a movie change the nature of movie-making, and even the wider culture. This may be one of the most important movie of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Luke Skywalker joins force to fight against the Darth Vader and evil empire and bring peace in the universe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alex milonas
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The star wars saga is one of the most best movies about the space and development of language and technology as light saber droids and creatures from far beyond our imaginations.The character of Darth Vader which every kid and adult wants to wear his costume as well as the light saber which everyone buy one and play with an friend.Luke is raised by his uncle in planet totooine,Luke buys two droids R2 and C-3PO which had a message to ex-Jedi Knight Obi-Wan,Luke find him and told him about the message from the princess Leia,Obi wan convinced Luke to became Jedi knight,Luke accepts and next meets pilot Han solo and paid him to fly them in the Death star and rescue the princess Leia and deliver to rebel alliance against the Empire the plans about destroy Death star.Luke destroy the Death star and escapes.Come after the Empire strikes back and Return of the Jedi the epic tales continues.Obi wan used to say may the force be with you which is energy field created by all living things.The George Lucas fantasy galaxy is far far away and we want a ticket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars film review final draft 2.docx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brockhunt34
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brock Hunt Mr.Hicks ENG 101-008 September 20, 2013 A Space Opera Star Wars is a movie which focuses on a rebel alliance that fights against an oppressive regime set in a fictionalized universe a long time ago in a galaxy far far away. We're introduced to the main characters Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) and Darth Vader (David Prowse) for the first time. Luke is a farm boy who doesn't have a clue of what is about to happen. Darth Vader is an evil dark lord of the Sith who is trained in the dark side of the force and wants to defeat the rebel alliance. After Luke's family is murdered by the empire, he trains to be a Jedi by Obi-Wan Kenobi to defeat the evil Galactic Empire. George Lucas made Star Wars: A New Hope in 1976 and was released in the summer of 1977. He made episode four first because the story didn't require any high dollar special effects and wasn't sure how the movie would be accepted. When the movie opened, it received great reviews and audiences were amazed at the special effects. He would go on to direct the following sequels Empire Strikes Back and Return of the Jedi. Little do people know that George Lucas had the stories and screenplays of episodes one, two, and three already done before episode four was ever released. He did this because at the time technology didn't exist to produce the first three films with the fight sequences and settings that were in the first three films. I personally love the Star Wars films because of my personal connection with them. My grandmother introduced me to the Star Wars franchise as a child. On Saturday nights I would stay with my grandmother and she would play the movies on VHS. I never get tired of watching the films. Because every time I do, it takes me back in time when she was alive. Star Wars also opened up my interest in Sci-Fi movies. Some can say I'm a nerd but most don't know my extensive knowledge of the Star Wars franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of a new era!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the genius George Lucas was about to go help Spielberg make the majestic " Raiders", he decided to do something, something that many were surprised when it was announced and didn't take a lot of faith on, which after his release was an absolute success both at the box office and critical, and today the masterpiece of Lucas is a classic that will live forever in the history of cinema! "Star Wars" (not Star Wars IV A New Hope, please), begins with the yellow title suddenly appearing on the screen with an amazing soundtrack from the master John Williams giving us a resume of the history we are about to watch. It all starts with a small spaceship full of rebel soldiers start being invaded by imperial troops led by the sinister and cruel lord Darth Vader (David Prowse). Suddenly the film transports us directly to another side of the galaxy where we have the story of the young Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), a simple machine repairman teenager who lives with his uncles. A day after his uncle buy two servant robots, R2 - D2 (Kenny Baker) and C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), which inadvertently bring Luke the chance to realize his dreams of becoming a rebel and fight against the tyrant of the empire, a mission that will take him to the ends of the galaxy and will bring new friends but at the same time extreme dangers. From the beginning, "Star Wars" revolutionized cinema forever, especially the genre of sci - fi that at the time was just "Star Trek" with great success. Lucas of course certain elements form "Trek", since the crew of a spaceship with name style and friendship among the crew, but everything else was a tremendous attack of originality. Unlike "Star Trek" Lucas took the story and the great adventure with a lighter and fantasy tone, not childish but humorous, fun and even a certain religious point when the Jedi Obi - Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) appears in Luke's life with secrets of him and Luke's father past. And just like "Star Trek", Lucas gave his masterpiece unforgettable characters, of course: Luke, R2, C-3PO, Obi-Wan. But also the unforgettable Han Solo (Harrison Ford), the bounty hunter from space who ALWAYS shoots first and asks questions later, giving the film a great humorous touch and a lot of fun (never one character caused such influences as Han Solo did), and even Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) no royal woman before her in a film had never taken up arms showing she knew very well how to take care of herself. Not only the good guys who stand out perfectly in the story, but also the great and unforgettable antagonist ever put to film, Darth Vader, no villain was so cruel and yet so adored by fans. Characters and stories fitting perfectly, but the adventure to be full completed it needed the huge Galactic scenario, which is not lacking in this film. I think Lucas should have thanked Kubrick about "2001" because if it were not for this film, visual effects would never be the same. And thanks to that Lucas gave the film with beautiful scenery and a vast galaxies and an unforgettable and thrilling final battle. The classic that redefined cinema forever with a story well-crafted and told, full of suspense, humor and adventure thanks to its unforgettable characters and stunning visual effects , the legendary George Lucas gave the world a film with tremendous quality and early one of the best trilogies ever made. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated and outdated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emil Marty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying the movie doesn't suck, given the time it was made. The problem is that its legacy has created die-hard fans which have spawned the biggest franchise of all time; nothing wrong with that of course. But if you take a step back into modern day, you will see a film with all the elements a great fantasy epic should have (unimportant boy gets trained by old man, becomes great warrior etc) but a film where each element lacks the emotion to make you feel what you should. You don't feel sympathy when Luke's aunt and uncle die, you don't care about Kenobi's death because there was never an emotional stand-point that pinpointed him as a "great man". Everything simply happens without any given thought about the characters emotions. I could name a million films with all the same elements that have been done ten times better. That said, the originality is genuine, the whole story exciting and it's generally fun to watch. Just a shame its practically been ruined by its reputation as the greatest franchise ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Influential and Spectacular.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This first "Star Wars" film(though now retitled 'Episode IV') was a groundbreaking, box office shattering breath of fresh air to the cinemas, and science fiction in particular, which had gotten bogged down in bleak Dystopian futures. Nothing wrong with that in some cases, but moviegoers craved more, and got it with this extremely exciting tale of youth rebellion against an evil galactic empire led by Darth Vader(I though he was a robot at first viewing as a youngster!) a memorable creation, whose entrances were punctuated by the grand music of John Williams, who created an unforgettable score here that kids imitated endlessly! Fine cast includes Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing and Sir Alec Guiness. Climax is truly exciting, though film has a few lulls at times, this is still great fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope (originally released as just "Star Wars") is a masterpiece. Although the plot of the film is so simple that it almost hurts, it is brilliantly executed. It's a hero's journey in which the main character, Luke Skywalker, starts his adventures and finds himself in the middle of something bigger than he ever imagined. It is his story. Unfortunately, Luke's story tends to diminish the other character's stories in the first Star Wars trilogy. It's quite acceptable in this film, because Leia is the only character who really suffers from that (her non-reaction and non-follow-up on Alderaan's destruction is a shame). Sadly, this got even with with the next two films. Star Wars was a technical breakthrough and is in some ways still the best of all the Star Wars films. 9 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterful Work of Art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrrockey
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why am I even here? What's the point of me trying to review this film? Really, what's the point? Everybody knows about this film already and how great it is. So me trying to write a review of this film and trying to explain why it's so great is like re-telling the story of A Christmas Carol. Everybody knows it but yet, are always willing to listen. So I'll try my best to explain why I think this film has made the impact it did. Let's cut the crap and begin my analysis. PART 1: The Aesthetic Appeal of Star Wars Science-fiction was nothing new by the 70's. We've already had a lot of science-fiction movies by that time such as 2001: A Space Odyssey, THX 1138(another George Lucas film), Invasion of the Body Snatchers etc but the thing that made Star Wars different was its spirit. Most science- fiction films prior to Star Wars were cold, dark, and art-house-driven. Star Wars on the other hand, had an uplifting, positive, and imaginative tone to it that made it appeal to the child inside us. Star Wars takes place a long time ago, in a galaxy far far away with the classic hero's journey in the form of Luke Skywalker, the wise old mentor in the form of Obi-Wan Kenobi, the beautiful princess in Leia, the sinister, scheming villain in the form of Darth Vader, and the adventurous rogue in Han Solo. These things make Star Wars feel like a fairy-tale and made it timeless. Plus, the film had an amazing, classic, adventure serial look to it. The costumes, sets, sound effects, animatronics, and music all feel like they belong in a classic adventure serial, it makes you feel like a kid again! But while Star Wars is imaginative and uplifting, it's also a very smart film. PART 2: The Deeper Meanings Behind Star Wars On surface, Star Wars is just a little kiddie adventure with spaceships, laser gun battles, and wizards with laser swords but when you actually look into the story, there's actually a lot more substance to it than that. One of the themes in Star Wars is about finding meanings in life and the meaning of heroism. Star Wars is about finding meanings in life because it deals with characters who were never meant to be heroes but end up becoming greater than what they are. Luke Skywalker is a farmboy. He has no experience in any form of combat whatsoever and isn't even particularly smart but he ultimately saves the day because of his bravery and his good heart. Han Solo is just a smuggler. He was never the guy who would lead a bunch of Rebels to fight against the Empire, he only fought for one person which was himself. But towards the end of the movie, he finds a new purpose in life which is to become a Rebel and fight the Empire. Another theme in Star Wars is the idea of destiny. Most of these people here never belonged in the adventures they got themselves into in this movie but they ultimately do so because of The Force finding good in them and putting them there. In a way, it's destiny that brought these characters together and it's great that they didn't spell this out directly with its dialogue. PART 3: Why is Star Wars Still so Beloved Today? I think it's because of how original and fun it is. Even though it borrows a lot from classic adventure serials, classic fantasy literature, religious philosophy, historical events, and a whole other galaxy of inspirations, it combines them to create something new. It has endearing characters, an imaginative world, deep philosophy, and just provides good escapism overall. Plus, it's also just a lot of fun to watch with its action, humor, romance, and adventure. There's things here for everyone. Star Wars is intelligent, imaginative, clever, original, and just plain fun, it rightfully deserves a 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars, a new era...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Star Wars" was the start of something new, something different, something extraordinary for those times. Until today "Star Wars" considered the best Star Wars movie of all times. Personally I liked it very much and I can compare it with the other two movies of the classic trilogy: "Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back" and "Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi". George Lucas makes a great direction (nominated for the Oscar of Best Director in 1978) such the writing and screenplay (nominated for both for the the Oscar of Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen) and that great job seemed during the whole movie. Gary Kurtz also did an extremely good job for the Picture of the movie who is also nominated for the Oscar of Best Picture. The theme of this movie is that Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), Han Solo (Harrison Ford), C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), R2-D2 (Kenny Baker) and Chewbacca (Peter Mayhew) are going to save Princess Leia Organa (Carrie Fisher) from the evil Darth Vader (David Prowse) and they are also want to save the universe from the Empire's world-destroying battle-station.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Feat of Imagination, Fantasy & Creativity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ingredients that made Star Wars a revolution of its time are clearly noticeable, without a doubt, but the visual encapsulation of this sci-fi saga has aged pretty badly & today looks like an unintentionally funny ride than a masterpiece adventure. Still, at its core, Star Wars is a cinematic feat of imagination, fantasy & creativity that hypnotized an entire generation with its freshly envisioned & awe-inspiring world, gripping story, first-rate adventure & celebrated characters. It may not look as dazzling & groundbreaking today as it was in its time but its vast influences can be seen in plethora of sci-fi space fantasies, even today. Nicely crafted by George Lucas & introducing a sweeping visual effects, greatly influenced from Stanley Kubrick's 2001: A Space Odyssey, the outer surface of Star Wars may have degraded with time but the core hasn't aged a day, resulting in it making an impact in the sci-fi genre, blockbuster filmmaking & marketing, even today & hopefully for few more decades.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not just a great movie. It's important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story happened 'A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away'. The galaxy is under dictatorship. Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) is part of the rebellion but is capture by the evil Darth Vader. Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) the young hero, Han Solo (Harrison Ford) the brigand, and the wise master Ben Obi-Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) must together rescue the princess. The characters are icons pulled from classic storytelling. George Lucas was able to assemble such iconic characters into a well told story. Rarely is a movie change the nature of movie-making, and even the wider culture. This may be one of the most important movie of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Luke Skywalker joins force to fight against the Darth Vader and evil empire and bring peace in the universe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alex milonas
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The star wars saga is one of the most best movies about the space and development of language and technology as light saber droids and creatures from far beyond our imaginations.The character of Darth Vader which every kid and adult wants to wear his costume as well as the light saber which everyone buy one and play with an friend.Luke is raised by his uncle in planet totooine,Luke buys two droids R2 and C-3PO which had a message to ex-Jedi Knight Obi-Wan,Luke find him and told him about the message from the princess Leia,Obi wan convinced Luke to became Jedi knight,Luke accepts and next meets pilot Han solo and paid him to fly them in the Death star and rescue the princess Leia and deliver to rebel alliance against the Empire the plans about destroy Death star.Luke destroy the Death star and escapes.Come after the Empire strikes back and Return of the Jedi the epic tales continues.Obi wan used to say may the force be with you which is energy field created by all living things.The George Lucas fantasy galaxy is far far away and we want a ticket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars film review final draft 2.docx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brockhunt34
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brock Hunt Mr.Hicks ENG 101-008 September 20, 2013 A Space Opera Star Wars is a movie which focuses on a rebel alliance that fights against an oppressive regime set in a fictionalized universe a long time ago in a galaxy far far away. We're introduced to the main characters Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) and Darth Vader (David Prowse) for the first time. Luke is a farm boy who doesn't have a clue of what is about to happen. Darth Vader is an evil dark lord of the Sith who is trained in the dark side of the force and wants to defeat the rebel alliance. After Luke's family is murdered by the empire, he trains to be a Jedi by Obi-Wan Kenobi to defeat the evil Galactic Empire. George Lucas made Star Wars: A New Hope in 1976 and was released in the summer of 1977. He made episode four first because the story didn't require any high dollar special effects and wasn't sure how the movie would be accepted. When the movie opened, it received great reviews and audiences were amazed at the special effects. He would go on to direct the following sequels Empire Strikes Back and Return of the Jedi. Little do people know that George Lucas had the stories and screenplays of episodes one, two, and three already done before episode four was ever released. He did this because at the time technology didn't exist to produce the first three films with the fight sequences and settings that were in the first three films. I personally love the Star Wars films because of my personal connection with them. My grandmother introduced me to the Star Wars franchise as a child. On Saturday nights I would stay with my grandmother and she would play the movies on VHS. I never get tired of watching the films. Because every time I do, it takes me back in time when she was alive. Star Wars also opened up my interest in Sci-Fi movies. Some can say I'm a nerd but most don't know my extensive knowledge of the Star Wars franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of a new era!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the genius George Lucas was about to go help Spielberg make the majestic " Raiders", he decided to do something, something that many were surprised when it was announced and didn't take a lot of faith on, which after his release was an absolute success both at the box office and critical, and today the masterpiece of Lucas is a classic that will live forever in the history of cinema! "Star Wars" (not Star Wars IV A New Hope, please), begins with the yellow title suddenly appearing on the screen with an amazing soundtrack from the master John Williams giving us a resume of the history we are about to watch. It all starts with a small spaceship full of rebel soldiers start being invaded by imperial troops led by the sinister and cruel lord Darth Vader (David Prowse). Suddenly the film transports us directly to another side of the galaxy where we have the story of the young Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), a simple machine repairman teenager who lives with his uncles. A day after his uncle buy two servant robots, R2 - D2 (Kenny Baker) and C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), which inadvertently bring Luke the chance to realize his dreams of becoming a rebel and fight against the tyrant of the empire, a mission that will take him to the ends of the galaxy and will bring new friends but at the same time extreme dangers. From the beginning, "Star Wars" revolutionized cinema forever, especially the genre of sci - fi that at the time was just "Star Trek" with great success. Lucas of course certain elements form "Trek", since the crew of a spaceship with name style and friendship among the crew, but everything else was a tremendous attack of originality. Unlike "Star Trek" Lucas took the story and the great adventure with a lighter and fantasy tone, not childish but humorous, fun and even a certain religious point when the Jedi Obi - Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) appears in Luke's life with secrets of him and Luke's father past. And just like "Star Trek", Lucas gave his masterpiece unforgettable characters, of course: Luke, R2, C-3PO, Obi-Wan. But also the unforgettable Han Solo (Harrison Ford), the bounty hunter from space who ALWAYS shoots first and asks questions later, giving the film a great humorous touch and a lot of fun (never one character caused such influences as Han Solo did), and even Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) no royal woman before her in a film had never taken up arms showing she knew very well how to take care of herself. Not only the good guys who stand out perfectly in the story, but also the great and unforgettable antagonist ever put to film, Darth Vader, no villain was so cruel and yet so adored by fans. Characters and stories fitting perfectly, but the adventure to be full completed it needed the huge Galactic scenario, which is not lacking in this film. I think Lucas should have thanked Kubrick about "2001" because if it were not for this film, visual effects would never be the same. And thanks to that Lucas gave the film with beautiful scenery and a vast galaxies and an unforgettable and thrilling final battle. The classic that redefined cinema forever with a story well-crafted and told, full of suspense, humor and adventure thanks to its unforgettable characters and stunning visual effects , the legendary George Lucas gave the world a film with tremendous quality and early one of the best trilogies ever made. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated and outdated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emil Marty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying the movie doesn't suck, given the time it was made. The problem is that its legacy has created die-hard fans which have spawned the biggest franchise of all time; nothing wrong with that of course. But if you take a step back into modern day, you will see a film with all the elements a great fantasy epic should have (unimportant boy gets trained by old man, becomes great warrior etc) but a film where each element lacks the emotion to make you feel what you should. You don't feel sympathy when Luke's aunt and uncle die, you don't care about Kenobi's death because there was never an emotional stand-point that pinpointed him as a "great man". Everything simply happens without any given thought about the characters emotions. I could name a million films with all the same elements that have been done ten times better. That said, the originality is genuine, the whole story exciting and it's generally fun to watch. Just a shame its practically been ruined by its reputation as the greatest franchise ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Influential and Spectacular.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This first "Star Wars" film(though now retitled 'Episode IV') was a groundbreaking, box office shattering breath of fresh air to the cinemas, and science fiction in particular, which had gotten bogged down in bleak Dystopian futures. Nothing wrong with that in some cases, but moviegoers craved more, and got it with this extremely exciting tale of youth rebellion against an evil galactic empire led by Darth Vader(I though he was a robot at first viewing as a youngster!) a memorable creation, whose entrances were punctuated by the grand music of John Williams, who created an unforgettable score here that kids imitated endlessly! Fine cast includes Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing and Sir Alec Guiness. Climax is truly exciting, though film has a few lulls at times, this is still great fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope (originally released as just "Star Wars") is a masterpiece. Although the plot of the film is so simple that it almost hurts, it is brilliantly executed. It's a hero's journey in which the main character, Luke Skywalker, starts his adventures and finds himself in the middle of something bigger than he ever imagined. It is his story. Unfortunately, Luke's story tends to diminish the other character's stories in the first Star Wars trilogy. It's quite acceptable in this film, because Leia is the only character who really suffers from that (her non-reaction and non-follow-up on Alderaan's destruction is a shame). Sadly, this got even with with the next two films. Star Wars was a technical breakthrough and is in some ways still the best of all the Star Wars films. 9 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterful Work of Art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrrockey
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why am I even here? What's the point of me trying to review this film? Really, what's the point? Everybody knows about this film already and how great it is. So me trying to write a review of this film and trying to explain why it's so great is like re-telling the story of A Christmas Carol. Everybody knows it but yet, are always willing to listen. So I'll try my best to explain why I think this film has made the impact it did. Let's cut the crap and begin my analysis. PART 1: The Aesthetic Appeal of Star Wars Science-fiction was nothing new by the 70's. We've already had a lot of science-fiction movies by that time such as 2001: A Space Odyssey, THX 1138(another George Lucas film), Invasion of the Body Snatchers etc but the thing that made Star Wars different was its spirit. Most science- fiction films prior to Star Wars were cold, dark, and art-house-driven. Star Wars on the other hand, had an uplifting, positive, and imaginative tone to it that made it appeal to the child inside us. Star Wars takes place a long time ago, in a galaxy far far away with the classic hero's journey in the form of Luke Skywalker, the wise old mentor in the form of Obi-Wan Kenobi, the beautiful princess in Leia, the sinister, scheming villain in the form of Darth Vader, and the adventurous rogue in Han Solo. These things make Star Wars feel like a fairy-tale and made it timeless. Plus, the film had an amazing, classic, adventure serial look to it. The costumes, sets, sound effects, animatronics, and music all feel like they belong in a classic adventure serial, it makes you feel like a kid again! But while Star Wars is imaginative and uplifting, it's also a very smart film. PART 2: The Deeper Meanings Behind Star Wars On surface, Star Wars is just a little kiddie adventure with spaceships, laser gun battles, and wizards with laser swords but when you actually look into the story, there's actually a lot more substance to it than that. One of the themes in Star Wars is about finding meanings in life and the meaning of heroism. Star Wars is about finding meanings in life because it deals with characters who were never meant to be heroes but end up becoming greater than what they are. Luke Skywalker is a farmboy. He has no experience in any form of combat whatsoever and isn't even particularly smart but he ultimately saves the day because of his bravery and his good heart. Han Solo is just a smuggler. He was never the guy who would lead a bunch of Rebels to fight against the Empire, he only fought for one person which was himself. But towards the end of the movie, he finds a new purpose in life which is to become a Rebel and fight the Empire. Another theme in Star Wars is the idea of destiny. Most of these people here never belonged in the adventures they got themselves into in this movie but they ultimately do so because of The Force finding good in them and putting them there. In a way, it's destiny that brought these characters together and it's great that they didn't spell this out directly with its dialogue. PART 3: Why is Star Wars Still so Beloved Today? I think it's because of how original and fun it is. Even though it borrows a lot from classic adventure serials, classic fantasy literature, religious philosophy, historical events, and a whole other galaxy of inspirations, it combines them to create something new. It has endearing characters, an imaginative world, deep philosophy, and just provides good escapism overall. Plus, it's also just a lot of fun to watch with its action, humor, romance, and adventure. There's things here for everyone. Star Wars is intelligent, imaginative, clever, original, and just plain fun, it rightfully deserves a 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars, a new era...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Star Wars" was the start of something new, something different, something extraordinary for those times. Until today "Star Wars" considered the best Star Wars movie of all times. Personally I liked it very much and I can compare it with the other two movies of the classic trilogy: "Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back" and "Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi". George Lucas makes a great direction (nominated for the Oscar of Best Director in 1978) such the writing and screenplay (nominated for both for the the Oscar of Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen) and that great job seemed during the whole movie. Gary Kurtz also did an extremely good job for the Picture of the movie who is also nominated for the Oscar of Best Picture. The theme of this movie is that Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), Han Solo (Harrison Ford), C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), R2-D2 (Kenny Baker) and Chewbacca (Peter Mayhew) are going to save Princess Leia Organa (Carrie Fisher) from the evil Darth Vader (David Prowse) and they are also want to save the universe from the Empire's world-destroying battle-station.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Feat of Imagination, Fantasy & Creativity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ingredients that made Star Wars a revolution of its time are clearly noticeable, without a doubt, but the visual encapsulation of this sci-fi saga has aged pretty badly & today looks like an unintentionally funny ride than a masterpiece adventure. Still, at its core, Star Wars is a cinematic feat of imagination, fantasy & creativity that hypnotized an entire generation with its freshly envisioned & awe-inspiring world, gripping story, first-rate adventure & celebrated characters. It may not look as dazzling & groundbreaking today as it was in its time but its vast influences can be seen in plethora of sci-fi space fantasies, even today. Nicely crafted by George Lucas & introducing a sweeping visual effects, greatly influenced from Stanley Kubrick's 2001: A Space Odyssey, the outer surface of Star Wars may have degraded with time but the core hasn't aged a day, resulting in it making an impact in the sci-fi genre, blockbuster filmmaking & marketing, even today & hopefully for few more decades.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not just a great movie. It's important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story happened 'A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away'. The galaxy is under dictatorship. Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) is part of the rebellion but is capture by the evil Darth Vader. Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) the young hero, Han Solo (Harrison Ford) the brigand, and the wise master Ben Obi-Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) must together rescue the princess. The characters are icons pulled from classic storytelling. George Lucas was able to assemble such iconic characters into a well told story. Rarely is a movie change the nature of movie-making, and even the wider culture. This may be one of the most important movie of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Luke Skywalker joins force to fight against the Darth Vader and evil empire and bring peace in the universe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alex milonas
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The star wars saga is one of the most best movies about the space and development of language and technology as light saber droids and creatures from far beyond our imaginations.The character of Darth Vader which every kid and adult wants to wear his costume as well as the light saber which everyone buy one and play with an friend.Luke is raised by his uncle in planet totooine,Luke buys two droids R2 and C-3PO which had a message to ex-Jedi Knight Obi-Wan,Luke find him and told him about the message from the princess Leia,Obi wan convinced Luke to became Jedi knight,Luke accepts and next meets pilot Han solo and paid him to fly them in the Death star and rescue the princess Leia and deliver to rebel alliance against the Empire the plans about destroy Death star.Luke destroy the Death star and escapes.Come after the Empire strikes back and Return of the Jedi the epic tales continues.Obi wan used to say may the force be with you which is energy field created by all living things.The George Lucas fantasy galaxy is far far away and we want a ticket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars film review final draft 2.docx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brockhunt34
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brock Hunt Mr.Hicks ENG 101-008 September 20, 2013 A Space Opera Star Wars is a movie which focuses on a rebel alliance that fights against an oppressive regime set in a fictionalized universe a long time ago in a galaxy far far away. We're introduced to the main characters Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) and Darth Vader (David Prowse) for the first time. Luke is a farm boy who doesn't have a clue of what is about to happen. Darth Vader is an evil dark lord of the Sith who is trained in the dark side of the force and wants to defeat the rebel alliance. After Luke's family is murdered by the empire, he trains to be a Jedi by Obi-Wan Kenobi to defeat the evil Galactic Empire. George Lucas made Star Wars: A New Hope in 1976 and was released in the summer of 1977. He made episode four first because the story didn't require any high dollar special effects and wasn't sure how the movie would be accepted. When the movie opened, it received great reviews and audiences were amazed at the special effects. He would go on to direct the following sequels Empire Strikes Back and Return of the Jedi. Little do people know that George Lucas had the stories and screenplays of episodes one, two, and three already done before episode four was ever released. He did this because at the time technology didn't exist to produce the first three films with the fight sequences and settings that were in the first three films. I personally love the Star Wars films because of my personal connection with them. My grandmother introduced me to the Star Wars franchise as a child. On Saturday nights I would stay with my grandmother and she would play the movies on VHS. I never get tired of watching the films. Because every time I do, it takes me back in time when she was alive. Star Wars also opened up my interest in Sci-Fi movies. Some can say I'm a nerd but most don't know my extensive knowledge of the Star Wars franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of a new era!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the genius George Lucas was about to go help Spielberg make the majestic " Raiders", he decided to do something, something that many were surprised when it was announced and didn't take a lot of faith on, which after his release was an absolute success both at the box office and critical, and today the masterpiece of Lucas is a classic that will live forever in the history of cinema! "Star Wars" (not Star Wars IV A New Hope, please), begins with the yellow title suddenly appearing on the screen with an amazing soundtrack from the master John Williams giving us a resume of the history we are about to watch. It all starts with a small spaceship full of rebel soldiers start being invaded by imperial troops led by the sinister and cruel lord Darth Vader (David Prowse). Suddenly the film transports us directly to another side of the galaxy where we have the story of the young Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), a simple machine repairman teenager who lives with his uncles. A day after his uncle buy two servant robots, R2 - D2 (Kenny Baker) and C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), which inadvertently bring Luke the chance to realize his dreams of becoming a rebel and fight against the tyrant of the empire, a mission that will take him to the ends of the galaxy and will bring new friends but at the same time extreme dangers. From the beginning, "Star Wars" revolutionized cinema forever, especially the genre of sci - fi that at the time was just "Star Trek" with great success. Lucas of course certain elements form "Trek", since the crew of a spaceship with name style and friendship among the crew, but everything else was a tremendous attack of originality. Unlike "Star Trek" Lucas took the story and the great adventure with a lighter and fantasy tone, not childish but humorous, fun and even a certain religious point when the Jedi Obi - Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) appears in Luke's life with secrets of him and Luke's father past. And just like "Star Trek", Lucas gave his masterpiece unforgettable characters, of course: Luke, R2, C-3PO, Obi-Wan. But also the unforgettable Han Solo (Harrison Ford), the bounty hunter from space who ALWAYS shoots first and asks questions later, giving the film a great humorous touch and a lot of fun (never one character caused such influences as Han Solo did), and even Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) no royal woman before her in a film had never taken up arms showing she knew very well how to take care of herself. Not only the good guys who stand out perfectly in the story, but also the great and unforgettable antagonist ever put to film, Darth Vader, no villain was so cruel and yet so adored by fans. Characters and stories fitting perfectly, but the adventure to be full completed it needed the huge Galactic scenario, which is not lacking in this film. I think Lucas should have thanked Kubrick about "2001" because if it were not for this film, visual effects would never be the same. And thanks to that Lucas gave the film with beautiful scenery and a vast galaxies and an unforgettable and thrilling final battle. The classic that redefined cinema forever with a story well-crafted and told, full of suspense, humor and adventure thanks to its unforgettable characters and stunning visual effects , the legendary George Lucas gave the world a film with tremendous quality and early one of the best trilogies ever made. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated and outdated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emil Marty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying the movie doesn't suck, given the time it was made. The problem is that its legacy has created die-hard fans which have spawned the biggest franchise of all time; nothing wrong with that of course. But if you take a step back into modern day, you will see a film with all the elements a great fantasy epic should have (unimportant boy gets trained by old man, becomes great warrior etc) but a film where each element lacks the emotion to make you feel what you should. You don't feel sympathy when Luke's aunt and uncle die, you don't care about Kenobi's death because there was never an emotional stand-point that pinpointed him as a "great man". Everything simply happens without any given thought about the characters emotions. I could name a million films with all the same elements that have been done ten times better. That said, the originality is genuine, the whole story exciting and it's generally fun to watch. Just a shame its practically been ruined by its reputation as the greatest franchise ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Influential and Spectacular.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This first "Star Wars" film(though now retitled 'Episode IV') was a groundbreaking, box office shattering breath of fresh air to the cinemas, and science fiction in particular, which had gotten bogged down in bleak Dystopian futures. Nothing wrong with that in some cases, but moviegoers craved more, and got it with this extremely exciting tale of youth rebellion against an evil galactic empire led by Darth Vader(I though he was a robot at first viewing as a youngster!) a memorable creation, whose entrances were punctuated by the grand music of John Williams, who created an unforgettable score here that kids imitated endlessly! Fine cast includes Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing and Sir Alec Guiness. Climax is truly exciting, though film has a few lulls at times, this is still great fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope (originally released as just "Star Wars") is a masterpiece. Although the plot of the film is so simple that it almost hurts, it is brilliantly executed. It's a hero's journey in which the main character, Luke Skywalker, starts his adventures and finds himself in the middle of something bigger than he ever imagined. It is his story. Unfortunately, Luke's story tends to diminish the other character's stories in the first Star Wars trilogy. It's quite acceptable in this film, because Leia is the only character who really suffers from that (her non-reaction and non-follow-up on Alderaan's destruction is a shame). Sadly, this got even with with the next two films. Star Wars was a technical breakthrough and is in some ways still the best of all the Star Wars films. 9 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterful Work of Art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrrockey
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why am I even here? What's the point of me trying to review this film? Really, what's the point? Everybody knows about this film already and how great it is. So me trying to write a review of this film and trying to explain why it's so great is like re-telling the story of A Christmas Carol. Everybody knows it but yet, are always willing to listen. So I'll try my best to explain why I think this film has made the impact it did. Let's cut the crap and begin my analysis. PART 1: The Aesthetic Appeal of Star Wars Science-fiction was nothing new by the 70's. We've already had a lot of science-fiction movies by that time such as 2001: A Space Odyssey, THX 1138(another George Lucas film), Invasion of the Body Snatchers etc but the thing that made Star Wars different was its spirit. Most science- fiction films prior to Star Wars were cold, dark, and art-house-driven. Star Wars on the other hand, had an uplifting, positive, and imaginative tone to it that made it appeal to the child inside us. Star Wars takes place a long time ago, in a galaxy far far away with the classic hero's journey in the form of Luke Skywalker, the wise old mentor in the form of Obi-Wan Kenobi, the beautiful princess in Leia, the sinister, scheming villain in the form of Darth Vader, and the adventurous rogue in Han Solo. These things make Star Wars feel like a fairy-tale and made it timeless. Plus, the film had an amazing, classic, adventure serial look to it. The costumes, sets, sound effects, animatronics, and music all feel like they belong in a classic adventure serial, it makes you feel like a kid again! But while Star Wars is imaginative and uplifting, it's also a very smart film. PART 2: The Deeper Meanings Behind Star Wars On surface, Star Wars is just a little kiddie adventure with spaceships, laser gun battles, and wizards with laser swords but when you actually look into the story, there's actually a lot more substance to it than that. One of the themes in Star Wars is about finding meanings in life and the meaning of heroism. Star Wars is about finding meanings in life because it deals with characters who were never meant to be heroes but end up becoming greater than what they are. Luke Skywalker is a farmboy. He has no experience in any form of combat whatsoever and isn't even particularly smart but he ultimately saves the day because of his bravery and his good heart. Han Solo is just a smuggler. He was never the guy who would lead a bunch of Rebels to fight against the Empire, he only fought for one person which was himself. But towards the end of the movie, he finds a new purpose in life which is to become a Rebel and fight the Empire. Another theme in Star Wars is the idea of destiny. Most of these people here never belonged in the adventures they got themselves into in this movie but they ultimately do so because of The Force finding good in them and putting them there. In a way, it's destiny that brought these characters together and it's great that they didn't spell this out directly with its dialogue. PART 3: Why is Star Wars Still so Beloved Today? I think it's because of how original and fun it is. Even though it borrows a lot from classic adventure serials, classic fantasy literature, religious philosophy, historical events, and a whole other galaxy of inspirations, it combines them to create something new. It has endearing characters, an imaginative world, deep philosophy, and just provides good escapism overall. Plus, it's also just a lot of fun to watch with its action, humor, romance, and adventure. There's things here for everyone. Star Wars is intelligent, imaginative, clever, original, and just plain fun, it rightfully deserves a 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars, a new era...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Star Wars" was the start of something new, something different, something extraordinary for those times. Until today "Star Wars" considered the best Star Wars movie of all times. Personally I liked it very much and I can compare it with the other two movies of the classic trilogy: "Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back" and "Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi". George Lucas makes a great direction (nominated for the Oscar of Best Director in 1978) such the writing and screenplay (nominated for both for the the Oscar of Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen) and that great job seemed during the whole movie. Gary Kurtz also did an extremely good job for the Picture of the movie who is also nominated for the Oscar of Best Picture. The theme of this movie is that Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), Han Solo (Harrison Ford), C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), R2-D2 (Kenny Baker) and Chewbacca (Peter Mayhew) are going to save Princess Leia Organa (Carrie Fisher) from the evil Darth Vader (David Prowse) and they are also want to save the universe from the Empire's world-destroying battle-station.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Feat of Imagination, Fantasy & Creativity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ingredients that made Star Wars a revolution of its time are clearly noticeable, without a doubt, but the visual encapsulation of this sci-fi saga has aged pretty badly & today looks like an unintentionally funny ride than a masterpiece adventure. Still, at its core, Star Wars is a cinematic feat of imagination, fantasy & creativity that hypnotized an entire generation with its freshly envisioned & awe-inspiring world, gripping story, first-rate adventure & celebrated characters. It may not look as dazzling & groundbreaking today as it was in its time but its vast influences can be seen in plethora of sci-fi space fantasies, even today. Nicely crafted by George Lucas & introducing a sweeping visual effects, greatly influenced from Stanley Kubrick's 2001: A Space Odyssey, the outer surface of Star Wars may have degraded with time but the core hasn't aged a day, resulting in it making an impact in the sci-fi genre, blockbuster filmmaking & marketing, even today & hopefully for few more decades.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not just a great movie. It's important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story happened 'A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away'. The galaxy is under dictatorship. Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) is part of the rebellion but is capture by the evil Darth Vader. Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) the young hero, Han Solo (Harrison Ford) the brigand, and the wise master Ben Obi-Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) must together rescue the princess. The characters are icons pulled from classic storytelling. George Lucas was able to assemble such iconic characters into a well told story. Rarely is a movie change the nature of movie-making, and even the wider culture. This may be one of the most important movie of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Luke Skywalker joins force to fight against the Darth Vader and evil empire and bring peace in the universe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alex milonas
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The star wars saga is one of the most best movies about the space and development of language and technology as light saber droids and creatures from far beyond our imaginations.The character of Darth Vader which every kid and adult wants to wear his costume as well as the light saber which everyone buy one and play with an friend.Luke is raised by his uncle in planet totooine,Luke buys two droids R2 and C-3PO which had a message to ex-Jedi Knight Obi-Wan,Luke find him and told him about the message from the princess Leia,Obi wan convinced Luke to became Jedi knight,Luke accepts and next meets pilot Han solo and paid him to fly them in the Death star and rescue the princess Leia and deliver to rebel alliance against the Empire the plans about destroy Death star.Luke destroy the Death star and escapes.Come after the Empire strikes back and Return of the Jedi the epic tales continues.Obi wan used to say may the force be with you which is energy field created by all living things.The George Lucas fantasy galaxy is far far away and we want a ticket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars film review final draft 2.docx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brockhunt34
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brock Hunt Mr.Hicks ENG 101-008 September 20, 2013 A Space Opera Star Wars is a movie which focuses on a rebel alliance that fights against an oppressive regime set in a fictionalized universe a long time ago in a galaxy far far away. We're introduced to the main characters Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) and Darth Vader (David Prowse) for the first time. Luke is a farm boy who doesn't have a clue of what is about to happen. Darth Vader is an evil dark lord of the Sith who is trained in the dark side of the force and wants to defeat the rebel alliance. After Luke's family is murdered by the empire, he trains to be a Jedi by Obi-Wan Kenobi to defeat the evil Galactic Empire. George Lucas made Star Wars: A New Hope in 1976 and was released in the summer of 1977. He made episode four first because the story didn't require any high dollar special effects and wasn't sure how the movie would be accepted. When the movie opened, it received great reviews and audiences were amazed at the special effects. He would go on to direct the following sequels Empire Strikes Back and Return of the Jedi. Little do people know that George Lucas had the stories and screenplays of episodes one, two, and three already done before episode four was ever released. He did this because at the time technology didn't exist to produce the first three films with the fight sequences and settings that were in the first three films. I personally love the Star Wars films because of my personal connection with them. My grandmother introduced me to the Star Wars franchise as a child. On Saturday nights I would stay with my grandmother and she would play the movies on VHS. I never get tired of watching the films. Because every time I do, it takes me back in time when she was alive. Star Wars also opened up my interest in Sci-Fi movies. Some can say I'm a nerd but most don't know my extensive knowledge of the Star Wars franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of a new era!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the genius George Lucas was about to go help Spielberg make the majestic " Raiders", he decided to do something, something that many were surprised when it was announced and didn't take a lot of faith on, which after his release was an absolute success both at the box office and critical, and today the masterpiece of Lucas is a classic that will live forever in the history of cinema! "Star Wars" (not Star Wars IV A New Hope, please), begins with the yellow title suddenly appearing on the screen with an amazing soundtrack from the master John Williams giving us a resume of the history we are about to watch. It all starts with a small spaceship full of rebel soldiers start being invaded by imperial troops led by the sinister and cruel lord Darth Vader (David Prowse). Suddenly the film transports us directly to another side of the galaxy where we have the story of the young Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), a simple machine repairman teenager who lives with his uncles. A day after his uncle buy two servant robots, R2 - D2 (Kenny Baker) and C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), which inadvertently bring Luke the chance to realize his dreams of becoming a rebel and fight against the tyrant of the empire, a mission that will take him to the ends of the galaxy and will bring new friends but at the same time extreme dangers. From the beginning, "Star Wars" revolutionized cinema forever, especially the genre of sci - fi that at the time was just "Star Trek" with great success. Lucas of course certain elements form "Trek", since the crew of a spaceship with name style and friendship among the crew, but everything else was a tremendous attack of originality. Unlike "Star Trek" Lucas took the story and the great adventure with a lighter and fantasy tone, not childish but humorous, fun and even a certain religious point when the Jedi Obi - Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) appears in Luke's life with secrets of him and Luke's father past. And just like "Star Trek", Lucas gave his masterpiece unforgettable characters, of course: Luke, R2, C-3PO, Obi-Wan. But also the unforgettable Han Solo (Harrison Ford), the bounty hunter from space who ALWAYS shoots first and asks questions later, giving the film a great humorous touch and a lot of fun (never one character caused such influences as Han Solo did), and even Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) no royal woman before her in a film had never taken up arms showing she knew very well how to take care of herself. Not only the good guys who stand out perfectly in the story, but also the great and unforgettable antagonist ever put to film, Darth Vader, no villain was so cruel and yet so adored by fans. Characters and stories fitting perfectly, but the adventure to be full completed it needed the huge Galactic scenario, which is not lacking in this film. I think Lucas should have thanked Kubrick about "2001" because if it were not for this film, visual effects would never be the same. And thanks to that Lucas gave the film with beautiful scenery and a vast galaxies and an unforgettable and thrilling final battle. The classic that redefined cinema forever with a story well-crafted and told, full of suspense, humor and adventure thanks to its unforgettable characters and stunning visual effects , the legendary George Lucas gave the world a film with tremendous quality and early one of the best trilogies ever made. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated and outdated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emil Marty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying the movie doesn't suck, given the time it was made. The problem is that its legacy has created die-hard fans which have spawned the biggest franchise of all time; nothing wrong with that of course. But if you take a step back into modern day, you will see a film with all the elements a great fantasy epic should have (unimportant boy gets trained by old man, becomes great warrior etc) but a film where each element lacks the emotion to make you feel what you should. You don't feel sympathy when Luke's aunt and uncle die, you don't care about Kenobi's death because there was never an emotional stand-point that pinpointed him as a "great man". Everything simply happens without any given thought about the characters emotions. I could name a million films with all the same elements that have been done ten times better. That said, the originality is genuine, the whole story exciting and it's generally fun to watch. Just a shame its practically been ruined by its reputation as the greatest franchise ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Influential and Spectacular.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This first "Star Wars" film(though now retitled 'Episode IV') was a groundbreaking, box office shattering breath of fresh air to the cinemas, and science fiction in particular, which had gotten bogged down in bleak Dystopian futures. Nothing wrong with that in some cases, but moviegoers craved more, and got it with this extremely exciting tale of youth rebellion against an evil galactic empire led by Darth Vader(I though he was a robot at first viewing as a youngster!) a memorable creation, whose entrances were punctuated by the grand music of John Williams, who created an unforgettable score here that kids imitated endlessly! Fine cast includes Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing and Sir Alec Guiness. Climax is truly exciting, though film has a few lulls at times, this is still great fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope (originally released as just "Star Wars") is a masterpiece. Although the plot of the film is so simple that it almost hurts, it is brilliantly executed. It's a hero's journey in which the main character, Luke Skywalker, starts his adventures and finds himself in the middle of something bigger than he ever imagined. It is his story. Unfortunately, Luke's story tends to diminish the other character's stories in the first Star Wars trilogy. It's quite acceptable in this film, because Leia is the only character who really suffers from that (her non-reaction and non-follow-up on Alderaan's destruction is a shame). Sadly, this got even with with the next two films. Star Wars was a technical breakthrough and is in some ways still the best of all the Star Wars films. 9 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterful Work of Art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrrockey
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why am I even here? What's the point of me trying to review this film? Really, what's the point? Everybody knows about this film already and how great it is. So me trying to write a review of this film and trying to explain why it's so great is like re-telling the story of A Christmas Carol. Everybody knows it but yet, are always willing to listen. So I'll try my best to explain why I think this film has made the impact it did. Let's cut the crap and begin my analysis. PART 1: The Aesthetic Appeal of Star Wars Science-fiction was nothing new by the 70's. We've already had a lot of science-fiction movies by that time such as 2001: A Space Odyssey, THX 1138(another George Lucas film), Invasion of the Body Snatchers etc but the thing that made Star Wars different was its spirit. Most science- fiction films prior to Star Wars were cold, dark, and art-house-driven. Star Wars on the other hand, had an uplifting, positive, and imaginative tone to it that made it appeal to the child inside us. Star Wars takes place a long time ago, in a galaxy far far away with the classic hero's journey in the form of Luke Skywalker, the wise old mentor in the form of Obi-Wan Kenobi, the beautiful princess in Leia, the sinister, scheming villain in the form of Darth Vader, and the adventurous rogue in Han Solo. These things make Star Wars feel like a fairy-tale and made it timeless. Plus, the film had an amazing, classic, adventure serial look to it. The costumes, sets, sound effects, animatronics, and music all feel like they belong in a classic adventure serial, it makes you feel like a kid again! But while Star Wars is imaginative and uplifting, it's also a very smart film. PART 2: The Deeper Meanings Behind Star Wars On surface, Star Wars is just a little kiddie adventure with spaceships, laser gun battles, and wizards with laser swords but when you actually look into the story, there's actually a lot more substance to it than that. One of the themes in Star Wars is about finding meanings in life and the meaning of heroism. Star Wars is about finding meanings in life because it deals with characters who were never meant to be heroes but end up becoming greater than what they are. Luke Skywalker is a farmboy. He has no experience in any form of combat whatsoever and isn't even particularly smart but he ultimately saves the day because of his bravery and his good heart. Han Solo is just a smuggler. He was never the guy who would lead a bunch of Rebels to fight against the Empire, he only fought for one person which was himself. But towards the end of the movie, he finds a new purpose in life which is to become a Rebel and fight the Empire. Another theme in Star Wars is the idea of destiny. Most of these people here never belonged in the adventures they got themselves into in this movie but they ultimately do so because of The Force finding good in them and putting them there. In a way, it's destiny that brought these characters together and it's great that they didn't spell this out directly with its dialogue. PART 3: Why is Star Wars Still so Beloved Today? I think it's because of how original and fun it is. Even though it borrows a lot from classic adventure serials, classic fantasy literature, religious philosophy, historical events, and a whole other galaxy of inspirations, it combines them to create something new. It has endearing characters, an imaginative world, deep philosophy, and just provides good escapism overall. Plus, it's also just a lot of fun to watch with its action, humor, romance, and adventure. There's things here for everyone. Star Wars is intelligent, imaginative, clever, original, and just plain fun, it rightfully deserves a 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars, a new era...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Star Wars" was the start of something new, something different, something extraordinary for those times. Until today "Star Wars" considered the best Star Wars movie of all times. Personally I liked it very much and I can compare it with the other two movies of the classic trilogy: "Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back" and "Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi". George Lucas makes a great direction (nominated for the Oscar of Best Director in 1978) such the writing and screenplay (nominated for both for the the Oscar of Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen) and that great job seemed during the whole movie. Gary Kurtz also did an extremely good job for the Picture of the movie who is also nominated for the Oscar of Best Picture. The theme of this movie is that Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), Han Solo (Harrison Ford), C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), R2-D2 (Kenny Baker) and Chewbacca (Peter Mayhew) are going to save Princess Leia Organa (Carrie Fisher) from the evil Darth Vader (David Prowse) and they are also want to save the universe from the Empire's world-destroying battle-station.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Feat of Imagination, Fantasy & Creativity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ingredients that made Star Wars a revolution of its time are clearly noticeable, without a doubt, but the visual encapsulation of this sci-fi saga has aged pretty badly & today looks like an unintentionally funny ride than a masterpiece adventure. Still, at its core, Star Wars is a cinematic feat of imagination, fantasy & creativity that hypnotized an entire generation with its freshly envisioned & awe-inspiring world, gripping story, first-rate adventure & celebrated characters. It may not look as dazzling & groundbreaking today as it was in its time but its vast influences can be seen in plethora of sci-fi space fantasies, even today. Nicely crafted by George Lucas & introducing a sweeping visual effects, greatly influenced from Stanley Kubrick's 2001: A Space Odyssey, the outer surface of Star Wars may have degraded with time but the core hasn't aged a day, resulting in it making an impact in the sci-fi genre, blockbuster filmmaking & marketing, even today & hopefully for few more decades.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not just a great movie. It's important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story happened 'A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away'. The galaxy is under dictatorship. Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) is part of the rebellion but is capture by the evil Darth Vader. Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) the young hero, Han Solo (Harrison Ford) the brigand, and the wise master Ben Obi-Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) must together rescue the princess. The characters are icons pulled from classic storytelling. George Lucas was able to assemble such iconic characters into a well told story. Rarely is a movie change the nature of movie-making, and even the wider culture. This may be one of the most important movie of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Luke Skywalker joins force to fight against the Darth Vader and evil empire and bring peace in the universe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alex milonas
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The star wars saga is one of the most best movies about the space and development of language and technology as light saber droids and creatures from far beyond our imaginations.The character of Darth Vader which every kid and adult wants to wear his costume as well as the light saber which everyone buy one and play with an friend.Luke is raised by his uncle in planet totooine,Luke buys two droids R2 and C-3PO which had a message to ex-Jedi Knight Obi-Wan,Luke find him and told him about the message from the princess Leia,Obi wan convinced Luke to became Jedi knight,Luke accepts and next meets pilot Han solo and paid him to fly them in the Death star and rescue the princess Leia and deliver to rebel alliance against the Empire the plans about destroy Death star.Luke destroy the Death star and escapes.Come after the Empire strikes back and Return of the Jedi the epic tales continues.Obi wan used to say may the force be with you which is energy field created by all living things.The George Lucas fantasy galaxy is far far away and we want a ticket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars film review final draft 2.docx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brockhunt34
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brock Hunt Mr.Hicks ENG 101-008 September 20, 2013 A Space Opera Star Wars is a movie which focuses on a rebel alliance that fights against an oppressive regime set in a fictionalized universe a long time ago in a galaxy far far away. We're introduced to the main characters Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) and Darth Vader (David Prowse) for the first time. Luke is a farm boy who doesn't have a clue of what is about to happen. Darth Vader is an evil dark lord of the Sith who is trained in the dark side of the force and wants to defeat the rebel alliance. After Luke's family is murdered by the empire, he trains to be a Jedi by Obi-Wan Kenobi to defeat the evil Galactic Empire. George Lucas made Star Wars: A New Hope in 1976 and was released in the summer of 1977. He made episode four first because the story didn't require any high dollar special effects and wasn't sure how the movie would be accepted. When the movie opened, it received great reviews and audiences were amazed at the special effects. He would go on to direct the following sequels Empire Strikes Back and Return of the Jedi. Little do people know that George Lucas had the stories and screenplays of episodes one, two, and three already done before episode four was ever released. He did this because at the time technology didn't exist to produce the first three films with the fight sequences and settings that were in the first three films. I personally love the Star Wars films because of my personal connection with them. My grandmother introduced me to the Star Wars franchise as a child. On Saturday nights I would stay with my grandmother and she would play the movies on VHS. I never get tired of watching the films. Because every time I do, it takes me back in time when she was alive. Star Wars also opened up my interest in Sci-Fi movies. Some can say I'm a nerd but most don't know my extensive knowledge of the Star Wars franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of a new era!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the genius George Lucas was about to go help Spielberg make the majestic " Raiders", he decided to do something, something that many were surprised when it was announced and didn't take a lot of faith on, which after his release was an absolute success both at the box office and critical, and today the masterpiece of Lucas is a classic that will live forever in the history of cinema! "Star Wars" (not Star Wars IV A New Hope, please), begins with the yellow title suddenly appearing on the screen with an amazing soundtrack from the master John Williams giving us a resume of the history we are about to watch. It all starts with a small spaceship full of rebel soldiers start being invaded by imperial troops led by the sinister and cruel lord Darth Vader (David Prowse). Suddenly the film transports us directly to another side of the galaxy where we have the story of the young Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), a simple machine repairman teenager who lives with his uncles. A day after his uncle buy two servant robots, R2 - D2 (Kenny Baker) and C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), which inadvertently bring Luke the chance to realize his dreams of becoming a rebel and fight against the tyrant of the empire, a mission that will take him to the ends of the galaxy and will bring new friends but at the same time extreme dangers. From the beginning, "Star Wars" revolutionized cinema forever, especially the genre of sci - fi that at the time was just "Star Trek" with great success. Lucas of course certain elements form "Trek", since the crew of a spaceship with name style and friendship among the crew, but everything else was a tremendous attack of originality. Unlike "Star Trek" Lucas took the story and the great adventure with a lighter and fantasy tone, not childish but humorous, fun and even a certain religious point when the Jedi Obi - Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) appears in Luke's life with secrets of him and Luke's father past. And just like "Star Trek", Lucas gave his masterpiece unforgettable characters, of course: Luke, R2, C-3PO, Obi-Wan. But also the unforgettable Han Solo (Harrison Ford), the bounty hunter from space who ALWAYS shoots first and asks questions later, giving the film a great humorous touch and a lot of fun (never one character caused such influences as Han Solo did), and even Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) no royal woman before her in a film had never taken up arms showing she knew very well how to take care of herself. Not only the good guys who stand out perfectly in the story, but also the great and unforgettable antagonist ever put to film, Darth Vader, no villain was so cruel and yet so adored by fans. Characters and stories fitting perfectly, but the adventure to be full completed it needed the huge Galactic scenario, which is not lacking in this film. I think Lucas should have thanked Kubrick about "2001" because if it were not for this film, visual effects would never be the same. And thanks to that Lucas gave the film with beautiful scenery and a vast galaxies and an unforgettable and thrilling final battle. The classic that redefined cinema forever with a story well-crafted and told, full of suspense, humor and adventure thanks to its unforgettable characters and stunning visual effects , the legendary George Lucas gave the world a film with tremendous quality and early one of the best trilogies ever made. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated and outdated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emil Marty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying the movie doesn't suck, given the time it was made. The problem is that its legacy has created die-hard fans which have spawned the biggest franchise of all time; nothing wrong with that of course. But if you take a step back into modern day, you will see a film with all the elements a great fantasy epic should have (unimportant boy gets trained by old man, becomes great warrior etc) but a film where each element lacks the emotion to make you feel what you should. You don't feel sympathy when Luke's aunt and uncle die, you don't care about Kenobi's death because there was never an emotional stand-point that pinpointed him as a "great man". Everything simply happens without any given thought about the characters emotions. I could name a million films with all the same elements that have been done ten times better. That said, the originality is genuine, the whole story exciting and it's generally fun to watch. Just a shame its practically been ruined by its reputation as the greatest franchise ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Influential and Spectacular.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This first "Star Wars" film(though now retitled 'Episode IV') was a groundbreaking, box office shattering breath of fresh air to the cinemas, and science fiction in particular, which had gotten bogged down in bleak Dystopian futures. Nothing wrong with that in some cases, but moviegoers craved more, and got it with this extremely exciting tale of youth rebellion against an evil galactic empire led by Darth Vader(I though he was a robot at first viewing as a youngster!) a memorable creation, whose entrances were punctuated by the grand music of John Williams, who created an unforgettable score here that kids imitated endlessly! Fine cast includes Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing and Sir Alec Guiness. Climax is truly exciting, though film has a few lulls at times, this is still great fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope (originally released as just "Star Wars") is a masterpiece. Although the plot of the film is so simple that it almost hurts, it is brilliantly executed. It's a hero's journey in which the main character, Luke Skywalker, starts his adventures and finds himself in the middle of something bigger than he ever imagined. It is his story. Unfortunately, Luke's story tends to diminish the other character's stories in the first Star Wars trilogy. It's quite acceptable in this film, because Leia is the only character who really suffers from that (her non-reaction and non-follow-up on Alderaan's destruction is a shame). Sadly, this got even with with the next two films. Star Wars was a technical breakthrough and is in some ways still the best of all the Star Wars films. 9 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterful Work of Art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrrockey
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why am I even here? What's the point of me trying to review this film? Really, what's the point? Everybody knows about this film already and how great it is. So me trying to write a review of this film and trying to explain why it's so great is like re-telling the story of A Christmas Carol. Everybody knows it but yet, are always willing to listen. So I'll try my best to explain why I think this film has made the impact it did. Let's cut the crap and begin my analysis. PART 1: The Aesthetic Appeal of Star Wars Science-fiction was nothing new by the 70's. We've already had a lot of science-fiction movies by that time such as 2001: A Space Odyssey, THX 1138(another George Lucas film), Invasion of the Body Snatchers etc but the thing that made Star Wars different was its spirit. Most science- fiction films prior to Star Wars were cold, dark, and art-house-driven. Star Wars on the other hand, had an uplifting, positive, and imaginative tone to it that made it appeal to the child inside us. Star Wars takes place a long time ago, in a galaxy far far away with the classic hero's journey in the form of Luke Skywalker, the wise old mentor in the form of Obi-Wan Kenobi, the beautiful princess in Leia, the sinister, scheming villain in the form of Darth Vader, and the adventurous rogue in Han Solo. These things make Star Wars feel like a fairy-tale and made it timeless. Plus, the film had an amazing, classic, adventure serial look to it. The costumes, sets, sound effects, animatronics, and music all feel like they belong in a classic adventure serial, it makes you feel like a kid again! But while Star Wars is imaginative and uplifting, it's also a very smart film. PART 2: The Deeper Meanings Behind Star Wars On surface, Star Wars is just a little kiddie adventure with spaceships, laser gun battles, and wizards with laser swords but when you actually look into the story, there's actually a lot more substance to it than that. One of the themes in Star Wars is about finding meanings in life and the meaning of heroism. Star Wars is about finding meanings in life because it deals with characters who were never meant to be heroes but end up becoming greater than what they are. Luke Skywalker is a farmboy. He has no experience in any form of combat whatsoever and isn't even particularly smart but he ultimately saves the day because of his bravery and his good heart. Han Solo is just a smuggler. He was never the guy who would lead a bunch of Rebels to fight against the Empire, he only fought for one person which was himself. But towards the end of the movie, he finds a new purpose in life which is to become a Rebel and fight the Empire. Another theme in Star Wars is the idea of destiny. Most of these people here never belonged in the adventures they got themselves into in this movie but they ultimately do so because of The Force finding good in them and putting them there. In a way, it's destiny that brought these characters together and it's great that they didn't spell this out directly with its dialogue. PART 3: Why is Star Wars Still so Beloved Today? I think it's because of how original and fun it is. Even though it borrows a lot from classic adventure serials, classic fantasy literature, religious philosophy, historical events, and a whole other galaxy of inspirations, it combines them to create something new. It has endearing characters, an imaginative world, deep philosophy, and just provides good escapism overall. Plus, it's also just a lot of fun to watch with its action, humor, romance, and adventure. There's things here for everyone. Star Wars is intelligent, imaginative, clever, original, and just plain fun, it rightfully deserves a 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars, a new era...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Star Wars" was the start of something new, something different, something extraordinary for those times. Until today "Star Wars" considered the best Star Wars movie of all times. Personally I liked it very much and I can compare it with the other two movies of the classic trilogy: "Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back" and "Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi". George Lucas makes a great direction (nominated for the Oscar of Best Director in 1978) such the writing and screenplay (nominated for both for the the Oscar of Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen) and that great job seemed during the whole movie. Gary Kurtz also did an extremely good job for the Picture of the movie who is also nominated for the Oscar of Best Picture. The theme of this movie is that Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), Han Solo (Harrison Ford), C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), R2-D2 (Kenny Baker) and Chewbacca (Peter Mayhew) are going to save Princess Leia Organa (Carrie Fisher) from the evil Darth Vader (David Prowse) and they are also want to save the universe from the Empire's world-destroying battle-station.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Feat of Imagination, Fantasy & Creativity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ingredients that made Star Wars a revolution of its time are clearly noticeable, without a doubt, but the visual encapsulation of this sci-fi saga has aged pretty badly & today looks like an unintentionally funny ride than a masterpiece adventure. Still, at its core, Star Wars is a cinematic feat of imagination, fantasy & creativity that hypnotized an entire generation with its freshly envisioned & awe-inspiring world, gripping story, first-rate adventure & celebrated characters. It may not look as dazzling & groundbreaking today as it was in its time but its vast influences can be seen in plethora of sci-fi space fantasies, even today. Nicely crafted by George Lucas & introducing a sweeping visual effects, greatly influenced from Stanley Kubrick's 2001: A Space Odyssey, the outer surface of Star Wars may have degraded with time but the core hasn't aged a day, resulting in it making an impact in the sci-fi genre, blockbuster filmmaking & marketing, even today & hopefully for few more decades.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not just a great movie. It's important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story happened 'A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away'. The galaxy is under dictatorship. Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) is part of the rebellion but is capture by the evil Darth Vader. Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) the young hero, Han Solo (Harrison Ford) the brigand, and the wise master Ben Obi-Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) must together rescue the princess. The characters are icons pulled from classic storytelling. George Lucas was able to assemble such iconic characters into a well told story. Rarely is a movie change the nature of movie-making, and even the wider culture. This may be one of the most important movie of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Luke Skywalker joins force to fight against the Darth Vader and evil empire and bring peace in the universe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alex milonas
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The star wars saga is one of the most best movies about the space and development of language and technology as light saber droids and creatures from far beyond our imaginations.The character of Darth Vader which every kid and adult wants to wear his costume as well as the light saber which everyone buy one and play with an friend.Luke is raised by his uncle in planet totooine,Luke buys two droids R2 and C-3PO which had a message to ex-Jedi Knight Obi-Wan,Luke find him and told him about the message from the princess Leia,Obi wan convinced Luke to became Jedi knight,Luke accepts and next meets pilot Han solo and paid him to fly them in the Death star and rescue the princess Leia and deliver to rebel alliance against the Empire the plans about destroy Death star.Luke destroy the Death star and escapes.Come after the Empire strikes back and Return of the Jedi the epic tales continues.Obi wan used to say may the force be with you which is energy field created by all living things.The George Lucas fantasy galaxy is far far away and we want a ticket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars film review final draft 2.docx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brockhunt34
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brock Hunt Mr.Hicks ENG 101-008 September 20, 2013 A Space Opera Star Wars is a movie which focuses on a rebel alliance that fights against an oppressive regime set in a fictionalized universe a long time ago in a galaxy far far away. We're introduced to the main characters Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) and Darth Vader (David Prowse) for the first time. Luke is a farm boy who doesn't have a clue of what is about to happen. Darth Vader is an evil dark lord of the Sith who is trained in the dark side of the force and wants to defeat the rebel alliance. After Luke's family is murdered by the empire, he trains to be a Jedi by Obi-Wan Kenobi to defeat the evil Galactic Empire. George Lucas made Star Wars: A New Hope in 1976 and was released in the summer of 1977. He made episode four first because the story didn't require any high dollar special effects and wasn't sure how the movie would be accepted. When the movie opened, it received great reviews and audiences were amazed at the special effects. He would go on to direct the following sequels Empire Strikes Back and Return of the Jedi. Little do people know that George Lucas had the stories and screenplays of episodes one, two, and three already done before episode four was ever released. He did this because at the time technology didn't exist to produce the first three films with the fight sequences and settings that were in the first three films. I personally love the Star Wars films because of my personal connection with them. My grandmother introduced me to the Star Wars franchise as a child. On Saturday nights I would stay with my grandmother and she would play the movies on VHS. I never get tired of watching the films. Because every time I do, it takes me back in time when she was alive. Star Wars also opened up my interest in Sci-Fi movies. Some can say I'm a nerd but most don't know my extensive knowledge of the Star Wars franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of a new era!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the genius George Lucas was about to go help Spielberg make the majestic " Raiders", he decided to do something, something that many were surprised when it was announced and didn't take a lot of faith on, which after his release was an absolute success both at the box office and critical, and today the masterpiece of Lucas is a classic that will live forever in the history of cinema! "Star Wars" (not Star Wars IV A New Hope, please), begins with the yellow title suddenly appearing on the screen with an amazing soundtrack from the master John Williams giving us a resume of the history we are about to watch. It all starts with a small spaceship full of rebel soldiers start being invaded by imperial troops led by the sinister and cruel lord Darth Vader (David Prowse). Suddenly the film transports us directly to another side of the galaxy where we have the story of the young Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), a simple machine repairman teenager who lives with his uncles. A day after his uncle buy two servant robots, R2 - D2 (Kenny Baker) and C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), which inadvertently bring Luke the chance to realize his dreams of becoming a rebel and fight against the tyrant of the empire, a mission that will take him to the ends of the galaxy and will bring new friends but at the same time extreme dangers. From the beginning, "Star Wars" revolutionized cinema forever, especially the genre of sci - fi that at the time was just "Star Trek" with great success. Lucas of course certain elements form "Trek", since the crew of a spaceship with name style and friendship among the crew, but everything else was a tremendous attack of originality. Unlike "Star Trek" Lucas took the story and the great adventure with a lighter and fantasy tone, not childish but humorous, fun and even a certain religious point when the Jedi Obi - Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) appears in Luke's life with secrets of him and Luke's father past. And just like "Star Trek", Lucas gave his masterpiece unforgettable characters, of course: Luke, R2, C-3PO, Obi-Wan. But also the unforgettable Han Solo (Harrison Ford), the bounty hunter from space who ALWAYS shoots first and asks questions later, giving the film a great humorous touch and a lot of fun (never one character caused such influences as Han Solo did), and even Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) no royal woman before her in a film had never taken up arms showing she knew very well how to take care of herself. Not only the good guys who stand out perfectly in the story, but also the great and unforgettable antagonist ever put to film, Darth Vader, no villain was so cruel and yet so adored by fans. Characters and stories fitting perfectly, but the adventure to be full completed it needed the huge Galactic scenario, which is not lacking in this film. I think Lucas should have thanked Kubrick about "2001" because if it were not for this film, visual effects would never be the same. And thanks to that Lucas gave the film with beautiful scenery and a vast galaxies and an unforgettable and thrilling final battle. The classic that redefined cinema forever with a story well-crafted and told, full of suspense, humor and adventure thanks to its unforgettable characters and stunning visual effects , the legendary George Lucas gave the world a film with tremendous quality and early one of the best trilogies ever made. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated and outdated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emil Marty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying the movie doesn't suck, given the time it was made. The problem is that its legacy has created die-hard fans which have spawned the biggest franchise of all time; nothing wrong with that of course. But if you take a step back into modern day, you will see a film with all the elements a great fantasy epic should have (unimportant boy gets trained by old man, becomes great warrior etc) but a film where each element lacks the emotion to make you feel what you should. You don't feel sympathy when Luke's aunt and uncle die, you don't care about Kenobi's death because there was never an emotional stand-point that pinpointed him as a "great man". Everything simply happens without any given thought about the characters emotions. I could name a million films with all the same elements that have been done ten times better. That said, the originality is genuine, the whole story exciting and it's generally fun to watch. Just a shame its practically been ruined by its reputation as the greatest franchise ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Influential and Spectacular.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This first "Star Wars" film(though now retitled 'Episode IV') was a groundbreaking, box office shattering breath of fresh air to the cinemas, and science fiction in particular, which had gotten bogged down in bleak Dystopian futures. Nothing wrong with that in some cases, but moviegoers craved more, and got it with this extremely exciting tale of youth rebellion against an evil galactic empire led by Darth Vader(I though he was a robot at first viewing as a youngster!) a memorable creation, whose entrances were punctuated by the grand music of John Williams, who created an unforgettable score here that kids imitated endlessly! Fine cast includes Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing and Sir Alec Guiness. Climax is truly exciting, though film has a few lulls at times, this is still great fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope (originally released as just "Star Wars") is a masterpiece. Although the plot of the film is so simple that it almost hurts, it is brilliantly executed. It's a hero's journey in which the main character, Luke Skywalker, starts his adventures and finds himself in the middle of something bigger than he ever imagined. It is his story. Unfortunately, Luke's story tends to diminish the other character's stories in the first Star Wars trilogy. It's quite acceptable in this film, because Leia is the only character who really suffers from that (her non-reaction and non-follow-up on Alderaan's destruction is a shame). Sadly, this got even with with the next two films. Star Wars was a technical breakthrough and is in some ways still the best of all the Star Wars films. 9 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterful Work of Art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrrockey
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why am I even here? What's the point of me trying to review this film? Really, what's the point? Everybody knows about this film already and how great it is. So me trying to write a review of this film and trying to explain why it's so great is like re-telling the story of A Christmas Carol. Everybody knows it but yet, are always willing to listen. So I'll try my best to explain why I think this film has made the impact it did. Let's cut the crap and begin my analysis. PART 1: The Aesthetic Appeal of Star Wars Science-fiction was nothing new by the 70's. We've already had a lot of science-fiction movies by that time such as 2001: A Space Odyssey, THX 1138(another George Lucas film), Invasion of the Body Snatchers etc but the thing that made Star Wars different was its spirit. Most science- fiction films prior to Star Wars were cold, dark, and art-house-driven. Star Wars on the other hand, had an uplifting, positive, and imaginative tone to it that made it appeal to the child inside us. Star Wars takes place a long time ago, in a galaxy far far away with the classic hero's journey in the form of Luke Skywalker, the wise old mentor in the form of Obi-Wan Kenobi, the beautiful princess in Leia, the sinister, scheming villain in the form of Darth Vader, and the adventurous rogue in Han Solo. These things make Star Wars feel like a fairy-tale and made it timeless. Plus, the film had an amazing, classic, adventure serial look to it. The costumes, sets, sound effects, animatronics, and music all feel like they belong in a classic adventure serial, it makes you feel like a kid again! But while Star Wars is imaginative and uplifting, it's also a very smart film. PART 2: The Deeper Meanings Behind Star Wars On surface, Star Wars is just a little kiddie adventure with spaceships, laser gun battles, and wizards with laser swords but when you actually look into the story, there's actually a lot more substance to it than that. One of the themes in Star Wars is about finding meanings in life and the meaning of heroism. Star Wars is about finding meanings in life because it deals with characters who were never meant to be heroes but end up becoming greater than what they are. Luke Skywalker is a farmboy. He has no experience in any form of combat whatsoever and isn't even particularly smart but he ultimately saves the day because of his bravery and his good heart. Han Solo is just a smuggler. He was never the guy who would lead a bunch of Rebels to fight against the Empire, he only fought for one person which was himself. But towards the end of the movie, he finds a new purpose in life which is to become a Rebel and fight the Empire. Another theme in Star Wars is the idea of destiny. Most of these people here never belonged in the adventures they got themselves into in this movie but they ultimately do so because of The Force finding good in them and putting them there. In a way, it's destiny that brought these characters together and it's great that they didn't spell this out directly with its dialogue. PART 3: Why is Star Wars Still so Beloved Today? I think it's because of how original and fun it is. Even though it borrows a lot from classic adventure serials, classic fantasy literature, religious philosophy, historical events, and a whole other galaxy of inspirations, it combines them to create something new. It has endearing characters, an imaginative world, deep philosophy, and just provides good escapism overall. Plus, it's also just a lot of fun to watch with its action, humor, romance, and adventure. There's things here for everyone. Star Wars is intelligent, imaginative, clever, original, and just plain fun, it rightfully deserves a 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars, a new era...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Star Wars" was the start of something new, something different, something extraordinary for those times. Until today "Star Wars" considered the best Star Wars movie of all times. Personally I liked it very much and I can compare it with the other two movies of the classic trilogy: "Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back" and "Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi". George Lucas makes a great direction (nominated for the Oscar of Best Director in 1978) such the writing and screenplay (nominated for both for the the Oscar of Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen) and that great job seemed during the whole movie. Gary Kurtz also did an extremely good job for the Picture of the movie who is also nominated for the Oscar of Best Picture. The theme of this movie is that Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), Han Solo (Harrison Ford), C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), R2-D2 (Kenny Baker) and Chewbacca (Peter Mayhew) are going to save Princess Leia Organa (Carrie Fisher) from the evil Darth Vader (David Prowse) and they are also want to save the universe from the Empire's world-destroying battle-station.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Feat of Imagination, Fantasy & Creativity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ingredients that made Star Wars a revolution of its time are clearly noticeable, without a doubt, but the visual encapsulation of this sci-fi saga has aged pretty badly & today looks like an unintentionally funny ride than a masterpiece adventure. Still, at its core, Star Wars is a cinematic feat of imagination, fantasy & creativity that hypnotized an entire generation with its freshly envisioned & awe-inspiring world, gripping story, first-rate adventure & celebrated characters. It may not look as dazzling & groundbreaking today as it was in its time but its vast influences can be seen in plethora of sci-fi space fantasies, even today. Nicely crafted by George Lucas & introducing a sweeping visual effects, greatly influenced from Stanley Kubrick's 2001: A Space Odyssey, the outer surface of Star Wars may have degraded with time but the core hasn't aged a day, resulting in it making an impact in the sci-fi genre, blockbuster filmmaking & marketing, even today & hopefully for few more decades.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not just a great movie. It's important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story happened 'A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away'. The galaxy is under dictatorship. Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) is part of the rebellion but is capture by the evil Darth Vader. Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) the young hero, Han Solo (Harrison Ford) the brigand, and the wise master Ben Obi-Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) must together rescue the princess. The characters are icons pulled from classic storytelling. George Lucas was able to assemble such iconic characters into a well told story. Rarely is a movie change the nature of movie-making, and even the wider culture. This may be one of the most important movie of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Luke Skywalker joins force to fight against the Darth Vader and evil empire and bring peace in the universe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alex milonas
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The star wars saga is one of the most best movies about the space and development of language and technology as light saber droids and creatures from far beyond our imaginations.The character of Darth Vader which every kid and adult wants to wear his costume as well as the light saber which everyone buy one and play with an friend.Luke is raised by his uncle in planet totooine,Luke buys two droids R2 and C-3PO which had a message to ex-Jedi Knight Obi-Wan,Luke find him and told him about the message from the princess Leia,Obi wan convinced Luke to became Jedi knight,Luke accepts and next meets pilot Han solo and paid him to fly them in the Death star and rescue the princess Leia and deliver to rebel alliance against the Empire the plans about destroy Death star.Luke destroy the Death star and escapes.Come after the Empire strikes back and Return of the Jedi the epic tales continues.Obi wan used to say may the force be with you which is energy field created by all living things.The George Lucas fantasy galaxy is far far away and we want a ticket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars film review final draft 2.docx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brockhunt34
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brock Hunt Mr.Hicks ENG 101-008 September 20, 2013 A Space Opera Star Wars is a movie which focuses on a rebel alliance that fights against an oppressive regime set in a fictionalized universe a long time ago in a galaxy far far away. We're introduced to the main characters Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) and Darth Vader (David Prowse) for the first time. Luke is a farm boy who doesn't have a clue of what is about to happen. Darth Vader is an evil dark lord of the Sith who is trained in the dark side of the force and wants to defeat the rebel alliance. After Luke's family is murdered by the empire, he trains to be a Jedi by Obi-Wan Kenobi to defeat the evil Galactic Empire. George Lucas made Star Wars: A New Hope in 1976 and was released in the summer of 1977. He made episode four first because the story didn't require any high dollar special effects and wasn't sure how the movie would be accepted. When the movie opened, it received great reviews and audiences were amazed at the special effects. He would go on to direct the following sequels Empire Strikes Back and Return of the Jedi. Little do people know that George Lucas had the stories and screenplays of episodes one, two, and three already done before episode four was ever released. He did this because at the time technology didn't exist to produce the first three films with the fight sequences and settings that were in the first three films. I personally love the Star Wars films because of my personal connection with them. My grandmother introduced me to the Star Wars franchise as a child. On Saturday nights I would stay with my grandmother and she would play the movies on VHS. I never get tired of watching the films. Because every time I do, it takes me back in time when she was alive. Star Wars also opened up my interest in Sci-Fi movies. Some can say I'm a nerd but most don't know my extensive knowledge of the Star Wars franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of a new era!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the genius George Lucas was about to go help Spielberg make the majestic " Raiders", he decided to do something, something that many were surprised when it was announced and didn't take a lot of faith on, which after his release was an absolute success both at the box office and critical, and today the masterpiece of Lucas is a classic that will live forever in the history of cinema! "Star Wars" (not Star Wars IV A New Hope, please), begins with the yellow title suddenly appearing on the screen with an amazing soundtrack from the master John Williams giving us a resume of the history we are about to watch. It all starts with a small spaceship full of rebel soldiers start being invaded by imperial troops led by the sinister and cruel lord Darth Vader (David Prowse). Suddenly the film transports us directly to another side of the galaxy where we have the story of the young Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), a simple machine repairman teenager who lives with his uncles. A day after his uncle buy two servant robots, R2 - D2 (Kenny Baker) and C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), which inadvertently bring Luke the chance to realize his dreams of becoming a rebel and fight against the tyrant of the empire, a mission that will take him to the ends of the galaxy and will bring new friends but at the same time extreme dangers. From the beginning, "Star Wars" revolutionized cinema forever, especially the genre of sci - fi that at the time was just "Star Trek" with great success. Lucas of course certain elements form "Trek", since the crew of a spaceship with name style and friendship among the crew, but everything else was a tremendous attack of originality. Unlike "Star Trek" Lucas took the story and the great adventure with a lighter and fantasy tone, not childish but humorous, fun and even a certain religious point when the Jedi Obi - Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) appears in Luke's life with secrets of him and Luke's father past. And just like "Star Trek", Lucas gave his masterpiece unforgettable characters, of course: Luke, R2, C-3PO, Obi-Wan. But also the unforgettable Han Solo (Harrison Ford), the bounty hunter from space who ALWAYS shoots first and asks questions later, giving the film a great humorous touch and a lot of fun (never one character caused such influences as Han Solo did), and even Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) no royal woman before her in a film had never taken up arms showing she knew very well how to take care of herself. Not only the good guys who stand out perfectly in the story, but also the great and unforgettable antagonist ever put to film, Darth Vader, no villain was so cruel and yet so adored by fans. Characters and stories fitting perfectly, but the adventure to be full completed it needed the huge Galactic scenario, which is not lacking in this film. I think Lucas should have thanked Kubrick about "2001" because if it were not for this film, visual effects would never be the same. And thanks to that Lucas gave the film with beautiful scenery and a vast galaxies and an unforgettable and thrilling final battle. The classic that redefined cinema forever with a story well-crafted and told, full of suspense, humor and adventure thanks to its unforgettable characters and stunning visual effects , the legendary George Lucas gave the world a film with tremendous quality and early one of the best trilogies ever made. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated and outdated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emil Marty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying the movie doesn't suck, given the time it was made. The problem is that its legacy has created die-hard fans which have spawned the biggest franchise of all time; nothing wrong with that of course. But if you take a step back into modern day, you will see a film with all the elements a great fantasy epic should have (unimportant boy gets trained by old man, becomes great warrior etc) but a film where each element lacks the emotion to make you feel what you should. You don't feel sympathy when Luke's aunt and uncle die, you don't care about Kenobi's death because there was never an emotional stand-point that pinpointed him as a "great man". Everything simply happens without any given thought about the characters emotions. I could name a million films with all the same elements that have been done ten times better. That said, the originality is genuine, the whole story exciting and it's generally fun to watch. Just a shame its practically been ruined by its reputation as the greatest franchise ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Influential and Spectacular.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This first "Star Wars" film(though now retitled 'Episode IV') was a groundbreaking, box office shattering breath of fresh air to the cinemas, and science fiction in particular, which had gotten bogged down in bleak Dystopian futures. Nothing wrong with that in some cases, but moviegoers craved more, and got it with this extremely exciting tale of youth rebellion against an evil galactic empire led by Darth Vader(I though he was a robot at first viewing as a youngster!) a memorable creation, whose entrances were punctuated by the grand music of John Williams, who created an unforgettable score here that kids imitated endlessly! Fine cast includes Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing and Sir Alec Guiness. Climax is truly exciting, though film has a few lulls at times, this is still great fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope (originally released as just "Star Wars") is a masterpiece. Although the plot of the film is so simple that it almost hurts, it is brilliantly executed. It's a hero's journey in which the main character, Luke Skywalker, starts his adventures and finds himself in the middle of something bigger than he ever imagined. It is his story. Unfortunately, Luke's story tends to diminish the other character's stories in the first Star Wars trilogy. It's quite acceptable in this film, because Leia is the only character who really suffers from that (her non-reaction and non-follow-up on Alderaan's destruction is a shame). Sadly, this got even with with the next two films. Star Wars was a technical breakthrough and is in some ways still the best of all the Star Wars films. 9 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterful Work of Art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrrockey
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why am I even here? What's the point of me trying to review this film? Really, what's the point? Everybody knows about this film already and how great it is. So me trying to write a review of this film and trying to explain why it's so great is like re-telling the story of A Christmas Carol. Everybody knows it but yet, are always willing to listen. So I'll try my best to explain why I think this film has made the impact it did. Let's cut the crap and begin my analysis. PART 1: The Aesthetic Appeal of Star Wars Science-fiction was nothing new by the 70's. We've already had a lot of science-fiction movies by that time such as 2001: A Space Odyssey, THX 1138(another George Lucas film), Invasion of the Body Snatchers etc but the thing that made Star Wars different was its spirit. Most science- fiction films prior to Star Wars were cold, dark, and art-house-driven. Star Wars on the other hand, had an uplifting, positive, and imaginative tone to it that made it appeal to the child inside us. Star Wars takes place a long time ago, in a galaxy far far away with the classic hero's journey in the form of Luke Skywalker, the wise old mentor in the form of Obi-Wan Kenobi, the beautiful princess in Leia, the sinister, scheming villain in the form of Darth Vader, and the adventurous rogue in Han Solo. These things make Star Wars feel like a fairy-tale and made it timeless. Plus, the film had an amazing, classic, adventure serial look to it. The costumes, sets, sound effects, animatronics, and music all feel like they belong in a classic adventure serial, it makes you feel like a kid again! But while Star Wars is imaginative and uplifting, it's also a very smart film. PART 2: The Deeper Meanings Behind Star Wars On surface, Star Wars is just a little kiddie adventure with spaceships, laser gun battles, and wizards with laser swords but when you actually look into the story, there's actually a lot more substance to it than that. One of the themes in Star Wars is about finding meanings in life and the meaning of heroism. Star Wars is about finding meanings in life because it deals with characters who were never meant to be heroes but end up becoming greater than what they are. Luke Skywalker is a farmboy. He has no experience in any form of combat whatsoever and isn't even particularly smart but he ultimately saves the day because of his bravery and his good heart. Han Solo is just a smuggler. He was never the guy who would lead a bunch of Rebels to fight against the Empire, he only fought for one person which was himself. But towards the end of the movie, he finds a new purpose in life which is to become a Rebel and fight the Empire. Another theme in Star Wars is the idea of destiny. Most of these people here never belonged in the adventures they got themselves into in this movie but they ultimately do so because of The Force finding good in them and putting them there. In a way, it's destiny that brought these characters together and it's great that they didn't spell this out directly with its dialogue. PART 3: Why is Star Wars Still so Beloved Today? I think it's because of how original and fun it is. Even though it borrows a lot from classic adventure serials, classic fantasy literature, religious philosophy, historical events, and a whole other galaxy of inspirations, it combines them to create something new. It has endearing characters, an imaginative world, deep philosophy, and just provides good escapism overall. Plus, it's also just a lot of fun to watch with its action, humor, romance, and adventure. There's things here for everyone. Star Wars is intelligent, imaginative, clever, original, and just plain fun, it rightfully deserves a 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars, a new era...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Star Wars" was the start of something new, something different, something extraordinary for those times. Until today "Star Wars" considered the best Star Wars movie of all times. Personally I liked it very much and I can compare it with the other two movies of the classic trilogy: "Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back" and "Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi". George Lucas makes a great direction (nominated for the Oscar of Best Director in 1978) such the writing and screenplay (nominated for both for the the Oscar of Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen) and that great job seemed during the whole movie. Gary Kurtz also did an extremely good job for the Picture of the movie who is also nominated for the Oscar of Best Picture. The theme of this movie is that Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), Han Solo (Harrison Ford), C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), R2-D2 (Kenny Baker) and Chewbacca (Peter Mayhew) are going to save Princess Leia Organa (Carrie Fisher) from the evil Darth Vader (David Prowse) and they are also want to save the universe from the Empire's world-destroying battle-station.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Feat of Imagination, Fantasy & Creativity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ingredients that made Star Wars a revolution of its time are clearly noticeable, without a doubt, but the visual encapsulation of this sci-fi saga has aged pretty badly & today looks like an unintentionally funny ride than a masterpiece adventure. Still, at its core, Star Wars is a cinematic feat of imagination, fantasy & creativity that hypnotized an entire generation with its freshly envisioned & awe-inspiring world, gripping story, first-rate adventure & celebrated characters. It may not look as dazzling & groundbreaking today as it was in its time but its vast influences can be seen in plethora of sci-fi space fantasies, even today. Nicely crafted by George Lucas & introducing a sweeping visual effects, greatly influenced from Stanley Kubrick's 2001: A Space Odyssey, the outer surface of Star Wars may have degraded with time but the core hasn't aged a day, resulting in it making an impact in the sci-fi genre, blockbuster filmmaking & marketing, even today & hopefully for few more decades.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not just a great movie. It's important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story happened 'A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away'. The galaxy is under dictatorship. Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) is part of the rebellion but is capture by the evil Darth Vader. Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) the young hero, Han Solo (Harrison Ford) the brigand, and the wise master Ben Obi-Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) must together rescue the princess. The characters are icons pulled from classic storytelling. George Lucas was able to assemble such iconic characters into a well told story. Rarely is a movie change the nature of movie-making, and even the wider culture. This may be one of the most important movie of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Luke Skywalker joins force to fight against the Darth Vader and evil empire and bring peace in the universe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alex milonas
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The star wars saga is one of the most best movies about the space and development of language and technology as light saber droids and creatures from far beyond our imaginations.The character of Darth Vader which every kid and adult wants to wear his costume as well as the light saber which everyone buy one and play with an friend.Luke is raised by his uncle in planet totooine,Luke buys two droids R2 and C-3PO which had a message to ex-Jedi Knight Obi-Wan,Luke find him and told him about the message from the princess Leia,Obi wan convinced Luke to became Jedi knight,Luke accepts and next meets pilot Han solo and paid him to fly them in the Death star and rescue the princess Leia and deliver to rebel alliance against the Empire the plans about destroy Death star.Luke destroy the Death star and escapes.Come after the Empire strikes back and Return of the Jedi the epic tales continues.Obi wan used to say may the force be with you which is energy field created by all living things.The George Lucas fantasy galaxy is far far away and we want a ticket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars film review final draft 2.docx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brockhunt34
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brock Hunt Mr.Hicks ENG 101-008 September 20, 2013 A Space Opera Star Wars is a movie which focuses on a rebel alliance that fights against an oppressive regime set in a fictionalized universe a long time ago in a galaxy far far away. We're introduced to the main characters Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) and Darth Vader (David Prowse) for the first time. Luke is a farm boy who doesn't have a clue of what is about to happen. Darth Vader is an evil dark lord of the Sith who is trained in the dark side of the force and wants to defeat the rebel alliance. After Luke's family is murdered by the empire, he trains to be a Jedi by Obi-Wan Kenobi to defeat the evil Galactic Empire. George Lucas made Star Wars: A New Hope in 1976 and was released in the summer of 1977. He made episode four first because the story didn't require any high dollar special effects and wasn't sure how the movie would be accepted. When the movie opened, it received great reviews and audiences were amazed at the special effects. He would go on to direct the following sequels Empire Strikes Back and Return of the Jedi. Little do people know that George Lucas had the stories and screenplays of episodes one, two, and three already done before episode four was ever released. He did this because at the time technology didn't exist to produce the first three films with the fight sequences and settings that were in the first three films. I personally love the Star Wars films because of my personal connection with them. My grandmother introduced me to the Star Wars franchise as a child. On Saturday nights I would stay with my grandmother and she would play the movies on VHS. I never get tired of watching the films. Because every time I do, it takes me back in time when she was alive. Star Wars also opened up my interest in Sci-Fi movies. Some can say I'm a nerd but most don't know my extensive knowledge of the Star Wars franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of a new era!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the genius George Lucas was about to go help Spielberg make the majestic " Raiders", he decided to do something, something that many were surprised when it was announced and didn't take a lot of faith on, which after his release was an absolute success both at the box office and critical, and today the masterpiece of Lucas is a classic that will live forever in the history of cinema! "Star Wars" (not Star Wars IV A New Hope, please), begins with the yellow title suddenly appearing on the screen with an amazing soundtrack from the master John Williams giving us a resume of the history we are about to watch. It all starts with a small spaceship full of rebel soldiers start being invaded by imperial troops led by the sinister and cruel lord Darth Vader (David Prowse). Suddenly the film transports us directly to another side of the galaxy where we have the story of the young Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), a simple machine repairman teenager who lives with his uncles. A day after his uncle buy two servant robots, R2 - D2 (Kenny Baker) and C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), which inadvertently bring Luke the chance to realize his dreams of becoming a rebel and fight against the tyrant of the empire, a mission that will take him to the ends of the galaxy and will bring new friends but at the same time extreme dangers. From the beginning, "Star Wars" revolutionized cinema forever, especially the genre of sci - fi that at the time was just "Star Trek" with great success. Lucas of course certain elements form "Trek", since the crew of a spaceship with name style and friendship among the crew, but everything else was a tremendous attack of originality. Unlike "Star Trek" Lucas took the story and the great adventure with a lighter and fantasy tone, not childish but humorous, fun and even a certain religious point when the Jedi Obi - Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) appears in Luke's life with secrets of him and Luke's father past. And just like "Star Trek", Lucas gave his masterpiece unforgettable characters, of course: Luke, R2, C-3PO, Obi-Wan. But also the unforgettable Han Solo (Harrison Ford), the bounty hunter from space who ALWAYS shoots first and asks questions later, giving the film a great humorous touch and a lot of fun (never one character caused such influences as Han Solo did), and even Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) no royal woman before her in a film had never taken up arms showing she knew very well how to take care of herself. Not only the good guys who stand out perfectly in the story, but also the great and unforgettable antagonist ever put to film, Darth Vader, no villain was so cruel and yet so adored by fans. Characters and stories fitting perfectly, but the adventure to be full completed it needed the huge Galactic scenario, which is not lacking in this film. I think Lucas should have thanked Kubrick about "2001" because if it were not for this film, visual effects would never be the same. And thanks to that Lucas gave the film with beautiful scenery and a vast galaxies and an unforgettable and thrilling final battle. The classic that redefined cinema forever with a story well-crafted and told, full of suspense, humor and adventure thanks to its unforgettable characters and stunning visual effects , the legendary George Lucas gave the world a film with tremendous quality and early one of the best trilogies ever made. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated and outdated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emil Marty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying the movie doesn't suck, given the time it was made. The problem is that its legacy has created die-hard fans which have spawned the biggest franchise of all time; nothing wrong with that of course. But if you take a step back into modern day, you will see a film with all the elements a great fantasy epic should have (unimportant boy gets trained by old man, becomes great warrior etc) but a film where each element lacks the emotion to make you feel what you should. You don't feel sympathy when Luke's aunt and uncle die, you don't care about Kenobi's death because there was never an emotional stand-point that pinpointed him as a "great man". Everything simply happens without any given thought about the characters emotions. I could name a million films with all the same elements that have been done ten times better. That said, the originality is genuine, the whole story exciting and it's generally fun to watch. Just a shame its practically been ruined by its reputation as the greatest franchise ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Influential and Spectacular.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This first "Star Wars" film(though now retitled 'Episode IV') was a groundbreaking, box office shattering breath of fresh air to the cinemas, and science fiction in particular, which had gotten bogged down in bleak Dystopian futures. Nothing wrong with that in some cases, but moviegoers craved more, and got it with this extremely exciting tale of youth rebellion against an evil galactic empire led by Darth Vader(I though he was a robot at first viewing as a youngster!) a memorable creation, whose entrances were punctuated by the grand music of John Williams, who created an unforgettable score here that kids imitated endlessly! Fine cast includes Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing and Sir Alec Guiness. Climax is truly exciting, though film has a few lulls at times, this is still great fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope (originally released as just "Star Wars") is a masterpiece. Although the plot of the film is so simple that it almost hurts, it is brilliantly executed. It's a hero's journey in which the main character, Luke Skywalker, starts his adventures and finds himself in the middle of something bigger than he ever imagined. It is his story. Unfortunately, Luke's story tends to diminish the other character's stories in the first Star Wars trilogy. It's quite acceptable in this film, because Leia is the only character who really suffers from that (her non-reaction and non-follow-up on Alderaan's destruction is a shame). Sadly, this got even with with the next two films. Star Wars was a technical breakthrough and is in some ways still the best of all the Star Wars films. 9 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterful Work of Art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrrockey
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why am I even here? What's the point of me trying to review this film? Really, what's the point? Everybody knows about this film already and how great it is. So me trying to write a review of this film and trying to explain why it's so great is like re-telling the story of A Christmas Carol. Everybody knows it but yet, are always willing to listen. So I'll try my best to explain why I think this film has made the impact it did. Let's cut the crap and begin my analysis. PART 1: The Aesthetic Appeal of Star Wars Science-fiction was nothing new by the 70's. We've already had a lot of science-fiction movies by that time such as 2001: A Space Odyssey, THX 1138(another George Lucas film), Invasion of the Body Snatchers etc but the thing that made Star Wars different was its spirit. Most science- fiction films prior to Star Wars were cold, dark, and art-house-driven. Star Wars on the other hand, had an uplifting, positive, and imaginative tone to it that made it appeal to the child inside us. Star Wars takes place a long time ago, in a galaxy far far away with the classic hero's journey in the form of Luke Skywalker, the wise old mentor in the form of Obi-Wan Kenobi, the beautiful princess in Leia, the sinister, scheming villain in the form of Darth Vader, and the adventurous rogue in Han Solo. These things make Star Wars feel like a fairy-tale and made it timeless. Plus, the film had an amazing, classic, adventure serial look to it. The costumes, sets, sound effects, animatronics, and music all feel like they belong in a classic adventure serial, it makes you feel like a kid again! But while Star Wars is imaginative and uplifting, it's also a very smart film. PART 2: The Deeper Meanings Behind Star Wars On surface, Star Wars is just a little kiddie adventure with spaceships, laser gun battles, and wizards with laser swords but when you actually look into the story, there's actually a lot more substance to it than that. One of the themes in Star Wars is about finding meanings in life and the meaning of heroism. Star Wars is about finding meanings in life because it deals with characters who were never meant to be heroes but end up becoming greater than what they are. Luke Skywalker is a farmboy. He has no experience in any form of combat whatsoever and isn't even particularly smart but he ultimately saves the day because of his bravery and his good heart. Han Solo is just a smuggler. He was never the guy who would lead a bunch of Rebels to fight against the Empire, he only fought for one person which was himself. But towards the end of the movie, he finds a new purpose in life which is to become a Rebel and fight the Empire. Another theme in Star Wars is the idea of destiny. Most of these people here never belonged in the adventures they got themselves into in this movie but they ultimately do so because of The Force finding good in them and putting them there. In a way, it's destiny that brought these characters together and it's great that they didn't spell this out directly with its dialogue. PART 3: Why is Star Wars Still so Beloved Today? I think it's because of how original and fun it is. Even though it borrows a lot from classic adventure serials, classic fantasy literature, religious philosophy, historical events, and a whole other galaxy of inspirations, it combines them to create something new. It has endearing characters, an imaginative world, deep philosophy, and just provides good escapism overall. Plus, it's also just a lot of fun to watch with its action, humor, romance, and adventure. There's things here for everyone. Star Wars is intelligent, imaginative, clever, original, and just plain fun, it rightfully deserves a 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars, a new era...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Star Wars" was the start of something new, something different, something extraordinary for those times. Until today "Star Wars" considered the best Star Wars movie of all times. Personally I liked it very much and I can compare it with the other two movies of the classic trilogy: "Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back" and "Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi". George Lucas makes a great direction (nominated for the Oscar of Best Director in 1978) such the writing and screenplay (nominated for both for the the Oscar of Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen) and that great job seemed during the whole movie. Gary Kurtz also did an extremely good job for the Picture of the movie who is also nominated for the Oscar of Best Picture. The theme of this movie is that Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), Han Solo (Harrison Ford), C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), R2-D2 (Kenny Baker) and Chewbacca (Peter Mayhew) are going to save Princess Leia Organa (Carrie Fisher) from the evil Darth Vader (David Prowse) and they are also want to save the universe from the Empire's world-destroying battle-station.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Feat of Imagination, Fantasy & Creativity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ingredients that made Star Wars a revolution of its time are clearly noticeable, without a doubt, but the visual encapsulation of this sci-fi saga has aged pretty badly & today looks like an unintentionally funny ride than a masterpiece adventure. Still, at its core, Star Wars is a cinematic feat of imagination, fantasy & creativity that hypnotized an entire generation with its freshly envisioned & awe-inspiring world, gripping story, first-rate adventure & celebrated characters. It may not look as dazzling & groundbreaking today as it was in its time but its vast influences can be seen in plethora of sci-fi space fantasies, even today. Nicely crafted by George Lucas & introducing a sweeping visual effects, greatly influenced from Stanley Kubrick's 2001: A Space Odyssey, the outer surface of Star Wars may have degraded with time but the core hasn't aged a day, resulting in it making an impact in the sci-fi genre, blockbuster filmmaking & marketing, even today & hopefully for few more decades.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not just a great movie. It's important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story happened 'A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away'. The galaxy is under dictatorship. Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) is part of the rebellion but is capture by the evil Darth Vader. Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) the young hero, Han Solo (Harrison Ford) the brigand, and the wise master Ben Obi-Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) must together rescue the princess. The characters are icons pulled from classic storytelling. George Lucas was able to assemble such iconic characters into a well told story. Rarely is a movie change the nature of movie-making, and even the wider culture. This may be one of the most important movie of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Luke Skywalker joins force to fight against the Darth Vader and evil empire and bring peace in the universe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alex milonas
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The star wars saga is one of the most best movies about the space and development of language and technology as light saber droids and creatures from far beyond our imaginations.The character of Darth Vader which every kid and adult wants to wear his costume as well as the light saber which everyone buy one and play with an friend.Luke is raised by his uncle in planet totooine,Luke buys two droids R2 and C-3PO which had a message to ex-Jedi Knight Obi-Wan,Luke find him and told him about the message from the princess Leia,Obi wan convinced Luke to became Jedi knight,Luke accepts and next meets pilot Han solo and paid him to fly them in the Death star and rescue the princess Leia and deliver to rebel alliance against the Empire the plans about destroy Death star.Luke destroy the Death star and escapes.Come after the Empire strikes back and Return of the Jedi the epic tales continues.Obi wan used to say may the force be with you which is energy field created by all living things.The George Lucas fantasy galaxy is far far away and we want a ticket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars film review final draft 2.docx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brockhunt34
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brock Hunt Mr.Hicks ENG 101-008 September 20, 2013 A Space Opera Star Wars is a movie which focuses on a rebel alliance that fights against an oppressive regime set in a fictionalized universe a long time ago in a galaxy far far away. We're introduced to the main characters Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) and Darth Vader (David Prowse) for the first time. Luke is a farm boy who doesn't have a clue of what is about to happen. Darth Vader is an evil dark lord of the Sith who is trained in the dark side of the force and wants to defeat the rebel alliance. After Luke's family is murdered by the empire, he trains to be a Jedi by Obi-Wan Kenobi to defeat the evil Galactic Empire. George Lucas made Star Wars: A New Hope in 1976 and was released in the summer of 1977. He made episode four first because the story didn't require any high dollar special effects and wasn't sure how the movie would be accepted. When the movie opened, it received great reviews and audiences were amazed at the special effects. He would go on to direct the following sequels Empire Strikes Back and Return of the Jedi. Little do people know that George Lucas had the stories and screenplays of episodes one, two, and three already done before episode four was ever released. He did this because at the time technology didn't exist to produce the first three films with the fight sequences and settings that were in the first three films. I personally love the Star Wars films because of my personal connection with them. My grandmother introduced me to the Star Wars franchise as a child. On Saturday nights I would stay with my grandmother and she would play the movies on VHS. I never get tired of watching the films. Because every time I do, it takes me back in time when she was alive. Star Wars also opened up my interest in Sci-Fi movies. Some can say I'm a nerd but most don't know my extensive knowledge of the Star Wars franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of a new era!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the genius George Lucas was about to go help Spielberg make the majestic " Raiders", he decided to do something, something that many were surprised when it was announced and didn't take a lot of faith on, which after his release was an absolute success both at the box office and critical, and today the masterpiece of Lucas is a classic that will live forever in the history of cinema! "Star Wars" (not Star Wars IV A New Hope, please), begins with the yellow title suddenly appearing on the screen with an amazing soundtrack from the master John Williams giving us a resume of the history we are about to watch. It all starts with a small spaceship full of rebel soldiers start being invaded by imperial troops led by the sinister and cruel lord Darth Vader (David Prowse). Suddenly the film transports us directly to another side of the galaxy where we have the story of the young Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), a simple machine repairman teenager who lives with his uncles. A day after his uncle buy two servant robots, R2 - D2 (Kenny Baker) and C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), which inadvertently bring Luke the chance to realize his dreams of becoming a rebel and fight against the tyrant of the empire, a mission that will take him to the ends of the galaxy and will bring new friends but at the same time extreme dangers. From the beginning, "Star Wars" revolutionized cinema forever, especially the genre of sci - fi that at the time was just "Star Trek" with great success. Lucas of course certain elements form "Trek", since the crew of a spaceship with name style and friendship among the crew, but everything else was a tremendous attack of originality. Unlike "Star Trek" Lucas took the story and the great adventure with a lighter and fantasy tone, not childish but humorous, fun and even a certain religious point when the Jedi Obi - Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) appears in Luke's life with secrets of him and Luke's father past. And just like "Star Trek", Lucas gave his masterpiece unforgettable characters, of course: Luke, R2, C-3PO, Obi-Wan. But also the unforgettable Han Solo (Harrison Ford), the bounty hunter from space who ALWAYS shoots first and asks questions later, giving the film a great humorous touch and a lot of fun (never one character caused such influences as Han Solo did), and even Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) no royal woman before her in a film had never taken up arms showing she knew very well how to take care of herself. Not only the good guys who stand out perfectly in the story, but also the great and unforgettable antagonist ever put to film, Darth Vader, no villain was so cruel and yet so adored by fans. Characters and stories fitting perfectly, but the adventure to be full completed it needed the huge Galactic scenario, which is not lacking in this film. I think Lucas should have thanked Kubrick about "2001" because if it were not for this film, visual effects would never be the same. And thanks to that Lucas gave the film with beautiful scenery and a vast galaxies and an unforgettable and thrilling final battle. The classic that redefined cinema forever with a story well-crafted and told, full of suspense, humor and adventure thanks to its unforgettable characters and stunning visual effects , the legendary George Lucas gave the world a film with tremendous quality and early one of the best trilogies ever made. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated and outdated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emil Marty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying the movie doesn't suck, given the time it was made. The problem is that its legacy has created die-hard fans which have spawned the biggest franchise of all time; nothing wrong with that of course. But if you take a step back into modern day, you will see a film with all the elements a great fantasy epic should have (unimportant boy gets trained by old man, becomes great warrior etc) but a film where each element lacks the emotion to make you feel what you should. You don't feel sympathy when Luke's aunt and uncle die, you don't care about Kenobi's death because there was never an emotional stand-point that pinpointed him as a "great man". Everything simply happens without any given thought about the characters emotions. I could name a million films with all the same elements that have been done ten times better. That said, the originality is genuine, the whole story exciting and it's generally fun to watch. Just a shame its practically been ruined by its reputation as the greatest franchise ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Influential and Spectacular.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This first "Star Wars" film(though now retitled 'Episode IV') was a groundbreaking, box office shattering breath of fresh air to the cinemas, and science fiction in particular, which had gotten bogged down in bleak Dystopian futures. Nothing wrong with that in some cases, but moviegoers craved more, and got it with this extremely exciting tale of youth rebellion against an evil galactic empire led by Darth Vader(I though he was a robot at first viewing as a youngster!) a memorable creation, whose entrances were punctuated by the grand music of John Williams, who created an unforgettable score here that kids imitated endlessly! Fine cast includes Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing and Sir Alec Guiness. Climax is truly exciting, though film has a few lulls at times, this is still great fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope (originally released as just "Star Wars") is a masterpiece. Although the plot of the film is so simple that it almost hurts, it is brilliantly executed. It's a hero's journey in which the main character, Luke Skywalker, starts his adventures and finds himself in the middle of something bigger than he ever imagined. It is his story. Unfortunately, Luke's story tends to diminish the other character's stories in the first Star Wars trilogy. It's quite acceptable in this film, because Leia is the only character who really suffers from that (her non-reaction and non-follow-up on Alderaan's destruction is a shame). Sadly, this got even with with the next two films. Star Wars was a technical breakthrough and is in some ways still the best of all the Star Wars films. 9 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterful Work of Art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrrockey
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why am I even here? What's the point of me trying to review this film? Really, what's the point? Everybody knows about this film already and how great it is. So me trying to write a review of this film and trying to explain why it's so great is like re-telling the story of A Christmas Carol. Everybody knows it but yet, are always willing to listen. So I'll try my best to explain why I think this film has made the impact it did. Let's cut the crap and begin my analysis. PART 1: The Aesthetic Appeal of Star Wars Science-fiction was nothing new by the 70's. We've already had a lot of science-fiction movies by that time such as 2001: A Space Odyssey, THX 1138(another George Lucas film), Invasion of the Body Snatchers etc but the thing that made Star Wars different was its spirit. Most science- fiction films prior to Star Wars were cold, dark, and art-house-driven. Star Wars on the other hand, had an uplifting, positive, and imaginative tone to it that made it appeal to the child inside us. Star Wars takes place a long time ago, in a galaxy far far away with the classic hero's journey in the form of Luke Skywalker, the wise old mentor in the form of Obi-Wan Kenobi, the beautiful princess in Leia, the sinister, scheming villain in the form of Darth Vader, and the adventurous rogue in Han Solo. These things make Star Wars feel like a fairy-tale and made it timeless. Plus, the film had an amazing, classic, adventure serial look to it. The costumes, sets, sound effects, animatronics, and music all feel like they belong in a classic adventure serial, it makes you feel like a kid again! But while Star Wars is imaginative and uplifting, it's also a very smart film. PART 2: The Deeper Meanings Behind Star Wars On surface, Star Wars is just a little kiddie adventure with spaceships, laser gun battles, and wizards with laser swords but when you actually look into the story, there's actually a lot more substance to it than that. One of the themes in Star Wars is about finding meanings in life and the meaning of heroism. Star Wars is about finding meanings in life because it deals with characters who were never meant to be heroes but end up becoming greater than what they are. Luke Skywalker is a farmboy. He has no experience in any form of combat whatsoever and isn't even particularly smart but he ultimately saves the day because of his bravery and his good heart. Han Solo is just a smuggler. He was never the guy who would lead a bunch of Rebels to fight against the Empire, he only fought for one person which was himself. But towards the end of the movie, he finds a new purpose in life which is to become a Rebel and fight the Empire. Another theme in Star Wars is the idea of destiny. Most of these people here never belonged in the adventures they got themselves into in this movie but they ultimately do so because of The Force finding good in them and putting them there. In a way, it's destiny that brought these characters together and it's great that they didn't spell this out directly with its dialogue. PART 3: Why is Star Wars Still so Beloved Today? I think it's because of how original and fun it is. Even though it borrows a lot from classic adventure serials, classic fantasy literature, religious philosophy, historical events, and a whole other galaxy of inspirations, it combines them to create something new. It has endearing characters, an imaginative world, deep philosophy, and just provides good escapism overall. Plus, it's also just a lot of fun to watch with its action, humor, romance, and adventure. There's things here for everyone. Star Wars is intelligent, imaginative, clever, original, and just plain fun, it rightfully deserves a 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars, a new era...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Star Wars" was the start of something new, something different, something extraordinary for those times. Until today "Star Wars" considered the best Star Wars movie of all times. Personally I liked it very much and I can compare it with the other two movies of the classic trilogy: "Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back" and "Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi". George Lucas makes a great direction (nominated for the Oscar of Best Director in 1978) such the writing and screenplay (nominated for both for the the Oscar of Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen) and that great job seemed during the whole movie. Gary Kurtz also did an extremely good job for the Picture of the movie who is also nominated for the Oscar of Best Picture. The theme of this movie is that Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), Han Solo (Harrison Ford), C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), R2-D2 (Kenny Baker) and Chewbacca (Peter Mayhew) are going to save Princess Leia Organa (Carrie Fisher) from the evil Darth Vader (David Prowse) and they are also want to save the universe from the Empire's world-destroying battle-station.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Cinematic Feat of Imagination, Fantasy & Creativity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The ingredients that made Star Wars a revolution of its time are clearly noticeable, without a doubt, but the visual encapsulation of this sci-fi saga has aged pretty badly & today looks like an unintentionally funny ride than a masterpiece adventure. Still, at its core, Star Wars is a cinematic feat of imagination, fantasy & creativity that hypnotized an entire generation with its freshly envisioned & awe-inspiring world, gripping story, first-rate adventure & celebrated characters. It may not look as dazzling & groundbreaking today as it was in its time but its vast influences can be seen in plethora of sci-fi space fantasies, even today. Nicely crafted by George Lucas & introducing a sweeping visual effects, greatly influenced from Stanley Kubrick's 2001: A Space Odyssey, the outer surface of Star Wars may have degraded with time but the core hasn't aged a day, resulting in it making an impact in the sci-fi genre, blockbuster filmmaking & marketing, even today & hopefully for few more decades.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not just a great movie. It's important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This story happened 'A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away'. The galaxy is under dictatorship. Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) is part of the rebellion but is capture by the evil Darth Vader. Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) the young hero, Han Solo (Harrison Ford) the brigand, and the wise master Ben Obi-Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) must together rescue the princess. The characters are icons pulled from classic storytelling. George Lucas was able to assemble such iconic characters into a well told story. Rarely is a movie change the nature of movie-making, and even the wider culture. This may be one of the most important movie of all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Luke Skywalker joins force to fight against the Darth Vader and evil empire and bring peace in the universe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alex milonas
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The star wars saga is one of the most best movies about the space and development of language and technology as light saber droids and creatures from far beyond our imaginations.The character of Darth Vader which every kid and adult wants to wear his costume as well as the light saber which everyone buy one and play with an friend.Luke is raised by his uncle in planet totooine,Luke buys two droids R2 and C-3PO which had a message to ex-Jedi Knight Obi-Wan,Luke find him and told him about the message from the princess Leia,Obi wan convinced Luke to became Jedi knight,Luke accepts and next meets pilot Han solo and paid him to fly them in the Death star and rescue the princess Leia and deliver to rebel alliance against the Empire the plans about destroy Death star.Luke destroy the Death star and escapes.Come after the Empire strikes back and Return of the Jedi the epic tales continues.Obi wan used to say may the force be with you which is energy field created by all living things.The George Lucas fantasy galaxy is far far away and we want a ticket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars film review final draft 2.docx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brockhunt34
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brock Hunt Mr.Hicks ENG 101-008 September 20, 2013 A Space Opera Star Wars is a movie which focuses on a rebel alliance that fights against an oppressive regime set in a fictionalized universe a long time ago in a galaxy far far away. We're introduced to the main characters Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill) and Darth Vader (David Prowse) for the first time. Luke is a farm boy who doesn't have a clue of what is about to happen. Darth Vader is an evil dark lord of the Sith who is trained in the dark side of the force and wants to defeat the rebel alliance. After Luke's family is murdered by the empire, he trains to be a Jedi by Obi-Wan Kenobi to defeat the evil Galactic Empire. George Lucas made Star Wars: A New Hope in 1976 and was released in the summer of 1977. He made episode four first because the story didn't require any high dollar special effects and wasn't sure how the movie would be accepted. When the movie opened, it received great reviews and audiences were amazed at the special effects. He would go on to direct the following sequels Empire Strikes Back and Return of the Jedi. Little do people know that George Lucas had the stories and screenplays of episodes one, two, and three already done before episode four was ever released. He did this because at the time technology didn't exist to produce the first three films with the fight sequences and settings that were in the first three films. I personally love the Star Wars films because of my personal connection with them. My grandmother introduced me to the Star Wars franchise as a child. On Saturday nights I would stay with my grandmother and she would play the movies on VHS. I never get tired of watching the films. Because every time I do, it takes me back in time when she was alive. Star Wars also opened up my interest in Sci-Fi movies. Some can say I'm a nerd but most don't know my extensive knowledge of the Star Wars franchise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of a new era!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the genius George Lucas was about to go help Spielberg make the majestic " Raiders", he decided to do something, something that many were surprised when it was announced and didn't take a lot of faith on, which after his release was an absolute success both at the box office and critical, and today the masterpiece of Lucas is a classic that will live forever in the history of cinema! "Star Wars" (not Star Wars IV A New Hope, please), begins with the yellow title suddenly appearing on the screen with an amazing soundtrack from the master John Williams giving us a resume of the history we are about to watch. It all starts with a small spaceship full of rebel soldiers start being invaded by imperial troops led by the sinister and cruel lord Darth Vader (David Prowse). Suddenly the film transports us directly to another side of the galaxy where we have the story of the young Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), a simple machine repairman teenager who lives with his uncles. A day after his uncle buy two servant robots, R2 - D2 (Kenny Baker) and C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), which inadvertently bring Luke the chance to realize his dreams of becoming a rebel and fight against the tyrant of the empire, a mission that will take him to the ends of the galaxy and will bring new friends but at the same time extreme dangers. From the beginning, "Star Wars" revolutionized cinema forever, especially the genre of sci - fi that at the time was just "Star Trek" with great success. Lucas of course certain elements form "Trek", since the crew of a spaceship with name style and friendship among the crew, but everything else was a tremendous attack of originality. Unlike "Star Trek" Lucas took the story and the great adventure with a lighter and fantasy tone, not childish but humorous, fun and even a certain religious point when the Jedi Obi - Wan Kenobi (Alec Guinness) appears in Luke's life with secrets of him and Luke's father past. And just like "Star Trek", Lucas gave his masterpiece unforgettable characters, of course: Luke, R2, C-3PO, Obi-Wan. But also the unforgettable Han Solo (Harrison Ford), the bounty hunter from space who ALWAYS shoots first and asks questions later, giving the film a great humorous touch and a lot of fun (never one character caused such influences as Han Solo did), and even Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher) no royal woman before her in a film had never taken up arms showing she knew very well how to take care of herself. Not only the good guys who stand out perfectly in the story, but also the great and unforgettable antagonist ever put to film, Darth Vader, no villain was so cruel and yet so adored by fans. Characters and stories fitting perfectly, but the adventure to be full completed it needed the huge Galactic scenario, which is not lacking in this film. I think Lucas should have thanked Kubrick about "2001" because if it were not for this film, visual effects would never be the same. And thanks to that Lucas gave the film with beautiful scenery and a vast galaxies and an unforgettable and thrilling final battle. The classic that redefined cinema forever with a story well-crafted and told, full of suspense, humor and adventure thanks to its unforgettable characters and stunning visual effects , the legendary George Lucas gave the world a film with tremendous quality and early one of the best trilogies ever made. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated and outdated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emil Marty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying the movie doesn't suck, given the time it was made. The problem is that its legacy has created die-hard fans which have spawned the biggest franchise of all time; nothing wrong with that of course. But if you take a step back into modern day, you will see a film with all the elements a great fantasy epic should have (unimportant boy gets trained by old man, becomes great warrior etc) but a film where each element lacks the emotion to make you feel what you should. You don't feel sympathy when Luke's aunt and uncle die, you don't care about Kenobi's death because there was never an emotional stand-point that pinpointed him as a "great man". Everything simply happens without any given thought about the characters emotions. I could name a million films with all the same elements that have been done ten times better. That said, the originality is genuine, the whole story exciting and it's generally fun to watch. Just a shame its practically been ruined by its reputation as the greatest franchise ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Influential and Spectacular.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This first "Star Wars" film(though now retitled 'Episode IV') was a groundbreaking, box office shattering breath of fresh air to the cinemas, and science fiction in particular, which had gotten bogged down in bleak Dystopian futures. Nothing wrong with that in some cases, but moviegoers craved more, and got it with this extremely exciting tale of youth rebellion against an evil galactic empire led by Darth Vader(I though he was a robot at first viewing as a youngster!) a memorable creation, whose entrances were punctuated by the grand music of John Williams, who created an unforgettable score here that kids imitated endlessly! Fine cast includes Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing and Sir Alec Guiness. Climax is truly exciting, though film has a few lulls at times, this is still great fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope (originally released as just "Star Wars") is a masterpiece. Although the plot of the film is so simple that it almost hurts, it is brilliantly executed. It's a hero's journey in which the main character, Luke Skywalker, starts his adventures and finds himself in the middle of something bigger than he ever imagined. It is his story. Unfortunately, Luke's story tends to diminish the other character's stories in the first Star Wars trilogy. It's quite acceptable in this film, because Leia is the only character who really suffers from that (her non-reaction and non-follow-up on Alderaan's destruction is a shame). Sadly, this got even with with the next two films. Star Wars was a technical breakthrough and is in some ways still the best of all the Star Wars films. 9 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterful Work of Art
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrrockey
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why am I even here? What's the point of me trying to review this film? Really, what's the point? Everybody knows about this film already and how great it is. So me trying to write a review of this film and trying to explain why it's so great is like re-telling the story of A Christmas Carol. Everybody knows it but yet, are always willing to listen. So I'll try my best to explain why I think this film has made the impact it did. Let's cut the crap and begin my analysis. PART 1: The Aesthetic Appeal of Star Wars Science-fiction was nothing new by the 70's. We've already had a lot of science-fiction movies by that time such as 2001: A Space Odyssey, THX 1138(another George Lucas film), Invasion of the Body Snatchers etc but the thing that made Star Wars different was its spirit. Most science- fiction films prior to Star Wars were cold, dark, and art-house-driven. Star Wars on the other hand, had an uplifting, positive, and imaginative tone to it that made it appeal to the child inside us. Star Wars takes place a long time ago, in a galaxy far far away with the classic hero's journey in the form of Luke Skywalker, the wise old mentor in the form of Obi-Wan Kenobi, the beautiful princess in Leia, the sinister, scheming villain in the form of Darth Vader, and the adventurous rogue in Han Solo. These things make Star Wars feel like a fairy-tale and made it timeless. Plus, the film had an amazing, classic, adventure serial look to it. The costumes, sets, sound effects, animatronics, and music all feel like they belong in a classic adventure serial, it makes you feel like a kid again! But while Star Wars is imaginative and uplifting, it's also a very smart film. PART 2: The Deeper Meanings Behind Star Wars On surface, Star Wars is just a little kiddie adventure with spaceships, laser gun battles, and wizards with laser swords but when you actually look into the story, there's actually a lot more substance to it than that. One of the themes in Star Wars is about finding meanings in life and the meaning of heroism. Star Wars is about finding meanings in life because it deals with characters who were never meant to be heroes but end up becoming greater than what they are. Luke Skywalker is a farmboy. He has no experience in any form of combat whatsoever and isn't even particularly smart but he ultimately saves the day because of his bravery and his good heart. Han Solo is just a smuggler. He was never the guy who would lead a bunch of Rebels to fight against the Empire, he only fought for one person which was himself. But towards the end of the movie, he finds a new purpose in life which is to become a Rebel and fight the Empire. Another theme in Star Wars is the idea of destiny. Most of these people here never belonged in the adventures they got themselves into in this movie but they ultimately do so because of The Force finding good in them and putting them there. In a way, it's destiny that brought these characters together and it's great that they didn't spell this out directly with its dialogue. PART 3: Why is Star Wars Still so Beloved Today? I think it's because of how original and fun it is. Even though it borrows a lot from classic adventure serials, classic fantasy literature, religious philosophy, historical events, and a whole other galaxy of inspirations, it combines them to create something new. It has endearing characters, an imaginative world, deep philosophy, and just provides good escapism overall. Plus, it's also just a lot of fun to watch with its action, humor, romance, and adventure. There's things here for everyone. Star Wars is intelligent, imaginative, clever, original, and just plain fun, it rightfully deserves a 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Wars, a new era...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Star Wars" was the start of something new, something different, something extraordinary for those times. Until today "Star Wars" considered the best Star Wars movie of all times. Personally I liked it very much and I can compare it with the other two movies of the classic trilogy: "Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back" and "Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi". George Lucas makes a great direction (nominated for the Oscar of Best Director in 1978) such the writing and screenplay (nominated for both for the the Oscar of Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen) and that great job seemed during the whole movie. Gary Kurtz also did an extremely good job for the Picture of the movie who is also nominated for the Oscar of Best Picture. The theme of this movie is that Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill), Han Solo (Harrison Ford), C-3PO (Anthony Daniels), R2-D2 (Kenny Baker) and Chewbacca (Peter Mayhew) are going to save Princess Leia Organa (Carrie Fisher) from the evil Darth Vader (David Prowse) and they are also want to save the universe from the Empire's world-destroying battle-station.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
