<filme>
 <id>
  500
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116329
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Voando Para Casa
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A father and daughter decide to attempt to lead a flock of orphaned Canada Geese south by air.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Amy is only 13 years old when her mother is killed in an auto wreck in New Zealand. She goes to Canada to live with her father, an eccentric inventor whom she barely knows. Amy is miserable in her new life...that is until she discovers a nest of goose eggs that were abandoned when developers began tearing up a local forest. The eggs hatch and Amy becomes "Mama Goose". The young birds must fly south for the winter, but who will lead them there? With a pair of ultralight airplanes, Amy, her dad and their friends must find a way to do it...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   goose
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   canada
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   inventor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bird
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Carroll Ballard
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Bill Lishman
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Robert Rodat
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jeff Daniels
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Anna Paquin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dana Delany
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Timeless Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brown-faith922
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fly Away Home" has been a favorite in my family for years. The story is classic, with every element of a film that is sure to last. The movie gives a vivid and often raw presentation of the relationships within a family, particularly between estranged members, and raises interesting questions about what family itself is and what it means. The view is utterly breathtaking as we're taken on a flight through the Canadian skies, following both the physical and emotional journey of Amy and her father. The father-daughter relationship, in any context, is often a touchy subject, and many films have a tendency to overdramatize certain elements of such a relationship. While the drama is certainly here with this one, we see less of the verbal, noisy drama than we do the quiet, awkward, tense, and somewhat snippy sentiments which exist between the two. Anna Paquin is flawless. Jeff Daniels will make you laugh, cry, and applaud. The chemistry between these two actors is beautiful, making this film one of the first and only that I have ever seen that has not made me despise the "rebellious daughter" figure. If this movie has a flaw, it is only that it is a bit slow by times. Still, for those who, like me, don't mind those sweepingly beautiful images of Canadian landscape, even if nothing much is happening... you'll enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattkratz (themattk@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a great movie about courage, overcoming tragedy, and leadership. After her mother is killed in a car accident, Anna Paquin moves to Canada with her father (Jeff Daniels) after he comes to pick her up. They discover a nestful of baby geese (newly hatched!) whose mother has just died too, and they have to learn how to fly. Unfortunately, they can't learn without example, and she has to be that example. She does so by building model airplanes which she flies. She makes news by showing them the way south. I loved the aerial scenes (which were beautifully shot) and the scene where the daughter was horrified when the guy wanted to clip the chicks' wings. Everybody matures and serves as "parent figures" in the process. This was a throughly enjoyable movie and great "family fare." You will love it-guaranteed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incredibly disappointing and extremely overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BelmaresJodene
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film a few months ago and I did not like it. Where do i start the storyline is just about as dull as you can get. The only thing that saved this from getting a one was the fairly good acting. The story is simple a teenage girl loses her mother in a car crash, she goes to the hospital and is picked up by her estranged father. then she tries to isolate from the rest of the world but what really made me mad about this movie is how bratty, rude annoying and stuck up she was, and the whole geese thing was way overdone. Another thing that annoyed me was that stupid little chant she kept on doing. She also was not very bright she refused to go to school she flew some kind of glider even though she knew she could not fly it. If you are looking for a movie to watch I strongly suggest you stay away from this one. final evaluation 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, Funny, Human
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    contact-951-691937
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, another excellent family film that has received low ratings from many reviewers here - I just don't get it. Fly Away Home is a beautiful story, filled with realistic emotion and incredible views of Canada and the geese. Jeff Daniel's portrayal of the eccentric father is smooth and realistic to the point that you might feel like you could run into him during a drive in the country. Anna Paquin tugs at your heartstrings and our family was cheering her on throughout the movie. Fly Away Home is a wholesome and entertaining family experience that we have watched several times - this says a lot since we rarely all agree on viewing the same film together twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Loved It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Ritter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There aren't that many movies that are well-written, well-directed, that have beautiful scenery and a heart touching story, but this is certainly one of them. This movie is well worth the time it takes to watch it. In fact, we seem to rent it about every two or three years so we can view it again and will probably end up purchasing it, which we seldom do. I just can't say enough for this film. Whatever you do, watch it all the way to the end. Very worthwhile for families or anyone who appreciates nature and a great movie. One of the other things we really liked about the film was the fact that we live about a half mile away from one of the locations where it was filmed just outside of Niagara Falls, NY. That made it more personal for us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Personal and Sentimental Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home is a family oriented, emotionally charged drama in which a young girl's mental recovery from her Mother's death is achieved by a monumental feat. Thrust into her Father Tom's world of inventions and experiments, Amy is lost and uncomfortable in this new environment along with still being vulnerable from her Mother's death, shown in her anxious reactions watching Tom try out his latest invention. Yet it is an aspect of Tom's life that Amy soon finds herself in after discovering Geese eggs, once they hatch Amy is lead down a memorable path of courage and bonding. As Amy begins to raise the Geese as her own Fly Away Home becomes an incredibility touching story where it is hard not to want Amy achieve the goal of getting the Geese to migrate south. Fly Away Home succeeds on an emotional scale in placing the viewer into the predicament Amy faces and the love she feels for the Geese. The cinematography is an additional factor to the heart - tugging vibe, watching the Geese eggs hatch and crawl out of their shells with crystal clear precision as if we are witnessing the birth in person is extraordinary to see and sentimental to feel as they are just as vulnerable as Amy. This sense of vulnerability makes the aerial shots of Amy and Tom leading the Geese to their rightful place in nature later on all the more powerful. It coincides with the soundtrack in relation to Fly Away Home's poignancy, with the use of the song '10, 000 Miles' towards the end of the climatic scene which had been the show piece of the opening credits depicting the death of Amy's Mother increases the atmosphere to the status of a tear jerker, bringing home how much Amy has achieved. However there are some clich&eacute;s which slightly spoil the experience. Having corporate bosses as antagonists is nothing new and tense moments made to briefly unease the audience most notably when Air Traffic Control are about to send out a war plane on Amy, Tom and the Geese when they are seen as a UFO comes across respectively as platitude and ridiculous. But these are only minor flaws in a film whose good heartedness paves these criticisms over. So if you enjoy story lines with a feel - good vibe and the old fashioned good triumphing over evil, Fly Away Home should be one for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Treat Yourself to a Sense of Joy and Wonder. Great Family Film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TedMichaelMor
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sctmpir's review nails this film, which celebrates a young female character with immense richness, complexity even, and grace. I think that the treatment of women in this work is among the most finely nuanced and intelligent I have ever seen in any film. Carroll Ballard, who directed the gracious and almost unbearably beautiful "Wind" as well as "The Black Stallion", "Duma", and "Never Cry Wolf"--all films that have an almost sentimental tone but a tone really closer to romantic in the classic Victorian sense of awe and wonder at life itselfcontrols every aspect of the narrative. This film might seem close to but is never saccharine. It is about wonder in the sense of awe. Anna Paquin exhibits brilliance as an adolescent actor that overwhelms me, in part, because there is never anything trite or coquettish that often mares the role many fine young actresses play. The role here required immense transparency, poise, and nuance. Dana Delaney has the same poise, apparent simplicity, attention to nuance and understatement as Ms. Paquin. No actor is better than Jeff Daniels is when he expresses understatement and subtlyremember him, for example, in "Pleasantville" and "Purple Rose of Cairo". Tim Kerry is a great boon to the film but everyone seems outstanding to me. Caleb Deschane is a master of magic hour cinematography, which works exceptionally well here. He did, for example, "The Right Stuff" with Philip Kaufman directing, "The Passion of the Christ" with Mel Gibson directing, "A Woman Under the Influence" with John Cassavetes, and "Being There" with Hal Ashby. He also directed the thoughtful film "Caruso". The attention to detail in this movie amazes me. There is not a bad frame anywhere in the film. That, of course, is in part the work of the editor Nicholas Smith. Music by Mark Isham is a tad dramatic but still lovely. Mr. Isham is one of the most productive of film composers. And the airplanes are terrific. The aerial images alone overwhelm me and recall the imagery from "Wind", one of my favourite action films. The flight though Baltimore alone is worth the price of admission and it one of utter majesty. One plane was the one used in the true story behind the work. As usual, I am not up to doing this fine work credit that it earns. I want to own a copy of it. I rate it ten because I judge films on their individual merits, not necessarily in comparison with other works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to make your dreams soar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandol70
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is already written a lot about the story of Fly Away Home, so I'm not going to repeat my previous reviewers. I have watched the movie for the first time on German TV in 1998, by chance I zapped into the movie and stayed there, mesmerized, fascinated, enchanted by its magical richness of animal (goose) beauty and lush landscape cinematography. When the film ended, I had a lump of emotion in my throat for several days. Something changed deep inside of me, namely the perception of nature, animals, birds, specifically of wild geese. Something made click inside my mind, and since then I adore geese very deeply. Before the movie, geese were of no special interest to me, oh how ignorant I was! As a matter of fact, my love is so deep and the movie inspires me so much that I want get my own geese. Fly Away home's cinematography and script is performed what I can describe as silent, calm, quiet and serene, but never lengthy; is performed suspense-packed, but never thriller-like. Romantic, but never corny or clich&eacute;. Close to life itself and nature, but never overcharged with exaggerated eco-messages. In short, a perfect mixture of all the elements that make a movie worthwhile. The landscape shots are very idyllic (Oscar nomination on this movie for cinematography) and you begin to long and crave for a life on the country-side, away from it all, the boisterous cities and its citizens with their insignificant problems of their everyday lives. When Amy is flying in her ultralight airplane, leading the flock of geese as their surrogate mother, then you can see that the problems on land, down there, are small and trivial. That is where the geese show us how life is meant to be, more simple, more straight-forward, and peaceful. Brilliant. And the film music, the fantastic movie score composed by Mark Isham, transports all the previous mentioned qualities and features in a perfect manner. The introductory song, 10,000 Miles by Mary Chapin Carpenter and co-composed by Mark Isham, is a real tearjerker of the special kind. This song alone summarizes what this movie is all about. Love, friendship, a deep bond among humans and animals, care for nature, peace, freedom and to never give up no matter what. The track expresses Amy's love to her family, and at the same time, the love between Amy and the wild geese. I cannot watch the movie without a package of Kleenex, and I'm male and an adult, a child at heart. I believe everyone has this ability, we just have to show it more often, and this movie can help to release the inner child in all of us. There is no lukewarm love story in Fly Away Home which is a big plus, if at all, it's only presented very subtle and unobtrusive. There have to be more movies like this to prevent a shallow development in our society, but I digress. The main focus of attention is clearly on the geese, who out-act all human actors with feathery ease. Bravo! Please, more movies like this! There are, to my knowledge, only a handful of movies where script, cinematography, directing, music, dialogs and actors come together and are mixed in this perfection. I can only recommend this movie to anyone who still believes in his or her dreams and wants to realize them. This movie supports you there and makes your imaginations soar, literally. As for my part, I'm checking out where I can get geese and how I have to keep them and gain their amazing friendship, deep bond and love. One of the most fascinating movies Hollywood has ever done, Oscar-nominated, and rightly so. Big kudos. Seal of approval: Highly recommended!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    budoinst@aol.com
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How anyone cannot like and appreciate this movie is beyond me. It has an incredible background in fact and is a moving tribute to the human spirit. It also strongly shows that all is not completely lost in the human race and that there is care among us and our fellow beings. What an inspiring movie and so well filmed and documented. Each time it is on, I watch it without fail. So nice to see true human caring and responsibility to all things. We can all learn something from the unwavering focus and support from so many people in overcoming the charge and many times unnecessary destruction of what is left of our former world and mostly in the name of greed and money. It is so nice to see greed being beaten back! We all can learn from this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quiet days and adventure stories
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home begins on a quiet note. A car driving in the rain, mother and daughter exchanging glances. The focus goes from the windscreen to the road, and back again. Suddenly and surprisingly, violence strikes. This introduces a common theme in children's adventure stories - the loss of one or both parents. It's the very same device that Ballard used in his first film, The Black Stallion, and would use once again in Duma. He's placed no inherent value in it as a plot device, however, stating that "If you're going to have a parent die, that has to be the emotional core of the movie". And that's just what it is in this case. Amy (Anna Paquin) doesn't walk off to have fun with the animals simply forgetting her past. But, in a way, this makes the focus less on nature and more on the characters, which I'm not entirely certain was Ballard's original intention. After all, his first two pictures featured next to no human interaction, and this very thing was what made the production of "Wind" so bothersome for him. After watching Fly Away Home for the first time in nearly ten years, I was struck by its high dramatic quality. Just a week earlier, I had watched another, inferior animal film (also starring Jeff Daniels) called "Because of Winn-Dixie". I realized then just how hard it is to strike a balance between what is 'cute' and what is real. The aforementioned film dove headlong into the 'cute' side of things. At the sake of becoming too academic, this is one of the most beautiful films I have ever seen. Caleb Deschanel's photography is effortless in appearance, giving the sensation of weightlessness far more often than in the actual flight sequences. Carroll Ballard has had great success in choosing the best people to photograph his films, and this is a great reunion for the two since their last collaboration on The Black Stallion. Mark Isham takes a totally different approach from his stunning minimalist score of Never Cry Wolf, reaching for - and sometimes - tugging at your heartstrings. In fact, the music is really quite spectacular throughout, except for a rather long and out of place interlude to "10,000 Miles" by Mary Chapin Carpenter. This would have been better suited earlier in the flight, it's current placement feeling a little off. It seems reminiscent of Linda Ronstadt's song "Winter Light" in a 1993 version of "The Secret Garden" (That film, by the way, I highly recommend for fans of Carroll Ballard). As this film progresses, it moves beyond the relationship aspect as Amy makes a discovery in the forest - geese eggs. In a way, her rescuing and raising of these orphaned chicks helps her to heal from her own loss. At its heart, this film is about loss and rebirth. This takes the story of Fly Away Home into new territory, less about the human aspect, and more about nature. All the supporting cast is good and effective (especially Terry Kinney), but Jeff Daniels and Anna Paquin are the central dramatic point which the other actors center around. I've never seen a more lively or energetic performance by Daniels - it's the sort of role he's always excelled at. Paquin, on the other hand, is in a rather uncommon role for her, a simple, more unrestrained character. Without her, or another exactly suited child (of which I know none), the film's dramatic half would have collapsed in on itself. But for all the geese, the drama and the cinematography, it's the moments of quiet that stand out. As the film comes to a close, there are certain factors that bring in a lack of realism. The human and media response to the flight south seems as if borrowed from another film. This perhaps brings the story to a bit of an anti-climax. The 'evil corporate developer' subplot seems lifted from other, less imaginative films. Regardless of the slightly weak ending, perhaps no other conclusion would work better, not without a significantly longer running time. It's a delicately balanced film, and I greatly respect its director for that. There's no immature jokes, no animals being too cute, or overwrought melodrama. For the most part, it feels natural, and the characters act like real people. I appreciate that in a youth-oriented film. I've long since grown out of other movies such as Free Willy, but this film has stuck with me since childhood - and I appreciate it more now than when I first saw it as a kid myself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Timeless Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brown-faith922
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fly Away Home" has been a favorite in my family for years. The story is classic, with every element of a film that is sure to last. The movie gives a vivid and often raw presentation of the relationships within a family, particularly between estranged members, and raises interesting questions about what family itself is and what it means. The view is utterly breathtaking as we're taken on a flight through the Canadian skies, following both the physical and emotional journey of Amy and her father. The father-daughter relationship, in any context, is often a touchy subject, and many films have a tendency to overdramatize certain elements of such a relationship. While the drama is certainly here with this one, we see less of the verbal, noisy drama than we do the quiet, awkward, tense, and somewhat snippy sentiments which exist between the two. Anna Paquin is flawless. Jeff Daniels will make you laugh, cry, and applaud. The chemistry between these two actors is beautiful, making this film one of the first and only that I have ever seen that has not made me despise the "rebellious daughter" figure. If this movie has a flaw, it is only that it is a bit slow by times. Still, for those who, like me, don't mind those sweepingly beautiful images of Canadian landscape, even if nothing much is happening... you'll enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattkratz (themattk@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a great movie about courage, overcoming tragedy, and leadership. After her mother is killed in a car accident, Anna Paquin moves to Canada with her father (Jeff Daniels) after he comes to pick her up. They discover a nestful of baby geese (newly hatched!) whose mother has just died too, and they have to learn how to fly. Unfortunately, they can't learn without example, and she has to be that example. She does so by building model airplanes which she flies. She makes news by showing them the way south. I loved the aerial scenes (which were beautifully shot) and the scene where the daughter was horrified when the guy wanted to clip the chicks' wings. Everybody matures and serves as "parent figures" in the process. This was a throughly enjoyable movie and great "family fare." You will love it-guaranteed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incredibly disappointing and extremely overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BelmaresJodene
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film a few months ago and I did not like it. Where do i start the storyline is just about as dull as you can get. The only thing that saved this from getting a one was the fairly good acting. The story is simple a teenage girl loses her mother in a car crash, she goes to the hospital and is picked up by her estranged father. then she tries to isolate from the rest of the world but what really made me mad about this movie is how bratty, rude annoying and stuck up she was, and the whole geese thing was way overdone. Another thing that annoyed me was that stupid little chant she kept on doing. She also was not very bright she refused to go to school she flew some kind of glider even though she knew she could not fly it. If you are looking for a movie to watch I strongly suggest you stay away from this one. final evaluation 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, Funny, Human
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    contact-951-691937
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, another excellent family film that has received low ratings from many reviewers here - I just don't get it. Fly Away Home is a beautiful story, filled with realistic emotion and incredible views of Canada and the geese. Jeff Daniel's portrayal of the eccentric father is smooth and realistic to the point that you might feel like you could run into him during a drive in the country. Anna Paquin tugs at your heartstrings and our family was cheering her on throughout the movie. Fly Away Home is a wholesome and entertaining family experience that we have watched several times - this says a lot since we rarely all agree on viewing the same film together twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Loved It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Ritter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There aren't that many movies that are well-written, well-directed, that have beautiful scenery and a heart touching story, but this is certainly one of them. This movie is well worth the time it takes to watch it. In fact, we seem to rent it about every two or three years so we can view it again and will probably end up purchasing it, which we seldom do. I just can't say enough for this film. Whatever you do, watch it all the way to the end. Very worthwhile for families or anyone who appreciates nature and a great movie. One of the other things we really liked about the film was the fact that we live about a half mile away from one of the locations where it was filmed just outside of Niagara Falls, NY. That made it more personal for us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Personal and Sentimental Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home is a family oriented, emotionally charged drama in which a young girl's mental recovery from her Mother's death is achieved by a monumental feat. Thrust into her Father Tom's world of inventions and experiments, Amy is lost and uncomfortable in this new environment along with still being vulnerable from her Mother's death, shown in her anxious reactions watching Tom try out his latest invention. Yet it is an aspect of Tom's life that Amy soon finds herself in after discovering Geese eggs, once they hatch Amy is lead down a memorable path of courage and bonding. As Amy begins to raise the Geese as her own Fly Away Home becomes an incredibility touching story where it is hard not to want Amy achieve the goal of getting the Geese to migrate south. Fly Away Home succeeds on an emotional scale in placing the viewer into the predicament Amy faces and the love she feels for the Geese. The cinematography is an additional factor to the heart - tugging vibe, watching the Geese eggs hatch and crawl out of their shells with crystal clear precision as if we are witnessing the birth in person is extraordinary to see and sentimental to feel as they are just as vulnerable as Amy. This sense of vulnerability makes the aerial shots of Amy and Tom leading the Geese to their rightful place in nature later on all the more powerful. It coincides with the soundtrack in relation to Fly Away Home's poignancy, with the use of the song '10, 000 Miles' towards the end of the climatic scene which had been the show piece of the opening credits depicting the death of Amy's Mother increases the atmosphere to the status of a tear jerker, bringing home how much Amy has achieved. However there are some clich&eacute;s which slightly spoil the experience. Having corporate bosses as antagonists is nothing new and tense moments made to briefly unease the audience most notably when Air Traffic Control are about to send out a war plane on Amy, Tom and the Geese when they are seen as a UFO comes across respectively as platitude and ridiculous. But these are only minor flaws in a film whose good heartedness paves these criticisms over. So if you enjoy story lines with a feel - good vibe and the old fashioned good triumphing over evil, Fly Away Home should be one for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Treat Yourself to a Sense of Joy and Wonder. Great Family Film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TedMichaelMor
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sctmpir's review nails this film, which celebrates a young female character with immense richness, complexity even, and grace. I think that the treatment of women in this work is among the most finely nuanced and intelligent I have ever seen in any film. Carroll Ballard, who directed the gracious and almost unbearably beautiful "Wind" as well as "The Black Stallion", "Duma", and "Never Cry Wolf"--all films that have an almost sentimental tone but a tone really closer to romantic in the classic Victorian sense of awe and wonder at life itselfcontrols every aspect of the narrative. This film might seem close to but is never saccharine. It is about wonder in the sense of awe. Anna Paquin exhibits brilliance as an adolescent actor that overwhelms me, in part, because there is never anything trite or coquettish that often mares the role many fine young actresses play. The role here required immense transparency, poise, and nuance. Dana Delaney has the same poise, apparent simplicity, attention to nuance and understatement as Ms. Paquin. No actor is better than Jeff Daniels is when he expresses understatement and subtlyremember him, for example, in "Pleasantville" and "Purple Rose of Cairo". Tim Kerry is a great boon to the film but everyone seems outstanding to me. Caleb Deschane is a master of magic hour cinematography, which works exceptionally well here. He did, for example, "The Right Stuff" with Philip Kaufman directing, "The Passion of the Christ" with Mel Gibson directing, "A Woman Under the Influence" with John Cassavetes, and "Being There" with Hal Ashby. He also directed the thoughtful film "Caruso". The attention to detail in this movie amazes me. There is not a bad frame anywhere in the film. That, of course, is in part the work of the editor Nicholas Smith. Music by Mark Isham is a tad dramatic but still lovely. Mr. Isham is one of the most productive of film composers. And the airplanes are terrific. The aerial images alone overwhelm me and recall the imagery from "Wind", one of my favourite action films. The flight though Baltimore alone is worth the price of admission and it one of utter majesty. One plane was the one used in the true story behind the work. As usual, I am not up to doing this fine work credit that it earns. I want to own a copy of it. I rate it ten because I judge films on their individual merits, not necessarily in comparison with other works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to make your dreams soar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandol70
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is already written a lot about the story of Fly Away Home, so I'm not going to repeat my previous reviewers. I have watched the movie for the first time on German TV in 1998, by chance I zapped into the movie and stayed there, mesmerized, fascinated, enchanted by its magical richness of animal (goose) beauty and lush landscape cinematography. When the film ended, I had a lump of emotion in my throat for several days. Something changed deep inside of me, namely the perception of nature, animals, birds, specifically of wild geese. Something made click inside my mind, and since then I adore geese very deeply. Before the movie, geese were of no special interest to me, oh how ignorant I was! As a matter of fact, my love is so deep and the movie inspires me so much that I want get my own geese. Fly Away home's cinematography and script is performed what I can describe as silent, calm, quiet and serene, but never lengthy; is performed suspense-packed, but never thriller-like. Romantic, but never corny or clich&eacute;. Close to life itself and nature, but never overcharged with exaggerated eco-messages. In short, a perfect mixture of all the elements that make a movie worthwhile. The landscape shots are very idyllic (Oscar nomination on this movie for cinematography) and you begin to long and crave for a life on the country-side, away from it all, the boisterous cities and its citizens with their insignificant problems of their everyday lives. When Amy is flying in her ultralight airplane, leading the flock of geese as their surrogate mother, then you can see that the problems on land, down there, are small and trivial. That is where the geese show us how life is meant to be, more simple, more straight-forward, and peaceful. Brilliant. And the film music, the fantastic movie score composed by Mark Isham, transports all the previous mentioned qualities and features in a perfect manner. The introductory song, 10,000 Miles by Mary Chapin Carpenter and co-composed by Mark Isham, is a real tearjerker of the special kind. This song alone summarizes what this movie is all about. Love, friendship, a deep bond among humans and animals, care for nature, peace, freedom and to never give up no matter what. The track expresses Amy's love to her family, and at the same time, the love between Amy and the wild geese. I cannot watch the movie without a package of Kleenex, and I'm male and an adult, a child at heart. I believe everyone has this ability, we just have to show it more often, and this movie can help to release the inner child in all of us. There is no lukewarm love story in Fly Away Home which is a big plus, if at all, it's only presented very subtle and unobtrusive. There have to be more movies like this to prevent a shallow development in our society, but I digress. The main focus of attention is clearly on the geese, who out-act all human actors with feathery ease. Bravo! Please, more movies like this! There are, to my knowledge, only a handful of movies where script, cinematography, directing, music, dialogs and actors come together and are mixed in this perfection. I can only recommend this movie to anyone who still believes in his or her dreams and wants to realize them. This movie supports you there and makes your imaginations soar, literally. As for my part, I'm checking out where I can get geese and how I have to keep them and gain their amazing friendship, deep bond and love. One of the most fascinating movies Hollywood has ever done, Oscar-nominated, and rightly so. Big kudos. Seal of approval: Highly recommended!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    budoinst@aol.com
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How anyone cannot like and appreciate this movie is beyond me. It has an incredible background in fact and is a moving tribute to the human spirit. It also strongly shows that all is not completely lost in the human race and that there is care among us and our fellow beings. What an inspiring movie and so well filmed and documented. Each time it is on, I watch it without fail. So nice to see true human caring and responsibility to all things. We can all learn something from the unwavering focus and support from so many people in overcoming the charge and many times unnecessary destruction of what is left of our former world and mostly in the name of greed and money. It is so nice to see greed being beaten back! We all can learn from this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quiet days and adventure stories
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home begins on a quiet note. A car driving in the rain, mother and daughter exchanging glances. The focus goes from the windscreen to the road, and back again. Suddenly and surprisingly, violence strikes. This introduces a common theme in children's adventure stories - the loss of one or both parents. It's the very same device that Ballard used in his first film, The Black Stallion, and would use once again in Duma. He's placed no inherent value in it as a plot device, however, stating that "If you're going to have a parent die, that has to be the emotional core of the movie". And that's just what it is in this case. Amy (Anna Paquin) doesn't walk off to have fun with the animals simply forgetting her past. But, in a way, this makes the focus less on nature and more on the characters, which I'm not entirely certain was Ballard's original intention. After all, his first two pictures featured next to no human interaction, and this very thing was what made the production of "Wind" so bothersome for him. After watching Fly Away Home for the first time in nearly ten years, I was struck by its high dramatic quality. Just a week earlier, I had watched another, inferior animal film (also starring Jeff Daniels) called "Because of Winn-Dixie". I realized then just how hard it is to strike a balance between what is 'cute' and what is real. The aforementioned film dove headlong into the 'cute' side of things. At the sake of becoming too academic, this is one of the most beautiful films I have ever seen. Caleb Deschanel's photography is effortless in appearance, giving the sensation of weightlessness far more often than in the actual flight sequences. Carroll Ballard has had great success in choosing the best people to photograph his films, and this is a great reunion for the two since their last collaboration on The Black Stallion. Mark Isham takes a totally different approach from his stunning minimalist score of Never Cry Wolf, reaching for - and sometimes - tugging at your heartstrings. In fact, the music is really quite spectacular throughout, except for a rather long and out of place interlude to "10,000 Miles" by Mary Chapin Carpenter. This would have been better suited earlier in the flight, it's current placement feeling a little off. It seems reminiscent of Linda Ronstadt's song "Winter Light" in a 1993 version of "The Secret Garden" (That film, by the way, I highly recommend for fans of Carroll Ballard). As this film progresses, it moves beyond the relationship aspect as Amy makes a discovery in the forest - geese eggs. In a way, her rescuing and raising of these orphaned chicks helps her to heal from her own loss. At its heart, this film is about loss and rebirth. This takes the story of Fly Away Home into new territory, less about the human aspect, and more about nature. All the supporting cast is good and effective (especially Terry Kinney), but Jeff Daniels and Anna Paquin are the central dramatic point which the other actors center around. I've never seen a more lively or energetic performance by Daniels - it's the sort of role he's always excelled at. Paquin, on the other hand, is in a rather uncommon role for her, a simple, more unrestrained character. Without her, or another exactly suited child (of which I know none), the film's dramatic half would have collapsed in on itself. But for all the geese, the drama and the cinematography, it's the moments of quiet that stand out. As the film comes to a close, there are certain factors that bring in a lack of realism. The human and media response to the flight south seems as if borrowed from another film. This perhaps brings the story to a bit of an anti-climax. The 'evil corporate developer' subplot seems lifted from other, less imaginative films. Regardless of the slightly weak ending, perhaps no other conclusion would work better, not without a significantly longer running time. It's a delicately balanced film, and I greatly respect its director for that. There's no immature jokes, no animals being too cute, or overwrought melodrama. For the most part, it feels natural, and the characters act like real people. I appreciate that in a youth-oriented film. I've long since grown out of other movies such as Free Willy, but this film has stuck with me since childhood - and I appreciate it more now than when I first saw it as a kid myself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Timeless Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brown-faith922
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fly Away Home" has been a favorite in my family for years. The story is classic, with every element of a film that is sure to last. The movie gives a vivid and often raw presentation of the relationships within a family, particularly between estranged members, and raises interesting questions about what family itself is and what it means. The view is utterly breathtaking as we're taken on a flight through the Canadian skies, following both the physical and emotional journey of Amy and her father. The father-daughter relationship, in any context, is often a touchy subject, and many films have a tendency to overdramatize certain elements of such a relationship. While the drama is certainly here with this one, we see less of the verbal, noisy drama than we do the quiet, awkward, tense, and somewhat snippy sentiments which exist between the two. Anna Paquin is flawless. Jeff Daniels will make you laugh, cry, and applaud. The chemistry between these two actors is beautiful, making this film one of the first and only that I have ever seen that has not made me despise the "rebellious daughter" figure. If this movie has a flaw, it is only that it is a bit slow by times. Still, for those who, like me, don't mind those sweepingly beautiful images of Canadian landscape, even if nothing much is happening... you'll enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattkratz (themattk@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a great movie about courage, overcoming tragedy, and leadership. After her mother is killed in a car accident, Anna Paquin moves to Canada with her father (Jeff Daniels) after he comes to pick her up. They discover a nestful of baby geese (newly hatched!) whose mother has just died too, and they have to learn how to fly. Unfortunately, they can't learn without example, and she has to be that example. She does so by building model airplanes which she flies. She makes news by showing them the way south. I loved the aerial scenes (which were beautifully shot) and the scene where the daughter was horrified when the guy wanted to clip the chicks' wings. Everybody matures and serves as "parent figures" in the process. This was a throughly enjoyable movie and great "family fare." You will love it-guaranteed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incredibly disappointing and extremely overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BelmaresJodene
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film a few months ago and I did not like it. Where do i start the storyline is just about as dull as you can get. The only thing that saved this from getting a one was the fairly good acting. The story is simple a teenage girl loses her mother in a car crash, she goes to the hospital and is picked up by her estranged father. then she tries to isolate from the rest of the world but what really made me mad about this movie is how bratty, rude annoying and stuck up she was, and the whole geese thing was way overdone. Another thing that annoyed me was that stupid little chant she kept on doing. She also was not very bright she refused to go to school she flew some kind of glider even though she knew she could not fly it. If you are looking for a movie to watch I strongly suggest you stay away from this one. final evaluation 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, Funny, Human
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    contact-951-691937
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, another excellent family film that has received low ratings from many reviewers here - I just don't get it. Fly Away Home is a beautiful story, filled with realistic emotion and incredible views of Canada and the geese. Jeff Daniel's portrayal of the eccentric father is smooth and realistic to the point that you might feel like you could run into him during a drive in the country. Anna Paquin tugs at your heartstrings and our family was cheering her on throughout the movie. Fly Away Home is a wholesome and entertaining family experience that we have watched several times - this says a lot since we rarely all agree on viewing the same film together twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Loved It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Ritter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There aren't that many movies that are well-written, well-directed, that have beautiful scenery and a heart touching story, but this is certainly one of them. This movie is well worth the time it takes to watch it. In fact, we seem to rent it about every two or three years so we can view it again and will probably end up purchasing it, which we seldom do. I just can't say enough for this film. Whatever you do, watch it all the way to the end. Very worthwhile for families or anyone who appreciates nature and a great movie. One of the other things we really liked about the film was the fact that we live about a half mile away from one of the locations where it was filmed just outside of Niagara Falls, NY. That made it more personal for us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Personal and Sentimental Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home is a family oriented, emotionally charged drama in which a young girl's mental recovery from her Mother's death is achieved by a monumental feat. Thrust into her Father Tom's world of inventions and experiments, Amy is lost and uncomfortable in this new environment along with still being vulnerable from her Mother's death, shown in her anxious reactions watching Tom try out his latest invention. Yet it is an aspect of Tom's life that Amy soon finds herself in after discovering Geese eggs, once they hatch Amy is lead down a memorable path of courage and bonding. As Amy begins to raise the Geese as her own Fly Away Home becomes an incredibility touching story where it is hard not to want Amy achieve the goal of getting the Geese to migrate south. Fly Away Home succeeds on an emotional scale in placing the viewer into the predicament Amy faces and the love she feels for the Geese. The cinematography is an additional factor to the heart - tugging vibe, watching the Geese eggs hatch and crawl out of their shells with crystal clear precision as if we are witnessing the birth in person is extraordinary to see and sentimental to feel as they are just as vulnerable as Amy. This sense of vulnerability makes the aerial shots of Amy and Tom leading the Geese to their rightful place in nature later on all the more powerful. It coincides with the soundtrack in relation to Fly Away Home's poignancy, with the use of the song '10, 000 Miles' towards the end of the climatic scene which had been the show piece of the opening credits depicting the death of Amy's Mother increases the atmosphere to the status of a tear jerker, bringing home how much Amy has achieved. However there are some clich&eacute;s which slightly spoil the experience. Having corporate bosses as antagonists is nothing new and tense moments made to briefly unease the audience most notably when Air Traffic Control are about to send out a war plane on Amy, Tom and the Geese when they are seen as a UFO comes across respectively as platitude and ridiculous. But these are only minor flaws in a film whose good heartedness paves these criticisms over. So if you enjoy story lines with a feel - good vibe and the old fashioned good triumphing over evil, Fly Away Home should be one for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Treat Yourself to a Sense of Joy and Wonder. Great Family Film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TedMichaelMor
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sctmpir's review nails this film, which celebrates a young female character with immense richness, complexity even, and grace. I think that the treatment of women in this work is among the most finely nuanced and intelligent I have ever seen in any film. Carroll Ballard, who directed the gracious and almost unbearably beautiful "Wind" as well as "The Black Stallion", "Duma", and "Never Cry Wolf"--all films that have an almost sentimental tone but a tone really closer to romantic in the classic Victorian sense of awe and wonder at life itselfcontrols every aspect of the narrative. This film might seem close to but is never saccharine. It is about wonder in the sense of awe. Anna Paquin exhibits brilliance as an adolescent actor that overwhelms me, in part, because there is never anything trite or coquettish that often mares the role many fine young actresses play. The role here required immense transparency, poise, and nuance. Dana Delaney has the same poise, apparent simplicity, attention to nuance and understatement as Ms. Paquin. No actor is better than Jeff Daniels is when he expresses understatement and subtlyremember him, for example, in "Pleasantville" and "Purple Rose of Cairo". Tim Kerry is a great boon to the film but everyone seems outstanding to me. Caleb Deschane is a master of magic hour cinematography, which works exceptionally well here. He did, for example, "The Right Stuff" with Philip Kaufman directing, "The Passion of the Christ" with Mel Gibson directing, "A Woman Under the Influence" with John Cassavetes, and "Being There" with Hal Ashby. He also directed the thoughtful film "Caruso". The attention to detail in this movie amazes me. There is not a bad frame anywhere in the film. That, of course, is in part the work of the editor Nicholas Smith. Music by Mark Isham is a tad dramatic but still lovely. Mr. Isham is one of the most productive of film composers. And the airplanes are terrific. The aerial images alone overwhelm me and recall the imagery from "Wind", one of my favourite action films. The flight though Baltimore alone is worth the price of admission and it one of utter majesty. One plane was the one used in the true story behind the work. As usual, I am not up to doing this fine work credit that it earns. I want to own a copy of it. I rate it ten because I judge films on their individual merits, not necessarily in comparison with other works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to make your dreams soar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandol70
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is already written a lot about the story of Fly Away Home, so I'm not going to repeat my previous reviewers. I have watched the movie for the first time on German TV in 1998, by chance I zapped into the movie and stayed there, mesmerized, fascinated, enchanted by its magical richness of animal (goose) beauty and lush landscape cinematography. When the film ended, I had a lump of emotion in my throat for several days. Something changed deep inside of me, namely the perception of nature, animals, birds, specifically of wild geese. Something made click inside my mind, and since then I adore geese very deeply. Before the movie, geese were of no special interest to me, oh how ignorant I was! As a matter of fact, my love is so deep and the movie inspires me so much that I want get my own geese. Fly Away home's cinematography and script is performed what I can describe as silent, calm, quiet and serene, but never lengthy; is performed suspense-packed, but never thriller-like. Romantic, but never corny or clich&eacute;. Close to life itself and nature, but never overcharged with exaggerated eco-messages. In short, a perfect mixture of all the elements that make a movie worthwhile. The landscape shots are very idyllic (Oscar nomination on this movie for cinematography) and you begin to long and crave for a life on the country-side, away from it all, the boisterous cities and its citizens with their insignificant problems of their everyday lives. When Amy is flying in her ultralight airplane, leading the flock of geese as their surrogate mother, then you can see that the problems on land, down there, are small and trivial. That is where the geese show us how life is meant to be, more simple, more straight-forward, and peaceful. Brilliant. And the film music, the fantastic movie score composed by Mark Isham, transports all the previous mentioned qualities and features in a perfect manner. The introductory song, 10,000 Miles by Mary Chapin Carpenter and co-composed by Mark Isham, is a real tearjerker of the special kind. This song alone summarizes what this movie is all about. Love, friendship, a deep bond among humans and animals, care for nature, peace, freedom and to never give up no matter what. The track expresses Amy's love to her family, and at the same time, the love between Amy and the wild geese. I cannot watch the movie without a package of Kleenex, and I'm male and an adult, a child at heart. I believe everyone has this ability, we just have to show it more often, and this movie can help to release the inner child in all of us. There is no lukewarm love story in Fly Away Home which is a big plus, if at all, it's only presented very subtle and unobtrusive. There have to be more movies like this to prevent a shallow development in our society, but I digress. The main focus of attention is clearly on the geese, who out-act all human actors with feathery ease. Bravo! Please, more movies like this! There are, to my knowledge, only a handful of movies where script, cinematography, directing, music, dialogs and actors come together and are mixed in this perfection. I can only recommend this movie to anyone who still believes in his or her dreams and wants to realize them. This movie supports you there and makes your imaginations soar, literally. As for my part, I'm checking out where I can get geese and how I have to keep them and gain their amazing friendship, deep bond and love. One of the most fascinating movies Hollywood has ever done, Oscar-nominated, and rightly so. Big kudos. Seal of approval: Highly recommended!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    budoinst@aol.com
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How anyone cannot like and appreciate this movie is beyond me. It has an incredible background in fact and is a moving tribute to the human spirit. It also strongly shows that all is not completely lost in the human race and that there is care among us and our fellow beings. What an inspiring movie and so well filmed and documented. Each time it is on, I watch it without fail. So nice to see true human caring and responsibility to all things. We can all learn something from the unwavering focus and support from so many people in overcoming the charge and many times unnecessary destruction of what is left of our former world and mostly in the name of greed and money. It is so nice to see greed being beaten back! We all can learn from this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quiet days and adventure stories
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home begins on a quiet note. A car driving in the rain, mother and daughter exchanging glances. The focus goes from the windscreen to the road, and back again. Suddenly and surprisingly, violence strikes. This introduces a common theme in children's adventure stories - the loss of one or both parents. It's the very same device that Ballard used in his first film, The Black Stallion, and would use once again in Duma. He's placed no inherent value in it as a plot device, however, stating that "If you're going to have a parent die, that has to be the emotional core of the movie". And that's just what it is in this case. Amy (Anna Paquin) doesn't walk off to have fun with the animals simply forgetting her past. But, in a way, this makes the focus less on nature and more on the characters, which I'm not entirely certain was Ballard's original intention. After all, his first two pictures featured next to no human interaction, and this very thing was what made the production of "Wind" so bothersome for him. After watching Fly Away Home for the first time in nearly ten years, I was struck by its high dramatic quality. Just a week earlier, I had watched another, inferior animal film (also starring Jeff Daniels) called "Because of Winn-Dixie". I realized then just how hard it is to strike a balance between what is 'cute' and what is real. The aforementioned film dove headlong into the 'cute' side of things. At the sake of becoming too academic, this is one of the most beautiful films I have ever seen. Caleb Deschanel's photography is effortless in appearance, giving the sensation of weightlessness far more often than in the actual flight sequences. Carroll Ballard has had great success in choosing the best people to photograph his films, and this is a great reunion for the two since their last collaboration on The Black Stallion. Mark Isham takes a totally different approach from his stunning minimalist score of Never Cry Wolf, reaching for - and sometimes - tugging at your heartstrings. In fact, the music is really quite spectacular throughout, except for a rather long and out of place interlude to "10,000 Miles" by Mary Chapin Carpenter. This would have been better suited earlier in the flight, it's current placement feeling a little off. It seems reminiscent of Linda Ronstadt's song "Winter Light" in a 1993 version of "The Secret Garden" (That film, by the way, I highly recommend for fans of Carroll Ballard). As this film progresses, it moves beyond the relationship aspect as Amy makes a discovery in the forest - geese eggs. In a way, her rescuing and raising of these orphaned chicks helps her to heal from her own loss. At its heart, this film is about loss and rebirth. This takes the story of Fly Away Home into new territory, less about the human aspect, and more about nature. All the supporting cast is good and effective (especially Terry Kinney), but Jeff Daniels and Anna Paquin are the central dramatic point which the other actors center around. I've never seen a more lively or energetic performance by Daniels - it's the sort of role he's always excelled at. Paquin, on the other hand, is in a rather uncommon role for her, a simple, more unrestrained character. Without her, or another exactly suited child (of which I know none), the film's dramatic half would have collapsed in on itself. But for all the geese, the drama and the cinematography, it's the moments of quiet that stand out. As the film comes to a close, there are certain factors that bring in a lack of realism. The human and media response to the flight south seems as if borrowed from another film. This perhaps brings the story to a bit of an anti-climax. The 'evil corporate developer' subplot seems lifted from other, less imaginative films. Regardless of the slightly weak ending, perhaps no other conclusion would work better, not without a significantly longer running time. It's a delicately balanced film, and I greatly respect its director for that. There's no immature jokes, no animals being too cute, or overwrought melodrama. For the most part, it feels natural, and the characters act like real people. I appreciate that in a youth-oriented film. I've long since grown out of other movies such as Free Willy, but this film has stuck with me since childhood - and I appreciate it more now than when I first saw it as a kid myself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Timeless Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brown-faith922
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fly Away Home" has been a favorite in my family for years. The story is classic, with every element of a film that is sure to last. The movie gives a vivid and often raw presentation of the relationships within a family, particularly between estranged members, and raises interesting questions about what family itself is and what it means. The view is utterly breathtaking as we're taken on a flight through the Canadian skies, following both the physical and emotional journey of Amy and her father. The father-daughter relationship, in any context, is often a touchy subject, and many films have a tendency to overdramatize certain elements of such a relationship. While the drama is certainly here with this one, we see less of the verbal, noisy drama than we do the quiet, awkward, tense, and somewhat snippy sentiments which exist between the two. Anna Paquin is flawless. Jeff Daniels will make you laugh, cry, and applaud. The chemistry between these two actors is beautiful, making this film one of the first and only that I have ever seen that has not made me despise the "rebellious daughter" figure. If this movie has a flaw, it is only that it is a bit slow by times. Still, for those who, like me, don't mind those sweepingly beautiful images of Canadian landscape, even if nothing much is happening... you'll enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattkratz (themattk@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a great movie about courage, overcoming tragedy, and leadership. After her mother is killed in a car accident, Anna Paquin moves to Canada with her father (Jeff Daniels) after he comes to pick her up. They discover a nestful of baby geese (newly hatched!) whose mother has just died too, and they have to learn how to fly. Unfortunately, they can't learn without example, and she has to be that example. She does so by building model airplanes which she flies. She makes news by showing them the way south. I loved the aerial scenes (which were beautifully shot) and the scene where the daughter was horrified when the guy wanted to clip the chicks' wings. Everybody matures and serves as "parent figures" in the process. This was a throughly enjoyable movie and great "family fare." You will love it-guaranteed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incredibly disappointing and extremely overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BelmaresJodene
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film a few months ago and I did not like it. Where do i start the storyline is just about as dull as you can get. The only thing that saved this from getting a one was the fairly good acting. The story is simple a teenage girl loses her mother in a car crash, she goes to the hospital and is picked up by her estranged father. then she tries to isolate from the rest of the world but what really made me mad about this movie is how bratty, rude annoying and stuck up she was, and the whole geese thing was way overdone. Another thing that annoyed me was that stupid little chant she kept on doing. She also was not very bright she refused to go to school she flew some kind of glider even though she knew she could not fly it. If you are looking for a movie to watch I strongly suggest you stay away from this one. final evaluation 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, Funny, Human
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    contact-951-691937
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, another excellent family film that has received low ratings from many reviewers here - I just don't get it. Fly Away Home is a beautiful story, filled with realistic emotion and incredible views of Canada and the geese. Jeff Daniel's portrayal of the eccentric father is smooth and realistic to the point that you might feel like you could run into him during a drive in the country. Anna Paquin tugs at your heartstrings and our family was cheering her on throughout the movie. Fly Away Home is a wholesome and entertaining family experience that we have watched several times - this says a lot since we rarely all agree on viewing the same film together twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Loved It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Ritter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There aren't that many movies that are well-written, well-directed, that have beautiful scenery and a heart touching story, but this is certainly one of them. This movie is well worth the time it takes to watch it. In fact, we seem to rent it about every two or three years so we can view it again and will probably end up purchasing it, which we seldom do. I just can't say enough for this film. Whatever you do, watch it all the way to the end. Very worthwhile for families or anyone who appreciates nature and a great movie. One of the other things we really liked about the film was the fact that we live about a half mile away from one of the locations where it was filmed just outside of Niagara Falls, NY. That made it more personal for us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Personal and Sentimental Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home is a family oriented, emotionally charged drama in which a young girl's mental recovery from her Mother's death is achieved by a monumental feat. Thrust into her Father Tom's world of inventions and experiments, Amy is lost and uncomfortable in this new environment along with still being vulnerable from her Mother's death, shown in her anxious reactions watching Tom try out his latest invention. Yet it is an aspect of Tom's life that Amy soon finds herself in after discovering Geese eggs, once they hatch Amy is lead down a memorable path of courage and bonding. As Amy begins to raise the Geese as her own Fly Away Home becomes an incredibility touching story where it is hard not to want Amy achieve the goal of getting the Geese to migrate south. Fly Away Home succeeds on an emotional scale in placing the viewer into the predicament Amy faces and the love she feels for the Geese. The cinematography is an additional factor to the heart - tugging vibe, watching the Geese eggs hatch and crawl out of their shells with crystal clear precision as if we are witnessing the birth in person is extraordinary to see and sentimental to feel as they are just as vulnerable as Amy. This sense of vulnerability makes the aerial shots of Amy and Tom leading the Geese to their rightful place in nature later on all the more powerful. It coincides with the soundtrack in relation to Fly Away Home's poignancy, with the use of the song '10, 000 Miles' towards the end of the climatic scene which had been the show piece of the opening credits depicting the death of Amy's Mother increases the atmosphere to the status of a tear jerker, bringing home how much Amy has achieved. However there are some clich&eacute;s which slightly spoil the experience. Having corporate bosses as antagonists is nothing new and tense moments made to briefly unease the audience most notably when Air Traffic Control are about to send out a war plane on Amy, Tom and the Geese when they are seen as a UFO comes across respectively as platitude and ridiculous. But these are only minor flaws in a film whose good heartedness paves these criticisms over. So if you enjoy story lines with a feel - good vibe and the old fashioned good triumphing over evil, Fly Away Home should be one for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Treat Yourself to a Sense of Joy and Wonder. Great Family Film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TedMichaelMor
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sctmpir's review nails this film, which celebrates a young female character with immense richness, complexity even, and grace. I think that the treatment of women in this work is among the most finely nuanced and intelligent I have ever seen in any film. Carroll Ballard, who directed the gracious and almost unbearably beautiful "Wind" as well as "The Black Stallion", "Duma", and "Never Cry Wolf"--all films that have an almost sentimental tone but a tone really closer to romantic in the classic Victorian sense of awe and wonder at life itselfcontrols every aspect of the narrative. This film might seem close to but is never saccharine. It is about wonder in the sense of awe. Anna Paquin exhibits brilliance as an adolescent actor that overwhelms me, in part, because there is never anything trite or coquettish that often mares the role many fine young actresses play. The role here required immense transparency, poise, and nuance. Dana Delaney has the same poise, apparent simplicity, attention to nuance and understatement as Ms. Paquin. No actor is better than Jeff Daniels is when he expresses understatement and subtlyremember him, for example, in "Pleasantville" and "Purple Rose of Cairo". Tim Kerry is a great boon to the film but everyone seems outstanding to me. Caleb Deschane is a master of magic hour cinematography, which works exceptionally well here. He did, for example, "The Right Stuff" with Philip Kaufman directing, "The Passion of the Christ" with Mel Gibson directing, "A Woman Under the Influence" with John Cassavetes, and "Being There" with Hal Ashby. He also directed the thoughtful film "Caruso". The attention to detail in this movie amazes me. There is not a bad frame anywhere in the film. That, of course, is in part the work of the editor Nicholas Smith. Music by Mark Isham is a tad dramatic but still lovely. Mr. Isham is one of the most productive of film composers. And the airplanes are terrific. The aerial images alone overwhelm me and recall the imagery from "Wind", one of my favourite action films. The flight though Baltimore alone is worth the price of admission and it one of utter majesty. One plane was the one used in the true story behind the work. As usual, I am not up to doing this fine work credit that it earns. I want to own a copy of it. I rate it ten because I judge films on their individual merits, not necessarily in comparison with other works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to make your dreams soar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandol70
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is already written a lot about the story of Fly Away Home, so I'm not going to repeat my previous reviewers. I have watched the movie for the first time on German TV in 1998, by chance I zapped into the movie and stayed there, mesmerized, fascinated, enchanted by its magical richness of animal (goose) beauty and lush landscape cinematography. When the film ended, I had a lump of emotion in my throat for several days. Something changed deep inside of me, namely the perception of nature, animals, birds, specifically of wild geese. Something made click inside my mind, and since then I adore geese very deeply. Before the movie, geese were of no special interest to me, oh how ignorant I was! As a matter of fact, my love is so deep and the movie inspires me so much that I want get my own geese. Fly Away home's cinematography and script is performed what I can describe as silent, calm, quiet and serene, but never lengthy; is performed suspense-packed, but never thriller-like. Romantic, but never corny or clich&eacute;. Close to life itself and nature, but never overcharged with exaggerated eco-messages. In short, a perfect mixture of all the elements that make a movie worthwhile. The landscape shots are very idyllic (Oscar nomination on this movie for cinematography) and you begin to long and crave for a life on the country-side, away from it all, the boisterous cities and its citizens with their insignificant problems of their everyday lives. When Amy is flying in her ultralight airplane, leading the flock of geese as their surrogate mother, then you can see that the problems on land, down there, are small and trivial. That is where the geese show us how life is meant to be, more simple, more straight-forward, and peaceful. Brilliant. And the film music, the fantastic movie score composed by Mark Isham, transports all the previous mentioned qualities and features in a perfect manner. The introductory song, 10,000 Miles by Mary Chapin Carpenter and co-composed by Mark Isham, is a real tearjerker of the special kind. This song alone summarizes what this movie is all about. Love, friendship, a deep bond among humans and animals, care for nature, peace, freedom and to never give up no matter what. The track expresses Amy's love to her family, and at the same time, the love between Amy and the wild geese. I cannot watch the movie without a package of Kleenex, and I'm male and an adult, a child at heart. I believe everyone has this ability, we just have to show it more often, and this movie can help to release the inner child in all of us. There is no lukewarm love story in Fly Away Home which is a big plus, if at all, it's only presented very subtle and unobtrusive. There have to be more movies like this to prevent a shallow development in our society, but I digress. The main focus of attention is clearly on the geese, who out-act all human actors with feathery ease. Bravo! Please, more movies like this! There are, to my knowledge, only a handful of movies where script, cinematography, directing, music, dialogs and actors come together and are mixed in this perfection. I can only recommend this movie to anyone who still believes in his or her dreams and wants to realize them. This movie supports you there and makes your imaginations soar, literally. As for my part, I'm checking out where I can get geese and how I have to keep them and gain their amazing friendship, deep bond and love. One of the most fascinating movies Hollywood has ever done, Oscar-nominated, and rightly so. Big kudos. Seal of approval: Highly recommended!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    budoinst@aol.com
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How anyone cannot like and appreciate this movie is beyond me. It has an incredible background in fact and is a moving tribute to the human spirit. It also strongly shows that all is not completely lost in the human race and that there is care among us and our fellow beings. What an inspiring movie and so well filmed and documented. Each time it is on, I watch it without fail. So nice to see true human caring and responsibility to all things. We can all learn something from the unwavering focus and support from so many people in overcoming the charge and many times unnecessary destruction of what is left of our former world and mostly in the name of greed and money. It is so nice to see greed being beaten back! We all can learn from this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quiet days and adventure stories
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home begins on a quiet note. A car driving in the rain, mother and daughter exchanging glances. The focus goes from the windscreen to the road, and back again. Suddenly and surprisingly, violence strikes. This introduces a common theme in children's adventure stories - the loss of one or both parents. It's the very same device that Ballard used in his first film, The Black Stallion, and would use once again in Duma. He's placed no inherent value in it as a plot device, however, stating that "If you're going to have a parent die, that has to be the emotional core of the movie". And that's just what it is in this case. Amy (Anna Paquin) doesn't walk off to have fun with the animals simply forgetting her past. But, in a way, this makes the focus less on nature and more on the characters, which I'm not entirely certain was Ballard's original intention. After all, his first two pictures featured next to no human interaction, and this very thing was what made the production of "Wind" so bothersome for him. After watching Fly Away Home for the first time in nearly ten years, I was struck by its high dramatic quality. Just a week earlier, I had watched another, inferior animal film (also starring Jeff Daniels) called "Because of Winn-Dixie". I realized then just how hard it is to strike a balance between what is 'cute' and what is real. The aforementioned film dove headlong into the 'cute' side of things. At the sake of becoming too academic, this is one of the most beautiful films I have ever seen. Caleb Deschanel's photography is effortless in appearance, giving the sensation of weightlessness far more often than in the actual flight sequences. Carroll Ballard has had great success in choosing the best people to photograph his films, and this is a great reunion for the two since their last collaboration on The Black Stallion. Mark Isham takes a totally different approach from his stunning minimalist score of Never Cry Wolf, reaching for - and sometimes - tugging at your heartstrings. In fact, the music is really quite spectacular throughout, except for a rather long and out of place interlude to "10,000 Miles" by Mary Chapin Carpenter. This would have been better suited earlier in the flight, it's current placement feeling a little off. It seems reminiscent of Linda Ronstadt's song "Winter Light" in a 1993 version of "The Secret Garden" (That film, by the way, I highly recommend for fans of Carroll Ballard). As this film progresses, it moves beyond the relationship aspect as Amy makes a discovery in the forest - geese eggs. In a way, her rescuing and raising of these orphaned chicks helps her to heal from her own loss. At its heart, this film is about loss and rebirth. This takes the story of Fly Away Home into new territory, less about the human aspect, and more about nature. All the supporting cast is good and effective (especially Terry Kinney), but Jeff Daniels and Anna Paquin are the central dramatic point which the other actors center around. I've never seen a more lively or energetic performance by Daniels - it's the sort of role he's always excelled at. Paquin, on the other hand, is in a rather uncommon role for her, a simple, more unrestrained character. Without her, or another exactly suited child (of which I know none), the film's dramatic half would have collapsed in on itself. But for all the geese, the drama and the cinematography, it's the moments of quiet that stand out. As the film comes to a close, there are certain factors that bring in a lack of realism. The human and media response to the flight south seems as if borrowed from another film. This perhaps brings the story to a bit of an anti-climax. The 'evil corporate developer' subplot seems lifted from other, less imaginative films. Regardless of the slightly weak ending, perhaps no other conclusion would work better, not without a significantly longer running time. It's a delicately balanced film, and I greatly respect its director for that. There's no immature jokes, no animals being too cute, or overwrought melodrama. For the most part, it feels natural, and the characters act like real people. I appreciate that in a youth-oriented film. I've long since grown out of other movies such as Free Willy, but this film has stuck with me since childhood - and I appreciate it more now than when I first saw it as a kid myself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Timeless Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brown-faith922
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fly Away Home" has been a favorite in my family for years. The story is classic, with every element of a film that is sure to last. The movie gives a vivid and often raw presentation of the relationships within a family, particularly between estranged members, and raises interesting questions about what family itself is and what it means. The view is utterly breathtaking as we're taken on a flight through the Canadian skies, following both the physical and emotional journey of Amy and her father. The father-daughter relationship, in any context, is often a touchy subject, and many films have a tendency to overdramatize certain elements of such a relationship. While the drama is certainly here with this one, we see less of the verbal, noisy drama than we do the quiet, awkward, tense, and somewhat snippy sentiments which exist between the two. Anna Paquin is flawless. Jeff Daniels will make you laugh, cry, and applaud. The chemistry between these two actors is beautiful, making this film one of the first and only that I have ever seen that has not made me despise the "rebellious daughter" figure. If this movie has a flaw, it is only that it is a bit slow by times. Still, for those who, like me, don't mind those sweepingly beautiful images of Canadian landscape, even if nothing much is happening... you'll enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattkratz (themattk@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a great movie about courage, overcoming tragedy, and leadership. After her mother is killed in a car accident, Anna Paquin moves to Canada with her father (Jeff Daniels) after he comes to pick her up. They discover a nestful of baby geese (newly hatched!) whose mother has just died too, and they have to learn how to fly. Unfortunately, they can't learn without example, and she has to be that example. She does so by building model airplanes which she flies. She makes news by showing them the way south. I loved the aerial scenes (which were beautifully shot) and the scene where the daughter was horrified when the guy wanted to clip the chicks' wings. Everybody matures and serves as "parent figures" in the process. This was a throughly enjoyable movie and great "family fare." You will love it-guaranteed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incredibly disappointing and extremely overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BelmaresJodene
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film a few months ago and I did not like it. Where do i start the storyline is just about as dull as you can get. The only thing that saved this from getting a one was the fairly good acting. The story is simple a teenage girl loses her mother in a car crash, she goes to the hospital and is picked up by her estranged father. then she tries to isolate from the rest of the world but what really made me mad about this movie is how bratty, rude annoying and stuck up she was, and the whole geese thing was way overdone. Another thing that annoyed me was that stupid little chant she kept on doing. She also was not very bright she refused to go to school she flew some kind of glider even though she knew she could not fly it. If you are looking for a movie to watch I strongly suggest you stay away from this one. final evaluation 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, Funny, Human
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    contact-951-691937
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, another excellent family film that has received low ratings from many reviewers here - I just don't get it. Fly Away Home is a beautiful story, filled with realistic emotion and incredible views of Canada and the geese. Jeff Daniel's portrayal of the eccentric father is smooth and realistic to the point that you might feel like you could run into him during a drive in the country. Anna Paquin tugs at your heartstrings and our family was cheering her on throughout the movie. Fly Away Home is a wholesome and entertaining family experience that we have watched several times - this says a lot since we rarely all agree on viewing the same film together twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Loved It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Ritter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There aren't that many movies that are well-written, well-directed, that have beautiful scenery and a heart touching story, but this is certainly one of them. This movie is well worth the time it takes to watch it. In fact, we seem to rent it about every two or three years so we can view it again and will probably end up purchasing it, which we seldom do. I just can't say enough for this film. Whatever you do, watch it all the way to the end. Very worthwhile for families or anyone who appreciates nature and a great movie. One of the other things we really liked about the film was the fact that we live about a half mile away from one of the locations where it was filmed just outside of Niagara Falls, NY. That made it more personal for us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Personal and Sentimental Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home is a family oriented, emotionally charged drama in which a young girl's mental recovery from her Mother's death is achieved by a monumental feat. Thrust into her Father Tom's world of inventions and experiments, Amy is lost and uncomfortable in this new environment along with still being vulnerable from her Mother's death, shown in her anxious reactions watching Tom try out his latest invention. Yet it is an aspect of Tom's life that Amy soon finds herself in after discovering Geese eggs, once they hatch Amy is lead down a memorable path of courage and bonding. As Amy begins to raise the Geese as her own Fly Away Home becomes an incredibility touching story where it is hard not to want Amy achieve the goal of getting the Geese to migrate south. Fly Away Home succeeds on an emotional scale in placing the viewer into the predicament Amy faces and the love she feels for the Geese. The cinematography is an additional factor to the heart - tugging vibe, watching the Geese eggs hatch and crawl out of their shells with crystal clear precision as if we are witnessing the birth in person is extraordinary to see and sentimental to feel as they are just as vulnerable as Amy. This sense of vulnerability makes the aerial shots of Amy and Tom leading the Geese to their rightful place in nature later on all the more powerful. It coincides with the soundtrack in relation to Fly Away Home's poignancy, with the use of the song '10, 000 Miles' towards the end of the climatic scene which had been the show piece of the opening credits depicting the death of Amy's Mother increases the atmosphere to the status of a tear jerker, bringing home how much Amy has achieved. However there are some clich&eacute;s which slightly spoil the experience. Having corporate bosses as antagonists is nothing new and tense moments made to briefly unease the audience most notably when Air Traffic Control are about to send out a war plane on Amy, Tom and the Geese when they are seen as a UFO comes across respectively as platitude and ridiculous. But these are only minor flaws in a film whose good heartedness paves these criticisms over. So if you enjoy story lines with a feel - good vibe and the old fashioned good triumphing over evil, Fly Away Home should be one for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Treat Yourself to a Sense of Joy and Wonder. Great Family Film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TedMichaelMor
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sctmpir's review nails this film, which celebrates a young female character with immense richness, complexity even, and grace. I think that the treatment of women in this work is among the most finely nuanced and intelligent I have ever seen in any film. Carroll Ballard, who directed the gracious and almost unbearably beautiful "Wind" as well as "The Black Stallion", "Duma", and "Never Cry Wolf"--all films that have an almost sentimental tone but a tone really closer to romantic in the classic Victorian sense of awe and wonder at life itselfcontrols every aspect of the narrative. This film might seem close to but is never saccharine. It is about wonder in the sense of awe. Anna Paquin exhibits brilliance as an adolescent actor that overwhelms me, in part, because there is never anything trite or coquettish that often mares the role many fine young actresses play. The role here required immense transparency, poise, and nuance. Dana Delaney has the same poise, apparent simplicity, attention to nuance and understatement as Ms. Paquin. No actor is better than Jeff Daniels is when he expresses understatement and subtlyremember him, for example, in "Pleasantville" and "Purple Rose of Cairo". Tim Kerry is a great boon to the film but everyone seems outstanding to me. Caleb Deschane is a master of magic hour cinematography, which works exceptionally well here. He did, for example, "The Right Stuff" with Philip Kaufman directing, "The Passion of the Christ" with Mel Gibson directing, "A Woman Under the Influence" with John Cassavetes, and "Being There" with Hal Ashby. He also directed the thoughtful film "Caruso". The attention to detail in this movie amazes me. There is not a bad frame anywhere in the film. That, of course, is in part the work of the editor Nicholas Smith. Music by Mark Isham is a tad dramatic but still lovely. Mr. Isham is one of the most productive of film composers. And the airplanes are terrific. The aerial images alone overwhelm me and recall the imagery from "Wind", one of my favourite action films. The flight though Baltimore alone is worth the price of admission and it one of utter majesty. One plane was the one used in the true story behind the work. As usual, I am not up to doing this fine work credit that it earns. I want to own a copy of it. I rate it ten because I judge films on their individual merits, not necessarily in comparison with other works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to make your dreams soar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandol70
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is already written a lot about the story of Fly Away Home, so I'm not going to repeat my previous reviewers. I have watched the movie for the first time on German TV in 1998, by chance I zapped into the movie and stayed there, mesmerized, fascinated, enchanted by its magical richness of animal (goose) beauty and lush landscape cinematography. When the film ended, I had a lump of emotion in my throat for several days. Something changed deep inside of me, namely the perception of nature, animals, birds, specifically of wild geese. Something made click inside my mind, and since then I adore geese very deeply. Before the movie, geese were of no special interest to me, oh how ignorant I was! As a matter of fact, my love is so deep and the movie inspires me so much that I want get my own geese. Fly Away home's cinematography and script is performed what I can describe as silent, calm, quiet and serene, but never lengthy; is performed suspense-packed, but never thriller-like. Romantic, but never corny or clich&eacute;. Close to life itself and nature, but never overcharged with exaggerated eco-messages. In short, a perfect mixture of all the elements that make a movie worthwhile. The landscape shots are very idyllic (Oscar nomination on this movie for cinematography) and you begin to long and crave for a life on the country-side, away from it all, the boisterous cities and its citizens with their insignificant problems of their everyday lives. When Amy is flying in her ultralight airplane, leading the flock of geese as their surrogate mother, then you can see that the problems on land, down there, are small and trivial. That is where the geese show us how life is meant to be, more simple, more straight-forward, and peaceful. Brilliant. And the film music, the fantastic movie score composed by Mark Isham, transports all the previous mentioned qualities and features in a perfect manner. The introductory song, 10,000 Miles by Mary Chapin Carpenter and co-composed by Mark Isham, is a real tearjerker of the special kind. This song alone summarizes what this movie is all about. Love, friendship, a deep bond among humans and animals, care for nature, peace, freedom and to never give up no matter what. The track expresses Amy's love to her family, and at the same time, the love between Amy and the wild geese. I cannot watch the movie without a package of Kleenex, and I'm male and an adult, a child at heart. I believe everyone has this ability, we just have to show it more often, and this movie can help to release the inner child in all of us. There is no lukewarm love story in Fly Away Home which is a big plus, if at all, it's only presented very subtle and unobtrusive. There have to be more movies like this to prevent a shallow development in our society, but I digress. The main focus of attention is clearly on the geese, who out-act all human actors with feathery ease. Bravo! Please, more movies like this! There are, to my knowledge, only a handful of movies where script, cinematography, directing, music, dialogs and actors come together and are mixed in this perfection. I can only recommend this movie to anyone who still believes in his or her dreams and wants to realize them. This movie supports you there and makes your imaginations soar, literally. As for my part, I'm checking out where I can get geese and how I have to keep them and gain their amazing friendship, deep bond and love. One of the most fascinating movies Hollywood has ever done, Oscar-nominated, and rightly so. Big kudos. Seal of approval: Highly recommended!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    budoinst@aol.com
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How anyone cannot like and appreciate this movie is beyond me. It has an incredible background in fact and is a moving tribute to the human spirit. It also strongly shows that all is not completely lost in the human race and that there is care among us and our fellow beings. What an inspiring movie and so well filmed and documented. Each time it is on, I watch it without fail. So nice to see true human caring and responsibility to all things. We can all learn something from the unwavering focus and support from so many people in overcoming the charge and many times unnecessary destruction of what is left of our former world and mostly in the name of greed and money. It is so nice to see greed being beaten back! We all can learn from this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quiet days and adventure stories
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home begins on a quiet note. A car driving in the rain, mother and daughter exchanging glances. The focus goes from the windscreen to the road, and back again. Suddenly and surprisingly, violence strikes. This introduces a common theme in children's adventure stories - the loss of one or both parents. It's the very same device that Ballard used in his first film, The Black Stallion, and would use once again in Duma. He's placed no inherent value in it as a plot device, however, stating that "If you're going to have a parent die, that has to be the emotional core of the movie". And that's just what it is in this case. Amy (Anna Paquin) doesn't walk off to have fun with the animals simply forgetting her past. But, in a way, this makes the focus less on nature and more on the characters, which I'm not entirely certain was Ballard's original intention. After all, his first two pictures featured next to no human interaction, and this very thing was what made the production of "Wind" so bothersome for him. After watching Fly Away Home for the first time in nearly ten years, I was struck by its high dramatic quality. Just a week earlier, I had watched another, inferior animal film (also starring Jeff Daniels) called "Because of Winn-Dixie". I realized then just how hard it is to strike a balance between what is 'cute' and what is real. The aforementioned film dove headlong into the 'cute' side of things. At the sake of becoming too academic, this is one of the most beautiful films I have ever seen. Caleb Deschanel's photography is effortless in appearance, giving the sensation of weightlessness far more often than in the actual flight sequences. Carroll Ballard has had great success in choosing the best people to photograph his films, and this is a great reunion for the two since their last collaboration on The Black Stallion. Mark Isham takes a totally different approach from his stunning minimalist score of Never Cry Wolf, reaching for - and sometimes - tugging at your heartstrings. In fact, the music is really quite spectacular throughout, except for a rather long and out of place interlude to "10,000 Miles" by Mary Chapin Carpenter. This would have been better suited earlier in the flight, it's current placement feeling a little off. It seems reminiscent of Linda Ronstadt's song "Winter Light" in a 1993 version of "The Secret Garden" (That film, by the way, I highly recommend for fans of Carroll Ballard). As this film progresses, it moves beyond the relationship aspect as Amy makes a discovery in the forest - geese eggs. In a way, her rescuing and raising of these orphaned chicks helps her to heal from her own loss. At its heart, this film is about loss and rebirth. This takes the story of Fly Away Home into new territory, less about the human aspect, and more about nature. All the supporting cast is good and effective (especially Terry Kinney), but Jeff Daniels and Anna Paquin are the central dramatic point which the other actors center around. I've never seen a more lively or energetic performance by Daniels - it's the sort of role he's always excelled at. Paquin, on the other hand, is in a rather uncommon role for her, a simple, more unrestrained character. Without her, or another exactly suited child (of which I know none), the film's dramatic half would have collapsed in on itself. But for all the geese, the drama and the cinematography, it's the moments of quiet that stand out. As the film comes to a close, there are certain factors that bring in a lack of realism. The human and media response to the flight south seems as if borrowed from another film. This perhaps brings the story to a bit of an anti-climax. The 'evil corporate developer' subplot seems lifted from other, less imaginative films. Regardless of the slightly weak ending, perhaps no other conclusion would work better, not without a significantly longer running time. It's a delicately balanced film, and I greatly respect its director for that. There's no immature jokes, no animals being too cute, or overwrought melodrama. For the most part, it feels natural, and the characters act like real people. I appreciate that in a youth-oriented film. I've long since grown out of other movies such as Free Willy, but this film has stuck with me since childhood - and I appreciate it more now than when I first saw it as a kid myself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Timeless Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brown-faith922
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fly Away Home" has been a favorite in my family for years. The story is classic, with every element of a film that is sure to last. The movie gives a vivid and often raw presentation of the relationships within a family, particularly between estranged members, and raises interesting questions about what family itself is and what it means. The view is utterly breathtaking as we're taken on a flight through the Canadian skies, following both the physical and emotional journey of Amy and her father. The father-daughter relationship, in any context, is often a touchy subject, and many films have a tendency to overdramatize certain elements of such a relationship. While the drama is certainly here with this one, we see less of the verbal, noisy drama than we do the quiet, awkward, tense, and somewhat snippy sentiments which exist between the two. Anna Paquin is flawless. Jeff Daniels will make you laugh, cry, and applaud. The chemistry between these two actors is beautiful, making this film one of the first and only that I have ever seen that has not made me despise the "rebellious daughter" figure. If this movie has a flaw, it is only that it is a bit slow by times. Still, for those who, like me, don't mind those sweepingly beautiful images of Canadian landscape, even if nothing much is happening... you'll enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattkratz (themattk@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a great movie about courage, overcoming tragedy, and leadership. After her mother is killed in a car accident, Anna Paquin moves to Canada with her father (Jeff Daniels) after he comes to pick her up. They discover a nestful of baby geese (newly hatched!) whose mother has just died too, and they have to learn how to fly. Unfortunately, they can't learn without example, and she has to be that example. She does so by building model airplanes which she flies. She makes news by showing them the way south. I loved the aerial scenes (which were beautifully shot) and the scene where the daughter was horrified when the guy wanted to clip the chicks' wings. Everybody matures and serves as "parent figures" in the process. This was a throughly enjoyable movie and great "family fare." You will love it-guaranteed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incredibly disappointing and extremely overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BelmaresJodene
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film a few months ago and I did not like it. Where do i start the storyline is just about as dull as you can get. The only thing that saved this from getting a one was the fairly good acting. The story is simple a teenage girl loses her mother in a car crash, she goes to the hospital and is picked up by her estranged father. then she tries to isolate from the rest of the world but what really made me mad about this movie is how bratty, rude annoying and stuck up she was, and the whole geese thing was way overdone. Another thing that annoyed me was that stupid little chant she kept on doing. She also was not very bright she refused to go to school she flew some kind of glider even though she knew she could not fly it. If you are looking for a movie to watch I strongly suggest you stay away from this one. final evaluation 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, Funny, Human
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    contact-951-691937
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, another excellent family film that has received low ratings from many reviewers here - I just don't get it. Fly Away Home is a beautiful story, filled with realistic emotion and incredible views of Canada and the geese. Jeff Daniel's portrayal of the eccentric father is smooth and realistic to the point that you might feel like you could run into him during a drive in the country. Anna Paquin tugs at your heartstrings and our family was cheering her on throughout the movie. Fly Away Home is a wholesome and entertaining family experience that we have watched several times - this says a lot since we rarely all agree on viewing the same film together twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Loved It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Ritter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There aren't that many movies that are well-written, well-directed, that have beautiful scenery and a heart touching story, but this is certainly one of them. This movie is well worth the time it takes to watch it. In fact, we seem to rent it about every two or three years so we can view it again and will probably end up purchasing it, which we seldom do. I just can't say enough for this film. Whatever you do, watch it all the way to the end. Very worthwhile for families or anyone who appreciates nature and a great movie. One of the other things we really liked about the film was the fact that we live about a half mile away from one of the locations where it was filmed just outside of Niagara Falls, NY. That made it more personal for us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Personal and Sentimental Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home is a family oriented, emotionally charged drama in which a young girl's mental recovery from her Mother's death is achieved by a monumental feat. Thrust into her Father Tom's world of inventions and experiments, Amy is lost and uncomfortable in this new environment along with still being vulnerable from her Mother's death, shown in her anxious reactions watching Tom try out his latest invention. Yet it is an aspect of Tom's life that Amy soon finds herself in after discovering Geese eggs, once they hatch Amy is lead down a memorable path of courage and bonding. As Amy begins to raise the Geese as her own Fly Away Home becomes an incredibility touching story where it is hard not to want Amy achieve the goal of getting the Geese to migrate south. Fly Away Home succeeds on an emotional scale in placing the viewer into the predicament Amy faces and the love she feels for the Geese. The cinematography is an additional factor to the heart - tugging vibe, watching the Geese eggs hatch and crawl out of their shells with crystal clear precision as if we are witnessing the birth in person is extraordinary to see and sentimental to feel as they are just as vulnerable as Amy. This sense of vulnerability makes the aerial shots of Amy and Tom leading the Geese to their rightful place in nature later on all the more powerful. It coincides with the soundtrack in relation to Fly Away Home's poignancy, with the use of the song '10, 000 Miles' towards the end of the climatic scene which had been the show piece of the opening credits depicting the death of Amy's Mother increases the atmosphere to the status of a tear jerker, bringing home how much Amy has achieved. However there are some clich&eacute;s which slightly spoil the experience. Having corporate bosses as antagonists is nothing new and tense moments made to briefly unease the audience most notably when Air Traffic Control are about to send out a war plane on Amy, Tom and the Geese when they are seen as a UFO comes across respectively as platitude and ridiculous. But these are only minor flaws in a film whose good heartedness paves these criticisms over. So if you enjoy story lines with a feel - good vibe and the old fashioned good triumphing over evil, Fly Away Home should be one for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Treat Yourself to a Sense of Joy and Wonder. Great Family Film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TedMichaelMor
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sctmpir's review nails this film, which celebrates a young female character with immense richness, complexity even, and grace. I think that the treatment of women in this work is among the most finely nuanced and intelligent I have ever seen in any film. Carroll Ballard, who directed the gracious and almost unbearably beautiful "Wind" as well as "The Black Stallion", "Duma", and "Never Cry Wolf"--all films that have an almost sentimental tone but a tone really closer to romantic in the classic Victorian sense of awe and wonder at life itselfcontrols every aspect of the narrative. This film might seem close to but is never saccharine. It is about wonder in the sense of awe. Anna Paquin exhibits brilliance as an adolescent actor that overwhelms me, in part, because there is never anything trite or coquettish that often mares the role many fine young actresses play. The role here required immense transparency, poise, and nuance. Dana Delaney has the same poise, apparent simplicity, attention to nuance and understatement as Ms. Paquin. No actor is better than Jeff Daniels is when he expresses understatement and subtlyremember him, for example, in "Pleasantville" and "Purple Rose of Cairo". Tim Kerry is a great boon to the film but everyone seems outstanding to me. Caleb Deschane is a master of magic hour cinematography, which works exceptionally well here. He did, for example, "The Right Stuff" with Philip Kaufman directing, "The Passion of the Christ" with Mel Gibson directing, "A Woman Under the Influence" with John Cassavetes, and "Being There" with Hal Ashby. He also directed the thoughtful film "Caruso". The attention to detail in this movie amazes me. There is not a bad frame anywhere in the film. That, of course, is in part the work of the editor Nicholas Smith. Music by Mark Isham is a tad dramatic but still lovely. Mr. Isham is one of the most productive of film composers. And the airplanes are terrific. The aerial images alone overwhelm me and recall the imagery from "Wind", one of my favourite action films. The flight though Baltimore alone is worth the price of admission and it one of utter majesty. One plane was the one used in the true story behind the work. As usual, I am not up to doing this fine work credit that it earns. I want to own a copy of it. I rate it ten because I judge films on their individual merits, not necessarily in comparison with other works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to make your dreams soar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandol70
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is already written a lot about the story of Fly Away Home, so I'm not going to repeat my previous reviewers. I have watched the movie for the first time on German TV in 1998, by chance I zapped into the movie and stayed there, mesmerized, fascinated, enchanted by its magical richness of animal (goose) beauty and lush landscape cinematography. When the film ended, I had a lump of emotion in my throat for several days. Something changed deep inside of me, namely the perception of nature, animals, birds, specifically of wild geese. Something made click inside my mind, and since then I adore geese very deeply. Before the movie, geese were of no special interest to me, oh how ignorant I was! As a matter of fact, my love is so deep and the movie inspires me so much that I want get my own geese. Fly Away home's cinematography and script is performed what I can describe as silent, calm, quiet and serene, but never lengthy; is performed suspense-packed, but never thriller-like. Romantic, but never corny or clich&eacute;. Close to life itself and nature, but never overcharged with exaggerated eco-messages. In short, a perfect mixture of all the elements that make a movie worthwhile. The landscape shots are very idyllic (Oscar nomination on this movie for cinematography) and you begin to long and crave for a life on the country-side, away from it all, the boisterous cities and its citizens with their insignificant problems of their everyday lives. When Amy is flying in her ultralight airplane, leading the flock of geese as their surrogate mother, then you can see that the problems on land, down there, are small and trivial. That is where the geese show us how life is meant to be, more simple, more straight-forward, and peaceful. Brilliant. And the film music, the fantastic movie score composed by Mark Isham, transports all the previous mentioned qualities and features in a perfect manner. The introductory song, 10,000 Miles by Mary Chapin Carpenter and co-composed by Mark Isham, is a real tearjerker of the special kind. This song alone summarizes what this movie is all about. Love, friendship, a deep bond among humans and animals, care for nature, peace, freedom and to never give up no matter what. The track expresses Amy's love to her family, and at the same time, the love between Amy and the wild geese. I cannot watch the movie without a package of Kleenex, and I'm male and an adult, a child at heart. I believe everyone has this ability, we just have to show it more often, and this movie can help to release the inner child in all of us. There is no lukewarm love story in Fly Away Home which is a big plus, if at all, it's only presented very subtle and unobtrusive. There have to be more movies like this to prevent a shallow development in our society, but I digress. The main focus of attention is clearly on the geese, who out-act all human actors with feathery ease. Bravo! Please, more movies like this! There are, to my knowledge, only a handful of movies where script, cinematography, directing, music, dialogs and actors come together and are mixed in this perfection. I can only recommend this movie to anyone who still believes in his or her dreams and wants to realize them. This movie supports you there and makes your imaginations soar, literally. As for my part, I'm checking out where I can get geese and how I have to keep them and gain their amazing friendship, deep bond and love. One of the most fascinating movies Hollywood has ever done, Oscar-nominated, and rightly so. Big kudos. Seal of approval: Highly recommended!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    budoinst@aol.com
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How anyone cannot like and appreciate this movie is beyond me. It has an incredible background in fact and is a moving tribute to the human spirit. It also strongly shows that all is not completely lost in the human race and that there is care among us and our fellow beings. What an inspiring movie and so well filmed and documented. Each time it is on, I watch it without fail. So nice to see true human caring and responsibility to all things. We can all learn something from the unwavering focus and support from so many people in overcoming the charge and many times unnecessary destruction of what is left of our former world and mostly in the name of greed and money. It is so nice to see greed being beaten back! We all can learn from this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quiet days and adventure stories
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home begins on a quiet note. A car driving in the rain, mother and daughter exchanging glances. The focus goes from the windscreen to the road, and back again. Suddenly and surprisingly, violence strikes. This introduces a common theme in children's adventure stories - the loss of one or both parents. It's the very same device that Ballard used in his first film, The Black Stallion, and would use once again in Duma. He's placed no inherent value in it as a plot device, however, stating that "If you're going to have a parent die, that has to be the emotional core of the movie". And that's just what it is in this case. Amy (Anna Paquin) doesn't walk off to have fun with the animals simply forgetting her past. But, in a way, this makes the focus less on nature and more on the characters, which I'm not entirely certain was Ballard's original intention. After all, his first two pictures featured next to no human interaction, and this very thing was what made the production of "Wind" so bothersome for him. After watching Fly Away Home for the first time in nearly ten years, I was struck by its high dramatic quality. Just a week earlier, I had watched another, inferior animal film (also starring Jeff Daniels) called "Because of Winn-Dixie". I realized then just how hard it is to strike a balance between what is 'cute' and what is real. The aforementioned film dove headlong into the 'cute' side of things. At the sake of becoming too academic, this is one of the most beautiful films I have ever seen. Caleb Deschanel's photography is effortless in appearance, giving the sensation of weightlessness far more often than in the actual flight sequences. Carroll Ballard has had great success in choosing the best people to photograph his films, and this is a great reunion for the two since their last collaboration on The Black Stallion. Mark Isham takes a totally different approach from his stunning minimalist score of Never Cry Wolf, reaching for - and sometimes - tugging at your heartstrings. In fact, the music is really quite spectacular throughout, except for a rather long and out of place interlude to "10,000 Miles" by Mary Chapin Carpenter. This would have been better suited earlier in the flight, it's current placement feeling a little off. It seems reminiscent of Linda Ronstadt's song "Winter Light" in a 1993 version of "The Secret Garden" (That film, by the way, I highly recommend for fans of Carroll Ballard). As this film progresses, it moves beyond the relationship aspect as Amy makes a discovery in the forest - geese eggs. In a way, her rescuing and raising of these orphaned chicks helps her to heal from her own loss. At its heart, this film is about loss and rebirth. This takes the story of Fly Away Home into new territory, less about the human aspect, and more about nature. All the supporting cast is good and effective (especially Terry Kinney), but Jeff Daniels and Anna Paquin are the central dramatic point which the other actors center around. I've never seen a more lively or energetic performance by Daniels - it's the sort of role he's always excelled at. Paquin, on the other hand, is in a rather uncommon role for her, a simple, more unrestrained character. Without her, or another exactly suited child (of which I know none), the film's dramatic half would have collapsed in on itself. But for all the geese, the drama and the cinematography, it's the moments of quiet that stand out. As the film comes to a close, there are certain factors that bring in a lack of realism. The human and media response to the flight south seems as if borrowed from another film. This perhaps brings the story to a bit of an anti-climax. The 'evil corporate developer' subplot seems lifted from other, less imaginative films. Regardless of the slightly weak ending, perhaps no other conclusion would work better, not without a significantly longer running time. It's a delicately balanced film, and I greatly respect its director for that. There's no immature jokes, no animals being too cute, or overwrought melodrama. For the most part, it feels natural, and the characters act like real people. I appreciate that in a youth-oriented film. I've long since grown out of other movies such as Free Willy, but this film has stuck with me since childhood - and I appreciate it more now than when I first saw it as a kid myself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Timeless Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brown-faith922
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fly Away Home" has been a favorite in my family for years. The story is classic, with every element of a film that is sure to last. The movie gives a vivid and often raw presentation of the relationships within a family, particularly between estranged members, and raises interesting questions about what family itself is and what it means. The view is utterly breathtaking as we're taken on a flight through the Canadian skies, following both the physical and emotional journey of Amy and her father. The father-daughter relationship, in any context, is often a touchy subject, and many films have a tendency to overdramatize certain elements of such a relationship. While the drama is certainly here with this one, we see less of the verbal, noisy drama than we do the quiet, awkward, tense, and somewhat snippy sentiments which exist between the two. Anna Paquin is flawless. Jeff Daniels will make you laugh, cry, and applaud. The chemistry between these two actors is beautiful, making this film one of the first and only that I have ever seen that has not made me despise the "rebellious daughter" figure. If this movie has a flaw, it is only that it is a bit slow by times. Still, for those who, like me, don't mind those sweepingly beautiful images of Canadian landscape, even if nothing much is happening... you'll enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattkratz (themattk@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a great movie about courage, overcoming tragedy, and leadership. After her mother is killed in a car accident, Anna Paquin moves to Canada with her father (Jeff Daniels) after he comes to pick her up. They discover a nestful of baby geese (newly hatched!) whose mother has just died too, and they have to learn how to fly. Unfortunately, they can't learn without example, and she has to be that example. She does so by building model airplanes which she flies. She makes news by showing them the way south. I loved the aerial scenes (which were beautifully shot) and the scene where the daughter was horrified when the guy wanted to clip the chicks' wings. Everybody matures and serves as "parent figures" in the process. This was a throughly enjoyable movie and great "family fare." You will love it-guaranteed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incredibly disappointing and extremely overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BelmaresJodene
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film a few months ago and I did not like it. Where do i start the storyline is just about as dull as you can get. The only thing that saved this from getting a one was the fairly good acting. The story is simple a teenage girl loses her mother in a car crash, she goes to the hospital and is picked up by her estranged father. then she tries to isolate from the rest of the world but what really made me mad about this movie is how bratty, rude annoying and stuck up she was, and the whole geese thing was way overdone. Another thing that annoyed me was that stupid little chant she kept on doing. She also was not very bright she refused to go to school she flew some kind of glider even though she knew she could not fly it. If you are looking for a movie to watch I strongly suggest you stay away from this one. final evaluation 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, Funny, Human
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    contact-951-691937
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, another excellent family film that has received low ratings from many reviewers here - I just don't get it. Fly Away Home is a beautiful story, filled with realistic emotion and incredible views of Canada and the geese. Jeff Daniel's portrayal of the eccentric father is smooth and realistic to the point that you might feel like you could run into him during a drive in the country. Anna Paquin tugs at your heartstrings and our family was cheering her on throughout the movie. Fly Away Home is a wholesome and entertaining family experience that we have watched several times - this says a lot since we rarely all agree on viewing the same film together twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Loved It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Ritter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There aren't that many movies that are well-written, well-directed, that have beautiful scenery and a heart touching story, but this is certainly one of them. This movie is well worth the time it takes to watch it. In fact, we seem to rent it about every two or three years so we can view it again and will probably end up purchasing it, which we seldom do. I just can't say enough for this film. Whatever you do, watch it all the way to the end. Very worthwhile for families or anyone who appreciates nature and a great movie. One of the other things we really liked about the film was the fact that we live about a half mile away from one of the locations where it was filmed just outside of Niagara Falls, NY. That made it more personal for us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Personal and Sentimental Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home is a family oriented, emotionally charged drama in which a young girl's mental recovery from her Mother's death is achieved by a monumental feat. Thrust into her Father Tom's world of inventions and experiments, Amy is lost and uncomfortable in this new environment along with still being vulnerable from her Mother's death, shown in her anxious reactions watching Tom try out his latest invention. Yet it is an aspect of Tom's life that Amy soon finds herself in after discovering Geese eggs, once they hatch Amy is lead down a memorable path of courage and bonding. As Amy begins to raise the Geese as her own Fly Away Home becomes an incredibility touching story where it is hard not to want Amy achieve the goal of getting the Geese to migrate south. Fly Away Home succeeds on an emotional scale in placing the viewer into the predicament Amy faces and the love she feels for the Geese. The cinematography is an additional factor to the heart - tugging vibe, watching the Geese eggs hatch and crawl out of their shells with crystal clear precision as if we are witnessing the birth in person is extraordinary to see and sentimental to feel as they are just as vulnerable as Amy. This sense of vulnerability makes the aerial shots of Amy and Tom leading the Geese to their rightful place in nature later on all the more powerful. It coincides with the soundtrack in relation to Fly Away Home's poignancy, with the use of the song '10, 000 Miles' towards the end of the climatic scene which had been the show piece of the opening credits depicting the death of Amy's Mother increases the atmosphere to the status of a tear jerker, bringing home how much Amy has achieved. However there are some clich&eacute;s which slightly spoil the experience. Having corporate bosses as antagonists is nothing new and tense moments made to briefly unease the audience most notably when Air Traffic Control are about to send out a war plane on Amy, Tom and the Geese when they are seen as a UFO comes across respectively as platitude and ridiculous. But these are only minor flaws in a film whose good heartedness paves these criticisms over. So if you enjoy story lines with a feel - good vibe and the old fashioned good triumphing over evil, Fly Away Home should be one for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Treat Yourself to a Sense of Joy and Wonder. Great Family Film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TedMichaelMor
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sctmpir's review nails this film, which celebrates a young female character with immense richness, complexity even, and grace. I think that the treatment of women in this work is among the most finely nuanced and intelligent I have ever seen in any film. Carroll Ballard, who directed the gracious and almost unbearably beautiful "Wind" as well as "The Black Stallion", "Duma", and "Never Cry Wolf"--all films that have an almost sentimental tone but a tone really closer to romantic in the classic Victorian sense of awe and wonder at life itselfcontrols every aspect of the narrative. This film might seem close to but is never saccharine. It is about wonder in the sense of awe. Anna Paquin exhibits brilliance as an adolescent actor that overwhelms me, in part, because there is never anything trite or coquettish that often mares the role many fine young actresses play. The role here required immense transparency, poise, and nuance. Dana Delaney has the same poise, apparent simplicity, attention to nuance and understatement as Ms. Paquin. No actor is better than Jeff Daniels is when he expresses understatement and subtlyremember him, for example, in "Pleasantville" and "Purple Rose of Cairo". Tim Kerry is a great boon to the film but everyone seems outstanding to me. Caleb Deschane is a master of magic hour cinematography, which works exceptionally well here. He did, for example, "The Right Stuff" with Philip Kaufman directing, "The Passion of the Christ" with Mel Gibson directing, "A Woman Under the Influence" with John Cassavetes, and "Being There" with Hal Ashby. He also directed the thoughtful film "Caruso". The attention to detail in this movie amazes me. There is not a bad frame anywhere in the film. That, of course, is in part the work of the editor Nicholas Smith. Music by Mark Isham is a tad dramatic but still lovely. Mr. Isham is one of the most productive of film composers. And the airplanes are terrific. The aerial images alone overwhelm me and recall the imagery from "Wind", one of my favourite action films. The flight though Baltimore alone is worth the price of admission and it one of utter majesty. One plane was the one used in the true story behind the work. As usual, I am not up to doing this fine work credit that it earns. I want to own a copy of it. I rate it ten because I judge films on their individual merits, not necessarily in comparison with other works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to make your dreams soar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandol70
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is already written a lot about the story of Fly Away Home, so I'm not going to repeat my previous reviewers. I have watched the movie for the first time on German TV in 1998, by chance I zapped into the movie and stayed there, mesmerized, fascinated, enchanted by its magical richness of animal (goose) beauty and lush landscape cinematography. When the film ended, I had a lump of emotion in my throat for several days. Something changed deep inside of me, namely the perception of nature, animals, birds, specifically of wild geese. Something made click inside my mind, and since then I adore geese very deeply. Before the movie, geese were of no special interest to me, oh how ignorant I was! As a matter of fact, my love is so deep and the movie inspires me so much that I want get my own geese. Fly Away home's cinematography and script is performed what I can describe as silent, calm, quiet and serene, but never lengthy; is performed suspense-packed, but never thriller-like. Romantic, but never corny or clich&eacute;. Close to life itself and nature, but never overcharged with exaggerated eco-messages. In short, a perfect mixture of all the elements that make a movie worthwhile. The landscape shots are very idyllic (Oscar nomination on this movie for cinematography) and you begin to long and crave for a life on the country-side, away from it all, the boisterous cities and its citizens with their insignificant problems of their everyday lives. When Amy is flying in her ultralight airplane, leading the flock of geese as their surrogate mother, then you can see that the problems on land, down there, are small and trivial. That is where the geese show us how life is meant to be, more simple, more straight-forward, and peaceful. Brilliant. And the film music, the fantastic movie score composed by Mark Isham, transports all the previous mentioned qualities and features in a perfect manner. The introductory song, 10,000 Miles by Mary Chapin Carpenter and co-composed by Mark Isham, is a real tearjerker of the special kind. This song alone summarizes what this movie is all about. Love, friendship, a deep bond among humans and animals, care for nature, peace, freedom and to never give up no matter what. The track expresses Amy's love to her family, and at the same time, the love between Amy and the wild geese. I cannot watch the movie without a package of Kleenex, and I'm male and an adult, a child at heart. I believe everyone has this ability, we just have to show it more often, and this movie can help to release the inner child in all of us. There is no lukewarm love story in Fly Away Home which is a big plus, if at all, it's only presented very subtle and unobtrusive. There have to be more movies like this to prevent a shallow development in our society, but I digress. The main focus of attention is clearly on the geese, who out-act all human actors with feathery ease. Bravo! Please, more movies like this! There are, to my knowledge, only a handful of movies where script, cinematography, directing, music, dialogs and actors come together and are mixed in this perfection. I can only recommend this movie to anyone who still believes in his or her dreams and wants to realize them. This movie supports you there and makes your imaginations soar, literally. As for my part, I'm checking out where I can get geese and how I have to keep them and gain their amazing friendship, deep bond and love. One of the most fascinating movies Hollywood has ever done, Oscar-nominated, and rightly so. Big kudos. Seal of approval: Highly recommended!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    budoinst@aol.com
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How anyone cannot like and appreciate this movie is beyond me. It has an incredible background in fact and is a moving tribute to the human spirit. It also strongly shows that all is not completely lost in the human race and that there is care among us and our fellow beings. What an inspiring movie and so well filmed and documented. Each time it is on, I watch it without fail. So nice to see true human caring and responsibility to all things. We can all learn something from the unwavering focus and support from so many people in overcoming the charge and many times unnecessary destruction of what is left of our former world and mostly in the name of greed and money. It is so nice to see greed being beaten back! We all can learn from this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quiet days and adventure stories
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home begins on a quiet note. A car driving in the rain, mother and daughter exchanging glances. The focus goes from the windscreen to the road, and back again. Suddenly and surprisingly, violence strikes. This introduces a common theme in children's adventure stories - the loss of one or both parents. It's the very same device that Ballard used in his first film, The Black Stallion, and would use once again in Duma. He's placed no inherent value in it as a plot device, however, stating that "If you're going to have a parent die, that has to be the emotional core of the movie". And that's just what it is in this case. Amy (Anna Paquin) doesn't walk off to have fun with the animals simply forgetting her past. But, in a way, this makes the focus less on nature and more on the characters, which I'm not entirely certain was Ballard's original intention. After all, his first two pictures featured next to no human interaction, and this very thing was what made the production of "Wind" so bothersome for him. After watching Fly Away Home for the first time in nearly ten years, I was struck by its high dramatic quality. Just a week earlier, I had watched another, inferior animal film (also starring Jeff Daniels) called "Because of Winn-Dixie". I realized then just how hard it is to strike a balance between what is 'cute' and what is real. The aforementioned film dove headlong into the 'cute' side of things. At the sake of becoming too academic, this is one of the most beautiful films I have ever seen. Caleb Deschanel's photography is effortless in appearance, giving the sensation of weightlessness far more often than in the actual flight sequences. Carroll Ballard has had great success in choosing the best people to photograph his films, and this is a great reunion for the two since their last collaboration on The Black Stallion. Mark Isham takes a totally different approach from his stunning minimalist score of Never Cry Wolf, reaching for - and sometimes - tugging at your heartstrings. In fact, the music is really quite spectacular throughout, except for a rather long and out of place interlude to "10,000 Miles" by Mary Chapin Carpenter. This would have been better suited earlier in the flight, it's current placement feeling a little off. It seems reminiscent of Linda Ronstadt's song "Winter Light" in a 1993 version of "The Secret Garden" (That film, by the way, I highly recommend for fans of Carroll Ballard). As this film progresses, it moves beyond the relationship aspect as Amy makes a discovery in the forest - geese eggs. In a way, her rescuing and raising of these orphaned chicks helps her to heal from her own loss. At its heart, this film is about loss and rebirth. This takes the story of Fly Away Home into new territory, less about the human aspect, and more about nature. All the supporting cast is good and effective (especially Terry Kinney), but Jeff Daniels and Anna Paquin are the central dramatic point which the other actors center around. I've never seen a more lively or energetic performance by Daniels - it's the sort of role he's always excelled at. Paquin, on the other hand, is in a rather uncommon role for her, a simple, more unrestrained character. Without her, or another exactly suited child (of which I know none), the film's dramatic half would have collapsed in on itself. But for all the geese, the drama and the cinematography, it's the moments of quiet that stand out. As the film comes to a close, there are certain factors that bring in a lack of realism. The human and media response to the flight south seems as if borrowed from another film. This perhaps brings the story to a bit of an anti-climax. The 'evil corporate developer' subplot seems lifted from other, less imaginative films. Regardless of the slightly weak ending, perhaps no other conclusion would work better, not without a significantly longer running time. It's a delicately balanced film, and I greatly respect its director for that. There's no immature jokes, no animals being too cute, or overwrought melodrama. For the most part, it feels natural, and the characters act like real people. I appreciate that in a youth-oriented film. I've long since grown out of other movies such as Free Willy, but this film has stuck with me since childhood - and I appreciate it more now than when I first saw it as a kid myself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Timeless Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brown-faith922
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fly Away Home" has been a favorite in my family for years. The story is classic, with every element of a film that is sure to last. The movie gives a vivid and often raw presentation of the relationships within a family, particularly between estranged members, and raises interesting questions about what family itself is and what it means. The view is utterly breathtaking as we're taken on a flight through the Canadian skies, following both the physical and emotional journey of Amy and her father. The father-daughter relationship, in any context, is often a touchy subject, and many films have a tendency to overdramatize certain elements of such a relationship. While the drama is certainly here with this one, we see less of the verbal, noisy drama than we do the quiet, awkward, tense, and somewhat snippy sentiments which exist between the two. Anna Paquin is flawless. Jeff Daniels will make you laugh, cry, and applaud. The chemistry between these two actors is beautiful, making this film one of the first and only that I have ever seen that has not made me despise the "rebellious daughter" figure. If this movie has a flaw, it is only that it is a bit slow by times. Still, for those who, like me, don't mind those sweepingly beautiful images of Canadian landscape, even if nothing much is happening... you'll enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattkratz (themattk@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a great movie about courage, overcoming tragedy, and leadership. After her mother is killed in a car accident, Anna Paquin moves to Canada with her father (Jeff Daniels) after he comes to pick her up. They discover a nestful of baby geese (newly hatched!) whose mother has just died too, and they have to learn how to fly. Unfortunately, they can't learn without example, and she has to be that example. She does so by building model airplanes which she flies. She makes news by showing them the way south. I loved the aerial scenes (which were beautifully shot) and the scene where the daughter was horrified when the guy wanted to clip the chicks' wings. Everybody matures and serves as "parent figures" in the process. This was a throughly enjoyable movie and great "family fare." You will love it-guaranteed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incredibly disappointing and extremely overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BelmaresJodene
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film a few months ago and I did not like it. Where do i start the storyline is just about as dull as you can get. The only thing that saved this from getting a one was the fairly good acting. The story is simple a teenage girl loses her mother in a car crash, she goes to the hospital and is picked up by her estranged father. then she tries to isolate from the rest of the world but what really made me mad about this movie is how bratty, rude annoying and stuck up she was, and the whole geese thing was way overdone. Another thing that annoyed me was that stupid little chant she kept on doing. She also was not very bright she refused to go to school she flew some kind of glider even though she knew she could not fly it. If you are looking for a movie to watch I strongly suggest you stay away from this one. final evaluation 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, Funny, Human
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    contact-951-691937
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, another excellent family film that has received low ratings from many reviewers here - I just don't get it. Fly Away Home is a beautiful story, filled with realistic emotion and incredible views of Canada and the geese. Jeff Daniel's portrayal of the eccentric father is smooth and realistic to the point that you might feel like you could run into him during a drive in the country. Anna Paquin tugs at your heartstrings and our family was cheering her on throughout the movie. Fly Away Home is a wholesome and entertaining family experience that we have watched several times - this says a lot since we rarely all agree on viewing the same film together twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Loved It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Ritter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There aren't that many movies that are well-written, well-directed, that have beautiful scenery and a heart touching story, but this is certainly one of them. This movie is well worth the time it takes to watch it. In fact, we seem to rent it about every two or three years so we can view it again and will probably end up purchasing it, which we seldom do. I just can't say enough for this film. Whatever you do, watch it all the way to the end. Very worthwhile for families or anyone who appreciates nature and a great movie. One of the other things we really liked about the film was the fact that we live about a half mile away from one of the locations where it was filmed just outside of Niagara Falls, NY. That made it more personal for us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Personal and Sentimental Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home is a family oriented, emotionally charged drama in which a young girl's mental recovery from her Mother's death is achieved by a monumental feat. Thrust into her Father Tom's world of inventions and experiments, Amy is lost and uncomfortable in this new environment along with still being vulnerable from her Mother's death, shown in her anxious reactions watching Tom try out his latest invention. Yet it is an aspect of Tom's life that Amy soon finds herself in after discovering Geese eggs, once they hatch Amy is lead down a memorable path of courage and bonding. As Amy begins to raise the Geese as her own Fly Away Home becomes an incredibility touching story where it is hard not to want Amy achieve the goal of getting the Geese to migrate south. Fly Away Home succeeds on an emotional scale in placing the viewer into the predicament Amy faces and the love she feels for the Geese. The cinematography is an additional factor to the heart - tugging vibe, watching the Geese eggs hatch and crawl out of their shells with crystal clear precision as if we are witnessing the birth in person is extraordinary to see and sentimental to feel as they are just as vulnerable as Amy. This sense of vulnerability makes the aerial shots of Amy and Tom leading the Geese to their rightful place in nature later on all the more powerful. It coincides with the soundtrack in relation to Fly Away Home's poignancy, with the use of the song '10, 000 Miles' towards the end of the climatic scene which had been the show piece of the opening credits depicting the death of Amy's Mother increases the atmosphere to the status of a tear jerker, bringing home how much Amy has achieved. However there are some clich&eacute;s which slightly spoil the experience. Having corporate bosses as antagonists is nothing new and tense moments made to briefly unease the audience most notably when Air Traffic Control are about to send out a war plane on Amy, Tom and the Geese when they are seen as a UFO comes across respectively as platitude and ridiculous. But these are only minor flaws in a film whose good heartedness paves these criticisms over. So if you enjoy story lines with a feel - good vibe and the old fashioned good triumphing over evil, Fly Away Home should be one for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Treat Yourself to a Sense of Joy and Wonder. Great Family Film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TedMichaelMor
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sctmpir's review nails this film, which celebrates a young female character with immense richness, complexity even, and grace. I think that the treatment of women in this work is among the most finely nuanced and intelligent I have ever seen in any film. Carroll Ballard, who directed the gracious and almost unbearably beautiful "Wind" as well as "The Black Stallion", "Duma", and "Never Cry Wolf"--all films that have an almost sentimental tone but a tone really closer to romantic in the classic Victorian sense of awe and wonder at life itselfcontrols every aspect of the narrative. This film might seem close to but is never saccharine. It is about wonder in the sense of awe. Anna Paquin exhibits brilliance as an adolescent actor that overwhelms me, in part, because there is never anything trite or coquettish that often mares the role many fine young actresses play. The role here required immense transparency, poise, and nuance. Dana Delaney has the same poise, apparent simplicity, attention to nuance and understatement as Ms. Paquin. No actor is better than Jeff Daniels is when he expresses understatement and subtlyremember him, for example, in "Pleasantville" and "Purple Rose of Cairo". Tim Kerry is a great boon to the film but everyone seems outstanding to me. Caleb Deschane is a master of magic hour cinematography, which works exceptionally well here. He did, for example, "The Right Stuff" with Philip Kaufman directing, "The Passion of the Christ" with Mel Gibson directing, "A Woman Under the Influence" with John Cassavetes, and "Being There" with Hal Ashby. He also directed the thoughtful film "Caruso". The attention to detail in this movie amazes me. There is not a bad frame anywhere in the film. That, of course, is in part the work of the editor Nicholas Smith. Music by Mark Isham is a tad dramatic but still lovely. Mr. Isham is one of the most productive of film composers. And the airplanes are terrific. The aerial images alone overwhelm me and recall the imagery from "Wind", one of my favourite action films. The flight though Baltimore alone is worth the price of admission and it one of utter majesty. One plane was the one used in the true story behind the work. As usual, I am not up to doing this fine work credit that it earns. I want to own a copy of it. I rate it ten because I judge films on their individual merits, not necessarily in comparison with other works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to make your dreams soar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandol70
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is already written a lot about the story of Fly Away Home, so I'm not going to repeat my previous reviewers. I have watched the movie for the first time on German TV in 1998, by chance I zapped into the movie and stayed there, mesmerized, fascinated, enchanted by its magical richness of animal (goose) beauty and lush landscape cinematography. When the film ended, I had a lump of emotion in my throat for several days. Something changed deep inside of me, namely the perception of nature, animals, birds, specifically of wild geese. Something made click inside my mind, and since then I adore geese very deeply. Before the movie, geese were of no special interest to me, oh how ignorant I was! As a matter of fact, my love is so deep and the movie inspires me so much that I want get my own geese. Fly Away home's cinematography and script is performed what I can describe as silent, calm, quiet and serene, but never lengthy; is performed suspense-packed, but never thriller-like. Romantic, but never corny or clich&eacute;. Close to life itself and nature, but never overcharged with exaggerated eco-messages. In short, a perfect mixture of all the elements that make a movie worthwhile. The landscape shots are very idyllic (Oscar nomination on this movie for cinematography) and you begin to long and crave for a life on the country-side, away from it all, the boisterous cities and its citizens with their insignificant problems of their everyday lives. When Amy is flying in her ultralight airplane, leading the flock of geese as their surrogate mother, then you can see that the problems on land, down there, are small and trivial. That is where the geese show us how life is meant to be, more simple, more straight-forward, and peaceful. Brilliant. And the film music, the fantastic movie score composed by Mark Isham, transports all the previous mentioned qualities and features in a perfect manner. The introductory song, 10,000 Miles by Mary Chapin Carpenter and co-composed by Mark Isham, is a real tearjerker of the special kind. This song alone summarizes what this movie is all about. Love, friendship, a deep bond among humans and animals, care for nature, peace, freedom and to never give up no matter what. The track expresses Amy's love to her family, and at the same time, the love between Amy and the wild geese. I cannot watch the movie without a package of Kleenex, and I'm male and an adult, a child at heart. I believe everyone has this ability, we just have to show it more often, and this movie can help to release the inner child in all of us. There is no lukewarm love story in Fly Away Home which is a big plus, if at all, it's only presented very subtle and unobtrusive. There have to be more movies like this to prevent a shallow development in our society, but I digress. The main focus of attention is clearly on the geese, who out-act all human actors with feathery ease. Bravo! Please, more movies like this! There are, to my knowledge, only a handful of movies where script, cinematography, directing, music, dialogs and actors come together and are mixed in this perfection. I can only recommend this movie to anyone who still believes in his or her dreams and wants to realize them. This movie supports you there and makes your imaginations soar, literally. As for my part, I'm checking out where I can get geese and how I have to keep them and gain their amazing friendship, deep bond and love. One of the most fascinating movies Hollywood has ever done, Oscar-nominated, and rightly so. Big kudos. Seal of approval: Highly recommended!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    budoinst@aol.com
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How anyone cannot like and appreciate this movie is beyond me. It has an incredible background in fact and is a moving tribute to the human spirit. It also strongly shows that all is not completely lost in the human race and that there is care among us and our fellow beings. What an inspiring movie and so well filmed and documented. Each time it is on, I watch it without fail. So nice to see true human caring and responsibility to all things. We can all learn something from the unwavering focus and support from so many people in overcoming the charge and many times unnecessary destruction of what is left of our former world and mostly in the name of greed and money. It is so nice to see greed being beaten back! We all can learn from this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quiet days and adventure stories
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home begins on a quiet note. A car driving in the rain, mother and daughter exchanging glances. The focus goes from the windscreen to the road, and back again. Suddenly and surprisingly, violence strikes. This introduces a common theme in children's adventure stories - the loss of one or both parents. It's the very same device that Ballard used in his first film, The Black Stallion, and would use once again in Duma. He's placed no inherent value in it as a plot device, however, stating that "If you're going to have a parent die, that has to be the emotional core of the movie". And that's just what it is in this case. Amy (Anna Paquin) doesn't walk off to have fun with the animals simply forgetting her past. But, in a way, this makes the focus less on nature and more on the characters, which I'm not entirely certain was Ballard's original intention. After all, his first two pictures featured next to no human interaction, and this very thing was what made the production of "Wind" so bothersome for him. After watching Fly Away Home for the first time in nearly ten years, I was struck by its high dramatic quality. Just a week earlier, I had watched another, inferior animal film (also starring Jeff Daniels) called "Because of Winn-Dixie". I realized then just how hard it is to strike a balance between what is 'cute' and what is real. The aforementioned film dove headlong into the 'cute' side of things. At the sake of becoming too academic, this is one of the most beautiful films I have ever seen. Caleb Deschanel's photography is effortless in appearance, giving the sensation of weightlessness far more often than in the actual flight sequences. Carroll Ballard has had great success in choosing the best people to photograph his films, and this is a great reunion for the two since their last collaboration on The Black Stallion. Mark Isham takes a totally different approach from his stunning minimalist score of Never Cry Wolf, reaching for - and sometimes - tugging at your heartstrings. In fact, the music is really quite spectacular throughout, except for a rather long and out of place interlude to "10,000 Miles" by Mary Chapin Carpenter. This would have been better suited earlier in the flight, it's current placement feeling a little off. It seems reminiscent of Linda Ronstadt's song "Winter Light" in a 1993 version of "The Secret Garden" (That film, by the way, I highly recommend for fans of Carroll Ballard). As this film progresses, it moves beyond the relationship aspect as Amy makes a discovery in the forest - geese eggs. In a way, her rescuing and raising of these orphaned chicks helps her to heal from her own loss. At its heart, this film is about loss and rebirth. This takes the story of Fly Away Home into new territory, less about the human aspect, and more about nature. All the supporting cast is good and effective (especially Terry Kinney), but Jeff Daniels and Anna Paquin are the central dramatic point which the other actors center around. I've never seen a more lively or energetic performance by Daniels - it's the sort of role he's always excelled at. Paquin, on the other hand, is in a rather uncommon role for her, a simple, more unrestrained character. Without her, or another exactly suited child (of which I know none), the film's dramatic half would have collapsed in on itself. But for all the geese, the drama and the cinematography, it's the moments of quiet that stand out. As the film comes to a close, there are certain factors that bring in a lack of realism. The human and media response to the flight south seems as if borrowed from another film. This perhaps brings the story to a bit of an anti-climax. The 'evil corporate developer' subplot seems lifted from other, less imaginative films. Regardless of the slightly weak ending, perhaps no other conclusion would work better, not without a significantly longer running time. It's a delicately balanced film, and I greatly respect its director for that. There's no immature jokes, no animals being too cute, or overwrought melodrama. For the most part, it feels natural, and the characters act like real people. I appreciate that in a youth-oriented film. I've long since grown out of other movies such as Free Willy, but this film has stuck with me since childhood - and I appreciate it more now than when I first saw it as a kid myself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Timeless Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brown-faith922
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Fly Away Home" has been a favorite in my family for years. The story is classic, with every element of a film that is sure to last. The movie gives a vivid and often raw presentation of the relationships within a family, particularly between estranged members, and raises interesting questions about what family itself is and what it means. The view is utterly breathtaking as we're taken on a flight through the Canadian skies, following both the physical and emotional journey of Amy and her father. The father-daughter relationship, in any context, is often a touchy subject, and many films have a tendency to overdramatize certain elements of such a relationship. While the drama is certainly here with this one, we see less of the verbal, noisy drama than we do the quiet, awkward, tense, and somewhat snippy sentiments which exist between the two. Anna Paquin is flawless. Jeff Daniels will make you laugh, cry, and applaud. The chemistry between these two actors is beautiful, making this film one of the first and only that I have ever seen that has not made me despise the "rebellious daughter" figure. If this movie has a flaw, it is only that it is a bit slow by times. Still, for those who, like me, don't mind those sweepingly beautiful images of Canadian landscape, even if nothing much is happening... you'll enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattkratz (themattk@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a great movie about courage, overcoming tragedy, and leadership. After her mother is killed in a car accident, Anna Paquin moves to Canada with her father (Jeff Daniels) after he comes to pick her up. They discover a nestful of baby geese (newly hatched!) whose mother has just died too, and they have to learn how to fly. Unfortunately, they can't learn without example, and she has to be that example. She does so by building model airplanes which she flies. She makes news by showing them the way south. I loved the aerial scenes (which were beautifully shot) and the scene where the daughter was horrified when the guy wanted to clip the chicks' wings. Everybody matures and serves as "parent figures" in the process. This was a throughly enjoyable movie and great "family fare." You will love it-guaranteed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incredibly disappointing and extremely overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BelmaresJodene
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film a few months ago and I did not like it. Where do i start the storyline is just about as dull as you can get. The only thing that saved this from getting a one was the fairly good acting. The story is simple a teenage girl loses her mother in a car crash, she goes to the hospital and is picked up by her estranged father. then she tries to isolate from the rest of the world but what really made me mad about this movie is how bratty, rude annoying and stuck up she was, and the whole geese thing was way overdone. Another thing that annoyed me was that stupid little chant she kept on doing. She also was not very bright she refused to go to school she flew some kind of glider even though she knew she could not fly it. If you are looking for a movie to watch I strongly suggest you stay away from this one. final evaluation 3/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, Funny, Human
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    contact-951-691937
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, another excellent family film that has received low ratings from many reviewers here - I just don't get it. Fly Away Home is a beautiful story, filled with realistic emotion and incredible views of Canada and the geese. Jeff Daniel's portrayal of the eccentric father is smooth and realistic to the point that you might feel like you could run into him during a drive in the country. Anna Paquin tugs at your heartstrings and our family was cheering her on throughout the movie. Fly Away Home is a wholesome and entertaining family experience that we have watched several times - this says a lot since we rarely all agree on viewing the same film together twice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just Loved It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Ritter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There aren't that many movies that are well-written, well-directed, that have beautiful scenery and a heart touching story, but this is certainly one of them. This movie is well worth the time it takes to watch it. In fact, we seem to rent it about every two or three years so we can view it again and will probably end up purchasing it, which we seldom do. I just can't say enough for this film. Whatever you do, watch it all the way to the end. Very worthwhile for families or anyone who appreciates nature and a great movie. One of the other things we really liked about the film was the fact that we live about a half mile away from one of the locations where it was filmed just outside of Niagara Falls, NY. That made it more personal for us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Personal and Sentimental Tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home is a family oriented, emotionally charged drama in which a young girl's mental recovery from her Mother's death is achieved by a monumental feat. Thrust into her Father Tom's world of inventions and experiments, Amy is lost and uncomfortable in this new environment along with still being vulnerable from her Mother's death, shown in her anxious reactions watching Tom try out his latest invention. Yet it is an aspect of Tom's life that Amy soon finds herself in after discovering Geese eggs, once they hatch Amy is lead down a memorable path of courage and bonding. As Amy begins to raise the Geese as her own Fly Away Home becomes an incredibility touching story where it is hard not to want Amy achieve the goal of getting the Geese to migrate south. Fly Away Home succeeds on an emotional scale in placing the viewer into the predicament Amy faces and the love she feels for the Geese. The cinematography is an additional factor to the heart - tugging vibe, watching the Geese eggs hatch and crawl out of their shells with crystal clear precision as if we are witnessing the birth in person is extraordinary to see and sentimental to feel as they are just as vulnerable as Amy. This sense of vulnerability makes the aerial shots of Amy and Tom leading the Geese to their rightful place in nature later on all the more powerful. It coincides with the soundtrack in relation to Fly Away Home's poignancy, with the use of the song '10, 000 Miles' towards the end of the climatic scene which had been the show piece of the opening credits depicting the death of Amy's Mother increases the atmosphere to the status of a tear jerker, bringing home how much Amy has achieved. However there are some clich&eacute;s which slightly spoil the experience. Having corporate bosses as antagonists is nothing new and tense moments made to briefly unease the audience most notably when Air Traffic Control are about to send out a war plane on Amy, Tom and the Geese when they are seen as a UFO comes across respectively as platitude and ridiculous. But these are only minor flaws in a film whose good heartedness paves these criticisms over. So if you enjoy story lines with a feel - good vibe and the old fashioned good triumphing over evil, Fly Away Home should be one for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Treat Yourself to a Sense of Joy and Wonder. Great Family Film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TedMichaelMor
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sctmpir's review nails this film, which celebrates a young female character with immense richness, complexity even, and grace. I think that the treatment of women in this work is among the most finely nuanced and intelligent I have ever seen in any film. Carroll Ballard, who directed the gracious and almost unbearably beautiful "Wind" as well as "The Black Stallion", "Duma", and "Never Cry Wolf"--all films that have an almost sentimental tone but a tone really closer to romantic in the classic Victorian sense of awe and wonder at life itselfcontrols every aspect of the narrative. This film might seem close to but is never saccharine. It is about wonder in the sense of awe. Anna Paquin exhibits brilliance as an adolescent actor that overwhelms me, in part, because there is never anything trite or coquettish that often mares the role many fine young actresses play. The role here required immense transparency, poise, and nuance. Dana Delaney has the same poise, apparent simplicity, attention to nuance and understatement as Ms. Paquin. No actor is better than Jeff Daniels is when he expresses understatement and subtlyremember him, for example, in "Pleasantville" and "Purple Rose of Cairo". Tim Kerry is a great boon to the film but everyone seems outstanding to me. Caleb Deschane is a master of magic hour cinematography, which works exceptionally well here. He did, for example, "The Right Stuff" with Philip Kaufman directing, "The Passion of the Christ" with Mel Gibson directing, "A Woman Under the Influence" with John Cassavetes, and "Being There" with Hal Ashby. He also directed the thoughtful film "Caruso". The attention to detail in this movie amazes me. There is not a bad frame anywhere in the film. That, of course, is in part the work of the editor Nicholas Smith. Music by Mark Isham is a tad dramatic but still lovely. Mr. Isham is one of the most productive of film composers. And the airplanes are terrific. The aerial images alone overwhelm me and recall the imagery from "Wind", one of my favourite action films. The flight though Baltimore alone is worth the price of admission and it one of utter majesty. One plane was the one used in the true story behind the work. As usual, I am not up to doing this fine work credit that it earns. I want to own a copy of it. I rate it ten because I judge films on their individual merits, not necessarily in comparison with other works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to make your dreams soar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandol70
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is already written a lot about the story of Fly Away Home, so I'm not going to repeat my previous reviewers. I have watched the movie for the first time on German TV in 1998, by chance I zapped into the movie and stayed there, mesmerized, fascinated, enchanted by its magical richness of animal (goose) beauty and lush landscape cinematography. When the film ended, I had a lump of emotion in my throat for several days. Something changed deep inside of me, namely the perception of nature, animals, birds, specifically of wild geese. Something made click inside my mind, and since then I adore geese very deeply. Before the movie, geese were of no special interest to me, oh how ignorant I was! As a matter of fact, my love is so deep and the movie inspires me so much that I want get my own geese. Fly Away home's cinematography and script is performed what I can describe as silent, calm, quiet and serene, but never lengthy; is performed suspense-packed, but never thriller-like. Romantic, but never corny or clich&eacute;. Close to life itself and nature, but never overcharged with exaggerated eco-messages. In short, a perfect mixture of all the elements that make a movie worthwhile. The landscape shots are very idyllic (Oscar nomination on this movie for cinematography) and you begin to long and crave for a life on the country-side, away from it all, the boisterous cities and its citizens with their insignificant problems of their everyday lives. When Amy is flying in her ultralight airplane, leading the flock of geese as their surrogate mother, then you can see that the problems on land, down there, are small and trivial. That is where the geese show us how life is meant to be, more simple, more straight-forward, and peaceful. Brilliant. And the film music, the fantastic movie score composed by Mark Isham, transports all the previous mentioned qualities and features in a perfect manner. The introductory song, 10,000 Miles by Mary Chapin Carpenter and co-composed by Mark Isham, is a real tearjerker of the special kind. This song alone summarizes what this movie is all about. Love, friendship, a deep bond among humans and animals, care for nature, peace, freedom and to never give up no matter what. The track expresses Amy's love to her family, and at the same time, the love between Amy and the wild geese. I cannot watch the movie without a package of Kleenex, and I'm male and an adult, a child at heart. I believe everyone has this ability, we just have to show it more often, and this movie can help to release the inner child in all of us. There is no lukewarm love story in Fly Away Home which is a big plus, if at all, it's only presented very subtle and unobtrusive. There have to be more movies like this to prevent a shallow development in our society, but I digress. The main focus of attention is clearly on the geese, who out-act all human actors with feathery ease. Bravo! Please, more movies like this! There are, to my knowledge, only a handful of movies where script, cinematography, directing, music, dialogs and actors come together and are mixed in this perfection. I can only recommend this movie to anyone who still believes in his or her dreams and wants to realize them. This movie supports you there and makes your imaginations soar, literally. As for my part, I'm checking out where I can get geese and how I have to keep them and gain their amazing friendship, deep bond and love. One of the most fascinating movies Hollywood has ever done, Oscar-nominated, and rightly so. Big kudos. Seal of approval: Highly recommended!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredible movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    budoinst@aol.com
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How anyone cannot like and appreciate this movie is beyond me. It has an incredible background in fact and is a moving tribute to the human spirit. It also strongly shows that all is not completely lost in the human race and that there is care among us and our fellow beings. What an inspiring movie and so well filmed and documented. Each time it is on, I watch it without fail. So nice to see true human caring and responsibility to all things. We can all learn something from the unwavering focus and support from so many people in overcoming the charge and many times unnecessary destruction of what is left of our former world and mostly in the name of greed and money. It is so nice to see greed being beaten back! We all can learn from this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quiet days and adventure stories
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Skafte
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fly Away Home begins on a quiet note. A car driving in the rain, mother and daughter exchanging glances. The focus goes from the windscreen to the road, and back again. Suddenly and surprisingly, violence strikes. This introduces a common theme in children's adventure stories - the loss of one or both parents. It's the very same device that Ballard used in his first film, The Black Stallion, and would use once again in Duma. He's placed no inherent value in it as a plot device, however, stating that "If you're going to have a parent die, that has to be the emotional core of the movie". And that's just what it is in this case. Amy (Anna Paquin) doesn't walk off to have fun with the animals simply forgetting her past. But, in a way, this makes the focus less on nature and more on the characters, which I'm not entirely certain was Ballard's original intention. After all, his first two pictures featured next to no human interaction, and this very thing was what made the production of "Wind" so bothersome for him. After watching Fly Away Home for the first time in nearly ten years, I was struck by its high dramatic quality. Just a week earlier, I had watched another, inferior animal film (also starring Jeff Daniels) called "Because of Winn-Dixie". I realized then just how hard it is to strike a balance between what is 'cute' and what is real. The aforementioned film dove headlong into the 'cute' side of things. At the sake of becoming too academic, this is one of the most beautiful films I have ever seen. Caleb Deschanel's photography is effortless in appearance, giving the sensation of weightlessness far more often than in the actual flight sequences. Carroll Ballard has had great success in choosing the best people to photograph his films, and this is a great reunion for the two since their last collaboration on The Black Stallion. Mark Isham takes a totally different approach from his stunning minimalist score of Never Cry Wolf, reaching for - and sometimes - tugging at your heartstrings. In fact, the music is really quite spectacular throughout, except for a rather long and out of place interlude to "10,000 Miles" by Mary Chapin Carpenter. This would have been better suited earlier in the flight, it's current placement feeling a little off. It seems reminiscent of Linda Ronstadt's song "Winter Light" in a 1993 version of "The Secret Garden" (That film, by the way, I highly recommend for fans of Carroll Ballard). As this film progresses, it moves beyond the relationship aspect as Amy makes a discovery in the forest - geese eggs. In a way, her rescuing and raising of these orphaned chicks helps her to heal from her own loss. At its heart, this film is about loss and rebirth. This takes the story of Fly Away Home into new territory, less about the human aspect, and more about nature. All the supporting cast is good and effective (especially Terry Kinney), but Jeff Daniels and Anna Paquin are the central dramatic point which the other actors center around. I've never seen a more lively or energetic performance by Daniels - it's the sort of role he's always excelled at. Paquin, on the other hand, is in a rather uncommon role for her, a simple, more unrestrained character. Without her, or another exactly suited child (of which I know none), the film's dramatic half would have collapsed in on itself. But for all the geese, the drama and the cinematography, it's the moments of quiet that stand out. As the film comes to a close, there are certain factors that bring in a lack of realism. The human and media response to the flight south seems as if borrowed from another film. This perhaps brings the story to a bit of an anti-climax. The 'evil corporate developer' subplot seems lifted from other, less imaginative films. Regardless of the slightly weak ending, perhaps no other conclusion would work better, not without a significantly longer running time. It's a delicately balanced film, and I greatly respect its director for that. There's no immature jokes, no animals being too cute, or overwrought melodrama. For the most part, it feels natural, and the characters act like real people. I appreciate that in a youth-oriented film. I've long since grown out of other movies such as Free Willy, but this film has stuck with me since childhood - and I appreciate it more now than when I first saw it as a kid myself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
