<filme>
 <id>
  505
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0046912
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1954
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Disque M para Matar
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An ex-tennis pro carries out a plot to murder his wife. When things go wrong, he improvises a brilliant plan B.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In London, wealthy Margot Mary Wendice had a brief love affair with the American writer Mark Halliday while her husband and professional tennis player Tony Wendice was on a tennis tour. Tony quits playing to dedicate to his wife and finds a regular job. She decides to give him a second chance for their marriage. When Mark arrives from America to visit the couple, Margot tells him that she had destroyed all his letters but one that was stolen. Subsequently she was blackmailed, but she had never retrieved the stolen letter. Tony arrives home, claims that he needs to work and asks Margot to go with Mark to the theater. Meanwhile Tony calls Captain Lesgate (aka Charles Alexander Swann who studied with him at college) and blackmails him to murder his wife, so that he can inherit her fortune. But there is no perfect crime, and things do not work as planned.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   blackmail
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   writer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   evidence
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   letter
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Alfred Hitchcock
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Frederick Knott
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ray Milland
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Grace Kelly
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert Cummings
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    korneel-brq
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant script, good acting and nice setting. This movie is definitely worth watching every minute. It goes off with a strong start with the dialogue between Swann and Wendice, which is already intricate on itself. Then the development leaving Wendice to bend the entire event to let once again someone else (the justice system) kill his wife, and then yet again Halliday discovering the truth whilst fantasizing is so quickly and natural. A murder plot that was worked through down to the smallest details, I wouldn't like to be an enemy to Alfred Hitchcock.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific performances, especially enjoyed Bob Cummings and John Williams. A real gem!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only problem that some people may have with this film is that it's very talky, and filmed almost entirely in an apartment. However, that in a way was the brilliance of Hitchcock here. Talky, because it was a psychological drama about a man planning to have his wife murdered, and most of the talking is how he suckers a man into doing it for him, and then how he gets out of that after his wife kills that man during the attack. It virtually all takes place in the apartment, because this was a film translation of a play, although it doesn't really have the feeling of a play like a few films have. The cast here is excellent. Top billing went to Ray Milland as the murderous husband, and here is another case of an actor who today is very underrated. Milland, who has more dialog in the film than anyone else, handles it brilliantly. Grace Kelly is the wife. I'm not a particular fan of Kelly, but she was very good here...I can't think of a thing about her acting here to criticize. Robert Cummings, who devoted much of his career to comedy, had a few very fine dramatic turns, and this is one of them (another is in Hitchcock's "Saboteur"). As good as Cummings was in comedy, perhaps he missed his mark...he could have easily been a straight dramatic actor! He plays it just right here. A real treat is character actor John Williams, who steals many of the scenes he is in...as Chief Police Inspector. As good as the 3 leads are, Williams makes the film special. So sit back and relax with a great Hitchcock film, though it is not one of his bigger hits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In stories things usually turn out the way the author wants them to; and in real life they don't... always. [] No, I'm afraid my murders would be something like my bridge: I'd make some stupid mistake and never realize it until I found everybody was looking at me. The scene in which the above dialogue takes place seems to be key to Dial M for Murder, as it stakes out both the theme and the inevitable outcome of the film. The idea of the perfect crime, the failure of it and the idea that crime never pays run throughout many of Alfred Hitchcock's films. It's also the one theme of his that I'm the least interested in as knowing where the film is going takes away some of the excitement. For instance, when the supposedly perfect murder of Grace Kelly goes wrong, but she is still arrested and sentenced to death, it is a brilliantly cruel and sadistic twist, but the stakes would be even higher if you thought there was any chance she wouldn't make it. Complaints about predictability notwithstanding, Hitchcock still shines in his execution. There's a real elegance and assurance about the way the characters act and interact and the way the plot, with some ingenious details revolving for instance around the keys to the apartment, unfolds. Hitchcock can still squeeze a lot of tension into certain scenes. When Anthony Dawson is standing behind the curtain during the attempted murder waiting for that call, Hitchcock makes the audience sweat too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty darn good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice would quite like his wife's money without the hassle of having her to go with it: how fortunate then that he makes contact with a would-be murderer who he can blackmail/bribe. Despite my advancing years, I had managed not to see Hitchcock's Dial M For Murder until the 3D Bluray arrived with my postman. So this comes from the point of view of someone whose first viewing of this film is of the remastered version in 3D (and filmed in 3D rather than a post-production conversion). From the distance of 2013, this film doesn't have much in the way of surprises - the story, while a good one, is nonetheless fairly familiar. And its stage origin shows - despite a handful of scenes in other locations, this remains essentially a single set drama with a small cast. So, given that we have something which is not necessarily the most exciting property in the world, what has Hitchcock done with it? He has drawn excellent performances from his cast, to start with, and he has made the very most of his single set. The camera prowls around it, constantly seeking new viewpoints to reinforce the dramatic impact of what is happening, lighting changes create a number of different moods - impersonal, comforting, dark and menacing - and the mobility of the camera is all the more remarkable given the bulkiness of the 3D rig. For the visual impact of the film, especially in 3D, is amazing. The remastering is excellent, with pin-sharp image and saturated colours. And the 3D is stunning. Hitchcock joins a scant few directors as an artist who understands how to use 3D as an artistic tool to enhance what appears on screen. Nothing is going to jump out of the screen at you, but the true 3D image has staggering depth, particularly when the camera is on the move, and this adds enormously to the visual appreciation of the film. This film should be compulsory viewing in 3D for any director who is currently in the position of having to make a 3D film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classy Thriller that Mixes Things Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dial M for Murder: I've always liked the remake of Dial M for Murder, A Perfect Murder. Consequently, seeing the remake before the original, I knew every twist that was coming my way. Though I think A Perfect Murder has a better female lead, setting, and tone, Dial M for Murder is a classy thriller that mixes things up; it's a great project for Hitchcock to pour his energy into. Dial M for Murder originates from a stage play, it's evident here. This is a movie who's driving force is the dialogue exchanges between its characters. It's very talky. The cinematography has some odd shots, but that's forgiven for the gruesome action. "The scene" is the most violent scene Hitchcock has ever directed. Dial M For Murder dissects the gravity of a murder, every possible thing that could lead the detectives to the guilty one. The film is terrific until the final two minutes which is out of tone with the mood the film held for 100 minutes. Dial M for Murder's ultimately says that everyone is manipulative and to watch out backs (literally Grace Kelly, watch your back). Rating: 9/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply exhilarating !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aditya panwar
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    {Sir}Hitchcock is not a new face to crime, thriller and mystery genre, but dial m for murder is a piece of utter brilliance and mastery.Well, if you love watching movies while lying on bed with laptop at the front prepare to rise and get immersed in this cinema. Movie never takes time to develop characters, it just shoves the plot right into the viewers' face right at the beginning and yet we are so into the premise of the cinema like we are living it and characters build themselves. Actors have done their jobs exceptionally well from Grace Kelly to Robert Cummings, from Roy Milland to John Williams everyone is perfect and simply awesome.With the subtlety Milland plays Wendice is truly unbelievable. You will definitely succumb to his devilish yet charming personality.In short I am now a great fan of Roy Milland..!! Dialogues and the screenplay are very well executed. there are no clich&eacute;s or not a single detail is cheesy like today's mystery movies with exception of a few. This simply is one of best movies ever made. Sir, I salute you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but not great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joaco-h-s
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is entertaining, but isn't one of Hitchcock's greats. There isn't much suspense. Most of it is just about the police investigation and about the "perfect crime". I was searching for something to keep me on my toes. A movie where I can't stop watching. "Dial M for Murder" produces none of these things. On the other hand, it was originally shot in 3D. The 3D effects of the movie are very subtle. It's more like watching a theater play than a movie. I liked this quite a lot. It makes the film quite pleasant. I don't like those movies where 3D is all about projecting things out of the screen just for scares. I would like more 3D movies using this kind of effect. In overall, I enjoyed watching it. And the 3D is a plus. That's why I gave it 5 stars. It isn't great, but if you want to chill watching an easy film, this could be it. The 3D is definitely a plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My last two viewings of Alfred Hitchcock's work before this film were "Rope" and "Strangers on a Train". What do all three films have in common? They are all based around the theory that one can commit the perfect murder and like "Rope" this film is once again an adaptation of a play. In "Dial M for Murder" Tony Wendice discovers that his wife Margot has been having an affair and after stealing a letter sent from her secret lover he uses it to blackmail an old college friend of his Charles Swann. The perfect murder in this film sees Swann follow a precise set of instructions that are based around a phone call made by Tony who would himself have the perfect alibi. When things do not go to plan, Tony Wendice improvises a brilliant plan B that would see his wife framed for the murder of Swann. The screenplay is superb, the film is 105 minutes long and largely takes place in one room, yet our interest is engaged for the full 105 minutes as we listen carefully to every line that is spoken. Every line is greatly delivered by the cast and each character brings their own unique personality, the screenplay is so intelligent and tight that it plays like a classic Agatha Christie murder tale, we are engaged so closely to the tale as it keeps us thinking throughout. We listen to each line of dialogue, searching for clues as the landscape changes throughout, the characters know things we do not and we are scrambling to work out who knows what and what will be the end for each character. The film's lead stars Ray Milland and his wife Grace Kelly are both superb. Milland gives a performance you would expect from a Hitchcock lead man such as Grant or Stewart, he is calm, intelligent and ruthless, although what he is doing is wrong we do not really oppose his evil plan to start. But the beautiful Grace Kelly steals the show as we really sympathise with her following her wrongful verdict of guilty, she shows her talent in this film in what was a great year for her, also starring in Hitchcock's more famous "Rear Window". I have to give a mention to another actor who I was very much impressed by. John Williams is superb as the detective who becomes involved in the case, his character combines the serious element of the crime with humour, he provides some great and memorable dialogue and is the character that engages our interest the most throughout the second half of the film. "Dial M for Murder" is another excellent Hitchcock film that I have seen from the great director, certainly one of his stronger and more enjoyable efforts. It has the same elements of many of his other films but feels very much different, it is not a murder mystery as we no exactly who murdered who but it feels like one because of the way we are constantly engaged in the story and its dialogue as we eagerly wait for the film's conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hitchcock's Dial M for Murder is an adaptation of the successful Broadway play of the same name by Frederick Knott. The movie was shot in 3-D, since in 1953 the movies Bwana Devil and House of Wax started a 3-D craze. But that lasted just after the release of Dial M, and therefore this movie was mostly played in 2-D. Because it's mainly set in an apartment's living room, the movie was shot in only 36 days. Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an ex professional tennis player who retired because his wife Margot (Grace Kelly) complained about his busy schedule and started an affair with Mark Halliday (Robert Cummings). Out of jealousy, Tony decides to meet with an old acquaintance to blackmail him into murdering his wife by following a plan Tony alone devised. Being an adaptation of a play, the movie is primarily based on smart dialogue that carries the plot and manages to keep us interested while the characters try to solve the mystery, even though we know from the beginning what has happened. This is one of the things I liked the most about the movie. Then, there is the great acting: Ray Milland is constantly indifferent, cold, extremely rational and doesn't let emotions interfere with his horrid plan. Grace Kelly is a typical damsel in distress but doesn't know who her saviour is supposed to be, and Robert Cummings would do anything for her. All of them, along with the supporting cast, are very convincing in their roles. That's probably why it's easy to empathise with everyone, no matter their actions. Since, like I said, Dial M was mostly shot in a living room, many people have talked about the movie as "claustrophobic". I would rather say the lack of open spaces gives this movie a feeling of inevitability and hopelessness  nobody can escape their fate and we're all responsible for our actions. This also proves how much Dial M relies on good acting. Another thing I loved about this movie (and old movies in general) is the thoughtful use of soundtrack. Nowadays, the majority of mainstream movies try to evoke feelings in the audience by being too loud all the time, and that's when a soundtrack loses its purpose. In conclusion, Dial M might not appeal to all Hitchcock fans because of the lack of action and long dialogues, but it's an excellent movie nobody should miss. Rating: 8/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Retooling the perfect murder when it turns out to be imperfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an aging tennis pro who learns that his wealthy wife (Grace Kelly as Margot) has a lover (Bob Cummings as Mark). Tony figures out what might have led his wife astray and fixes it - he gets a real job with a real boss. But what if his wife divorces him? He'd get nothing! Realizing that getting a job may have enlarged his wife's respect for him but not diminished her affection for the lover, he spends a large amount of time figuring out a perfect way to kill his wife so that he can inherit her money. Tony has nothing personal against Margot and her infidelity, he just can't take the chance of winding up penniless. He can't do the job himself - the husband is always the prime suspect in such matters. So, he must find someone who will be willing to do the job for him. He's not the type who hangs with organized crime types, so he has to find someone already guilty of murder but yet untouched by the law and get that person to agree to do the job for him. It sounds perfect. Tony even has the lover with him as an alibi the night the murder is to occur. But everything does go wrong, and now Tony has to retool his perfect murder. Who will kill Margot for Tony? The law of course! Watch this great little thriller and see what I'm talking about. Most directors lose a step after they are in their 50's. There is just something about their creativity that just fizzles, and I say that as someone who is 55 myself. But here Hitchcock is at age 55 doing some of his best and most clever work. This one is so ironic it could be considered a film noir if not for the elegance of the players, the setting, and that great score. Just one thing that nobody ever seems to talk about much - did anybody else want Tony to get away with it just a little? He does play it icy cold and smiling throughout, but when he makes the phone call that sets everything in motion, you can see the regret in his face - the fact that he hates that this is the way that it must be. Meanwhile my sympathy was not with the cheating wife and especially the false friend Mark Halliday. The guy was sleeping with a man's wife while pretending to be his friend, even carrying on a kissing session with her while the husband went down the street for an errand. If you're going to steal someone's wife, let it be a stranger's. Don't shake the guy's hand, eat the guy's food, and accept his hospitality and take his wife behind his back too. Maybe Hitch wanted the audience to be conflicted though, maybe he was trying to add to the complexity of the situation with this added dimension. At any rate, watch this if you get a chance. In fact, watch it more than once. You'll always see something you didn't see before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    korneel-brq
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant script, good acting and nice setting. This movie is definitely worth watching every minute. It goes off with a strong start with the dialogue between Swann and Wendice, which is already intricate on itself. Then the development leaving Wendice to bend the entire event to let once again someone else (the justice system) kill his wife, and then yet again Halliday discovering the truth whilst fantasizing is so quickly and natural. A murder plot that was worked through down to the smallest details, I wouldn't like to be an enemy to Alfred Hitchcock.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific performances, especially enjoyed Bob Cummings and John Williams. A real gem!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only problem that some people may have with this film is that it's very talky, and filmed almost entirely in an apartment. However, that in a way was the brilliance of Hitchcock here. Talky, because it was a psychological drama about a man planning to have his wife murdered, and most of the talking is how he suckers a man into doing it for him, and then how he gets out of that after his wife kills that man during the attack. It virtually all takes place in the apartment, because this was a film translation of a play, although it doesn't really have the feeling of a play like a few films have. The cast here is excellent. Top billing went to Ray Milland as the murderous husband, and here is another case of an actor who today is very underrated. Milland, who has more dialog in the film than anyone else, handles it brilliantly. Grace Kelly is the wife. I'm not a particular fan of Kelly, but she was very good here...I can't think of a thing about her acting here to criticize. Robert Cummings, who devoted much of his career to comedy, had a few very fine dramatic turns, and this is one of them (another is in Hitchcock's "Saboteur"). As good as Cummings was in comedy, perhaps he missed his mark...he could have easily been a straight dramatic actor! He plays it just right here. A real treat is character actor John Williams, who steals many of the scenes he is in...as Chief Police Inspector. As good as the 3 leads are, Williams makes the film special. So sit back and relax with a great Hitchcock film, though it is not one of his bigger hits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In stories things usually turn out the way the author wants them to; and in real life they don't... always. [] No, I'm afraid my murders would be something like my bridge: I'd make some stupid mistake and never realize it until I found everybody was looking at me. The scene in which the above dialogue takes place seems to be key to Dial M for Murder, as it stakes out both the theme and the inevitable outcome of the film. The idea of the perfect crime, the failure of it and the idea that crime never pays run throughout many of Alfred Hitchcock's films. It's also the one theme of his that I'm the least interested in as knowing where the film is going takes away some of the excitement. For instance, when the supposedly perfect murder of Grace Kelly goes wrong, but she is still arrested and sentenced to death, it is a brilliantly cruel and sadistic twist, but the stakes would be even higher if you thought there was any chance she wouldn't make it. Complaints about predictability notwithstanding, Hitchcock still shines in his execution. There's a real elegance and assurance about the way the characters act and interact and the way the plot, with some ingenious details revolving for instance around the keys to the apartment, unfolds. Hitchcock can still squeeze a lot of tension into certain scenes. When Anthony Dawson is standing behind the curtain during the attempted murder waiting for that call, Hitchcock makes the audience sweat too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty darn good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice would quite like his wife's money without the hassle of having her to go with it: how fortunate then that he makes contact with a would-be murderer who he can blackmail/bribe. Despite my advancing years, I had managed not to see Hitchcock's Dial M For Murder until the 3D Bluray arrived with my postman. So this comes from the point of view of someone whose first viewing of this film is of the remastered version in 3D (and filmed in 3D rather than a post-production conversion). From the distance of 2013, this film doesn't have much in the way of surprises - the story, while a good one, is nonetheless fairly familiar. And its stage origin shows - despite a handful of scenes in other locations, this remains essentially a single set drama with a small cast. So, given that we have something which is not necessarily the most exciting property in the world, what has Hitchcock done with it? He has drawn excellent performances from his cast, to start with, and he has made the very most of his single set. The camera prowls around it, constantly seeking new viewpoints to reinforce the dramatic impact of what is happening, lighting changes create a number of different moods - impersonal, comforting, dark and menacing - and the mobility of the camera is all the more remarkable given the bulkiness of the 3D rig. For the visual impact of the film, especially in 3D, is amazing. The remastering is excellent, with pin-sharp image and saturated colours. And the 3D is stunning. Hitchcock joins a scant few directors as an artist who understands how to use 3D as an artistic tool to enhance what appears on screen. Nothing is going to jump out of the screen at you, but the true 3D image has staggering depth, particularly when the camera is on the move, and this adds enormously to the visual appreciation of the film. This film should be compulsory viewing in 3D for any director who is currently in the position of having to make a 3D film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classy Thriller that Mixes Things Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dial M for Murder: I've always liked the remake of Dial M for Murder, A Perfect Murder. Consequently, seeing the remake before the original, I knew every twist that was coming my way. Though I think A Perfect Murder has a better female lead, setting, and tone, Dial M for Murder is a classy thriller that mixes things up; it's a great project for Hitchcock to pour his energy into. Dial M for Murder originates from a stage play, it's evident here. This is a movie who's driving force is the dialogue exchanges between its characters. It's very talky. The cinematography has some odd shots, but that's forgiven for the gruesome action. "The scene" is the most violent scene Hitchcock has ever directed. Dial M For Murder dissects the gravity of a murder, every possible thing that could lead the detectives to the guilty one. The film is terrific until the final two minutes which is out of tone with the mood the film held for 100 minutes. Dial M for Murder's ultimately says that everyone is manipulative and to watch out backs (literally Grace Kelly, watch your back). Rating: 9/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply exhilarating !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aditya panwar
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    {Sir}Hitchcock is not a new face to crime, thriller and mystery genre, but dial m for murder is a piece of utter brilliance and mastery.Well, if you love watching movies while lying on bed with laptop at the front prepare to rise and get immersed in this cinema. Movie never takes time to develop characters, it just shoves the plot right into the viewers' face right at the beginning and yet we are so into the premise of the cinema like we are living it and characters build themselves. Actors have done their jobs exceptionally well from Grace Kelly to Robert Cummings, from Roy Milland to John Williams everyone is perfect and simply awesome.With the subtlety Milland plays Wendice is truly unbelievable. You will definitely succumb to his devilish yet charming personality.In short I am now a great fan of Roy Milland..!! Dialogues and the screenplay are very well executed. there are no clich&eacute;s or not a single detail is cheesy like today's mystery movies with exception of a few. This simply is one of best movies ever made. Sir, I salute you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but not great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joaco-h-s
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is entertaining, but isn't one of Hitchcock's greats. There isn't much suspense. Most of it is just about the police investigation and about the "perfect crime". I was searching for something to keep me on my toes. A movie where I can't stop watching. "Dial M for Murder" produces none of these things. On the other hand, it was originally shot in 3D. The 3D effects of the movie are very subtle. It's more like watching a theater play than a movie. I liked this quite a lot. It makes the film quite pleasant. I don't like those movies where 3D is all about projecting things out of the screen just for scares. I would like more 3D movies using this kind of effect. In overall, I enjoyed watching it. And the 3D is a plus. That's why I gave it 5 stars. It isn't great, but if you want to chill watching an easy film, this could be it. The 3D is definitely a plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My last two viewings of Alfred Hitchcock's work before this film were "Rope" and "Strangers on a Train". What do all three films have in common? They are all based around the theory that one can commit the perfect murder and like "Rope" this film is once again an adaptation of a play. In "Dial M for Murder" Tony Wendice discovers that his wife Margot has been having an affair and after stealing a letter sent from her secret lover he uses it to blackmail an old college friend of his Charles Swann. The perfect murder in this film sees Swann follow a precise set of instructions that are based around a phone call made by Tony who would himself have the perfect alibi. When things do not go to plan, Tony Wendice improvises a brilliant plan B that would see his wife framed for the murder of Swann. The screenplay is superb, the film is 105 minutes long and largely takes place in one room, yet our interest is engaged for the full 105 minutes as we listen carefully to every line that is spoken. Every line is greatly delivered by the cast and each character brings their own unique personality, the screenplay is so intelligent and tight that it plays like a classic Agatha Christie murder tale, we are engaged so closely to the tale as it keeps us thinking throughout. We listen to each line of dialogue, searching for clues as the landscape changes throughout, the characters know things we do not and we are scrambling to work out who knows what and what will be the end for each character. The film's lead stars Ray Milland and his wife Grace Kelly are both superb. Milland gives a performance you would expect from a Hitchcock lead man such as Grant or Stewart, he is calm, intelligent and ruthless, although what he is doing is wrong we do not really oppose his evil plan to start. But the beautiful Grace Kelly steals the show as we really sympathise with her following her wrongful verdict of guilty, she shows her talent in this film in what was a great year for her, also starring in Hitchcock's more famous "Rear Window". I have to give a mention to another actor who I was very much impressed by. John Williams is superb as the detective who becomes involved in the case, his character combines the serious element of the crime with humour, he provides some great and memorable dialogue and is the character that engages our interest the most throughout the second half of the film. "Dial M for Murder" is another excellent Hitchcock film that I have seen from the great director, certainly one of his stronger and more enjoyable efforts. It has the same elements of many of his other films but feels very much different, it is not a murder mystery as we no exactly who murdered who but it feels like one because of the way we are constantly engaged in the story and its dialogue as we eagerly wait for the film's conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hitchcock's Dial M for Murder is an adaptation of the successful Broadway play of the same name by Frederick Knott. The movie was shot in 3-D, since in 1953 the movies Bwana Devil and House of Wax started a 3-D craze. But that lasted just after the release of Dial M, and therefore this movie was mostly played in 2-D. Because it's mainly set in an apartment's living room, the movie was shot in only 36 days. Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an ex professional tennis player who retired because his wife Margot (Grace Kelly) complained about his busy schedule and started an affair with Mark Halliday (Robert Cummings). Out of jealousy, Tony decides to meet with an old acquaintance to blackmail him into murdering his wife by following a plan Tony alone devised. Being an adaptation of a play, the movie is primarily based on smart dialogue that carries the plot and manages to keep us interested while the characters try to solve the mystery, even though we know from the beginning what has happened. This is one of the things I liked the most about the movie. Then, there is the great acting: Ray Milland is constantly indifferent, cold, extremely rational and doesn't let emotions interfere with his horrid plan. Grace Kelly is a typical damsel in distress but doesn't know who her saviour is supposed to be, and Robert Cummings would do anything for her. All of them, along with the supporting cast, are very convincing in their roles. That's probably why it's easy to empathise with everyone, no matter their actions. Since, like I said, Dial M was mostly shot in a living room, many people have talked about the movie as "claustrophobic". I would rather say the lack of open spaces gives this movie a feeling of inevitability and hopelessness  nobody can escape their fate and we're all responsible for our actions. This also proves how much Dial M relies on good acting. Another thing I loved about this movie (and old movies in general) is the thoughtful use of soundtrack. Nowadays, the majority of mainstream movies try to evoke feelings in the audience by being too loud all the time, and that's when a soundtrack loses its purpose. In conclusion, Dial M might not appeal to all Hitchcock fans because of the lack of action and long dialogues, but it's an excellent movie nobody should miss. Rating: 8/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Retooling the perfect murder when it turns out to be imperfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an aging tennis pro who learns that his wealthy wife (Grace Kelly as Margot) has a lover (Bob Cummings as Mark). Tony figures out what might have led his wife astray and fixes it - he gets a real job with a real boss. But what if his wife divorces him? He'd get nothing! Realizing that getting a job may have enlarged his wife's respect for him but not diminished her affection for the lover, he spends a large amount of time figuring out a perfect way to kill his wife so that he can inherit her money. Tony has nothing personal against Margot and her infidelity, he just can't take the chance of winding up penniless. He can't do the job himself - the husband is always the prime suspect in such matters. So, he must find someone who will be willing to do the job for him. He's not the type who hangs with organized crime types, so he has to find someone already guilty of murder but yet untouched by the law and get that person to agree to do the job for him. It sounds perfect. Tony even has the lover with him as an alibi the night the murder is to occur. But everything does go wrong, and now Tony has to retool his perfect murder. Who will kill Margot for Tony? The law of course! Watch this great little thriller and see what I'm talking about. Most directors lose a step after they are in their 50's. There is just something about their creativity that just fizzles, and I say that as someone who is 55 myself. But here Hitchcock is at age 55 doing some of his best and most clever work. This one is so ironic it could be considered a film noir if not for the elegance of the players, the setting, and that great score. Just one thing that nobody ever seems to talk about much - did anybody else want Tony to get away with it just a little? He does play it icy cold and smiling throughout, but when he makes the phone call that sets everything in motion, you can see the regret in his face - the fact that he hates that this is the way that it must be. Meanwhile my sympathy was not with the cheating wife and especially the false friend Mark Halliday. The guy was sleeping with a man's wife while pretending to be his friend, even carrying on a kissing session with her while the husband went down the street for an errand. If you're going to steal someone's wife, let it be a stranger's. Don't shake the guy's hand, eat the guy's food, and accept his hospitality and take his wife behind his back too. Maybe Hitch wanted the audience to be conflicted though, maybe he was trying to add to the complexity of the situation with this added dimension. At any rate, watch this if you get a chance. In fact, watch it more than once. You'll always see something you didn't see before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    korneel-brq
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant script, good acting and nice setting. This movie is definitely worth watching every minute. It goes off with a strong start with the dialogue between Swann and Wendice, which is already intricate on itself. Then the development leaving Wendice to bend the entire event to let once again someone else (the justice system) kill his wife, and then yet again Halliday discovering the truth whilst fantasizing is so quickly and natural. A murder plot that was worked through down to the smallest details, I wouldn't like to be an enemy to Alfred Hitchcock.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific performances, especially enjoyed Bob Cummings and John Williams. A real gem!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only problem that some people may have with this film is that it's very talky, and filmed almost entirely in an apartment. However, that in a way was the brilliance of Hitchcock here. Talky, because it was a psychological drama about a man planning to have his wife murdered, and most of the talking is how he suckers a man into doing it for him, and then how he gets out of that after his wife kills that man during the attack. It virtually all takes place in the apartment, because this was a film translation of a play, although it doesn't really have the feeling of a play like a few films have. The cast here is excellent. Top billing went to Ray Milland as the murderous husband, and here is another case of an actor who today is very underrated. Milland, who has more dialog in the film than anyone else, handles it brilliantly. Grace Kelly is the wife. I'm not a particular fan of Kelly, but she was very good here...I can't think of a thing about her acting here to criticize. Robert Cummings, who devoted much of his career to comedy, had a few very fine dramatic turns, and this is one of them (another is in Hitchcock's "Saboteur"). As good as Cummings was in comedy, perhaps he missed his mark...he could have easily been a straight dramatic actor! He plays it just right here. A real treat is character actor John Williams, who steals many of the scenes he is in...as Chief Police Inspector. As good as the 3 leads are, Williams makes the film special. So sit back and relax with a great Hitchcock film, though it is not one of his bigger hits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In stories things usually turn out the way the author wants them to; and in real life they don't... always. [] No, I'm afraid my murders would be something like my bridge: I'd make some stupid mistake and never realize it until I found everybody was looking at me. The scene in which the above dialogue takes place seems to be key to Dial M for Murder, as it stakes out both the theme and the inevitable outcome of the film. The idea of the perfect crime, the failure of it and the idea that crime never pays run throughout many of Alfred Hitchcock's films. It's also the one theme of his that I'm the least interested in as knowing where the film is going takes away some of the excitement. For instance, when the supposedly perfect murder of Grace Kelly goes wrong, but she is still arrested and sentenced to death, it is a brilliantly cruel and sadistic twist, but the stakes would be even higher if you thought there was any chance she wouldn't make it. Complaints about predictability notwithstanding, Hitchcock still shines in his execution. There's a real elegance and assurance about the way the characters act and interact and the way the plot, with some ingenious details revolving for instance around the keys to the apartment, unfolds. Hitchcock can still squeeze a lot of tension into certain scenes. When Anthony Dawson is standing behind the curtain during the attempted murder waiting for that call, Hitchcock makes the audience sweat too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty darn good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice would quite like his wife's money without the hassle of having her to go with it: how fortunate then that he makes contact with a would-be murderer who he can blackmail/bribe. Despite my advancing years, I had managed not to see Hitchcock's Dial M For Murder until the 3D Bluray arrived with my postman. So this comes from the point of view of someone whose first viewing of this film is of the remastered version in 3D (and filmed in 3D rather than a post-production conversion). From the distance of 2013, this film doesn't have much in the way of surprises - the story, while a good one, is nonetheless fairly familiar. And its stage origin shows - despite a handful of scenes in other locations, this remains essentially a single set drama with a small cast. So, given that we have something which is not necessarily the most exciting property in the world, what has Hitchcock done with it? He has drawn excellent performances from his cast, to start with, and he has made the very most of his single set. The camera prowls around it, constantly seeking new viewpoints to reinforce the dramatic impact of what is happening, lighting changes create a number of different moods - impersonal, comforting, dark and menacing - and the mobility of the camera is all the more remarkable given the bulkiness of the 3D rig. For the visual impact of the film, especially in 3D, is amazing. The remastering is excellent, with pin-sharp image and saturated colours. And the 3D is stunning. Hitchcock joins a scant few directors as an artist who understands how to use 3D as an artistic tool to enhance what appears on screen. Nothing is going to jump out of the screen at you, but the true 3D image has staggering depth, particularly when the camera is on the move, and this adds enormously to the visual appreciation of the film. This film should be compulsory viewing in 3D for any director who is currently in the position of having to make a 3D film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classy Thriller that Mixes Things Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dial M for Murder: I've always liked the remake of Dial M for Murder, A Perfect Murder. Consequently, seeing the remake before the original, I knew every twist that was coming my way. Though I think A Perfect Murder has a better female lead, setting, and tone, Dial M for Murder is a classy thriller that mixes things up; it's a great project for Hitchcock to pour his energy into. Dial M for Murder originates from a stage play, it's evident here. This is a movie who's driving force is the dialogue exchanges between its characters. It's very talky. The cinematography has some odd shots, but that's forgiven for the gruesome action. "The scene" is the most violent scene Hitchcock has ever directed. Dial M For Murder dissects the gravity of a murder, every possible thing that could lead the detectives to the guilty one. The film is terrific until the final two minutes which is out of tone with the mood the film held for 100 minutes. Dial M for Murder's ultimately says that everyone is manipulative and to watch out backs (literally Grace Kelly, watch your back). Rating: 9/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply exhilarating !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aditya panwar
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    {Sir}Hitchcock is not a new face to crime, thriller and mystery genre, but dial m for murder is a piece of utter brilliance and mastery.Well, if you love watching movies while lying on bed with laptop at the front prepare to rise and get immersed in this cinema. Movie never takes time to develop characters, it just shoves the plot right into the viewers' face right at the beginning and yet we are so into the premise of the cinema like we are living it and characters build themselves. Actors have done their jobs exceptionally well from Grace Kelly to Robert Cummings, from Roy Milland to John Williams everyone is perfect and simply awesome.With the subtlety Milland plays Wendice is truly unbelievable. You will definitely succumb to his devilish yet charming personality.In short I am now a great fan of Roy Milland..!! Dialogues and the screenplay are very well executed. there are no clich&eacute;s or not a single detail is cheesy like today's mystery movies with exception of a few. This simply is one of best movies ever made. Sir, I salute you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but not great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joaco-h-s
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is entertaining, but isn't one of Hitchcock's greats. There isn't much suspense. Most of it is just about the police investigation and about the "perfect crime". I was searching for something to keep me on my toes. A movie where I can't stop watching. "Dial M for Murder" produces none of these things. On the other hand, it was originally shot in 3D. The 3D effects of the movie are very subtle. It's more like watching a theater play than a movie. I liked this quite a lot. It makes the film quite pleasant. I don't like those movies where 3D is all about projecting things out of the screen just for scares. I would like more 3D movies using this kind of effect. In overall, I enjoyed watching it. And the 3D is a plus. That's why I gave it 5 stars. It isn't great, but if you want to chill watching an easy film, this could be it. The 3D is definitely a plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My last two viewings of Alfred Hitchcock's work before this film were "Rope" and "Strangers on a Train". What do all three films have in common? They are all based around the theory that one can commit the perfect murder and like "Rope" this film is once again an adaptation of a play. In "Dial M for Murder" Tony Wendice discovers that his wife Margot has been having an affair and after stealing a letter sent from her secret lover he uses it to blackmail an old college friend of his Charles Swann. The perfect murder in this film sees Swann follow a precise set of instructions that are based around a phone call made by Tony who would himself have the perfect alibi. When things do not go to plan, Tony Wendice improvises a brilliant plan B that would see his wife framed for the murder of Swann. The screenplay is superb, the film is 105 minutes long and largely takes place in one room, yet our interest is engaged for the full 105 minutes as we listen carefully to every line that is spoken. Every line is greatly delivered by the cast and each character brings their own unique personality, the screenplay is so intelligent and tight that it plays like a classic Agatha Christie murder tale, we are engaged so closely to the tale as it keeps us thinking throughout. We listen to each line of dialogue, searching for clues as the landscape changes throughout, the characters know things we do not and we are scrambling to work out who knows what and what will be the end for each character. The film's lead stars Ray Milland and his wife Grace Kelly are both superb. Milland gives a performance you would expect from a Hitchcock lead man such as Grant or Stewart, he is calm, intelligent and ruthless, although what he is doing is wrong we do not really oppose his evil plan to start. But the beautiful Grace Kelly steals the show as we really sympathise with her following her wrongful verdict of guilty, she shows her talent in this film in what was a great year for her, also starring in Hitchcock's more famous "Rear Window". I have to give a mention to another actor who I was very much impressed by. John Williams is superb as the detective who becomes involved in the case, his character combines the serious element of the crime with humour, he provides some great and memorable dialogue and is the character that engages our interest the most throughout the second half of the film. "Dial M for Murder" is another excellent Hitchcock film that I have seen from the great director, certainly one of his stronger and more enjoyable efforts. It has the same elements of many of his other films but feels very much different, it is not a murder mystery as we no exactly who murdered who but it feels like one because of the way we are constantly engaged in the story and its dialogue as we eagerly wait for the film's conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hitchcock's Dial M for Murder is an adaptation of the successful Broadway play of the same name by Frederick Knott. The movie was shot in 3-D, since in 1953 the movies Bwana Devil and House of Wax started a 3-D craze. But that lasted just after the release of Dial M, and therefore this movie was mostly played in 2-D. Because it's mainly set in an apartment's living room, the movie was shot in only 36 days. Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an ex professional tennis player who retired because his wife Margot (Grace Kelly) complained about his busy schedule and started an affair with Mark Halliday (Robert Cummings). Out of jealousy, Tony decides to meet with an old acquaintance to blackmail him into murdering his wife by following a plan Tony alone devised. Being an adaptation of a play, the movie is primarily based on smart dialogue that carries the plot and manages to keep us interested while the characters try to solve the mystery, even though we know from the beginning what has happened. This is one of the things I liked the most about the movie. Then, there is the great acting: Ray Milland is constantly indifferent, cold, extremely rational and doesn't let emotions interfere with his horrid plan. Grace Kelly is a typical damsel in distress but doesn't know who her saviour is supposed to be, and Robert Cummings would do anything for her. All of them, along with the supporting cast, are very convincing in their roles. That's probably why it's easy to empathise with everyone, no matter their actions. Since, like I said, Dial M was mostly shot in a living room, many people have talked about the movie as "claustrophobic". I would rather say the lack of open spaces gives this movie a feeling of inevitability and hopelessness  nobody can escape their fate and we're all responsible for our actions. This also proves how much Dial M relies on good acting. Another thing I loved about this movie (and old movies in general) is the thoughtful use of soundtrack. Nowadays, the majority of mainstream movies try to evoke feelings in the audience by being too loud all the time, and that's when a soundtrack loses its purpose. In conclusion, Dial M might not appeal to all Hitchcock fans because of the lack of action and long dialogues, but it's an excellent movie nobody should miss. Rating: 8/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Retooling the perfect murder when it turns out to be imperfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an aging tennis pro who learns that his wealthy wife (Grace Kelly as Margot) has a lover (Bob Cummings as Mark). Tony figures out what might have led his wife astray and fixes it - he gets a real job with a real boss. But what if his wife divorces him? He'd get nothing! Realizing that getting a job may have enlarged his wife's respect for him but not diminished her affection for the lover, he spends a large amount of time figuring out a perfect way to kill his wife so that he can inherit her money. Tony has nothing personal against Margot and her infidelity, he just can't take the chance of winding up penniless. He can't do the job himself - the husband is always the prime suspect in such matters. So, he must find someone who will be willing to do the job for him. He's not the type who hangs with organized crime types, so he has to find someone already guilty of murder but yet untouched by the law and get that person to agree to do the job for him. It sounds perfect. Tony even has the lover with him as an alibi the night the murder is to occur. But everything does go wrong, and now Tony has to retool his perfect murder. Who will kill Margot for Tony? The law of course! Watch this great little thriller and see what I'm talking about. Most directors lose a step after they are in their 50's. There is just something about their creativity that just fizzles, and I say that as someone who is 55 myself. But here Hitchcock is at age 55 doing some of his best and most clever work. This one is so ironic it could be considered a film noir if not for the elegance of the players, the setting, and that great score. Just one thing that nobody ever seems to talk about much - did anybody else want Tony to get away with it just a little? He does play it icy cold and smiling throughout, but when he makes the phone call that sets everything in motion, you can see the regret in his face - the fact that he hates that this is the way that it must be. Meanwhile my sympathy was not with the cheating wife and especially the false friend Mark Halliday. The guy was sleeping with a man's wife while pretending to be his friend, even carrying on a kissing session with her while the husband went down the street for an errand. If you're going to steal someone's wife, let it be a stranger's. Don't shake the guy's hand, eat the guy's food, and accept his hospitality and take his wife behind his back too. Maybe Hitch wanted the audience to be conflicted though, maybe he was trying to add to the complexity of the situation with this added dimension. At any rate, watch this if you get a chance. In fact, watch it more than once. You'll always see something you didn't see before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    korneel-brq
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant script, good acting and nice setting. This movie is definitely worth watching every minute. It goes off with a strong start with the dialogue between Swann and Wendice, which is already intricate on itself. Then the development leaving Wendice to bend the entire event to let once again someone else (the justice system) kill his wife, and then yet again Halliday discovering the truth whilst fantasizing is so quickly and natural. A murder plot that was worked through down to the smallest details, I wouldn't like to be an enemy to Alfred Hitchcock.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific performances, especially enjoyed Bob Cummings and John Williams. A real gem!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only problem that some people may have with this film is that it's very talky, and filmed almost entirely in an apartment. However, that in a way was the brilliance of Hitchcock here. Talky, because it was a psychological drama about a man planning to have his wife murdered, and most of the talking is how he suckers a man into doing it for him, and then how he gets out of that after his wife kills that man during the attack. It virtually all takes place in the apartment, because this was a film translation of a play, although it doesn't really have the feeling of a play like a few films have. The cast here is excellent. Top billing went to Ray Milland as the murderous husband, and here is another case of an actor who today is very underrated. Milland, who has more dialog in the film than anyone else, handles it brilliantly. Grace Kelly is the wife. I'm not a particular fan of Kelly, but she was very good here...I can't think of a thing about her acting here to criticize. Robert Cummings, who devoted much of his career to comedy, had a few very fine dramatic turns, and this is one of them (another is in Hitchcock's "Saboteur"). As good as Cummings was in comedy, perhaps he missed his mark...he could have easily been a straight dramatic actor! He plays it just right here. A real treat is character actor John Williams, who steals many of the scenes he is in...as Chief Police Inspector. As good as the 3 leads are, Williams makes the film special. So sit back and relax with a great Hitchcock film, though it is not one of his bigger hits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In stories things usually turn out the way the author wants them to; and in real life they don't... always. [] No, I'm afraid my murders would be something like my bridge: I'd make some stupid mistake and never realize it until I found everybody was looking at me. The scene in which the above dialogue takes place seems to be key to Dial M for Murder, as it stakes out both the theme and the inevitable outcome of the film. The idea of the perfect crime, the failure of it and the idea that crime never pays run throughout many of Alfred Hitchcock's films. It's also the one theme of his that I'm the least interested in as knowing where the film is going takes away some of the excitement. For instance, when the supposedly perfect murder of Grace Kelly goes wrong, but she is still arrested and sentenced to death, it is a brilliantly cruel and sadistic twist, but the stakes would be even higher if you thought there was any chance she wouldn't make it. Complaints about predictability notwithstanding, Hitchcock still shines in his execution. There's a real elegance and assurance about the way the characters act and interact and the way the plot, with some ingenious details revolving for instance around the keys to the apartment, unfolds. Hitchcock can still squeeze a lot of tension into certain scenes. When Anthony Dawson is standing behind the curtain during the attempted murder waiting for that call, Hitchcock makes the audience sweat too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty darn good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice would quite like his wife's money without the hassle of having her to go with it: how fortunate then that he makes contact with a would-be murderer who he can blackmail/bribe. Despite my advancing years, I had managed not to see Hitchcock's Dial M For Murder until the 3D Bluray arrived with my postman. So this comes from the point of view of someone whose first viewing of this film is of the remastered version in 3D (and filmed in 3D rather than a post-production conversion). From the distance of 2013, this film doesn't have much in the way of surprises - the story, while a good one, is nonetheless fairly familiar. And its stage origin shows - despite a handful of scenes in other locations, this remains essentially a single set drama with a small cast. So, given that we have something which is not necessarily the most exciting property in the world, what has Hitchcock done with it? He has drawn excellent performances from his cast, to start with, and he has made the very most of his single set. The camera prowls around it, constantly seeking new viewpoints to reinforce the dramatic impact of what is happening, lighting changes create a number of different moods - impersonal, comforting, dark and menacing - and the mobility of the camera is all the more remarkable given the bulkiness of the 3D rig. For the visual impact of the film, especially in 3D, is amazing. The remastering is excellent, with pin-sharp image and saturated colours. And the 3D is stunning. Hitchcock joins a scant few directors as an artist who understands how to use 3D as an artistic tool to enhance what appears on screen. Nothing is going to jump out of the screen at you, but the true 3D image has staggering depth, particularly when the camera is on the move, and this adds enormously to the visual appreciation of the film. This film should be compulsory viewing in 3D for any director who is currently in the position of having to make a 3D film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classy Thriller that Mixes Things Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dial M for Murder: I've always liked the remake of Dial M for Murder, A Perfect Murder. Consequently, seeing the remake before the original, I knew every twist that was coming my way. Though I think A Perfect Murder has a better female lead, setting, and tone, Dial M for Murder is a classy thriller that mixes things up; it's a great project for Hitchcock to pour his energy into. Dial M for Murder originates from a stage play, it's evident here. This is a movie who's driving force is the dialogue exchanges between its characters. It's very talky. The cinematography has some odd shots, but that's forgiven for the gruesome action. "The scene" is the most violent scene Hitchcock has ever directed. Dial M For Murder dissects the gravity of a murder, every possible thing that could lead the detectives to the guilty one. The film is terrific until the final two minutes which is out of tone with the mood the film held for 100 minutes. Dial M for Murder's ultimately says that everyone is manipulative and to watch out backs (literally Grace Kelly, watch your back). Rating: 9/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply exhilarating !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aditya panwar
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    {Sir}Hitchcock is not a new face to crime, thriller and mystery genre, but dial m for murder is a piece of utter brilliance and mastery.Well, if you love watching movies while lying on bed with laptop at the front prepare to rise and get immersed in this cinema. Movie never takes time to develop characters, it just shoves the plot right into the viewers' face right at the beginning and yet we are so into the premise of the cinema like we are living it and characters build themselves. Actors have done their jobs exceptionally well from Grace Kelly to Robert Cummings, from Roy Milland to John Williams everyone is perfect and simply awesome.With the subtlety Milland plays Wendice is truly unbelievable. You will definitely succumb to his devilish yet charming personality.In short I am now a great fan of Roy Milland..!! Dialogues and the screenplay are very well executed. there are no clich&eacute;s or not a single detail is cheesy like today's mystery movies with exception of a few. This simply is one of best movies ever made. Sir, I salute you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but not great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joaco-h-s
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is entertaining, but isn't one of Hitchcock's greats. There isn't much suspense. Most of it is just about the police investigation and about the "perfect crime". I was searching for something to keep me on my toes. A movie where I can't stop watching. "Dial M for Murder" produces none of these things. On the other hand, it was originally shot in 3D. The 3D effects of the movie are very subtle. It's more like watching a theater play than a movie. I liked this quite a lot. It makes the film quite pleasant. I don't like those movies where 3D is all about projecting things out of the screen just for scares. I would like more 3D movies using this kind of effect. In overall, I enjoyed watching it. And the 3D is a plus. That's why I gave it 5 stars. It isn't great, but if you want to chill watching an easy film, this could be it. The 3D is definitely a plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My last two viewings of Alfred Hitchcock's work before this film were "Rope" and "Strangers on a Train". What do all three films have in common? They are all based around the theory that one can commit the perfect murder and like "Rope" this film is once again an adaptation of a play. In "Dial M for Murder" Tony Wendice discovers that his wife Margot has been having an affair and after stealing a letter sent from her secret lover he uses it to blackmail an old college friend of his Charles Swann. The perfect murder in this film sees Swann follow a precise set of instructions that are based around a phone call made by Tony who would himself have the perfect alibi. When things do not go to plan, Tony Wendice improvises a brilliant plan B that would see his wife framed for the murder of Swann. The screenplay is superb, the film is 105 minutes long and largely takes place in one room, yet our interest is engaged for the full 105 minutes as we listen carefully to every line that is spoken. Every line is greatly delivered by the cast and each character brings their own unique personality, the screenplay is so intelligent and tight that it plays like a classic Agatha Christie murder tale, we are engaged so closely to the tale as it keeps us thinking throughout. We listen to each line of dialogue, searching for clues as the landscape changes throughout, the characters know things we do not and we are scrambling to work out who knows what and what will be the end for each character. The film's lead stars Ray Milland and his wife Grace Kelly are both superb. Milland gives a performance you would expect from a Hitchcock lead man such as Grant or Stewart, he is calm, intelligent and ruthless, although what he is doing is wrong we do not really oppose his evil plan to start. But the beautiful Grace Kelly steals the show as we really sympathise with her following her wrongful verdict of guilty, she shows her talent in this film in what was a great year for her, also starring in Hitchcock's more famous "Rear Window". I have to give a mention to another actor who I was very much impressed by. John Williams is superb as the detective who becomes involved in the case, his character combines the serious element of the crime with humour, he provides some great and memorable dialogue and is the character that engages our interest the most throughout the second half of the film. "Dial M for Murder" is another excellent Hitchcock film that I have seen from the great director, certainly one of his stronger and more enjoyable efforts. It has the same elements of many of his other films but feels very much different, it is not a murder mystery as we no exactly who murdered who but it feels like one because of the way we are constantly engaged in the story and its dialogue as we eagerly wait for the film's conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hitchcock's Dial M for Murder is an adaptation of the successful Broadway play of the same name by Frederick Knott. The movie was shot in 3-D, since in 1953 the movies Bwana Devil and House of Wax started a 3-D craze. But that lasted just after the release of Dial M, and therefore this movie was mostly played in 2-D. Because it's mainly set in an apartment's living room, the movie was shot in only 36 days. Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an ex professional tennis player who retired because his wife Margot (Grace Kelly) complained about his busy schedule and started an affair with Mark Halliday (Robert Cummings). Out of jealousy, Tony decides to meet with an old acquaintance to blackmail him into murdering his wife by following a plan Tony alone devised. Being an adaptation of a play, the movie is primarily based on smart dialogue that carries the plot and manages to keep us interested while the characters try to solve the mystery, even though we know from the beginning what has happened. This is one of the things I liked the most about the movie. Then, there is the great acting: Ray Milland is constantly indifferent, cold, extremely rational and doesn't let emotions interfere with his horrid plan. Grace Kelly is a typical damsel in distress but doesn't know who her saviour is supposed to be, and Robert Cummings would do anything for her. All of them, along with the supporting cast, are very convincing in their roles. That's probably why it's easy to empathise with everyone, no matter their actions. Since, like I said, Dial M was mostly shot in a living room, many people have talked about the movie as "claustrophobic". I would rather say the lack of open spaces gives this movie a feeling of inevitability and hopelessness  nobody can escape their fate and we're all responsible for our actions. This also proves how much Dial M relies on good acting. Another thing I loved about this movie (and old movies in general) is the thoughtful use of soundtrack. Nowadays, the majority of mainstream movies try to evoke feelings in the audience by being too loud all the time, and that's when a soundtrack loses its purpose. In conclusion, Dial M might not appeal to all Hitchcock fans because of the lack of action and long dialogues, but it's an excellent movie nobody should miss. Rating: 8/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Retooling the perfect murder when it turns out to be imperfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an aging tennis pro who learns that his wealthy wife (Grace Kelly as Margot) has a lover (Bob Cummings as Mark). Tony figures out what might have led his wife astray and fixes it - he gets a real job with a real boss. But what if his wife divorces him? He'd get nothing! Realizing that getting a job may have enlarged his wife's respect for him but not diminished her affection for the lover, he spends a large amount of time figuring out a perfect way to kill his wife so that he can inherit her money. Tony has nothing personal against Margot and her infidelity, he just can't take the chance of winding up penniless. He can't do the job himself - the husband is always the prime suspect in such matters. So, he must find someone who will be willing to do the job for him. He's not the type who hangs with organized crime types, so he has to find someone already guilty of murder but yet untouched by the law and get that person to agree to do the job for him. It sounds perfect. Tony even has the lover with him as an alibi the night the murder is to occur. But everything does go wrong, and now Tony has to retool his perfect murder. Who will kill Margot for Tony? The law of course! Watch this great little thriller and see what I'm talking about. Most directors lose a step after they are in their 50's. There is just something about their creativity that just fizzles, and I say that as someone who is 55 myself. But here Hitchcock is at age 55 doing some of his best and most clever work. This one is so ironic it could be considered a film noir if not for the elegance of the players, the setting, and that great score. Just one thing that nobody ever seems to talk about much - did anybody else want Tony to get away with it just a little? He does play it icy cold and smiling throughout, but when he makes the phone call that sets everything in motion, you can see the regret in his face - the fact that he hates that this is the way that it must be. Meanwhile my sympathy was not with the cheating wife and especially the false friend Mark Halliday. The guy was sleeping with a man's wife while pretending to be his friend, even carrying on a kissing session with her while the husband went down the street for an errand. If you're going to steal someone's wife, let it be a stranger's. Don't shake the guy's hand, eat the guy's food, and accept his hospitality and take his wife behind his back too. Maybe Hitch wanted the audience to be conflicted though, maybe he was trying to add to the complexity of the situation with this added dimension. At any rate, watch this if you get a chance. In fact, watch it more than once. You'll always see something you didn't see before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    korneel-brq
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant script, good acting and nice setting. This movie is definitely worth watching every minute. It goes off with a strong start with the dialogue between Swann and Wendice, which is already intricate on itself. Then the development leaving Wendice to bend the entire event to let once again someone else (the justice system) kill his wife, and then yet again Halliday discovering the truth whilst fantasizing is so quickly and natural. A murder plot that was worked through down to the smallest details, I wouldn't like to be an enemy to Alfred Hitchcock.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific performances, especially enjoyed Bob Cummings and John Williams. A real gem!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only problem that some people may have with this film is that it's very talky, and filmed almost entirely in an apartment. However, that in a way was the brilliance of Hitchcock here. Talky, because it was a psychological drama about a man planning to have his wife murdered, and most of the talking is how he suckers a man into doing it for him, and then how he gets out of that after his wife kills that man during the attack. It virtually all takes place in the apartment, because this was a film translation of a play, although it doesn't really have the feeling of a play like a few films have. The cast here is excellent. Top billing went to Ray Milland as the murderous husband, and here is another case of an actor who today is very underrated. Milland, who has more dialog in the film than anyone else, handles it brilliantly. Grace Kelly is the wife. I'm not a particular fan of Kelly, but she was very good here...I can't think of a thing about her acting here to criticize. Robert Cummings, who devoted much of his career to comedy, had a few very fine dramatic turns, and this is one of them (another is in Hitchcock's "Saboteur"). As good as Cummings was in comedy, perhaps he missed his mark...he could have easily been a straight dramatic actor! He plays it just right here. A real treat is character actor John Williams, who steals many of the scenes he is in...as Chief Police Inspector. As good as the 3 leads are, Williams makes the film special. So sit back and relax with a great Hitchcock film, though it is not one of his bigger hits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In stories things usually turn out the way the author wants them to; and in real life they don't... always. [] No, I'm afraid my murders would be something like my bridge: I'd make some stupid mistake and never realize it until I found everybody was looking at me. The scene in which the above dialogue takes place seems to be key to Dial M for Murder, as it stakes out both the theme and the inevitable outcome of the film. The idea of the perfect crime, the failure of it and the idea that crime never pays run throughout many of Alfred Hitchcock's films. It's also the one theme of his that I'm the least interested in as knowing where the film is going takes away some of the excitement. For instance, when the supposedly perfect murder of Grace Kelly goes wrong, but she is still arrested and sentenced to death, it is a brilliantly cruel and sadistic twist, but the stakes would be even higher if you thought there was any chance she wouldn't make it. Complaints about predictability notwithstanding, Hitchcock still shines in his execution. There's a real elegance and assurance about the way the characters act and interact and the way the plot, with some ingenious details revolving for instance around the keys to the apartment, unfolds. Hitchcock can still squeeze a lot of tension into certain scenes. When Anthony Dawson is standing behind the curtain during the attempted murder waiting for that call, Hitchcock makes the audience sweat too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty darn good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice would quite like his wife's money without the hassle of having her to go with it: how fortunate then that he makes contact with a would-be murderer who he can blackmail/bribe. Despite my advancing years, I had managed not to see Hitchcock's Dial M For Murder until the 3D Bluray arrived with my postman. So this comes from the point of view of someone whose first viewing of this film is of the remastered version in 3D (and filmed in 3D rather than a post-production conversion). From the distance of 2013, this film doesn't have much in the way of surprises - the story, while a good one, is nonetheless fairly familiar. And its stage origin shows - despite a handful of scenes in other locations, this remains essentially a single set drama with a small cast. So, given that we have something which is not necessarily the most exciting property in the world, what has Hitchcock done with it? He has drawn excellent performances from his cast, to start with, and he has made the very most of his single set. The camera prowls around it, constantly seeking new viewpoints to reinforce the dramatic impact of what is happening, lighting changes create a number of different moods - impersonal, comforting, dark and menacing - and the mobility of the camera is all the more remarkable given the bulkiness of the 3D rig. For the visual impact of the film, especially in 3D, is amazing. The remastering is excellent, with pin-sharp image and saturated colours. And the 3D is stunning. Hitchcock joins a scant few directors as an artist who understands how to use 3D as an artistic tool to enhance what appears on screen. Nothing is going to jump out of the screen at you, but the true 3D image has staggering depth, particularly when the camera is on the move, and this adds enormously to the visual appreciation of the film. This film should be compulsory viewing in 3D for any director who is currently in the position of having to make a 3D film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classy Thriller that Mixes Things Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dial M for Murder: I've always liked the remake of Dial M for Murder, A Perfect Murder. Consequently, seeing the remake before the original, I knew every twist that was coming my way. Though I think A Perfect Murder has a better female lead, setting, and tone, Dial M for Murder is a classy thriller that mixes things up; it's a great project for Hitchcock to pour his energy into. Dial M for Murder originates from a stage play, it's evident here. This is a movie who's driving force is the dialogue exchanges between its characters. It's very talky. The cinematography has some odd shots, but that's forgiven for the gruesome action. "The scene" is the most violent scene Hitchcock has ever directed. Dial M For Murder dissects the gravity of a murder, every possible thing that could lead the detectives to the guilty one. The film is terrific until the final two minutes which is out of tone with the mood the film held for 100 minutes. Dial M for Murder's ultimately says that everyone is manipulative and to watch out backs (literally Grace Kelly, watch your back). Rating: 9/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply exhilarating !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aditya panwar
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    {Sir}Hitchcock is not a new face to crime, thriller and mystery genre, but dial m for murder is a piece of utter brilliance and mastery.Well, if you love watching movies while lying on bed with laptop at the front prepare to rise and get immersed in this cinema. Movie never takes time to develop characters, it just shoves the plot right into the viewers' face right at the beginning and yet we are so into the premise of the cinema like we are living it and characters build themselves. Actors have done their jobs exceptionally well from Grace Kelly to Robert Cummings, from Roy Milland to John Williams everyone is perfect and simply awesome.With the subtlety Milland plays Wendice is truly unbelievable. You will definitely succumb to his devilish yet charming personality.In short I am now a great fan of Roy Milland..!! Dialogues and the screenplay are very well executed. there are no clich&eacute;s or not a single detail is cheesy like today's mystery movies with exception of a few. This simply is one of best movies ever made. Sir, I salute you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but not great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joaco-h-s
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is entertaining, but isn't one of Hitchcock's greats. There isn't much suspense. Most of it is just about the police investigation and about the "perfect crime". I was searching for something to keep me on my toes. A movie where I can't stop watching. "Dial M for Murder" produces none of these things. On the other hand, it was originally shot in 3D. The 3D effects of the movie are very subtle. It's more like watching a theater play than a movie. I liked this quite a lot. It makes the film quite pleasant. I don't like those movies where 3D is all about projecting things out of the screen just for scares. I would like more 3D movies using this kind of effect. In overall, I enjoyed watching it. And the 3D is a plus. That's why I gave it 5 stars. It isn't great, but if you want to chill watching an easy film, this could be it. The 3D is definitely a plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My last two viewings of Alfred Hitchcock's work before this film were "Rope" and "Strangers on a Train". What do all three films have in common? They are all based around the theory that one can commit the perfect murder and like "Rope" this film is once again an adaptation of a play. In "Dial M for Murder" Tony Wendice discovers that his wife Margot has been having an affair and after stealing a letter sent from her secret lover he uses it to blackmail an old college friend of his Charles Swann. The perfect murder in this film sees Swann follow a precise set of instructions that are based around a phone call made by Tony who would himself have the perfect alibi. When things do not go to plan, Tony Wendice improvises a brilliant plan B that would see his wife framed for the murder of Swann. The screenplay is superb, the film is 105 minutes long and largely takes place in one room, yet our interest is engaged for the full 105 minutes as we listen carefully to every line that is spoken. Every line is greatly delivered by the cast and each character brings their own unique personality, the screenplay is so intelligent and tight that it plays like a classic Agatha Christie murder tale, we are engaged so closely to the tale as it keeps us thinking throughout. We listen to each line of dialogue, searching for clues as the landscape changes throughout, the characters know things we do not and we are scrambling to work out who knows what and what will be the end for each character. The film's lead stars Ray Milland and his wife Grace Kelly are both superb. Milland gives a performance you would expect from a Hitchcock lead man such as Grant or Stewart, he is calm, intelligent and ruthless, although what he is doing is wrong we do not really oppose his evil plan to start. But the beautiful Grace Kelly steals the show as we really sympathise with her following her wrongful verdict of guilty, she shows her talent in this film in what was a great year for her, also starring in Hitchcock's more famous "Rear Window". I have to give a mention to another actor who I was very much impressed by. John Williams is superb as the detective who becomes involved in the case, his character combines the serious element of the crime with humour, he provides some great and memorable dialogue and is the character that engages our interest the most throughout the second half of the film. "Dial M for Murder" is another excellent Hitchcock film that I have seen from the great director, certainly one of his stronger and more enjoyable efforts. It has the same elements of many of his other films but feels very much different, it is not a murder mystery as we no exactly who murdered who but it feels like one because of the way we are constantly engaged in the story and its dialogue as we eagerly wait for the film's conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hitchcock's Dial M for Murder is an adaptation of the successful Broadway play of the same name by Frederick Knott. The movie was shot in 3-D, since in 1953 the movies Bwana Devil and House of Wax started a 3-D craze. But that lasted just after the release of Dial M, and therefore this movie was mostly played in 2-D. Because it's mainly set in an apartment's living room, the movie was shot in only 36 days. Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an ex professional tennis player who retired because his wife Margot (Grace Kelly) complained about his busy schedule and started an affair with Mark Halliday (Robert Cummings). Out of jealousy, Tony decides to meet with an old acquaintance to blackmail him into murdering his wife by following a plan Tony alone devised. Being an adaptation of a play, the movie is primarily based on smart dialogue that carries the plot and manages to keep us interested while the characters try to solve the mystery, even though we know from the beginning what has happened. This is one of the things I liked the most about the movie. Then, there is the great acting: Ray Milland is constantly indifferent, cold, extremely rational and doesn't let emotions interfere with his horrid plan. Grace Kelly is a typical damsel in distress but doesn't know who her saviour is supposed to be, and Robert Cummings would do anything for her. All of them, along with the supporting cast, are very convincing in their roles. That's probably why it's easy to empathise with everyone, no matter their actions. Since, like I said, Dial M was mostly shot in a living room, many people have talked about the movie as "claustrophobic". I would rather say the lack of open spaces gives this movie a feeling of inevitability and hopelessness  nobody can escape their fate and we're all responsible for our actions. This also proves how much Dial M relies on good acting. Another thing I loved about this movie (and old movies in general) is the thoughtful use of soundtrack. Nowadays, the majority of mainstream movies try to evoke feelings in the audience by being too loud all the time, and that's when a soundtrack loses its purpose. In conclusion, Dial M might not appeal to all Hitchcock fans because of the lack of action and long dialogues, but it's an excellent movie nobody should miss. Rating: 8/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Retooling the perfect murder when it turns out to be imperfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an aging tennis pro who learns that his wealthy wife (Grace Kelly as Margot) has a lover (Bob Cummings as Mark). Tony figures out what might have led his wife astray and fixes it - he gets a real job with a real boss. But what if his wife divorces him? He'd get nothing! Realizing that getting a job may have enlarged his wife's respect for him but not diminished her affection for the lover, he spends a large amount of time figuring out a perfect way to kill his wife so that he can inherit her money. Tony has nothing personal against Margot and her infidelity, he just can't take the chance of winding up penniless. He can't do the job himself - the husband is always the prime suspect in such matters. So, he must find someone who will be willing to do the job for him. He's not the type who hangs with organized crime types, so he has to find someone already guilty of murder but yet untouched by the law and get that person to agree to do the job for him. It sounds perfect. Tony even has the lover with him as an alibi the night the murder is to occur. But everything does go wrong, and now Tony has to retool his perfect murder. Who will kill Margot for Tony? The law of course! Watch this great little thriller and see what I'm talking about. Most directors lose a step after they are in their 50's. There is just something about their creativity that just fizzles, and I say that as someone who is 55 myself. But here Hitchcock is at age 55 doing some of his best and most clever work. This one is so ironic it could be considered a film noir if not for the elegance of the players, the setting, and that great score. Just one thing that nobody ever seems to talk about much - did anybody else want Tony to get away with it just a little? He does play it icy cold and smiling throughout, but when he makes the phone call that sets everything in motion, you can see the regret in his face - the fact that he hates that this is the way that it must be. Meanwhile my sympathy was not with the cheating wife and especially the false friend Mark Halliday. The guy was sleeping with a man's wife while pretending to be his friend, even carrying on a kissing session with her while the husband went down the street for an errand. If you're going to steal someone's wife, let it be a stranger's. Don't shake the guy's hand, eat the guy's food, and accept his hospitality and take his wife behind his back too. Maybe Hitch wanted the audience to be conflicted though, maybe he was trying to add to the complexity of the situation with this added dimension. At any rate, watch this if you get a chance. In fact, watch it more than once. You'll always see something you didn't see before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    korneel-brq
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant script, good acting and nice setting. This movie is definitely worth watching every minute. It goes off with a strong start with the dialogue between Swann and Wendice, which is already intricate on itself. Then the development leaving Wendice to bend the entire event to let once again someone else (the justice system) kill his wife, and then yet again Halliday discovering the truth whilst fantasizing is so quickly and natural. A murder plot that was worked through down to the smallest details, I wouldn't like to be an enemy to Alfred Hitchcock.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific performances, especially enjoyed Bob Cummings and John Williams. A real gem!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only problem that some people may have with this film is that it's very talky, and filmed almost entirely in an apartment. However, that in a way was the brilliance of Hitchcock here. Talky, because it was a psychological drama about a man planning to have his wife murdered, and most of the talking is how he suckers a man into doing it for him, and then how he gets out of that after his wife kills that man during the attack. It virtually all takes place in the apartment, because this was a film translation of a play, although it doesn't really have the feeling of a play like a few films have. The cast here is excellent. Top billing went to Ray Milland as the murderous husband, and here is another case of an actor who today is very underrated. Milland, who has more dialog in the film than anyone else, handles it brilliantly. Grace Kelly is the wife. I'm not a particular fan of Kelly, but she was very good here...I can't think of a thing about her acting here to criticize. Robert Cummings, who devoted much of his career to comedy, had a few very fine dramatic turns, and this is one of them (another is in Hitchcock's "Saboteur"). As good as Cummings was in comedy, perhaps he missed his mark...he could have easily been a straight dramatic actor! He plays it just right here. A real treat is character actor John Williams, who steals many of the scenes he is in...as Chief Police Inspector. As good as the 3 leads are, Williams makes the film special. So sit back and relax with a great Hitchcock film, though it is not one of his bigger hits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In stories things usually turn out the way the author wants them to; and in real life they don't... always. [] No, I'm afraid my murders would be something like my bridge: I'd make some stupid mistake and never realize it until I found everybody was looking at me. The scene in which the above dialogue takes place seems to be key to Dial M for Murder, as it stakes out both the theme and the inevitable outcome of the film. The idea of the perfect crime, the failure of it and the idea that crime never pays run throughout many of Alfred Hitchcock's films. It's also the one theme of his that I'm the least interested in as knowing where the film is going takes away some of the excitement. For instance, when the supposedly perfect murder of Grace Kelly goes wrong, but she is still arrested and sentenced to death, it is a brilliantly cruel and sadistic twist, but the stakes would be even higher if you thought there was any chance she wouldn't make it. Complaints about predictability notwithstanding, Hitchcock still shines in his execution. There's a real elegance and assurance about the way the characters act and interact and the way the plot, with some ingenious details revolving for instance around the keys to the apartment, unfolds. Hitchcock can still squeeze a lot of tension into certain scenes. When Anthony Dawson is standing behind the curtain during the attempted murder waiting for that call, Hitchcock makes the audience sweat too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty darn good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice would quite like his wife's money without the hassle of having her to go with it: how fortunate then that he makes contact with a would-be murderer who he can blackmail/bribe. Despite my advancing years, I had managed not to see Hitchcock's Dial M For Murder until the 3D Bluray arrived with my postman. So this comes from the point of view of someone whose first viewing of this film is of the remastered version in 3D (and filmed in 3D rather than a post-production conversion). From the distance of 2013, this film doesn't have much in the way of surprises - the story, while a good one, is nonetheless fairly familiar. And its stage origin shows - despite a handful of scenes in other locations, this remains essentially a single set drama with a small cast. So, given that we have something which is not necessarily the most exciting property in the world, what has Hitchcock done with it? He has drawn excellent performances from his cast, to start with, and he has made the very most of his single set. The camera prowls around it, constantly seeking new viewpoints to reinforce the dramatic impact of what is happening, lighting changes create a number of different moods - impersonal, comforting, dark and menacing - and the mobility of the camera is all the more remarkable given the bulkiness of the 3D rig. For the visual impact of the film, especially in 3D, is amazing. The remastering is excellent, with pin-sharp image and saturated colours. And the 3D is stunning. Hitchcock joins a scant few directors as an artist who understands how to use 3D as an artistic tool to enhance what appears on screen. Nothing is going to jump out of the screen at you, but the true 3D image has staggering depth, particularly when the camera is on the move, and this adds enormously to the visual appreciation of the film. This film should be compulsory viewing in 3D for any director who is currently in the position of having to make a 3D film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classy Thriller that Mixes Things Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dial M for Murder: I've always liked the remake of Dial M for Murder, A Perfect Murder. Consequently, seeing the remake before the original, I knew every twist that was coming my way. Though I think A Perfect Murder has a better female lead, setting, and tone, Dial M for Murder is a classy thriller that mixes things up; it's a great project for Hitchcock to pour his energy into. Dial M for Murder originates from a stage play, it's evident here. This is a movie who's driving force is the dialogue exchanges between its characters. It's very talky. The cinematography has some odd shots, but that's forgiven for the gruesome action. "The scene" is the most violent scene Hitchcock has ever directed. Dial M For Murder dissects the gravity of a murder, every possible thing that could lead the detectives to the guilty one. The film is terrific until the final two minutes which is out of tone with the mood the film held for 100 minutes. Dial M for Murder's ultimately says that everyone is manipulative and to watch out backs (literally Grace Kelly, watch your back). Rating: 9/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply exhilarating !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aditya panwar
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    {Sir}Hitchcock is not a new face to crime, thriller and mystery genre, but dial m for murder is a piece of utter brilliance and mastery.Well, if you love watching movies while lying on bed with laptop at the front prepare to rise and get immersed in this cinema. Movie never takes time to develop characters, it just shoves the plot right into the viewers' face right at the beginning and yet we are so into the premise of the cinema like we are living it and characters build themselves. Actors have done their jobs exceptionally well from Grace Kelly to Robert Cummings, from Roy Milland to John Williams everyone is perfect and simply awesome.With the subtlety Milland plays Wendice is truly unbelievable. You will definitely succumb to his devilish yet charming personality.In short I am now a great fan of Roy Milland..!! Dialogues and the screenplay are very well executed. there are no clich&eacute;s or not a single detail is cheesy like today's mystery movies with exception of a few. This simply is one of best movies ever made. Sir, I salute you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but not great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joaco-h-s
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is entertaining, but isn't one of Hitchcock's greats. There isn't much suspense. Most of it is just about the police investigation and about the "perfect crime". I was searching for something to keep me on my toes. A movie where I can't stop watching. "Dial M for Murder" produces none of these things. On the other hand, it was originally shot in 3D. The 3D effects of the movie are very subtle. It's more like watching a theater play than a movie. I liked this quite a lot. It makes the film quite pleasant. I don't like those movies where 3D is all about projecting things out of the screen just for scares. I would like more 3D movies using this kind of effect. In overall, I enjoyed watching it. And the 3D is a plus. That's why I gave it 5 stars. It isn't great, but if you want to chill watching an easy film, this could be it. The 3D is definitely a plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My last two viewings of Alfred Hitchcock's work before this film were "Rope" and "Strangers on a Train". What do all three films have in common? They are all based around the theory that one can commit the perfect murder and like "Rope" this film is once again an adaptation of a play. In "Dial M for Murder" Tony Wendice discovers that his wife Margot has been having an affair and after stealing a letter sent from her secret lover he uses it to blackmail an old college friend of his Charles Swann. The perfect murder in this film sees Swann follow a precise set of instructions that are based around a phone call made by Tony who would himself have the perfect alibi. When things do not go to plan, Tony Wendice improvises a brilliant plan B that would see his wife framed for the murder of Swann. The screenplay is superb, the film is 105 minutes long and largely takes place in one room, yet our interest is engaged for the full 105 minutes as we listen carefully to every line that is spoken. Every line is greatly delivered by the cast and each character brings their own unique personality, the screenplay is so intelligent and tight that it plays like a classic Agatha Christie murder tale, we are engaged so closely to the tale as it keeps us thinking throughout. We listen to each line of dialogue, searching for clues as the landscape changes throughout, the characters know things we do not and we are scrambling to work out who knows what and what will be the end for each character. The film's lead stars Ray Milland and his wife Grace Kelly are both superb. Milland gives a performance you would expect from a Hitchcock lead man such as Grant or Stewart, he is calm, intelligent and ruthless, although what he is doing is wrong we do not really oppose his evil plan to start. But the beautiful Grace Kelly steals the show as we really sympathise with her following her wrongful verdict of guilty, she shows her talent in this film in what was a great year for her, also starring in Hitchcock's more famous "Rear Window". I have to give a mention to another actor who I was very much impressed by. John Williams is superb as the detective who becomes involved in the case, his character combines the serious element of the crime with humour, he provides some great and memorable dialogue and is the character that engages our interest the most throughout the second half of the film. "Dial M for Murder" is another excellent Hitchcock film that I have seen from the great director, certainly one of his stronger and more enjoyable efforts. It has the same elements of many of his other films but feels very much different, it is not a murder mystery as we no exactly who murdered who but it feels like one because of the way we are constantly engaged in the story and its dialogue as we eagerly wait for the film's conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hitchcock's Dial M for Murder is an adaptation of the successful Broadway play of the same name by Frederick Knott. The movie was shot in 3-D, since in 1953 the movies Bwana Devil and House of Wax started a 3-D craze. But that lasted just after the release of Dial M, and therefore this movie was mostly played in 2-D. Because it's mainly set in an apartment's living room, the movie was shot in only 36 days. Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an ex professional tennis player who retired because his wife Margot (Grace Kelly) complained about his busy schedule and started an affair with Mark Halliday (Robert Cummings). Out of jealousy, Tony decides to meet with an old acquaintance to blackmail him into murdering his wife by following a plan Tony alone devised. Being an adaptation of a play, the movie is primarily based on smart dialogue that carries the plot and manages to keep us interested while the characters try to solve the mystery, even though we know from the beginning what has happened. This is one of the things I liked the most about the movie. Then, there is the great acting: Ray Milland is constantly indifferent, cold, extremely rational and doesn't let emotions interfere with his horrid plan. Grace Kelly is a typical damsel in distress but doesn't know who her saviour is supposed to be, and Robert Cummings would do anything for her. All of them, along with the supporting cast, are very convincing in their roles. That's probably why it's easy to empathise with everyone, no matter their actions. Since, like I said, Dial M was mostly shot in a living room, many people have talked about the movie as "claustrophobic". I would rather say the lack of open spaces gives this movie a feeling of inevitability and hopelessness  nobody can escape their fate and we're all responsible for our actions. This also proves how much Dial M relies on good acting. Another thing I loved about this movie (and old movies in general) is the thoughtful use of soundtrack. Nowadays, the majority of mainstream movies try to evoke feelings in the audience by being too loud all the time, and that's when a soundtrack loses its purpose. In conclusion, Dial M might not appeal to all Hitchcock fans because of the lack of action and long dialogues, but it's an excellent movie nobody should miss. Rating: 8/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Retooling the perfect murder when it turns out to be imperfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an aging tennis pro who learns that his wealthy wife (Grace Kelly as Margot) has a lover (Bob Cummings as Mark). Tony figures out what might have led his wife astray and fixes it - he gets a real job with a real boss. But what if his wife divorces him? He'd get nothing! Realizing that getting a job may have enlarged his wife's respect for him but not diminished her affection for the lover, he spends a large amount of time figuring out a perfect way to kill his wife so that he can inherit her money. Tony has nothing personal against Margot and her infidelity, he just can't take the chance of winding up penniless. He can't do the job himself - the husband is always the prime suspect in such matters. So, he must find someone who will be willing to do the job for him. He's not the type who hangs with organized crime types, so he has to find someone already guilty of murder but yet untouched by the law and get that person to agree to do the job for him. It sounds perfect. Tony even has the lover with him as an alibi the night the murder is to occur. But everything does go wrong, and now Tony has to retool his perfect murder. Who will kill Margot for Tony? The law of course! Watch this great little thriller and see what I'm talking about. Most directors lose a step after they are in their 50's. There is just something about their creativity that just fizzles, and I say that as someone who is 55 myself. But here Hitchcock is at age 55 doing some of his best and most clever work. This one is so ironic it could be considered a film noir if not for the elegance of the players, the setting, and that great score. Just one thing that nobody ever seems to talk about much - did anybody else want Tony to get away with it just a little? He does play it icy cold and smiling throughout, but when he makes the phone call that sets everything in motion, you can see the regret in his face - the fact that he hates that this is the way that it must be. Meanwhile my sympathy was not with the cheating wife and especially the false friend Mark Halliday. The guy was sleeping with a man's wife while pretending to be his friend, even carrying on a kissing session with her while the husband went down the street for an errand. If you're going to steal someone's wife, let it be a stranger's. Don't shake the guy's hand, eat the guy's food, and accept his hospitality and take his wife behind his back too. Maybe Hitch wanted the audience to be conflicted though, maybe he was trying to add to the complexity of the situation with this added dimension. At any rate, watch this if you get a chance. In fact, watch it more than once. You'll always see something you didn't see before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    korneel-brq
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant script, good acting and nice setting. This movie is definitely worth watching every minute. It goes off with a strong start with the dialogue between Swann and Wendice, which is already intricate on itself. Then the development leaving Wendice to bend the entire event to let once again someone else (the justice system) kill his wife, and then yet again Halliday discovering the truth whilst fantasizing is so quickly and natural. A murder plot that was worked through down to the smallest details, I wouldn't like to be an enemy to Alfred Hitchcock.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific performances, especially enjoyed Bob Cummings and John Williams. A real gem!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only problem that some people may have with this film is that it's very talky, and filmed almost entirely in an apartment. However, that in a way was the brilliance of Hitchcock here. Talky, because it was a psychological drama about a man planning to have his wife murdered, and most of the talking is how he suckers a man into doing it for him, and then how he gets out of that after his wife kills that man during the attack. It virtually all takes place in the apartment, because this was a film translation of a play, although it doesn't really have the feeling of a play like a few films have. The cast here is excellent. Top billing went to Ray Milland as the murderous husband, and here is another case of an actor who today is very underrated. Milland, who has more dialog in the film than anyone else, handles it brilliantly. Grace Kelly is the wife. I'm not a particular fan of Kelly, but she was very good here...I can't think of a thing about her acting here to criticize. Robert Cummings, who devoted much of his career to comedy, had a few very fine dramatic turns, and this is one of them (another is in Hitchcock's "Saboteur"). As good as Cummings was in comedy, perhaps he missed his mark...he could have easily been a straight dramatic actor! He plays it just right here. A real treat is character actor John Williams, who steals many of the scenes he is in...as Chief Police Inspector. As good as the 3 leads are, Williams makes the film special. So sit back and relax with a great Hitchcock film, though it is not one of his bigger hits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In stories things usually turn out the way the author wants them to; and in real life they don't... always. [] No, I'm afraid my murders would be something like my bridge: I'd make some stupid mistake and never realize it until I found everybody was looking at me. The scene in which the above dialogue takes place seems to be key to Dial M for Murder, as it stakes out both the theme and the inevitable outcome of the film. The idea of the perfect crime, the failure of it and the idea that crime never pays run throughout many of Alfred Hitchcock's films. It's also the one theme of his that I'm the least interested in as knowing where the film is going takes away some of the excitement. For instance, when the supposedly perfect murder of Grace Kelly goes wrong, but she is still arrested and sentenced to death, it is a brilliantly cruel and sadistic twist, but the stakes would be even higher if you thought there was any chance she wouldn't make it. Complaints about predictability notwithstanding, Hitchcock still shines in his execution. There's a real elegance and assurance about the way the characters act and interact and the way the plot, with some ingenious details revolving for instance around the keys to the apartment, unfolds. Hitchcock can still squeeze a lot of tension into certain scenes. When Anthony Dawson is standing behind the curtain during the attempted murder waiting for that call, Hitchcock makes the audience sweat too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty darn good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice would quite like his wife's money without the hassle of having her to go with it: how fortunate then that he makes contact with a would-be murderer who he can blackmail/bribe. Despite my advancing years, I had managed not to see Hitchcock's Dial M For Murder until the 3D Bluray arrived with my postman. So this comes from the point of view of someone whose first viewing of this film is of the remastered version in 3D (and filmed in 3D rather than a post-production conversion). From the distance of 2013, this film doesn't have much in the way of surprises - the story, while a good one, is nonetheless fairly familiar. And its stage origin shows - despite a handful of scenes in other locations, this remains essentially a single set drama with a small cast. So, given that we have something which is not necessarily the most exciting property in the world, what has Hitchcock done with it? He has drawn excellent performances from his cast, to start with, and he has made the very most of his single set. The camera prowls around it, constantly seeking new viewpoints to reinforce the dramatic impact of what is happening, lighting changes create a number of different moods - impersonal, comforting, dark and menacing - and the mobility of the camera is all the more remarkable given the bulkiness of the 3D rig. For the visual impact of the film, especially in 3D, is amazing. The remastering is excellent, with pin-sharp image and saturated colours. And the 3D is stunning. Hitchcock joins a scant few directors as an artist who understands how to use 3D as an artistic tool to enhance what appears on screen. Nothing is going to jump out of the screen at you, but the true 3D image has staggering depth, particularly when the camera is on the move, and this adds enormously to the visual appreciation of the film. This film should be compulsory viewing in 3D for any director who is currently in the position of having to make a 3D film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classy Thriller that Mixes Things Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dial M for Murder: I've always liked the remake of Dial M for Murder, A Perfect Murder. Consequently, seeing the remake before the original, I knew every twist that was coming my way. Though I think A Perfect Murder has a better female lead, setting, and tone, Dial M for Murder is a classy thriller that mixes things up; it's a great project for Hitchcock to pour his energy into. Dial M for Murder originates from a stage play, it's evident here. This is a movie who's driving force is the dialogue exchanges between its characters. It's very talky. The cinematography has some odd shots, but that's forgiven for the gruesome action. "The scene" is the most violent scene Hitchcock has ever directed. Dial M For Murder dissects the gravity of a murder, every possible thing that could lead the detectives to the guilty one. The film is terrific until the final two minutes which is out of tone with the mood the film held for 100 minutes. Dial M for Murder's ultimately says that everyone is manipulative and to watch out backs (literally Grace Kelly, watch your back). Rating: 9/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply exhilarating !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aditya panwar
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    {Sir}Hitchcock is not a new face to crime, thriller and mystery genre, but dial m for murder is a piece of utter brilliance and mastery.Well, if you love watching movies while lying on bed with laptop at the front prepare to rise and get immersed in this cinema. Movie never takes time to develop characters, it just shoves the plot right into the viewers' face right at the beginning and yet we are so into the premise of the cinema like we are living it and characters build themselves. Actors have done their jobs exceptionally well from Grace Kelly to Robert Cummings, from Roy Milland to John Williams everyone is perfect and simply awesome.With the subtlety Milland plays Wendice is truly unbelievable. You will definitely succumb to his devilish yet charming personality.In short I am now a great fan of Roy Milland..!! Dialogues and the screenplay are very well executed. there are no clich&eacute;s or not a single detail is cheesy like today's mystery movies with exception of a few. This simply is one of best movies ever made. Sir, I salute you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but not great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joaco-h-s
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is entertaining, but isn't one of Hitchcock's greats. There isn't much suspense. Most of it is just about the police investigation and about the "perfect crime". I was searching for something to keep me on my toes. A movie where I can't stop watching. "Dial M for Murder" produces none of these things. On the other hand, it was originally shot in 3D. The 3D effects of the movie are very subtle. It's more like watching a theater play than a movie. I liked this quite a lot. It makes the film quite pleasant. I don't like those movies where 3D is all about projecting things out of the screen just for scares. I would like more 3D movies using this kind of effect. In overall, I enjoyed watching it. And the 3D is a plus. That's why I gave it 5 stars. It isn't great, but if you want to chill watching an easy film, this could be it. The 3D is definitely a plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My last two viewings of Alfred Hitchcock's work before this film were "Rope" and "Strangers on a Train". What do all three films have in common? They are all based around the theory that one can commit the perfect murder and like "Rope" this film is once again an adaptation of a play. In "Dial M for Murder" Tony Wendice discovers that his wife Margot has been having an affair and after stealing a letter sent from her secret lover he uses it to blackmail an old college friend of his Charles Swann. The perfect murder in this film sees Swann follow a precise set of instructions that are based around a phone call made by Tony who would himself have the perfect alibi. When things do not go to plan, Tony Wendice improvises a brilliant plan B that would see his wife framed for the murder of Swann. The screenplay is superb, the film is 105 minutes long and largely takes place in one room, yet our interest is engaged for the full 105 minutes as we listen carefully to every line that is spoken. Every line is greatly delivered by the cast and each character brings their own unique personality, the screenplay is so intelligent and tight that it plays like a classic Agatha Christie murder tale, we are engaged so closely to the tale as it keeps us thinking throughout. We listen to each line of dialogue, searching for clues as the landscape changes throughout, the characters know things we do not and we are scrambling to work out who knows what and what will be the end for each character. The film's lead stars Ray Milland and his wife Grace Kelly are both superb. Milland gives a performance you would expect from a Hitchcock lead man such as Grant or Stewart, he is calm, intelligent and ruthless, although what he is doing is wrong we do not really oppose his evil plan to start. But the beautiful Grace Kelly steals the show as we really sympathise with her following her wrongful verdict of guilty, she shows her talent in this film in what was a great year for her, also starring in Hitchcock's more famous "Rear Window". I have to give a mention to another actor who I was very much impressed by. John Williams is superb as the detective who becomes involved in the case, his character combines the serious element of the crime with humour, he provides some great and memorable dialogue and is the character that engages our interest the most throughout the second half of the film. "Dial M for Murder" is another excellent Hitchcock film that I have seen from the great director, certainly one of his stronger and more enjoyable efforts. It has the same elements of many of his other films but feels very much different, it is not a murder mystery as we no exactly who murdered who but it feels like one because of the way we are constantly engaged in the story and its dialogue as we eagerly wait for the film's conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hitchcock's Dial M for Murder is an adaptation of the successful Broadway play of the same name by Frederick Knott. The movie was shot in 3-D, since in 1953 the movies Bwana Devil and House of Wax started a 3-D craze. But that lasted just after the release of Dial M, and therefore this movie was mostly played in 2-D. Because it's mainly set in an apartment's living room, the movie was shot in only 36 days. Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an ex professional tennis player who retired because his wife Margot (Grace Kelly) complained about his busy schedule and started an affair with Mark Halliday (Robert Cummings). Out of jealousy, Tony decides to meet with an old acquaintance to blackmail him into murdering his wife by following a plan Tony alone devised. Being an adaptation of a play, the movie is primarily based on smart dialogue that carries the plot and manages to keep us interested while the characters try to solve the mystery, even though we know from the beginning what has happened. This is one of the things I liked the most about the movie. Then, there is the great acting: Ray Milland is constantly indifferent, cold, extremely rational and doesn't let emotions interfere with his horrid plan. Grace Kelly is a typical damsel in distress but doesn't know who her saviour is supposed to be, and Robert Cummings would do anything for her. All of them, along with the supporting cast, are very convincing in their roles. That's probably why it's easy to empathise with everyone, no matter their actions. Since, like I said, Dial M was mostly shot in a living room, many people have talked about the movie as "claustrophobic". I would rather say the lack of open spaces gives this movie a feeling of inevitability and hopelessness  nobody can escape their fate and we're all responsible for our actions. This also proves how much Dial M relies on good acting. Another thing I loved about this movie (and old movies in general) is the thoughtful use of soundtrack. Nowadays, the majority of mainstream movies try to evoke feelings in the audience by being too loud all the time, and that's when a soundtrack loses its purpose. In conclusion, Dial M might not appeal to all Hitchcock fans because of the lack of action and long dialogues, but it's an excellent movie nobody should miss. Rating: 8/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Retooling the perfect murder when it turns out to be imperfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an aging tennis pro who learns that his wealthy wife (Grace Kelly as Margot) has a lover (Bob Cummings as Mark). Tony figures out what might have led his wife astray and fixes it - he gets a real job with a real boss. But what if his wife divorces him? He'd get nothing! Realizing that getting a job may have enlarged his wife's respect for him but not diminished her affection for the lover, he spends a large amount of time figuring out a perfect way to kill his wife so that he can inherit her money. Tony has nothing personal against Margot and her infidelity, he just can't take the chance of winding up penniless. He can't do the job himself - the husband is always the prime suspect in such matters. So, he must find someone who will be willing to do the job for him. He's not the type who hangs with organized crime types, so he has to find someone already guilty of murder but yet untouched by the law and get that person to agree to do the job for him. It sounds perfect. Tony even has the lover with him as an alibi the night the murder is to occur. But everything does go wrong, and now Tony has to retool his perfect murder. Who will kill Margot for Tony? The law of course! Watch this great little thriller and see what I'm talking about. Most directors lose a step after they are in their 50's. There is just something about their creativity that just fizzles, and I say that as someone who is 55 myself. But here Hitchcock is at age 55 doing some of his best and most clever work. This one is so ironic it could be considered a film noir if not for the elegance of the players, the setting, and that great score. Just one thing that nobody ever seems to talk about much - did anybody else want Tony to get away with it just a little? He does play it icy cold and smiling throughout, but when he makes the phone call that sets everything in motion, you can see the regret in his face - the fact that he hates that this is the way that it must be. Meanwhile my sympathy was not with the cheating wife and especially the false friend Mark Halliday. The guy was sleeping with a man's wife while pretending to be his friend, even carrying on a kissing session with her while the husband went down the street for an errand. If you're going to steal someone's wife, let it be a stranger's. Don't shake the guy's hand, eat the guy's food, and accept his hospitality and take his wife behind his back too. Maybe Hitch wanted the audience to be conflicted though, maybe he was trying to add to the complexity of the situation with this added dimension. At any rate, watch this if you get a chance. In fact, watch it more than once. You'll always see something you didn't see before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    korneel-brq
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant script, good acting and nice setting. This movie is definitely worth watching every minute. It goes off with a strong start with the dialogue between Swann and Wendice, which is already intricate on itself. Then the development leaving Wendice to bend the entire event to let once again someone else (the justice system) kill his wife, and then yet again Halliday discovering the truth whilst fantasizing is so quickly and natural. A murder plot that was worked through down to the smallest details, I wouldn't like to be an enemy to Alfred Hitchcock.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific performances, especially enjoyed Bob Cummings and John Williams. A real gem!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only problem that some people may have with this film is that it's very talky, and filmed almost entirely in an apartment. However, that in a way was the brilliance of Hitchcock here. Talky, because it was a psychological drama about a man planning to have his wife murdered, and most of the talking is how he suckers a man into doing it for him, and then how he gets out of that after his wife kills that man during the attack. It virtually all takes place in the apartment, because this was a film translation of a play, although it doesn't really have the feeling of a play like a few films have. The cast here is excellent. Top billing went to Ray Milland as the murderous husband, and here is another case of an actor who today is very underrated. Milland, who has more dialog in the film than anyone else, handles it brilliantly. Grace Kelly is the wife. I'm not a particular fan of Kelly, but she was very good here...I can't think of a thing about her acting here to criticize. Robert Cummings, who devoted much of his career to comedy, had a few very fine dramatic turns, and this is one of them (another is in Hitchcock's "Saboteur"). As good as Cummings was in comedy, perhaps he missed his mark...he could have easily been a straight dramatic actor! He plays it just right here. A real treat is character actor John Williams, who steals many of the scenes he is in...as Chief Police Inspector. As good as the 3 leads are, Williams makes the film special. So sit back and relax with a great Hitchcock film, though it is not one of his bigger hits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In stories things usually turn out the way the author wants them to; and in real life they don't... always. [] No, I'm afraid my murders would be something like my bridge: I'd make some stupid mistake and never realize it until I found everybody was looking at me. The scene in which the above dialogue takes place seems to be key to Dial M for Murder, as it stakes out both the theme and the inevitable outcome of the film. The idea of the perfect crime, the failure of it and the idea that crime never pays run throughout many of Alfred Hitchcock's films. It's also the one theme of his that I'm the least interested in as knowing where the film is going takes away some of the excitement. For instance, when the supposedly perfect murder of Grace Kelly goes wrong, but she is still arrested and sentenced to death, it is a brilliantly cruel and sadistic twist, but the stakes would be even higher if you thought there was any chance she wouldn't make it. Complaints about predictability notwithstanding, Hitchcock still shines in his execution. There's a real elegance and assurance about the way the characters act and interact and the way the plot, with some ingenious details revolving for instance around the keys to the apartment, unfolds. Hitchcock can still squeeze a lot of tension into certain scenes. When Anthony Dawson is standing behind the curtain during the attempted murder waiting for that call, Hitchcock makes the audience sweat too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty darn good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice would quite like his wife's money without the hassle of having her to go with it: how fortunate then that he makes contact with a would-be murderer who he can blackmail/bribe. Despite my advancing years, I had managed not to see Hitchcock's Dial M For Murder until the 3D Bluray arrived with my postman. So this comes from the point of view of someone whose first viewing of this film is of the remastered version in 3D (and filmed in 3D rather than a post-production conversion). From the distance of 2013, this film doesn't have much in the way of surprises - the story, while a good one, is nonetheless fairly familiar. And its stage origin shows - despite a handful of scenes in other locations, this remains essentially a single set drama with a small cast. So, given that we have something which is not necessarily the most exciting property in the world, what has Hitchcock done with it? He has drawn excellent performances from his cast, to start with, and he has made the very most of his single set. The camera prowls around it, constantly seeking new viewpoints to reinforce the dramatic impact of what is happening, lighting changes create a number of different moods - impersonal, comforting, dark and menacing - and the mobility of the camera is all the more remarkable given the bulkiness of the 3D rig. For the visual impact of the film, especially in 3D, is amazing. The remastering is excellent, with pin-sharp image and saturated colours. And the 3D is stunning. Hitchcock joins a scant few directors as an artist who understands how to use 3D as an artistic tool to enhance what appears on screen. Nothing is going to jump out of the screen at you, but the true 3D image has staggering depth, particularly when the camera is on the move, and this adds enormously to the visual appreciation of the film. This film should be compulsory viewing in 3D for any director who is currently in the position of having to make a 3D film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classy Thriller that Mixes Things Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dial M for Murder: I've always liked the remake of Dial M for Murder, A Perfect Murder. Consequently, seeing the remake before the original, I knew every twist that was coming my way. Though I think A Perfect Murder has a better female lead, setting, and tone, Dial M for Murder is a classy thriller that mixes things up; it's a great project for Hitchcock to pour his energy into. Dial M for Murder originates from a stage play, it's evident here. This is a movie who's driving force is the dialogue exchanges between its characters. It's very talky. The cinematography has some odd shots, but that's forgiven for the gruesome action. "The scene" is the most violent scene Hitchcock has ever directed. Dial M For Murder dissects the gravity of a murder, every possible thing that could lead the detectives to the guilty one. The film is terrific until the final two minutes which is out of tone with the mood the film held for 100 minutes. Dial M for Murder's ultimately says that everyone is manipulative and to watch out backs (literally Grace Kelly, watch your back). Rating: 9/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply exhilarating !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aditya panwar
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    {Sir}Hitchcock is not a new face to crime, thriller and mystery genre, but dial m for murder is a piece of utter brilliance and mastery.Well, if you love watching movies while lying on bed with laptop at the front prepare to rise and get immersed in this cinema. Movie never takes time to develop characters, it just shoves the plot right into the viewers' face right at the beginning and yet we are so into the premise of the cinema like we are living it and characters build themselves. Actors have done their jobs exceptionally well from Grace Kelly to Robert Cummings, from Roy Milland to John Williams everyone is perfect and simply awesome.With the subtlety Milland plays Wendice is truly unbelievable. You will definitely succumb to his devilish yet charming personality.In short I am now a great fan of Roy Milland..!! Dialogues and the screenplay are very well executed. there are no clich&eacute;s or not a single detail is cheesy like today's mystery movies with exception of a few. This simply is one of best movies ever made. Sir, I salute you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but not great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joaco-h-s
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is entertaining, but isn't one of Hitchcock's greats. There isn't much suspense. Most of it is just about the police investigation and about the "perfect crime". I was searching for something to keep me on my toes. A movie where I can't stop watching. "Dial M for Murder" produces none of these things. On the other hand, it was originally shot in 3D. The 3D effects of the movie are very subtle. It's more like watching a theater play than a movie. I liked this quite a lot. It makes the film quite pleasant. I don't like those movies where 3D is all about projecting things out of the screen just for scares. I would like more 3D movies using this kind of effect. In overall, I enjoyed watching it. And the 3D is a plus. That's why I gave it 5 stars. It isn't great, but if you want to chill watching an easy film, this could be it. The 3D is definitely a plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My last two viewings of Alfred Hitchcock's work before this film were "Rope" and "Strangers on a Train". What do all three films have in common? They are all based around the theory that one can commit the perfect murder and like "Rope" this film is once again an adaptation of a play. In "Dial M for Murder" Tony Wendice discovers that his wife Margot has been having an affair and after stealing a letter sent from her secret lover he uses it to blackmail an old college friend of his Charles Swann. The perfect murder in this film sees Swann follow a precise set of instructions that are based around a phone call made by Tony who would himself have the perfect alibi. When things do not go to plan, Tony Wendice improvises a brilliant plan B that would see his wife framed for the murder of Swann. The screenplay is superb, the film is 105 minutes long and largely takes place in one room, yet our interest is engaged for the full 105 minutes as we listen carefully to every line that is spoken. Every line is greatly delivered by the cast and each character brings their own unique personality, the screenplay is so intelligent and tight that it plays like a classic Agatha Christie murder tale, we are engaged so closely to the tale as it keeps us thinking throughout. We listen to each line of dialogue, searching for clues as the landscape changes throughout, the characters know things we do not and we are scrambling to work out who knows what and what will be the end for each character. The film's lead stars Ray Milland and his wife Grace Kelly are both superb. Milland gives a performance you would expect from a Hitchcock lead man such as Grant or Stewart, he is calm, intelligent and ruthless, although what he is doing is wrong we do not really oppose his evil plan to start. But the beautiful Grace Kelly steals the show as we really sympathise with her following her wrongful verdict of guilty, she shows her talent in this film in what was a great year for her, also starring in Hitchcock's more famous "Rear Window". I have to give a mention to another actor who I was very much impressed by. John Williams is superb as the detective who becomes involved in the case, his character combines the serious element of the crime with humour, he provides some great and memorable dialogue and is the character that engages our interest the most throughout the second half of the film. "Dial M for Murder" is another excellent Hitchcock film that I have seen from the great director, certainly one of his stronger and more enjoyable efforts. It has the same elements of many of his other films but feels very much different, it is not a murder mystery as we no exactly who murdered who but it feels like one because of the way we are constantly engaged in the story and its dialogue as we eagerly wait for the film's conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hitchcock's Dial M for Murder is an adaptation of the successful Broadway play of the same name by Frederick Knott. The movie was shot in 3-D, since in 1953 the movies Bwana Devil and House of Wax started a 3-D craze. But that lasted just after the release of Dial M, and therefore this movie was mostly played in 2-D. Because it's mainly set in an apartment's living room, the movie was shot in only 36 days. Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an ex professional tennis player who retired because his wife Margot (Grace Kelly) complained about his busy schedule and started an affair with Mark Halliday (Robert Cummings). Out of jealousy, Tony decides to meet with an old acquaintance to blackmail him into murdering his wife by following a plan Tony alone devised. Being an adaptation of a play, the movie is primarily based on smart dialogue that carries the plot and manages to keep us interested while the characters try to solve the mystery, even though we know from the beginning what has happened. This is one of the things I liked the most about the movie. Then, there is the great acting: Ray Milland is constantly indifferent, cold, extremely rational and doesn't let emotions interfere with his horrid plan. Grace Kelly is a typical damsel in distress but doesn't know who her saviour is supposed to be, and Robert Cummings would do anything for her. All of them, along with the supporting cast, are very convincing in their roles. That's probably why it's easy to empathise with everyone, no matter their actions. Since, like I said, Dial M was mostly shot in a living room, many people have talked about the movie as "claustrophobic". I would rather say the lack of open spaces gives this movie a feeling of inevitability and hopelessness  nobody can escape their fate and we're all responsible for our actions. This also proves how much Dial M relies on good acting. Another thing I loved about this movie (and old movies in general) is the thoughtful use of soundtrack. Nowadays, the majority of mainstream movies try to evoke feelings in the audience by being too loud all the time, and that's when a soundtrack loses its purpose. In conclusion, Dial M might not appeal to all Hitchcock fans because of the lack of action and long dialogues, but it's an excellent movie nobody should miss. Rating: 8/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Retooling the perfect murder when it turns out to be imperfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an aging tennis pro who learns that his wealthy wife (Grace Kelly as Margot) has a lover (Bob Cummings as Mark). Tony figures out what might have led his wife astray and fixes it - he gets a real job with a real boss. But what if his wife divorces him? He'd get nothing! Realizing that getting a job may have enlarged his wife's respect for him but not diminished her affection for the lover, he spends a large amount of time figuring out a perfect way to kill his wife so that he can inherit her money. Tony has nothing personal against Margot and her infidelity, he just can't take the chance of winding up penniless. He can't do the job himself - the husband is always the prime suspect in such matters. So, he must find someone who will be willing to do the job for him. He's not the type who hangs with organized crime types, so he has to find someone already guilty of murder but yet untouched by the law and get that person to agree to do the job for him. It sounds perfect. Tony even has the lover with him as an alibi the night the murder is to occur. But everything does go wrong, and now Tony has to retool his perfect murder. Who will kill Margot for Tony? The law of course! Watch this great little thriller and see what I'm talking about. Most directors lose a step after they are in their 50's. There is just something about their creativity that just fizzles, and I say that as someone who is 55 myself. But here Hitchcock is at age 55 doing some of his best and most clever work. This one is so ironic it could be considered a film noir if not for the elegance of the players, the setting, and that great score. Just one thing that nobody ever seems to talk about much - did anybody else want Tony to get away with it just a little? He does play it icy cold and smiling throughout, but when he makes the phone call that sets everything in motion, you can see the regret in his face - the fact that he hates that this is the way that it must be. Meanwhile my sympathy was not with the cheating wife and especially the false friend Mark Halliday. The guy was sleeping with a man's wife while pretending to be his friend, even carrying on a kissing session with her while the husband went down the street for an errand. If you're going to steal someone's wife, let it be a stranger's. Don't shake the guy's hand, eat the guy's food, and accept his hospitality and take his wife behind his back too. Maybe Hitch wanted the audience to be conflicted though, maybe he was trying to add to the complexity of the situation with this added dimension. At any rate, watch this if you get a chance. In fact, watch it more than once. You'll always see something you didn't see before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    korneel-brq
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant script, good acting and nice setting. This movie is definitely worth watching every minute. It goes off with a strong start with the dialogue between Swann and Wendice, which is already intricate on itself. Then the development leaving Wendice to bend the entire event to let once again someone else (the justice system) kill his wife, and then yet again Halliday discovering the truth whilst fantasizing is so quickly and natural. A murder plot that was worked through down to the smallest details, I wouldn't like to be an enemy to Alfred Hitchcock.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific performances, especially enjoyed Bob Cummings and John Williams. A real gem!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only problem that some people may have with this film is that it's very talky, and filmed almost entirely in an apartment. However, that in a way was the brilliance of Hitchcock here. Talky, because it was a psychological drama about a man planning to have his wife murdered, and most of the talking is how he suckers a man into doing it for him, and then how he gets out of that after his wife kills that man during the attack. It virtually all takes place in the apartment, because this was a film translation of a play, although it doesn't really have the feeling of a play like a few films have. The cast here is excellent. Top billing went to Ray Milland as the murderous husband, and here is another case of an actor who today is very underrated. Milland, who has more dialog in the film than anyone else, handles it brilliantly. Grace Kelly is the wife. I'm not a particular fan of Kelly, but she was very good here...I can't think of a thing about her acting here to criticize. Robert Cummings, who devoted much of his career to comedy, had a few very fine dramatic turns, and this is one of them (another is in Hitchcock's "Saboteur"). As good as Cummings was in comedy, perhaps he missed his mark...he could have easily been a straight dramatic actor! He plays it just right here. A real treat is character actor John Williams, who steals many of the scenes he is in...as Chief Police Inspector. As good as the 3 leads are, Williams makes the film special. So sit back and relax with a great Hitchcock film, though it is not one of his bigger hits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In stories things usually turn out the way the author wants them to; and in real life they don't... always. [] No, I'm afraid my murders would be something like my bridge: I'd make some stupid mistake and never realize it until I found everybody was looking at me. The scene in which the above dialogue takes place seems to be key to Dial M for Murder, as it stakes out both the theme and the inevitable outcome of the film. The idea of the perfect crime, the failure of it and the idea that crime never pays run throughout many of Alfred Hitchcock's films. It's also the one theme of his that I'm the least interested in as knowing where the film is going takes away some of the excitement. For instance, when the supposedly perfect murder of Grace Kelly goes wrong, but she is still arrested and sentenced to death, it is a brilliantly cruel and sadistic twist, but the stakes would be even higher if you thought there was any chance she wouldn't make it. Complaints about predictability notwithstanding, Hitchcock still shines in his execution. There's a real elegance and assurance about the way the characters act and interact and the way the plot, with some ingenious details revolving for instance around the keys to the apartment, unfolds. Hitchcock can still squeeze a lot of tension into certain scenes. When Anthony Dawson is standing behind the curtain during the attempted murder waiting for that call, Hitchcock makes the audience sweat too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty darn good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice would quite like his wife's money without the hassle of having her to go with it: how fortunate then that he makes contact with a would-be murderer who he can blackmail/bribe. Despite my advancing years, I had managed not to see Hitchcock's Dial M For Murder until the 3D Bluray arrived with my postman. So this comes from the point of view of someone whose first viewing of this film is of the remastered version in 3D (and filmed in 3D rather than a post-production conversion). From the distance of 2013, this film doesn't have much in the way of surprises - the story, while a good one, is nonetheless fairly familiar. And its stage origin shows - despite a handful of scenes in other locations, this remains essentially a single set drama with a small cast. So, given that we have something which is not necessarily the most exciting property in the world, what has Hitchcock done with it? He has drawn excellent performances from his cast, to start with, and he has made the very most of his single set. The camera prowls around it, constantly seeking new viewpoints to reinforce the dramatic impact of what is happening, lighting changes create a number of different moods - impersonal, comforting, dark and menacing - and the mobility of the camera is all the more remarkable given the bulkiness of the 3D rig. For the visual impact of the film, especially in 3D, is amazing. The remastering is excellent, with pin-sharp image and saturated colours. And the 3D is stunning. Hitchcock joins a scant few directors as an artist who understands how to use 3D as an artistic tool to enhance what appears on screen. Nothing is going to jump out of the screen at you, but the true 3D image has staggering depth, particularly when the camera is on the move, and this adds enormously to the visual appreciation of the film. This film should be compulsory viewing in 3D for any director who is currently in the position of having to make a 3D film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classy Thriller that Mixes Things Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dial M for Murder: I've always liked the remake of Dial M for Murder, A Perfect Murder. Consequently, seeing the remake before the original, I knew every twist that was coming my way. Though I think A Perfect Murder has a better female lead, setting, and tone, Dial M for Murder is a classy thriller that mixes things up; it's a great project for Hitchcock to pour his energy into. Dial M for Murder originates from a stage play, it's evident here. This is a movie who's driving force is the dialogue exchanges between its characters. It's very talky. The cinematography has some odd shots, but that's forgiven for the gruesome action. "The scene" is the most violent scene Hitchcock has ever directed. Dial M For Murder dissects the gravity of a murder, every possible thing that could lead the detectives to the guilty one. The film is terrific until the final two minutes which is out of tone with the mood the film held for 100 minutes. Dial M for Murder's ultimately says that everyone is manipulative and to watch out backs (literally Grace Kelly, watch your back). Rating: 9/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply exhilarating !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aditya panwar
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    {Sir}Hitchcock is not a new face to crime, thriller and mystery genre, but dial m for murder is a piece of utter brilliance and mastery.Well, if you love watching movies while lying on bed with laptop at the front prepare to rise and get immersed in this cinema. Movie never takes time to develop characters, it just shoves the plot right into the viewers' face right at the beginning and yet we are so into the premise of the cinema like we are living it and characters build themselves. Actors have done their jobs exceptionally well from Grace Kelly to Robert Cummings, from Roy Milland to John Williams everyone is perfect and simply awesome.With the subtlety Milland plays Wendice is truly unbelievable. You will definitely succumb to his devilish yet charming personality.In short I am now a great fan of Roy Milland..!! Dialogues and the screenplay are very well executed. there are no clich&eacute;s or not a single detail is cheesy like today's mystery movies with exception of a few. This simply is one of best movies ever made. Sir, I salute you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but not great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joaco-h-s
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is entertaining, but isn't one of Hitchcock's greats. There isn't much suspense. Most of it is just about the police investigation and about the "perfect crime". I was searching for something to keep me on my toes. A movie where I can't stop watching. "Dial M for Murder" produces none of these things. On the other hand, it was originally shot in 3D. The 3D effects of the movie are very subtle. It's more like watching a theater play than a movie. I liked this quite a lot. It makes the film quite pleasant. I don't like those movies where 3D is all about projecting things out of the screen just for scares. I would like more 3D movies using this kind of effect. In overall, I enjoyed watching it. And the 3D is a plus. That's why I gave it 5 stars. It isn't great, but if you want to chill watching an easy film, this could be it. The 3D is definitely a plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My last two viewings of Alfred Hitchcock's work before this film were "Rope" and "Strangers on a Train". What do all three films have in common? They are all based around the theory that one can commit the perfect murder and like "Rope" this film is once again an adaptation of a play. In "Dial M for Murder" Tony Wendice discovers that his wife Margot has been having an affair and after stealing a letter sent from her secret lover he uses it to blackmail an old college friend of his Charles Swann. The perfect murder in this film sees Swann follow a precise set of instructions that are based around a phone call made by Tony who would himself have the perfect alibi. When things do not go to plan, Tony Wendice improvises a brilliant plan B that would see his wife framed for the murder of Swann. The screenplay is superb, the film is 105 minutes long and largely takes place in one room, yet our interest is engaged for the full 105 minutes as we listen carefully to every line that is spoken. Every line is greatly delivered by the cast and each character brings their own unique personality, the screenplay is so intelligent and tight that it plays like a classic Agatha Christie murder tale, we are engaged so closely to the tale as it keeps us thinking throughout. We listen to each line of dialogue, searching for clues as the landscape changes throughout, the characters know things we do not and we are scrambling to work out who knows what and what will be the end for each character. The film's lead stars Ray Milland and his wife Grace Kelly are both superb. Milland gives a performance you would expect from a Hitchcock lead man such as Grant or Stewart, he is calm, intelligent and ruthless, although what he is doing is wrong we do not really oppose his evil plan to start. But the beautiful Grace Kelly steals the show as we really sympathise with her following her wrongful verdict of guilty, she shows her talent in this film in what was a great year for her, also starring in Hitchcock's more famous "Rear Window". I have to give a mention to another actor who I was very much impressed by. John Williams is superb as the detective who becomes involved in the case, his character combines the serious element of the crime with humour, he provides some great and memorable dialogue and is the character that engages our interest the most throughout the second half of the film. "Dial M for Murder" is another excellent Hitchcock film that I have seen from the great director, certainly one of his stronger and more enjoyable efforts. It has the same elements of many of his other films but feels very much different, it is not a murder mystery as we no exactly who murdered who but it feels like one because of the way we are constantly engaged in the story and its dialogue as we eagerly wait for the film's conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hitchcock's Dial M for Murder is an adaptation of the successful Broadway play of the same name by Frederick Knott. The movie was shot in 3-D, since in 1953 the movies Bwana Devil and House of Wax started a 3-D craze. But that lasted just after the release of Dial M, and therefore this movie was mostly played in 2-D. Because it's mainly set in an apartment's living room, the movie was shot in only 36 days. Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an ex professional tennis player who retired because his wife Margot (Grace Kelly) complained about his busy schedule and started an affair with Mark Halliday (Robert Cummings). Out of jealousy, Tony decides to meet with an old acquaintance to blackmail him into murdering his wife by following a plan Tony alone devised. Being an adaptation of a play, the movie is primarily based on smart dialogue that carries the plot and manages to keep us interested while the characters try to solve the mystery, even though we know from the beginning what has happened. This is one of the things I liked the most about the movie. Then, there is the great acting: Ray Milland is constantly indifferent, cold, extremely rational and doesn't let emotions interfere with his horrid plan. Grace Kelly is a typical damsel in distress but doesn't know who her saviour is supposed to be, and Robert Cummings would do anything for her. All of them, along with the supporting cast, are very convincing in their roles. That's probably why it's easy to empathise with everyone, no matter their actions. Since, like I said, Dial M was mostly shot in a living room, many people have talked about the movie as "claustrophobic". I would rather say the lack of open spaces gives this movie a feeling of inevitability and hopelessness  nobody can escape their fate and we're all responsible for our actions. This also proves how much Dial M relies on good acting. Another thing I loved about this movie (and old movies in general) is the thoughtful use of soundtrack. Nowadays, the majority of mainstream movies try to evoke feelings in the audience by being too loud all the time, and that's when a soundtrack loses its purpose. In conclusion, Dial M might not appeal to all Hitchcock fans because of the lack of action and long dialogues, but it's an excellent movie nobody should miss. Rating: 8/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Retooling the perfect murder when it turns out to be imperfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an aging tennis pro who learns that his wealthy wife (Grace Kelly as Margot) has a lover (Bob Cummings as Mark). Tony figures out what might have led his wife astray and fixes it - he gets a real job with a real boss. But what if his wife divorces him? He'd get nothing! Realizing that getting a job may have enlarged his wife's respect for him but not diminished her affection for the lover, he spends a large amount of time figuring out a perfect way to kill his wife so that he can inherit her money. Tony has nothing personal against Margot and her infidelity, he just can't take the chance of winding up penniless. He can't do the job himself - the husband is always the prime suspect in such matters. So, he must find someone who will be willing to do the job for him. He's not the type who hangs with organized crime types, so he has to find someone already guilty of murder but yet untouched by the law and get that person to agree to do the job for him. It sounds perfect. Tony even has the lover with him as an alibi the night the murder is to occur. But everything does go wrong, and now Tony has to retool his perfect murder. Who will kill Margot for Tony? The law of course! Watch this great little thriller and see what I'm talking about. Most directors lose a step after they are in their 50's. There is just something about their creativity that just fizzles, and I say that as someone who is 55 myself. But here Hitchcock is at age 55 doing some of his best and most clever work. This one is so ironic it could be considered a film noir if not for the elegance of the players, the setting, and that great score. Just one thing that nobody ever seems to talk about much - did anybody else want Tony to get away with it just a little? He does play it icy cold and smiling throughout, but when he makes the phone call that sets everything in motion, you can see the regret in his face - the fact that he hates that this is the way that it must be. Meanwhile my sympathy was not with the cheating wife and especially the false friend Mark Halliday. The guy was sleeping with a man's wife while pretending to be his friend, even carrying on a kissing session with her while the husband went down the street for an errand. If you're going to steal someone's wife, let it be a stranger's. Don't shake the guy's hand, eat the guy's food, and accept his hospitality and take his wife behind his back too. Maybe Hitch wanted the audience to be conflicted though, maybe he was trying to add to the complexity of the situation with this added dimension. At any rate, watch this if you get a chance. In fact, watch it more than once. You'll always see something you didn't see before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    korneel-brq
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant script, good acting and nice setting. This movie is definitely worth watching every minute. It goes off with a strong start with the dialogue between Swann and Wendice, which is already intricate on itself. Then the development leaving Wendice to bend the entire event to let once again someone else (the justice system) kill his wife, and then yet again Halliday discovering the truth whilst fantasizing is so quickly and natural. A murder plot that was worked through down to the smallest details, I wouldn't like to be an enemy to Alfred Hitchcock.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific performances, especially enjoyed Bob Cummings and John Williams. A real gem!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only problem that some people may have with this film is that it's very talky, and filmed almost entirely in an apartment. However, that in a way was the brilliance of Hitchcock here. Talky, because it was a psychological drama about a man planning to have his wife murdered, and most of the talking is how he suckers a man into doing it for him, and then how he gets out of that after his wife kills that man during the attack. It virtually all takes place in the apartment, because this was a film translation of a play, although it doesn't really have the feeling of a play like a few films have. The cast here is excellent. Top billing went to Ray Milland as the murderous husband, and here is another case of an actor who today is very underrated. Milland, who has more dialog in the film than anyone else, handles it brilliantly. Grace Kelly is the wife. I'm not a particular fan of Kelly, but she was very good here...I can't think of a thing about her acting here to criticize. Robert Cummings, who devoted much of his career to comedy, had a few very fine dramatic turns, and this is one of them (another is in Hitchcock's "Saboteur"). As good as Cummings was in comedy, perhaps he missed his mark...he could have easily been a straight dramatic actor! He plays it just right here. A real treat is character actor John Williams, who steals many of the scenes he is in...as Chief Police Inspector. As good as the 3 leads are, Williams makes the film special. So sit back and relax with a great Hitchcock film, though it is not one of his bigger hits.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magenta_Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In stories things usually turn out the way the author wants them to; and in real life they don't... always. [] No, I'm afraid my murders would be something like my bridge: I'd make some stupid mistake and never realize it until I found everybody was looking at me. The scene in which the above dialogue takes place seems to be key to Dial M for Murder, as it stakes out both the theme and the inevitable outcome of the film. The idea of the perfect crime, the failure of it and the idea that crime never pays run throughout many of Alfred Hitchcock's films. It's also the one theme of his that I'm the least interested in as knowing where the film is going takes away some of the excitement. For instance, when the supposedly perfect murder of Grace Kelly goes wrong, but she is still arrested and sentenced to death, it is a brilliantly cruel and sadistic twist, but the stakes would be even higher if you thought there was any chance she wouldn't make it. Complaints about predictability notwithstanding, Hitchcock still shines in his execution. There's a real elegance and assurance about the way the characters act and interact and the way the plot, with some ingenious details revolving for instance around the keys to the apartment, unfolds. Hitchcock can still squeeze a lot of tension into certain scenes. When Anthony Dawson is standing behind the curtain during the attempted murder waiting for that call, Hitchcock makes the audience sweat too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty darn good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice would quite like his wife's money without the hassle of having her to go with it: how fortunate then that he makes contact with a would-be murderer who he can blackmail/bribe. Despite my advancing years, I had managed not to see Hitchcock's Dial M For Murder until the 3D Bluray arrived with my postman. So this comes from the point of view of someone whose first viewing of this film is of the remastered version in 3D (and filmed in 3D rather than a post-production conversion). From the distance of 2013, this film doesn't have much in the way of surprises - the story, while a good one, is nonetheless fairly familiar. And its stage origin shows - despite a handful of scenes in other locations, this remains essentially a single set drama with a small cast. So, given that we have something which is not necessarily the most exciting property in the world, what has Hitchcock done with it? He has drawn excellent performances from his cast, to start with, and he has made the very most of his single set. The camera prowls around it, constantly seeking new viewpoints to reinforce the dramatic impact of what is happening, lighting changes create a number of different moods - impersonal, comforting, dark and menacing - and the mobility of the camera is all the more remarkable given the bulkiness of the 3D rig. For the visual impact of the film, especially in 3D, is amazing. The remastering is excellent, with pin-sharp image and saturated colours. And the 3D is stunning. Hitchcock joins a scant few directors as an artist who understands how to use 3D as an artistic tool to enhance what appears on screen. Nothing is going to jump out of the screen at you, but the true 3D image has staggering depth, particularly when the camera is on the move, and this adds enormously to the visual appreciation of the film. This film should be compulsory viewing in 3D for any director who is currently in the position of having to make a 3D film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classy Thriller that Mixes Things Up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dial M for Murder: I've always liked the remake of Dial M for Murder, A Perfect Murder. Consequently, seeing the remake before the original, I knew every twist that was coming my way. Though I think A Perfect Murder has a better female lead, setting, and tone, Dial M for Murder is a classy thriller that mixes things up; it's a great project for Hitchcock to pour his energy into. Dial M for Murder originates from a stage play, it's evident here. This is a movie who's driving force is the dialogue exchanges between its characters. It's very talky. The cinematography has some odd shots, but that's forgiven for the gruesome action. "The scene" is the most violent scene Hitchcock has ever directed. Dial M For Murder dissects the gravity of a murder, every possible thing that could lead the detectives to the guilty one. The film is terrific until the final two minutes which is out of tone with the mood the film held for 100 minutes. Dial M for Murder's ultimately says that everyone is manipulative and to watch out backs (literally Grace Kelly, watch your back). Rating: 9/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply exhilarating !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aditya panwar
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    {Sir}Hitchcock is not a new face to crime, thriller and mystery genre, but dial m for murder is a piece of utter brilliance and mastery.Well, if you love watching movies while lying on bed with laptop at the front prepare to rise and get immersed in this cinema. Movie never takes time to develop characters, it just shoves the plot right into the viewers' face right at the beginning and yet we are so into the premise of the cinema like we are living it and characters build themselves. Actors have done their jobs exceptionally well from Grace Kelly to Robert Cummings, from Roy Milland to John Williams everyone is perfect and simply awesome.With the subtlety Milland plays Wendice is truly unbelievable. You will definitely succumb to his devilish yet charming personality.In short I am now a great fan of Roy Milland..!! Dialogues and the screenplay are very well executed. there are no clich&eacute;s or not a single detail is cheesy like today's mystery movies with exception of a few. This simply is one of best movies ever made. Sir, I salute you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but not great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joaco-h-s
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is entertaining, but isn't one of Hitchcock's greats. There isn't much suspense. Most of it is just about the police investigation and about the "perfect crime". I was searching for something to keep me on my toes. A movie where I can't stop watching. "Dial M for Murder" produces none of these things. On the other hand, it was originally shot in 3D. The 3D effects of the movie are very subtle. It's more like watching a theater play than a movie. I liked this quite a lot. It makes the film quite pleasant. I don't like those movies where 3D is all about projecting things out of the screen just for scares. I would like more 3D movies using this kind of effect. In overall, I enjoyed watching it. And the 3D is a plus. That's why I gave it 5 stars. It isn't great, but if you want to chill watching an easy film, this could be it. The 3D is definitely a plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial M for Murder - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My last two viewings of Alfred Hitchcock's work before this film were "Rope" and "Strangers on a Train". What do all three films have in common? They are all based around the theory that one can commit the perfect murder and like "Rope" this film is once again an adaptation of a play. In "Dial M for Murder" Tony Wendice discovers that his wife Margot has been having an affair and after stealing a letter sent from her secret lover he uses it to blackmail an old college friend of his Charles Swann. The perfect murder in this film sees Swann follow a precise set of instructions that are based around a phone call made by Tony who would himself have the perfect alibi. When things do not go to plan, Tony Wendice improvises a brilliant plan B that would see his wife framed for the murder of Swann. The screenplay is superb, the film is 105 minutes long and largely takes place in one room, yet our interest is engaged for the full 105 minutes as we listen carefully to every line that is spoken. Every line is greatly delivered by the cast and each character brings their own unique personality, the screenplay is so intelligent and tight that it plays like a classic Agatha Christie murder tale, we are engaged so closely to the tale as it keeps us thinking throughout. We listen to each line of dialogue, searching for clues as the landscape changes throughout, the characters know things we do not and we are scrambling to work out who knows what and what will be the end for each character. The film's lead stars Ray Milland and his wife Grace Kelly are both superb. Milland gives a performance you would expect from a Hitchcock lead man such as Grant or Stewart, he is calm, intelligent and ruthless, although what he is doing is wrong we do not really oppose his evil plan to start. But the beautiful Grace Kelly steals the show as we really sympathise with her following her wrongful verdict of guilty, she shows her talent in this film in what was a great year for her, also starring in Hitchcock's more famous "Rear Window". I have to give a mention to another actor who I was very much impressed by. John Williams is superb as the detective who becomes involved in the case, his character combines the serious element of the crime with humour, he provides some great and memorable dialogue and is the character that engages our interest the most throughout the second half of the film. "Dial M for Murder" is another excellent Hitchcock film that I have seen from the great director, certainly one of his stronger and more enjoyable efforts. It has the same elements of many of his other films but feels very much different, it is not a murder mystery as we no exactly who murdered who but it feels like one because of the way we are constantly engaged in the story and its dialogue as we eagerly wait for the film's conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hitchcock's Dial M for Murder is an adaptation of the successful Broadway play of the same name by Frederick Knott. The movie was shot in 3-D, since in 1953 the movies Bwana Devil and House of Wax started a 3-D craze. But that lasted just after the release of Dial M, and therefore this movie was mostly played in 2-D. Because it's mainly set in an apartment's living room, the movie was shot in only 36 days. Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an ex professional tennis player who retired because his wife Margot (Grace Kelly) complained about his busy schedule and started an affair with Mark Halliday (Robert Cummings). Out of jealousy, Tony decides to meet with an old acquaintance to blackmail him into murdering his wife by following a plan Tony alone devised. Being an adaptation of a play, the movie is primarily based on smart dialogue that carries the plot and manages to keep us interested while the characters try to solve the mystery, even though we know from the beginning what has happened. This is one of the things I liked the most about the movie. Then, there is the great acting: Ray Milland is constantly indifferent, cold, extremely rational and doesn't let emotions interfere with his horrid plan. Grace Kelly is a typical damsel in distress but doesn't know who her saviour is supposed to be, and Robert Cummings would do anything for her. All of them, along with the supporting cast, are very convincing in their roles. That's probably why it's easy to empathise with everyone, no matter their actions. Since, like I said, Dial M was mostly shot in a living room, many people have talked about the movie as "claustrophobic". I would rather say the lack of open spaces gives this movie a feeling of inevitability and hopelessness  nobody can escape their fate and we're all responsible for our actions. This also proves how much Dial M relies on good acting. Another thing I loved about this movie (and old movies in general) is the thoughtful use of soundtrack. Nowadays, the majority of mainstream movies try to evoke feelings in the audience by being too loud all the time, and that's when a soundtrack loses its purpose. In conclusion, Dial M might not appeal to all Hitchcock fans because of the lack of action and long dialogues, but it's an excellent movie nobody should miss. Rating: 8/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Retooling the perfect murder when it turns out to be imperfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tony Wendice (Ray Milland) is an aging tennis pro who learns that his wealthy wife (Grace Kelly as Margot) has a lover (Bob Cummings as Mark). Tony figures out what might have led his wife astray and fixes it - he gets a real job with a real boss. But what if his wife divorces him? He'd get nothing! Realizing that getting a job may have enlarged his wife's respect for him but not diminished her affection for the lover, he spends a large amount of time figuring out a perfect way to kill his wife so that he can inherit her money. Tony has nothing personal against Margot and her infidelity, he just can't take the chance of winding up penniless. He can't do the job himself - the husband is always the prime suspect in such matters. So, he must find someone who will be willing to do the job for him. He's not the type who hangs with organized crime types, so he has to find someone already guilty of murder but yet untouched by the law and get that person to agree to do the job for him. It sounds perfect. Tony even has the lover with him as an alibi the night the murder is to occur. But everything does go wrong, and now Tony has to retool his perfect murder. Who will kill Margot for Tony? The law of course! Watch this great little thriller and see what I'm talking about. Most directors lose a step after they are in their 50's. There is just something about their creativity that just fizzles, and I say that as someone who is 55 myself. But here Hitchcock is at age 55 doing some of his best and most clever work. This one is so ironic it could be considered a film noir if not for the elegance of the players, the setting, and that great score. Just one thing that nobody ever seems to talk about much - did anybody else want Tony to get away with it just a little? He does play it icy cold and smiling throughout, but when he makes the phone call that sets everything in motion, you can see the regret in his face - the fact that he hates that this is the way that it must be. Meanwhile my sympathy was not with the cheating wife and especially the false friend Mark Halliday. The guy was sleeping with a man's wife while pretending to be his friend, even carrying on a kissing session with her while the husband went down the street for an errand. If you're going to steal someone's wife, let it be a stranger's. Don't shake the guy's hand, eat the guy's food, and accept his hospitality and take his wife behind his back too. Maybe Hitch wanted the audience to be conflicted though, maybe he was trying to add to the complexity of the situation with this added dimension. At any rate, watch this if you get a chance. In fact, watch it more than once. You'll always see something you didn't see before.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
