<filme>
 <id>
  507
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0044081
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1951
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Uma Rua Chamada Pecado
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Disturbed Blanche DuBois moves in with her sister in New Orleans and is tormented by her brutish brother-in-law while her reality crumbles around her.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Blanche is in real need of a protector at this stage in her life when circumstances lead her into paying a visit to her younger sister Stella in New Orleans. She doesn't understand how Stella, who is expecting her first child, could have picked a husband so lacking in refinement. Stanley Kowalski's buddies come over to the house to play cards and one of them, Mitch, finds Blanche attractive until Stanley tells him about what kind of a woman Blanche really is. What will happen when Stella goes to the hospital to have her baby and just Blanche and her brother-in-law are in the house?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   pregnant sister
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   streetcar
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   louisiana
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   neurotic
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Elia Kazan
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Tennessee Williams
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Oscar Saul
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Vivien Leigh
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Marlon Brando
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kim Hunter
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie almost in its entirety, but the ending ain't right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intp
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie as part of a college film class, around 1987 (I didn't actually take the class; I knew someone taking the class to fill a basic sociology distribution requirement; but I went to all the films for free-- and almost all of them were great!). Excellent film, with great performances all around-- until the very ending, which really bothered me. The ending in the movie was fundamentally changed from that in the original play. I had read the play in high school and thought it was brilliant. The movie, however, fundamentally alters the ending in a way, I guess, to make it a bit more "uplifting" to the audience. However, the film thereby ends up completely missing one of the key themes of the play (which is also a theme shared by Williams' "Glass Menagerie"): the way that unthinking men destroy the lives of women around them, yet the women are seemingly unable to help themselves in their attachment to those men. A tragic theme, perhaps, but too often true. While the altered ending is less downbeat, it just wasn't Williams' original story. Oddly, Roger Ebert's review doesn't even mention the change in the ending, even though he does mention other changes forced by the censors at the time. I wonder to this day if the changed ending was the director's idea, or was it forced upon him?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best acting ensemble ever in a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its actors assemble the best group of performances I've ever seen by a cast before in a motion picture. Viven Leigh is at the head, in work that reaffirms her talent as some of the finest in the business. She has the strength in one look to another character that most performances work for their entire film. Marlon Brando turns in a frightening effort that turns your stomach into mush. Kim Hunter does some great work, as well. A Streetcar Named Desire's screenplay is something to admire. The cracking dialogue and exceptional scenes that follow are sparse in the movie industry. Some of the most complex characters ever written are explored here; thankfully the cast and director put just as much effort into portraying them as the writer did into writing them in the play, which the film is based on. It's not an easy film to watch, some scenes are chilling (aided by haunting, black and white cinematography). Though I think A Streetcar Named Desire strays at times in the second half, it's an emotional roller coaster with anchoring acting. It's a great theatrical experience on film. Rating: 9.5/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated for sure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emanuel Rojas
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read many reviewers here saying that Marlon Brando's performance was amazing. I don't think it was amazing because there was nothing really complex about it. He just got mad in almost every scene, started yelling, and eventually broke stuff or smacked somebody. I felt that he had a limited range of emotions in the movie. Vivien Leigh gave an excellent performance, and she had to go to really abstract places to pull off her role. Blanche is a character that harbours delusions, lies pathologically, and suffers from terrible anxiety, so it was a complex role. The rest of the cast acts well, and Karl Malden's performance was the third most interesting in the movie. As for the story, it is not really that interesting. It takes place in one setting only for 99% of the movie, and is really heavy on the dialogue because it's based on a play. I think Tennesse Williams really dropped the ball by not including a night club scene in the play, with it being set in New Orleans. I haven't read the play, but I think the play / movie would have been way better had we seen Blanche going out with Stella in New Orleans and mixing it up with the locals. There was none of that in this movie, we see her in a bedroom most of the time being a weird brand of crazy southern belle, which gets boring. I think the reason that this movie made such an impact in 1951, was because it depicted mental illness in a way that hadn't been seen before. That's my guess at least. However, I doubt that either Tennessee Williams or Vivien Leigh really did much research into mental illness. I think the main thing that Tennessee Williams wanted to achieve was to create an iconic figure of a southern belle who goes crazy because the world is too harsh, and that southern ideals were doomed. If you care about any of that, you might enjoy this movie. Most of us don't care about any of that, for good reason, so that is why the movie won't make an impression on us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary Reese
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1950s film Adaptation of Tennessee Williams' A Streetcar Named Desire. Set in New Orleans, Blanche DuBois (Vivien Leigh) comes to with her sister, Stella, played by Kim Hunter, and her brother in law, Stanley, Marlon Brando. Blanche has found herself in a heap of personal troubles, but keeps up with the charade for her sister. She is prim and proper, an English teacher, with a trunk full of fancy outfits and jewelry. Stanley sees through this. Stanley is a rough around the edges, loud-mouthed character. This is an amazing breakthrough role for Brando. It was well casted all around. Domestic disputes breakout and emotions run high. This is one of the best movies still, to this day. Iconic scenes and characters. Worth a watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brando's volcanic energy gives Vivien the needed momentum to deliver one of the finest and most iconic performances in screen history as Blanche DuBois
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We witness Blanch Dubois burn in the flames ignited by Stanley Kowalski, thereby obliterating the destitute woman's small hopes of redeeming herself and starting life afresh. The other way to look at the situation would be: Stanley's force compels Blanch to face her crimes and gives her an opportunity to live a normal life sometime in the future. 'A Streetcar named Desire' veers between Blanch's attempts at ridding herself of guilt through ignorance and delusion and Stanley's will to expose Blanch's past and force her to admit and punish herself for her sins. Its playwright Tennessee Williams gives us a harrowing example of the difficulties faced by women who have stained their characters, and the cruelty with which men chastise them while they themselves take little notice of the sins they commit every day. Elia Kazan brings the play to screen experimenting little with editing and instead allows his actors to take charge, and boy do they bring tragedy to life! It is Marlon Brando's intense heat that allows Vivien Leigh's character to have a terrifying meltdown and the actress delivers one of the finest and most iconic performances in film history by nailing a highly complex and extremely interesting character. She may not have done it so well without Brando and we should give credit to Brando for helping her, but if you ask me who performed better, I'd unhesitatingly choose Leigh. A Streetcar Named Desire gained popularity on stage because of the quality of the story itself and Brando's acclaimed performance. When it was reproduced on screen, director Kazan roped in method-maharaja Marlon Brando and classical-chanteuse Vivien Leigh for the roles of Stanley and Blanche respectively. The rest of the cast were filled by talented actors like Kim Hunter for the role of Stella Kowalski and Karl Malden for Mitch. The controversial nature of the play made it difficult for bringing it on screen without certain cuts, but the restoration version released years later fortunately retains the deleted scenes. The story begins with Blanche Dubois' character arriving from Auriol to New Orleans by train, and taking the streetcar named Desire to Cemeteries and finally Elysian fields where her sister Stella lives with her husband Stanley. Blanche is extremely secretive about her past and only discloses to Stella that she had lost possession to their old home in Belle-Reve and was asked by the higher authority, in the school where Blanche taught English, to 'take some rest'. Blanche moves in temporarily with her sister and quickly shows displeasure at Stella's bourgeois existence and her attraction towards a violent man like Stanley. Blanche's prime desire is to begin a new life using an idealistic approach where 'magic and art' play a preeminent role and she pursues this by charming her brother-in-law's close friend and co-worker Mitch; her main obstacle comes in the form of Stanley, who does not entertain her whims, and finding loopholes in her claims, begins digging her past to break the spell Blanche wants to put everyone under. While he is instrumental in ripping her past apart, it seems like Blanche herself gives everyone an opportunity to scrutinize her past; it is as though she planted the seeds of her own destruction which were nurtured by Stanley. William's astonishing work should have been adapted to screen without altering anything because it is perfectly penned. Unfortunately, the film version alters the ending which makes Stanley looks like a complete jerk who is not only crass with Blanch but also not empathetic towards his own wife's grief. It goes against Stanley's motive of living happily with his wife and child without any de trop to disturb the 'wild peace' at home. Barring that scene, every other moment is brilliantly told and played on screen. Kazan hardly tries experimenting with the camera and in the process creates a work that is sharp and subtle. The most effective moments are when the camera abruptly cuts to or zooms into Blanche's face whenever anyone broaches the subject of her husband. Most of the effort is left to the actors who have terrific chemistry with each other, mainly because a majority of them have reprised the roles from stage. Hunter looks a lot like Debra Winger and the manner in which she spoke reminded me of young Debra from the movie 'Terms of Endearment' (of course, Debra came years later). While Debra Winger played a rich young rebellious girl who marries a simpleton, Hunter's Stella marries a commoner like Stanley because she is partly fascinated by his often violent and callous bravado. The actress convincingly plays Stella in a manner that makes us understand the character's choice, in a difficult role where she not only has to show love towards a violent man like Stanley, but also concern for her sister Blanch and slight contempt and reproach towards her husband for his treatment of Blanch. The other supporting role of Stan's friend Mitch is taken up by Malden; his character reminded me of J. Edgar Hoover who too lived alone with his sick mother and was very much concerned about her. Malden does his job well, especially in the confrontation scene between Mitch and Blanch where Mitch begins kissing her only because he then considers her a use-and-throw woman. However it is Brando and Leigh that make the day. I've now seen Brando in five different films in completely different characters and he fits each one like a glove. His realism or super-realism brings the movie alive with kinetic energy, and I realized a something watching him and Leigh  the classical Hollywood, with its stylized scripts veering towards melodramas and actors trying to bring the energies of their characters' psyche on screen, looked far more alluring a field to enter than today's Hollywood, which focuses heavily on slightly banal realism, with juiceless scripts without quote-worthy dialogs. Only one thing I shall say about Leigh: she gives us another iconic and unforgettable screen persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must see!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ImportantFilmReviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most people may call Marlon Brando a beautiful and charming man but he is no where close to charming in this film. He is primitive, controlling and territorial. He kicks a poor woman while she's down but brings a tremendous acting performance to the screen. It is very surprising that Brando shows such class and maturity yet this is only his second film. Absolute delight to watch him. Vivien Leigh is terrific as Blanche DuBois. Her spiral into insanity is wonderful as she is dominated physically and mentally by Brando's character. Kazan is a genius with the camera. His direction in this film is flawless. I would've loved to see the actual stage performance under his direction and with all these great performers. This is on my list as one of the best films in cinema history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marlon Brando...Thank god your in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the Tennesse William's play of A Streetcar Named Desire and I thought it was rather well done but I couldn't really get immersed into the story or the characters. None of the characters in the play appealed to me like they do in other novels, plays and films. I like the basic story line of the movie and how it remains simple and focuses on a young woman named Blanche who really "depends on the kindness of strangers" but realizes different after Stanley's abusive behavior. While this story works in a play, I just don't think it works all that great in a movie. Here's why... In a play/novel, you can simply enjoy one by reading in depth without much story but here in a movie, much of the film really seems boring and the fact that most of the film occurs in the dark really annoys me, even though I understand how its like in the play. There's nothing wrong with the acting. I thought Vivien Leigh did a fine job but easily the stand out of the film is the great Marlon Brandon...R.I.P. Had it not being for his portrayal of the abusive husband Stanley, this film would've been far less entertaining than what I could get of it in the end. In the film and the play, Stanley seems to be the only character with any real tone to him. In the play, I always imagined Blanche to be a rude woman and in the book, I always imagined Stella to be a disrespectful woman in the name of her family. However, in the film, you can clearly see that Stella is someone who suffers from Stanley's behavior and that Blanche is someone we are supposed to feel for. However, this film does something that makes a movie much a fail. That is, in films, we are normally supposed to be emotionally connected in some way to the protagonist. Here, Blanche is depicted as an annoying, eccentric woman (who was depicted the same in the play but also seemed to be normal)who talks in an extremely annoying and difficult to understand accent. While reading a play, we either view Blanche as a woman who is broken down by everything in her life (and so we pity her)or as someone we are portrayed to in the film (in which case, we don't care) I must admit, Mitch was quite a disappointment to me. In fact, the only character I enjoyed was Stanley who was depicted true to William's work. I must also point out that the entire script for the film is what Tennesse William wrote for the play and it annoyed me. Using parts of it is different to simply using the dialogue in the play. It doesn't add too much new to a film. In fact, how hard could it be to make parts of a script up????? NOT THAT HARD!!! I must also point out that the music used in the film really bugged me. I'm not expecting any epic music...NOOOO! But I expect some melodramatic music for a melodramatic film. In most scenes, the music did not suit the film and it felt too merry when it was supposed to be sad. Overall, many will love this film but I found it boring and annoying. Marlon Brando's superb acting and portrayal of Stanley saves it for me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complicated......yet simply told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jitin Menon
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blanche arrives in New Orleans to stay with her sister Stella and her husband Stanley. Blanche is unhappy to see her sister live in a shabby place and have her reservations on the unruly, stone age behaved brother-in-law. Stanley in turn does not like Blanche and not approve of her as he thinks she will come in between his happy marriage. This movie introduced me to the young Marlon Brando after his idolizing performance in The Godfather, And Boy!!! did he not disappoint me with his awe inspiring performance as the menacing yet charming Stanley Kowalski. The movie, mostly if not equally, belonged to Vivien Leigh whose portrayal of the neurotic Blanche DuBois was a fine example of some excellent old school performance. Kim Hunter provides a worthy support as Stella who's torn up between her sister and husband. Mitch(Karl Maiden) is adorable as he falls head over heels for Blanche. The movie based on the play by the same name,has been adapted and executed beautifully. Tennessee William's screenplay is tightly written and Elia Kazan has directed a memorable movie which will remain in the memories of the viewers for its complicated yet simple portrayal of a story of love and acceptance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No winners, only losers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Connor
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm torn by this film. In many ways it's sublime- the atmosphere, music, and the remarkable acting... but in others I can't stand it. Karl Malden's character Mitch is a nuisance, the duality of the major characters was a constant bait and switch, and with the Southern accents there are scenes where the clarity of speaking is a real problem. The characters are so double- edged it's frustrating. Blanche is clearly strange from the beginning, a tad ditsy with her head in the clouds. She feels Stanley's wrath as we do, but like any good character she isn't perfect. But then it goes so far that I couldn't root for her and I wanted to see Stanley explode on her, then back again, and it became a big mess. Stanley is physically and thematically the opposite of Blanche. Played by an absolute animal in Marlon Brando (he's huge!), Stan is bad, very alpha, completely dominant. As well he has violent tendencies, but we see his calmer side and see that he's looking out for his family and I began to side with him. He can be a horrible person, but in many instances its not unjustified. This see-saw goes back and forth through the film, until its end which goes right off of one side of the teeter- totter. But nonetheless, Stanley's portrayal- and presence on screen- is supreme. I feel like Sunset Blvd. beat Streetcar to the plot punch, and is dwarfed by On the Waterfront. The film is dark and very negative. The themes are negative and the conclusion is very sour. The moral is unclear, and with the Hays code the plot can be too vague. One of the most critical plotpoints at the end went over my head because I can't interpret what a smashed mirror means. After finishing I thought: "what did I even just watch?". Streetcar is like nothing of its era: though this review seems to have pointed out all the negatives, that is just a result of my emotions after finishing the film. It's an excellent film that decided to tell an unhappy story, very well. 8.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Explosive Movie........Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fantastic movie, of the stage play by Tennese Williams. Williams also wrote the screenplay for the movie. The four central actors Marlon Brando, Vivien Liegh, Karl Malden and Kim Hunter are excellent, and Elia Kazans direction is superb. Vivien Leigh won an Oscar for her great performance as the mentally un-hinged Blanch. Leigh had been suffering from bi-polar disorder all of her adult life, and often became "quite, quite mad" as David Niven observed. Playing Blanch was probably not too difficult for Leigh, who had a reputation for being unpredictable on film sets. Brando lost out to Humphrey Bogart (African Queen) at the academy awards that year (1951)---perhaps the world was not ready for the explosive Marlon who played part Neanderthal part Orange tang in an explosive macho performance. One of the great movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie almost in its entirety, but the ending ain't right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intp
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie as part of a college film class, around 1987 (I didn't actually take the class; I knew someone taking the class to fill a basic sociology distribution requirement; but I went to all the films for free-- and almost all of them were great!). Excellent film, with great performances all around-- until the very ending, which really bothered me. The ending in the movie was fundamentally changed from that in the original play. I had read the play in high school and thought it was brilliant. The movie, however, fundamentally alters the ending in a way, I guess, to make it a bit more "uplifting" to the audience. However, the film thereby ends up completely missing one of the key themes of the play (which is also a theme shared by Williams' "Glass Menagerie"): the way that unthinking men destroy the lives of women around them, yet the women are seemingly unable to help themselves in their attachment to those men. A tragic theme, perhaps, but too often true. While the altered ending is less downbeat, it just wasn't Williams' original story. Oddly, Roger Ebert's review doesn't even mention the change in the ending, even though he does mention other changes forced by the censors at the time. I wonder to this day if the changed ending was the director's idea, or was it forced upon him?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best acting ensemble ever in a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its actors assemble the best group of performances I've ever seen by a cast before in a motion picture. Viven Leigh is at the head, in work that reaffirms her talent as some of the finest in the business. She has the strength in one look to another character that most performances work for their entire film. Marlon Brando turns in a frightening effort that turns your stomach into mush. Kim Hunter does some great work, as well. A Streetcar Named Desire's screenplay is something to admire. The cracking dialogue and exceptional scenes that follow are sparse in the movie industry. Some of the most complex characters ever written are explored here; thankfully the cast and director put just as much effort into portraying them as the writer did into writing them in the play, which the film is based on. It's not an easy film to watch, some scenes are chilling (aided by haunting, black and white cinematography). Though I think A Streetcar Named Desire strays at times in the second half, it's an emotional roller coaster with anchoring acting. It's a great theatrical experience on film. Rating: 9.5/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated for sure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emanuel Rojas
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read many reviewers here saying that Marlon Brando's performance was amazing. I don't think it was amazing because there was nothing really complex about it. He just got mad in almost every scene, started yelling, and eventually broke stuff or smacked somebody. I felt that he had a limited range of emotions in the movie. Vivien Leigh gave an excellent performance, and she had to go to really abstract places to pull off her role. Blanche is a character that harbours delusions, lies pathologically, and suffers from terrible anxiety, so it was a complex role. The rest of the cast acts well, and Karl Malden's performance was the third most interesting in the movie. As for the story, it is not really that interesting. It takes place in one setting only for 99% of the movie, and is really heavy on the dialogue because it's based on a play. I think Tennesse Williams really dropped the ball by not including a night club scene in the play, with it being set in New Orleans. I haven't read the play, but I think the play / movie would have been way better had we seen Blanche going out with Stella in New Orleans and mixing it up with the locals. There was none of that in this movie, we see her in a bedroom most of the time being a weird brand of crazy southern belle, which gets boring. I think the reason that this movie made such an impact in 1951, was because it depicted mental illness in a way that hadn't been seen before. That's my guess at least. However, I doubt that either Tennessee Williams or Vivien Leigh really did much research into mental illness. I think the main thing that Tennessee Williams wanted to achieve was to create an iconic figure of a southern belle who goes crazy because the world is too harsh, and that southern ideals were doomed. If you care about any of that, you might enjoy this movie. Most of us don't care about any of that, for good reason, so that is why the movie won't make an impression on us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary Reese
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1950s film Adaptation of Tennessee Williams' A Streetcar Named Desire. Set in New Orleans, Blanche DuBois (Vivien Leigh) comes to with her sister, Stella, played by Kim Hunter, and her brother in law, Stanley, Marlon Brando. Blanche has found herself in a heap of personal troubles, but keeps up with the charade for her sister. She is prim and proper, an English teacher, with a trunk full of fancy outfits and jewelry. Stanley sees through this. Stanley is a rough around the edges, loud-mouthed character. This is an amazing breakthrough role for Brando. It was well casted all around. Domestic disputes breakout and emotions run high. This is one of the best movies still, to this day. Iconic scenes and characters. Worth a watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brando's volcanic energy gives Vivien the needed momentum to deliver one of the finest and most iconic performances in screen history as Blanche DuBois
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We witness Blanch Dubois burn in the flames ignited by Stanley Kowalski, thereby obliterating the destitute woman's small hopes of redeeming herself and starting life afresh. The other way to look at the situation would be: Stanley's force compels Blanch to face her crimes and gives her an opportunity to live a normal life sometime in the future. 'A Streetcar named Desire' veers between Blanch's attempts at ridding herself of guilt through ignorance and delusion and Stanley's will to expose Blanch's past and force her to admit and punish herself for her sins. Its playwright Tennessee Williams gives us a harrowing example of the difficulties faced by women who have stained their characters, and the cruelty with which men chastise them while they themselves take little notice of the sins they commit every day. Elia Kazan brings the play to screen experimenting little with editing and instead allows his actors to take charge, and boy do they bring tragedy to life! It is Marlon Brando's intense heat that allows Vivien Leigh's character to have a terrifying meltdown and the actress delivers one of the finest and most iconic performances in film history by nailing a highly complex and extremely interesting character. She may not have done it so well without Brando and we should give credit to Brando for helping her, but if you ask me who performed better, I'd unhesitatingly choose Leigh. A Streetcar Named Desire gained popularity on stage because of the quality of the story itself and Brando's acclaimed performance. When it was reproduced on screen, director Kazan roped in method-maharaja Marlon Brando and classical-chanteuse Vivien Leigh for the roles of Stanley and Blanche respectively. The rest of the cast were filled by talented actors like Kim Hunter for the role of Stella Kowalski and Karl Malden for Mitch. The controversial nature of the play made it difficult for bringing it on screen without certain cuts, but the restoration version released years later fortunately retains the deleted scenes. The story begins with Blanche Dubois' character arriving from Auriol to New Orleans by train, and taking the streetcar named Desire to Cemeteries and finally Elysian fields where her sister Stella lives with her husband Stanley. Blanche is extremely secretive about her past and only discloses to Stella that she had lost possession to their old home in Belle-Reve and was asked by the higher authority, in the school where Blanche taught English, to 'take some rest'. Blanche moves in temporarily with her sister and quickly shows displeasure at Stella's bourgeois existence and her attraction towards a violent man like Stanley. Blanche's prime desire is to begin a new life using an idealistic approach where 'magic and art' play a preeminent role and she pursues this by charming her brother-in-law's close friend and co-worker Mitch; her main obstacle comes in the form of Stanley, who does not entertain her whims, and finding loopholes in her claims, begins digging her past to break the spell Blanche wants to put everyone under. While he is instrumental in ripping her past apart, it seems like Blanche herself gives everyone an opportunity to scrutinize her past; it is as though she planted the seeds of her own destruction which were nurtured by Stanley. William's astonishing work should have been adapted to screen without altering anything because it is perfectly penned. Unfortunately, the film version alters the ending which makes Stanley looks like a complete jerk who is not only crass with Blanch but also not empathetic towards his own wife's grief. It goes against Stanley's motive of living happily with his wife and child without any de trop to disturb the 'wild peace' at home. Barring that scene, every other moment is brilliantly told and played on screen. Kazan hardly tries experimenting with the camera and in the process creates a work that is sharp and subtle. The most effective moments are when the camera abruptly cuts to or zooms into Blanche's face whenever anyone broaches the subject of her husband. Most of the effort is left to the actors who have terrific chemistry with each other, mainly because a majority of them have reprised the roles from stage. Hunter looks a lot like Debra Winger and the manner in which she spoke reminded me of young Debra from the movie 'Terms of Endearment' (of course, Debra came years later). While Debra Winger played a rich young rebellious girl who marries a simpleton, Hunter's Stella marries a commoner like Stanley because she is partly fascinated by his often violent and callous bravado. The actress convincingly plays Stella in a manner that makes us understand the character's choice, in a difficult role where she not only has to show love towards a violent man like Stanley, but also concern for her sister Blanch and slight contempt and reproach towards her husband for his treatment of Blanch. The other supporting role of Stan's friend Mitch is taken up by Malden; his character reminded me of J. Edgar Hoover who too lived alone with his sick mother and was very much concerned about her. Malden does his job well, especially in the confrontation scene between Mitch and Blanch where Mitch begins kissing her only because he then considers her a use-and-throw woman. However it is Brando and Leigh that make the day. I've now seen Brando in five different films in completely different characters and he fits each one like a glove. His realism or super-realism brings the movie alive with kinetic energy, and I realized a something watching him and Leigh  the classical Hollywood, with its stylized scripts veering towards melodramas and actors trying to bring the energies of their characters' psyche on screen, looked far more alluring a field to enter than today's Hollywood, which focuses heavily on slightly banal realism, with juiceless scripts without quote-worthy dialogs. Only one thing I shall say about Leigh: she gives us another iconic and unforgettable screen persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must see!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ImportantFilmReviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most people may call Marlon Brando a beautiful and charming man but he is no where close to charming in this film. He is primitive, controlling and territorial. He kicks a poor woman while she's down but brings a tremendous acting performance to the screen. It is very surprising that Brando shows such class and maturity yet this is only his second film. Absolute delight to watch him. Vivien Leigh is terrific as Blanche DuBois. Her spiral into insanity is wonderful as she is dominated physically and mentally by Brando's character. Kazan is a genius with the camera. His direction in this film is flawless. I would've loved to see the actual stage performance under his direction and with all these great performers. This is on my list as one of the best films in cinema history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marlon Brando...Thank god your in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the Tennesse William's play of A Streetcar Named Desire and I thought it was rather well done but I couldn't really get immersed into the story or the characters. None of the characters in the play appealed to me like they do in other novels, plays and films. I like the basic story line of the movie and how it remains simple and focuses on a young woman named Blanche who really "depends on the kindness of strangers" but realizes different after Stanley's abusive behavior. While this story works in a play, I just don't think it works all that great in a movie. Here's why... In a play/novel, you can simply enjoy one by reading in depth without much story but here in a movie, much of the film really seems boring and the fact that most of the film occurs in the dark really annoys me, even though I understand how its like in the play. There's nothing wrong with the acting. I thought Vivien Leigh did a fine job but easily the stand out of the film is the great Marlon Brandon...R.I.P. Had it not being for his portrayal of the abusive husband Stanley, this film would've been far less entertaining than what I could get of it in the end. In the film and the play, Stanley seems to be the only character with any real tone to him. In the play, I always imagined Blanche to be a rude woman and in the book, I always imagined Stella to be a disrespectful woman in the name of her family. However, in the film, you can clearly see that Stella is someone who suffers from Stanley's behavior and that Blanche is someone we are supposed to feel for. However, this film does something that makes a movie much a fail. That is, in films, we are normally supposed to be emotionally connected in some way to the protagonist. Here, Blanche is depicted as an annoying, eccentric woman (who was depicted the same in the play but also seemed to be normal)who talks in an extremely annoying and difficult to understand accent. While reading a play, we either view Blanche as a woman who is broken down by everything in her life (and so we pity her)or as someone we are portrayed to in the film (in which case, we don't care) I must admit, Mitch was quite a disappointment to me. In fact, the only character I enjoyed was Stanley who was depicted true to William's work. I must also point out that the entire script for the film is what Tennesse William wrote for the play and it annoyed me. Using parts of it is different to simply using the dialogue in the play. It doesn't add too much new to a film. In fact, how hard could it be to make parts of a script up????? NOT THAT HARD!!! I must also point out that the music used in the film really bugged me. I'm not expecting any epic music...NOOOO! But I expect some melodramatic music for a melodramatic film. In most scenes, the music did not suit the film and it felt too merry when it was supposed to be sad. Overall, many will love this film but I found it boring and annoying. Marlon Brando's superb acting and portrayal of Stanley saves it for me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complicated......yet simply told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jitin Menon
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blanche arrives in New Orleans to stay with her sister Stella and her husband Stanley. Blanche is unhappy to see her sister live in a shabby place and have her reservations on the unruly, stone age behaved brother-in-law. Stanley in turn does not like Blanche and not approve of her as he thinks she will come in between his happy marriage. This movie introduced me to the young Marlon Brando after his idolizing performance in The Godfather, And Boy!!! did he not disappoint me with his awe inspiring performance as the menacing yet charming Stanley Kowalski. The movie, mostly if not equally, belonged to Vivien Leigh whose portrayal of the neurotic Blanche DuBois was a fine example of some excellent old school performance. Kim Hunter provides a worthy support as Stella who's torn up between her sister and husband. Mitch(Karl Maiden) is adorable as he falls head over heels for Blanche. The movie based on the play by the same name,has been adapted and executed beautifully. Tennessee William's screenplay is tightly written and Elia Kazan has directed a memorable movie which will remain in the memories of the viewers for its complicated yet simple portrayal of a story of love and acceptance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No winners, only losers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Connor
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm torn by this film. In many ways it's sublime- the atmosphere, music, and the remarkable acting... but in others I can't stand it. Karl Malden's character Mitch is a nuisance, the duality of the major characters was a constant bait and switch, and with the Southern accents there are scenes where the clarity of speaking is a real problem. The characters are so double- edged it's frustrating. Blanche is clearly strange from the beginning, a tad ditsy with her head in the clouds. She feels Stanley's wrath as we do, but like any good character she isn't perfect. But then it goes so far that I couldn't root for her and I wanted to see Stanley explode on her, then back again, and it became a big mess. Stanley is physically and thematically the opposite of Blanche. Played by an absolute animal in Marlon Brando (he's huge!), Stan is bad, very alpha, completely dominant. As well he has violent tendencies, but we see his calmer side and see that he's looking out for his family and I began to side with him. He can be a horrible person, but in many instances its not unjustified. This see-saw goes back and forth through the film, until its end which goes right off of one side of the teeter- totter. But nonetheless, Stanley's portrayal- and presence on screen- is supreme. I feel like Sunset Blvd. beat Streetcar to the plot punch, and is dwarfed by On the Waterfront. The film is dark and very negative. The themes are negative and the conclusion is very sour. The moral is unclear, and with the Hays code the plot can be too vague. One of the most critical plotpoints at the end went over my head because I can't interpret what a smashed mirror means. After finishing I thought: "what did I even just watch?". Streetcar is like nothing of its era: though this review seems to have pointed out all the negatives, that is just a result of my emotions after finishing the film. It's an excellent film that decided to tell an unhappy story, very well. 8.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Explosive Movie........Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fantastic movie, of the stage play by Tennese Williams. Williams also wrote the screenplay for the movie. The four central actors Marlon Brando, Vivien Liegh, Karl Malden and Kim Hunter are excellent, and Elia Kazans direction is superb. Vivien Leigh won an Oscar for her great performance as the mentally un-hinged Blanch. Leigh had been suffering from bi-polar disorder all of her adult life, and often became "quite, quite mad" as David Niven observed. Playing Blanch was probably not too difficult for Leigh, who had a reputation for being unpredictable on film sets. Brando lost out to Humphrey Bogart (African Queen) at the academy awards that year (1951)---perhaps the world was not ready for the explosive Marlon who played part Neanderthal part Orange tang in an explosive macho performance. One of the great movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie almost in its entirety, but the ending ain't right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intp
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie as part of a college film class, around 1987 (I didn't actually take the class; I knew someone taking the class to fill a basic sociology distribution requirement; but I went to all the films for free-- and almost all of them were great!). Excellent film, with great performances all around-- until the very ending, which really bothered me. The ending in the movie was fundamentally changed from that in the original play. I had read the play in high school and thought it was brilliant. The movie, however, fundamentally alters the ending in a way, I guess, to make it a bit more "uplifting" to the audience. However, the film thereby ends up completely missing one of the key themes of the play (which is also a theme shared by Williams' "Glass Menagerie"): the way that unthinking men destroy the lives of women around them, yet the women are seemingly unable to help themselves in their attachment to those men. A tragic theme, perhaps, but too often true. While the altered ending is less downbeat, it just wasn't Williams' original story. Oddly, Roger Ebert's review doesn't even mention the change in the ending, even though he does mention other changes forced by the censors at the time. I wonder to this day if the changed ending was the director's idea, or was it forced upon him?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best acting ensemble ever in a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its actors assemble the best group of performances I've ever seen by a cast before in a motion picture. Viven Leigh is at the head, in work that reaffirms her talent as some of the finest in the business. She has the strength in one look to another character that most performances work for their entire film. Marlon Brando turns in a frightening effort that turns your stomach into mush. Kim Hunter does some great work, as well. A Streetcar Named Desire's screenplay is something to admire. The cracking dialogue and exceptional scenes that follow are sparse in the movie industry. Some of the most complex characters ever written are explored here; thankfully the cast and director put just as much effort into portraying them as the writer did into writing them in the play, which the film is based on. It's not an easy film to watch, some scenes are chilling (aided by haunting, black and white cinematography). Though I think A Streetcar Named Desire strays at times in the second half, it's an emotional roller coaster with anchoring acting. It's a great theatrical experience on film. Rating: 9.5/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated for sure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emanuel Rojas
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read many reviewers here saying that Marlon Brando's performance was amazing. I don't think it was amazing because there was nothing really complex about it. He just got mad in almost every scene, started yelling, and eventually broke stuff or smacked somebody. I felt that he had a limited range of emotions in the movie. Vivien Leigh gave an excellent performance, and she had to go to really abstract places to pull off her role. Blanche is a character that harbours delusions, lies pathologically, and suffers from terrible anxiety, so it was a complex role. The rest of the cast acts well, and Karl Malden's performance was the third most interesting in the movie. As for the story, it is not really that interesting. It takes place in one setting only for 99% of the movie, and is really heavy on the dialogue because it's based on a play. I think Tennesse Williams really dropped the ball by not including a night club scene in the play, with it being set in New Orleans. I haven't read the play, but I think the play / movie would have been way better had we seen Blanche going out with Stella in New Orleans and mixing it up with the locals. There was none of that in this movie, we see her in a bedroom most of the time being a weird brand of crazy southern belle, which gets boring. I think the reason that this movie made such an impact in 1951, was because it depicted mental illness in a way that hadn't been seen before. That's my guess at least. However, I doubt that either Tennessee Williams or Vivien Leigh really did much research into mental illness. I think the main thing that Tennessee Williams wanted to achieve was to create an iconic figure of a southern belle who goes crazy because the world is too harsh, and that southern ideals were doomed. If you care about any of that, you might enjoy this movie. Most of us don't care about any of that, for good reason, so that is why the movie won't make an impression on us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary Reese
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1950s film Adaptation of Tennessee Williams' A Streetcar Named Desire. Set in New Orleans, Blanche DuBois (Vivien Leigh) comes to with her sister, Stella, played by Kim Hunter, and her brother in law, Stanley, Marlon Brando. Blanche has found herself in a heap of personal troubles, but keeps up with the charade for her sister. She is prim and proper, an English teacher, with a trunk full of fancy outfits and jewelry. Stanley sees through this. Stanley is a rough around the edges, loud-mouthed character. This is an amazing breakthrough role for Brando. It was well casted all around. Domestic disputes breakout and emotions run high. This is one of the best movies still, to this day. Iconic scenes and characters. Worth a watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brando's volcanic energy gives Vivien the needed momentum to deliver one of the finest and most iconic performances in screen history as Blanche DuBois
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We witness Blanch Dubois burn in the flames ignited by Stanley Kowalski, thereby obliterating the destitute woman's small hopes of redeeming herself and starting life afresh. The other way to look at the situation would be: Stanley's force compels Blanch to face her crimes and gives her an opportunity to live a normal life sometime in the future. 'A Streetcar named Desire' veers between Blanch's attempts at ridding herself of guilt through ignorance and delusion and Stanley's will to expose Blanch's past and force her to admit and punish herself for her sins. Its playwright Tennessee Williams gives us a harrowing example of the difficulties faced by women who have stained their characters, and the cruelty with which men chastise them while they themselves take little notice of the sins they commit every day. Elia Kazan brings the play to screen experimenting little with editing and instead allows his actors to take charge, and boy do they bring tragedy to life! It is Marlon Brando's intense heat that allows Vivien Leigh's character to have a terrifying meltdown and the actress delivers one of the finest and most iconic performances in film history by nailing a highly complex and extremely interesting character. She may not have done it so well without Brando and we should give credit to Brando for helping her, but if you ask me who performed better, I'd unhesitatingly choose Leigh. A Streetcar Named Desire gained popularity on stage because of the quality of the story itself and Brando's acclaimed performance. When it was reproduced on screen, director Kazan roped in method-maharaja Marlon Brando and classical-chanteuse Vivien Leigh for the roles of Stanley and Blanche respectively. The rest of the cast were filled by talented actors like Kim Hunter for the role of Stella Kowalski and Karl Malden for Mitch. The controversial nature of the play made it difficult for bringing it on screen without certain cuts, but the restoration version released years later fortunately retains the deleted scenes. The story begins with Blanche Dubois' character arriving from Auriol to New Orleans by train, and taking the streetcar named Desire to Cemeteries and finally Elysian fields where her sister Stella lives with her husband Stanley. Blanche is extremely secretive about her past and only discloses to Stella that she had lost possession to their old home in Belle-Reve and was asked by the higher authority, in the school where Blanche taught English, to 'take some rest'. Blanche moves in temporarily with her sister and quickly shows displeasure at Stella's bourgeois existence and her attraction towards a violent man like Stanley. Blanche's prime desire is to begin a new life using an idealistic approach where 'magic and art' play a preeminent role and she pursues this by charming her brother-in-law's close friend and co-worker Mitch; her main obstacle comes in the form of Stanley, who does not entertain her whims, and finding loopholes in her claims, begins digging her past to break the spell Blanche wants to put everyone under. While he is instrumental in ripping her past apart, it seems like Blanche herself gives everyone an opportunity to scrutinize her past; it is as though she planted the seeds of her own destruction which were nurtured by Stanley. William's astonishing work should have been adapted to screen without altering anything because it is perfectly penned. Unfortunately, the film version alters the ending which makes Stanley looks like a complete jerk who is not only crass with Blanch but also not empathetic towards his own wife's grief. It goes against Stanley's motive of living happily with his wife and child without any de trop to disturb the 'wild peace' at home. Barring that scene, every other moment is brilliantly told and played on screen. Kazan hardly tries experimenting with the camera and in the process creates a work that is sharp and subtle. The most effective moments are when the camera abruptly cuts to or zooms into Blanche's face whenever anyone broaches the subject of her husband. Most of the effort is left to the actors who have terrific chemistry with each other, mainly because a majority of them have reprised the roles from stage. Hunter looks a lot like Debra Winger and the manner in which she spoke reminded me of young Debra from the movie 'Terms of Endearment' (of course, Debra came years later). While Debra Winger played a rich young rebellious girl who marries a simpleton, Hunter's Stella marries a commoner like Stanley because she is partly fascinated by his often violent and callous bravado. The actress convincingly plays Stella in a manner that makes us understand the character's choice, in a difficult role where she not only has to show love towards a violent man like Stanley, but also concern for her sister Blanch and slight contempt and reproach towards her husband for his treatment of Blanch. The other supporting role of Stan's friend Mitch is taken up by Malden; his character reminded me of J. Edgar Hoover who too lived alone with his sick mother and was very much concerned about her. Malden does his job well, especially in the confrontation scene between Mitch and Blanch where Mitch begins kissing her only because he then considers her a use-and-throw woman. However it is Brando and Leigh that make the day. I've now seen Brando in five different films in completely different characters and he fits each one like a glove. His realism or super-realism brings the movie alive with kinetic energy, and I realized a something watching him and Leigh  the classical Hollywood, with its stylized scripts veering towards melodramas and actors trying to bring the energies of their characters' psyche on screen, looked far more alluring a field to enter than today's Hollywood, which focuses heavily on slightly banal realism, with juiceless scripts without quote-worthy dialogs. Only one thing I shall say about Leigh: she gives us another iconic and unforgettable screen persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must see!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ImportantFilmReviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most people may call Marlon Brando a beautiful and charming man but he is no where close to charming in this film. He is primitive, controlling and territorial. He kicks a poor woman while she's down but brings a tremendous acting performance to the screen. It is very surprising that Brando shows such class and maturity yet this is only his second film. Absolute delight to watch him. Vivien Leigh is terrific as Blanche DuBois. Her spiral into insanity is wonderful as she is dominated physically and mentally by Brando's character. Kazan is a genius with the camera. His direction in this film is flawless. I would've loved to see the actual stage performance under his direction and with all these great performers. This is on my list as one of the best films in cinema history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marlon Brando...Thank god your in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the Tennesse William's play of A Streetcar Named Desire and I thought it was rather well done but I couldn't really get immersed into the story or the characters. None of the characters in the play appealed to me like they do in other novels, plays and films. I like the basic story line of the movie and how it remains simple and focuses on a young woman named Blanche who really "depends on the kindness of strangers" but realizes different after Stanley's abusive behavior. While this story works in a play, I just don't think it works all that great in a movie. Here's why... In a play/novel, you can simply enjoy one by reading in depth without much story but here in a movie, much of the film really seems boring and the fact that most of the film occurs in the dark really annoys me, even though I understand how its like in the play. There's nothing wrong with the acting. I thought Vivien Leigh did a fine job but easily the stand out of the film is the great Marlon Brandon...R.I.P. Had it not being for his portrayal of the abusive husband Stanley, this film would've been far less entertaining than what I could get of it in the end. In the film and the play, Stanley seems to be the only character with any real tone to him. In the play, I always imagined Blanche to be a rude woman and in the book, I always imagined Stella to be a disrespectful woman in the name of her family. However, in the film, you can clearly see that Stella is someone who suffers from Stanley's behavior and that Blanche is someone we are supposed to feel for. However, this film does something that makes a movie much a fail. That is, in films, we are normally supposed to be emotionally connected in some way to the protagonist. Here, Blanche is depicted as an annoying, eccentric woman (who was depicted the same in the play but also seemed to be normal)who talks in an extremely annoying and difficult to understand accent. While reading a play, we either view Blanche as a woman who is broken down by everything in her life (and so we pity her)or as someone we are portrayed to in the film (in which case, we don't care) I must admit, Mitch was quite a disappointment to me. In fact, the only character I enjoyed was Stanley who was depicted true to William's work. I must also point out that the entire script for the film is what Tennesse William wrote for the play and it annoyed me. Using parts of it is different to simply using the dialogue in the play. It doesn't add too much new to a film. In fact, how hard could it be to make parts of a script up????? NOT THAT HARD!!! I must also point out that the music used in the film really bugged me. I'm not expecting any epic music...NOOOO! But I expect some melodramatic music for a melodramatic film. In most scenes, the music did not suit the film and it felt too merry when it was supposed to be sad. Overall, many will love this film but I found it boring and annoying. Marlon Brando's superb acting and portrayal of Stanley saves it for me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complicated......yet simply told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jitin Menon
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blanche arrives in New Orleans to stay with her sister Stella and her husband Stanley. Blanche is unhappy to see her sister live in a shabby place and have her reservations on the unruly, stone age behaved brother-in-law. Stanley in turn does not like Blanche and not approve of her as he thinks she will come in between his happy marriage. This movie introduced me to the young Marlon Brando after his idolizing performance in The Godfather, And Boy!!! did he not disappoint me with his awe inspiring performance as the menacing yet charming Stanley Kowalski. The movie, mostly if not equally, belonged to Vivien Leigh whose portrayal of the neurotic Blanche DuBois was a fine example of some excellent old school performance. Kim Hunter provides a worthy support as Stella who's torn up between her sister and husband. Mitch(Karl Maiden) is adorable as he falls head over heels for Blanche. The movie based on the play by the same name,has been adapted and executed beautifully. Tennessee William's screenplay is tightly written and Elia Kazan has directed a memorable movie which will remain in the memories of the viewers for its complicated yet simple portrayal of a story of love and acceptance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No winners, only losers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Connor
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm torn by this film. In many ways it's sublime- the atmosphere, music, and the remarkable acting... but in others I can't stand it. Karl Malden's character Mitch is a nuisance, the duality of the major characters was a constant bait and switch, and with the Southern accents there are scenes where the clarity of speaking is a real problem. The characters are so double- edged it's frustrating. Blanche is clearly strange from the beginning, a tad ditsy with her head in the clouds. She feels Stanley's wrath as we do, but like any good character she isn't perfect. But then it goes so far that I couldn't root for her and I wanted to see Stanley explode on her, then back again, and it became a big mess. Stanley is physically and thematically the opposite of Blanche. Played by an absolute animal in Marlon Brando (he's huge!), Stan is bad, very alpha, completely dominant. As well he has violent tendencies, but we see his calmer side and see that he's looking out for his family and I began to side with him. He can be a horrible person, but in many instances its not unjustified. This see-saw goes back and forth through the film, until its end which goes right off of one side of the teeter- totter. But nonetheless, Stanley's portrayal- and presence on screen- is supreme. I feel like Sunset Blvd. beat Streetcar to the plot punch, and is dwarfed by On the Waterfront. The film is dark and very negative. The themes are negative and the conclusion is very sour. The moral is unclear, and with the Hays code the plot can be too vague. One of the most critical plotpoints at the end went over my head because I can't interpret what a smashed mirror means. After finishing I thought: "what did I even just watch?". Streetcar is like nothing of its era: though this review seems to have pointed out all the negatives, that is just a result of my emotions after finishing the film. It's an excellent film that decided to tell an unhappy story, very well. 8.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Explosive Movie........Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fantastic movie, of the stage play by Tennese Williams. Williams also wrote the screenplay for the movie. The four central actors Marlon Brando, Vivien Liegh, Karl Malden and Kim Hunter are excellent, and Elia Kazans direction is superb. Vivien Leigh won an Oscar for her great performance as the mentally un-hinged Blanch. Leigh had been suffering from bi-polar disorder all of her adult life, and often became "quite, quite mad" as David Niven observed. Playing Blanch was probably not too difficult for Leigh, who had a reputation for being unpredictable on film sets. Brando lost out to Humphrey Bogart (African Queen) at the academy awards that year (1951)---perhaps the world was not ready for the explosive Marlon who played part Neanderthal part Orange tang in an explosive macho performance. One of the great movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie almost in its entirety, but the ending ain't right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intp
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie as part of a college film class, around 1987 (I didn't actually take the class; I knew someone taking the class to fill a basic sociology distribution requirement; but I went to all the films for free-- and almost all of them were great!). Excellent film, with great performances all around-- until the very ending, which really bothered me. The ending in the movie was fundamentally changed from that in the original play. I had read the play in high school and thought it was brilliant. The movie, however, fundamentally alters the ending in a way, I guess, to make it a bit more "uplifting" to the audience. However, the film thereby ends up completely missing one of the key themes of the play (which is also a theme shared by Williams' "Glass Menagerie"): the way that unthinking men destroy the lives of women around them, yet the women are seemingly unable to help themselves in their attachment to those men. A tragic theme, perhaps, but too often true. While the altered ending is less downbeat, it just wasn't Williams' original story. Oddly, Roger Ebert's review doesn't even mention the change in the ending, even though he does mention other changes forced by the censors at the time. I wonder to this day if the changed ending was the director's idea, or was it forced upon him?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best acting ensemble ever in a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its actors assemble the best group of performances I've ever seen by a cast before in a motion picture. Viven Leigh is at the head, in work that reaffirms her talent as some of the finest in the business. She has the strength in one look to another character that most performances work for their entire film. Marlon Brando turns in a frightening effort that turns your stomach into mush. Kim Hunter does some great work, as well. A Streetcar Named Desire's screenplay is something to admire. The cracking dialogue and exceptional scenes that follow are sparse in the movie industry. Some of the most complex characters ever written are explored here; thankfully the cast and director put just as much effort into portraying them as the writer did into writing them in the play, which the film is based on. It's not an easy film to watch, some scenes are chilling (aided by haunting, black and white cinematography). Though I think A Streetcar Named Desire strays at times in the second half, it's an emotional roller coaster with anchoring acting. It's a great theatrical experience on film. Rating: 9.5/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated for sure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emanuel Rojas
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read many reviewers here saying that Marlon Brando's performance was amazing. I don't think it was amazing because there was nothing really complex about it. He just got mad in almost every scene, started yelling, and eventually broke stuff or smacked somebody. I felt that he had a limited range of emotions in the movie. Vivien Leigh gave an excellent performance, and she had to go to really abstract places to pull off her role. Blanche is a character that harbours delusions, lies pathologically, and suffers from terrible anxiety, so it was a complex role. The rest of the cast acts well, and Karl Malden's performance was the third most interesting in the movie. As for the story, it is not really that interesting. It takes place in one setting only for 99% of the movie, and is really heavy on the dialogue because it's based on a play. I think Tennesse Williams really dropped the ball by not including a night club scene in the play, with it being set in New Orleans. I haven't read the play, but I think the play / movie would have been way better had we seen Blanche going out with Stella in New Orleans and mixing it up with the locals. There was none of that in this movie, we see her in a bedroom most of the time being a weird brand of crazy southern belle, which gets boring. I think the reason that this movie made such an impact in 1951, was because it depicted mental illness in a way that hadn't been seen before. That's my guess at least. However, I doubt that either Tennessee Williams or Vivien Leigh really did much research into mental illness. I think the main thing that Tennessee Williams wanted to achieve was to create an iconic figure of a southern belle who goes crazy because the world is too harsh, and that southern ideals were doomed. If you care about any of that, you might enjoy this movie. Most of us don't care about any of that, for good reason, so that is why the movie won't make an impression on us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary Reese
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1950s film Adaptation of Tennessee Williams' A Streetcar Named Desire. Set in New Orleans, Blanche DuBois (Vivien Leigh) comes to with her sister, Stella, played by Kim Hunter, and her brother in law, Stanley, Marlon Brando. Blanche has found herself in a heap of personal troubles, but keeps up with the charade for her sister. She is prim and proper, an English teacher, with a trunk full of fancy outfits and jewelry. Stanley sees through this. Stanley is a rough around the edges, loud-mouthed character. This is an amazing breakthrough role for Brando. It was well casted all around. Domestic disputes breakout and emotions run high. This is one of the best movies still, to this day. Iconic scenes and characters. Worth a watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brando's volcanic energy gives Vivien the needed momentum to deliver one of the finest and most iconic performances in screen history as Blanche DuBois
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We witness Blanch Dubois burn in the flames ignited by Stanley Kowalski, thereby obliterating the destitute woman's small hopes of redeeming herself and starting life afresh. The other way to look at the situation would be: Stanley's force compels Blanch to face her crimes and gives her an opportunity to live a normal life sometime in the future. 'A Streetcar named Desire' veers between Blanch's attempts at ridding herself of guilt through ignorance and delusion and Stanley's will to expose Blanch's past and force her to admit and punish herself for her sins. Its playwright Tennessee Williams gives us a harrowing example of the difficulties faced by women who have stained their characters, and the cruelty with which men chastise them while they themselves take little notice of the sins they commit every day. Elia Kazan brings the play to screen experimenting little with editing and instead allows his actors to take charge, and boy do they bring tragedy to life! It is Marlon Brando's intense heat that allows Vivien Leigh's character to have a terrifying meltdown and the actress delivers one of the finest and most iconic performances in film history by nailing a highly complex and extremely interesting character. She may not have done it so well without Brando and we should give credit to Brando for helping her, but if you ask me who performed better, I'd unhesitatingly choose Leigh. A Streetcar Named Desire gained popularity on stage because of the quality of the story itself and Brando's acclaimed performance. When it was reproduced on screen, director Kazan roped in method-maharaja Marlon Brando and classical-chanteuse Vivien Leigh for the roles of Stanley and Blanche respectively. The rest of the cast were filled by talented actors like Kim Hunter for the role of Stella Kowalski and Karl Malden for Mitch. The controversial nature of the play made it difficult for bringing it on screen without certain cuts, but the restoration version released years later fortunately retains the deleted scenes. The story begins with Blanche Dubois' character arriving from Auriol to New Orleans by train, and taking the streetcar named Desire to Cemeteries and finally Elysian fields where her sister Stella lives with her husband Stanley. Blanche is extremely secretive about her past and only discloses to Stella that she had lost possession to their old home in Belle-Reve and was asked by the higher authority, in the school where Blanche taught English, to 'take some rest'. Blanche moves in temporarily with her sister and quickly shows displeasure at Stella's bourgeois existence and her attraction towards a violent man like Stanley. Blanche's prime desire is to begin a new life using an idealistic approach where 'magic and art' play a preeminent role and she pursues this by charming her brother-in-law's close friend and co-worker Mitch; her main obstacle comes in the form of Stanley, who does not entertain her whims, and finding loopholes in her claims, begins digging her past to break the spell Blanche wants to put everyone under. While he is instrumental in ripping her past apart, it seems like Blanche herself gives everyone an opportunity to scrutinize her past; it is as though she planted the seeds of her own destruction which were nurtured by Stanley. William's astonishing work should have been adapted to screen without altering anything because it is perfectly penned. Unfortunately, the film version alters the ending which makes Stanley looks like a complete jerk who is not only crass with Blanch but also not empathetic towards his own wife's grief. It goes against Stanley's motive of living happily with his wife and child without any de trop to disturb the 'wild peace' at home. Barring that scene, every other moment is brilliantly told and played on screen. Kazan hardly tries experimenting with the camera and in the process creates a work that is sharp and subtle. The most effective moments are when the camera abruptly cuts to or zooms into Blanche's face whenever anyone broaches the subject of her husband. Most of the effort is left to the actors who have terrific chemistry with each other, mainly because a majority of them have reprised the roles from stage. Hunter looks a lot like Debra Winger and the manner in which she spoke reminded me of young Debra from the movie 'Terms of Endearment' (of course, Debra came years later). While Debra Winger played a rich young rebellious girl who marries a simpleton, Hunter's Stella marries a commoner like Stanley because she is partly fascinated by his often violent and callous bravado. The actress convincingly plays Stella in a manner that makes us understand the character's choice, in a difficult role where she not only has to show love towards a violent man like Stanley, but also concern for her sister Blanch and slight contempt and reproach towards her husband for his treatment of Blanch. The other supporting role of Stan's friend Mitch is taken up by Malden; his character reminded me of J. Edgar Hoover who too lived alone with his sick mother and was very much concerned about her. Malden does his job well, especially in the confrontation scene between Mitch and Blanch where Mitch begins kissing her only because he then considers her a use-and-throw woman. However it is Brando and Leigh that make the day. I've now seen Brando in five different films in completely different characters and he fits each one like a glove. His realism or super-realism brings the movie alive with kinetic energy, and I realized a something watching him and Leigh  the classical Hollywood, with its stylized scripts veering towards melodramas and actors trying to bring the energies of their characters' psyche on screen, looked far more alluring a field to enter than today's Hollywood, which focuses heavily on slightly banal realism, with juiceless scripts without quote-worthy dialogs. Only one thing I shall say about Leigh: she gives us another iconic and unforgettable screen persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must see!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ImportantFilmReviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most people may call Marlon Brando a beautiful and charming man but he is no where close to charming in this film. He is primitive, controlling and territorial. He kicks a poor woman while she's down but brings a tremendous acting performance to the screen. It is very surprising that Brando shows such class and maturity yet this is only his second film. Absolute delight to watch him. Vivien Leigh is terrific as Blanche DuBois. Her spiral into insanity is wonderful as she is dominated physically and mentally by Brando's character. Kazan is a genius with the camera. His direction in this film is flawless. I would've loved to see the actual stage performance under his direction and with all these great performers. This is on my list as one of the best films in cinema history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marlon Brando...Thank god your in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the Tennesse William's play of A Streetcar Named Desire and I thought it was rather well done but I couldn't really get immersed into the story or the characters. None of the characters in the play appealed to me like they do in other novels, plays and films. I like the basic story line of the movie and how it remains simple and focuses on a young woman named Blanche who really "depends on the kindness of strangers" but realizes different after Stanley's abusive behavior. While this story works in a play, I just don't think it works all that great in a movie. Here's why... In a play/novel, you can simply enjoy one by reading in depth without much story but here in a movie, much of the film really seems boring and the fact that most of the film occurs in the dark really annoys me, even though I understand how its like in the play. There's nothing wrong with the acting. I thought Vivien Leigh did a fine job but easily the stand out of the film is the great Marlon Brandon...R.I.P. Had it not being for his portrayal of the abusive husband Stanley, this film would've been far less entertaining than what I could get of it in the end. In the film and the play, Stanley seems to be the only character with any real tone to him. In the play, I always imagined Blanche to be a rude woman and in the book, I always imagined Stella to be a disrespectful woman in the name of her family. However, in the film, you can clearly see that Stella is someone who suffers from Stanley's behavior and that Blanche is someone we are supposed to feel for. However, this film does something that makes a movie much a fail. That is, in films, we are normally supposed to be emotionally connected in some way to the protagonist. Here, Blanche is depicted as an annoying, eccentric woman (who was depicted the same in the play but also seemed to be normal)who talks in an extremely annoying and difficult to understand accent. While reading a play, we either view Blanche as a woman who is broken down by everything in her life (and so we pity her)or as someone we are portrayed to in the film (in which case, we don't care) I must admit, Mitch was quite a disappointment to me. In fact, the only character I enjoyed was Stanley who was depicted true to William's work. I must also point out that the entire script for the film is what Tennesse William wrote for the play and it annoyed me. Using parts of it is different to simply using the dialogue in the play. It doesn't add too much new to a film. In fact, how hard could it be to make parts of a script up????? NOT THAT HARD!!! I must also point out that the music used in the film really bugged me. I'm not expecting any epic music...NOOOO! But I expect some melodramatic music for a melodramatic film. In most scenes, the music did not suit the film and it felt too merry when it was supposed to be sad. Overall, many will love this film but I found it boring and annoying. Marlon Brando's superb acting and portrayal of Stanley saves it for me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complicated......yet simply told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jitin Menon
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blanche arrives in New Orleans to stay with her sister Stella and her husband Stanley. Blanche is unhappy to see her sister live in a shabby place and have her reservations on the unruly, stone age behaved brother-in-law. Stanley in turn does not like Blanche and not approve of her as he thinks she will come in between his happy marriage. This movie introduced me to the young Marlon Brando after his idolizing performance in The Godfather, And Boy!!! did he not disappoint me with his awe inspiring performance as the menacing yet charming Stanley Kowalski. The movie, mostly if not equally, belonged to Vivien Leigh whose portrayal of the neurotic Blanche DuBois was a fine example of some excellent old school performance. Kim Hunter provides a worthy support as Stella who's torn up between her sister and husband. Mitch(Karl Maiden) is adorable as he falls head over heels for Blanche. The movie based on the play by the same name,has been adapted and executed beautifully. Tennessee William's screenplay is tightly written and Elia Kazan has directed a memorable movie which will remain in the memories of the viewers for its complicated yet simple portrayal of a story of love and acceptance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No winners, only losers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Connor
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm torn by this film. In many ways it's sublime- the atmosphere, music, and the remarkable acting... but in others I can't stand it. Karl Malden's character Mitch is a nuisance, the duality of the major characters was a constant bait and switch, and with the Southern accents there are scenes where the clarity of speaking is a real problem. The characters are so double- edged it's frustrating. Blanche is clearly strange from the beginning, a tad ditsy with her head in the clouds. She feels Stanley's wrath as we do, but like any good character she isn't perfect. But then it goes so far that I couldn't root for her and I wanted to see Stanley explode on her, then back again, and it became a big mess. Stanley is physically and thematically the opposite of Blanche. Played by an absolute animal in Marlon Brando (he's huge!), Stan is bad, very alpha, completely dominant. As well he has violent tendencies, but we see his calmer side and see that he's looking out for his family and I began to side with him. He can be a horrible person, but in many instances its not unjustified. This see-saw goes back and forth through the film, until its end which goes right off of one side of the teeter- totter. But nonetheless, Stanley's portrayal- and presence on screen- is supreme. I feel like Sunset Blvd. beat Streetcar to the plot punch, and is dwarfed by On the Waterfront. The film is dark and very negative. The themes are negative and the conclusion is very sour. The moral is unclear, and with the Hays code the plot can be too vague. One of the most critical plotpoints at the end went over my head because I can't interpret what a smashed mirror means. After finishing I thought: "what did I even just watch?". Streetcar is like nothing of its era: though this review seems to have pointed out all the negatives, that is just a result of my emotions after finishing the film. It's an excellent film that decided to tell an unhappy story, very well. 8.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Explosive Movie........Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fantastic movie, of the stage play by Tennese Williams. Williams also wrote the screenplay for the movie. The four central actors Marlon Brando, Vivien Liegh, Karl Malden and Kim Hunter are excellent, and Elia Kazans direction is superb. Vivien Leigh won an Oscar for her great performance as the mentally un-hinged Blanch. Leigh had been suffering from bi-polar disorder all of her adult life, and often became "quite, quite mad" as David Niven observed. Playing Blanch was probably not too difficult for Leigh, who had a reputation for being unpredictable on film sets. Brando lost out to Humphrey Bogart (African Queen) at the academy awards that year (1951)---perhaps the world was not ready for the explosive Marlon who played part Neanderthal part Orange tang in an explosive macho performance. One of the great movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie almost in its entirety, but the ending ain't right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intp
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie as part of a college film class, around 1987 (I didn't actually take the class; I knew someone taking the class to fill a basic sociology distribution requirement; but I went to all the films for free-- and almost all of them were great!). Excellent film, with great performances all around-- until the very ending, which really bothered me. The ending in the movie was fundamentally changed from that in the original play. I had read the play in high school and thought it was brilliant. The movie, however, fundamentally alters the ending in a way, I guess, to make it a bit more "uplifting" to the audience. However, the film thereby ends up completely missing one of the key themes of the play (which is also a theme shared by Williams' "Glass Menagerie"): the way that unthinking men destroy the lives of women around them, yet the women are seemingly unable to help themselves in their attachment to those men. A tragic theme, perhaps, but too often true. While the altered ending is less downbeat, it just wasn't Williams' original story. Oddly, Roger Ebert's review doesn't even mention the change in the ending, even though he does mention other changes forced by the censors at the time. I wonder to this day if the changed ending was the director's idea, or was it forced upon him?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best acting ensemble ever in a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its actors assemble the best group of performances I've ever seen by a cast before in a motion picture. Viven Leigh is at the head, in work that reaffirms her talent as some of the finest in the business. She has the strength in one look to another character that most performances work for their entire film. Marlon Brando turns in a frightening effort that turns your stomach into mush. Kim Hunter does some great work, as well. A Streetcar Named Desire's screenplay is something to admire. The cracking dialogue and exceptional scenes that follow are sparse in the movie industry. Some of the most complex characters ever written are explored here; thankfully the cast and director put just as much effort into portraying them as the writer did into writing them in the play, which the film is based on. It's not an easy film to watch, some scenes are chilling (aided by haunting, black and white cinematography). Though I think A Streetcar Named Desire strays at times in the second half, it's an emotional roller coaster with anchoring acting. It's a great theatrical experience on film. Rating: 9.5/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated for sure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emanuel Rojas
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read many reviewers here saying that Marlon Brando's performance was amazing. I don't think it was amazing because there was nothing really complex about it. He just got mad in almost every scene, started yelling, and eventually broke stuff or smacked somebody. I felt that he had a limited range of emotions in the movie. Vivien Leigh gave an excellent performance, and she had to go to really abstract places to pull off her role. Blanche is a character that harbours delusions, lies pathologically, and suffers from terrible anxiety, so it was a complex role. The rest of the cast acts well, and Karl Malden's performance was the third most interesting in the movie. As for the story, it is not really that interesting. It takes place in one setting only for 99% of the movie, and is really heavy on the dialogue because it's based on a play. I think Tennesse Williams really dropped the ball by not including a night club scene in the play, with it being set in New Orleans. I haven't read the play, but I think the play / movie would have been way better had we seen Blanche going out with Stella in New Orleans and mixing it up with the locals. There was none of that in this movie, we see her in a bedroom most of the time being a weird brand of crazy southern belle, which gets boring. I think the reason that this movie made such an impact in 1951, was because it depicted mental illness in a way that hadn't been seen before. That's my guess at least. However, I doubt that either Tennessee Williams or Vivien Leigh really did much research into mental illness. I think the main thing that Tennessee Williams wanted to achieve was to create an iconic figure of a southern belle who goes crazy because the world is too harsh, and that southern ideals were doomed. If you care about any of that, you might enjoy this movie. Most of us don't care about any of that, for good reason, so that is why the movie won't make an impression on us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary Reese
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1950s film Adaptation of Tennessee Williams' A Streetcar Named Desire. Set in New Orleans, Blanche DuBois (Vivien Leigh) comes to with her sister, Stella, played by Kim Hunter, and her brother in law, Stanley, Marlon Brando. Blanche has found herself in a heap of personal troubles, but keeps up with the charade for her sister. She is prim and proper, an English teacher, with a trunk full of fancy outfits and jewelry. Stanley sees through this. Stanley is a rough around the edges, loud-mouthed character. This is an amazing breakthrough role for Brando. It was well casted all around. Domestic disputes breakout and emotions run high. This is one of the best movies still, to this day. Iconic scenes and characters. Worth a watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brando's volcanic energy gives Vivien the needed momentum to deliver one of the finest and most iconic performances in screen history as Blanche DuBois
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We witness Blanch Dubois burn in the flames ignited by Stanley Kowalski, thereby obliterating the destitute woman's small hopes of redeeming herself and starting life afresh. The other way to look at the situation would be: Stanley's force compels Blanch to face her crimes and gives her an opportunity to live a normal life sometime in the future. 'A Streetcar named Desire' veers between Blanch's attempts at ridding herself of guilt through ignorance and delusion and Stanley's will to expose Blanch's past and force her to admit and punish herself for her sins. Its playwright Tennessee Williams gives us a harrowing example of the difficulties faced by women who have stained their characters, and the cruelty with which men chastise them while they themselves take little notice of the sins they commit every day. Elia Kazan brings the play to screen experimenting little with editing and instead allows his actors to take charge, and boy do they bring tragedy to life! It is Marlon Brando's intense heat that allows Vivien Leigh's character to have a terrifying meltdown and the actress delivers one of the finest and most iconic performances in film history by nailing a highly complex and extremely interesting character. She may not have done it so well without Brando and we should give credit to Brando for helping her, but if you ask me who performed better, I'd unhesitatingly choose Leigh. A Streetcar Named Desire gained popularity on stage because of the quality of the story itself and Brando's acclaimed performance. When it was reproduced on screen, director Kazan roped in method-maharaja Marlon Brando and classical-chanteuse Vivien Leigh for the roles of Stanley and Blanche respectively. The rest of the cast were filled by talented actors like Kim Hunter for the role of Stella Kowalski and Karl Malden for Mitch. The controversial nature of the play made it difficult for bringing it on screen without certain cuts, but the restoration version released years later fortunately retains the deleted scenes. The story begins with Blanche Dubois' character arriving from Auriol to New Orleans by train, and taking the streetcar named Desire to Cemeteries and finally Elysian fields where her sister Stella lives with her husband Stanley. Blanche is extremely secretive about her past and only discloses to Stella that she had lost possession to their old home in Belle-Reve and was asked by the higher authority, in the school where Blanche taught English, to 'take some rest'. Blanche moves in temporarily with her sister and quickly shows displeasure at Stella's bourgeois existence and her attraction towards a violent man like Stanley. Blanche's prime desire is to begin a new life using an idealistic approach where 'magic and art' play a preeminent role and she pursues this by charming her brother-in-law's close friend and co-worker Mitch; her main obstacle comes in the form of Stanley, who does not entertain her whims, and finding loopholes in her claims, begins digging her past to break the spell Blanche wants to put everyone under. While he is instrumental in ripping her past apart, it seems like Blanche herself gives everyone an opportunity to scrutinize her past; it is as though she planted the seeds of her own destruction which were nurtured by Stanley. William's astonishing work should have been adapted to screen without altering anything because it is perfectly penned. Unfortunately, the film version alters the ending which makes Stanley looks like a complete jerk who is not only crass with Blanch but also not empathetic towards his own wife's grief. It goes against Stanley's motive of living happily with his wife and child without any de trop to disturb the 'wild peace' at home. Barring that scene, every other moment is brilliantly told and played on screen. Kazan hardly tries experimenting with the camera and in the process creates a work that is sharp and subtle. The most effective moments are when the camera abruptly cuts to or zooms into Blanche's face whenever anyone broaches the subject of her husband. Most of the effort is left to the actors who have terrific chemistry with each other, mainly because a majority of them have reprised the roles from stage. Hunter looks a lot like Debra Winger and the manner in which she spoke reminded me of young Debra from the movie 'Terms of Endearment' (of course, Debra came years later). While Debra Winger played a rich young rebellious girl who marries a simpleton, Hunter's Stella marries a commoner like Stanley because she is partly fascinated by his often violent and callous bravado. The actress convincingly plays Stella in a manner that makes us understand the character's choice, in a difficult role where she not only has to show love towards a violent man like Stanley, but also concern for her sister Blanch and slight contempt and reproach towards her husband for his treatment of Blanch. The other supporting role of Stan's friend Mitch is taken up by Malden; his character reminded me of J. Edgar Hoover who too lived alone with his sick mother and was very much concerned about her. Malden does his job well, especially in the confrontation scene between Mitch and Blanch where Mitch begins kissing her only because he then considers her a use-and-throw woman. However it is Brando and Leigh that make the day. I've now seen Brando in five different films in completely different characters and he fits each one like a glove. His realism or super-realism brings the movie alive with kinetic energy, and I realized a something watching him and Leigh  the classical Hollywood, with its stylized scripts veering towards melodramas and actors trying to bring the energies of their characters' psyche on screen, looked far more alluring a field to enter than today's Hollywood, which focuses heavily on slightly banal realism, with juiceless scripts without quote-worthy dialogs. Only one thing I shall say about Leigh: she gives us another iconic and unforgettable screen persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must see!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ImportantFilmReviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most people may call Marlon Brando a beautiful and charming man but he is no where close to charming in this film. He is primitive, controlling and territorial. He kicks a poor woman while she's down but brings a tremendous acting performance to the screen. It is very surprising that Brando shows such class and maturity yet this is only his second film. Absolute delight to watch him. Vivien Leigh is terrific as Blanche DuBois. Her spiral into insanity is wonderful as she is dominated physically and mentally by Brando's character. Kazan is a genius with the camera. His direction in this film is flawless. I would've loved to see the actual stage performance under his direction and with all these great performers. This is on my list as one of the best films in cinema history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marlon Brando...Thank god your in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the Tennesse William's play of A Streetcar Named Desire and I thought it was rather well done but I couldn't really get immersed into the story or the characters. None of the characters in the play appealed to me like they do in other novels, plays and films. I like the basic story line of the movie and how it remains simple and focuses on a young woman named Blanche who really "depends on the kindness of strangers" but realizes different after Stanley's abusive behavior. While this story works in a play, I just don't think it works all that great in a movie. Here's why... In a play/novel, you can simply enjoy one by reading in depth without much story but here in a movie, much of the film really seems boring and the fact that most of the film occurs in the dark really annoys me, even though I understand how its like in the play. There's nothing wrong with the acting. I thought Vivien Leigh did a fine job but easily the stand out of the film is the great Marlon Brandon...R.I.P. Had it not being for his portrayal of the abusive husband Stanley, this film would've been far less entertaining than what I could get of it in the end. In the film and the play, Stanley seems to be the only character with any real tone to him. In the play, I always imagined Blanche to be a rude woman and in the book, I always imagined Stella to be a disrespectful woman in the name of her family. However, in the film, you can clearly see that Stella is someone who suffers from Stanley's behavior and that Blanche is someone we are supposed to feel for. However, this film does something that makes a movie much a fail. That is, in films, we are normally supposed to be emotionally connected in some way to the protagonist. Here, Blanche is depicted as an annoying, eccentric woman (who was depicted the same in the play but also seemed to be normal)who talks in an extremely annoying and difficult to understand accent. While reading a play, we either view Blanche as a woman who is broken down by everything in her life (and so we pity her)or as someone we are portrayed to in the film (in which case, we don't care) I must admit, Mitch was quite a disappointment to me. In fact, the only character I enjoyed was Stanley who was depicted true to William's work. I must also point out that the entire script for the film is what Tennesse William wrote for the play and it annoyed me. Using parts of it is different to simply using the dialogue in the play. It doesn't add too much new to a film. In fact, how hard could it be to make parts of a script up????? NOT THAT HARD!!! I must also point out that the music used in the film really bugged me. I'm not expecting any epic music...NOOOO! But I expect some melodramatic music for a melodramatic film. In most scenes, the music did not suit the film and it felt too merry when it was supposed to be sad. Overall, many will love this film but I found it boring and annoying. Marlon Brando's superb acting and portrayal of Stanley saves it for me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complicated......yet simply told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jitin Menon
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blanche arrives in New Orleans to stay with her sister Stella and her husband Stanley. Blanche is unhappy to see her sister live in a shabby place and have her reservations on the unruly, stone age behaved brother-in-law. Stanley in turn does not like Blanche and not approve of her as he thinks she will come in between his happy marriage. This movie introduced me to the young Marlon Brando after his idolizing performance in The Godfather, And Boy!!! did he not disappoint me with his awe inspiring performance as the menacing yet charming Stanley Kowalski. The movie, mostly if not equally, belonged to Vivien Leigh whose portrayal of the neurotic Blanche DuBois was a fine example of some excellent old school performance. Kim Hunter provides a worthy support as Stella who's torn up between her sister and husband. Mitch(Karl Maiden) is adorable as he falls head over heels for Blanche. The movie based on the play by the same name,has been adapted and executed beautifully. Tennessee William's screenplay is tightly written and Elia Kazan has directed a memorable movie which will remain in the memories of the viewers for its complicated yet simple portrayal of a story of love and acceptance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No winners, only losers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Connor
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm torn by this film. In many ways it's sublime- the atmosphere, music, and the remarkable acting... but in others I can't stand it. Karl Malden's character Mitch is a nuisance, the duality of the major characters was a constant bait and switch, and with the Southern accents there are scenes where the clarity of speaking is a real problem. The characters are so double- edged it's frustrating. Blanche is clearly strange from the beginning, a tad ditsy with her head in the clouds. She feels Stanley's wrath as we do, but like any good character she isn't perfect. But then it goes so far that I couldn't root for her and I wanted to see Stanley explode on her, then back again, and it became a big mess. Stanley is physically and thematically the opposite of Blanche. Played by an absolute animal in Marlon Brando (he's huge!), Stan is bad, very alpha, completely dominant. As well he has violent tendencies, but we see his calmer side and see that he's looking out for his family and I began to side with him. He can be a horrible person, but in many instances its not unjustified. This see-saw goes back and forth through the film, until its end which goes right off of one side of the teeter- totter. But nonetheless, Stanley's portrayal- and presence on screen- is supreme. I feel like Sunset Blvd. beat Streetcar to the plot punch, and is dwarfed by On the Waterfront. The film is dark and very negative. The themes are negative and the conclusion is very sour. The moral is unclear, and with the Hays code the plot can be too vague. One of the most critical plotpoints at the end went over my head because I can't interpret what a smashed mirror means. After finishing I thought: "what did I even just watch?". Streetcar is like nothing of its era: though this review seems to have pointed out all the negatives, that is just a result of my emotions after finishing the film. It's an excellent film that decided to tell an unhappy story, very well. 8.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Explosive Movie........Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fantastic movie, of the stage play by Tennese Williams. Williams also wrote the screenplay for the movie. The four central actors Marlon Brando, Vivien Liegh, Karl Malden and Kim Hunter are excellent, and Elia Kazans direction is superb. Vivien Leigh won an Oscar for her great performance as the mentally un-hinged Blanch. Leigh had been suffering from bi-polar disorder all of her adult life, and often became "quite, quite mad" as David Niven observed. Playing Blanch was probably not too difficult for Leigh, who had a reputation for being unpredictable on film sets. Brando lost out to Humphrey Bogart (African Queen) at the academy awards that year (1951)---perhaps the world was not ready for the explosive Marlon who played part Neanderthal part Orange tang in an explosive macho performance. One of the great movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie almost in its entirety, but the ending ain't right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intp
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie as part of a college film class, around 1987 (I didn't actually take the class; I knew someone taking the class to fill a basic sociology distribution requirement; but I went to all the films for free-- and almost all of them were great!). Excellent film, with great performances all around-- until the very ending, which really bothered me. The ending in the movie was fundamentally changed from that in the original play. I had read the play in high school and thought it was brilliant. The movie, however, fundamentally alters the ending in a way, I guess, to make it a bit more "uplifting" to the audience. However, the film thereby ends up completely missing one of the key themes of the play (which is also a theme shared by Williams' "Glass Menagerie"): the way that unthinking men destroy the lives of women around them, yet the women are seemingly unable to help themselves in their attachment to those men. A tragic theme, perhaps, but too often true. While the altered ending is less downbeat, it just wasn't Williams' original story. Oddly, Roger Ebert's review doesn't even mention the change in the ending, even though he does mention other changes forced by the censors at the time. I wonder to this day if the changed ending was the director's idea, or was it forced upon him?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best acting ensemble ever in a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its actors assemble the best group of performances I've ever seen by a cast before in a motion picture. Viven Leigh is at the head, in work that reaffirms her talent as some of the finest in the business. She has the strength in one look to another character that most performances work for their entire film. Marlon Brando turns in a frightening effort that turns your stomach into mush. Kim Hunter does some great work, as well. A Streetcar Named Desire's screenplay is something to admire. The cracking dialogue and exceptional scenes that follow are sparse in the movie industry. Some of the most complex characters ever written are explored here; thankfully the cast and director put just as much effort into portraying them as the writer did into writing them in the play, which the film is based on. It's not an easy film to watch, some scenes are chilling (aided by haunting, black and white cinematography). Though I think A Streetcar Named Desire strays at times in the second half, it's an emotional roller coaster with anchoring acting. It's a great theatrical experience on film. Rating: 9.5/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated for sure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emanuel Rojas
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read many reviewers here saying that Marlon Brando's performance was amazing. I don't think it was amazing because there was nothing really complex about it. He just got mad in almost every scene, started yelling, and eventually broke stuff or smacked somebody. I felt that he had a limited range of emotions in the movie. Vivien Leigh gave an excellent performance, and she had to go to really abstract places to pull off her role. Blanche is a character that harbours delusions, lies pathologically, and suffers from terrible anxiety, so it was a complex role. The rest of the cast acts well, and Karl Malden's performance was the third most interesting in the movie. As for the story, it is not really that interesting. It takes place in one setting only for 99% of the movie, and is really heavy on the dialogue because it's based on a play. I think Tennesse Williams really dropped the ball by not including a night club scene in the play, with it being set in New Orleans. I haven't read the play, but I think the play / movie would have been way better had we seen Blanche going out with Stella in New Orleans and mixing it up with the locals. There was none of that in this movie, we see her in a bedroom most of the time being a weird brand of crazy southern belle, which gets boring. I think the reason that this movie made such an impact in 1951, was because it depicted mental illness in a way that hadn't been seen before. That's my guess at least. However, I doubt that either Tennessee Williams or Vivien Leigh really did much research into mental illness. I think the main thing that Tennessee Williams wanted to achieve was to create an iconic figure of a southern belle who goes crazy because the world is too harsh, and that southern ideals were doomed. If you care about any of that, you might enjoy this movie. Most of us don't care about any of that, for good reason, so that is why the movie won't make an impression on us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary Reese
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1950s film Adaptation of Tennessee Williams' A Streetcar Named Desire. Set in New Orleans, Blanche DuBois (Vivien Leigh) comes to with her sister, Stella, played by Kim Hunter, and her brother in law, Stanley, Marlon Brando. Blanche has found herself in a heap of personal troubles, but keeps up with the charade for her sister. She is prim and proper, an English teacher, with a trunk full of fancy outfits and jewelry. Stanley sees through this. Stanley is a rough around the edges, loud-mouthed character. This is an amazing breakthrough role for Brando. It was well casted all around. Domestic disputes breakout and emotions run high. This is one of the best movies still, to this day. Iconic scenes and characters. Worth a watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brando's volcanic energy gives Vivien the needed momentum to deliver one of the finest and most iconic performances in screen history as Blanche DuBois
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We witness Blanch Dubois burn in the flames ignited by Stanley Kowalski, thereby obliterating the destitute woman's small hopes of redeeming herself and starting life afresh. The other way to look at the situation would be: Stanley's force compels Blanch to face her crimes and gives her an opportunity to live a normal life sometime in the future. 'A Streetcar named Desire' veers between Blanch's attempts at ridding herself of guilt through ignorance and delusion and Stanley's will to expose Blanch's past and force her to admit and punish herself for her sins. Its playwright Tennessee Williams gives us a harrowing example of the difficulties faced by women who have stained their characters, and the cruelty with which men chastise them while they themselves take little notice of the sins they commit every day. Elia Kazan brings the play to screen experimenting little with editing and instead allows his actors to take charge, and boy do they bring tragedy to life! It is Marlon Brando's intense heat that allows Vivien Leigh's character to have a terrifying meltdown and the actress delivers one of the finest and most iconic performances in film history by nailing a highly complex and extremely interesting character. She may not have done it so well without Brando and we should give credit to Brando for helping her, but if you ask me who performed better, I'd unhesitatingly choose Leigh. A Streetcar Named Desire gained popularity on stage because of the quality of the story itself and Brando's acclaimed performance. When it was reproduced on screen, director Kazan roped in method-maharaja Marlon Brando and classical-chanteuse Vivien Leigh for the roles of Stanley and Blanche respectively. The rest of the cast were filled by talented actors like Kim Hunter for the role of Stella Kowalski and Karl Malden for Mitch. The controversial nature of the play made it difficult for bringing it on screen without certain cuts, but the restoration version released years later fortunately retains the deleted scenes. The story begins with Blanche Dubois' character arriving from Auriol to New Orleans by train, and taking the streetcar named Desire to Cemeteries and finally Elysian fields where her sister Stella lives with her husband Stanley. Blanche is extremely secretive about her past and only discloses to Stella that she had lost possession to their old home in Belle-Reve and was asked by the higher authority, in the school where Blanche taught English, to 'take some rest'. Blanche moves in temporarily with her sister and quickly shows displeasure at Stella's bourgeois existence and her attraction towards a violent man like Stanley. Blanche's prime desire is to begin a new life using an idealistic approach where 'magic and art' play a preeminent role and she pursues this by charming her brother-in-law's close friend and co-worker Mitch; her main obstacle comes in the form of Stanley, who does not entertain her whims, and finding loopholes in her claims, begins digging her past to break the spell Blanche wants to put everyone under. While he is instrumental in ripping her past apart, it seems like Blanche herself gives everyone an opportunity to scrutinize her past; it is as though she planted the seeds of her own destruction which were nurtured by Stanley. William's astonishing work should have been adapted to screen without altering anything because it is perfectly penned. Unfortunately, the film version alters the ending which makes Stanley looks like a complete jerk who is not only crass with Blanch but also not empathetic towards his own wife's grief. It goes against Stanley's motive of living happily with his wife and child without any de trop to disturb the 'wild peace' at home. Barring that scene, every other moment is brilliantly told and played on screen. Kazan hardly tries experimenting with the camera and in the process creates a work that is sharp and subtle. The most effective moments are when the camera abruptly cuts to or zooms into Blanche's face whenever anyone broaches the subject of her husband. Most of the effort is left to the actors who have terrific chemistry with each other, mainly because a majority of them have reprised the roles from stage. Hunter looks a lot like Debra Winger and the manner in which she spoke reminded me of young Debra from the movie 'Terms of Endearment' (of course, Debra came years later). While Debra Winger played a rich young rebellious girl who marries a simpleton, Hunter's Stella marries a commoner like Stanley because she is partly fascinated by his often violent and callous bravado. The actress convincingly plays Stella in a manner that makes us understand the character's choice, in a difficult role where she not only has to show love towards a violent man like Stanley, but also concern for her sister Blanch and slight contempt and reproach towards her husband for his treatment of Blanch. The other supporting role of Stan's friend Mitch is taken up by Malden; his character reminded me of J. Edgar Hoover who too lived alone with his sick mother and was very much concerned about her. Malden does his job well, especially in the confrontation scene between Mitch and Blanch where Mitch begins kissing her only because he then considers her a use-and-throw woman. However it is Brando and Leigh that make the day. I've now seen Brando in five different films in completely different characters and he fits each one like a glove. His realism or super-realism brings the movie alive with kinetic energy, and I realized a something watching him and Leigh  the classical Hollywood, with its stylized scripts veering towards melodramas and actors trying to bring the energies of their characters' psyche on screen, looked far more alluring a field to enter than today's Hollywood, which focuses heavily on slightly banal realism, with juiceless scripts without quote-worthy dialogs. Only one thing I shall say about Leigh: she gives us another iconic and unforgettable screen persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must see!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ImportantFilmReviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most people may call Marlon Brando a beautiful and charming man but he is no where close to charming in this film. He is primitive, controlling and territorial. He kicks a poor woman while she's down but brings a tremendous acting performance to the screen. It is very surprising that Brando shows such class and maturity yet this is only his second film. Absolute delight to watch him. Vivien Leigh is terrific as Blanche DuBois. Her spiral into insanity is wonderful as she is dominated physically and mentally by Brando's character. Kazan is a genius with the camera. His direction in this film is flawless. I would've loved to see the actual stage performance under his direction and with all these great performers. This is on my list as one of the best films in cinema history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marlon Brando...Thank god your in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the Tennesse William's play of A Streetcar Named Desire and I thought it was rather well done but I couldn't really get immersed into the story or the characters. None of the characters in the play appealed to me like they do in other novels, plays and films. I like the basic story line of the movie and how it remains simple and focuses on a young woman named Blanche who really "depends on the kindness of strangers" but realizes different after Stanley's abusive behavior. While this story works in a play, I just don't think it works all that great in a movie. Here's why... In a play/novel, you can simply enjoy one by reading in depth without much story but here in a movie, much of the film really seems boring and the fact that most of the film occurs in the dark really annoys me, even though I understand how its like in the play. There's nothing wrong with the acting. I thought Vivien Leigh did a fine job but easily the stand out of the film is the great Marlon Brandon...R.I.P. Had it not being for his portrayal of the abusive husband Stanley, this film would've been far less entertaining than what I could get of it in the end. In the film and the play, Stanley seems to be the only character with any real tone to him. In the play, I always imagined Blanche to be a rude woman and in the book, I always imagined Stella to be a disrespectful woman in the name of her family. However, in the film, you can clearly see that Stella is someone who suffers from Stanley's behavior and that Blanche is someone we are supposed to feel for. However, this film does something that makes a movie much a fail. That is, in films, we are normally supposed to be emotionally connected in some way to the protagonist. Here, Blanche is depicted as an annoying, eccentric woman (who was depicted the same in the play but also seemed to be normal)who talks in an extremely annoying and difficult to understand accent. While reading a play, we either view Blanche as a woman who is broken down by everything in her life (and so we pity her)or as someone we are portrayed to in the film (in which case, we don't care) I must admit, Mitch was quite a disappointment to me. In fact, the only character I enjoyed was Stanley who was depicted true to William's work. I must also point out that the entire script for the film is what Tennesse William wrote for the play and it annoyed me. Using parts of it is different to simply using the dialogue in the play. It doesn't add too much new to a film. In fact, how hard could it be to make parts of a script up????? NOT THAT HARD!!! I must also point out that the music used in the film really bugged me. I'm not expecting any epic music...NOOOO! But I expect some melodramatic music for a melodramatic film. In most scenes, the music did not suit the film and it felt too merry when it was supposed to be sad. Overall, many will love this film but I found it boring and annoying. Marlon Brando's superb acting and portrayal of Stanley saves it for me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complicated......yet simply told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jitin Menon
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blanche arrives in New Orleans to stay with her sister Stella and her husband Stanley. Blanche is unhappy to see her sister live in a shabby place and have her reservations on the unruly, stone age behaved brother-in-law. Stanley in turn does not like Blanche and not approve of her as he thinks she will come in between his happy marriage. This movie introduced me to the young Marlon Brando after his idolizing performance in The Godfather, And Boy!!! did he not disappoint me with his awe inspiring performance as the menacing yet charming Stanley Kowalski. The movie, mostly if not equally, belonged to Vivien Leigh whose portrayal of the neurotic Blanche DuBois was a fine example of some excellent old school performance. Kim Hunter provides a worthy support as Stella who's torn up between her sister and husband. Mitch(Karl Maiden) is adorable as he falls head over heels for Blanche. The movie based on the play by the same name,has been adapted and executed beautifully. Tennessee William's screenplay is tightly written and Elia Kazan has directed a memorable movie which will remain in the memories of the viewers for its complicated yet simple portrayal of a story of love and acceptance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No winners, only losers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Connor
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm torn by this film. In many ways it's sublime- the atmosphere, music, and the remarkable acting... but in others I can't stand it. Karl Malden's character Mitch is a nuisance, the duality of the major characters was a constant bait and switch, and with the Southern accents there are scenes where the clarity of speaking is a real problem. The characters are so double- edged it's frustrating. Blanche is clearly strange from the beginning, a tad ditsy with her head in the clouds. She feels Stanley's wrath as we do, but like any good character she isn't perfect. But then it goes so far that I couldn't root for her and I wanted to see Stanley explode on her, then back again, and it became a big mess. Stanley is physically and thematically the opposite of Blanche. Played by an absolute animal in Marlon Brando (he's huge!), Stan is bad, very alpha, completely dominant. As well he has violent tendencies, but we see his calmer side and see that he's looking out for his family and I began to side with him. He can be a horrible person, but in many instances its not unjustified. This see-saw goes back and forth through the film, until its end which goes right off of one side of the teeter- totter. But nonetheless, Stanley's portrayal- and presence on screen- is supreme. I feel like Sunset Blvd. beat Streetcar to the plot punch, and is dwarfed by On the Waterfront. The film is dark and very negative. The themes are negative and the conclusion is very sour. The moral is unclear, and with the Hays code the plot can be too vague. One of the most critical plotpoints at the end went over my head because I can't interpret what a smashed mirror means. After finishing I thought: "what did I even just watch?". Streetcar is like nothing of its era: though this review seems to have pointed out all the negatives, that is just a result of my emotions after finishing the film. It's an excellent film that decided to tell an unhappy story, very well. 8.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Explosive Movie........Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fantastic movie, of the stage play by Tennese Williams. Williams also wrote the screenplay for the movie. The four central actors Marlon Brando, Vivien Liegh, Karl Malden and Kim Hunter are excellent, and Elia Kazans direction is superb. Vivien Leigh won an Oscar for her great performance as the mentally un-hinged Blanch. Leigh had been suffering from bi-polar disorder all of her adult life, and often became "quite, quite mad" as David Niven observed. Playing Blanch was probably not too difficult for Leigh, who had a reputation for being unpredictable on film sets. Brando lost out to Humphrey Bogart (African Queen) at the academy awards that year (1951)---perhaps the world was not ready for the explosive Marlon who played part Neanderthal part Orange tang in an explosive macho performance. One of the great movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie almost in its entirety, but the ending ain't right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intp
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie as part of a college film class, around 1987 (I didn't actually take the class; I knew someone taking the class to fill a basic sociology distribution requirement; but I went to all the films for free-- and almost all of them were great!). Excellent film, with great performances all around-- until the very ending, which really bothered me. The ending in the movie was fundamentally changed from that in the original play. I had read the play in high school and thought it was brilliant. The movie, however, fundamentally alters the ending in a way, I guess, to make it a bit more "uplifting" to the audience. However, the film thereby ends up completely missing one of the key themes of the play (which is also a theme shared by Williams' "Glass Menagerie"): the way that unthinking men destroy the lives of women around them, yet the women are seemingly unable to help themselves in their attachment to those men. A tragic theme, perhaps, but too often true. While the altered ending is less downbeat, it just wasn't Williams' original story. Oddly, Roger Ebert's review doesn't even mention the change in the ending, even though he does mention other changes forced by the censors at the time. I wonder to this day if the changed ending was the director's idea, or was it forced upon him?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best acting ensemble ever in a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its actors assemble the best group of performances I've ever seen by a cast before in a motion picture. Viven Leigh is at the head, in work that reaffirms her talent as some of the finest in the business. She has the strength in one look to another character that most performances work for their entire film. Marlon Brando turns in a frightening effort that turns your stomach into mush. Kim Hunter does some great work, as well. A Streetcar Named Desire's screenplay is something to admire. The cracking dialogue and exceptional scenes that follow are sparse in the movie industry. Some of the most complex characters ever written are explored here; thankfully the cast and director put just as much effort into portraying them as the writer did into writing them in the play, which the film is based on. It's not an easy film to watch, some scenes are chilling (aided by haunting, black and white cinematography). Though I think A Streetcar Named Desire strays at times in the second half, it's an emotional roller coaster with anchoring acting. It's a great theatrical experience on film. Rating: 9.5/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated for sure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emanuel Rojas
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read many reviewers here saying that Marlon Brando's performance was amazing. I don't think it was amazing because there was nothing really complex about it. He just got mad in almost every scene, started yelling, and eventually broke stuff or smacked somebody. I felt that he had a limited range of emotions in the movie. Vivien Leigh gave an excellent performance, and she had to go to really abstract places to pull off her role. Blanche is a character that harbours delusions, lies pathologically, and suffers from terrible anxiety, so it was a complex role. The rest of the cast acts well, and Karl Malden's performance was the third most interesting in the movie. As for the story, it is not really that interesting. It takes place in one setting only for 99% of the movie, and is really heavy on the dialogue because it's based on a play. I think Tennesse Williams really dropped the ball by not including a night club scene in the play, with it being set in New Orleans. I haven't read the play, but I think the play / movie would have been way better had we seen Blanche going out with Stella in New Orleans and mixing it up with the locals. There was none of that in this movie, we see her in a bedroom most of the time being a weird brand of crazy southern belle, which gets boring. I think the reason that this movie made such an impact in 1951, was because it depicted mental illness in a way that hadn't been seen before. That's my guess at least. However, I doubt that either Tennessee Williams or Vivien Leigh really did much research into mental illness. I think the main thing that Tennessee Williams wanted to achieve was to create an iconic figure of a southern belle who goes crazy because the world is too harsh, and that southern ideals were doomed. If you care about any of that, you might enjoy this movie. Most of us don't care about any of that, for good reason, so that is why the movie won't make an impression on us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary Reese
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1950s film Adaptation of Tennessee Williams' A Streetcar Named Desire. Set in New Orleans, Blanche DuBois (Vivien Leigh) comes to with her sister, Stella, played by Kim Hunter, and her brother in law, Stanley, Marlon Brando. Blanche has found herself in a heap of personal troubles, but keeps up with the charade for her sister. She is prim and proper, an English teacher, with a trunk full of fancy outfits and jewelry. Stanley sees through this. Stanley is a rough around the edges, loud-mouthed character. This is an amazing breakthrough role for Brando. It was well casted all around. Domestic disputes breakout and emotions run high. This is one of the best movies still, to this day. Iconic scenes and characters. Worth a watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brando's volcanic energy gives Vivien the needed momentum to deliver one of the finest and most iconic performances in screen history as Blanche DuBois
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We witness Blanch Dubois burn in the flames ignited by Stanley Kowalski, thereby obliterating the destitute woman's small hopes of redeeming herself and starting life afresh. The other way to look at the situation would be: Stanley's force compels Blanch to face her crimes and gives her an opportunity to live a normal life sometime in the future. 'A Streetcar named Desire' veers between Blanch's attempts at ridding herself of guilt through ignorance and delusion and Stanley's will to expose Blanch's past and force her to admit and punish herself for her sins. Its playwright Tennessee Williams gives us a harrowing example of the difficulties faced by women who have stained their characters, and the cruelty with which men chastise them while they themselves take little notice of the sins they commit every day. Elia Kazan brings the play to screen experimenting little with editing and instead allows his actors to take charge, and boy do they bring tragedy to life! It is Marlon Brando's intense heat that allows Vivien Leigh's character to have a terrifying meltdown and the actress delivers one of the finest and most iconic performances in film history by nailing a highly complex and extremely interesting character. She may not have done it so well without Brando and we should give credit to Brando for helping her, but if you ask me who performed better, I'd unhesitatingly choose Leigh. A Streetcar Named Desire gained popularity on stage because of the quality of the story itself and Brando's acclaimed performance. When it was reproduced on screen, director Kazan roped in method-maharaja Marlon Brando and classical-chanteuse Vivien Leigh for the roles of Stanley and Blanche respectively. The rest of the cast were filled by talented actors like Kim Hunter for the role of Stella Kowalski and Karl Malden for Mitch. The controversial nature of the play made it difficult for bringing it on screen without certain cuts, but the restoration version released years later fortunately retains the deleted scenes. The story begins with Blanche Dubois' character arriving from Auriol to New Orleans by train, and taking the streetcar named Desire to Cemeteries and finally Elysian fields where her sister Stella lives with her husband Stanley. Blanche is extremely secretive about her past and only discloses to Stella that she had lost possession to their old home in Belle-Reve and was asked by the higher authority, in the school where Blanche taught English, to 'take some rest'. Blanche moves in temporarily with her sister and quickly shows displeasure at Stella's bourgeois existence and her attraction towards a violent man like Stanley. Blanche's prime desire is to begin a new life using an idealistic approach where 'magic and art' play a preeminent role and she pursues this by charming her brother-in-law's close friend and co-worker Mitch; her main obstacle comes in the form of Stanley, who does not entertain her whims, and finding loopholes in her claims, begins digging her past to break the spell Blanche wants to put everyone under. While he is instrumental in ripping her past apart, it seems like Blanche herself gives everyone an opportunity to scrutinize her past; it is as though she planted the seeds of her own destruction which were nurtured by Stanley. William's astonishing work should have been adapted to screen without altering anything because it is perfectly penned. Unfortunately, the film version alters the ending which makes Stanley looks like a complete jerk who is not only crass with Blanch but also not empathetic towards his own wife's grief. It goes against Stanley's motive of living happily with his wife and child without any de trop to disturb the 'wild peace' at home. Barring that scene, every other moment is brilliantly told and played on screen. Kazan hardly tries experimenting with the camera and in the process creates a work that is sharp and subtle. The most effective moments are when the camera abruptly cuts to or zooms into Blanche's face whenever anyone broaches the subject of her husband. Most of the effort is left to the actors who have terrific chemistry with each other, mainly because a majority of them have reprised the roles from stage. Hunter looks a lot like Debra Winger and the manner in which she spoke reminded me of young Debra from the movie 'Terms of Endearment' (of course, Debra came years later). While Debra Winger played a rich young rebellious girl who marries a simpleton, Hunter's Stella marries a commoner like Stanley because she is partly fascinated by his often violent and callous bravado. The actress convincingly plays Stella in a manner that makes us understand the character's choice, in a difficult role where she not only has to show love towards a violent man like Stanley, but also concern for her sister Blanch and slight contempt and reproach towards her husband for his treatment of Blanch. The other supporting role of Stan's friend Mitch is taken up by Malden; his character reminded me of J. Edgar Hoover who too lived alone with his sick mother and was very much concerned about her. Malden does his job well, especially in the confrontation scene between Mitch and Blanch where Mitch begins kissing her only because he then considers her a use-and-throw woman. However it is Brando and Leigh that make the day. I've now seen Brando in five different films in completely different characters and he fits each one like a glove. His realism or super-realism brings the movie alive with kinetic energy, and I realized a something watching him and Leigh  the classical Hollywood, with its stylized scripts veering towards melodramas and actors trying to bring the energies of their characters' psyche on screen, looked far more alluring a field to enter than today's Hollywood, which focuses heavily on slightly banal realism, with juiceless scripts without quote-worthy dialogs. Only one thing I shall say about Leigh: she gives us another iconic and unforgettable screen persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must see!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ImportantFilmReviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most people may call Marlon Brando a beautiful and charming man but he is no where close to charming in this film. He is primitive, controlling and territorial. He kicks a poor woman while she's down but brings a tremendous acting performance to the screen. It is very surprising that Brando shows such class and maturity yet this is only his second film. Absolute delight to watch him. Vivien Leigh is terrific as Blanche DuBois. Her spiral into insanity is wonderful as she is dominated physically and mentally by Brando's character. Kazan is a genius with the camera. His direction in this film is flawless. I would've loved to see the actual stage performance under his direction and with all these great performers. This is on my list as one of the best films in cinema history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marlon Brando...Thank god your in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the Tennesse William's play of A Streetcar Named Desire and I thought it was rather well done but I couldn't really get immersed into the story or the characters. None of the characters in the play appealed to me like they do in other novels, plays and films. I like the basic story line of the movie and how it remains simple and focuses on a young woman named Blanche who really "depends on the kindness of strangers" but realizes different after Stanley's abusive behavior. While this story works in a play, I just don't think it works all that great in a movie. Here's why... In a play/novel, you can simply enjoy one by reading in depth without much story but here in a movie, much of the film really seems boring and the fact that most of the film occurs in the dark really annoys me, even though I understand how its like in the play. There's nothing wrong with the acting. I thought Vivien Leigh did a fine job but easily the stand out of the film is the great Marlon Brandon...R.I.P. Had it not being for his portrayal of the abusive husband Stanley, this film would've been far less entertaining than what I could get of it in the end. In the film and the play, Stanley seems to be the only character with any real tone to him. In the play, I always imagined Blanche to be a rude woman and in the book, I always imagined Stella to be a disrespectful woman in the name of her family. However, in the film, you can clearly see that Stella is someone who suffers from Stanley's behavior and that Blanche is someone we are supposed to feel for. However, this film does something that makes a movie much a fail. That is, in films, we are normally supposed to be emotionally connected in some way to the protagonist. Here, Blanche is depicted as an annoying, eccentric woman (who was depicted the same in the play but also seemed to be normal)who talks in an extremely annoying and difficult to understand accent. While reading a play, we either view Blanche as a woman who is broken down by everything in her life (and so we pity her)or as someone we are portrayed to in the film (in which case, we don't care) I must admit, Mitch was quite a disappointment to me. In fact, the only character I enjoyed was Stanley who was depicted true to William's work. I must also point out that the entire script for the film is what Tennesse William wrote for the play and it annoyed me. Using parts of it is different to simply using the dialogue in the play. It doesn't add too much new to a film. In fact, how hard could it be to make parts of a script up????? NOT THAT HARD!!! I must also point out that the music used in the film really bugged me. I'm not expecting any epic music...NOOOO! But I expect some melodramatic music for a melodramatic film. In most scenes, the music did not suit the film and it felt too merry when it was supposed to be sad. Overall, many will love this film but I found it boring and annoying. Marlon Brando's superb acting and portrayal of Stanley saves it for me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complicated......yet simply told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jitin Menon
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blanche arrives in New Orleans to stay with her sister Stella and her husband Stanley. Blanche is unhappy to see her sister live in a shabby place and have her reservations on the unruly, stone age behaved brother-in-law. Stanley in turn does not like Blanche and not approve of her as he thinks she will come in between his happy marriage. This movie introduced me to the young Marlon Brando after his idolizing performance in The Godfather, And Boy!!! did he not disappoint me with his awe inspiring performance as the menacing yet charming Stanley Kowalski. The movie, mostly if not equally, belonged to Vivien Leigh whose portrayal of the neurotic Blanche DuBois was a fine example of some excellent old school performance. Kim Hunter provides a worthy support as Stella who's torn up between her sister and husband. Mitch(Karl Maiden) is adorable as he falls head over heels for Blanche. The movie based on the play by the same name,has been adapted and executed beautifully. Tennessee William's screenplay is tightly written and Elia Kazan has directed a memorable movie which will remain in the memories of the viewers for its complicated yet simple portrayal of a story of love and acceptance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No winners, only losers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Connor
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm torn by this film. In many ways it's sublime- the atmosphere, music, and the remarkable acting... but in others I can't stand it. Karl Malden's character Mitch is a nuisance, the duality of the major characters was a constant bait and switch, and with the Southern accents there are scenes where the clarity of speaking is a real problem. The characters are so double- edged it's frustrating. Blanche is clearly strange from the beginning, a tad ditsy with her head in the clouds. She feels Stanley's wrath as we do, but like any good character she isn't perfect. But then it goes so far that I couldn't root for her and I wanted to see Stanley explode on her, then back again, and it became a big mess. Stanley is physically and thematically the opposite of Blanche. Played by an absolute animal in Marlon Brando (he's huge!), Stan is bad, very alpha, completely dominant. As well he has violent tendencies, but we see his calmer side and see that he's looking out for his family and I began to side with him. He can be a horrible person, but in many instances its not unjustified. This see-saw goes back and forth through the film, until its end which goes right off of one side of the teeter- totter. But nonetheless, Stanley's portrayal- and presence on screen- is supreme. I feel like Sunset Blvd. beat Streetcar to the plot punch, and is dwarfed by On the Waterfront. The film is dark and very negative. The themes are negative and the conclusion is very sour. The moral is unclear, and with the Hays code the plot can be too vague. One of the most critical plotpoints at the end went over my head because I can't interpret what a smashed mirror means. After finishing I thought: "what did I even just watch?". Streetcar is like nothing of its era: though this review seems to have pointed out all the negatives, that is just a result of my emotions after finishing the film. It's an excellent film that decided to tell an unhappy story, very well. 8.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Explosive Movie........Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fantastic movie, of the stage play by Tennese Williams. Williams also wrote the screenplay for the movie. The four central actors Marlon Brando, Vivien Liegh, Karl Malden and Kim Hunter are excellent, and Elia Kazans direction is superb. Vivien Leigh won an Oscar for her great performance as the mentally un-hinged Blanch. Leigh had been suffering from bi-polar disorder all of her adult life, and often became "quite, quite mad" as David Niven observed. Playing Blanch was probably not too difficult for Leigh, who had a reputation for being unpredictable on film sets. Brando lost out to Humphrey Bogart (African Queen) at the academy awards that year (1951)---perhaps the world was not ready for the explosive Marlon who played part Neanderthal part Orange tang in an explosive macho performance. One of the great movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie almost in its entirety, but the ending ain't right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intp
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie as part of a college film class, around 1987 (I didn't actually take the class; I knew someone taking the class to fill a basic sociology distribution requirement; but I went to all the films for free-- and almost all of them were great!). Excellent film, with great performances all around-- until the very ending, which really bothered me. The ending in the movie was fundamentally changed from that in the original play. I had read the play in high school and thought it was brilliant. The movie, however, fundamentally alters the ending in a way, I guess, to make it a bit more "uplifting" to the audience. However, the film thereby ends up completely missing one of the key themes of the play (which is also a theme shared by Williams' "Glass Menagerie"): the way that unthinking men destroy the lives of women around them, yet the women are seemingly unable to help themselves in their attachment to those men. A tragic theme, perhaps, but too often true. While the altered ending is less downbeat, it just wasn't Williams' original story. Oddly, Roger Ebert's review doesn't even mention the change in the ending, even though he does mention other changes forced by the censors at the time. I wonder to this day if the changed ending was the director's idea, or was it forced upon him?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best acting ensemble ever in a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its actors assemble the best group of performances I've ever seen by a cast before in a motion picture. Viven Leigh is at the head, in work that reaffirms her talent as some of the finest in the business. She has the strength in one look to another character that most performances work for their entire film. Marlon Brando turns in a frightening effort that turns your stomach into mush. Kim Hunter does some great work, as well. A Streetcar Named Desire's screenplay is something to admire. The cracking dialogue and exceptional scenes that follow are sparse in the movie industry. Some of the most complex characters ever written are explored here; thankfully the cast and director put just as much effort into portraying them as the writer did into writing them in the play, which the film is based on. It's not an easy film to watch, some scenes are chilling (aided by haunting, black and white cinematography). Though I think A Streetcar Named Desire strays at times in the second half, it's an emotional roller coaster with anchoring acting. It's a great theatrical experience on film. Rating: 9.5/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated for sure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emanuel Rojas
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read many reviewers here saying that Marlon Brando's performance was amazing. I don't think it was amazing because there was nothing really complex about it. He just got mad in almost every scene, started yelling, and eventually broke stuff or smacked somebody. I felt that he had a limited range of emotions in the movie. Vivien Leigh gave an excellent performance, and she had to go to really abstract places to pull off her role. Blanche is a character that harbours delusions, lies pathologically, and suffers from terrible anxiety, so it was a complex role. The rest of the cast acts well, and Karl Malden's performance was the third most interesting in the movie. As for the story, it is not really that interesting. It takes place in one setting only for 99% of the movie, and is really heavy on the dialogue because it's based on a play. I think Tennesse Williams really dropped the ball by not including a night club scene in the play, with it being set in New Orleans. I haven't read the play, but I think the play / movie would have been way better had we seen Blanche going out with Stella in New Orleans and mixing it up with the locals. There was none of that in this movie, we see her in a bedroom most of the time being a weird brand of crazy southern belle, which gets boring. I think the reason that this movie made such an impact in 1951, was because it depicted mental illness in a way that hadn't been seen before. That's my guess at least. However, I doubt that either Tennessee Williams or Vivien Leigh really did much research into mental illness. I think the main thing that Tennessee Williams wanted to achieve was to create an iconic figure of a southern belle who goes crazy because the world is too harsh, and that southern ideals were doomed. If you care about any of that, you might enjoy this movie. Most of us don't care about any of that, for good reason, so that is why the movie won't make an impression on us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary Reese
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1950s film Adaptation of Tennessee Williams' A Streetcar Named Desire. Set in New Orleans, Blanche DuBois (Vivien Leigh) comes to with her sister, Stella, played by Kim Hunter, and her brother in law, Stanley, Marlon Brando. Blanche has found herself in a heap of personal troubles, but keeps up with the charade for her sister. She is prim and proper, an English teacher, with a trunk full of fancy outfits and jewelry. Stanley sees through this. Stanley is a rough around the edges, loud-mouthed character. This is an amazing breakthrough role for Brando. It was well casted all around. Domestic disputes breakout and emotions run high. This is one of the best movies still, to this day. Iconic scenes and characters. Worth a watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brando's volcanic energy gives Vivien the needed momentum to deliver one of the finest and most iconic performances in screen history as Blanche DuBois
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We witness Blanch Dubois burn in the flames ignited by Stanley Kowalski, thereby obliterating the destitute woman's small hopes of redeeming herself and starting life afresh. The other way to look at the situation would be: Stanley's force compels Blanch to face her crimes and gives her an opportunity to live a normal life sometime in the future. 'A Streetcar named Desire' veers between Blanch's attempts at ridding herself of guilt through ignorance and delusion and Stanley's will to expose Blanch's past and force her to admit and punish herself for her sins. Its playwright Tennessee Williams gives us a harrowing example of the difficulties faced by women who have stained their characters, and the cruelty with which men chastise them while they themselves take little notice of the sins they commit every day. Elia Kazan brings the play to screen experimenting little with editing and instead allows his actors to take charge, and boy do they bring tragedy to life! It is Marlon Brando's intense heat that allows Vivien Leigh's character to have a terrifying meltdown and the actress delivers one of the finest and most iconic performances in film history by nailing a highly complex and extremely interesting character. She may not have done it so well without Brando and we should give credit to Brando for helping her, but if you ask me who performed better, I'd unhesitatingly choose Leigh. A Streetcar Named Desire gained popularity on stage because of the quality of the story itself and Brando's acclaimed performance. When it was reproduced on screen, director Kazan roped in method-maharaja Marlon Brando and classical-chanteuse Vivien Leigh for the roles of Stanley and Blanche respectively. The rest of the cast were filled by talented actors like Kim Hunter for the role of Stella Kowalski and Karl Malden for Mitch. The controversial nature of the play made it difficult for bringing it on screen without certain cuts, but the restoration version released years later fortunately retains the deleted scenes. The story begins with Blanche Dubois' character arriving from Auriol to New Orleans by train, and taking the streetcar named Desire to Cemeteries and finally Elysian fields where her sister Stella lives with her husband Stanley. Blanche is extremely secretive about her past and only discloses to Stella that she had lost possession to their old home in Belle-Reve and was asked by the higher authority, in the school where Blanche taught English, to 'take some rest'. Blanche moves in temporarily with her sister and quickly shows displeasure at Stella's bourgeois existence and her attraction towards a violent man like Stanley. Blanche's prime desire is to begin a new life using an idealistic approach where 'magic and art' play a preeminent role and she pursues this by charming her brother-in-law's close friend and co-worker Mitch; her main obstacle comes in the form of Stanley, who does not entertain her whims, and finding loopholes in her claims, begins digging her past to break the spell Blanche wants to put everyone under. While he is instrumental in ripping her past apart, it seems like Blanche herself gives everyone an opportunity to scrutinize her past; it is as though she planted the seeds of her own destruction which were nurtured by Stanley. William's astonishing work should have been adapted to screen without altering anything because it is perfectly penned. Unfortunately, the film version alters the ending which makes Stanley looks like a complete jerk who is not only crass with Blanch but also not empathetic towards his own wife's grief. It goes against Stanley's motive of living happily with his wife and child without any de trop to disturb the 'wild peace' at home. Barring that scene, every other moment is brilliantly told and played on screen. Kazan hardly tries experimenting with the camera and in the process creates a work that is sharp and subtle. The most effective moments are when the camera abruptly cuts to or zooms into Blanche's face whenever anyone broaches the subject of her husband. Most of the effort is left to the actors who have terrific chemistry with each other, mainly because a majority of them have reprised the roles from stage. Hunter looks a lot like Debra Winger and the manner in which she spoke reminded me of young Debra from the movie 'Terms of Endearment' (of course, Debra came years later). While Debra Winger played a rich young rebellious girl who marries a simpleton, Hunter's Stella marries a commoner like Stanley because she is partly fascinated by his often violent and callous bravado. The actress convincingly plays Stella in a manner that makes us understand the character's choice, in a difficult role where she not only has to show love towards a violent man like Stanley, but also concern for her sister Blanch and slight contempt and reproach towards her husband for his treatment of Blanch. The other supporting role of Stan's friend Mitch is taken up by Malden; his character reminded me of J. Edgar Hoover who too lived alone with his sick mother and was very much concerned about her. Malden does his job well, especially in the confrontation scene between Mitch and Blanch where Mitch begins kissing her only because he then considers her a use-and-throw woman. However it is Brando and Leigh that make the day. I've now seen Brando in five different films in completely different characters and he fits each one like a glove. His realism or super-realism brings the movie alive with kinetic energy, and I realized a something watching him and Leigh  the classical Hollywood, with its stylized scripts veering towards melodramas and actors trying to bring the energies of their characters' psyche on screen, looked far more alluring a field to enter than today's Hollywood, which focuses heavily on slightly banal realism, with juiceless scripts without quote-worthy dialogs. Only one thing I shall say about Leigh: she gives us another iconic and unforgettable screen persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must see!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ImportantFilmReviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most people may call Marlon Brando a beautiful and charming man but he is no where close to charming in this film. He is primitive, controlling and territorial. He kicks a poor woman while she's down but brings a tremendous acting performance to the screen. It is very surprising that Brando shows such class and maturity yet this is only his second film. Absolute delight to watch him. Vivien Leigh is terrific as Blanche DuBois. Her spiral into insanity is wonderful as she is dominated physically and mentally by Brando's character. Kazan is a genius with the camera. His direction in this film is flawless. I would've loved to see the actual stage performance under his direction and with all these great performers. This is on my list as one of the best films in cinema history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marlon Brando...Thank god your in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the Tennesse William's play of A Streetcar Named Desire and I thought it was rather well done but I couldn't really get immersed into the story or the characters. None of the characters in the play appealed to me like they do in other novels, plays and films. I like the basic story line of the movie and how it remains simple and focuses on a young woman named Blanche who really "depends on the kindness of strangers" but realizes different after Stanley's abusive behavior. While this story works in a play, I just don't think it works all that great in a movie. Here's why... In a play/novel, you can simply enjoy one by reading in depth without much story but here in a movie, much of the film really seems boring and the fact that most of the film occurs in the dark really annoys me, even though I understand how its like in the play. There's nothing wrong with the acting. I thought Vivien Leigh did a fine job but easily the stand out of the film is the great Marlon Brandon...R.I.P. Had it not being for his portrayal of the abusive husband Stanley, this film would've been far less entertaining than what I could get of it in the end. In the film and the play, Stanley seems to be the only character with any real tone to him. In the play, I always imagined Blanche to be a rude woman and in the book, I always imagined Stella to be a disrespectful woman in the name of her family. However, in the film, you can clearly see that Stella is someone who suffers from Stanley's behavior and that Blanche is someone we are supposed to feel for. However, this film does something that makes a movie much a fail. That is, in films, we are normally supposed to be emotionally connected in some way to the protagonist. Here, Blanche is depicted as an annoying, eccentric woman (who was depicted the same in the play but also seemed to be normal)who talks in an extremely annoying and difficult to understand accent. While reading a play, we either view Blanche as a woman who is broken down by everything in her life (and so we pity her)or as someone we are portrayed to in the film (in which case, we don't care) I must admit, Mitch was quite a disappointment to me. In fact, the only character I enjoyed was Stanley who was depicted true to William's work. I must also point out that the entire script for the film is what Tennesse William wrote for the play and it annoyed me. Using parts of it is different to simply using the dialogue in the play. It doesn't add too much new to a film. In fact, how hard could it be to make parts of a script up????? NOT THAT HARD!!! I must also point out that the music used in the film really bugged me. I'm not expecting any epic music...NOOOO! But I expect some melodramatic music for a melodramatic film. In most scenes, the music did not suit the film and it felt too merry when it was supposed to be sad. Overall, many will love this film but I found it boring and annoying. Marlon Brando's superb acting and portrayal of Stanley saves it for me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complicated......yet simply told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jitin Menon
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blanche arrives in New Orleans to stay with her sister Stella and her husband Stanley. Blanche is unhappy to see her sister live in a shabby place and have her reservations on the unruly, stone age behaved brother-in-law. Stanley in turn does not like Blanche and not approve of her as he thinks she will come in between his happy marriage. This movie introduced me to the young Marlon Brando after his idolizing performance in The Godfather, And Boy!!! did he not disappoint me with his awe inspiring performance as the menacing yet charming Stanley Kowalski. The movie, mostly if not equally, belonged to Vivien Leigh whose portrayal of the neurotic Blanche DuBois was a fine example of some excellent old school performance. Kim Hunter provides a worthy support as Stella who's torn up between her sister and husband. Mitch(Karl Maiden) is adorable as he falls head over heels for Blanche. The movie based on the play by the same name,has been adapted and executed beautifully. Tennessee William's screenplay is tightly written and Elia Kazan has directed a memorable movie which will remain in the memories of the viewers for its complicated yet simple portrayal of a story of love and acceptance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No winners, only losers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Connor
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm torn by this film. In many ways it's sublime- the atmosphere, music, and the remarkable acting... but in others I can't stand it. Karl Malden's character Mitch is a nuisance, the duality of the major characters was a constant bait and switch, and with the Southern accents there are scenes where the clarity of speaking is a real problem. The characters are so double- edged it's frustrating. Blanche is clearly strange from the beginning, a tad ditsy with her head in the clouds. She feels Stanley's wrath as we do, but like any good character she isn't perfect. But then it goes so far that I couldn't root for her and I wanted to see Stanley explode on her, then back again, and it became a big mess. Stanley is physically and thematically the opposite of Blanche. Played by an absolute animal in Marlon Brando (he's huge!), Stan is bad, very alpha, completely dominant. As well he has violent tendencies, but we see his calmer side and see that he's looking out for his family and I began to side with him. He can be a horrible person, but in many instances its not unjustified. This see-saw goes back and forth through the film, until its end which goes right off of one side of the teeter- totter. But nonetheless, Stanley's portrayal- and presence on screen- is supreme. I feel like Sunset Blvd. beat Streetcar to the plot punch, and is dwarfed by On the Waterfront. The film is dark and very negative. The themes are negative and the conclusion is very sour. The moral is unclear, and with the Hays code the plot can be too vague. One of the most critical plotpoints at the end went over my head because I can't interpret what a smashed mirror means. After finishing I thought: "what did I even just watch?". Streetcar is like nothing of its era: though this review seems to have pointed out all the negatives, that is just a result of my emotions after finishing the film. It's an excellent film that decided to tell an unhappy story, very well. 8.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Explosive Movie........Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fantastic movie, of the stage play by Tennese Williams. Williams also wrote the screenplay for the movie. The four central actors Marlon Brando, Vivien Liegh, Karl Malden and Kim Hunter are excellent, and Elia Kazans direction is superb. Vivien Leigh won an Oscar for her great performance as the mentally un-hinged Blanch. Leigh had been suffering from bi-polar disorder all of her adult life, and often became "quite, quite mad" as David Niven observed. Playing Blanch was probably not too difficult for Leigh, who had a reputation for being unpredictable on film sets. Brando lost out to Humphrey Bogart (African Queen) at the academy awards that year (1951)---perhaps the world was not ready for the explosive Marlon who played part Neanderthal part Orange tang in an explosive macho performance. One of the great movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie almost in its entirety, but the ending ain't right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intp
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie as part of a college film class, around 1987 (I didn't actually take the class; I knew someone taking the class to fill a basic sociology distribution requirement; but I went to all the films for free-- and almost all of them were great!). Excellent film, with great performances all around-- until the very ending, which really bothered me. The ending in the movie was fundamentally changed from that in the original play. I had read the play in high school and thought it was brilliant. The movie, however, fundamentally alters the ending in a way, I guess, to make it a bit more "uplifting" to the audience. However, the film thereby ends up completely missing one of the key themes of the play (which is also a theme shared by Williams' "Glass Menagerie"): the way that unthinking men destroy the lives of women around them, yet the women are seemingly unable to help themselves in their attachment to those men. A tragic theme, perhaps, but too often true. While the altered ending is less downbeat, it just wasn't Williams' original story. Oddly, Roger Ebert's review doesn't even mention the change in the ending, even though he does mention other changes forced by the censors at the time. I wonder to this day if the changed ending was the director's idea, or was it forced upon him?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best acting ensemble ever in a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its actors assemble the best group of performances I've ever seen by a cast before in a motion picture. Viven Leigh is at the head, in work that reaffirms her talent as some of the finest in the business. She has the strength in one look to another character that most performances work for their entire film. Marlon Brando turns in a frightening effort that turns your stomach into mush. Kim Hunter does some great work, as well. A Streetcar Named Desire's screenplay is something to admire. The cracking dialogue and exceptional scenes that follow are sparse in the movie industry. Some of the most complex characters ever written are explored here; thankfully the cast and director put just as much effort into portraying them as the writer did into writing them in the play, which the film is based on. It's not an easy film to watch, some scenes are chilling (aided by haunting, black and white cinematography). Though I think A Streetcar Named Desire strays at times in the second half, it's an emotional roller coaster with anchoring acting. It's a great theatrical experience on film. Rating: 9.5/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated for sure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emanuel Rojas
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read many reviewers here saying that Marlon Brando's performance was amazing. I don't think it was amazing because there was nothing really complex about it. He just got mad in almost every scene, started yelling, and eventually broke stuff or smacked somebody. I felt that he had a limited range of emotions in the movie. Vivien Leigh gave an excellent performance, and she had to go to really abstract places to pull off her role. Blanche is a character that harbours delusions, lies pathologically, and suffers from terrible anxiety, so it was a complex role. The rest of the cast acts well, and Karl Malden's performance was the third most interesting in the movie. As for the story, it is not really that interesting. It takes place in one setting only for 99% of the movie, and is really heavy on the dialogue because it's based on a play. I think Tennesse Williams really dropped the ball by not including a night club scene in the play, with it being set in New Orleans. I haven't read the play, but I think the play / movie would have been way better had we seen Blanche going out with Stella in New Orleans and mixing it up with the locals. There was none of that in this movie, we see her in a bedroom most of the time being a weird brand of crazy southern belle, which gets boring. I think the reason that this movie made such an impact in 1951, was because it depicted mental illness in a way that hadn't been seen before. That's my guess at least. However, I doubt that either Tennessee Williams or Vivien Leigh really did much research into mental illness. I think the main thing that Tennessee Williams wanted to achieve was to create an iconic figure of a southern belle who goes crazy because the world is too harsh, and that southern ideals were doomed. If you care about any of that, you might enjoy this movie. Most of us don't care about any of that, for good reason, so that is why the movie won't make an impression on us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary Reese
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1950s film Adaptation of Tennessee Williams' A Streetcar Named Desire. Set in New Orleans, Blanche DuBois (Vivien Leigh) comes to with her sister, Stella, played by Kim Hunter, and her brother in law, Stanley, Marlon Brando. Blanche has found herself in a heap of personal troubles, but keeps up with the charade for her sister. She is prim and proper, an English teacher, with a trunk full of fancy outfits and jewelry. Stanley sees through this. Stanley is a rough around the edges, loud-mouthed character. This is an amazing breakthrough role for Brando. It was well casted all around. Domestic disputes breakout and emotions run high. This is one of the best movies still, to this day. Iconic scenes and characters. Worth a watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brando's volcanic energy gives Vivien the needed momentum to deliver one of the finest and most iconic performances in screen history as Blanche DuBois
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We witness Blanch Dubois burn in the flames ignited by Stanley Kowalski, thereby obliterating the destitute woman's small hopes of redeeming herself and starting life afresh. The other way to look at the situation would be: Stanley's force compels Blanch to face her crimes and gives her an opportunity to live a normal life sometime in the future. 'A Streetcar named Desire' veers between Blanch's attempts at ridding herself of guilt through ignorance and delusion and Stanley's will to expose Blanch's past and force her to admit and punish herself for her sins. Its playwright Tennessee Williams gives us a harrowing example of the difficulties faced by women who have stained their characters, and the cruelty with which men chastise them while they themselves take little notice of the sins they commit every day. Elia Kazan brings the play to screen experimenting little with editing and instead allows his actors to take charge, and boy do they bring tragedy to life! It is Marlon Brando's intense heat that allows Vivien Leigh's character to have a terrifying meltdown and the actress delivers one of the finest and most iconic performances in film history by nailing a highly complex and extremely interesting character. She may not have done it so well without Brando and we should give credit to Brando for helping her, but if you ask me who performed better, I'd unhesitatingly choose Leigh. A Streetcar Named Desire gained popularity on stage because of the quality of the story itself and Brando's acclaimed performance. When it was reproduced on screen, director Kazan roped in method-maharaja Marlon Brando and classical-chanteuse Vivien Leigh for the roles of Stanley and Blanche respectively. The rest of the cast were filled by talented actors like Kim Hunter for the role of Stella Kowalski and Karl Malden for Mitch. The controversial nature of the play made it difficult for bringing it on screen without certain cuts, but the restoration version released years later fortunately retains the deleted scenes. The story begins with Blanche Dubois' character arriving from Auriol to New Orleans by train, and taking the streetcar named Desire to Cemeteries and finally Elysian fields where her sister Stella lives with her husband Stanley. Blanche is extremely secretive about her past and only discloses to Stella that she had lost possession to their old home in Belle-Reve and was asked by the higher authority, in the school where Blanche taught English, to 'take some rest'. Blanche moves in temporarily with her sister and quickly shows displeasure at Stella's bourgeois existence and her attraction towards a violent man like Stanley. Blanche's prime desire is to begin a new life using an idealistic approach where 'magic and art' play a preeminent role and she pursues this by charming her brother-in-law's close friend and co-worker Mitch; her main obstacle comes in the form of Stanley, who does not entertain her whims, and finding loopholes in her claims, begins digging her past to break the spell Blanche wants to put everyone under. While he is instrumental in ripping her past apart, it seems like Blanche herself gives everyone an opportunity to scrutinize her past; it is as though she planted the seeds of her own destruction which were nurtured by Stanley. William's astonishing work should have been adapted to screen without altering anything because it is perfectly penned. Unfortunately, the film version alters the ending which makes Stanley looks like a complete jerk who is not only crass with Blanch but also not empathetic towards his own wife's grief. It goes against Stanley's motive of living happily with his wife and child without any de trop to disturb the 'wild peace' at home. Barring that scene, every other moment is brilliantly told and played on screen. Kazan hardly tries experimenting with the camera and in the process creates a work that is sharp and subtle. The most effective moments are when the camera abruptly cuts to or zooms into Blanche's face whenever anyone broaches the subject of her husband. Most of the effort is left to the actors who have terrific chemistry with each other, mainly because a majority of them have reprised the roles from stage. Hunter looks a lot like Debra Winger and the manner in which she spoke reminded me of young Debra from the movie 'Terms of Endearment' (of course, Debra came years later). While Debra Winger played a rich young rebellious girl who marries a simpleton, Hunter's Stella marries a commoner like Stanley because she is partly fascinated by his often violent and callous bravado. The actress convincingly plays Stella in a manner that makes us understand the character's choice, in a difficult role where she not only has to show love towards a violent man like Stanley, but also concern for her sister Blanch and slight contempt and reproach towards her husband for his treatment of Blanch. The other supporting role of Stan's friend Mitch is taken up by Malden; his character reminded me of J. Edgar Hoover who too lived alone with his sick mother and was very much concerned about her. Malden does his job well, especially in the confrontation scene between Mitch and Blanch where Mitch begins kissing her only because he then considers her a use-and-throw woman. However it is Brando and Leigh that make the day. I've now seen Brando in five different films in completely different characters and he fits each one like a glove. His realism or super-realism brings the movie alive with kinetic energy, and I realized a something watching him and Leigh  the classical Hollywood, with its stylized scripts veering towards melodramas and actors trying to bring the energies of their characters' psyche on screen, looked far more alluring a field to enter than today's Hollywood, which focuses heavily on slightly banal realism, with juiceless scripts without quote-worthy dialogs. Only one thing I shall say about Leigh: she gives us another iconic and unforgettable screen persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must see!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ImportantFilmReviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most people may call Marlon Brando a beautiful and charming man but he is no where close to charming in this film. He is primitive, controlling and territorial. He kicks a poor woman while she's down but brings a tremendous acting performance to the screen. It is very surprising that Brando shows such class and maturity yet this is only his second film. Absolute delight to watch him. Vivien Leigh is terrific as Blanche DuBois. Her spiral into insanity is wonderful as she is dominated physically and mentally by Brando's character. Kazan is a genius with the camera. His direction in this film is flawless. I would've loved to see the actual stage performance under his direction and with all these great performers. This is on my list as one of the best films in cinema history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marlon Brando...Thank god your in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the Tennesse William's play of A Streetcar Named Desire and I thought it was rather well done but I couldn't really get immersed into the story or the characters. None of the characters in the play appealed to me like they do in other novels, plays and films. I like the basic story line of the movie and how it remains simple and focuses on a young woman named Blanche who really "depends on the kindness of strangers" but realizes different after Stanley's abusive behavior. While this story works in a play, I just don't think it works all that great in a movie. Here's why... In a play/novel, you can simply enjoy one by reading in depth without much story but here in a movie, much of the film really seems boring and the fact that most of the film occurs in the dark really annoys me, even though I understand how its like in the play. There's nothing wrong with the acting. I thought Vivien Leigh did a fine job but easily the stand out of the film is the great Marlon Brandon...R.I.P. Had it not being for his portrayal of the abusive husband Stanley, this film would've been far less entertaining than what I could get of it in the end. In the film and the play, Stanley seems to be the only character with any real tone to him. In the play, I always imagined Blanche to be a rude woman and in the book, I always imagined Stella to be a disrespectful woman in the name of her family. However, in the film, you can clearly see that Stella is someone who suffers from Stanley's behavior and that Blanche is someone we are supposed to feel for. However, this film does something that makes a movie much a fail. That is, in films, we are normally supposed to be emotionally connected in some way to the protagonist. Here, Blanche is depicted as an annoying, eccentric woman (who was depicted the same in the play but also seemed to be normal)who talks in an extremely annoying and difficult to understand accent. While reading a play, we either view Blanche as a woman who is broken down by everything in her life (and so we pity her)or as someone we are portrayed to in the film (in which case, we don't care) I must admit, Mitch was quite a disappointment to me. In fact, the only character I enjoyed was Stanley who was depicted true to William's work. I must also point out that the entire script for the film is what Tennesse William wrote for the play and it annoyed me. Using parts of it is different to simply using the dialogue in the play. It doesn't add too much new to a film. In fact, how hard could it be to make parts of a script up????? NOT THAT HARD!!! I must also point out that the music used in the film really bugged me. I'm not expecting any epic music...NOOOO! But I expect some melodramatic music for a melodramatic film. In most scenes, the music did not suit the film and it felt too merry when it was supposed to be sad. Overall, many will love this film but I found it boring and annoying. Marlon Brando's superb acting and portrayal of Stanley saves it for me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complicated......yet simply told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jitin Menon
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blanche arrives in New Orleans to stay with her sister Stella and her husband Stanley. Blanche is unhappy to see her sister live in a shabby place and have her reservations on the unruly, stone age behaved brother-in-law. Stanley in turn does not like Blanche and not approve of her as he thinks she will come in between his happy marriage. This movie introduced me to the young Marlon Brando after his idolizing performance in The Godfather, And Boy!!! did he not disappoint me with his awe inspiring performance as the menacing yet charming Stanley Kowalski. The movie, mostly if not equally, belonged to Vivien Leigh whose portrayal of the neurotic Blanche DuBois was a fine example of some excellent old school performance. Kim Hunter provides a worthy support as Stella who's torn up between her sister and husband. Mitch(Karl Maiden) is adorable as he falls head over heels for Blanche. The movie based on the play by the same name,has been adapted and executed beautifully. Tennessee William's screenplay is tightly written and Elia Kazan has directed a memorable movie which will remain in the memories of the viewers for its complicated yet simple portrayal of a story of love and acceptance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No winners, only losers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Connor
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm torn by this film. In many ways it's sublime- the atmosphere, music, and the remarkable acting... but in others I can't stand it. Karl Malden's character Mitch is a nuisance, the duality of the major characters was a constant bait and switch, and with the Southern accents there are scenes where the clarity of speaking is a real problem. The characters are so double- edged it's frustrating. Blanche is clearly strange from the beginning, a tad ditsy with her head in the clouds. She feels Stanley's wrath as we do, but like any good character she isn't perfect. But then it goes so far that I couldn't root for her and I wanted to see Stanley explode on her, then back again, and it became a big mess. Stanley is physically and thematically the opposite of Blanche. Played by an absolute animal in Marlon Brando (he's huge!), Stan is bad, very alpha, completely dominant. As well he has violent tendencies, but we see his calmer side and see that he's looking out for his family and I began to side with him. He can be a horrible person, but in many instances its not unjustified. This see-saw goes back and forth through the film, until its end which goes right off of one side of the teeter- totter. But nonetheless, Stanley's portrayal- and presence on screen- is supreme. I feel like Sunset Blvd. beat Streetcar to the plot punch, and is dwarfed by On the Waterfront. The film is dark and very negative. The themes are negative and the conclusion is very sour. The moral is unclear, and with the Hays code the plot can be too vague. One of the most critical plotpoints at the end went over my head because I can't interpret what a smashed mirror means. After finishing I thought: "what did I even just watch?". Streetcar is like nothing of its era: though this review seems to have pointed out all the negatives, that is just a result of my emotions after finishing the film. It's an excellent film that decided to tell an unhappy story, very well. 8.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Explosive Movie........Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fantastic movie, of the stage play by Tennese Williams. Williams also wrote the screenplay for the movie. The four central actors Marlon Brando, Vivien Liegh, Karl Malden and Kim Hunter are excellent, and Elia Kazans direction is superb. Vivien Leigh won an Oscar for her great performance as the mentally un-hinged Blanch. Leigh had been suffering from bi-polar disorder all of her adult life, and often became "quite, quite mad" as David Niven observed. Playing Blanch was probably not too difficult for Leigh, who had a reputation for being unpredictable on film sets. Brando lost out to Humphrey Bogart (African Queen) at the academy awards that year (1951)---perhaps the world was not ready for the explosive Marlon who played part Neanderthal part Orange tang in an explosive macho performance. One of the great movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent movie almost in its entirety, but the ending ain't right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intp
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie as part of a college film class, around 1987 (I didn't actually take the class; I knew someone taking the class to fill a basic sociology distribution requirement; but I went to all the films for free-- and almost all of them were great!). Excellent film, with great performances all around-- until the very ending, which really bothered me. The ending in the movie was fundamentally changed from that in the original play. I had read the play in high school and thought it was brilliant. The movie, however, fundamentally alters the ending in a way, I guess, to make it a bit more "uplifting" to the audience. However, the film thereby ends up completely missing one of the key themes of the play (which is also a theme shared by Williams' "Glass Menagerie"): the way that unthinking men destroy the lives of women around them, yet the women are seemingly unable to help themselves in their attachment to those men. A tragic theme, perhaps, but too often true. While the altered ending is less downbeat, it just wasn't Williams' original story. Oddly, Roger Ebert's review doesn't even mention the change in the ending, even though he does mention other changes forced by the censors at the time. I wonder to this day if the changed ending was the director's idea, or was it forced upon him?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best acting ensemble ever in a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its actors assemble the best group of performances I've ever seen by a cast before in a motion picture. Viven Leigh is at the head, in work that reaffirms her talent as some of the finest in the business. She has the strength in one look to another character that most performances work for their entire film. Marlon Brando turns in a frightening effort that turns your stomach into mush. Kim Hunter does some great work, as well. A Streetcar Named Desire's screenplay is something to admire. The cracking dialogue and exceptional scenes that follow are sparse in the movie industry. Some of the most complex characters ever written are explored here; thankfully the cast and director put just as much effort into portraying them as the writer did into writing them in the play, which the film is based on. It's not an easy film to watch, some scenes are chilling (aided by haunting, black and white cinematography). Though I think A Streetcar Named Desire strays at times in the second half, it's an emotional roller coaster with anchoring acting. It's a great theatrical experience on film. Rating: 9.5/10 Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated for sure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emanuel Rojas
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read many reviewers here saying that Marlon Brando's performance was amazing. I don't think it was amazing because there was nothing really complex about it. He just got mad in almost every scene, started yelling, and eventually broke stuff or smacked somebody. I felt that he had a limited range of emotions in the movie. Vivien Leigh gave an excellent performance, and she had to go to really abstract places to pull off her role. Blanche is a character that harbours delusions, lies pathologically, and suffers from terrible anxiety, so it was a complex role. The rest of the cast acts well, and Karl Malden's performance was the third most interesting in the movie. As for the story, it is not really that interesting. It takes place in one setting only for 99% of the movie, and is really heavy on the dialogue because it's based on a play. I think Tennesse Williams really dropped the ball by not including a night club scene in the play, with it being set in New Orleans. I haven't read the play, but I think the play / movie would have been way better had we seen Blanche going out with Stella in New Orleans and mixing it up with the locals. There was none of that in this movie, we see her in a bedroom most of the time being a weird brand of crazy southern belle, which gets boring. I think the reason that this movie made such an impact in 1951, was because it depicted mental illness in a way that hadn't been seen before. That's my guess at least. However, I doubt that either Tennessee Williams or Vivien Leigh really did much research into mental illness. I think the main thing that Tennessee Williams wanted to achieve was to create an iconic figure of a southern belle who goes crazy because the world is too harsh, and that southern ideals were doomed. If you care about any of that, you might enjoy this movie. Most of us don't care about any of that, for good reason, so that is why the movie won't make an impression on us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Iconic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary Reese
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1950s film Adaptation of Tennessee Williams' A Streetcar Named Desire. Set in New Orleans, Blanche DuBois (Vivien Leigh) comes to with her sister, Stella, played by Kim Hunter, and her brother in law, Stanley, Marlon Brando. Blanche has found herself in a heap of personal troubles, but keeps up with the charade for her sister. She is prim and proper, an English teacher, with a trunk full of fancy outfits and jewelry. Stanley sees through this. Stanley is a rough around the edges, loud-mouthed character. This is an amazing breakthrough role for Brando. It was well casted all around. Domestic disputes breakout and emotions run high. This is one of the best movies still, to this day. Iconic scenes and characters. Worth a watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brando's volcanic energy gives Vivien the needed momentum to deliver one of the finest and most iconic performances in screen history as Blanche DuBois
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We witness Blanch Dubois burn in the flames ignited by Stanley Kowalski, thereby obliterating the destitute woman's small hopes of redeeming herself and starting life afresh. The other way to look at the situation would be: Stanley's force compels Blanch to face her crimes and gives her an opportunity to live a normal life sometime in the future. 'A Streetcar named Desire' veers between Blanch's attempts at ridding herself of guilt through ignorance and delusion and Stanley's will to expose Blanch's past and force her to admit and punish herself for her sins. Its playwright Tennessee Williams gives us a harrowing example of the difficulties faced by women who have stained their characters, and the cruelty with which men chastise them while they themselves take little notice of the sins they commit every day. Elia Kazan brings the play to screen experimenting little with editing and instead allows his actors to take charge, and boy do they bring tragedy to life! It is Marlon Brando's intense heat that allows Vivien Leigh's character to have a terrifying meltdown and the actress delivers one of the finest and most iconic performances in film history by nailing a highly complex and extremely interesting character. She may not have done it so well without Brando and we should give credit to Brando for helping her, but if you ask me who performed better, I'd unhesitatingly choose Leigh. A Streetcar Named Desire gained popularity on stage because of the quality of the story itself and Brando's acclaimed performance. When it was reproduced on screen, director Kazan roped in method-maharaja Marlon Brando and classical-chanteuse Vivien Leigh for the roles of Stanley and Blanche respectively. The rest of the cast were filled by talented actors like Kim Hunter for the role of Stella Kowalski and Karl Malden for Mitch. The controversial nature of the play made it difficult for bringing it on screen without certain cuts, but the restoration version released years later fortunately retains the deleted scenes. The story begins with Blanche Dubois' character arriving from Auriol to New Orleans by train, and taking the streetcar named Desire to Cemeteries and finally Elysian fields where her sister Stella lives with her husband Stanley. Blanche is extremely secretive about her past and only discloses to Stella that she had lost possession to their old home in Belle-Reve and was asked by the higher authority, in the school where Blanche taught English, to 'take some rest'. Blanche moves in temporarily with her sister and quickly shows displeasure at Stella's bourgeois existence and her attraction towards a violent man like Stanley. Blanche's prime desire is to begin a new life using an idealistic approach where 'magic and art' play a preeminent role and she pursues this by charming her brother-in-law's close friend and co-worker Mitch; her main obstacle comes in the form of Stanley, who does not entertain her whims, and finding loopholes in her claims, begins digging her past to break the spell Blanche wants to put everyone under. While he is instrumental in ripping her past apart, it seems like Blanche herself gives everyone an opportunity to scrutinize her past; it is as though she planted the seeds of her own destruction which were nurtured by Stanley. William's astonishing work should have been adapted to screen without altering anything because it is perfectly penned. Unfortunately, the film version alters the ending which makes Stanley looks like a complete jerk who is not only crass with Blanch but also not empathetic towards his own wife's grief. It goes against Stanley's motive of living happily with his wife and child without any de trop to disturb the 'wild peace' at home. Barring that scene, every other moment is brilliantly told and played on screen. Kazan hardly tries experimenting with the camera and in the process creates a work that is sharp and subtle. The most effective moments are when the camera abruptly cuts to or zooms into Blanche's face whenever anyone broaches the subject of her husband. Most of the effort is left to the actors who have terrific chemistry with each other, mainly because a majority of them have reprised the roles from stage. Hunter looks a lot like Debra Winger and the manner in which she spoke reminded me of young Debra from the movie 'Terms of Endearment' (of course, Debra came years later). While Debra Winger played a rich young rebellious girl who marries a simpleton, Hunter's Stella marries a commoner like Stanley because she is partly fascinated by his often violent and callous bravado. The actress convincingly plays Stella in a manner that makes us understand the character's choice, in a difficult role where she not only has to show love towards a violent man like Stanley, but also concern for her sister Blanch and slight contempt and reproach towards her husband for his treatment of Blanch. The other supporting role of Stan's friend Mitch is taken up by Malden; his character reminded me of J. Edgar Hoover who too lived alone with his sick mother and was very much concerned about her. Malden does his job well, especially in the confrontation scene between Mitch and Blanch where Mitch begins kissing her only because he then considers her a use-and-throw woman. However it is Brando and Leigh that make the day. I've now seen Brando in five different films in completely different characters and he fits each one like a glove. His realism or super-realism brings the movie alive with kinetic energy, and I realized a something watching him and Leigh  the classical Hollywood, with its stylized scripts veering towards melodramas and actors trying to bring the energies of their characters' psyche on screen, looked far more alluring a field to enter than today's Hollywood, which focuses heavily on slightly banal realism, with juiceless scripts without quote-worthy dialogs. Only one thing I shall say about Leigh: she gives us another iconic and unforgettable screen persona.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must see!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ImportantFilmReviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most people may call Marlon Brando a beautiful and charming man but he is no where close to charming in this film. He is primitive, controlling and territorial. He kicks a poor woman while she's down but brings a tremendous acting performance to the screen. It is very surprising that Brando shows such class and maturity yet this is only his second film. Absolute delight to watch him. Vivien Leigh is terrific as Blanche DuBois. Her spiral into insanity is wonderful as she is dominated physically and mentally by Brando's character. Kazan is a genius with the camera. His direction in this film is flawless. I would've loved to see the actual stage performance under his direction and with all these great performers. This is on my list as one of the best films in cinema history.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Marlon Brando...Thank god your in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've read the Tennesse William's play of A Streetcar Named Desire and I thought it was rather well done but I couldn't really get immersed into the story or the characters. None of the characters in the play appealed to me like they do in other novels, plays and films. I like the basic story line of the movie and how it remains simple and focuses on a young woman named Blanche who really "depends on the kindness of strangers" but realizes different after Stanley's abusive behavior. While this story works in a play, I just don't think it works all that great in a movie. Here's why... In a play/novel, you can simply enjoy one by reading in depth without much story but here in a movie, much of the film really seems boring and the fact that most of the film occurs in the dark really annoys me, even though I understand how its like in the play. There's nothing wrong with the acting. I thought Vivien Leigh did a fine job but easily the stand out of the film is the great Marlon Brandon...R.I.P. Had it not being for his portrayal of the abusive husband Stanley, this film would've been far less entertaining than what I could get of it in the end. In the film and the play, Stanley seems to be the only character with any real tone to him. In the play, I always imagined Blanche to be a rude woman and in the book, I always imagined Stella to be a disrespectful woman in the name of her family. However, in the film, you can clearly see that Stella is someone who suffers from Stanley's behavior and that Blanche is someone we are supposed to feel for. However, this film does something that makes a movie much a fail. That is, in films, we are normally supposed to be emotionally connected in some way to the protagonist. Here, Blanche is depicted as an annoying, eccentric woman (who was depicted the same in the play but also seemed to be normal)who talks in an extremely annoying and difficult to understand accent. While reading a play, we either view Blanche as a woman who is broken down by everything in her life (and so we pity her)or as someone we are portrayed to in the film (in which case, we don't care) I must admit, Mitch was quite a disappointment to me. In fact, the only character I enjoyed was Stanley who was depicted true to William's work. I must also point out that the entire script for the film is what Tennesse William wrote for the play and it annoyed me. Using parts of it is different to simply using the dialogue in the play. It doesn't add too much new to a film. In fact, how hard could it be to make parts of a script up????? NOT THAT HARD!!! I must also point out that the music used in the film really bugged me. I'm not expecting any epic music...NOOOO! But I expect some melodramatic music for a melodramatic film. In most scenes, the music did not suit the film and it felt too merry when it was supposed to be sad. Overall, many will love this film but I found it boring and annoying. Marlon Brando's superb acting and portrayal of Stanley saves it for me!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complicated......yet simply told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jitin Menon
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blanche arrives in New Orleans to stay with her sister Stella and her husband Stanley. Blanche is unhappy to see her sister live in a shabby place and have her reservations on the unruly, stone age behaved brother-in-law. Stanley in turn does not like Blanche and not approve of her as he thinks she will come in between his happy marriage. This movie introduced me to the young Marlon Brando after his idolizing performance in The Godfather, And Boy!!! did he not disappoint me with his awe inspiring performance as the menacing yet charming Stanley Kowalski. The movie, mostly if not equally, belonged to Vivien Leigh whose portrayal of the neurotic Blanche DuBois was a fine example of some excellent old school performance. Kim Hunter provides a worthy support as Stella who's torn up between her sister and husband. Mitch(Karl Maiden) is adorable as he falls head over heels for Blanche. The movie based on the play by the same name,has been adapted and executed beautifully. Tennessee William's screenplay is tightly written and Elia Kazan has directed a memorable movie which will remain in the memories of the viewers for its complicated yet simple portrayal of a story of love and acceptance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No winners, only losers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Connor
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm torn by this film. In many ways it's sublime- the atmosphere, music, and the remarkable acting... but in others I can't stand it. Karl Malden's character Mitch is a nuisance, the duality of the major characters was a constant bait and switch, and with the Southern accents there are scenes where the clarity of speaking is a real problem. The characters are so double- edged it's frustrating. Blanche is clearly strange from the beginning, a tad ditsy with her head in the clouds. She feels Stanley's wrath as we do, but like any good character she isn't perfect. But then it goes so far that I couldn't root for her and I wanted to see Stanley explode on her, then back again, and it became a big mess. Stanley is physically and thematically the opposite of Blanche. Played by an absolute animal in Marlon Brando (he's huge!), Stan is bad, very alpha, completely dominant. As well he has violent tendencies, but we see his calmer side and see that he's looking out for his family and I began to side with him. He can be a horrible person, but in many instances its not unjustified. This see-saw goes back and forth through the film, until its end which goes right off of one side of the teeter- totter. But nonetheless, Stanley's portrayal- and presence on screen- is supreme. I feel like Sunset Blvd. beat Streetcar to the plot punch, and is dwarfed by On the Waterfront. The film is dark and very negative. The themes are negative and the conclusion is very sour. The moral is unclear, and with the Hays code the plot can be too vague. One of the most critical plotpoints at the end went over my head because I can't interpret what a smashed mirror means. After finishing I thought: "what did I even just watch?". Streetcar is like nothing of its era: though this review seems to have pointed out all the negatives, that is just a result of my emotions after finishing the film. It's an excellent film that decided to tell an unhappy story, very well. 8.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Explosive Movie........Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fantastic movie, of the stage play by Tennese Williams. Williams also wrote the screenplay for the movie. The four central actors Marlon Brando, Vivien Liegh, Karl Malden and Kim Hunter are excellent, and Elia Kazans direction is superb. Vivien Leigh won an Oscar for her great performance as the mentally un-hinged Blanch. Leigh had been suffering from bi-polar disorder all of her adult life, and often became "quite, quite mad" as David Niven observed. Playing Blanch was probably not too difficult for Leigh, who had a reputation for being unpredictable on film sets. Brando lost out to Humphrey Bogart (African Queen) at the academy awards that year (1951)---perhaps the world was not ready for the explosive Marlon who played part Neanderthal part Orange tang in an explosive macho performance. One of the great movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
