<filme>
 <id>
  527
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0083987
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1982
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Gandhi
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Biography of , the lawyer who became the famed leader of the Indian revolts against the British rule through his philosophy of nonviolent protest.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In 1893, Gandhi is thrown off a South African train for being an Indian and traveling in a first class compartment. Gandhi realizes that the laws are biased against Indians and decides to start a non-violent protest campaign for the rights of all Indians in South Africa. After numerous arrests and the unwanted attention of the world, the government finally relents by recognizing rights for Indians, though not for the native blacks of South Africa. After this victory, Gandhi is invited back to India, where he is now considered something of a national hero. He is urged to take up the fight for India's independence from the British Empire. Gandhi agrees, and mounts a non-violent non-cooperation campaign of unprecedented scale, coordinating millions of Indians nationwide. There are some setbacks, such as violence against the protesters and Gandhi's occasional imprisonment. Nevertheless, the campaign generates great attention, and Britain faces intense public pressure. Too weak from World ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   History
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   india
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   indian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   british
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   muslim
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hindu
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Richard Attenborough
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Briley
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ben Kingsley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Gielgud
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Candice Bergen
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All-Time Great Performance By Ben Kingsly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ben Kingsly plays real life Indian leader Mahatma Gandhi in one of the best performances in screen history, richly deserving his best actor Academy Award, and the film itself won Best Picture, with Richard Attenborough winning best director. Film details how Gandhi went from a young lawyer who leads the campaign for Indian rights in British ruled South Africa after he is shamefully thrown off a train because he wasn't allowed to travel first class(despite his ticket). Later, Gandhi becomes a national hero and leader who calls for India's independence from Great Britain, but who does so by strictly non-violent protest, which amazingly does work for them, since they gain world sympathy due to favorable press coverage. Independence doesn't come without cost, since the divide between Muslims and Hindus is too great, resulting in the formation of Pakistan, and later Gandhi's assassination... Long film is made compelling because of Ben Kingsly's superlative portrayal, and epic sized story telling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pratikw206
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie gives the classic dramatisation of the life of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, an Indian lawyer and activist. This movie superbly shows his non-violent, non-cooperative independence movement against the United Kingdom's rule of the country during the 20th century which ulitimately lead to Inida's freedom(along with thousands of sacrifices by Indian population).Also direction, cinematography, costumes, they're all great. Ben kingsley has done an amazing job with his portrayal of mahatmaji , For me this is his best performance .'Gandhi' is a moving portrait of a character with a disarming humility, who spins cotton, walks the country roads, meditates in front of the ocean, or scoops salt from the beach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Story, Bland Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jake Moskowitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sweeping, cinematic, and bombastic take on the life and achievements of Mr. Gandhi. The film relies entirely on Hollywood clich&eacute;s, simplifying the events of the period, the motives of those involved, and the moral and political complexities of this time period. This cartoonish version of Mr. Gandhi hobbles around India, spinning his wheel and always saying the exactly-correct thing at the exactly-correct time. None of the other characters seem to catch on to this eerie infallibility, however, and contradict him at every turn (or at least when it provides Gandhi with a chance to correct them). Gandhi's strained grandfather-humor, included as a blatant attempt to "humanize" him, gets old quick, and by the end, becomes an annoying self-parody. Then you have the issue of the doe-eyed women that surround him (Mrs. Gandhi, Mirabehn), who say very little the entire film. It seems as if their only real character trait is a total adoration for Mr. Gandhi. Moral tropes are used and re-used, and no complex moral questions are ever introduced. British bad. Indians good. Even worse, the film stands as an insult to all those besides Gandhi who worked tirelessly to make India free. No other leaders are ever mentioned - it's all Gandhi and his buffoonish politician friends, who only exist to stand at a foil to the clear wisdom of Gandhi. It all becomes a little ridiculous and repetitive after a while. It's sad, since the performance by Ben Kingsley is well-crafted. The script is simply not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intense Film About a Peaceful Man!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a sprawling, epic biography about one of the greatest, most influential leaders to have ever walked on our planet. That man was Mahatma Gandhi. He brought about the independence of India from the British Empire without enforcing the need for violence. He also wanted peace between all the Muslims and Hindus in India. This movie perfectly describes how Gandhi set to achieve his goals despite the British Empire trying to stop him. Richard Attenborough's film is about the life of Gandhi from his early adult life all the way to his brutal end. The way this man preached for peace and independence should influence all men and stop the unnecessary violence in this world. This film is very well-acted. I never thought a non-Indian like Ben Kingsley could pull off this kind of role off. But he did. Kingsley truly gave a magnificent performance and I felt like I was watching Gandhi himself. All the supporting actors were very good even though there are too many to list. A trivial fact for movie fans: Daniel-Day Lewis is indeed in this movie. Overall, this is one epic film about a man who united his country. This film has the essential cinematic qualities and it remains one of the top biographies ever made. The only thing that goes against this movie is the running length of over three hours long. But it was well-paced and has very powerful dialog. This film is a must-see for everyone. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gandhi.............Far Above A Saint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a great movie, and truly deserved its 8 Oscars. Director Sir Richard Attenbourgh finding an actor like Ben Kingsley, must have felt like he had discovered Plutonium. Kingsley turned out to be more like Gandhi than the Mahatma himself. If you don't learn something from this movie, check into a clinic for Nazis. There are many scenes that touch you. My favourite is when a big important judge played by Trevor Howard is visibly shaken when he looks at Gandhi in the dock. Howard is diminished in stature just by looking at humanity ...in the flesh. It is undoubtedly a true epic (Titanic was not...not even close) and a movie about a man who really was real...and his story very real. The old religions lean on old books that are almost certainly ...no-where near what REALLY happened. To-day the Catholic church scratches around for people who "other people" say did great things, so they can proclaim them saints. Utter rubbish. The first thing The Catholics need to do is stop sexually abusing children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jayson Wallace
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is breath taking and shows in a great way the struggles Gandhi had to go through. And even while the movie takes more than 3 hours to complete, it feels like just an hour. The only "problem" with this movie is that when you're watching, you don't want to stop it. (to eat or drink something) So.... when you have not yet seen this movie: 1. You should. 2. Always eat and drink (or take it with you!) before starting the movie. (Sorry if my English lacks a bit, i am Dutch.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great First Half, Weak Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the movie made me develop an interest in Mohandas Gandhi and why he developed as he did. You see him young, wearing a turban but otherwise a regular suit and tie, and he encounters racism when he is thrown off a train for illegally being an a first class compartment when he is an Indian. Then he leads a struggle against racism in South Africa, winning some success before moving to India, which he says (in the movie) is a strange country to him. He would fight against British colonial rule of India, but then realizes that ending it might only lead to a government of Indians who would be just as bad-and then he adopts his famous white Indian clothing. After that, the movie falters, and we see less about Gandhi than the political events that follow, not delivered with great accuracy. Ben Kingsley delivers a perfect performance, looking and acting the part. But the image of Gandhi is completely idealized, and he never gets angry or otherwise seems like a real human being. Indeed, there were things about the historical Gandhi that would appall most people. But this is a movie to entertain, not teach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare piece of history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Gilmore
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you have a legendary world icon how do you possibly make a movie that does that person justice. This movie is probably as close as you can get to a perfect movie even one on a man like Gandhi. The way a man who was not wealthy, no property, no title or office, wasn't a commander of a military or any kind of ruler. Yet millions choose to follow him to freedom. You have governments, people all around the world celebrate and join hands to a man who freed his country through non violence. This movie is and was such a epic undertaking in a time before cgi, the funeral at the end was probably the last live action crowd of that size and same with rest of the movie. The last scene was probably one of the greatest scenes of cinematic history. Gandhi's message of non violent resistance is showed as a enthralling piece of art. This serves as entertainment and one of most historical figures in the world that took on the British Empire and won. Kingsley was perfect for the role of Gandhi, he nailed the British influenced Indian accent perfectly. He won both the Academy award and Golden Globe for best actor, he didn't just play Gandhi he became him. With the skillful cinematography and scenes in the movie it was as if India became a character in the film rather then just a location. Reading about the making of the movie and the trouble they had with the elite class in the country that a Englishman was making the movie. They were steadfast and were able to enlist thousands of Indians to help with the creation of this film, the crowds used real Indians from that area. It was very captivating how such a work of art can reach the epic proportions that make this almost nothing less then a miracle. The interpretation by Kingsley is nothing but astonishing and should go down as one of more perfect cinema roles. Watching this you almost forget that you are seeing a actor playing a part, your watching a part of history. This movie has everything the crowd scenes, the intimate and emotional scenes all captured beautifully. You aren't watching the scenes you are living and feeling them. The music makes you sympathize and show admiration adding so many other feelings you don't have in movies. Unlike some embellishments from Hollywood when it comes to history movies this is not one of those. A work of art that should be a required viewing for class as the fight of prejudice will be forever relevant in our generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not only artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    after years, it remains for me an experience. not for its rich beauty or for force of message. but for the nuance of miracle who contains it. because it is a gorgeous construction, result of empathy. and skin for a really great story. but extraordinary art of a director, force of performance of an actor makes this film more than illustration of a life or prey of its subject. it is only a kind of testimony. about a fight behind words. about a way behind definitions. only sketch of a form of self-build. and picture of a time. Sir Ben Kingsley makes an unique role. but his success is more than artistic science but precise courage to transform a character in his skin. to give height of each nuance. and to be not to act. after years, Gandhi remains for me an experience. not only artistic. but a grain of amber as light of candle in special hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Took Richard Attenborough Over Twenty Years To Make This Movie, And Not One Single Second Of That Work Was Wasted.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a labor of love for Richard Attenborough, he tried so many times to get it made, but try as he might have done, he could not get it to happen. It finally happened in the early 1980's, and he completed it in 1982. It took Richard Attenborough over twenty years to make this movie, and not one single second of all of that hard work was wasted. Gandhi is a tremendously powerful experience, it's powerfully told, wonderfully acted, strongly directed, beautifully shot, powerfully scored (music that is), and especially, it's powerfully written. As the title suggests, the movie is based on the life of Mohandas K. Gandhi, who's demonstrations through nonviolent protests help gain India it's independence from Great Britain. The movie was well worth all of the effort, as it is a masterpiece, and it's not just one of the greatest biographical epics ever made, but it is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's flawless. Like many other long movies, such as Barry Lyndon, The Godfather Part II, and Seven Samauri, Gandhi may be long (it's 191 minutes), but it is such a beautiful and powerful film, that you will forget that it's over three hours long. To play Gandhi, Ben Kingsley (who at that time, was a literal unknown) was cast. I heard some stories saying that there where people who thought that Kingsley was Gandhi's ghost, and I could believe that, as I could swear that he WAS Gandhi. Kingsley's powerful performance earned him the Academy Award for Best Actor, which he rightfully deserved to win. I said earlier that it took over 20 years for Richard Attenborough to make this movie. He poured a lot of energy and effort into the making of this film, and his efforts payed off when the film won him two Academy Awards, for Best Picture and Best Director. The movie deserved every major award that it won, it's a masterpiece, it's excellent, and it's...well, you understand it by now. Out of all of the biographical epics that I have seen, such as Patton, Reds, Malcolm X, and Schindler's List, Gandhi is one of the best. I'm not knocking the other movies that I just mentioned, they are all outstanding, but Gandhi is in a class by itself. Gandhi is more than a masterpiece, it is the meaning of the word masterpiece, it takes the word to a new level. So all in all, this movie is without a doubt one of the greatest movies that has ever played on my television set. There are many great movies that deserve to be seen multiple times, like The Godfather, Goodfellas, Citizen Kane, Casablanca, Gone With The Wind, and The General, and Gandhi is definitely one of those movies. Richard Attenborough's biographical epic on perhaps one of the greatest men who ever lived is required viewing, it's a very accurate portrayal of the man who used nonviolent protest to gain India its independence. We all know what a great man that Gandhi was, but when somebody watches this, they will have a whole new opinion on it. When it is over, they will say: "Now this was a man." Anyway, Gandhi is a tremendously spectacular experience, it should not be missed. When you watch it, don't even think about the time or how long it is, think about how great it will be as it progresses more and more. And by the time that it is over, you will say that you have just seen on of the greatest movies ever made. Mr. Kingsley, Mr. Attenborough, you both have my unanimous praise for all of your hard work on this astounding accomplishment in the film industry. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All-Time Great Performance By Ben Kingsly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ben Kingsly plays real life Indian leader Mahatma Gandhi in one of the best performances in screen history, richly deserving his best actor Academy Award, and the film itself won Best Picture, with Richard Attenborough winning best director. Film details how Gandhi went from a young lawyer who leads the campaign for Indian rights in British ruled South Africa after he is shamefully thrown off a train because he wasn't allowed to travel first class(despite his ticket). Later, Gandhi becomes a national hero and leader who calls for India's independence from Great Britain, but who does so by strictly non-violent protest, which amazingly does work for them, since they gain world sympathy due to favorable press coverage. Independence doesn't come without cost, since the divide between Muslims and Hindus is too great, resulting in the formation of Pakistan, and later Gandhi's assassination... Long film is made compelling because of Ben Kingsly's superlative portrayal, and epic sized story telling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pratikw206
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie gives the classic dramatisation of the life of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, an Indian lawyer and activist. This movie superbly shows his non-violent, non-cooperative independence movement against the United Kingdom's rule of the country during the 20th century which ulitimately lead to Inida's freedom(along with thousands of sacrifices by Indian population).Also direction, cinematography, costumes, they're all great. Ben kingsley has done an amazing job with his portrayal of mahatmaji , For me this is his best performance .'Gandhi' is a moving portrait of a character with a disarming humility, who spins cotton, walks the country roads, meditates in front of the ocean, or scoops salt from the beach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Story, Bland Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jake Moskowitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sweeping, cinematic, and bombastic take on the life and achievements of Mr. Gandhi. The film relies entirely on Hollywood clich&eacute;s, simplifying the events of the period, the motives of those involved, and the moral and political complexities of this time period. This cartoonish version of Mr. Gandhi hobbles around India, spinning his wheel and always saying the exactly-correct thing at the exactly-correct time. None of the other characters seem to catch on to this eerie infallibility, however, and contradict him at every turn (or at least when it provides Gandhi with a chance to correct them). Gandhi's strained grandfather-humor, included as a blatant attempt to "humanize" him, gets old quick, and by the end, becomes an annoying self-parody. Then you have the issue of the doe-eyed women that surround him (Mrs. Gandhi, Mirabehn), who say very little the entire film. It seems as if their only real character trait is a total adoration for Mr. Gandhi. Moral tropes are used and re-used, and no complex moral questions are ever introduced. British bad. Indians good. Even worse, the film stands as an insult to all those besides Gandhi who worked tirelessly to make India free. No other leaders are ever mentioned - it's all Gandhi and his buffoonish politician friends, who only exist to stand at a foil to the clear wisdom of Gandhi. It all becomes a little ridiculous and repetitive after a while. It's sad, since the performance by Ben Kingsley is well-crafted. The script is simply not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intense Film About a Peaceful Man!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a sprawling, epic biography about one of the greatest, most influential leaders to have ever walked on our planet. That man was Mahatma Gandhi. He brought about the independence of India from the British Empire without enforcing the need for violence. He also wanted peace between all the Muslims and Hindus in India. This movie perfectly describes how Gandhi set to achieve his goals despite the British Empire trying to stop him. Richard Attenborough's film is about the life of Gandhi from his early adult life all the way to his brutal end. The way this man preached for peace and independence should influence all men and stop the unnecessary violence in this world. This film is very well-acted. I never thought a non-Indian like Ben Kingsley could pull off this kind of role off. But he did. Kingsley truly gave a magnificent performance and I felt like I was watching Gandhi himself. All the supporting actors were very good even though there are too many to list. A trivial fact for movie fans: Daniel-Day Lewis is indeed in this movie. Overall, this is one epic film about a man who united his country. This film has the essential cinematic qualities and it remains one of the top biographies ever made. The only thing that goes against this movie is the running length of over three hours long. But it was well-paced and has very powerful dialog. This film is a must-see for everyone. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gandhi.............Far Above A Saint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a great movie, and truly deserved its 8 Oscars. Director Sir Richard Attenbourgh finding an actor like Ben Kingsley, must have felt like he had discovered Plutonium. Kingsley turned out to be more like Gandhi than the Mahatma himself. If you don't learn something from this movie, check into a clinic for Nazis. There are many scenes that touch you. My favourite is when a big important judge played by Trevor Howard is visibly shaken when he looks at Gandhi in the dock. Howard is diminished in stature just by looking at humanity ...in the flesh. It is undoubtedly a true epic (Titanic was not...not even close) and a movie about a man who really was real...and his story very real. The old religions lean on old books that are almost certainly ...no-where near what REALLY happened. To-day the Catholic church scratches around for people who "other people" say did great things, so they can proclaim them saints. Utter rubbish. The first thing The Catholics need to do is stop sexually abusing children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jayson Wallace
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is breath taking and shows in a great way the struggles Gandhi had to go through. And even while the movie takes more than 3 hours to complete, it feels like just an hour. The only "problem" with this movie is that when you're watching, you don't want to stop it. (to eat or drink something) So.... when you have not yet seen this movie: 1. You should. 2. Always eat and drink (or take it with you!) before starting the movie. (Sorry if my English lacks a bit, i am Dutch.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great First Half, Weak Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the movie made me develop an interest in Mohandas Gandhi and why he developed as he did. You see him young, wearing a turban but otherwise a regular suit and tie, and he encounters racism when he is thrown off a train for illegally being an a first class compartment when he is an Indian. Then he leads a struggle against racism in South Africa, winning some success before moving to India, which he says (in the movie) is a strange country to him. He would fight against British colonial rule of India, but then realizes that ending it might only lead to a government of Indians who would be just as bad-and then he adopts his famous white Indian clothing. After that, the movie falters, and we see less about Gandhi than the political events that follow, not delivered with great accuracy. Ben Kingsley delivers a perfect performance, looking and acting the part. But the image of Gandhi is completely idealized, and he never gets angry or otherwise seems like a real human being. Indeed, there were things about the historical Gandhi that would appall most people. But this is a movie to entertain, not teach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare piece of history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Gilmore
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you have a legendary world icon how do you possibly make a movie that does that person justice. This movie is probably as close as you can get to a perfect movie even one on a man like Gandhi. The way a man who was not wealthy, no property, no title or office, wasn't a commander of a military or any kind of ruler. Yet millions choose to follow him to freedom. You have governments, people all around the world celebrate and join hands to a man who freed his country through non violence. This movie is and was such a epic undertaking in a time before cgi, the funeral at the end was probably the last live action crowd of that size and same with rest of the movie. The last scene was probably one of the greatest scenes of cinematic history. Gandhi's message of non violent resistance is showed as a enthralling piece of art. This serves as entertainment and one of most historical figures in the world that took on the British Empire and won. Kingsley was perfect for the role of Gandhi, he nailed the British influenced Indian accent perfectly. He won both the Academy award and Golden Globe for best actor, he didn't just play Gandhi he became him. With the skillful cinematography and scenes in the movie it was as if India became a character in the film rather then just a location. Reading about the making of the movie and the trouble they had with the elite class in the country that a Englishman was making the movie. They were steadfast and were able to enlist thousands of Indians to help with the creation of this film, the crowds used real Indians from that area. It was very captivating how such a work of art can reach the epic proportions that make this almost nothing less then a miracle. The interpretation by Kingsley is nothing but astonishing and should go down as one of more perfect cinema roles. Watching this you almost forget that you are seeing a actor playing a part, your watching a part of history. This movie has everything the crowd scenes, the intimate and emotional scenes all captured beautifully. You aren't watching the scenes you are living and feeling them. The music makes you sympathize and show admiration adding so many other feelings you don't have in movies. Unlike some embellishments from Hollywood when it comes to history movies this is not one of those. A work of art that should be a required viewing for class as the fight of prejudice will be forever relevant in our generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not only artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    after years, it remains for me an experience. not for its rich beauty or for force of message. but for the nuance of miracle who contains it. because it is a gorgeous construction, result of empathy. and skin for a really great story. but extraordinary art of a director, force of performance of an actor makes this film more than illustration of a life or prey of its subject. it is only a kind of testimony. about a fight behind words. about a way behind definitions. only sketch of a form of self-build. and picture of a time. Sir Ben Kingsley makes an unique role. but his success is more than artistic science but precise courage to transform a character in his skin. to give height of each nuance. and to be not to act. after years, Gandhi remains for me an experience. not only artistic. but a grain of amber as light of candle in special hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Took Richard Attenborough Over Twenty Years To Make This Movie, And Not One Single Second Of That Work Was Wasted.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a labor of love for Richard Attenborough, he tried so many times to get it made, but try as he might have done, he could not get it to happen. It finally happened in the early 1980's, and he completed it in 1982. It took Richard Attenborough over twenty years to make this movie, and not one single second of all of that hard work was wasted. Gandhi is a tremendously powerful experience, it's powerfully told, wonderfully acted, strongly directed, beautifully shot, powerfully scored (music that is), and especially, it's powerfully written. As the title suggests, the movie is based on the life of Mohandas K. Gandhi, who's demonstrations through nonviolent protests help gain India it's independence from Great Britain. The movie was well worth all of the effort, as it is a masterpiece, and it's not just one of the greatest biographical epics ever made, but it is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's flawless. Like many other long movies, such as Barry Lyndon, The Godfather Part II, and Seven Samauri, Gandhi may be long (it's 191 minutes), but it is such a beautiful and powerful film, that you will forget that it's over three hours long. To play Gandhi, Ben Kingsley (who at that time, was a literal unknown) was cast. I heard some stories saying that there where people who thought that Kingsley was Gandhi's ghost, and I could believe that, as I could swear that he WAS Gandhi. Kingsley's powerful performance earned him the Academy Award for Best Actor, which he rightfully deserved to win. I said earlier that it took over 20 years for Richard Attenborough to make this movie. He poured a lot of energy and effort into the making of this film, and his efforts payed off when the film won him two Academy Awards, for Best Picture and Best Director. The movie deserved every major award that it won, it's a masterpiece, it's excellent, and it's...well, you understand it by now. Out of all of the biographical epics that I have seen, such as Patton, Reds, Malcolm X, and Schindler's List, Gandhi is one of the best. I'm not knocking the other movies that I just mentioned, they are all outstanding, but Gandhi is in a class by itself. Gandhi is more than a masterpiece, it is the meaning of the word masterpiece, it takes the word to a new level. So all in all, this movie is without a doubt one of the greatest movies that has ever played on my television set. There are many great movies that deserve to be seen multiple times, like The Godfather, Goodfellas, Citizen Kane, Casablanca, Gone With The Wind, and The General, and Gandhi is definitely one of those movies. Richard Attenborough's biographical epic on perhaps one of the greatest men who ever lived is required viewing, it's a very accurate portrayal of the man who used nonviolent protest to gain India its independence. We all know what a great man that Gandhi was, but when somebody watches this, they will have a whole new opinion on it. When it is over, they will say: "Now this was a man." Anyway, Gandhi is a tremendously spectacular experience, it should not be missed. When you watch it, don't even think about the time or how long it is, think about how great it will be as it progresses more and more. And by the time that it is over, you will say that you have just seen on of the greatest movies ever made. Mr. Kingsley, Mr. Attenborough, you both have my unanimous praise for all of your hard work on this astounding accomplishment in the film industry. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All-Time Great Performance By Ben Kingsly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ben Kingsly plays real life Indian leader Mahatma Gandhi in one of the best performances in screen history, richly deserving his best actor Academy Award, and the film itself won Best Picture, with Richard Attenborough winning best director. Film details how Gandhi went from a young lawyer who leads the campaign for Indian rights in British ruled South Africa after he is shamefully thrown off a train because he wasn't allowed to travel first class(despite his ticket). Later, Gandhi becomes a national hero and leader who calls for India's independence from Great Britain, but who does so by strictly non-violent protest, which amazingly does work for them, since they gain world sympathy due to favorable press coverage. Independence doesn't come without cost, since the divide between Muslims and Hindus is too great, resulting in the formation of Pakistan, and later Gandhi's assassination... Long film is made compelling because of Ben Kingsly's superlative portrayal, and epic sized story telling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pratikw206
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie gives the classic dramatisation of the life of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, an Indian lawyer and activist. This movie superbly shows his non-violent, non-cooperative independence movement against the United Kingdom's rule of the country during the 20th century which ulitimately lead to Inida's freedom(along with thousands of sacrifices by Indian population).Also direction, cinematography, costumes, they're all great. Ben kingsley has done an amazing job with his portrayal of mahatmaji , For me this is his best performance .'Gandhi' is a moving portrait of a character with a disarming humility, who spins cotton, walks the country roads, meditates in front of the ocean, or scoops salt from the beach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Story, Bland Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jake Moskowitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sweeping, cinematic, and bombastic take on the life and achievements of Mr. Gandhi. The film relies entirely on Hollywood clich&eacute;s, simplifying the events of the period, the motives of those involved, and the moral and political complexities of this time period. This cartoonish version of Mr. Gandhi hobbles around India, spinning his wheel and always saying the exactly-correct thing at the exactly-correct time. None of the other characters seem to catch on to this eerie infallibility, however, and contradict him at every turn (or at least when it provides Gandhi with a chance to correct them). Gandhi's strained grandfather-humor, included as a blatant attempt to "humanize" him, gets old quick, and by the end, becomes an annoying self-parody. Then you have the issue of the doe-eyed women that surround him (Mrs. Gandhi, Mirabehn), who say very little the entire film. It seems as if their only real character trait is a total adoration for Mr. Gandhi. Moral tropes are used and re-used, and no complex moral questions are ever introduced. British bad. Indians good. Even worse, the film stands as an insult to all those besides Gandhi who worked tirelessly to make India free. No other leaders are ever mentioned - it's all Gandhi and his buffoonish politician friends, who only exist to stand at a foil to the clear wisdom of Gandhi. It all becomes a little ridiculous and repetitive after a while. It's sad, since the performance by Ben Kingsley is well-crafted. The script is simply not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intense Film About a Peaceful Man!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a sprawling, epic biography about one of the greatest, most influential leaders to have ever walked on our planet. That man was Mahatma Gandhi. He brought about the independence of India from the British Empire without enforcing the need for violence. He also wanted peace between all the Muslims and Hindus in India. This movie perfectly describes how Gandhi set to achieve his goals despite the British Empire trying to stop him. Richard Attenborough's film is about the life of Gandhi from his early adult life all the way to his brutal end. The way this man preached for peace and independence should influence all men and stop the unnecessary violence in this world. This film is very well-acted. I never thought a non-Indian like Ben Kingsley could pull off this kind of role off. But he did. Kingsley truly gave a magnificent performance and I felt like I was watching Gandhi himself. All the supporting actors were very good even though there are too many to list. A trivial fact for movie fans: Daniel-Day Lewis is indeed in this movie. Overall, this is one epic film about a man who united his country. This film has the essential cinematic qualities and it remains one of the top biographies ever made. The only thing that goes against this movie is the running length of over three hours long. But it was well-paced and has very powerful dialog. This film is a must-see for everyone. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gandhi.............Far Above A Saint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a great movie, and truly deserved its 8 Oscars. Director Sir Richard Attenbourgh finding an actor like Ben Kingsley, must have felt like he had discovered Plutonium. Kingsley turned out to be more like Gandhi than the Mahatma himself. If you don't learn something from this movie, check into a clinic for Nazis. There are many scenes that touch you. My favourite is when a big important judge played by Trevor Howard is visibly shaken when he looks at Gandhi in the dock. Howard is diminished in stature just by looking at humanity ...in the flesh. It is undoubtedly a true epic (Titanic was not...not even close) and a movie about a man who really was real...and his story very real. The old religions lean on old books that are almost certainly ...no-where near what REALLY happened. To-day the Catholic church scratches around for people who "other people" say did great things, so they can proclaim them saints. Utter rubbish. The first thing The Catholics need to do is stop sexually abusing children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jayson Wallace
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is breath taking and shows in a great way the struggles Gandhi had to go through. And even while the movie takes more than 3 hours to complete, it feels like just an hour. The only "problem" with this movie is that when you're watching, you don't want to stop it. (to eat or drink something) So.... when you have not yet seen this movie: 1. You should. 2. Always eat and drink (or take it with you!) before starting the movie. (Sorry if my English lacks a bit, i am Dutch.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great First Half, Weak Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the movie made me develop an interest in Mohandas Gandhi and why he developed as he did. You see him young, wearing a turban but otherwise a regular suit and tie, and he encounters racism when he is thrown off a train for illegally being an a first class compartment when he is an Indian. Then he leads a struggle against racism in South Africa, winning some success before moving to India, which he says (in the movie) is a strange country to him. He would fight against British colonial rule of India, but then realizes that ending it might only lead to a government of Indians who would be just as bad-and then he adopts his famous white Indian clothing. After that, the movie falters, and we see less about Gandhi than the political events that follow, not delivered with great accuracy. Ben Kingsley delivers a perfect performance, looking and acting the part. But the image of Gandhi is completely idealized, and he never gets angry or otherwise seems like a real human being. Indeed, there were things about the historical Gandhi that would appall most people. But this is a movie to entertain, not teach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare piece of history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Gilmore
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you have a legendary world icon how do you possibly make a movie that does that person justice. This movie is probably as close as you can get to a perfect movie even one on a man like Gandhi. The way a man who was not wealthy, no property, no title or office, wasn't a commander of a military or any kind of ruler. Yet millions choose to follow him to freedom. You have governments, people all around the world celebrate and join hands to a man who freed his country through non violence. This movie is and was such a epic undertaking in a time before cgi, the funeral at the end was probably the last live action crowd of that size and same with rest of the movie. The last scene was probably one of the greatest scenes of cinematic history. Gandhi's message of non violent resistance is showed as a enthralling piece of art. This serves as entertainment and one of most historical figures in the world that took on the British Empire and won. Kingsley was perfect for the role of Gandhi, he nailed the British influenced Indian accent perfectly. He won both the Academy award and Golden Globe for best actor, he didn't just play Gandhi he became him. With the skillful cinematography and scenes in the movie it was as if India became a character in the film rather then just a location. Reading about the making of the movie and the trouble they had with the elite class in the country that a Englishman was making the movie. They were steadfast and were able to enlist thousands of Indians to help with the creation of this film, the crowds used real Indians from that area. It was very captivating how such a work of art can reach the epic proportions that make this almost nothing less then a miracle. The interpretation by Kingsley is nothing but astonishing and should go down as one of more perfect cinema roles. Watching this you almost forget that you are seeing a actor playing a part, your watching a part of history. This movie has everything the crowd scenes, the intimate and emotional scenes all captured beautifully. You aren't watching the scenes you are living and feeling them. The music makes you sympathize and show admiration adding so many other feelings you don't have in movies. Unlike some embellishments from Hollywood when it comes to history movies this is not one of those. A work of art that should be a required viewing for class as the fight of prejudice will be forever relevant in our generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not only artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    after years, it remains for me an experience. not for its rich beauty or for force of message. but for the nuance of miracle who contains it. because it is a gorgeous construction, result of empathy. and skin for a really great story. but extraordinary art of a director, force of performance of an actor makes this film more than illustration of a life or prey of its subject. it is only a kind of testimony. about a fight behind words. about a way behind definitions. only sketch of a form of self-build. and picture of a time. Sir Ben Kingsley makes an unique role. but his success is more than artistic science but precise courage to transform a character in his skin. to give height of each nuance. and to be not to act. after years, Gandhi remains for me an experience. not only artistic. but a grain of amber as light of candle in special hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Took Richard Attenborough Over Twenty Years To Make This Movie, And Not One Single Second Of That Work Was Wasted.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a labor of love for Richard Attenborough, he tried so many times to get it made, but try as he might have done, he could not get it to happen. It finally happened in the early 1980's, and he completed it in 1982. It took Richard Attenborough over twenty years to make this movie, and not one single second of all of that hard work was wasted. Gandhi is a tremendously powerful experience, it's powerfully told, wonderfully acted, strongly directed, beautifully shot, powerfully scored (music that is), and especially, it's powerfully written. As the title suggests, the movie is based on the life of Mohandas K. Gandhi, who's demonstrations through nonviolent protests help gain India it's independence from Great Britain. The movie was well worth all of the effort, as it is a masterpiece, and it's not just one of the greatest biographical epics ever made, but it is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's flawless. Like many other long movies, such as Barry Lyndon, The Godfather Part II, and Seven Samauri, Gandhi may be long (it's 191 minutes), but it is such a beautiful and powerful film, that you will forget that it's over three hours long. To play Gandhi, Ben Kingsley (who at that time, was a literal unknown) was cast. I heard some stories saying that there where people who thought that Kingsley was Gandhi's ghost, and I could believe that, as I could swear that he WAS Gandhi. Kingsley's powerful performance earned him the Academy Award for Best Actor, which he rightfully deserved to win. I said earlier that it took over 20 years for Richard Attenborough to make this movie. He poured a lot of energy and effort into the making of this film, and his efforts payed off when the film won him two Academy Awards, for Best Picture and Best Director. The movie deserved every major award that it won, it's a masterpiece, it's excellent, and it's...well, you understand it by now. Out of all of the biographical epics that I have seen, such as Patton, Reds, Malcolm X, and Schindler's List, Gandhi is one of the best. I'm not knocking the other movies that I just mentioned, they are all outstanding, but Gandhi is in a class by itself. Gandhi is more than a masterpiece, it is the meaning of the word masterpiece, it takes the word to a new level. So all in all, this movie is without a doubt one of the greatest movies that has ever played on my television set. There are many great movies that deserve to be seen multiple times, like The Godfather, Goodfellas, Citizen Kane, Casablanca, Gone With The Wind, and The General, and Gandhi is definitely one of those movies. Richard Attenborough's biographical epic on perhaps one of the greatest men who ever lived is required viewing, it's a very accurate portrayal of the man who used nonviolent protest to gain India its independence. We all know what a great man that Gandhi was, but when somebody watches this, they will have a whole new opinion on it. When it is over, they will say: "Now this was a man." Anyway, Gandhi is a tremendously spectacular experience, it should not be missed. When you watch it, don't even think about the time or how long it is, think about how great it will be as it progresses more and more. And by the time that it is over, you will say that you have just seen on of the greatest movies ever made. Mr. Kingsley, Mr. Attenborough, you both have my unanimous praise for all of your hard work on this astounding accomplishment in the film industry. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All-Time Great Performance By Ben Kingsly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ben Kingsly plays real life Indian leader Mahatma Gandhi in one of the best performances in screen history, richly deserving his best actor Academy Award, and the film itself won Best Picture, with Richard Attenborough winning best director. Film details how Gandhi went from a young lawyer who leads the campaign for Indian rights in British ruled South Africa after he is shamefully thrown off a train because he wasn't allowed to travel first class(despite his ticket). Later, Gandhi becomes a national hero and leader who calls for India's independence from Great Britain, but who does so by strictly non-violent protest, which amazingly does work for them, since they gain world sympathy due to favorable press coverage. Independence doesn't come without cost, since the divide between Muslims and Hindus is too great, resulting in the formation of Pakistan, and later Gandhi's assassination... Long film is made compelling because of Ben Kingsly's superlative portrayal, and epic sized story telling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pratikw206
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie gives the classic dramatisation of the life of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, an Indian lawyer and activist. This movie superbly shows his non-violent, non-cooperative independence movement against the United Kingdom's rule of the country during the 20th century which ulitimately lead to Inida's freedom(along with thousands of sacrifices by Indian population).Also direction, cinematography, costumes, they're all great. Ben kingsley has done an amazing job with his portrayal of mahatmaji , For me this is his best performance .'Gandhi' is a moving portrait of a character with a disarming humility, who spins cotton, walks the country roads, meditates in front of the ocean, or scoops salt from the beach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Story, Bland Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jake Moskowitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sweeping, cinematic, and bombastic take on the life and achievements of Mr. Gandhi. The film relies entirely on Hollywood clich&eacute;s, simplifying the events of the period, the motives of those involved, and the moral and political complexities of this time period. This cartoonish version of Mr. Gandhi hobbles around India, spinning his wheel and always saying the exactly-correct thing at the exactly-correct time. None of the other characters seem to catch on to this eerie infallibility, however, and contradict him at every turn (or at least when it provides Gandhi with a chance to correct them). Gandhi's strained grandfather-humor, included as a blatant attempt to "humanize" him, gets old quick, and by the end, becomes an annoying self-parody. Then you have the issue of the doe-eyed women that surround him (Mrs. Gandhi, Mirabehn), who say very little the entire film. It seems as if their only real character trait is a total adoration for Mr. Gandhi. Moral tropes are used and re-used, and no complex moral questions are ever introduced. British bad. Indians good. Even worse, the film stands as an insult to all those besides Gandhi who worked tirelessly to make India free. No other leaders are ever mentioned - it's all Gandhi and his buffoonish politician friends, who only exist to stand at a foil to the clear wisdom of Gandhi. It all becomes a little ridiculous and repetitive after a while. It's sad, since the performance by Ben Kingsley is well-crafted. The script is simply not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intense Film About a Peaceful Man!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a sprawling, epic biography about one of the greatest, most influential leaders to have ever walked on our planet. That man was Mahatma Gandhi. He brought about the independence of India from the British Empire without enforcing the need for violence. He also wanted peace between all the Muslims and Hindus in India. This movie perfectly describes how Gandhi set to achieve his goals despite the British Empire trying to stop him. Richard Attenborough's film is about the life of Gandhi from his early adult life all the way to his brutal end. The way this man preached for peace and independence should influence all men and stop the unnecessary violence in this world. This film is very well-acted. I never thought a non-Indian like Ben Kingsley could pull off this kind of role off. But he did. Kingsley truly gave a magnificent performance and I felt like I was watching Gandhi himself. All the supporting actors were very good even though there are too many to list. A trivial fact for movie fans: Daniel-Day Lewis is indeed in this movie. Overall, this is one epic film about a man who united his country. This film has the essential cinematic qualities and it remains one of the top biographies ever made. The only thing that goes against this movie is the running length of over three hours long. But it was well-paced and has very powerful dialog. This film is a must-see for everyone. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gandhi.............Far Above A Saint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a great movie, and truly deserved its 8 Oscars. Director Sir Richard Attenbourgh finding an actor like Ben Kingsley, must have felt like he had discovered Plutonium. Kingsley turned out to be more like Gandhi than the Mahatma himself. If you don't learn something from this movie, check into a clinic for Nazis. There are many scenes that touch you. My favourite is when a big important judge played by Trevor Howard is visibly shaken when he looks at Gandhi in the dock. Howard is diminished in stature just by looking at humanity ...in the flesh. It is undoubtedly a true epic (Titanic was not...not even close) and a movie about a man who really was real...and his story very real. The old religions lean on old books that are almost certainly ...no-where near what REALLY happened. To-day the Catholic church scratches around for people who "other people" say did great things, so they can proclaim them saints. Utter rubbish. The first thing The Catholics need to do is stop sexually abusing children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jayson Wallace
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is breath taking and shows in a great way the struggles Gandhi had to go through. And even while the movie takes more than 3 hours to complete, it feels like just an hour. The only "problem" with this movie is that when you're watching, you don't want to stop it. (to eat or drink something) So.... when you have not yet seen this movie: 1. You should. 2. Always eat and drink (or take it with you!) before starting the movie. (Sorry if my English lacks a bit, i am Dutch.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great First Half, Weak Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the movie made me develop an interest in Mohandas Gandhi and why he developed as he did. You see him young, wearing a turban but otherwise a regular suit and tie, and he encounters racism when he is thrown off a train for illegally being an a first class compartment when he is an Indian. Then he leads a struggle against racism in South Africa, winning some success before moving to India, which he says (in the movie) is a strange country to him. He would fight against British colonial rule of India, but then realizes that ending it might only lead to a government of Indians who would be just as bad-and then he adopts his famous white Indian clothing. After that, the movie falters, and we see less about Gandhi than the political events that follow, not delivered with great accuracy. Ben Kingsley delivers a perfect performance, looking and acting the part. But the image of Gandhi is completely idealized, and he never gets angry or otherwise seems like a real human being. Indeed, there were things about the historical Gandhi that would appall most people. But this is a movie to entertain, not teach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare piece of history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Gilmore
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you have a legendary world icon how do you possibly make a movie that does that person justice. This movie is probably as close as you can get to a perfect movie even one on a man like Gandhi. The way a man who was not wealthy, no property, no title or office, wasn't a commander of a military or any kind of ruler. Yet millions choose to follow him to freedom. You have governments, people all around the world celebrate and join hands to a man who freed his country through non violence. This movie is and was such a epic undertaking in a time before cgi, the funeral at the end was probably the last live action crowd of that size and same with rest of the movie. The last scene was probably one of the greatest scenes of cinematic history. Gandhi's message of non violent resistance is showed as a enthralling piece of art. This serves as entertainment and one of most historical figures in the world that took on the British Empire and won. Kingsley was perfect for the role of Gandhi, he nailed the British influenced Indian accent perfectly. He won both the Academy award and Golden Globe for best actor, he didn't just play Gandhi he became him. With the skillful cinematography and scenes in the movie it was as if India became a character in the film rather then just a location. Reading about the making of the movie and the trouble they had with the elite class in the country that a Englishman was making the movie. They were steadfast and were able to enlist thousands of Indians to help with the creation of this film, the crowds used real Indians from that area. It was very captivating how such a work of art can reach the epic proportions that make this almost nothing less then a miracle. The interpretation by Kingsley is nothing but astonishing and should go down as one of more perfect cinema roles. Watching this you almost forget that you are seeing a actor playing a part, your watching a part of history. This movie has everything the crowd scenes, the intimate and emotional scenes all captured beautifully. You aren't watching the scenes you are living and feeling them. The music makes you sympathize and show admiration adding so many other feelings you don't have in movies. Unlike some embellishments from Hollywood when it comes to history movies this is not one of those. A work of art that should be a required viewing for class as the fight of prejudice will be forever relevant in our generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not only artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    after years, it remains for me an experience. not for its rich beauty or for force of message. but for the nuance of miracle who contains it. because it is a gorgeous construction, result of empathy. and skin for a really great story. but extraordinary art of a director, force of performance of an actor makes this film more than illustration of a life or prey of its subject. it is only a kind of testimony. about a fight behind words. about a way behind definitions. only sketch of a form of self-build. and picture of a time. Sir Ben Kingsley makes an unique role. but his success is more than artistic science but precise courage to transform a character in his skin. to give height of each nuance. and to be not to act. after years, Gandhi remains for me an experience. not only artistic. but a grain of amber as light of candle in special hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Took Richard Attenborough Over Twenty Years To Make This Movie, And Not One Single Second Of That Work Was Wasted.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a labor of love for Richard Attenborough, he tried so many times to get it made, but try as he might have done, he could not get it to happen. It finally happened in the early 1980's, and he completed it in 1982. It took Richard Attenborough over twenty years to make this movie, and not one single second of all of that hard work was wasted. Gandhi is a tremendously powerful experience, it's powerfully told, wonderfully acted, strongly directed, beautifully shot, powerfully scored (music that is), and especially, it's powerfully written. As the title suggests, the movie is based on the life of Mohandas K. Gandhi, who's demonstrations through nonviolent protests help gain India it's independence from Great Britain. The movie was well worth all of the effort, as it is a masterpiece, and it's not just one of the greatest biographical epics ever made, but it is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's flawless. Like many other long movies, such as Barry Lyndon, The Godfather Part II, and Seven Samauri, Gandhi may be long (it's 191 minutes), but it is such a beautiful and powerful film, that you will forget that it's over three hours long. To play Gandhi, Ben Kingsley (who at that time, was a literal unknown) was cast. I heard some stories saying that there where people who thought that Kingsley was Gandhi's ghost, and I could believe that, as I could swear that he WAS Gandhi. Kingsley's powerful performance earned him the Academy Award for Best Actor, which he rightfully deserved to win. I said earlier that it took over 20 years for Richard Attenborough to make this movie. He poured a lot of energy and effort into the making of this film, and his efforts payed off when the film won him two Academy Awards, for Best Picture and Best Director. The movie deserved every major award that it won, it's a masterpiece, it's excellent, and it's...well, you understand it by now. Out of all of the biographical epics that I have seen, such as Patton, Reds, Malcolm X, and Schindler's List, Gandhi is one of the best. I'm not knocking the other movies that I just mentioned, they are all outstanding, but Gandhi is in a class by itself. Gandhi is more than a masterpiece, it is the meaning of the word masterpiece, it takes the word to a new level. So all in all, this movie is without a doubt one of the greatest movies that has ever played on my television set. There are many great movies that deserve to be seen multiple times, like The Godfather, Goodfellas, Citizen Kane, Casablanca, Gone With The Wind, and The General, and Gandhi is definitely one of those movies. Richard Attenborough's biographical epic on perhaps one of the greatest men who ever lived is required viewing, it's a very accurate portrayal of the man who used nonviolent protest to gain India its independence. We all know what a great man that Gandhi was, but when somebody watches this, they will have a whole new opinion on it. When it is over, they will say: "Now this was a man." Anyway, Gandhi is a tremendously spectacular experience, it should not be missed. When you watch it, don't even think about the time or how long it is, think about how great it will be as it progresses more and more. And by the time that it is over, you will say that you have just seen on of the greatest movies ever made. Mr. Kingsley, Mr. Attenborough, you both have my unanimous praise for all of your hard work on this astounding accomplishment in the film industry. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All-Time Great Performance By Ben Kingsly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ben Kingsly plays real life Indian leader Mahatma Gandhi in one of the best performances in screen history, richly deserving his best actor Academy Award, and the film itself won Best Picture, with Richard Attenborough winning best director. Film details how Gandhi went from a young lawyer who leads the campaign for Indian rights in British ruled South Africa after he is shamefully thrown off a train because he wasn't allowed to travel first class(despite his ticket). Later, Gandhi becomes a national hero and leader who calls for India's independence from Great Britain, but who does so by strictly non-violent protest, which amazingly does work for them, since they gain world sympathy due to favorable press coverage. Independence doesn't come without cost, since the divide between Muslims and Hindus is too great, resulting in the formation of Pakistan, and later Gandhi's assassination... Long film is made compelling because of Ben Kingsly's superlative portrayal, and epic sized story telling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pratikw206
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie gives the classic dramatisation of the life of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, an Indian lawyer and activist. This movie superbly shows his non-violent, non-cooperative independence movement against the United Kingdom's rule of the country during the 20th century which ulitimately lead to Inida's freedom(along with thousands of sacrifices by Indian population).Also direction, cinematography, costumes, they're all great. Ben kingsley has done an amazing job with his portrayal of mahatmaji , For me this is his best performance .'Gandhi' is a moving portrait of a character with a disarming humility, who spins cotton, walks the country roads, meditates in front of the ocean, or scoops salt from the beach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Story, Bland Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jake Moskowitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sweeping, cinematic, and bombastic take on the life and achievements of Mr. Gandhi. The film relies entirely on Hollywood clich&eacute;s, simplifying the events of the period, the motives of those involved, and the moral and political complexities of this time period. This cartoonish version of Mr. Gandhi hobbles around India, spinning his wheel and always saying the exactly-correct thing at the exactly-correct time. None of the other characters seem to catch on to this eerie infallibility, however, and contradict him at every turn (or at least when it provides Gandhi with a chance to correct them). Gandhi's strained grandfather-humor, included as a blatant attempt to "humanize" him, gets old quick, and by the end, becomes an annoying self-parody. Then you have the issue of the doe-eyed women that surround him (Mrs. Gandhi, Mirabehn), who say very little the entire film. It seems as if their only real character trait is a total adoration for Mr. Gandhi. Moral tropes are used and re-used, and no complex moral questions are ever introduced. British bad. Indians good. Even worse, the film stands as an insult to all those besides Gandhi who worked tirelessly to make India free. No other leaders are ever mentioned - it's all Gandhi and his buffoonish politician friends, who only exist to stand at a foil to the clear wisdom of Gandhi. It all becomes a little ridiculous and repetitive after a while. It's sad, since the performance by Ben Kingsley is well-crafted. The script is simply not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intense Film About a Peaceful Man!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a sprawling, epic biography about one of the greatest, most influential leaders to have ever walked on our planet. That man was Mahatma Gandhi. He brought about the independence of India from the British Empire without enforcing the need for violence. He also wanted peace between all the Muslims and Hindus in India. This movie perfectly describes how Gandhi set to achieve his goals despite the British Empire trying to stop him. Richard Attenborough's film is about the life of Gandhi from his early adult life all the way to his brutal end. The way this man preached for peace and independence should influence all men and stop the unnecessary violence in this world. This film is very well-acted. I never thought a non-Indian like Ben Kingsley could pull off this kind of role off. But he did. Kingsley truly gave a magnificent performance and I felt like I was watching Gandhi himself. All the supporting actors were very good even though there are too many to list. A trivial fact for movie fans: Daniel-Day Lewis is indeed in this movie. Overall, this is one epic film about a man who united his country. This film has the essential cinematic qualities and it remains one of the top biographies ever made. The only thing that goes against this movie is the running length of over three hours long. But it was well-paced and has very powerful dialog. This film is a must-see for everyone. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gandhi.............Far Above A Saint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a great movie, and truly deserved its 8 Oscars. Director Sir Richard Attenbourgh finding an actor like Ben Kingsley, must have felt like he had discovered Plutonium. Kingsley turned out to be more like Gandhi than the Mahatma himself. If you don't learn something from this movie, check into a clinic for Nazis. There are many scenes that touch you. My favourite is when a big important judge played by Trevor Howard is visibly shaken when he looks at Gandhi in the dock. Howard is diminished in stature just by looking at humanity ...in the flesh. It is undoubtedly a true epic (Titanic was not...not even close) and a movie about a man who really was real...and his story very real. The old religions lean on old books that are almost certainly ...no-where near what REALLY happened. To-day the Catholic church scratches around for people who "other people" say did great things, so they can proclaim them saints. Utter rubbish. The first thing The Catholics need to do is stop sexually abusing children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jayson Wallace
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is breath taking and shows in a great way the struggles Gandhi had to go through. And even while the movie takes more than 3 hours to complete, it feels like just an hour. The only "problem" with this movie is that when you're watching, you don't want to stop it. (to eat or drink something) So.... when you have not yet seen this movie: 1. You should. 2. Always eat and drink (or take it with you!) before starting the movie. (Sorry if my English lacks a bit, i am Dutch.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great First Half, Weak Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the movie made me develop an interest in Mohandas Gandhi and why he developed as he did. You see him young, wearing a turban but otherwise a regular suit and tie, and he encounters racism when he is thrown off a train for illegally being an a first class compartment when he is an Indian. Then he leads a struggle against racism in South Africa, winning some success before moving to India, which he says (in the movie) is a strange country to him. He would fight against British colonial rule of India, but then realizes that ending it might only lead to a government of Indians who would be just as bad-and then he adopts his famous white Indian clothing. After that, the movie falters, and we see less about Gandhi than the political events that follow, not delivered with great accuracy. Ben Kingsley delivers a perfect performance, looking and acting the part. But the image of Gandhi is completely idealized, and he never gets angry or otherwise seems like a real human being. Indeed, there were things about the historical Gandhi that would appall most people. But this is a movie to entertain, not teach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare piece of history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Gilmore
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you have a legendary world icon how do you possibly make a movie that does that person justice. This movie is probably as close as you can get to a perfect movie even one on a man like Gandhi. The way a man who was not wealthy, no property, no title or office, wasn't a commander of a military or any kind of ruler. Yet millions choose to follow him to freedom. You have governments, people all around the world celebrate and join hands to a man who freed his country through non violence. This movie is and was such a epic undertaking in a time before cgi, the funeral at the end was probably the last live action crowd of that size and same with rest of the movie. The last scene was probably one of the greatest scenes of cinematic history. Gandhi's message of non violent resistance is showed as a enthralling piece of art. This serves as entertainment and one of most historical figures in the world that took on the British Empire and won. Kingsley was perfect for the role of Gandhi, he nailed the British influenced Indian accent perfectly. He won both the Academy award and Golden Globe for best actor, he didn't just play Gandhi he became him. With the skillful cinematography and scenes in the movie it was as if India became a character in the film rather then just a location. Reading about the making of the movie and the trouble they had with the elite class in the country that a Englishman was making the movie. They were steadfast and were able to enlist thousands of Indians to help with the creation of this film, the crowds used real Indians from that area. It was very captivating how such a work of art can reach the epic proportions that make this almost nothing less then a miracle. The interpretation by Kingsley is nothing but astonishing and should go down as one of more perfect cinema roles. Watching this you almost forget that you are seeing a actor playing a part, your watching a part of history. This movie has everything the crowd scenes, the intimate and emotional scenes all captured beautifully. You aren't watching the scenes you are living and feeling them. The music makes you sympathize and show admiration adding so many other feelings you don't have in movies. Unlike some embellishments from Hollywood when it comes to history movies this is not one of those. A work of art that should be a required viewing for class as the fight of prejudice will be forever relevant in our generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not only artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    after years, it remains for me an experience. not for its rich beauty or for force of message. but for the nuance of miracle who contains it. because it is a gorgeous construction, result of empathy. and skin for a really great story. but extraordinary art of a director, force of performance of an actor makes this film more than illustration of a life or prey of its subject. it is only a kind of testimony. about a fight behind words. about a way behind definitions. only sketch of a form of self-build. and picture of a time. Sir Ben Kingsley makes an unique role. but his success is more than artistic science but precise courage to transform a character in his skin. to give height of each nuance. and to be not to act. after years, Gandhi remains for me an experience. not only artistic. but a grain of amber as light of candle in special hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Took Richard Attenborough Over Twenty Years To Make This Movie, And Not One Single Second Of That Work Was Wasted.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a labor of love for Richard Attenborough, he tried so many times to get it made, but try as he might have done, he could not get it to happen. It finally happened in the early 1980's, and he completed it in 1982. It took Richard Attenborough over twenty years to make this movie, and not one single second of all of that hard work was wasted. Gandhi is a tremendously powerful experience, it's powerfully told, wonderfully acted, strongly directed, beautifully shot, powerfully scored (music that is), and especially, it's powerfully written. As the title suggests, the movie is based on the life of Mohandas K. Gandhi, who's demonstrations through nonviolent protests help gain India it's independence from Great Britain. The movie was well worth all of the effort, as it is a masterpiece, and it's not just one of the greatest biographical epics ever made, but it is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's flawless. Like many other long movies, such as Barry Lyndon, The Godfather Part II, and Seven Samauri, Gandhi may be long (it's 191 minutes), but it is such a beautiful and powerful film, that you will forget that it's over three hours long. To play Gandhi, Ben Kingsley (who at that time, was a literal unknown) was cast. I heard some stories saying that there where people who thought that Kingsley was Gandhi's ghost, and I could believe that, as I could swear that he WAS Gandhi. Kingsley's powerful performance earned him the Academy Award for Best Actor, which he rightfully deserved to win. I said earlier that it took over 20 years for Richard Attenborough to make this movie. He poured a lot of energy and effort into the making of this film, and his efforts payed off when the film won him two Academy Awards, for Best Picture and Best Director. The movie deserved every major award that it won, it's a masterpiece, it's excellent, and it's...well, you understand it by now. Out of all of the biographical epics that I have seen, such as Patton, Reds, Malcolm X, and Schindler's List, Gandhi is one of the best. I'm not knocking the other movies that I just mentioned, they are all outstanding, but Gandhi is in a class by itself. Gandhi is more than a masterpiece, it is the meaning of the word masterpiece, it takes the word to a new level. So all in all, this movie is without a doubt one of the greatest movies that has ever played on my television set. There are many great movies that deserve to be seen multiple times, like The Godfather, Goodfellas, Citizen Kane, Casablanca, Gone With The Wind, and The General, and Gandhi is definitely one of those movies. Richard Attenborough's biographical epic on perhaps one of the greatest men who ever lived is required viewing, it's a very accurate portrayal of the man who used nonviolent protest to gain India its independence. We all know what a great man that Gandhi was, but when somebody watches this, they will have a whole new opinion on it. When it is over, they will say: "Now this was a man." Anyway, Gandhi is a tremendously spectacular experience, it should not be missed. When you watch it, don't even think about the time or how long it is, think about how great it will be as it progresses more and more. And by the time that it is over, you will say that you have just seen on of the greatest movies ever made. Mr. Kingsley, Mr. Attenborough, you both have my unanimous praise for all of your hard work on this astounding accomplishment in the film industry. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All-Time Great Performance By Ben Kingsly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ben Kingsly plays real life Indian leader Mahatma Gandhi in one of the best performances in screen history, richly deserving his best actor Academy Award, and the film itself won Best Picture, with Richard Attenborough winning best director. Film details how Gandhi went from a young lawyer who leads the campaign for Indian rights in British ruled South Africa after he is shamefully thrown off a train because he wasn't allowed to travel first class(despite his ticket). Later, Gandhi becomes a national hero and leader who calls for India's independence from Great Britain, but who does so by strictly non-violent protest, which amazingly does work for them, since they gain world sympathy due to favorable press coverage. Independence doesn't come without cost, since the divide between Muslims and Hindus is too great, resulting in the formation of Pakistan, and later Gandhi's assassination... Long film is made compelling because of Ben Kingsly's superlative portrayal, and epic sized story telling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pratikw206
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie gives the classic dramatisation of the life of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, an Indian lawyer and activist. This movie superbly shows his non-violent, non-cooperative independence movement against the United Kingdom's rule of the country during the 20th century which ulitimately lead to Inida's freedom(along with thousands of sacrifices by Indian population).Also direction, cinematography, costumes, they're all great. Ben kingsley has done an amazing job with his portrayal of mahatmaji , For me this is his best performance .'Gandhi' is a moving portrait of a character with a disarming humility, who spins cotton, walks the country roads, meditates in front of the ocean, or scoops salt from the beach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Story, Bland Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jake Moskowitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sweeping, cinematic, and bombastic take on the life and achievements of Mr. Gandhi. The film relies entirely on Hollywood clich&eacute;s, simplifying the events of the period, the motives of those involved, and the moral and political complexities of this time period. This cartoonish version of Mr. Gandhi hobbles around India, spinning his wheel and always saying the exactly-correct thing at the exactly-correct time. None of the other characters seem to catch on to this eerie infallibility, however, and contradict him at every turn (or at least when it provides Gandhi with a chance to correct them). Gandhi's strained grandfather-humor, included as a blatant attempt to "humanize" him, gets old quick, and by the end, becomes an annoying self-parody. Then you have the issue of the doe-eyed women that surround him (Mrs. Gandhi, Mirabehn), who say very little the entire film. It seems as if their only real character trait is a total adoration for Mr. Gandhi. Moral tropes are used and re-used, and no complex moral questions are ever introduced. British bad. Indians good. Even worse, the film stands as an insult to all those besides Gandhi who worked tirelessly to make India free. No other leaders are ever mentioned - it's all Gandhi and his buffoonish politician friends, who only exist to stand at a foil to the clear wisdom of Gandhi. It all becomes a little ridiculous and repetitive after a while. It's sad, since the performance by Ben Kingsley is well-crafted. The script is simply not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intense Film About a Peaceful Man!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a sprawling, epic biography about one of the greatest, most influential leaders to have ever walked on our planet. That man was Mahatma Gandhi. He brought about the independence of India from the British Empire without enforcing the need for violence. He also wanted peace between all the Muslims and Hindus in India. This movie perfectly describes how Gandhi set to achieve his goals despite the British Empire trying to stop him. Richard Attenborough's film is about the life of Gandhi from his early adult life all the way to his brutal end. The way this man preached for peace and independence should influence all men and stop the unnecessary violence in this world. This film is very well-acted. I never thought a non-Indian like Ben Kingsley could pull off this kind of role off. But he did. Kingsley truly gave a magnificent performance and I felt like I was watching Gandhi himself. All the supporting actors were very good even though there are too many to list. A trivial fact for movie fans: Daniel-Day Lewis is indeed in this movie. Overall, this is one epic film about a man who united his country. This film has the essential cinematic qualities and it remains one of the top biographies ever made. The only thing that goes against this movie is the running length of over three hours long. But it was well-paced and has very powerful dialog. This film is a must-see for everyone. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gandhi.............Far Above A Saint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a great movie, and truly deserved its 8 Oscars. Director Sir Richard Attenbourgh finding an actor like Ben Kingsley, must have felt like he had discovered Plutonium. Kingsley turned out to be more like Gandhi than the Mahatma himself. If you don't learn something from this movie, check into a clinic for Nazis. There are many scenes that touch you. My favourite is when a big important judge played by Trevor Howard is visibly shaken when he looks at Gandhi in the dock. Howard is diminished in stature just by looking at humanity ...in the flesh. It is undoubtedly a true epic (Titanic was not...not even close) and a movie about a man who really was real...and his story very real. The old religions lean on old books that are almost certainly ...no-where near what REALLY happened. To-day the Catholic church scratches around for people who "other people" say did great things, so they can proclaim them saints. Utter rubbish. The first thing The Catholics need to do is stop sexually abusing children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jayson Wallace
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is breath taking and shows in a great way the struggles Gandhi had to go through. And even while the movie takes more than 3 hours to complete, it feels like just an hour. The only "problem" with this movie is that when you're watching, you don't want to stop it. (to eat or drink something) So.... when you have not yet seen this movie: 1. You should. 2. Always eat and drink (or take it with you!) before starting the movie. (Sorry if my English lacks a bit, i am Dutch.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great First Half, Weak Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the movie made me develop an interest in Mohandas Gandhi and why he developed as he did. You see him young, wearing a turban but otherwise a regular suit and tie, and he encounters racism when he is thrown off a train for illegally being an a first class compartment when he is an Indian. Then he leads a struggle against racism in South Africa, winning some success before moving to India, which he says (in the movie) is a strange country to him. He would fight against British colonial rule of India, but then realizes that ending it might only lead to a government of Indians who would be just as bad-and then he adopts his famous white Indian clothing. After that, the movie falters, and we see less about Gandhi than the political events that follow, not delivered with great accuracy. Ben Kingsley delivers a perfect performance, looking and acting the part. But the image of Gandhi is completely idealized, and he never gets angry or otherwise seems like a real human being. Indeed, there were things about the historical Gandhi that would appall most people. But this is a movie to entertain, not teach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare piece of history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Gilmore
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you have a legendary world icon how do you possibly make a movie that does that person justice. This movie is probably as close as you can get to a perfect movie even one on a man like Gandhi. The way a man who was not wealthy, no property, no title or office, wasn't a commander of a military or any kind of ruler. Yet millions choose to follow him to freedom. You have governments, people all around the world celebrate and join hands to a man who freed his country through non violence. This movie is and was such a epic undertaking in a time before cgi, the funeral at the end was probably the last live action crowd of that size and same with rest of the movie. The last scene was probably one of the greatest scenes of cinematic history. Gandhi's message of non violent resistance is showed as a enthralling piece of art. This serves as entertainment and one of most historical figures in the world that took on the British Empire and won. Kingsley was perfect for the role of Gandhi, he nailed the British influenced Indian accent perfectly. He won both the Academy award and Golden Globe for best actor, he didn't just play Gandhi he became him. With the skillful cinematography and scenes in the movie it was as if India became a character in the film rather then just a location. Reading about the making of the movie and the trouble they had with the elite class in the country that a Englishman was making the movie. They were steadfast and were able to enlist thousands of Indians to help with the creation of this film, the crowds used real Indians from that area. It was very captivating how such a work of art can reach the epic proportions that make this almost nothing less then a miracle. The interpretation by Kingsley is nothing but astonishing and should go down as one of more perfect cinema roles. Watching this you almost forget that you are seeing a actor playing a part, your watching a part of history. This movie has everything the crowd scenes, the intimate and emotional scenes all captured beautifully. You aren't watching the scenes you are living and feeling them. The music makes you sympathize and show admiration adding so many other feelings you don't have in movies. Unlike some embellishments from Hollywood when it comes to history movies this is not one of those. A work of art that should be a required viewing for class as the fight of prejudice will be forever relevant in our generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not only artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    after years, it remains for me an experience. not for its rich beauty or for force of message. but for the nuance of miracle who contains it. because it is a gorgeous construction, result of empathy. and skin for a really great story. but extraordinary art of a director, force of performance of an actor makes this film more than illustration of a life or prey of its subject. it is only a kind of testimony. about a fight behind words. about a way behind definitions. only sketch of a form of self-build. and picture of a time. Sir Ben Kingsley makes an unique role. but his success is more than artistic science but precise courage to transform a character in his skin. to give height of each nuance. and to be not to act. after years, Gandhi remains for me an experience. not only artistic. but a grain of amber as light of candle in special hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Took Richard Attenborough Over Twenty Years To Make This Movie, And Not One Single Second Of That Work Was Wasted.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a labor of love for Richard Attenborough, he tried so many times to get it made, but try as he might have done, he could not get it to happen. It finally happened in the early 1980's, and he completed it in 1982. It took Richard Attenborough over twenty years to make this movie, and not one single second of all of that hard work was wasted. Gandhi is a tremendously powerful experience, it's powerfully told, wonderfully acted, strongly directed, beautifully shot, powerfully scored (music that is), and especially, it's powerfully written. As the title suggests, the movie is based on the life of Mohandas K. Gandhi, who's demonstrations through nonviolent protests help gain India it's independence from Great Britain. The movie was well worth all of the effort, as it is a masterpiece, and it's not just one of the greatest biographical epics ever made, but it is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's flawless. Like many other long movies, such as Barry Lyndon, The Godfather Part II, and Seven Samauri, Gandhi may be long (it's 191 minutes), but it is such a beautiful and powerful film, that you will forget that it's over three hours long. To play Gandhi, Ben Kingsley (who at that time, was a literal unknown) was cast. I heard some stories saying that there where people who thought that Kingsley was Gandhi's ghost, and I could believe that, as I could swear that he WAS Gandhi. Kingsley's powerful performance earned him the Academy Award for Best Actor, which he rightfully deserved to win. I said earlier that it took over 20 years for Richard Attenborough to make this movie. He poured a lot of energy and effort into the making of this film, and his efforts payed off when the film won him two Academy Awards, for Best Picture and Best Director. The movie deserved every major award that it won, it's a masterpiece, it's excellent, and it's...well, you understand it by now. Out of all of the biographical epics that I have seen, such as Patton, Reds, Malcolm X, and Schindler's List, Gandhi is one of the best. I'm not knocking the other movies that I just mentioned, they are all outstanding, but Gandhi is in a class by itself. Gandhi is more than a masterpiece, it is the meaning of the word masterpiece, it takes the word to a new level. So all in all, this movie is without a doubt one of the greatest movies that has ever played on my television set. There are many great movies that deserve to be seen multiple times, like The Godfather, Goodfellas, Citizen Kane, Casablanca, Gone With The Wind, and The General, and Gandhi is definitely one of those movies. Richard Attenborough's biographical epic on perhaps one of the greatest men who ever lived is required viewing, it's a very accurate portrayal of the man who used nonviolent protest to gain India its independence. We all know what a great man that Gandhi was, but when somebody watches this, they will have a whole new opinion on it. When it is over, they will say: "Now this was a man." Anyway, Gandhi is a tremendously spectacular experience, it should not be missed. When you watch it, don't even think about the time or how long it is, think about how great it will be as it progresses more and more. And by the time that it is over, you will say that you have just seen on of the greatest movies ever made. Mr. Kingsley, Mr. Attenborough, you both have my unanimous praise for all of your hard work on this astounding accomplishment in the film industry. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All-Time Great Performance By Ben Kingsly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ben Kingsly plays real life Indian leader Mahatma Gandhi in one of the best performances in screen history, richly deserving his best actor Academy Award, and the film itself won Best Picture, with Richard Attenborough winning best director. Film details how Gandhi went from a young lawyer who leads the campaign for Indian rights in British ruled South Africa after he is shamefully thrown off a train because he wasn't allowed to travel first class(despite his ticket). Later, Gandhi becomes a national hero and leader who calls for India's independence from Great Britain, but who does so by strictly non-violent protest, which amazingly does work for them, since they gain world sympathy due to favorable press coverage. Independence doesn't come without cost, since the divide between Muslims and Hindus is too great, resulting in the formation of Pakistan, and later Gandhi's assassination... Long film is made compelling because of Ben Kingsly's superlative portrayal, and epic sized story telling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pratikw206
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie gives the classic dramatisation of the life of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, an Indian lawyer and activist. This movie superbly shows his non-violent, non-cooperative independence movement against the United Kingdom's rule of the country during the 20th century which ulitimately lead to Inida's freedom(along with thousands of sacrifices by Indian population).Also direction, cinematography, costumes, they're all great. Ben kingsley has done an amazing job with his portrayal of mahatmaji , For me this is his best performance .'Gandhi' is a moving portrait of a character with a disarming humility, who spins cotton, walks the country roads, meditates in front of the ocean, or scoops salt from the beach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Story, Bland Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jake Moskowitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sweeping, cinematic, and bombastic take on the life and achievements of Mr. Gandhi. The film relies entirely on Hollywood clich&eacute;s, simplifying the events of the period, the motives of those involved, and the moral and political complexities of this time period. This cartoonish version of Mr. Gandhi hobbles around India, spinning his wheel and always saying the exactly-correct thing at the exactly-correct time. None of the other characters seem to catch on to this eerie infallibility, however, and contradict him at every turn (or at least when it provides Gandhi with a chance to correct them). Gandhi's strained grandfather-humor, included as a blatant attempt to "humanize" him, gets old quick, and by the end, becomes an annoying self-parody. Then you have the issue of the doe-eyed women that surround him (Mrs. Gandhi, Mirabehn), who say very little the entire film. It seems as if their only real character trait is a total adoration for Mr. Gandhi. Moral tropes are used and re-used, and no complex moral questions are ever introduced. British bad. Indians good. Even worse, the film stands as an insult to all those besides Gandhi who worked tirelessly to make India free. No other leaders are ever mentioned - it's all Gandhi and his buffoonish politician friends, who only exist to stand at a foil to the clear wisdom of Gandhi. It all becomes a little ridiculous and repetitive after a while. It's sad, since the performance by Ben Kingsley is well-crafted. The script is simply not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intense Film About a Peaceful Man!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a sprawling, epic biography about one of the greatest, most influential leaders to have ever walked on our planet. That man was Mahatma Gandhi. He brought about the independence of India from the British Empire without enforcing the need for violence. He also wanted peace between all the Muslims and Hindus in India. This movie perfectly describes how Gandhi set to achieve his goals despite the British Empire trying to stop him. Richard Attenborough's film is about the life of Gandhi from his early adult life all the way to his brutal end. The way this man preached for peace and independence should influence all men and stop the unnecessary violence in this world. This film is very well-acted. I never thought a non-Indian like Ben Kingsley could pull off this kind of role off. But he did. Kingsley truly gave a magnificent performance and I felt like I was watching Gandhi himself. All the supporting actors were very good even though there are too many to list. A trivial fact for movie fans: Daniel-Day Lewis is indeed in this movie. Overall, this is one epic film about a man who united his country. This film has the essential cinematic qualities and it remains one of the top biographies ever made. The only thing that goes against this movie is the running length of over three hours long. But it was well-paced and has very powerful dialog. This film is a must-see for everyone. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gandhi.............Far Above A Saint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a great movie, and truly deserved its 8 Oscars. Director Sir Richard Attenbourgh finding an actor like Ben Kingsley, must have felt like he had discovered Plutonium. Kingsley turned out to be more like Gandhi than the Mahatma himself. If you don't learn something from this movie, check into a clinic for Nazis. There are many scenes that touch you. My favourite is when a big important judge played by Trevor Howard is visibly shaken when he looks at Gandhi in the dock. Howard is diminished in stature just by looking at humanity ...in the flesh. It is undoubtedly a true epic (Titanic was not...not even close) and a movie about a man who really was real...and his story very real. The old religions lean on old books that are almost certainly ...no-where near what REALLY happened. To-day the Catholic church scratches around for people who "other people" say did great things, so they can proclaim them saints. Utter rubbish. The first thing The Catholics need to do is stop sexually abusing children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jayson Wallace
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is breath taking and shows in a great way the struggles Gandhi had to go through. And even while the movie takes more than 3 hours to complete, it feels like just an hour. The only "problem" with this movie is that when you're watching, you don't want to stop it. (to eat or drink something) So.... when you have not yet seen this movie: 1. You should. 2. Always eat and drink (or take it with you!) before starting the movie. (Sorry if my English lacks a bit, i am Dutch.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great First Half, Weak Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the movie made me develop an interest in Mohandas Gandhi and why he developed as he did. You see him young, wearing a turban but otherwise a regular suit and tie, and he encounters racism when he is thrown off a train for illegally being an a first class compartment when he is an Indian. Then he leads a struggle against racism in South Africa, winning some success before moving to India, which he says (in the movie) is a strange country to him. He would fight against British colonial rule of India, but then realizes that ending it might only lead to a government of Indians who would be just as bad-and then he adopts his famous white Indian clothing. After that, the movie falters, and we see less about Gandhi than the political events that follow, not delivered with great accuracy. Ben Kingsley delivers a perfect performance, looking and acting the part. But the image of Gandhi is completely idealized, and he never gets angry or otherwise seems like a real human being. Indeed, there were things about the historical Gandhi that would appall most people. But this is a movie to entertain, not teach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare piece of history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Gilmore
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you have a legendary world icon how do you possibly make a movie that does that person justice. This movie is probably as close as you can get to a perfect movie even one on a man like Gandhi. The way a man who was not wealthy, no property, no title or office, wasn't a commander of a military or any kind of ruler. Yet millions choose to follow him to freedom. You have governments, people all around the world celebrate and join hands to a man who freed his country through non violence. This movie is and was such a epic undertaking in a time before cgi, the funeral at the end was probably the last live action crowd of that size and same with rest of the movie. The last scene was probably one of the greatest scenes of cinematic history. Gandhi's message of non violent resistance is showed as a enthralling piece of art. This serves as entertainment and one of most historical figures in the world that took on the British Empire and won. Kingsley was perfect for the role of Gandhi, he nailed the British influenced Indian accent perfectly. He won both the Academy award and Golden Globe for best actor, he didn't just play Gandhi he became him. With the skillful cinematography and scenes in the movie it was as if India became a character in the film rather then just a location. Reading about the making of the movie and the trouble they had with the elite class in the country that a Englishman was making the movie. They were steadfast and were able to enlist thousands of Indians to help with the creation of this film, the crowds used real Indians from that area. It was very captivating how such a work of art can reach the epic proportions that make this almost nothing less then a miracle. The interpretation by Kingsley is nothing but astonishing and should go down as one of more perfect cinema roles. Watching this you almost forget that you are seeing a actor playing a part, your watching a part of history. This movie has everything the crowd scenes, the intimate and emotional scenes all captured beautifully. You aren't watching the scenes you are living and feeling them. The music makes you sympathize and show admiration adding so many other feelings you don't have in movies. Unlike some embellishments from Hollywood when it comes to history movies this is not one of those. A work of art that should be a required viewing for class as the fight of prejudice will be forever relevant in our generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not only artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    after years, it remains for me an experience. not for its rich beauty or for force of message. but for the nuance of miracle who contains it. because it is a gorgeous construction, result of empathy. and skin for a really great story. but extraordinary art of a director, force of performance of an actor makes this film more than illustration of a life or prey of its subject. it is only a kind of testimony. about a fight behind words. about a way behind definitions. only sketch of a form of self-build. and picture of a time. Sir Ben Kingsley makes an unique role. but his success is more than artistic science but precise courage to transform a character in his skin. to give height of each nuance. and to be not to act. after years, Gandhi remains for me an experience. not only artistic. but a grain of amber as light of candle in special hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Took Richard Attenborough Over Twenty Years To Make This Movie, And Not One Single Second Of That Work Was Wasted.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a labor of love for Richard Attenborough, he tried so many times to get it made, but try as he might have done, he could not get it to happen. It finally happened in the early 1980's, and he completed it in 1982. It took Richard Attenborough over twenty years to make this movie, and not one single second of all of that hard work was wasted. Gandhi is a tremendously powerful experience, it's powerfully told, wonderfully acted, strongly directed, beautifully shot, powerfully scored (music that is), and especially, it's powerfully written. As the title suggests, the movie is based on the life of Mohandas K. Gandhi, who's demonstrations through nonviolent protests help gain India it's independence from Great Britain. The movie was well worth all of the effort, as it is a masterpiece, and it's not just one of the greatest biographical epics ever made, but it is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's flawless. Like many other long movies, such as Barry Lyndon, The Godfather Part II, and Seven Samauri, Gandhi may be long (it's 191 minutes), but it is such a beautiful and powerful film, that you will forget that it's over three hours long. To play Gandhi, Ben Kingsley (who at that time, was a literal unknown) was cast. I heard some stories saying that there where people who thought that Kingsley was Gandhi's ghost, and I could believe that, as I could swear that he WAS Gandhi. Kingsley's powerful performance earned him the Academy Award for Best Actor, which he rightfully deserved to win. I said earlier that it took over 20 years for Richard Attenborough to make this movie. He poured a lot of energy and effort into the making of this film, and his efforts payed off when the film won him two Academy Awards, for Best Picture and Best Director. The movie deserved every major award that it won, it's a masterpiece, it's excellent, and it's...well, you understand it by now. Out of all of the biographical epics that I have seen, such as Patton, Reds, Malcolm X, and Schindler's List, Gandhi is one of the best. I'm not knocking the other movies that I just mentioned, they are all outstanding, but Gandhi is in a class by itself. Gandhi is more than a masterpiece, it is the meaning of the word masterpiece, it takes the word to a new level. So all in all, this movie is without a doubt one of the greatest movies that has ever played on my television set. There are many great movies that deserve to be seen multiple times, like The Godfather, Goodfellas, Citizen Kane, Casablanca, Gone With The Wind, and The General, and Gandhi is definitely one of those movies. Richard Attenborough's biographical epic on perhaps one of the greatest men who ever lived is required viewing, it's a very accurate portrayal of the man who used nonviolent protest to gain India its independence. We all know what a great man that Gandhi was, but when somebody watches this, they will have a whole new opinion on it. When it is over, they will say: "Now this was a man." Anyway, Gandhi is a tremendously spectacular experience, it should not be missed. When you watch it, don't even think about the time or how long it is, think about how great it will be as it progresses more and more. And by the time that it is over, you will say that you have just seen on of the greatest movies ever made. Mr. Kingsley, Mr. Attenborough, you both have my unanimous praise for all of your hard work on this astounding accomplishment in the film industry. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All-Time Great Performance By Ben Kingsly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ben Kingsly plays real life Indian leader Mahatma Gandhi in one of the best performances in screen history, richly deserving his best actor Academy Award, and the film itself won Best Picture, with Richard Attenborough winning best director. Film details how Gandhi went from a young lawyer who leads the campaign for Indian rights in British ruled South Africa after he is shamefully thrown off a train because he wasn't allowed to travel first class(despite his ticket). Later, Gandhi becomes a national hero and leader who calls for India's independence from Great Britain, but who does so by strictly non-violent protest, which amazingly does work for them, since they gain world sympathy due to favorable press coverage. Independence doesn't come without cost, since the divide between Muslims and Hindus is too great, resulting in the formation of Pakistan, and later Gandhi's assassination... Long film is made compelling because of Ben Kingsly's superlative portrayal, and epic sized story telling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pratikw206
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie gives the classic dramatisation of the life of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, an Indian lawyer and activist. This movie superbly shows his non-violent, non-cooperative independence movement against the United Kingdom's rule of the country during the 20th century which ulitimately lead to Inida's freedom(along with thousands of sacrifices by Indian population).Also direction, cinematography, costumes, they're all great. Ben kingsley has done an amazing job with his portrayal of mahatmaji , For me this is his best performance .'Gandhi' is a moving portrait of a character with a disarming humility, who spins cotton, walks the country roads, meditates in front of the ocean, or scoops salt from the beach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Story, Bland Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jake Moskowitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sweeping, cinematic, and bombastic take on the life and achievements of Mr. Gandhi. The film relies entirely on Hollywood clich&eacute;s, simplifying the events of the period, the motives of those involved, and the moral and political complexities of this time period. This cartoonish version of Mr. Gandhi hobbles around India, spinning his wheel and always saying the exactly-correct thing at the exactly-correct time. None of the other characters seem to catch on to this eerie infallibility, however, and contradict him at every turn (or at least when it provides Gandhi with a chance to correct them). Gandhi's strained grandfather-humor, included as a blatant attempt to "humanize" him, gets old quick, and by the end, becomes an annoying self-parody. Then you have the issue of the doe-eyed women that surround him (Mrs. Gandhi, Mirabehn), who say very little the entire film. It seems as if their only real character trait is a total adoration for Mr. Gandhi. Moral tropes are used and re-used, and no complex moral questions are ever introduced. British bad. Indians good. Even worse, the film stands as an insult to all those besides Gandhi who worked tirelessly to make India free. No other leaders are ever mentioned - it's all Gandhi and his buffoonish politician friends, who only exist to stand at a foil to the clear wisdom of Gandhi. It all becomes a little ridiculous and repetitive after a while. It's sad, since the performance by Ben Kingsley is well-crafted. The script is simply not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intense Film About a Peaceful Man!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a sprawling, epic biography about one of the greatest, most influential leaders to have ever walked on our planet. That man was Mahatma Gandhi. He brought about the independence of India from the British Empire without enforcing the need for violence. He also wanted peace between all the Muslims and Hindus in India. This movie perfectly describes how Gandhi set to achieve his goals despite the British Empire trying to stop him. Richard Attenborough's film is about the life of Gandhi from his early adult life all the way to his brutal end. The way this man preached for peace and independence should influence all men and stop the unnecessary violence in this world. This film is very well-acted. I never thought a non-Indian like Ben Kingsley could pull off this kind of role off. But he did. Kingsley truly gave a magnificent performance and I felt like I was watching Gandhi himself. All the supporting actors were very good even though there are too many to list. A trivial fact for movie fans: Daniel-Day Lewis is indeed in this movie. Overall, this is one epic film about a man who united his country. This film has the essential cinematic qualities and it remains one of the top biographies ever made. The only thing that goes against this movie is the running length of over three hours long. But it was well-paced and has very powerful dialog. This film is a must-see for everyone. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gandhi.............Far Above A Saint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a great movie, and truly deserved its 8 Oscars. Director Sir Richard Attenbourgh finding an actor like Ben Kingsley, must have felt like he had discovered Plutonium. Kingsley turned out to be more like Gandhi than the Mahatma himself. If you don't learn something from this movie, check into a clinic for Nazis. There are many scenes that touch you. My favourite is when a big important judge played by Trevor Howard is visibly shaken when he looks at Gandhi in the dock. Howard is diminished in stature just by looking at humanity ...in the flesh. It is undoubtedly a true epic (Titanic was not...not even close) and a movie about a man who really was real...and his story very real. The old religions lean on old books that are almost certainly ...no-where near what REALLY happened. To-day the Catholic church scratches around for people who "other people" say did great things, so they can proclaim them saints. Utter rubbish. The first thing The Catholics need to do is stop sexually abusing children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jayson Wallace
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is breath taking and shows in a great way the struggles Gandhi had to go through. And even while the movie takes more than 3 hours to complete, it feels like just an hour. The only "problem" with this movie is that when you're watching, you don't want to stop it. (to eat or drink something) So.... when you have not yet seen this movie: 1. You should. 2. Always eat and drink (or take it with you!) before starting the movie. (Sorry if my English lacks a bit, i am Dutch.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great First Half, Weak Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the movie made me develop an interest in Mohandas Gandhi and why he developed as he did. You see him young, wearing a turban but otherwise a regular suit and tie, and he encounters racism when he is thrown off a train for illegally being an a first class compartment when he is an Indian. Then he leads a struggle against racism in South Africa, winning some success before moving to India, which he says (in the movie) is a strange country to him. He would fight against British colonial rule of India, but then realizes that ending it might only lead to a government of Indians who would be just as bad-and then he adopts his famous white Indian clothing. After that, the movie falters, and we see less about Gandhi than the political events that follow, not delivered with great accuracy. Ben Kingsley delivers a perfect performance, looking and acting the part. But the image of Gandhi is completely idealized, and he never gets angry or otherwise seems like a real human being. Indeed, there were things about the historical Gandhi that would appall most people. But this is a movie to entertain, not teach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare piece of history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Gilmore
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you have a legendary world icon how do you possibly make a movie that does that person justice. This movie is probably as close as you can get to a perfect movie even one on a man like Gandhi. The way a man who was not wealthy, no property, no title or office, wasn't a commander of a military or any kind of ruler. Yet millions choose to follow him to freedom. You have governments, people all around the world celebrate and join hands to a man who freed his country through non violence. This movie is and was such a epic undertaking in a time before cgi, the funeral at the end was probably the last live action crowd of that size and same with rest of the movie. The last scene was probably one of the greatest scenes of cinematic history. Gandhi's message of non violent resistance is showed as a enthralling piece of art. This serves as entertainment and one of most historical figures in the world that took on the British Empire and won. Kingsley was perfect for the role of Gandhi, he nailed the British influenced Indian accent perfectly. He won both the Academy award and Golden Globe for best actor, he didn't just play Gandhi he became him. With the skillful cinematography and scenes in the movie it was as if India became a character in the film rather then just a location. Reading about the making of the movie and the trouble they had with the elite class in the country that a Englishman was making the movie. They were steadfast and were able to enlist thousands of Indians to help with the creation of this film, the crowds used real Indians from that area. It was very captivating how such a work of art can reach the epic proportions that make this almost nothing less then a miracle. The interpretation by Kingsley is nothing but astonishing and should go down as one of more perfect cinema roles. Watching this you almost forget that you are seeing a actor playing a part, your watching a part of history. This movie has everything the crowd scenes, the intimate and emotional scenes all captured beautifully. You aren't watching the scenes you are living and feeling them. The music makes you sympathize and show admiration adding so many other feelings you don't have in movies. Unlike some embellishments from Hollywood when it comes to history movies this is not one of those. A work of art that should be a required viewing for class as the fight of prejudice will be forever relevant in our generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not only artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    after years, it remains for me an experience. not for its rich beauty or for force of message. but for the nuance of miracle who contains it. because it is a gorgeous construction, result of empathy. and skin for a really great story. but extraordinary art of a director, force of performance of an actor makes this film more than illustration of a life or prey of its subject. it is only a kind of testimony. about a fight behind words. about a way behind definitions. only sketch of a form of self-build. and picture of a time. Sir Ben Kingsley makes an unique role. but his success is more than artistic science but precise courage to transform a character in his skin. to give height of each nuance. and to be not to act. after years, Gandhi remains for me an experience. not only artistic. but a grain of amber as light of candle in special hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Took Richard Attenborough Over Twenty Years To Make This Movie, And Not One Single Second Of That Work Was Wasted.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a labor of love for Richard Attenborough, he tried so many times to get it made, but try as he might have done, he could not get it to happen. It finally happened in the early 1980's, and he completed it in 1982. It took Richard Attenborough over twenty years to make this movie, and not one single second of all of that hard work was wasted. Gandhi is a tremendously powerful experience, it's powerfully told, wonderfully acted, strongly directed, beautifully shot, powerfully scored (music that is), and especially, it's powerfully written. As the title suggests, the movie is based on the life of Mohandas K. Gandhi, who's demonstrations through nonviolent protests help gain India it's independence from Great Britain. The movie was well worth all of the effort, as it is a masterpiece, and it's not just one of the greatest biographical epics ever made, but it is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's flawless. Like many other long movies, such as Barry Lyndon, The Godfather Part II, and Seven Samauri, Gandhi may be long (it's 191 minutes), but it is such a beautiful and powerful film, that you will forget that it's over three hours long. To play Gandhi, Ben Kingsley (who at that time, was a literal unknown) was cast. I heard some stories saying that there where people who thought that Kingsley was Gandhi's ghost, and I could believe that, as I could swear that he WAS Gandhi. Kingsley's powerful performance earned him the Academy Award for Best Actor, which he rightfully deserved to win. I said earlier that it took over 20 years for Richard Attenborough to make this movie. He poured a lot of energy and effort into the making of this film, and his efforts payed off when the film won him two Academy Awards, for Best Picture and Best Director. The movie deserved every major award that it won, it's a masterpiece, it's excellent, and it's...well, you understand it by now. Out of all of the biographical epics that I have seen, such as Patton, Reds, Malcolm X, and Schindler's List, Gandhi is one of the best. I'm not knocking the other movies that I just mentioned, they are all outstanding, but Gandhi is in a class by itself. Gandhi is more than a masterpiece, it is the meaning of the word masterpiece, it takes the word to a new level. So all in all, this movie is without a doubt one of the greatest movies that has ever played on my television set. There are many great movies that deserve to be seen multiple times, like The Godfather, Goodfellas, Citizen Kane, Casablanca, Gone With The Wind, and The General, and Gandhi is definitely one of those movies. Richard Attenborough's biographical epic on perhaps one of the greatest men who ever lived is required viewing, it's a very accurate portrayal of the man who used nonviolent protest to gain India its independence. We all know what a great man that Gandhi was, but when somebody watches this, they will have a whole new opinion on it. When it is over, they will say: "Now this was a man." Anyway, Gandhi is a tremendously spectacular experience, it should not be missed. When you watch it, don't even think about the time or how long it is, think about how great it will be as it progresses more and more. And by the time that it is over, you will say that you have just seen on of the greatest movies ever made. Mr. Kingsley, Mr. Attenborough, you both have my unanimous praise for all of your hard work on this astounding accomplishment in the film industry. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All-Time Great Performance By Ben Kingsly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ben Kingsly plays real life Indian leader Mahatma Gandhi in one of the best performances in screen history, richly deserving his best actor Academy Award, and the film itself won Best Picture, with Richard Attenborough winning best director. Film details how Gandhi went from a young lawyer who leads the campaign for Indian rights in British ruled South Africa after he is shamefully thrown off a train because he wasn't allowed to travel first class(despite his ticket). Later, Gandhi becomes a national hero and leader who calls for India's independence from Great Britain, but who does so by strictly non-violent protest, which amazingly does work for them, since they gain world sympathy due to favorable press coverage. Independence doesn't come without cost, since the divide between Muslims and Hindus is too great, resulting in the formation of Pakistan, and later Gandhi's assassination... Long film is made compelling because of Ben Kingsly's superlative portrayal, and epic sized story telling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pratikw206
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie gives the classic dramatisation of the life of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, an Indian lawyer and activist. This movie superbly shows his non-violent, non-cooperative independence movement against the United Kingdom's rule of the country during the 20th century which ulitimately lead to Inida's freedom(along with thousands of sacrifices by Indian population).Also direction, cinematography, costumes, they're all great. Ben kingsley has done an amazing job with his portrayal of mahatmaji , For me this is his best performance .'Gandhi' is a moving portrait of a character with a disarming humility, who spins cotton, walks the country roads, meditates in front of the ocean, or scoops salt from the beach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Story, Bland Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jake Moskowitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sweeping, cinematic, and bombastic take on the life and achievements of Mr. Gandhi. The film relies entirely on Hollywood clich&eacute;s, simplifying the events of the period, the motives of those involved, and the moral and political complexities of this time period. This cartoonish version of Mr. Gandhi hobbles around India, spinning his wheel and always saying the exactly-correct thing at the exactly-correct time. None of the other characters seem to catch on to this eerie infallibility, however, and contradict him at every turn (or at least when it provides Gandhi with a chance to correct them). Gandhi's strained grandfather-humor, included as a blatant attempt to "humanize" him, gets old quick, and by the end, becomes an annoying self-parody. Then you have the issue of the doe-eyed women that surround him (Mrs. Gandhi, Mirabehn), who say very little the entire film. It seems as if their only real character trait is a total adoration for Mr. Gandhi. Moral tropes are used and re-used, and no complex moral questions are ever introduced. British bad. Indians good. Even worse, the film stands as an insult to all those besides Gandhi who worked tirelessly to make India free. No other leaders are ever mentioned - it's all Gandhi and his buffoonish politician friends, who only exist to stand at a foil to the clear wisdom of Gandhi. It all becomes a little ridiculous and repetitive after a while. It's sad, since the performance by Ben Kingsley is well-crafted. The script is simply not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intense Film About a Peaceful Man!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a sprawling, epic biography about one of the greatest, most influential leaders to have ever walked on our planet. That man was Mahatma Gandhi. He brought about the independence of India from the British Empire without enforcing the need for violence. He also wanted peace between all the Muslims and Hindus in India. This movie perfectly describes how Gandhi set to achieve his goals despite the British Empire trying to stop him. Richard Attenborough's film is about the life of Gandhi from his early adult life all the way to his brutal end. The way this man preached for peace and independence should influence all men and stop the unnecessary violence in this world. This film is very well-acted. I never thought a non-Indian like Ben Kingsley could pull off this kind of role off. But he did. Kingsley truly gave a magnificent performance and I felt like I was watching Gandhi himself. All the supporting actors were very good even though there are too many to list. A trivial fact for movie fans: Daniel-Day Lewis is indeed in this movie. Overall, this is one epic film about a man who united his country. This film has the essential cinematic qualities and it remains one of the top biographies ever made. The only thing that goes against this movie is the running length of over three hours long. But it was well-paced and has very powerful dialog. This film is a must-see for everyone. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gandhi.............Far Above A Saint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a great movie, and truly deserved its 8 Oscars. Director Sir Richard Attenbourgh finding an actor like Ben Kingsley, must have felt like he had discovered Plutonium. Kingsley turned out to be more like Gandhi than the Mahatma himself. If you don't learn something from this movie, check into a clinic for Nazis. There are many scenes that touch you. My favourite is when a big important judge played by Trevor Howard is visibly shaken when he looks at Gandhi in the dock. Howard is diminished in stature just by looking at humanity ...in the flesh. It is undoubtedly a true epic (Titanic was not...not even close) and a movie about a man who really was real...and his story very real. The old religions lean on old books that are almost certainly ...no-where near what REALLY happened. To-day the Catholic church scratches around for people who "other people" say did great things, so they can proclaim them saints. Utter rubbish. The first thing The Catholics need to do is stop sexually abusing children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jayson Wallace
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is breath taking and shows in a great way the struggles Gandhi had to go through. And even while the movie takes more than 3 hours to complete, it feels like just an hour. The only "problem" with this movie is that when you're watching, you don't want to stop it. (to eat or drink something) So.... when you have not yet seen this movie: 1. You should. 2. Always eat and drink (or take it with you!) before starting the movie. (Sorry if my English lacks a bit, i am Dutch.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great First Half, Weak Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the movie made me develop an interest in Mohandas Gandhi and why he developed as he did. You see him young, wearing a turban but otherwise a regular suit and tie, and he encounters racism when he is thrown off a train for illegally being an a first class compartment when he is an Indian. Then he leads a struggle against racism in South Africa, winning some success before moving to India, which he says (in the movie) is a strange country to him. He would fight against British colonial rule of India, but then realizes that ending it might only lead to a government of Indians who would be just as bad-and then he adopts his famous white Indian clothing. After that, the movie falters, and we see less about Gandhi than the political events that follow, not delivered with great accuracy. Ben Kingsley delivers a perfect performance, looking and acting the part. But the image of Gandhi is completely idealized, and he never gets angry or otherwise seems like a real human being. Indeed, there were things about the historical Gandhi that would appall most people. But this is a movie to entertain, not teach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare piece of history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Gilmore
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you have a legendary world icon how do you possibly make a movie that does that person justice. This movie is probably as close as you can get to a perfect movie even one on a man like Gandhi. The way a man who was not wealthy, no property, no title or office, wasn't a commander of a military or any kind of ruler. Yet millions choose to follow him to freedom. You have governments, people all around the world celebrate and join hands to a man who freed his country through non violence. This movie is and was such a epic undertaking in a time before cgi, the funeral at the end was probably the last live action crowd of that size and same with rest of the movie. The last scene was probably one of the greatest scenes of cinematic history. Gandhi's message of non violent resistance is showed as a enthralling piece of art. This serves as entertainment and one of most historical figures in the world that took on the British Empire and won. Kingsley was perfect for the role of Gandhi, he nailed the British influenced Indian accent perfectly. He won both the Academy award and Golden Globe for best actor, he didn't just play Gandhi he became him. With the skillful cinematography and scenes in the movie it was as if India became a character in the film rather then just a location. Reading about the making of the movie and the trouble they had with the elite class in the country that a Englishman was making the movie. They were steadfast and were able to enlist thousands of Indians to help with the creation of this film, the crowds used real Indians from that area. It was very captivating how such a work of art can reach the epic proportions that make this almost nothing less then a miracle. The interpretation by Kingsley is nothing but astonishing and should go down as one of more perfect cinema roles. Watching this you almost forget that you are seeing a actor playing a part, your watching a part of history. This movie has everything the crowd scenes, the intimate and emotional scenes all captured beautifully. You aren't watching the scenes you are living and feeling them. The music makes you sympathize and show admiration adding so many other feelings you don't have in movies. Unlike some embellishments from Hollywood when it comes to history movies this is not one of those. A work of art that should be a required viewing for class as the fight of prejudice will be forever relevant in our generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not only artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    after years, it remains for me an experience. not for its rich beauty or for force of message. but for the nuance of miracle who contains it. because it is a gorgeous construction, result of empathy. and skin for a really great story. but extraordinary art of a director, force of performance of an actor makes this film more than illustration of a life or prey of its subject. it is only a kind of testimony. about a fight behind words. about a way behind definitions. only sketch of a form of self-build. and picture of a time. Sir Ben Kingsley makes an unique role. but his success is more than artistic science but precise courage to transform a character in his skin. to give height of each nuance. and to be not to act. after years, Gandhi remains for me an experience. not only artistic. but a grain of amber as light of candle in special hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Took Richard Attenborough Over Twenty Years To Make This Movie, And Not One Single Second Of That Work Was Wasted.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a labor of love for Richard Attenborough, he tried so many times to get it made, but try as he might have done, he could not get it to happen. It finally happened in the early 1980's, and he completed it in 1982. It took Richard Attenborough over twenty years to make this movie, and not one single second of all of that hard work was wasted. Gandhi is a tremendously powerful experience, it's powerfully told, wonderfully acted, strongly directed, beautifully shot, powerfully scored (music that is), and especially, it's powerfully written. As the title suggests, the movie is based on the life of Mohandas K. Gandhi, who's demonstrations through nonviolent protests help gain India it's independence from Great Britain. The movie was well worth all of the effort, as it is a masterpiece, and it's not just one of the greatest biographical epics ever made, but it is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's flawless. Like many other long movies, such as Barry Lyndon, The Godfather Part II, and Seven Samauri, Gandhi may be long (it's 191 minutes), but it is such a beautiful and powerful film, that you will forget that it's over three hours long. To play Gandhi, Ben Kingsley (who at that time, was a literal unknown) was cast. I heard some stories saying that there where people who thought that Kingsley was Gandhi's ghost, and I could believe that, as I could swear that he WAS Gandhi. Kingsley's powerful performance earned him the Academy Award for Best Actor, which he rightfully deserved to win. I said earlier that it took over 20 years for Richard Attenborough to make this movie. He poured a lot of energy and effort into the making of this film, and his efforts payed off when the film won him two Academy Awards, for Best Picture and Best Director. The movie deserved every major award that it won, it's a masterpiece, it's excellent, and it's...well, you understand it by now. Out of all of the biographical epics that I have seen, such as Patton, Reds, Malcolm X, and Schindler's List, Gandhi is one of the best. I'm not knocking the other movies that I just mentioned, they are all outstanding, but Gandhi is in a class by itself. Gandhi is more than a masterpiece, it is the meaning of the word masterpiece, it takes the word to a new level. So all in all, this movie is without a doubt one of the greatest movies that has ever played on my television set. There are many great movies that deserve to be seen multiple times, like The Godfather, Goodfellas, Citizen Kane, Casablanca, Gone With The Wind, and The General, and Gandhi is definitely one of those movies. Richard Attenborough's biographical epic on perhaps one of the greatest men who ever lived is required viewing, it's a very accurate portrayal of the man who used nonviolent protest to gain India its independence. We all know what a great man that Gandhi was, but when somebody watches this, they will have a whole new opinion on it. When it is over, they will say: "Now this was a man." Anyway, Gandhi is a tremendously spectacular experience, it should not be missed. When you watch it, don't even think about the time or how long it is, think about how great it will be as it progresses more and more. And by the time that it is over, you will say that you have just seen on of the greatest movies ever made. Mr. Kingsley, Mr. Attenborough, you both have my unanimous praise for all of your hard work on this astounding accomplishment in the film industry. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All-Time Great Performance By Ben Kingsly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ben Kingsly plays real life Indian leader Mahatma Gandhi in one of the best performances in screen history, richly deserving his best actor Academy Award, and the film itself won Best Picture, with Richard Attenborough winning best director. Film details how Gandhi went from a young lawyer who leads the campaign for Indian rights in British ruled South Africa after he is shamefully thrown off a train because he wasn't allowed to travel first class(despite his ticket). Later, Gandhi becomes a national hero and leader who calls for India's independence from Great Britain, but who does so by strictly non-violent protest, which amazingly does work for them, since they gain world sympathy due to favorable press coverage. Independence doesn't come without cost, since the divide between Muslims and Hindus is too great, resulting in the formation of Pakistan, and later Gandhi's assassination... Long film is made compelling because of Ben Kingsly's superlative portrayal, and epic sized story telling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Best movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pratikw206
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie gives the classic dramatisation of the life of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi, an Indian lawyer and activist. This movie superbly shows his non-violent, non-cooperative independence movement against the United Kingdom's rule of the country during the 20th century which ulitimately lead to Inida's freedom(along with thousands of sacrifices by Indian population).Also direction, cinematography, costumes, they're all great. Ben kingsley has done an amazing job with his portrayal of mahatmaji , For me this is his best performance .'Gandhi' is a moving portrait of a character with a disarming humility, who spins cotton, walks the country roads, meditates in front of the ocean, or scoops salt from the beach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Story, Bland Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jake Moskowitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sweeping, cinematic, and bombastic take on the life and achievements of Mr. Gandhi. The film relies entirely on Hollywood clich&eacute;s, simplifying the events of the period, the motives of those involved, and the moral and political complexities of this time period. This cartoonish version of Mr. Gandhi hobbles around India, spinning his wheel and always saying the exactly-correct thing at the exactly-correct time. None of the other characters seem to catch on to this eerie infallibility, however, and contradict him at every turn (or at least when it provides Gandhi with a chance to correct them). Gandhi's strained grandfather-humor, included as a blatant attempt to "humanize" him, gets old quick, and by the end, becomes an annoying self-parody. Then you have the issue of the doe-eyed women that surround him (Mrs. Gandhi, Mirabehn), who say very little the entire film. It seems as if their only real character trait is a total adoration for Mr. Gandhi. Moral tropes are used and re-used, and no complex moral questions are ever introduced. British bad. Indians good. Even worse, the film stands as an insult to all those besides Gandhi who worked tirelessly to make India free. No other leaders are ever mentioned - it's all Gandhi and his buffoonish politician friends, who only exist to stand at a foil to the clear wisdom of Gandhi. It all becomes a little ridiculous and repetitive after a while. It's sad, since the performance by Ben Kingsley is well-crafted. The script is simply not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intense Film About a Peaceful Man!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a sprawling, epic biography about one of the greatest, most influential leaders to have ever walked on our planet. That man was Mahatma Gandhi. He brought about the independence of India from the British Empire without enforcing the need for violence. He also wanted peace between all the Muslims and Hindus in India. This movie perfectly describes how Gandhi set to achieve his goals despite the British Empire trying to stop him. Richard Attenborough's film is about the life of Gandhi from his early adult life all the way to his brutal end. The way this man preached for peace and independence should influence all men and stop the unnecessary violence in this world. This film is very well-acted. I never thought a non-Indian like Ben Kingsley could pull off this kind of role off. But he did. Kingsley truly gave a magnificent performance and I felt like I was watching Gandhi himself. All the supporting actors were very good even though there are too many to list. A trivial fact for movie fans: Daniel-Day Lewis is indeed in this movie. Overall, this is one epic film about a man who united his country. This film has the essential cinematic qualities and it remains one of the top biographies ever made. The only thing that goes against this movie is the running length of over three hours long. But it was well-paced and has very powerful dialog. This film is a must-see for everyone. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gandhi.............Far Above A Saint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gandhi is a great movie, and truly deserved its 8 Oscars. Director Sir Richard Attenbourgh finding an actor like Ben Kingsley, must have felt like he had discovered Plutonium. Kingsley turned out to be more like Gandhi than the Mahatma himself. If you don't learn something from this movie, check into a clinic for Nazis. There are many scenes that touch you. My favourite is when a big important judge played by Trevor Howard is visibly shaken when he looks at Gandhi in the dock. Howard is diminished in stature just by looking at humanity ...in the flesh. It is undoubtedly a true epic (Titanic was not...not even close) and a movie about a man who really was real...and his story very real. The old religions lean on old books that are almost certainly ...no-where near what REALLY happened. To-day the Catholic church scratches around for people who "other people" say did great things, so they can proclaim them saints. Utter rubbish. The first thing The Catholics need to do is stop sexually abusing children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jayson Wallace
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is breath taking and shows in a great way the struggles Gandhi had to go through. And even while the movie takes more than 3 hours to complete, it feels like just an hour. The only "problem" with this movie is that when you're watching, you don't want to stop it. (to eat or drink something) So.... when you have not yet seen this movie: 1. You should. 2. Always eat and drink (or take it with you!) before starting the movie. (Sorry if my English lacks a bit, i am Dutch.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great First Half, Weak Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the movie made me develop an interest in Mohandas Gandhi and why he developed as he did. You see him young, wearing a turban but otherwise a regular suit and tie, and he encounters racism when he is thrown off a train for illegally being an a first class compartment when he is an Indian. Then he leads a struggle against racism in South Africa, winning some success before moving to India, which he says (in the movie) is a strange country to him. He would fight against British colonial rule of India, but then realizes that ending it might only lead to a government of Indians who would be just as bad-and then he adopts his famous white Indian clothing. After that, the movie falters, and we see less about Gandhi than the political events that follow, not delivered with great accuracy. Ben Kingsley delivers a perfect performance, looking and acting the part. But the image of Gandhi is completely idealized, and he never gets angry or otherwise seems like a real human being. Indeed, there were things about the historical Gandhi that would appall most people. But this is a movie to entertain, not teach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare piece of history.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Gilmore
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you have a legendary world icon how do you possibly make a movie that does that person justice. This movie is probably as close as you can get to a perfect movie even one on a man like Gandhi. The way a man who was not wealthy, no property, no title or office, wasn't a commander of a military or any kind of ruler. Yet millions choose to follow him to freedom. You have governments, people all around the world celebrate and join hands to a man who freed his country through non violence. This movie is and was such a epic undertaking in a time before cgi, the funeral at the end was probably the last live action crowd of that size and same with rest of the movie. The last scene was probably one of the greatest scenes of cinematic history. Gandhi's message of non violent resistance is showed as a enthralling piece of art. This serves as entertainment and one of most historical figures in the world that took on the British Empire and won. Kingsley was perfect for the role of Gandhi, he nailed the British influenced Indian accent perfectly. He won both the Academy award and Golden Globe for best actor, he didn't just play Gandhi he became him. With the skillful cinematography and scenes in the movie it was as if India became a character in the film rather then just a location. Reading about the making of the movie and the trouble they had with the elite class in the country that a Englishman was making the movie. They were steadfast and were able to enlist thousands of Indians to help with the creation of this film, the crowds used real Indians from that area. It was very captivating how such a work of art can reach the epic proportions that make this almost nothing less then a miracle. The interpretation by Kingsley is nothing but astonishing and should go down as one of more perfect cinema roles. Watching this you almost forget that you are seeing a actor playing a part, your watching a part of history. This movie has everything the crowd scenes, the intimate and emotional scenes all captured beautifully. You aren't watching the scenes you are living and feeling them. The music makes you sympathize and show admiration adding so many other feelings you don't have in movies. Unlike some embellishments from Hollywood when it comes to history movies this is not one of those. A work of art that should be a required viewing for class as the fight of prejudice will be forever relevant in our generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not only artistic experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    after years, it remains for me an experience. not for its rich beauty or for force of message. but for the nuance of miracle who contains it. because it is a gorgeous construction, result of empathy. and skin for a really great story. but extraordinary art of a director, force of performance of an actor makes this film more than illustration of a life or prey of its subject. it is only a kind of testimony. about a fight behind words. about a way behind definitions. only sketch of a form of self-build. and picture of a time. Sir Ben Kingsley makes an unique role. but his success is more than artistic science but precise courage to transform a character in his skin. to give height of each nuance. and to be not to act. after years, Gandhi remains for me an experience. not only artistic. but a grain of amber as light of candle in special hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Took Richard Attenborough Over Twenty Years To Make This Movie, And Not One Single Second Of That Work Was Wasted.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a labor of love for Richard Attenborough, he tried so many times to get it made, but try as he might have done, he could not get it to happen. It finally happened in the early 1980's, and he completed it in 1982. It took Richard Attenborough over twenty years to make this movie, and not one single second of all of that hard work was wasted. Gandhi is a tremendously powerful experience, it's powerfully told, wonderfully acted, strongly directed, beautifully shot, powerfully scored (music that is), and especially, it's powerfully written. As the title suggests, the movie is based on the life of Mohandas K. Gandhi, who's demonstrations through nonviolent protests help gain India it's independence from Great Britain. The movie was well worth all of the effort, as it is a masterpiece, and it's not just one of the greatest biographical epics ever made, but it is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's flawless. Like many other long movies, such as Barry Lyndon, The Godfather Part II, and Seven Samauri, Gandhi may be long (it's 191 minutes), but it is such a beautiful and powerful film, that you will forget that it's over three hours long. To play Gandhi, Ben Kingsley (who at that time, was a literal unknown) was cast. I heard some stories saying that there where people who thought that Kingsley was Gandhi's ghost, and I could believe that, as I could swear that he WAS Gandhi. Kingsley's powerful performance earned him the Academy Award for Best Actor, which he rightfully deserved to win. I said earlier that it took over 20 years for Richard Attenborough to make this movie. He poured a lot of energy and effort into the making of this film, and his efforts payed off when the film won him two Academy Awards, for Best Picture and Best Director. The movie deserved every major award that it won, it's a masterpiece, it's excellent, and it's...well, you understand it by now. Out of all of the biographical epics that I have seen, such as Patton, Reds, Malcolm X, and Schindler's List, Gandhi is one of the best. I'm not knocking the other movies that I just mentioned, they are all outstanding, but Gandhi is in a class by itself. Gandhi is more than a masterpiece, it is the meaning of the word masterpiece, it takes the word to a new level. So all in all, this movie is without a doubt one of the greatest movies that has ever played on my television set. There are many great movies that deserve to be seen multiple times, like The Godfather, Goodfellas, Citizen Kane, Casablanca, Gone With The Wind, and The General, and Gandhi is definitely one of those movies. Richard Attenborough's biographical epic on perhaps one of the greatest men who ever lived is required viewing, it's a very accurate portrayal of the man who used nonviolent protest to gain India its independence. We all know what a great man that Gandhi was, but when somebody watches this, they will have a whole new opinion on it. When it is over, they will say: "Now this was a man." Anyway, Gandhi is a tremendously spectacular experience, it should not be missed. When you watch it, don't even think about the time or how long it is, think about how great it will be as it progresses more and more. And by the time that it is over, you will say that you have just seen on of the greatest movies ever made. Mr. Kingsley, Mr. Attenborough, you both have my unanimous praise for all of your hard work on this astounding accomplishment in the film industry. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
