<filme>
 <id>
  528
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0087553
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1984
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Os Gritos do Sil&ecirc;ncio
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A photographer is trapped in Cambodia during tyrant Pol Pot's bloody "Year Zero" cleansing campaign, which claimed the lives of two million "undesirable" civilians.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Sydney Schanberg is a New York Times journalist covering the civil war in Cambodia. Together with local representative Dith Pran, they cover some of the tragedy and madness of the war. When the American forces leave, Dith Pran sends his family with them, but stays behind himself to help Schanberg cover the event. As an American, Schanberg won't have any trouble leaving the country, but the situation is different for Pran; he's a local, and the Khmer Rouge are moving in.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   History
  </genero>
  <genero>
   War
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   cambodia
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   photographer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   khmer rouge
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new york times
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   awards dinner
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Roland Joff&eacute;
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Bruce Robinson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Sam Waterston
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Haing S. Ngor
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Malkovich
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Nixon Doctrine in its purest form..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ironies abound in THE KILLING FIELDS. "Cambodia is the Nixon doctrine in its purest form," boasts one of the twentieth century's greatest war criminals (who himself lived a long and happy life, thereby putting the lie to any and all notions of karma). The Vietnam War, we're told, resulted in 3 million deaths (70-80% of all casualties were civilian). Does that total factor in the Cambodians who were murdered in the war's "aftermath?" (90% of all deaths in Iraq were civilian, by the way. Evidence has now come to light that the U.$. actually AIDED Saddam Hussein when he used chemical weapons against the Kurds in Iraq. That's right: the same government threatening to bomb Syria back into The Stone Age actually had an active part in the mass murder of Kurdish civilians. Or was it IRANIANS, during the Iran-Iraq War? "Six of one, half dozen of the other," U.$. politicos might say, but the distinction DOES matter, especially if you're Iranian or Kurdish... I may be wrong about the Kurdish murders, but I'm not going to change my comments until I see some paperwork showing otherwise. And there are 30,000 drones in the skies over the U.$., even as I write...) Another of the ironies is what happened to Haing S. Ngor (Dith Pran in THE KILLING FIELDS) after he came to the U.$.: having survived genocide in Cambodia, he was murdered here, in the street. Maybe THIS is the true Killing Field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachana Rom
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of those all too rare movies, a movie that challenges you to think about what you have just witnessed on screen, a movie that has the power to make you very aware that human tragedy and persecution are very much with us today. That said, the film concerns one man's triumph over unbelievable tragedy and adversity. The cinematography is first class, and the acting is all too believable. To appreciate the full enormity of this film I would strongly recommend reading up on the events with which the film is concerned. This film is hard to fault, and the ending with John Lennon's "Imagine" in the background is perfect and may well reduce you to tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkness of the soul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richard6
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the former French colony of Indochina, The Killing Fields centres on New York Times correspondent Sydney Schanberg, together with fellow journalistic aid and Cambodian national Dith Pran reporting on the military involvement of the United States in South East Asia in the early 1970s, Significantly, and the films main focal point, commentating on the latter stages of the Cambodian civil war. Due to the close proximity to Vietnam, and the United States wearisome involvement in the on-going communist and democratic conflicts in South East Asia, American foreign policy and public interest paid portentous attentiveness to the affairs of Cambodia. The film is introduced at the time of America's covert aerial bombardment of Eastern Cambodian military targets following the communist guerrillas refusal to adhere to the 1973 Paris Peace Treaty. Zealous journalist Schanberg is eager to and hindered from reporting to the American public the trepidation caused by the American bombing. Succeeding this introduction, the film moves intensely to the 1975 evacuation of foreign nationals from Phnom Penh during the seizing of power by the totalitarian communists Kampuchea before focusing on the consequent killing fields caused through social transformation and the year-zero policy. The film's final act, following a left behind Pran's escape from a national forced labour camp, is the eventual reuniting of the two journalist friends. From one stand point, British director Ronald Joffe does not shy away from exposing the human atrocities caused by armed conflict. Yet, Joffe does not over-embellish the horrors that inhabitant's encounter in a war-torn Country. Particularly, The Killing Fields centrepiece is the acts of humanity both moral, relationship between close friends, and immoral, the killing of innocent civilians and possible to a lesser extent, the unintentional minor selfish betrayal of Schanberg towards Pran. Rather than taking a more dramatic conventional route, the films interesting aspect is to view from a pragmatic everyday journalistic media approach. Also, interestingly The Killing Fields is one of a handful of English language films to call attention the violence, economics and political ideologies of twentieth-century revolutions. The horrors of the Khmer Rouge and the story told in The killing Fields draws parallels with events in the 1930's collectivisation of Ukrainian agriculture, the Nazi Holocaust of World War II and Mao's Great Leap Forward in the 1950's, all of which resulted in systematic extermination. Unfortunately I was unable to view the film in anamorphic widescreen 1.78:1 format. Although not as detailed, viewing the film in standard format did not eradicate the intensity of the film. As well as a story of friendship, The Killing Fields is an exceptional example of a former colonial countries dilemma when faced with dissimilar political ideologies following independence. Furthermore, the indescribable torment citizens' encounter in a brutal civil war and the mass suffering during the course of inhumane social experiments and the forced undemocratic reorganising of a society.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well Made, But Not Particularly Informative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although The Killing Fields has a reputation as the definitive work on the Khmer Rouge genocide, it is actually a rather shallow treatment of the topic. It does not give much insight into the motivations of the Khmer Rouge or of its own characters for that matter. The film follows journalist Sydney Schanberg and his Cambodian translator Dith Pran as they cover the fall of the Cambodian government. In his enthusiasm to cover the story, Schanberg decides to stay behind when the American Embassy evacuates. This results in Pran being stranded in Cambodia for the duration of the Khmer Rouge regime. The film works best when it focuses on the personal drama between Schanberg and Dith Pran. Sam Waterston gives a good performance as Schanberg, making us empathize with the character even when he acts like a self-indulgent jerk. Haing S. Ngor is excellent as Pran, earning his Oscar with a moving performance. However, the film does not give us any insight into the characters, particularly why Pran, who is clearly terrified, decides to stay behind with Schanberg. Their relationship, while compelling portrayed by the actors, is not explored in any depth, leading to unintentional homosexual overtones. More gallingly, the film does not really give any insight into the Khmer Rouge or why they carried out their atrocities. With Nazis and other more familiar historical villains, viewers will generally have a good sense of their ideologies and motivations. This is not necessarily the case with the Khmer Rouge. We do not really get a sense of who the Khmer Rouge are targeting or why? This is a particularly glaring omission as many younger Americans are only familiar with the Cambodian genocide from this movie. Furthermore, the film's general lack of on-screen violence results in a failure to convey the true horror of what took place. This flaw is acknowledged even by some involved in the film. As Haing Ngor reported in his autobiography, both he and Dith Pran thought the film's violence should be more graphic to convey the brutality of the Khmer Rouge. If you want a true sense of who the Khmer Rouge were, see the documentary S21: The Khmer Rouge Killing Machine, which goes into far greater detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Exceptional Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyejacker
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is an important film. It tells the story of two journalists혰one American and one Cambodian혰struggling to stay alive in war-torn Cambodia. Of course, it tells a bigger story too, namely the result of the bombing of Cambodia by the United States and subsequent atrocities committed by the Khmer Rouge: torture, slavery, brainwashing, increasingly indiscriminate murder on a mass scale. All very real and very terrible things. The film manages to tackle all of this heavy material without glossing anything over, (I'm looking at you Hotel Rwanda) and without making it so brutal as to be unwatchable. Unfortunately, the majority of the acting and dialogue in The Killing Fields isn't quite good enough to do the aforementioned atrocities justice. That is not to say these aspects of the film are bad, they're perfectly adequate. I just wish they were as flawless as some enraptured reviewers would have you believe. Ironically, (and perhaps even fittingly) it's the non-actor Cambodian children that give the most convincing, (and touching) performances in the movie. They may just be being themselves, but it lends the film an authenticity which few of the trained actors were able to capture with any consistency. The cinematography is spot on. Brilliantly balanced and flawlessly framed, it's practically symbolic in a few shots. Just beautiful. All of the filming appeared to be shot on site, in Cambodia and elsewhere, a practice that the majority of modern directors seem to have forgotten about, which is a shame since no amount of CGI or special effects are as convincing as the real place. The sets look 100% real, nothing looks staged. The music ranges from moving, to merely fitting, to downright strange and painfully 80's. Fortunately, there's more of the former than of the latter. With the exception of a few crude sound effects, The Killing Fields sounds quite good overall. While important, The Killing Fields is unlikely to ever be a very popular film. While it's technically a "war movie" (in part) it never glorifies violence, or tries to make it look cool. There's plenty of violence, of course, but it's more of the uncensored 6 o' clock news variety. Obviously, the film also draws attention to a very dark page from the United States past, and raises a lot of uncomfortable questions, which is bound to turn some people off. However, for anyone mature enough to handle its subject matter, and empathetic enough to explore the wide range of emotions covered in the film, The Killing Fields should really not be missed. 7.9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Gut-Wrenching History Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1975 the revolutionary group Khmer Rouge took over Cambodia and initiated a regime that reportedly claimed two million lives. At the time the Vietnam War was still going on, Cambodia was a strategic territory for the American army and the country was full of journalists. The basis of the movie's story comes from the lives of two of them: New York Times journalist Sydney Schanberg, and Dith Pran, Cambodian photojournalist and interpreter who coined the term "Killing Fields." Written by Bruce Robinson based on their writings, the movie follows in fact two stories: one is the fall of Phnom Penh, the capital, and the evacuation of the international embassies, as witnessed by Sydney and Pran, and Sydney's return to the USA; and the second, more radical narrative, shows the horrors of the Khmer Rouge as witnessed by Pran after he's captured and sent to work in a Killing Field, and his epic escape to freedom. From Phnom Penh Sydney and Pran report the events of the civil war between the government and the Khmer Rouge, with the revolutionaries clearly gaining control of the country. The international embassies start evacuating their personnel. Sydney and Pran opt to remain, although Pran sends his wife and family away. As the Khmer Rouge revolutionaries enter the city, they're initially received with joy and prospects of peace, everyone tired of the war. Even Pran joins the festivities. However the Khmer Rouge, split in different factions due to internal power struggles, continue to fight in the capital. Sydney and Pran find refuge in the French embassy, until it's also evacuated and all Cambodians hiding there are turned over to the revolutionaries. For the time, the movie was quite revolutionary in casting a non-amateur actor in the role of Dith Pran. They found Haing Somnang Ngor, a doctor living in the USA, to portray Pran. Like Pran, Ngor had also spent four years in the killing fields before escaping. He won the Oscar for Best Supporting Actor in 1985 for this role. He played the role with naturalism and lightness, displaying a restraint in emotions in situations where an actor would typically go into melodramatic mode. The choice of Ngor is ahead of its time for another reason. Anglo-American movies tend to work on the logic that audiences can only care for the plight of foreign countries if the experiences are mediated through a character from their culture; that's why war correspondents are usually the main characters in such movies. Although now thanks to movies like Letters from Iwo Jima and Hotel Rwanda this is changing, casting a Cambodian actor to tell the story of a Cambodian prisoner of the Khmer Rouge was audacious then. Sam Waterston also delivers a powerful performance as Sydney, an authoritarian boss who blames himself for having used Pran to further his career only to abandon him. Back in New York he starts an international campaign to find his friend, always wondering whether he's doing enough for him. The movie is also helped with performances from John Malkovich and Julian Sands as two other journalists, Craig T. Nelson as the US Army officer in charge of the American evacuation, and Spalding Gray as the morally-torn American Consul, wary of abandoning the country to the revolutionaries. The scenes in the Killing Fields still have, decades later and after graphic violence has become generalised, the power to affect because of how the movie shows the psychological roots of the crimes. It's not that the images are excessively violent, it's that the movie depicts a philosophy of inhumanity. Regimes don't just producer horror for its own sake, the violence is just a tool to implement ideas. Rather than just showing the horrors, the movie shows the philosophy which the violence was used to enforce: the viewer is taken into the classrooms where children are being taught to hate the concept of family and any personal relationships that may threaten blind loyalty to the party; children are given power over life and death; intellectuals, teachers, journalists are executed for their skills; people are forbidden from growing crops, because that's a sign of free initiative, even though thousands are starving to death The movie confronts us with those ideas and we can't help but ask, "How the hell did anyone ever think these ideas could work in a society?" Not everything holds up as well in the movie. Many good scenes are ruined by Mike Oldfield's intrusive cacophony of synthesizer noises. Nowadays, when we listen to electronic scores with less patience than our ancestors did back in the '80s, a lot of this music sounds horrible. Oldfield, one of my favourite living musicians, is by no means an inept film composer, however: half the score, when he turns to traditional orchestration, is majestic. "Pran's Theme" and its variations are appropriately elegiac, and "Requim for a City," with its chorus of grieving voices, is a haunting attempt at showing through music the misery of the one million Cambodians forced by the Khmer Rouge to abandon the capital in a forced march to the countryside to work on the Killing Fields. Twenty-seven years later what the movie has to say about the darkness in the human soul, and the determination to overcome it, remains fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's nothing to forgive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    del91
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Joffe's "The Killing Fields" is a nerve-shredding full film of power and emotion. The facts that the film is not based, but an actual true story, coupled with the knowledge that star Haing S Ngor was an actual Khmer Rouge prisoner, makes it impossible to turn away from the screen. Sam Waterston's performance as the determined turned guilt-ridden reporter Sydney Schanberg is good, but the show belongs to Ngor whose compelling performance gives us not only a person we care about but also a realistic, real human being, thrown into horrible circumstances of outside causes. If anything Ngor's terrific performance can be the sole reason of this film's raw power and brutality. But there is more to watch in this human film. Mike Oldfield's great, suitable score which perfectly suits the action without getting too dramatic or too subtle. The stunning cinematography which shows the horrors of war amidst the beauty of Cambodia. Terrific production value showing atmospheric, realistic locations filled with thousands of extras, a feat reminding me of the days of David Lean, only less joyous and much more terrifying given the context. I cannot recommend this brilliant film enough. Actions speak louder than words, so go see this as soon as you can, and prepare to be moved immensely. The use of John Lennon's "Imagine" is perfectly suited. Overall rating: 91/100
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A historical drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bahadrkk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie takes us to 70s of Cambodia, let us know how vulnerable Cambodian government and US against Khmer Rouge, makes us witnesses of violence implemented by Khmer Rouge, we also can see two brave men, one of whom is Cambodian Dith Pran, how they are disciplined and workaholic even under these circumstances. Although Haing Ngor hadn't had acting experience before, he performed intermediate level of acting. All of the other actors performed well and did their business. Although we couldn't see a lot of battle scenes, there are a lot of scenes about the results of war actions; wounded people, dead people, captivated personal, and tortures. I would prefer to see more battle actions and would like to see them more effective in a war movie, but this movie is much a drama, drama of Cambodian people, and drama of a journalist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vale_krtal14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sydney Schanberg is a journalist in The New York Times, who was sent to Cambodia in 1972 as a correspondent of the war that was occurring there. When he arrives, he meets Dith Pran, a Cambodian photojournalist and refugee who survived the Cambodian Genocide. This man becomes Schaberg's guide and translator during the war. When trying to photograph the execution of two Khmer Rouge operatives, they are arrested and later learn that the press had reported a different version of the story. In 1975, people were being evacuated from the capital because of a possible invasion from the Khmer Rouge. Even though Pran's family is able to flee, he decided to stay and help Schanberg cover the story. After going through several situations, in which they get arrested again, Pran is turned over to the Khmer Rouge after they ask for every Cambodian citizen to be turned in. After months of searching for Pran, Schanberg begins to blame himself for Pran's situation. He wouldn't be trapped if it weren't for him. However, after several complications, Pran reaches a Red Cross camp in the border of Thailand. When he returns home to his family, he reunites with Schanberg who apologizes for everything. Pran forgives him and the movie ends. This movie was extraordinary. The acting, camera movements and the realism in the film captured everything necessary for the audience to be caught in the moment. It is credible, touching and it is poetically convincing. It doesn't have a traditional Hollywood structure, but as a human story, it is very well made. It captures a vivid image of how people's lives were during that period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marykate_nyland
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of the most influential films of the 20th century. Its provocative and dangerous subject matter stresses the importance of communication and the freedom to communicate. Based on the Khmer Rouge occupation and genocide of Cambodia in the 1970's, the film tells the story of two men, catapulted into chaos and peril. The movie is first and foremost, a historical account. The events are based off the true story of Dith Pran and Sydney Schanberg. Given that I had not known much about the Cambodian genocide of the 1970's prior to seeing this film, I must herald the piece as a successful feat of cinematography that served as both informational as well as inspirational. The film is believable, realistic, and heart wrenching. I immediately felt for the two main characters as they quickly exchanged trust and fell victim to the powers of political violence. While it is slightly romanticized, The Killing Fields still manages to produce a message with real life implications.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Nixon Doctrine in its purest form..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ironies abound in THE KILLING FIELDS. "Cambodia is the Nixon doctrine in its purest form," boasts one of the twentieth century's greatest war criminals (who himself lived a long and happy life, thereby putting the lie to any and all notions of karma). The Vietnam War, we're told, resulted in 3 million deaths (70-80% of all casualties were civilian). Does that total factor in the Cambodians who were murdered in the war's "aftermath?" (90% of all deaths in Iraq were civilian, by the way. Evidence has now come to light that the U.$. actually AIDED Saddam Hussein when he used chemical weapons against the Kurds in Iraq. That's right: the same government threatening to bomb Syria back into The Stone Age actually had an active part in the mass murder of Kurdish civilians. Or was it IRANIANS, during the Iran-Iraq War? "Six of one, half dozen of the other," U.$. politicos might say, but the distinction DOES matter, especially if you're Iranian or Kurdish... I may be wrong about the Kurdish murders, but I'm not going to change my comments until I see some paperwork showing otherwise. And there are 30,000 drones in the skies over the U.$., even as I write...) Another of the ironies is what happened to Haing S. Ngor (Dith Pran in THE KILLING FIELDS) after he came to the U.$.: having survived genocide in Cambodia, he was murdered here, in the street. Maybe THIS is the true Killing Field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachana Rom
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of those all too rare movies, a movie that challenges you to think about what you have just witnessed on screen, a movie that has the power to make you very aware that human tragedy and persecution are very much with us today. That said, the film concerns one man's triumph over unbelievable tragedy and adversity. The cinematography is first class, and the acting is all too believable. To appreciate the full enormity of this film I would strongly recommend reading up on the events with which the film is concerned. This film is hard to fault, and the ending with John Lennon's "Imagine" in the background is perfect and may well reduce you to tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkness of the soul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richard6
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the former French colony of Indochina, The Killing Fields centres on New York Times correspondent Sydney Schanberg, together with fellow journalistic aid and Cambodian national Dith Pran reporting on the military involvement of the United States in South East Asia in the early 1970s, Significantly, and the films main focal point, commentating on the latter stages of the Cambodian civil war. Due to the close proximity to Vietnam, and the United States wearisome involvement in the on-going communist and democratic conflicts in South East Asia, American foreign policy and public interest paid portentous attentiveness to the affairs of Cambodia. The film is introduced at the time of America's covert aerial bombardment of Eastern Cambodian military targets following the communist guerrillas refusal to adhere to the 1973 Paris Peace Treaty. Zealous journalist Schanberg is eager to and hindered from reporting to the American public the trepidation caused by the American bombing. Succeeding this introduction, the film moves intensely to the 1975 evacuation of foreign nationals from Phnom Penh during the seizing of power by the totalitarian communists Kampuchea before focusing on the consequent killing fields caused through social transformation and the year-zero policy. The film's final act, following a left behind Pran's escape from a national forced labour camp, is the eventual reuniting of the two journalist friends. From one stand point, British director Ronald Joffe does not shy away from exposing the human atrocities caused by armed conflict. Yet, Joffe does not over-embellish the horrors that inhabitant's encounter in a war-torn Country. Particularly, The Killing Fields centrepiece is the acts of humanity both moral, relationship between close friends, and immoral, the killing of innocent civilians and possible to a lesser extent, the unintentional minor selfish betrayal of Schanberg towards Pran. Rather than taking a more dramatic conventional route, the films interesting aspect is to view from a pragmatic everyday journalistic media approach. Also, interestingly The Killing Fields is one of a handful of English language films to call attention the violence, economics and political ideologies of twentieth-century revolutions. The horrors of the Khmer Rouge and the story told in The killing Fields draws parallels with events in the 1930's collectivisation of Ukrainian agriculture, the Nazi Holocaust of World War II and Mao's Great Leap Forward in the 1950's, all of which resulted in systematic extermination. Unfortunately I was unable to view the film in anamorphic widescreen 1.78:1 format. Although not as detailed, viewing the film in standard format did not eradicate the intensity of the film. As well as a story of friendship, The Killing Fields is an exceptional example of a former colonial countries dilemma when faced with dissimilar political ideologies following independence. Furthermore, the indescribable torment citizens' encounter in a brutal civil war and the mass suffering during the course of inhumane social experiments and the forced undemocratic reorganising of a society.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well Made, But Not Particularly Informative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although The Killing Fields has a reputation as the definitive work on the Khmer Rouge genocide, it is actually a rather shallow treatment of the topic. It does not give much insight into the motivations of the Khmer Rouge or of its own characters for that matter. The film follows journalist Sydney Schanberg and his Cambodian translator Dith Pran as they cover the fall of the Cambodian government. In his enthusiasm to cover the story, Schanberg decides to stay behind when the American Embassy evacuates. This results in Pran being stranded in Cambodia for the duration of the Khmer Rouge regime. The film works best when it focuses on the personal drama between Schanberg and Dith Pran. Sam Waterston gives a good performance as Schanberg, making us empathize with the character even when he acts like a self-indulgent jerk. Haing S. Ngor is excellent as Pran, earning his Oscar with a moving performance. However, the film does not give us any insight into the characters, particularly why Pran, who is clearly terrified, decides to stay behind with Schanberg. Their relationship, while compelling portrayed by the actors, is not explored in any depth, leading to unintentional homosexual overtones. More gallingly, the film does not really give any insight into the Khmer Rouge or why they carried out their atrocities. With Nazis and other more familiar historical villains, viewers will generally have a good sense of their ideologies and motivations. This is not necessarily the case with the Khmer Rouge. We do not really get a sense of who the Khmer Rouge are targeting or why? This is a particularly glaring omission as many younger Americans are only familiar with the Cambodian genocide from this movie. Furthermore, the film's general lack of on-screen violence results in a failure to convey the true horror of what took place. This flaw is acknowledged even by some involved in the film. As Haing Ngor reported in his autobiography, both he and Dith Pran thought the film's violence should be more graphic to convey the brutality of the Khmer Rouge. If you want a true sense of who the Khmer Rouge were, see the documentary S21: The Khmer Rouge Killing Machine, which goes into far greater detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Exceptional Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyejacker
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is an important film. It tells the story of two journalists혰one American and one Cambodian혰struggling to stay alive in war-torn Cambodia. Of course, it tells a bigger story too, namely the result of the bombing of Cambodia by the United States and subsequent atrocities committed by the Khmer Rouge: torture, slavery, brainwashing, increasingly indiscriminate murder on a mass scale. All very real and very terrible things. The film manages to tackle all of this heavy material without glossing anything over, (I'm looking at you Hotel Rwanda) and without making it so brutal as to be unwatchable. Unfortunately, the majority of the acting and dialogue in The Killing Fields isn't quite good enough to do the aforementioned atrocities justice. That is not to say these aspects of the film are bad, they're perfectly adequate. I just wish they were as flawless as some enraptured reviewers would have you believe. Ironically, (and perhaps even fittingly) it's the non-actor Cambodian children that give the most convincing, (and touching) performances in the movie. They may just be being themselves, but it lends the film an authenticity which few of the trained actors were able to capture with any consistency. The cinematography is spot on. Brilliantly balanced and flawlessly framed, it's practically symbolic in a few shots. Just beautiful. All of the filming appeared to be shot on site, in Cambodia and elsewhere, a practice that the majority of modern directors seem to have forgotten about, which is a shame since no amount of CGI or special effects are as convincing as the real place. The sets look 100% real, nothing looks staged. The music ranges from moving, to merely fitting, to downright strange and painfully 80's. Fortunately, there's more of the former than of the latter. With the exception of a few crude sound effects, The Killing Fields sounds quite good overall. While important, The Killing Fields is unlikely to ever be a very popular film. While it's technically a "war movie" (in part) it never glorifies violence, or tries to make it look cool. There's plenty of violence, of course, but it's more of the uncensored 6 o' clock news variety. Obviously, the film also draws attention to a very dark page from the United States past, and raises a lot of uncomfortable questions, which is bound to turn some people off. However, for anyone mature enough to handle its subject matter, and empathetic enough to explore the wide range of emotions covered in the film, The Killing Fields should really not be missed. 7.9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Gut-Wrenching History Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1975 the revolutionary group Khmer Rouge took over Cambodia and initiated a regime that reportedly claimed two million lives. At the time the Vietnam War was still going on, Cambodia was a strategic territory for the American army and the country was full of journalists. The basis of the movie's story comes from the lives of two of them: New York Times journalist Sydney Schanberg, and Dith Pran, Cambodian photojournalist and interpreter who coined the term "Killing Fields." Written by Bruce Robinson based on their writings, the movie follows in fact two stories: one is the fall of Phnom Penh, the capital, and the evacuation of the international embassies, as witnessed by Sydney and Pran, and Sydney's return to the USA; and the second, more radical narrative, shows the horrors of the Khmer Rouge as witnessed by Pran after he's captured and sent to work in a Killing Field, and his epic escape to freedom. From Phnom Penh Sydney and Pran report the events of the civil war between the government and the Khmer Rouge, with the revolutionaries clearly gaining control of the country. The international embassies start evacuating their personnel. Sydney and Pran opt to remain, although Pran sends his wife and family away. As the Khmer Rouge revolutionaries enter the city, they're initially received with joy and prospects of peace, everyone tired of the war. Even Pran joins the festivities. However the Khmer Rouge, split in different factions due to internal power struggles, continue to fight in the capital. Sydney and Pran find refuge in the French embassy, until it's also evacuated and all Cambodians hiding there are turned over to the revolutionaries. For the time, the movie was quite revolutionary in casting a non-amateur actor in the role of Dith Pran. They found Haing Somnang Ngor, a doctor living in the USA, to portray Pran. Like Pran, Ngor had also spent four years in the killing fields before escaping. He won the Oscar for Best Supporting Actor in 1985 for this role. He played the role with naturalism and lightness, displaying a restraint in emotions in situations where an actor would typically go into melodramatic mode. The choice of Ngor is ahead of its time for another reason. Anglo-American movies tend to work on the logic that audiences can only care for the plight of foreign countries if the experiences are mediated through a character from their culture; that's why war correspondents are usually the main characters in such movies. Although now thanks to movies like Letters from Iwo Jima and Hotel Rwanda this is changing, casting a Cambodian actor to tell the story of a Cambodian prisoner of the Khmer Rouge was audacious then. Sam Waterston also delivers a powerful performance as Sydney, an authoritarian boss who blames himself for having used Pran to further his career only to abandon him. Back in New York he starts an international campaign to find his friend, always wondering whether he's doing enough for him. The movie is also helped with performances from John Malkovich and Julian Sands as two other journalists, Craig T. Nelson as the US Army officer in charge of the American evacuation, and Spalding Gray as the morally-torn American Consul, wary of abandoning the country to the revolutionaries. The scenes in the Killing Fields still have, decades later and after graphic violence has become generalised, the power to affect because of how the movie shows the psychological roots of the crimes. It's not that the images are excessively violent, it's that the movie depicts a philosophy of inhumanity. Regimes don't just producer horror for its own sake, the violence is just a tool to implement ideas. Rather than just showing the horrors, the movie shows the philosophy which the violence was used to enforce: the viewer is taken into the classrooms where children are being taught to hate the concept of family and any personal relationships that may threaten blind loyalty to the party; children are given power over life and death; intellectuals, teachers, journalists are executed for their skills; people are forbidden from growing crops, because that's a sign of free initiative, even though thousands are starving to death The movie confronts us with those ideas and we can't help but ask, "How the hell did anyone ever think these ideas could work in a society?" Not everything holds up as well in the movie. Many good scenes are ruined by Mike Oldfield's intrusive cacophony of synthesizer noises. Nowadays, when we listen to electronic scores with less patience than our ancestors did back in the '80s, a lot of this music sounds horrible. Oldfield, one of my favourite living musicians, is by no means an inept film composer, however: half the score, when he turns to traditional orchestration, is majestic. "Pran's Theme" and its variations are appropriately elegiac, and "Requim for a City," with its chorus of grieving voices, is a haunting attempt at showing through music the misery of the one million Cambodians forced by the Khmer Rouge to abandon the capital in a forced march to the countryside to work on the Killing Fields. Twenty-seven years later what the movie has to say about the darkness in the human soul, and the determination to overcome it, remains fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's nothing to forgive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    del91
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Joffe's "The Killing Fields" is a nerve-shredding full film of power and emotion. The facts that the film is not based, but an actual true story, coupled with the knowledge that star Haing S Ngor was an actual Khmer Rouge prisoner, makes it impossible to turn away from the screen. Sam Waterston's performance as the determined turned guilt-ridden reporter Sydney Schanberg is good, but the show belongs to Ngor whose compelling performance gives us not only a person we care about but also a realistic, real human being, thrown into horrible circumstances of outside causes. If anything Ngor's terrific performance can be the sole reason of this film's raw power and brutality. But there is more to watch in this human film. Mike Oldfield's great, suitable score which perfectly suits the action without getting too dramatic or too subtle. The stunning cinematography which shows the horrors of war amidst the beauty of Cambodia. Terrific production value showing atmospheric, realistic locations filled with thousands of extras, a feat reminding me of the days of David Lean, only less joyous and much more terrifying given the context. I cannot recommend this brilliant film enough. Actions speak louder than words, so go see this as soon as you can, and prepare to be moved immensely. The use of John Lennon's "Imagine" is perfectly suited. Overall rating: 91/100
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A historical drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bahadrkk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie takes us to 70s of Cambodia, let us know how vulnerable Cambodian government and US against Khmer Rouge, makes us witnesses of violence implemented by Khmer Rouge, we also can see two brave men, one of whom is Cambodian Dith Pran, how they are disciplined and workaholic even under these circumstances. Although Haing Ngor hadn't had acting experience before, he performed intermediate level of acting. All of the other actors performed well and did their business. Although we couldn't see a lot of battle scenes, there are a lot of scenes about the results of war actions; wounded people, dead people, captivated personal, and tortures. I would prefer to see more battle actions and would like to see them more effective in a war movie, but this movie is much a drama, drama of Cambodian people, and drama of a journalist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vale_krtal14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sydney Schanberg is a journalist in The New York Times, who was sent to Cambodia in 1972 as a correspondent of the war that was occurring there. When he arrives, he meets Dith Pran, a Cambodian photojournalist and refugee who survived the Cambodian Genocide. This man becomes Schaberg's guide and translator during the war. When trying to photograph the execution of two Khmer Rouge operatives, they are arrested and later learn that the press had reported a different version of the story. In 1975, people were being evacuated from the capital because of a possible invasion from the Khmer Rouge. Even though Pran's family is able to flee, he decided to stay and help Schanberg cover the story. After going through several situations, in which they get arrested again, Pran is turned over to the Khmer Rouge after they ask for every Cambodian citizen to be turned in. After months of searching for Pran, Schanberg begins to blame himself for Pran's situation. He wouldn't be trapped if it weren't for him. However, after several complications, Pran reaches a Red Cross camp in the border of Thailand. When he returns home to his family, he reunites with Schanberg who apologizes for everything. Pran forgives him and the movie ends. This movie was extraordinary. The acting, camera movements and the realism in the film captured everything necessary for the audience to be caught in the moment. It is credible, touching and it is poetically convincing. It doesn't have a traditional Hollywood structure, but as a human story, it is very well made. It captures a vivid image of how people's lives were during that period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marykate_nyland
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of the most influential films of the 20th century. Its provocative and dangerous subject matter stresses the importance of communication and the freedom to communicate. Based on the Khmer Rouge occupation and genocide of Cambodia in the 1970's, the film tells the story of two men, catapulted into chaos and peril. The movie is first and foremost, a historical account. The events are based off the true story of Dith Pran and Sydney Schanberg. Given that I had not known much about the Cambodian genocide of the 1970's prior to seeing this film, I must herald the piece as a successful feat of cinematography that served as both informational as well as inspirational. The film is believable, realistic, and heart wrenching. I immediately felt for the two main characters as they quickly exchanged trust and fell victim to the powers of political violence. While it is slightly romanticized, The Killing Fields still manages to produce a message with real life implications.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Nixon Doctrine in its purest form..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ironies abound in THE KILLING FIELDS. "Cambodia is the Nixon doctrine in its purest form," boasts one of the twentieth century's greatest war criminals (who himself lived a long and happy life, thereby putting the lie to any and all notions of karma). The Vietnam War, we're told, resulted in 3 million deaths (70-80% of all casualties were civilian). Does that total factor in the Cambodians who were murdered in the war's "aftermath?" (90% of all deaths in Iraq were civilian, by the way. Evidence has now come to light that the U.$. actually AIDED Saddam Hussein when he used chemical weapons against the Kurds in Iraq. That's right: the same government threatening to bomb Syria back into The Stone Age actually had an active part in the mass murder of Kurdish civilians. Or was it IRANIANS, during the Iran-Iraq War? "Six of one, half dozen of the other," U.$. politicos might say, but the distinction DOES matter, especially if you're Iranian or Kurdish... I may be wrong about the Kurdish murders, but I'm not going to change my comments until I see some paperwork showing otherwise. And there are 30,000 drones in the skies over the U.$., even as I write...) Another of the ironies is what happened to Haing S. Ngor (Dith Pran in THE KILLING FIELDS) after he came to the U.$.: having survived genocide in Cambodia, he was murdered here, in the street. Maybe THIS is the true Killing Field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachana Rom
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of those all too rare movies, a movie that challenges you to think about what you have just witnessed on screen, a movie that has the power to make you very aware that human tragedy and persecution are very much with us today. That said, the film concerns one man's triumph over unbelievable tragedy and adversity. The cinematography is first class, and the acting is all too believable. To appreciate the full enormity of this film I would strongly recommend reading up on the events with which the film is concerned. This film is hard to fault, and the ending with John Lennon's "Imagine" in the background is perfect and may well reduce you to tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkness of the soul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richard6
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the former French colony of Indochina, The Killing Fields centres on New York Times correspondent Sydney Schanberg, together with fellow journalistic aid and Cambodian national Dith Pran reporting on the military involvement of the United States in South East Asia in the early 1970s, Significantly, and the films main focal point, commentating on the latter stages of the Cambodian civil war. Due to the close proximity to Vietnam, and the United States wearisome involvement in the on-going communist and democratic conflicts in South East Asia, American foreign policy and public interest paid portentous attentiveness to the affairs of Cambodia. The film is introduced at the time of America's covert aerial bombardment of Eastern Cambodian military targets following the communist guerrillas refusal to adhere to the 1973 Paris Peace Treaty. Zealous journalist Schanberg is eager to and hindered from reporting to the American public the trepidation caused by the American bombing. Succeeding this introduction, the film moves intensely to the 1975 evacuation of foreign nationals from Phnom Penh during the seizing of power by the totalitarian communists Kampuchea before focusing on the consequent killing fields caused through social transformation and the year-zero policy. The film's final act, following a left behind Pran's escape from a national forced labour camp, is the eventual reuniting of the two journalist friends. From one stand point, British director Ronald Joffe does not shy away from exposing the human atrocities caused by armed conflict. Yet, Joffe does not over-embellish the horrors that inhabitant's encounter in a war-torn Country. Particularly, The Killing Fields centrepiece is the acts of humanity both moral, relationship between close friends, and immoral, the killing of innocent civilians and possible to a lesser extent, the unintentional minor selfish betrayal of Schanberg towards Pran. Rather than taking a more dramatic conventional route, the films interesting aspect is to view from a pragmatic everyday journalistic media approach. Also, interestingly The Killing Fields is one of a handful of English language films to call attention the violence, economics and political ideologies of twentieth-century revolutions. The horrors of the Khmer Rouge and the story told in The killing Fields draws parallels with events in the 1930's collectivisation of Ukrainian agriculture, the Nazi Holocaust of World War II and Mao's Great Leap Forward in the 1950's, all of which resulted in systematic extermination. Unfortunately I was unable to view the film in anamorphic widescreen 1.78:1 format. Although not as detailed, viewing the film in standard format did not eradicate the intensity of the film. As well as a story of friendship, The Killing Fields is an exceptional example of a former colonial countries dilemma when faced with dissimilar political ideologies following independence. Furthermore, the indescribable torment citizens' encounter in a brutal civil war and the mass suffering during the course of inhumane social experiments and the forced undemocratic reorganising of a society.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well Made, But Not Particularly Informative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although The Killing Fields has a reputation as the definitive work on the Khmer Rouge genocide, it is actually a rather shallow treatment of the topic. It does not give much insight into the motivations of the Khmer Rouge or of its own characters for that matter. The film follows journalist Sydney Schanberg and his Cambodian translator Dith Pran as they cover the fall of the Cambodian government. In his enthusiasm to cover the story, Schanberg decides to stay behind when the American Embassy evacuates. This results in Pran being stranded in Cambodia for the duration of the Khmer Rouge regime. The film works best when it focuses on the personal drama between Schanberg and Dith Pran. Sam Waterston gives a good performance as Schanberg, making us empathize with the character even when he acts like a self-indulgent jerk. Haing S. Ngor is excellent as Pran, earning his Oscar with a moving performance. However, the film does not give us any insight into the characters, particularly why Pran, who is clearly terrified, decides to stay behind with Schanberg. Their relationship, while compelling portrayed by the actors, is not explored in any depth, leading to unintentional homosexual overtones. More gallingly, the film does not really give any insight into the Khmer Rouge or why they carried out their atrocities. With Nazis and other more familiar historical villains, viewers will generally have a good sense of their ideologies and motivations. This is not necessarily the case with the Khmer Rouge. We do not really get a sense of who the Khmer Rouge are targeting or why? This is a particularly glaring omission as many younger Americans are only familiar with the Cambodian genocide from this movie. Furthermore, the film's general lack of on-screen violence results in a failure to convey the true horror of what took place. This flaw is acknowledged even by some involved in the film. As Haing Ngor reported in his autobiography, both he and Dith Pran thought the film's violence should be more graphic to convey the brutality of the Khmer Rouge. If you want a true sense of who the Khmer Rouge were, see the documentary S21: The Khmer Rouge Killing Machine, which goes into far greater detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Exceptional Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyejacker
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is an important film. It tells the story of two journalists혰one American and one Cambodian혰struggling to stay alive in war-torn Cambodia. Of course, it tells a bigger story too, namely the result of the bombing of Cambodia by the United States and subsequent atrocities committed by the Khmer Rouge: torture, slavery, brainwashing, increasingly indiscriminate murder on a mass scale. All very real and very terrible things. The film manages to tackle all of this heavy material without glossing anything over, (I'm looking at you Hotel Rwanda) and without making it so brutal as to be unwatchable. Unfortunately, the majority of the acting and dialogue in The Killing Fields isn't quite good enough to do the aforementioned atrocities justice. That is not to say these aspects of the film are bad, they're perfectly adequate. I just wish they were as flawless as some enraptured reviewers would have you believe. Ironically, (and perhaps even fittingly) it's the non-actor Cambodian children that give the most convincing, (and touching) performances in the movie. They may just be being themselves, but it lends the film an authenticity which few of the trained actors were able to capture with any consistency. The cinematography is spot on. Brilliantly balanced and flawlessly framed, it's practically symbolic in a few shots. Just beautiful. All of the filming appeared to be shot on site, in Cambodia and elsewhere, a practice that the majority of modern directors seem to have forgotten about, which is a shame since no amount of CGI or special effects are as convincing as the real place. The sets look 100% real, nothing looks staged. The music ranges from moving, to merely fitting, to downright strange and painfully 80's. Fortunately, there's more of the former than of the latter. With the exception of a few crude sound effects, The Killing Fields sounds quite good overall. While important, The Killing Fields is unlikely to ever be a very popular film. While it's technically a "war movie" (in part) it never glorifies violence, or tries to make it look cool. There's plenty of violence, of course, but it's more of the uncensored 6 o' clock news variety. Obviously, the film also draws attention to a very dark page from the United States past, and raises a lot of uncomfortable questions, which is bound to turn some people off. However, for anyone mature enough to handle its subject matter, and empathetic enough to explore the wide range of emotions covered in the film, The Killing Fields should really not be missed. 7.9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Gut-Wrenching History Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1975 the revolutionary group Khmer Rouge took over Cambodia and initiated a regime that reportedly claimed two million lives. At the time the Vietnam War was still going on, Cambodia was a strategic territory for the American army and the country was full of journalists. The basis of the movie's story comes from the lives of two of them: New York Times journalist Sydney Schanberg, and Dith Pran, Cambodian photojournalist and interpreter who coined the term "Killing Fields." Written by Bruce Robinson based on their writings, the movie follows in fact two stories: one is the fall of Phnom Penh, the capital, and the evacuation of the international embassies, as witnessed by Sydney and Pran, and Sydney's return to the USA; and the second, more radical narrative, shows the horrors of the Khmer Rouge as witnessed by Pran after he's captured and sent to work in a Killing Field, and his epic escape to freedom. From Phnom Penh Sydney and Pran report the events of the civil war between the government and the Khmer Rouge, with the revolutionaries clearly gaining control of the country. The international embassies start evacuating their personnel. Sydney and Pran opt to remain, although Pran sends his wife and family away. As the Khmer Rouge revolutionaries enter the city, they're initially received with joy and prospects of peace, everyone tired of the war. Even Pran joins the festivities. However the Khmer Rouge, split in different factions due to internal power struggles, continue to fight in the capital. Sydney and Pran find refuge in the French embassy, until it's also evacuated and all Cambodians hiding there are turned over to the revolutionaries. For the time, the movie was quite revolutionary in casting a non-amateur actor in the role of Dith Pran. They found Haing Somnang Ngor, a doctor living in the USA, to portray Pran. Like Pran, Ngor had also spent four years in the killing fields before escaping. He won the Oscar for Best Supporting Actor in 1985 for this role. He played the role with naturalism and lightness, displaying a restraint in emotions in situations where an actor would typically go into melodramatic mode. The choice of Ngor is ahead of its time for another reason. Anglo-American movies tend to work on the logic that audiences can only care for the plight of foreign countries if the experiences are mediated through a character from their culture; that's why war correspondents are usually the main characters in such movies. Although now thanks to movies like Letters from Iwo Jima and Hotel Rwanda this is changing, casting a Cambodian actor to tell the story of a Cambodian prisoner of the Khmer Rouge was audacious then. Sam Waterston also delivers a powerful performance as Sydney, an authoritarian boss who blames himself for having used Pran to further his career only to abandon him. Back in New York he starts an international campaign to find his friend, always wondering whether he's doing enough for him. The movie is also helped with performances from John Malkovich and Julian Sands as two other journalists, Craig T. Nelson as the US Army officer in charge of the American evacuation, and Spalding Gray as the morally-torn American Consul, wary of abandoning the country to the revolutionaries. The scenes in the Killing Fields still have, decades later and after graphic violence has become generalised, the power to affect because of how the movie shows the psychological roots of the crimes. It's not that the images are excessively violent, it's that the movie depicts a philosophy of inhumanity. Regimes don't just producer horror for its own sake, the violence is just a tool to implement ideas. Rather than just showing the horrors, the movie shows the philosophy which the violence was used to enforce: the viewer is taken into the classrooms where children are being taught to hate the concept of family and any personal relationships that may threaten blind loyalty to the party; children are given power over life and death; intellectuals, teachers, journalists are executed for their skills; people are forbidden from growing crops, because that's a sign of free initiative, even though thousands are starving to death The movie confronts us with those ideas and we can't help but ask, "How the hell did anyone ever think these ideas could work in a society?" Not everything holds up as well in the movie. Many good scenes are ruined by Mike Oldfield's intrusive cacophony of synthesizer noises. Nowadays, when we listen to electronic scores with less patience than our ancestors did back in the '80s, a lot of this music sounds horrible. Oldfield, one of my favourite living musicians, is by no means an inept film composer, however: half the score, when he turns to traditional orchestration, is majestic. "Pran's Theme" and its variations are appropriately elegiac, and "Requim for a City," with its chorus of grieving voices, is a haunting attempt at showing through music the misery of the one million Cambodians forced by the Khmer Rouge to abandon the capital in a forced march to the countryside to work on the Killing Fields. Twenty-seven years later what the movie has to say about the darkness in the human soul, and the determination to overcome it, remains fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's nothing to forgive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    del91
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Joffe's "The Killing Fields" is a nerve-shredding full film of power and emotion. The facts that the film is not based, but an actual true story, coupled with the knowledge that star Haing S Ngor was an actual Khmer Rouge prisoner, makes it impossible to turn away from the screen. Sam Waterston's performance as the determined turned guilt-ridden reporter Sydney Schanberg is good, but the show belongs to Ngor whose compelling performance gives us not only a person we care about but also a realistic, real human being, thrown into horrible circumstances of outside causes. If anything Ngor's terrific performance can be the sole reason of this film's raw power and brutality. But there is more to watch in this human film. Mike Oldfield's great, suitable score which perfectly suits the action without getting too dramatic or too subtle. The stunning cinematography which shows the horrors of war amidst the beauty of Cambodia. Terrific production value showing atmospheric, realistic locations filled with thousands of extras, a feat reminding me of the days of David Lean, only less joyous and much more terrifying given the context. I cannot recommend this brilliant film enough. Actions speak louder than words, so go see this as soon as you can, and prepare to be moved immensely. The use of John Lennon's "Imagine" is perfectly suited. Overall rating: 91/100
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A historical drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bahadrkk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie takes us to 70s of Cambodia, let us know how vulnerable Cambodian government and US against Khmer Rouge, makes us witnesses of violence implemented by Khmer Rouge, we also can see two brave men, one of whom is Cambodian Dith Pran, how they are disciplined and workaholic even under these circumstances. Although Haing Ngor hadn't had acting experience before, he performed intermediate level of acting. All of the other actors performed well and did their business. Although we couldn't see a lot of battle scenes, there are a lot of scenes about the results of war actions; wounded people, dead people, captivated personal, and tortures. I would prefer to see more battle actions and would like to see them more effective in a war movie, but this movie is much a drama, drama of Cambodian people, and drama of a journalist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vale_krtal14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sydney Schanberg is a journalist in The New York Times, who was sent to Cambodia in 1972 as a correspondent of the war that was occurring there. When he arrives, he meets Dith Pran, a Cambodian photojournalist and refugee who survived the Cambodian Genocide. This man becomes Schaberg's guide and translator during the war. When trying to photograph the execution of two Khmer Rouge operatives, they are arrested and later learn that the press had reported a different version of the story. In 1975, people were being evacuated from the capital because of a possible invasion from the Khmer Rouge. Even though Pran's family is able to flee, he decided to stay and help Schanberg cover the story. After going through several situations, in which they get arrested again, Pran is turned over to the Khmer Rouge after they ask for every Cambodian citizen to be turned in. After months of searching for Pran, Schanberg begins to blame himself for Pran's situation. He wouldn't be trapped if it weren't for him. However, after several complications, Pran reaches a Red Cross camp in the border of Thailand. When he returns home to his family, he reunites with Schanberg who apologizes for everything. Pran forgives him and the movie ends. This movie was extraordinary. The acting, camera movements and the realism in the film captured everything necessary for the audience to be caught in the moment. It is credible, touching and it is poetically convincing. It doesn't have a traditional Hollywood structure, but as a human story, it is very well made. It captures a vivid image of how people's lives were during that period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marykate_nyland
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of the most influential films of the 20th century. Its provocative and dangerous subject matter stresses the importance of communication and the freedom to communicate. Based on the Khmer Rouge occupation and genocide of Cambodia in the 1970's, the film tells the story of two men, catapulted into chaos and peril. The movie is first and foremost, a historical account. The events are based off the true story of Dith Pran and Sydney Schanberg. Given that I had not known much about the Cambodian genocide of the 1970's prior to seeing this film, I must herald the piece as a successful feat of cinematography that served as both informational as well as inspirational. The film is believable, realistic, and heart wrenching. I immediately felt for the two main characters as they quickly exchanged trust and fell victim to the powers of political violence. While it is slightly romanticized, The Killing Fields still manages to produce a message with real life implications.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Nixon Doctrine in its purest form..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ironies abound in THE KILLING FIELDS. "Cambodia is the Nixon doctrine in its purest form," boasts one of the twentieth century's greatest war criminals (who himself lived a long and happy life, thereby putting the lie to any and all notions of karma). The Vietnam War, we're told, resulted in 3 million deaths (70-80% of all casualties were civilian). Does that total factor in the Cambodians who were murdered in the war's "aftermath?" (90% of all deaths in Iraq were civilian, by the way. Evidence has now come to light that the U.$. actually AIDED Saddam Hussein when he used chemical weapons against the Kurds in Iraq. That's right: the same government threatening to bomb Syria back into The Stone Age actually had an active part in the mass murder of Kurdish civilians. Or was it IRANIANS, during the Iran-Iraq War? "Six of one, half dozen of the other," U.$. politicos might say, but the distinction DOES matter, especially if you're Iranian or Kurdish... I may be wrong about the Kurdish murders, but I'm not going to change my comments until I see some paperwork showing otherwise. And there are 30,000 drones in the skies over the U.$., even as I write...) Another of the ironies is what happened to Haing S. Ngor (Dith Pran in THE KILLING FIELDS) after he came to the U.$.: having survived genocide in Cambodia, he was murdered here, in the street. Maybe THIS is the true Killing Field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachana Rom
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of those all too rare movies, a movie that challenges you to think about what you have just witnessed on screen, a movie that has the power to make you very aware that human tragedy and persecution are very much with us today. That said, the film concerns one man's triumph over unbelievable tragedy and adversity. The cinematography is first class, and the acting is all too believable. To appreciate the full enormity of this film I would strongly recommend reading up on the events with which the film is concerned. This film is hard to fault, and the ending with John Lennon's "Imagine" in the background is perfect and may well reduce you to tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkness of the soul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richard6
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the former French colony of Indochina, The Killing Fields centres on New York Times correspondent Sydney Schanberg, together with fellow journalistic aid and Cambodian national Dith Pran reporting on the military involvement of the United States in South East Asia in the early 1970s, Significantly, and the films main focal point, commentating on the latter stages of the Cambodian civil war. Due to the close proximity to Vietnam, and the United States wearisome involvement in the on-going communist and democratic conflicts in South East Asia, American foreign policy and public interest paid portentous attentiveness to the affairs of Cambodia. The film is introduced at the time of America's covert aerial bombardment of Eastern Cambodian military targets following the communist guerrillas refusal to adhere to the 1973 Paris Peace Treaty. Zealous journalist Schanberg is eager to and hindered from reporting to the American public the trepidation caused by the American bombing. Succeeding this introduction, the film moves intensely to the 1975 evacuation of foreign nationals from Phnom Penh during the seizing of power by the totalitarian communists Kampuchea before focusing on the consequent killing fields caused through social transformation and the year-zero policy. The film's final act, following a left behind Pran's escape from a national forced labour camp, is the eventual reuniting of the two journalist friends. From one stand point, British director Ronald Joffe does not shy away from exposing the human atrocities caused by armed conflict. Yet, Joffe does not over-embellish the horrors that inhabitant's encounter in a war-torn Country. Particularly, The Killing Fields centrepiece is the acts of humanity both moral, relationship between close friends, and immoral, the killing of innocent civilians and possible to a lesser extent, the unintentional minor selfish betrayal of Schanberg towards Pran. Rather than taking a more dramatic conventional route, the films interesting aspect is to view from a pragmatic everyday journalistic media approach. Also, interestingly The Killing Fields is one of a handful of English language films to call attention the violence, economics and political ideologies of twentieth-century revolutions. The horrors of the Khmer Rouge and the story told in The killing Fields draws parallels with events in the 1930's collectivisation of Ukrainian agriculture, the Nazi Holocaust of World War II and Mao's Great Leap Forward in the 1950's, all of which resulted in systematic extermination. Unfortunately I was unable to view the film in anamorphic widescreen 1.78:1 format. Although not as detailed, viewing the film in standard format did not eradicate the intensity of the film. As well as a story of friendship, The Killing Fields is an exceptional example of a former colonial countries dilemma when faced with dissimilar political ideologies following independence. Furthermore, the indescribable torment citizens' encounter in a brutal civil war and the mass suffering during the course of inhumane social experiments and the forced undemocratic reorganising of a society.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well Made, But Not Particularly Informative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although The Killing Fields has a reputation as the definitive work on the Khmer Rouge genocide, it is actually a rather shallow treatment of the topic. It does not give much insight into the motivations of the Khmer Rouge or of its own characters for that matter. The film follows journalist Sydney Schanberg and his Cambodian translator Dith Pran as they cover the fall of the Cambodian government. In his enthusiasm to cover the story, Schanberg decides to stay behind when the American Embassy evacuates. This results in Pran being stranded in Cambodia for the duration of the Khmer Rouge regime. The film works best when it focuses on the personal drama between Schanberg and Dith Pran. Sam Waterston gives a good performance as Schanberg, making us empathize with the character even when he acts like a self-indulgent jerk. Haing S. Ngor is excellent as Pran, earning his Oscar with a moving performance. However, the film does not give us any insight into the characters, particularly why Pran, who is clearly terrified, decides to stay behind with Schanberg. Their relationship, while compelling portrayed by the actors, is not explored in any depth, leading to unintentional homosexual overtones. More gallingly, the film does not really give any insight into the Khmer Rouge or why they carried out their atrocities. With Nazis and other more familiar historical villains, viewers will generally have a good sense of their ideologies and motivations. This is not necessarily the case with the Khmer Rouge. We do not really get a sense of who the Khmer Rouge are targeting or why? This is a particularly glaring omission as many younger Americans are only familiar with the Cambodian genocide from this movie. Furthermore, the film's general lack of on-screen violence results in a failure to convey the true horror of what took place. This flaw is acknowledged even by some involved in the film. As Haing Ngor reported in his autobiography, both he and Dith Pran thought the film's violence should be more graphic to convey the brutality of the Khmer Rouge. If you want a true sense of who the Khmer Rouge were, see the documentary S21: The Khmer Rouge Killing Machine, which goes into far greater detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Exceptional Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyejacker
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is an important film. It tells the story of two journalists혰one American and one Cambodian혰struggling to stay alive in war-torn Cambodia. Of course, it tells a bigger story too, namely the result of the bombing of Cambodia by the United States and subsequent atrocities committed by the Khmer Rouge: torture, slavery, brainwashing, increasingly indiscriminate murder on a mass scale. All very real and very terrible things. The film manages to tackle all of this heavy material without glossing anything over, (I'm looking at you Hotel Rwanda) and without making it so brutal as to be unwatchable. Unfortunately, the majority of the acting and dialogue in The Killing Fields isn't quite good enough to do the aforementioned atrocities justice. That is not to say these aspects of the film are bad, they're perfectly adequate. I just wish they were as flawless as some enraptured reviewers would have you believe. Ironically, (and perhaps even fittingly) it's the non-actor Cambodian children that give the most convincing, (and touching) performances in the movie. They may just be being themselves, but it lends the film an authenticity which few of the trained actors were able to capture with any consistency. The cinematography is spot on. Brilliantly balanced and flawlessly framed, it's practically symbolic in a few shots. Just beautiful. All of the filming appeared to be shot on site, in Cambodia and elsewhere, a practice that the majority of modern directors seem to have forgotten about, which is a shame since no amount of CGI or special effects are as convincing as the real place. The sets look 100% real, nothing looks staged. The music ranges from moving, to merely fitting, to downright strange and painfully 80's. Fortunately, there's more of the former than of the latter. With the exception of a few crude sound effects, The Killing Fields sounds quite good overall. While important, The Killing Fields is unlikely to ever be a very popular film. While it's technically a "war movie" (in part) it never glorifies violence, or tries to make it look cool. There's plenty of violence, of course, but it's more of the uncensored 6 o' clock news variety. Obviously, the film also draws attention to a very dark page from the United States past, and raises a lot of uncomfortable questions, which is bound to turn some people off. However, for anyone mature enough to handle its subject matter, and empathetic enough to explore the wide range of emotions covered in the film, The Killing Fields should really not be missed. 7.9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Gut-Wrenching History Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1975 the revolutionary group Khmer Rouge took over Cambodia and initiated a regime that reportedly claimed two million lives. At the time the Vietnam War was still going on, Cambodia was a strategic territory for the American army and the country was full of journalists. The basis of the movie's story comes from the lives of two of them: New York Times journalist Sydney Schanberg, and Dith Pran, Cambodian photojournalist and interpreter who coined the term "Killing Fields." Written by Bruce Robinson based on their writings, the movie follows in fact two stories: one is the fall of Phnom Penh, the capital, and the evacuation of the international embassies, as witnessed by Sydney and Pran, and Sydney's return to the USA; and the second, more radical narrative, shows the horrors of the Khmer Rouge as witnessed by Pran after he's captured and sent to work in a Killing Field, and his epic escape to freedom. From Phnom Penh Sydney and Pran report the events of the civil war between the government and the Khmer Rouge, with the revolutionaries clearly gaining control of the country. The international embassies start evacuating their personnel. Sydney and Pran opt to remain, although Pran sends his wife and family away. As the Khmer Rouge revolutionaries enter the city, they're initially received with joy and prospects of peace, everyone tired of the war. Even Pran joins the festivities. However the Khmer Rouge, split in different factions due to internal power struggles, continue to fight in the capital. Sydney and Pran find refuge in the French embassy, until it's also evacuated and all Cambodians hiding there are turned over to the revolutionaries. For the time, the movie was quite revolutionary in casting a non-amateur actor in the role of Dith Pran. They found Haing Somnang Ngor, a doctor living in the USA, to portray Pran. Like Pran, Ngor had also spent four years in the killing fields before escaping. He won the Oscar for Best Supporting Actor in 1985 for this role. He played the role with naturalism and lightness, displaying a restraint in emotions in situations where an actor would typically go into melodramatic mode. The choice of Ngor is ahead of its time for another reason. Anglo-American movies tend to work on the logic that audiences can only care for the plight of foreign countries if the experiences are mediated through a character from their culture; that's why war correspondents are usually the main characters in such movies. Although now thanks to movies like Letters from Iwo Jima and Hotel Rwanda this is changing, casting a Cambodian actor to tell the story of a Cambodian prisoner of the Khmer Rouge was audacious then. Sam Waterston also delivers a powerful performance as Sydney, an authoritarian boss who blames himself for having used Pran to further his career only to abandon him. Back in New York he starts an international campaign to find his friend, always wondering whether he's doing enough for him. The movie is also helped with performances from John Malkovich and Julian Sands as two other journalists, Craig T. Nelson as the US Army officer in charge of the American evacuation, and Spalding Gray as the morally-torn American Consul, wary of abandoning the country to the revolutionaries. The scenes in the Killing Fields still have, decades later and after graphic violence has become generalised, the power to affect because of how the movie shows the psychological roots of the crimes. It's not that the images are excessively violent, it's that the movie depicts a philosophy of inhumanity. Regimes don't just producer horror for its own sake, the violence is just a tool to implement ideas. Rather than just showing the horrors, the movie shows the philosophy which the violence was used to enforce: the viewer is taken into the classrooms where children are being taught to hate the concept of family and any personal relationships that may threaten blind loyalty to the party; children are given power over life and death; intellectuals, teachers, journalists are executed for their skills; people are forbidden from growing crops, because that's a sign of free initiative, even though thousands are starving to death The movie confronts us with those ideas and we can't help but ask, "How the hell did anyone ever think these ideas could work in a society?" Not everything holds up as well in the movie. Many good scenes are ruined by Mike Oldfield's intrusive cacophony of synthesizer noises. Nowadays, when we listen to electronic scores with less patience than our ancestors did back in the '80s, a lot of this music sounds horrible. Oldfield, one of my favourite living musicians, is by no means an inept film composer, however: half the score, when he turns to traditional orchestration, is majestic. "Pran's Theme" and its variations are appropriately elegiac, and "Requim for a City," with its chorus of grieving voices, is a haunting attempt at showing through music the misery of the one million Cambodians forced by the Khmer Rouge to abandon the capital in a forced march to the countryside to work on the Killing Fields. Twenty-seven years later what the movie has to say about the darkness in the human soul, and the determination to overcome it, remains fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's nothing to forgive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    del91
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Joffe's "The Killing Fields" is a nerve-shredding full film of power and emotion. The facts that the film is not based, but an actual true story, coupled with the knowledge that star Haing S Ngor was an actual Khmer Rouge prisoner, makes it impossible to turn away from the screen. Sam Waterston's performance as the determined turned guilt-ridden reporter Sydney Schanberg is good, but the show belongs to Ngor whose compelling performance gives us not only a person we care about but also a realistic, real human being, thrown into horrible circumstances of outside causes. If anything Ngor's terrific performance can be the sole reason of this film's raw power and brutality. But there is more to watch in this human film. Mike Oldfield's great, suitable score which perfectly suits the action without getting too dramatic or too subtle. The stunning cinematography which shows the horrors of war amidst the beauty of Cambodia. Terrific production value showing atmospheric, realistic locations filled with thousands of extras, a feat reminding me of the days of David Lean, only less joyous and much more terrifying given the context. I cannot recommend this brilliant film enough. Actions speak louder than words, so go see this as soon as you can, and prepare to be moved immensely. The use of John Lennon's "Imagine" is perfectly suited. Overall rating: 91/100
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A historical drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bahadrkk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie takes us to 70s of Cambodia, let us know how vulnerable Cambodian government and US against Khmer Rouge, makes us witnesses of violence implemented by Khmer Rouge, we also can see two brave men, one of whom is Cambodian Dith Pran, how they are disciplined and workaholic even under these circumstances. Although Haing Ngor hadn't had acting experience before, he performed intermediate level of acting. All of the other actors performed well and did their business. Although we couldn't see a lot of battle scenes, there are a lot of scenes about the results of war actions; wounded people, dead people, captivated personal, and tortures. I would prefer to see more battle actions and would like to see them more effective in a war movie, but this movie is much a drama, drama of Cambodian people, and drama of a journalist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vale_krtal14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sydney Schanberg is a journalist in The New York Times, who was sent to Cambodia in 1972 as a correspondent of the war that was occurring there. When he arrives, he meets Dith Pran, a Cambodian photojournalist and refugee who survived the Cambodian Genocide. This man becomes Schaberg's guide and translator during the war. When trying to photograph the execution of two Khmer Rouge operatives, they are arrested and later learn that the press had reported a different version of the story. In 1975, people were being evacuated from the capital because of a possible invasion from the Khmer Rouge. Even though Pran's family is able to flee, he decided to stay and help Schanberg cover the story. After going through several situations, in which they get arrested again, Pran is turned over to the Khmer Rouge after they ask for every Cambodian citizen to be turned in. After months of searching for Pran, Schanberg begins to blame himself for Pran's situation. He wouldn't be trapped if it weren't for him. However, after several complications, Pran reaches a Red Cross camp in the border of Thailand. When he returns home to his family, he reunites with Schanberg who apologizes for everything. Pran forgives him and the movie ends. This movie was extraordinary. The acting, camera movements and the realism in the film captured everything necessary for the audience to be caught in the moment. It is credible, touching and it is poetically convincing. It doesn't have a traditional Hollywood structure, but as a human story, it is very well made. It captures a vivid image of how people's lives were during that period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marykate_nyland
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of the most influential films of the 20th century. Its provocative and dangerous subject matter stresses the importance of communication and the freedom to communicate. Based on the Khmer Rouge occupation and genocide of Cambodia in the 1970's, the film tells the story of two men, catapulted into chaos and peril. The movie is first and foremost, a historical account. The events are based off the true story of Dith Pran and Sydney Schanberg. Given that I had not known much about the Cambodian genocide of the 1970's prior to seeing this film, I must herald the piece as a successful feat of cinematography that served as both informational as well as inspirational. The film is believable, realistic, and heart wrenching. I immediately felt for the two main characters as they quickly exchanged trust and fell victim to the powers of political violence. While it is slightly romanticized, The Killing Fields still manages to produce a message with real life implications.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Nixon Doctrine in its purest form..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ironies abound in THE KILLING FIELDS. "Cambodia is the Nixon doctrine in its purest form," boasts one of the twentieth century's greatest war criminals (who himself lived a long and happy life, thereby putting the lie to any and all notions of karma). The Vietnam War, we're told, resulted in 3 million deaths (70-80% of all casualties were civilian). Does that total factor in the Cambodians who were murdered in the war's "aftermath?" (90% of all deaths in Iraq were civilian, by the way. Evidence has now come to light that the U.$. actually AIDED Saddam Hussein when he used chemical weapons against the Kurds in Iraq. That's right: the same government threatening to bomb Syria back into The Stone Age actually had an active part in the mass murder of Kurdish civilians. Or was it IRANIANS, during the Iran-Iraq War? "Six of one, half dozen of the other," U.$. politicos might say, but the distinction DOES matter, especially if you're Iranian or Kurdish... I may be wrong about the Kurdish murders, but I'm not going to change my comments until I see some paperwork showing otherwise. And there are 30,000 drones in the skies over the U.$., even as I write...) Another of the ironies is what happened to Haing S. Ngor (Dith Pran in THE KILLING FIELDS) after he came to the U.$.: having survived genocide in Cambodia, he was murdered here, in the street. Maybe THIS is the true Killing Field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachana Rom
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of those all too rare movies, a movie that challenges you to think about what you have just witnessed on screen, a movie that has the power to make you very aware that human tragedy and persecution are very much with us today. That said, the film concerns one man's triumph over unbelievable tragedy and adversity. The cinematography is first class, and the acting is all too believable. To appreciate the full enormity of this film I would strongly recommend reading up on the events with which the film is concerned. This film is hard to fault, and the ending with John Lennon's "Imagine" in the background is perfect and may well reduce you to tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkness of the soul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richard6
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the former French colony of Indochina, The Killing Fields centres on New York Times correspondent Sydney Schanberg, together with fellow journalistic aid and Cambodian national Dith Pran reporting on the military involvement of the United States in South East Asia in the early 1970s, Significantly, and the films main focal point, commentating on the latter stages of the Cambodian civil war. Due to the close proximity to Vietnam, and the United States wearisome involvement in the on-going communist and democratic conflicts in South East Asia, American foreign policy and public interest paid portentous attentiveness to the affairs of Cambodia. The film is introduced at the time of America's covert aerial bombardment of Eastern Cambodian military targets following the communist guerrillas refusal to adhere to the 1973 Paris Peace Treaty. Zealous journalist Schanberg is eager to and hindered from reporting to the American public the trepidation caused by the American bombing. Succeeding this introduction, the film moves intensely to the 1975 evacuation of foreign nationals from Phnom Penh during the seizing of power by the totalitarian communists Kampuchea before focusing on the consequent killing fields caused through social transformation and the year-zero policy. The film's final act, following a left behind Pran's escape from a national forced labour camp, is the eventual reuniting of the two journalist friends. From one stand point, British director Ronald Joffe does not shy away from exposing the human atrocities caused by armed conflict. Yet, Joffe does not over-embellish the horrors that inhabitant's encounter in a war-torn Country. Particularly, The Killing Fields centrepiece is the acts of humanity both moral, relationship between close friends, and immoral, the killing of innocent civilians and possible to a lesser extent, the unintentional minor selfish betrayal of Schanberg towards Pran. Rather than taking a more dramatic conventional route, the films interesting aspect is to view from a pragmatic everyday journalistic media approach. Also, interestingly The Killing Fields is one of a handful of English language films to call attention the violence, economics and political ideologies of twentieth-century revolutions. The horrors of the Khmer Rouge and the story told in The killing Fields draws parallels with events in the 1930's collectivisation of Ukrainian agriculture, the Nazi Holocaust of World War II and Mao's Great Leap Forward in the 1950's, all of which resulted in systematic extermination. Unfortunately I was unable to view the film in anamorphic widescreen 1.78:1 format. Although not as detailed, viewing the film in standard format did not eradicate the intensity of the film. As well as a story of friendship, The Killing Fields is an exceptional example of a former colonial countries dilemma when faced with dissimilar political ideologies following independence. Furthermore, the indescribable torment citizens' encounter in a brutal civil war and the mass suffering during the course of inhumane social experiments and the forced undemocratic reorganising of a society.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well Made, But Not Particularly Informative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although The Killing Fields has a reputation as the definitive work on the Khmer Rouge genocide, it is actually a rather shallow treatment of the topic. It does not give much insight into the motivations of the Khmer Rouge or of its own characters for that matter. The film follows journalist Sydney Schanberg and his Cambodian translator Dith Pran as they cover the fall of the Cambodian government. In his enthusiasm to cover the story, Schanberg decides to stay behind when the American Embassy evacuates. This results in Pran being stranded in Cambodia for the duration of the Khmer Rouge regime. The film works best when it focuses on the personal drama between Schanberg and Dith Pran. Sam Waterston gives a good performance as Schanberg, making us empathize with the character even when he acts like a self-indulgent jerk. Haing S. Ngor is excellent as Pran, earning his Oscar with a moving performance. However, the film does not give us any insight into the characters, particularly why Pran, who is clearly terrified, decides to stay behind with Schanberg. Their relationship, while compelling portrayed by the actors, is not explored in any depth, leading to unintentional homosexual overtones. More gallingly, the film does not really give any insight into the Khmer Rouge or why they carried out their atrocities. With Nazis and other more familiar historical villains, viewers will generally have a good sense of their ideologies and motivations. This is not necessarily the case with the Khmer Rouge. We do not really get a sense of who the Khmer Rouge are targeting or why? This is a particularly glaring omission as many younger Americans are only familiar with the Cambodian genocide from this movie. Furthermore, the film's general lack of on-screen violence results in a failure to convey the true horror of what took place. This flaw is acknowledged even by some involved in the film. As Haing Ngor reported in his autobiography, both he and Dith Pran thought the film's violence should be more graphic to convey the brutality of the Khmer Rouge. If you want a true sense of who the Khmer Rouge were, see the documentary S21: The Khmer Rouge Killing Machine, which goes into far greater detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Exceptional Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyejacker
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is an important film. It tells the story of two journalists혰one American and one Cambodian혰struggling to stay alive in war-torn Cambodia. Of course, it tells a bigger story too, namely the result of the bombing of Cambodia by the United States and subsequent atrocities committed by the Khmer Rouge: torture, slavery, brainwashing, increasingly indiscriminate murder on a mass scale. All very real and very terrible things. The film manages to tackle all of this heavy material without glossing anything over, (I'm looking at you Hotel Rwanda) and without making it so brutal as to be unwatchable. Unfortunately, the majority of the acting and dialogue in The Killing Fields isn't quite good enough to do the aforementioned atrocities justice. That is not to say these aspects of the film are bad, they're perfectly adequate. I just wish they were as flawless as some enraptured reviewers would have you believe. Ironically, (and perhaps even fittingly) it's the non-actor Cambodian children that give the most convincing, (and touching) performances in the movie. They may just be being themselves, but it lends the film an authenticity which few of the trained actors were able to capture with any consistency. The cinematography is spot on. Brilliantly balanced and flawlessly framed, it's practically symbolic in a few shots. Just beautiful. All of the filming appeared to be shot on site, in Cambodia and elsewhere, a practice that the majority of modern directors seem to have forgotten about, which is a shame since no amount of CGI or special effects are as convincing as the real place. The sets look 100% real, nothing looks staged. The music ranges from moving, to merely fitting, to downright strange and painfully 80's. Fortunately, there's more of the former than of the latter. With the exception of a few crude sound effects, The Killing Fields sounds quite good overall. While important, The Killing Fields is unlikely to ever be a very popular film. While it's technically a "war movie" (in part) it never glorifies violence, or tries to make it look cool. There's plenty of violence, of course, but it's more of the uncensored 6 o' clock news variety. Obviously, the film also draws attention to a very dark page from the United States past, and raises a lot of uncomfortable questions, which is bound to turn some people off. However, for anyone mature enough to handle its subject matter, and empathetic enough to explore the wide range of emotions covered in the film, The Killing Fields should really not be missed. 7.9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Gut-Wrenching History Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1975 the revolutionary group Khmer Rouge took over Cambodia and initiated a regime that reportedly claimed two million lives. At the time the Vietnam War was still going on, Cambodia was a strategic territory for the American army and the country was full of journalists. The basis of the movie's story comes from the lives of two of them: New York Times journalist Sydney Schanberg, and Dith Pran, Cambodian photojournalist and interpreter who coined the term "Killing Fields." Written by Bruce Robinson based on their writings, the movie follows in fact two stories: one is the fall of Phnom Penh, the capital, and the evacuation of the international embassies, as witnessed by Sydney and Pran, and Sydney's return to the USA; and the second, more radical narrative, shows the horrors of the Khmer Rouge as witnessed by Pran after he's captured and sent to work in a Killing Field, and his epic escape to freedom. From Phnom Penh Sydney and Pran report the events of the civil war between the government and the Khmer Rouge, with the revolutionaries clearly gaining control of the country. The international embassies start evacuating their personnel. Sydney and Pran opt to remain, although Pran sends his wife and family away. As the Khmer Rouge revolutionaries enter the city, they're initially received with joy and prospects of peace, everyone tired of the war. Even Pran joins the festivities. However the Khmer Rouge, split in different factions due to internal power struggles, continue to fight in the capital. Sydney and Pran find refuge in the French embassy, until it's also evacuated and all Cambodians hiding there are turned over to the revolutionaries. For the time, the movie was quite revolutionary in casting a non-amateur actor in the role of Dith Pran. They found Haing Somnang Ngor, a doctor living in the USA, to portray Pran. Like Pran, Ngor had also spent four years in the killing fields before escaping. He won the Oscar for Best Supporting Actor in 1985 for this role. He played the role with naturalism and lightness, displaying a restraint in emotions in situations where an actor would typically go into melodramatic mode. The choice of Ngor is ahead of its time for another reason. Anglo-American movies tend to work on the logic that audiences can only care for the plight of foreign countries if the experiences are mediated through a character from their culture; that's why war correspondents are usually the main characters in such movies. Although now thanks to movies like Letters from Iwo Jima and Hotel Rwanda this is changing, casting a Cambodian actor to tell the story of a Cambodian prisoner of the Khmer Rouge was audacious then. Sam Waterston also delivers a powerful performance as Sydney, an authoritarian boss who blames himself for having used Pran to further his career only to abandon him. Back in New York he starts an international campaign to find his friend, always wondering whether he's doing enough for him. The movie is also helped with performances from John Malkovich and Julian Sands as two other journalists, Craig T. Nelson as the US Army officer in charge of the American evacuation, and Spalding Gray as the morally-torn American Consul, wary of abandoning the country to the revolutionaries. The scenes in the Killing Fields still have, decades later and after graphic violence has become generalised, the power to affect because of how the movie shows the psychological roots of the crimes. It's not that the images are excessively violent, it's that the movie depicts a philosophy of inhumanity. Regimes don't just producer horror for its own sake, the violence is just a tool to implement ideas. Rather than just showing the horrors, the movie shows the philosophy which the violence was used to enforce: the viewer is taken into the classrooms where children are being taught to hate the concept of family and any personal relationships that may threaten blind loyalty to the party; children are given power over life and death; intellectuals, teachers, journalists are executed for their skills; people are forbidden from growing crops, because that's a sign of free initiative, even though thousands are starving to death The movie confronts us with those ideas and we can't help but ask, "How the hell did anyone ever think these ideas could work in a society?" Not everything holds up as well in the movie. Many good scenes are ruined by Mike Oldfield's intrusive cacophony of synthesizer noises. Nowadays, when we listen to electronic scores with less patience than our ancestors did back in the '80s, a lot of this music sounds horrible. Oldfield, one of my favourite living musicians, is by no means an inept film composer, however: half the score, when he turns to traditional orchestration, is majestic. "Pran's Theme" and its variations are appropriately elegiac, and "Requim for a City," with its chorus of grieving voices, is a haunting attempt at showing through music the misery of the one million Cambodians forced by the Khmer Rouge to abandon the capital in a forced march to the countryside to work on the Killing Fields. Twenty-seven years later what the movie has to say about the darkness in the human soul, and the determination to overcome it, remains fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's nothing to forgive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    del91
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Joffe's "The Killing Fields" is a nerve-shredding full film of power and emotion. The facts that the film is not based, but an actual true story, coupled with the knowledge that star Haing S Ngor was an actual Khmer Rouge prisoner, makes it impossible to turn away from the screen. Sam Waterston's performance as the determined turned guilt-ridden reporter Sydney Schanberg is good, but the show belongs to Ngor whose compelling performance gives us not only a person we care about but also a realistic, real human being, thrown into horrible circumstances of outside causes. If anything Ngor's terrific performance can be the sole reason of this film's raw power and brutality. But there is more to watch in this human film. Mike Oldfield's great, suitable score which perfectly suits the action without getting too dramatic or too subtle. The stunning cinematography which shows the horrors of war amidst the beauty of Cambodia. Terrific production value showing atmospheric, realistic locations filled with thousands of extras, a feat reminding me of the days of David Lean, only less joyous and much more terrifying given the context. I cannot recommend this brilliant film enough. Actions speak louder than words, so go see this as soon as you can, and prepare to be moved immensely. The use of John Lennon's "Imagine" is perfectly suited. Overall rating: 91/100
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A historical drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bahadrkk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie takes us to 70s of Cambodia, let us know how vulnerable Cambodian government and US against Khmer Rouge, makes us witnesses of violence implemented by Khmer Rouge, we also can see two brave men, one of whom is Cambodian Dith Pran, how they are disciplined and workaholic even under these circumstances. Although Haing Ngor hadn't had acting experience before, he performed intermediate level of acting. All of the other actors performed well and did their business. Although we couldn't see a lot of battle scenes, there are a lot of scenes about the results of war actions; wounded people, dead people, captivated personal, and tortures. I would prefer to see more battle actions and would like to see them more effective in a war movie, but this movie is much a drama, drama of Cambodian people, and drama of a journalist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vale_krtal14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sydney Schanberg is a journalist in The New York Times, who was sent to Cambodia in 1972 as a correspondent of the war that was occurring there. When he arrives, he meets Dith Pran, a Cambodian photojournalist and refugee who survived the Cambodian Genocide. This man becomes Schaberg's guide and translator during the war. When trying to photograph the execution of two Khmer Rouge operatives, they are arrested and later learn that the press had reported a different version of the story. In 1975, people were being evacuated from the capital because of a possible invasion from the Khmer Rouge. Even though Pran's family is able to flee, he decided to stay and help Schanberg cover the story. After going through several situations, in which they get arrested again, Pran is turned over to the Khmer Rouge after they ask for every Cambodian citizen to be turned in. After months of searching for Pran, Schanberg begins to blame himself for Pran's situation. He wouldn't be trapped if it weren't for him. However, after several complications, Pran reaches a Red Cross camp in the border of Thailand. When he returns home to his family, he reunites with Schanberg who apologizes for everything. Pran forgives him and the movie ends. This movie was extraordinary. The acting, camera movements and the realism in the film captured everything necessary for the audience to be caught in the moment. It is credible, touching and it is poetically convincing. It doesn't have a traditional Hollywood structure, but as a human story, it is very well made. It captures a vivid image of how people's lives were during that period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marykate_nyland
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of the most influential films of the 20th century. Its provocative and dangerous subject matter stresses the importance of communication and the freedom to communicate. Based on the Khmer Rouge occupation and genocide of Cambodia in the 1970's, the film tells the story of two men, catapulted into chaos and peril. The movie is first and foremost, a historical account. The events are based off the true story of Dith Pran and Sydney Schanberg. Given that I had not known much about the Cambodian genocide of the 1970's prior to seeing this film, I must herald the piece as a successful feat of cinematography that served as both informational as well as inspirational. The film is believable, realistic, and heart wrenching. I immediately felt for the two main characters as they quickly exchanged trust and fell victim to the powers of political violence. While it is slightly romanticized, The Killing Fields still manages to produce a message with real life implications.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Nixon Doctrine in its purest form..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ironies abound in THE KILLING FIELDS. "Cambodia is the Nixon doctrine in its purest form," boasts one of the twentieth century's greatest war criminals (who himself lived a long and happy life, thereby putting the lie to any and all notions of karma). The Vietnam War, we're told, resulted in 3 million deaths (70-80% of all casualties were civilian). Does that total factor in the Cambodians who were murdered in the war's "aftermath?" (90% of all deaths in Iraq were civilian, by the way. Evidence has now come to light that the U.$. actually AIDED Saddam Hussein when he used chemical weapons against the Kurds in Iraq. That's right: the same government threatening to bomb Syria back into The Stone Age actually had an active part in the mass murder of Kurdish civilians. Or was it IRANIANS, during the Iran-Iraq War? "Six of one, half dozen of the other," U.$. politicos might say, but the distinction DOES matter, especially if you're Iranian or Kurdish... I may be wrong about the Kurdish murders, but I'm not going to change my comments until I see some paperwork showing otherwise. And there are 30,000 drones in the skies over the U.$., even as I write...) Another of the ironies is what happened to Haing S. Ngor (Dith Pran in THE KILLING FIELDS) after he came to the U.$.: having survived genocide in Cambodia, he was murdered here, in the street. Maybe THIS is the true Killing Field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachana Rom
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of those all too rare movies, a movie that challenges you to think about what you have just witnessed on screen, a movie that has the power to make you very aware that human tragedy and persecution are very much with us today. That said, the film concerns one man's triumph over unbelievable tragedy and adversity. The cinematography is first class, and the acting is all too believable. To appreciate the full enormity of this film I would strongly recommend reading up on the events with which the film is concerned. This film is hard to fault, and the ending with John Lennon's "Imagine" in the background is perfect and may well reduce you to tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkness of the soul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richard6
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the former French colony of Indochina, The Killing Fields centres on New York Times correspondent Sydney Schanberg, together with fellow journalistic aid and Cambodian national Dith Pran reporting on the military involvement of the United States in South East Asia in the early 1970s, Significantly, and the films main focal point, commentating on the latter stages of the Cambodian civil war. Due to the close proximity to Vietnam, and the United States wearisome involvement in the on-going communist and democratic conflicts in South East Asia, American foreign policy and public interest paid portentous attentiveness to the affairs of Cambodia. The film is introduced at the time of America's covert aerial bombardment of Eastern Cambodian military targets following the communist guerrillas refusal to adhere to the 1973 Paris Peace Treaty. Zealous journalist Schanberg is eager to and hindered from reporting to the American public the trepidation caused by the American bombing. Succeeding this introduction, the film moves intensely to the 1975 evacuation of foreign nationals from Phnom Penh during the seizing of power by the totalitarian communists Kampuchea before focusing on the consequent killing fields caused through social transformation and the year-zero policy. The film's final act, following a left behind Pran's escape from a national forced labour camp, is the eventual reuniting of the two journalist friends. From one stand point, British director Ronald Joffe does not shy away from exposing the human atrocities caused by armed conflict. Yet, Joffe does not over-embellish the horrors that inhabitant's encounter in a war-torn Country. Particularly, The Killing Fields centrepiece is the acts of humanity both moral, relationship between close friends, and immoral, the killing of innocent civilians and possible to a lesser extent, the unintentional minor selfish betrayal of Schanberg towards Pran. Rather than taking a more dramatic conventional route, the films interesting aspect is to view from a pragmatic everyday journalistic media approach. Also, interestingly The Killing Fields is one of a handful of English language films to call attention the violence, economics and political ideologies of twentieth-century revolutions. The horrors of the Khmer Rouge and the story told in The killing Fields draws parallels with events in the 1930's collectivisation of Ukrainian agriculture, the Nazi Holocaust of World War II and Mao's Great Leap Forward in the 1950's, all of which resulted in systematic extermination. Unfortunately I was unable to view the film in anamorphic widescreen 1.78:1 format. Although not as detailed, viewing the film in standard format did not eradicate the intensity of the film. As well as a story of friendship, The Killing Fields is an exceptional example of a former colonial countries dilemma when faced with dissimilar political ideologies following independence. Furthermore, the indescribable torment citizens' encounter in a brutal civil war and the mass suffering during the course of inhumane social experiments and the forced undemocratic reorganising of a society.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well Made, But Not Particularly Informative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although The Killing Fields has a reputation as the definitive work on the Khmer Rouge genocide, it is actually a rather shallow treatment of the topic. It does not give much insight into the motivations of the Khmer Rouge or of its own characters for that matter. The film follows journalist Sydney Schanberg and his Cambodian translator Dith Pran as they cover the fall of the Cambodian government. In his enthusiasm to cover the story, Schanberg decides to stay behind when the American Embassy evacuates. This results in Pran being stranded in Cambodia for the duration of the Khmer Rouge regime. The film works best when it focuses on the personal drama between Schanberg and Dith Pran. Sam Waterston gives a good performance as Schanberg, making us empathize with the character even when he acts like a self-indulgent jerk. Haing S. Ngor is excellent as Pran, earning his Oscar with a moving performance. However, the film does not give us any insight into the characters, particularly why Pran, who is clearly terrified, decides to stay behind with Schanberg. Their relationship, while compelling portrayed by the actors, is not explored in any depth, leading to unintentional homosexual overtones. More gallingly, the film does not really give any insight into the Khmer Rouge or why they carried out their atrocities. With Nazis and other more familiar historical villains, viewers will generally have a good sense of their ideologies and motivations. This is not necessarily the case with the Khmer Rouge. We do not really get a sense of who the Khmer Rouge are targeting or why? This is a particularly glaring omission as many younger Americans are only familiar with the Cambodian genocide from this movie. Furthermore, the film's general lack of on-screen violence results in a failure to convey the true horror of what took place. This flaw is acknowledged even by some involved in the film. As Haing Ngor reported in his autobiography, both he and Dith Pran thought the film's violence should be more graphic to convey the brutality of the Khmer Rouge. If you want a true sense of who the Khmer Rouge were, see the documentary S21: The Khmer Rouge Killing Machine, which goes into far greater detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Exceptional Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyejacker
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is an important film. It tells the story of two journalists혰one American and one Cambodian혰struggling to stay alive in war-torn Cambodia. Of course, it tells a bigger story too, namely the result of the bombing of Cambodia by the United States and subsequent atrocities committed by the Khmer Rouge: torture, slavery, brainwashing, increasingly indiscriminate murder on a mass scale. All very real and very terrible things. The film manages to tackle all of this heavy material without glossing anything over, (I'm looking at you Hotel Rwanda) and without making it so brutal as to be unwatchable. Unfortunately, the majority of the acting and dialogue in The Killing Fields isn't quite good enough to do the aforementioned atrocities justice. That is not to say these aspects of the film are bad, they're perfectly adequate. I just wish they were as flawless as some enraptured reviewers would have you believe. Ironically, (and perhaps even fittingly) it's the non-actor Cambodian children that give the most convincing, (and touching) performances in the movie. They may just be being themselves, but it lends the film an authenticity which few of the trained actors were able to capture with any consistency. The cinematography is spot on. Brilliantly balanced and flawlessly framed, it's practically symbolic in a few shots. Just beautiful. All of the filming appeared to be shot on site, in Cambodia and elsewhere, a practice that the majority of modern directors seem to have forgotten about, which is a shame since no amount of CGI or special effects are as convincing as the real place. The sets look 100% real, nothing looks staged. The music ranges from moving, to merely fitting, to downright strange and painfully 80's. Fortunately, there's more of the former than of the latter. With the exception of a few crude sound effects, The Killing Fields sounds quite good overall. While important, The Killing Fields is unlikely to ever be a very popular film. While it's technically a "war movie" (in part) it never glorifies violence, or tries to make it look cool. There's plenty of violence, of course, but it's more of the uncensored 6 o' clock news variety. Obviously, the film also draws attention to a very dark page from the United States past, and raises a lot of uncomfortable questions, which is bound to turn some people off. However, for anyone mature enough to handle its subject matter, and empathetic enough to explore the wide range of emotions covered in the film, The Killing Fields should really not be missed. 7.9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Gut-Wrenching History Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1975 the revolutionary group Khmer Rouge took over Cambodia and initiated a regime that reportedly claimed two million lives. At the time the Vietnam War was still going on, Cambodia was a strategic territory for the American army and the country was full of journalists. The basis of the movie's story comes from the lives of two of them: New York Times journalist Sydney Schanberg, and Dith Pran, Cambodian photojournalist and interpreter who coined the term "Killing Fields." Written by Bruce Robinson based on their writings, the movie follows in fact two stories: one is the fall of Phnom Penh, the capital, and the evacuation of the international embassies, as witnessed by Sydney and Pran, and Sydney's return to the USA; and the second, more radical narrative, shows the horrors of the Khmer Rouge as witnessed by Pran after he's captured and sent to work in a Killing Field, and his epic escape to freedom. From Phnom Penh Sydney and Pran report the events of the civil war between the government and the Khmer Rouge, with the revolutionaries clearly gaining control of the country. The international embassies start evacuating their personnel. Sydney and Pran opt to remain, although Pran sends his wife and family away. As the Khmer Rouge revolutionaries enter the city, they're initially received with joy and prospects of peace, everyone tired of the war. Even Pran joins the festivities. However the Khmer Rouge, split in different factions due to internal power struggles, continue to fight in the capital. Sydney and Pran find refuge in the French embassy, until it's also evacuated and all Cambodians hiding there are turned over to the revolutionaries. For the time, the movie was quite revolutionary in casting a non-amateur actor in the role of Dith Pran. They found Haing Somnang Ngor, a doctor living in the USA, to portray Pran. Like Pran, Ngor had also spent four years in the killing fields before escaping. He won the Oscar for Best Supporting Actor in 1985 for this role. He played the role with naturalism and lightness, displaying a restraint in emotions in situations where an actor would typically go into melodramatic mode. The choice of Ngor is ahead of its time for another reason. Anglo-American movies tend to work on the logic that audiences can only care for the plight of foreign countries if the experiences are mediated through a character from their culture; that's why war correspondents are usually the main characters in such movies. Although now thanks to movies like Letters from Iwo Jima and Hotel Rwanda this is changing, casting a Cambodian actor to tell the story of a Cambodian prisoner of the Khmer Rouge was audacious then. Sam Waterston also delivers a powerful performance as Sydney, an authoritarian boss who blames himself for having used Pran to further his career only to abandon him. Back in New York he starts an international campaign to find his friend, always wondering whether he's doing enough for him. The movie is also helped with performances from John Malkovich and Julian Sands as two other journalists, Craig T. Nelson as the US Army officer in charge of the American evacuation, and Spalding Gray as the morally-torn American Consul, wary of abandoning the country to the revolutionaries. The scenes in the Killing Fields still have, decades later and after graphic violence has become generalised, the power to affect because of how the movie shows the psychological roots of the crimes. It's not that the images are excessively violent, it's that the movie depicts a philosophy of inhumanity. Regimes don't just producer horror for its own sake, the violence is just a tool to implement ideas. Rather than just showing the horrors, the movie shows the philosophy which the violence was used to enforce: the viewer is taken into the classrooms where children are being taught to hate the concept of family and any personal relationships that may threaten blind loyalty to the party; children are given power over life and death; intellectuals, teachers, journalists are executed for their skills; people are forbidden from growing crops, because that's a sign of free initiative, even though thousands are starving to death The movie confronts us with those ideas and we can't help but ask, "How the hell did anyone ever think these ideas could work in a society?" Not everything holds up as well in the movie. Many good scenes are ruined by Mike Oldfield's intrusive cacophony of synthesizer noises. Nowadays, when we listen to electronic scores with less patience than our ancestors did back in the '80s, a lot of this music sounds horrible. Oldfield, one of my favourite living musicians, is by no means an inept film composer, however: half the score, when he turns to traditional orchestration, is majestic. "Pran's Theme" and its variations are appropriately elegiac, and "Requim for a City," with its chorus of grieving voices, is a haunting attempt at showing through music the misery of the one million Cambodians forced by the Khmer Rouge to abandon the capital in a forced march to the countryside to work on the Killing Fields. Twenty-seven years later what the movie has to say about the darkness in the human soul, and the determination to overcome it, remains fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's nothing to forgive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    del91
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Joffe's "The Killing Fields" is a nerve-shredding full film of power and emotion. The facts that the film is not based, but an actual true story, coupled with the knowledge that star Haing S Ngor was an actual Khmer Rouge prisoner, makes it impossible to turn away from the screen. Sam Waterston's performance as the determined turned guilt-ridden reporter Sydney Schanberg is good, but the show belongs to Ngor whose compelling performance gives us not only a person we care about but also a realistic, real human being, thrown into horrible circumstances of outside causes. If anything Ngor's terrific performance can be the sole reason of this film's raw power and brutality. But there is more to watch in this human film. Mike Oldfield's great, suitable score which perfectly suits the action without getting too dramatic or too subtle. The stunning cinematography which shows the horrors of war amidst the beauty of Cambodia. Terrific production value showing atmospheric, realistic locations filled with thousands of extras, a feat reminding me of the days of David Lean, only less joyous and much more terrifying given the context. I cannot recommend this brilliant film enough. Actions speak louder than words, so go see this as soon as you can, and prepare to be moved immensely. The use of John Lennon's "Imagine" is perfectly suited. Overall rating: 91/100
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A historical drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bahadrkk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie takes us to 70s of Cambodia, let us know how vulnerable Cambodian government and US against Khmer Rouge, makes us witnesses of violence implemented by Khmer Rouge, we also can see two brave men, one of whom is Cambodian Dith Pran, how they are disciplined and workaholic even under these circumstances. Although Haing Ngor hadn't had acting experience before, he performed intermediate level of acting. All of the other actors performed well and did their business. Although we couldn't see a lot of battle scenes, there are a lot of scenes about the results of war actions; wounded people, dead people, captivated personal, and tortures. I would prefer to see more battle actions and would like to see them more effective in a war movie, but this movie is much a drama, drama of Cambodian people, and drama of a journalist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vale_krtal14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sydney Schanberg is a journalist in The New York Times, who was sent to Cambodia in 1972 as a correspondent of the war that was occurring there. When he arrives, he meets Dith Pran, a Cambodian photojournalist and refugee who survived the Cambodian Genocide. This man becomes Schaberg's guide and translator during the war. When trying to photograph the execution of two Khmer Rouge operatives, they are arrested and later learn that the press had reported a different version of the story. In 1975, people were being evacuated from the capital because of a possible invasion from the Khmer Rouge. Even though Pran's family is able to flee, he decided to stay and help Schanberg cover the story. After going through several situations, in which they get arrested again, Pran is turned over to the Khmer Rouge after they ask for every Cambodian citizen to be turned in. After months of searching for Pran, Schanberg begins to blame himself for Pran's situation. He wouldn't be trapped if it weren't for him. However, after several complications, Pran reaches a Red Cross camp in the border of Thailand. When he returns home to his family, he reunites with Schanberg who apologizes for everything. Pran forgives him and the movie ends. This movie was extraordinary. The acting, camera movements and the realism in the film captured everything necessary for the audience to be caught in the moment. It is credible, touching and it is poetically convincing. It doesn't have a traditional Hollywood structure, but as a human story, it is very well made. It captures a vivid image of how people's lives were during that period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marykate_nyland
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of the most influential films of the 20th century. Its provocative and dangerous subject matter stresses the importance of communication and the freedom to communicate. Based on the Khmer Rouge occupation and genocide of Cambodia in the 1970's, the film tells the story of two men, catapulted into chaos and peril. The movie is first and foremost, a historical account. The events are based off the true story of Dith Pran and Sydney Schanberg. Given that I had not known much about the Cambodian genocide of the 1970's prior to seeing this film, I must herald the piece as a successful feat of cinematography that served as both informational as well as inspirational. The film is believable, realistic, and heart wrenching. I immediately felt for the two main characters as they quickly exchanged trust and fell victim to the powers of political violence. While it is slightly romanticized, The Killing Fields still manages to produce a message with real life implications.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Nixon Doctrine in its purest form..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ironies abound in THE KILLING FIELDS. "Cambodia is the Nixon doctrine in its purest form," boasts one of the twentieth century's greatest war criminals (who himself lived a long and happy life, thereby putting the lie to any and all notions of karma). The Vietnam War, we're told, resulted in 3 million deaths (70-80% of all casualties were civilian). Does that total factor in the Cambodians who were murdered in the war's "aftermath?" (90% of all deaths in Iraq were civilian, by the way. Evidence has now come to light that the U.$. actually AIDED Saddam Hussein when he used chemical weapons against the Kurds in Iraq. That's right: the same government threatening to bomb Syria back into The Stone Age actually had an active part in the mass murder of Kurdish civilians. Or was it IRANIANS, during the Iran-Iraq War? "Six of one, half dozen of the other," U.$. politicos might say, but the distinction DOES matter, especially if you're Iranian or Kurdish... I may be wrong about the Kurdish murders, but I'm not going to change my comments until I see some paperwork showing otherwise. And there are 30,000 drones in the skies over the U.$., even as I write...) Another of the ironies is what happened to Haing S. Ngor (Dith Pran in THE KILLING FIELDS) after he came to the U.$.: having survived genocide in Cambodia, he was murdered here, in the street. Maybe THIS is the true Killing Field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachana Rom
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of those all too rare movies, a movie that challenges you to think about what you have just witnessed on screen, a movie that has the power to make you very aware that human tragedy and persecution are very much with us today. That said, the film concerns one man's triumph over unbelievable tragedy and adversity. The cinematography is first class, and the acting is all too believable. To appreciate the full enormity of this film I would strongly recommend reading up on the events with which the film is concerned. This film is hard to fault, and the ending with John Lennon's "Imagine" in the background is perfect and may well reduce you to tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkness of the soul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richard6
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the former French colony of Indochina, The Killing Fields centres on New York Times correspondent Sydney Schanberg, together with fellow journalistic aid and Cambodian national Dith Pran reporting on the military involvement of the United States in South East Asia in the early 1970s, Significantly, and the films main focal point, commentating on the latter stages of the Cambodian civil war. Due to the close proximity to Vietnam, and the United States wearisome involvement in the on-going communist and democratic conflicts in South East Asia, American foreign policy and public interest paid portentous attentiveness to the affairs of Cambodia. The film is introduced at the time of America's covert aerial bombardment of Eastern Cambodian military targets following the communist guerrillas refusal to adhere to the 1973 Paris Peace Treaty. Zealous journalist Schanberg is eager to and hindered from reporting to the American public the trepidation caused by the American bombing. Succeeding this introduction, the film moves intensely to the 1975 evacuation of foreign nationals from Phnom Penh during the seizing of power by the totalitarian communists Kampuchea before focusing on the consequent killing fields caused through social transformation and the year-zero policy. The film's final act, following a left behind Pran's escape from a national forced labour camp, is the eventual reuniting of the two journalist friends. From one stand point, British director Ronald Joffe does not shy away from exposing the human atrocities caused by armed conflict. Yet, Joffe does not over-embellish the horrors that inhabitant's encounter in a war-torn Country. Particularly, The Killing Fields centrepiece is the acts of humanity both moral, relationship between close friends, and immoral, the killing of innocent civilians and possible to a lesser extent, the unintentional minor selfish betrayal of Schanberg towards Pran. Rather than taking a more dramatic conventional route, the films interesting aspect is to view from a pragmatic everyday journalistic media approach. Also, interestingly The Killing Fields is one of a handful of English language films to call attention the violence, economics and political ideologies of twentieth-century revolutions. The horrors of the Khmer Rouge and the story told in The killing Fields draws parallels with events in the 1930's collectivisation of Ukrainian agriculture, the Nazi Holocaust of World War II and Mao's Great Leap Forward in the 1950's, all of which resulted in systematic extermination. Unfortunately I was unable to view the film in anamorphic widescreen 1.78:1 format. Although not as detailed, viewing the film in standard format did not eradicate the intensity of the film. As well as a story of friendship, The Killing Fields is an exceptional example of a former colonial countries dilemma when faced with dissimilar political ideologies following independence. Furthermore, the indescribable torment citizens' encounter in a brutal civil war and the mass suffering during the course of inhumane social experiments and the forced undemocratic reorganising of a society.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well Made, But Not Particularly Informative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although The Killing Fields has a reputation as the definitive work on the Khmer Rouge genocide, it is actually a rather shallow treatment of the topic. It does not give much insight into the motivations of the Khmer Rouge or of its own characters for that matter. The film follows journalist Sydney Schanberg and his Cambodian translator Dith Pran as they cover the fall of the Cambodian government. In his enthusiasm to cover the story, Schanberg decides to stay behind when the American Embassy evacuates. This results in Pran being stranded in Cambodia for the duration of the Khmer Rouge regime. The film works best when it focuses on the personal drama between Schanberg and Dith Pran. Sam Waterston gives a good performance as Schanberg, making us empathize with the character even when he acts like a self-indulgent jerk. Haing S. Ngor is excellent as Pran, earning his Oscar with a moving performance. However, the film does not give us any insight into the characters, particularly why Pran, who is clearly terrified, decides to stay behind with Schanberg. Their relationship, while compelling portrayed by the actors, is not explored in any depth, leading to unintentional homosexual overtones. More gallingly, the film does not really give any insight into the Khmer Rouge or why they carried out their atrocities. With Nazis and other more familiar historical villains, viewers will generally have a good sense of their ideologies and motivations. This is not necessarily the case with the Khmer Rouge. We do not really get a sense of who the Khmer Rouge are targeting or why? This is a particularly glaring omission as many younger Americans are only familiar with the Cambodian genocide from this movie. Furthermore, the film's general lack of on-screen violence results in a failure to convey the true horror of what took place. This flaw is acknowledged even by some involved in the film. As Haing Ngor reported in his autobiography, both he and Dith Pran thought the film's violence should be more graphic to convey the brutality of the Khmer Rouge. If you want a true sense of who the Khmer Rouge were, see the documentary S21: The Khmer Rouge Killing Machine, which goes into far greater detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Exceptional Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyejacker
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is an important film. It tells the story of two journalists혰one American and one Cambodian혰struggling to stay alive in war-torn Cambodia. Of course, it tells a bigger story too, namely the result of the bombing of Cambodia by the United States and subsequent atrocities committed by the Khmer Rouge: torture, slavery, brainwashing, increasingly indiscriminate murder on a mass scale. All very real and very terrible things. The film manages to tackle all of this heavy material without glossing anything over, (I'm looking at you Hotel Rwanda) and without making it so brutal as to be unwatchable. Unfortunately, the majority of the acting and dialogue in The Killing Fields isn't quite good enough to do the aforementioned atrocities justice. That is not to say these aspects of the film are bad, they're perfectly adequate. I just wish they were as flawless as some enraptured reviewers would have you believe. Ironically, (and perhaps even fittingly) it's the non-actor Cambodian children that give the most convincing, (and touching) performances in the movie. They may just be being themselves, but it lends the film an authenticity which few of the trained actors were able to capture with any consistency. The cinematography is spot on. Brilliantly balanced and flawlessly framed, it's practically symbolic in a few shots. Just beautiful. All of the filming appeared to be shot on site, in Cambodia and elsewhere, a practice that the majority of modern directors seem to have forgotten about, which is a shame since no amount of CGI or special effects are as convincing as the real place. The sets look 100% real, nothing looks staged. The music ranges from moving, to merely fitting, to downright strange and painfully 80's. Fortunately, there's more of the former than of the latter. With the exception of a few crude sound effects, The Killing Fields sounds quite good overall. While important, The Killing Fields is unlikely to ever be a very popular film. While it's technically a "war movie" (in part) it never glorifies violence, or tries to make it look cool. There's plenty of violence, of course, but it's more of the uncensored 6 o' clock news variety. Obviously, the film also draws attention to a very dark page from the United States past, and raises a lot of uncomfortable questions, which is bound to turn some people off. However, for anyone mature enough to handle its subject matter, and empathetic enough to explore the wide range of emotions covered in the film, The Killing Fields should really not be missed. 7.9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Gut-Wrenching History Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1975 the revolutionary group Khmer Rouge took over Cambodia and initiated a regime that reportedly claimed two million lives. At the time the Vietnam War was still going on, Cambodia was a strategic territory for the American army and the country was full of journalists. The basis of the movie's story comes from the lives of two of them: New York Times journalist Sydney Schanberg, and Dith Pran, Cambodian photojournalist and interpreter who coined the term "Killing Fields." Written by Bruce Robinson based on their writings, the movie follows in fact two stories: one is the fall of Phnom Penh, the capital, and the evacuation of the international embassies, as witnessed by Sydney and Pran, and Sydney's return to the USA; and the second, more radical narrative, shows the horrors of the Khmer Rouge as witnessed by Pran after he's captured and sent to work in a Killing Field, and his epic escape to freedom. From Phnom Penh Sydney and Pran report the events of the civil war between the government and the Khmer Rouge, with the revolutionaries clearly gaining control of the country. The international embassies start evacuating their personnel. Sydney and Pran opt to remain, although Pran sends his wife and family away. As the Khmer Rouge revolutionaries enter the city, they're initially received with joy and prospects of peace, everyone tired of the war. Even Pran joins the festivities. However the Khmer Rouge, split in different factions due to internal power struggles, continue to fight in the capital. Sydney and Pran find refuge in the French embassy, until it's also evacuated and all Cambodians hiding there are turned over to the revolutionaries. For the time, the movie was quite revolutionary in casting a non-amateur actor in the role of Dith Pran. They found Haing Somnang Ngor, a doctor living in the USA, to portray Pran. Like Pran, Ngor had also spent four years in the killing fields before escaping. He won the Oscar for Best Supporting Actor in 1985 for this role. He played the role with naturalism and lightness, displaying a restraint in emotions in situations where an actor would typically go into melodramatic mode. The choice of Ngor is ahead of its time for another reason. Anglo-American movies tend to work on the logic that audiences can only care for the plight of foreign countries if the experiences are mediated through a character from their culture; that's why war correspondents are usually the main characters in such movies. Although now thanks to movies like Letters from Iwo Jima and Hotel Rwanda this is changing, casting a Cambodian actor to tell the story of a Cambodian prisoner of the Khmer Rouge was audacious then. Sam Waterston also delivers a powerful performance as Sydney, an authoritarian boss who blames himself for having used Pran to further his career only to abandon him. Back in New York he starts an international campaign to find his friend, always wondering whether he's doing enough for him. The movie is also helped with performances from John Malkovich and Julian Sands as two other journalists, Craig T. Nelson as the US Army officer in charge of the American evacuation, and Spalding Gray as the morally-torn American Consul, wary of abandoning the country to the revolutionaries. The scenes in the Killing Fields still have, decades later and after graphic violence has become generalised, the power to affect because of how the movie shows the psychological roots of the crimes. It's not that the images are excessively violent, it's that the movie depicts a philosophy of inhumanity. Regimes don't just producer horror for its own sake, the violence is just a tool to implement ideas. Rather than just showing the horrors, the movie shows the philosophy which the violence was used to enforce: the viewer is taken into the classrooms where children are being taught to hate the concept of family and any personal relationships that may threaten blind loyalty to the party; children are given power over life and death; intellectuals, teachers, journalists are executed for their skills; people are forbidden from growing crops, because that's a sign of free initiative, even though thousands are starving to death The movie confronts us with those ideas and we can't help but ask, "How the hell did anyone ever think these ideas could work in a society?" Not everything holds up as well in the movie. Many good scenes are ruined by Mike Oldfield's intrusive cacophony of synthesizer noises. Nowadays, when we listen to electronic scores with less patience than our ancestors did back in the '80s, a lot of this music sounds horrible. Oldfield, one of my favourite living musicians, is by no means an inept film composer, however: half the score, when he turns to traditional orchestration, is majestic. "Pran's Theme" and its variations are appropriately elegiac, and "Requim for a City," with its chorus of grieving voices, is a haunting attempt at showing through music the misery of the one million Cambodians forced by the Khmer Rouge to abandon the capital in a forced march to the countryside to work on the Killing Fields. Twenty-seven years later what the movie has to say about the darkness in the human soul, and the determination to overcome it, remains fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's nothing to forgive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    del91
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Joffe's "The Killing Fields" is a nerve-shredding full film of power and emotion. The facts that the film is not based, but an actual true story, coupled with the knowledge that star Haing S Ngor was an actual Khmer Rouge prisoner, makes it impossible to turn away from the screen. Sam Waterston's performance as the determined turned guilt-ridden reporter Sydney Schanberg is good, but the show belongs to Ngor whose compelling performance gives us not only a person we care about but also a realistic, real human being, thrown into horrible circumstances of outside causes. If anything Ngor's terrific performance can be the sole reason of this film's raw power and brutality. But there is more to watch in this human film. Mike Oldfield's great, suitable score which perfectly suits the action without getting too dramatic or too subtle. The stunning cinematography which shows the horrors of war amidst the beauty of Cambodia. Terrific production value showing atmospheric, realistic locations filled with thousands of extras, a feat reminding me of the days of David Lean, only less joyous and much more terrifying given the context. I cannot recommend this brilliant film enough. Actions speak louder than words, so go see this as soon as you can, and prepare to be moved immensely. The use of John Lennon's "Imagine" is perfectly suited. Overall rating: 91/100
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A historical drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bahadrkk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie takes us to 70s of Cambodia, let us know how vulnerable Cambodian government and US against Khmer Rouge, makes us witnesses of violence implemented by Khmer Rouge, we also can see two brave men, one of whom is Cambodian Dith Pran, how they are disciplined and workaholic even under these circumstances. Although Haing Ngor hadn't had acting experience before, he performed intermediate level of acting. All of the other actors performed well and did their business. Although we couldn't see a lot of battle scenes, there are a lot of scenes about the results of war actions; wounded people, dead people, captivated personal, and tortures. I would prefer to see more battle actions and would like to see them more effective in a war movie, but this movie is much a drama, drama of Cambodian people, and drama of a journalist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vale_krtal14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sydney Schanberg is a journalist in The New York Times, who was sent to Cambodia in 1972 as a correspondent of the war that was occurring there. When he arrives, he meets Dith Pran, a Cambodian photojournalist and refugee who survived the Cambodian Genocide. This man becomes Schaberg's guide and translator during the war. When trying to photograph the execution of two Khmer Rouge operatives, they are arrested and later learn that the press had reported a different version of the story. In 1975, people were being evacuated from the capital because of a possible invasion from the Khmer Rouge. Even though Pran's family is able to flee, he decided to stay and help Schanberg cover the story. After going through several situations, in which they get arrested again, Pran is turned over to the Khmer Rouge after they ask for every Cambodian citizen to be turned in. After months of searching for Pran, Schanberg begins to blame himself for Pran's situation. He wouldn't be trapped if it weren't for him. However, after several complications, Pran reaches a Red Cross camp in the border of Thailand. When he returns home to his family, he reunites with Schanberg who apologizes for everything. Pran forgives him and the movie ends. This movie was extraordinary. The acting, camera movements and the realism in the film captured everything necessary for the audience to be caught in the moment. It is credible, touching and it is poetically convincing. It doesn't have a traditional Hollywood structure, but as a human story, it is very well made. It captures a vivid image of how people's lives were during that period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marykate_nyland
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of the most influential films of the 20th century. Its provocative and dangerous subject matter stresses the importance of communication and the freedom to communicate. Based on the Khmer Rouge occupation and genocide of Cambodia in the 1970's, the film tells the story of two men, catapulted into chaos and peril. The movie is first and foremost, a historical account. The events are based off the true story of Dith Pran and Sydney Schanberg. Given that I had not known much about the Cambodian genocide of the 1970's prior to seeing this film, I must herald the piece as a successful feat of cinematography that served as both informational as well as inspirational. The film is believable, realistic, and heart wrenching. I immediately felt for the two main characters as they quickly exchanged trust and fell victim to the powers of political violence. While it is slightly romanticized, The Killing Fields still manages to produce a message with real life implications.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Nixon Doctrine in its purest form..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ironies abound in THE KILLING FIELDS. "Cambodia is the Nixon doctrine in its purest form," boasts one of the twentieth century's greatest war criminals (who himself lived a long and happy life, thereby putting the lie to any and all notions of karma). The Vietnam War, we're told, resulted in 3 million deaths (70-80% of all casualties were civilian). Does that total factor in the Cambodians who were murdered in the war's "aftermath?" (90% of all deaths in Iraq were civilian, by the way. Evidence has now come to light that the U.$. actually AIDED Saddam Hussein when he used chemical weapons against the Kurds in Iraq. That's right: the same government threatening to bomb Syria back into The Stone Age actually had an active part in the mass murder of Kurdish civilians. Or was it IRANIANS, during the Iran-Iraq War? "Six of one, half dozen of the other," U.$. politicos might say, but the distinction DOES matter, especially if you're Iranian or Kurdish... I may be wrong about the Kurdish murders, but I'm not going to change my comments until I see some paperwork showing otherwise. And there are 30,000 drones in the skies over the U.$., even as I write...) Another of the ironies is what happened to Haing S. Ngor (Dith Pran in THE KILLING FIELDS) after he came to the U.$.: having survived genocide in Cambodia, he was murdered here, in the street. Maybe THIS is the true Killing Field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachana Rom
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of those all too rare movies, a movie that challenges you to think about what you have just witnessed on screen, a movie that has the power to make you very aware that human tragedy and persecution are very much with us today. That said, the film concerns one man's triumph over unbelievable tragedy and adversity. The cinematography is first class, and the acting is all too believable. To appreciate the full enormity of this film I would strongly recommend reading up on the events with which the film is concerned. This film is hard to fault, and the ending with John Lennon's "Imagine" in the background is perfect and may well reduce you to tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkness of the soul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richard6
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the former French colony of Indochina, The Killing Fields centres on New York Times correspondent Sydney Schanberg, together with fellow journalistic aid and Cambodian national Dith Pran reporting on the military involvement of the United States in South East Asia in the early 1970s, Significantly, and the films main focal point, commentating on the latter stages of the Cambodian civil war. Due to the close proximity to Vietnam, and the United States wearisome involvement in the on-going communist and democratic conflicts in South East Asia, American foreign policy and public interest paid portentous attentiveness to the affairs of Cambodia. The film is introduced at the time of America's covert aerial bombardment of Eastern Cambodian military targets following the communist guerrillas refusal to adhere to the 1973 Paris Peace Treaty. Zealous journalist Schanberg is eager to and hindered from reporting to the American public the trepidation caused by the American bombing. Succeeding this introduction, the film moves intensely to the 1975 evacuation of foreign nationals from Phnom Penh during the seizing of power by the totalitarian communists Kampuchea before focusing on the consequent killing fields caused through social transformation and the year-zero policy. The film's final act, following a left behind Pran's escape from a national forced labour camp, is the eventual reuniting of the two journalist friends. From one stand point, British director Ronald Joffe does not shy away from exposing the human atrocities caused by armed conflict. Yet, Joffe does not over-embellish the horrors that inhabitant's encounter in a war-torn Country. Particularly, The Killing Fields centrepiece is the acts of humanity both moral, relationship between close friends, and immoral, the killing of innocent civilians and possible to a lesser extent, the unintentional minor selfish betrayal of Schanberg towards Pran. Rather than taking a more dramatic conventional route, the films interesting aspect is to view from a pragmatic everyday journalistic media approach. Also, interestingly The Killing Fields is one of a handful of English language films to call attention the violence, economics and political ideologies of twentieth-century revolutions. The horrors of the Khmer Rouge and the story told in The killing Fields draws parallels with events in the 1930's collectivisation of Ukrainian agriculture, the Nazi Holocaust of World War II and Mao's Great Leap Forward in the 1950's, all of which resulted in systematic extermination. Unfortunately I was unable to view the film in anamorphic widescreen 1.78:1 format. Although not as detailed, viewing the film in standard format did not eradicate the intensity of the film. As well as a story of friendship, The Killing Fields is an exceptional example of a former colonial countries dilemma when faced with dissimilar political ideologies following independence. Furthermore, the indescribable torment citizens' encounter in a brutal civil war and the mass suffering during the course of inhumane social experiments and the forced undemocratic reorganising of a society.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well Made, But Not Particularly Informative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although The Killing Fields has a reputation as the definitive work on the Khmer Rouge genocide, it is actually a rather shallow treatment of the topic. It does not give much insight into the motivations of the Khmer Rouge or of its own characters for that matter. The film follows journalist Sydney Schanberg and his Cambodian translator Dith Pran as they cover the fall of the Cambodian government. In his enthusiasm to cover the story, Schanberg decides to stay behind when the American Embassy evacuates. This results in Pran being stranded in Cambodia for the duration of the Khmer Rouge regime. The film works best when it focuses on the personal drama between Schanberg and Dith Pran. Sam Waterston gives a good performance as Schanberg, making us empathize with the character even when he acts like a self-indulgent jerk. Haing S. Ngor is excellent as Pran, earning his Oscar with a moving performance. However, the film does not give us any insight into the characters, particularly why Pran, who is clearly terrified, decides to stay behind with Schanberg. Their relationship, while compelling portrayed by the actors, is not explored in any depth, leading to unintentional homosexual overtones. More gallingly, the film does not really give any insight into the Khmer Rouge or why they carried out their atrocities. With Nazis and other more familiar historical villains, viewers will generally have a good sense of their ideologies and motivations. This is not necessarily the case with the Khmer Rouge. We do not really get a sense of who the Khmer Rouge are targeting or why? This is a particularly glaring omission as many younger Americans are only familiar with the Cambodian genocide from this movie. Furthermore, the film's general lack of on-screen violence results in a failure to convey the true horror of what took place. This flaw is acknowledged even by some involved in the film. As Haing Ngor reported in his autobiography, both he and Dith Pran thought the film's violence should be more graphic to convey the brutality of the Khmer Rouge. If you want a true sense of who the Khmer Rouge were, see the documentary S21: The Khmer Rouge Killing Machine, which goes into far greater detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Exceptional Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyejacker
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is an important film. It tells the story of two journalists혰one American and one Cambodian혰struggling to stay alive in war-torn Cambodia. Of course, it tells a bigger story too, namely the result of the bombing of Cambodia by the United States and subsequent atrocities committed by the Khmer Rouge: torture, slavery, brainwashing, increasingly indiscriminate murder on a mass scale. All very real and very terrible things. The film manages to tackle all of this heavy material without glossing anything over, (I'm looking at you Hotel Rwanda) and without making it so brutal as to be unwatchable. Unfortunately, the majority of the acting and dialogue in The Killing Fields isn't quite good enough to do the aforementioned atrocities justice. That is not to say these aspects of the film are bad, they're perfectly adequate. I just wish they were as flawless as some enraptured reviewers would have you believe. Ironically, (and perhaps even fittingly) it's the non-actor Cambodian children that give the most convincing, (and touching) performances in the movie. They may just be being themselves, but it lends the film an authenticity which few of the trained actors were able to capture with any consistency. The cinematography is spot on. Brilliantly balanced and flawlessly framed, it's practically symbolic in a few shots. Just beautiful. All of the filming appeared to be shot on site, in Cambodia and elsewhere, a practice that the majority of modern directors seem to have forgotten about, which is a shame since no amount of CGI or special effects are as convincing as the real place. The sets look 100% real, nothing looks staged. The music ranges from moving, to merely fitting, to downright strange and painfully 80's. Fortunately, there's more of the former than of the latter. With the exception of a few crude sound effects, The Killing Fields sounds quite good overall. While important, The Killing Fields is unlikely to ever be a very popular film. While it's technically a "war movie" (in part) it never glorifies violence, or tries to make it look cool. There's plenty of violence, of course, but it's more of the uncensored 6 o' clock news variety. Obviously, the film also draws attention to a very dark page from the United States past, and raises a lot of uncomfortable questions, which is bound to turn some people off. However, for anyone mature enough to handle its subject matter, and empathetic enough to explore the wide range of emotions covered in the film, The Killing Fields should really not be missed. 7.9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Gut-Wrenching History Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1975 the revolutionary group Khmer Rouge took over Cambodia and initiated a regime that reportedly claimed two million lives. At the time the Vietnam War was still going on, Cambodia was a strategic territory for the American army and the country was full of journalists. The basis of the movie's story comes from the lives of two of them: New York Times journalist Sydney Schanberg, and Dith Pran, Cambodian photojournalist and interpreter who coined the term "Killing Fields." Written by Bruce Robinson based on their writings, the movie follows in fact two stories: one is the fall of Phnom Penh, the capital, and the evacuation of the international embassies, as witnessed by Sydney and Pran, and Sydney's return to the USA; and the second, more radical narrative, shows the horrors of the Khmer Rouge as witnessed by Pran after he's captured and sent to work in a Killing Field, and his epic escape to freedom. From Phnom Penh Sydney and Pran report the events of the civil war between the government and the Khmer Rouge, with the revolutionaries clearly gaining control of the country. The international embassies start evacuating their personnel. Sydney and Pran opt to remain, although Pran sends his wife and family away. As the Khmer Rouge revolutionaries enter the city, they're initially received with joy and prospects of peace, everyone tired of the war. Even Pran joins the festivities. However the Khmer Rouge, split in different factions due to internal power struggles, continue to fight in the capital. Sydney and Pran find refuge in the French embassy, until it's also evacuated and all Cambodians hiding there are turned over to the revolutionaries. For the time, the movie was quite revolutionary in casting a non-amateur actor in the role of Dith Pran. They found Haing Somnang Ngor, a doctor living in the USA, to portray Pran. Like Pran, Ngor had also spent four years in the killing fields before escaping. He won the Oscar for Best Supporting Actor in 1985 for this role. He played the role with naturalism and lightness, displaying a restraint in emotions in situations where an actor would typically go into melodramatic mode. The choice of Ngor is ahead of its time for another reason. Anglo-American movies tend to work on the logic that audiences can only care for the plight of foreign countries if the experiences are mediated through a character from their culture; that's why war correspondents are usually the main characters in such movies. Although now thanks to movies like Letters from Iwo Jima and Hotel Rwanda this is changing, casting a Cambodian actor to tell the story of a Cambodian prisoner of the Khmer Rouge was audacious then. Sam Waterston also delivers a powerful performance as Sydney, an authoritarian boss who blames himself for having used Pran to further his career only to abandon him. Back in New York he starts an international campaign to find his friend, always wondering whether he's doing enough for him. The movie is also helped with performances from John Malkovich and Julian Sands as two other journalists, Craig T. Nelson as the US Army officer in charge of the American evacuation, and Spalding Gray as the morally-torn American Consul, wary of abandoning the country to the revolutionaries. The scenes in the Killing Fields still have, decades later and after graphic violence has become generalised, the power to affect because of how the movie shows the psychological roots of the crimes. It's not that the images are excessively violent, it's that the movie depicts a philosophy of inhumanity. Regimes don't just producer horror for its own sake, the violence is just a tool to implement ideas. Rather than just showing the horrors, the movie shows the philosophy which the violence was used to enforce: the viewer is taken into the classrooms where children are being taught to hate the concept of family and any personal relationships that may threaten blind loyalty to the party; children are given power over life and death; intellectuals, teachers, journalists are executed for their skills; people are forbidden from growing crops, because that's a sign of free initiative, even though thousands are starving to death The movie confronts us with those ideas and we can't help but ask, "How the hell did anyone ever think these ideas could work in a society?" Not everything holds up as well in the movie. Many good scenes are ruined by Mike Oldfield's intrusive cacophony of synthesizer noises. Nowadays, when we listen to electronic scores with less patience than our ancestors did back in the '80s, a lot of this music sounds horrible. Oldfield, one of my favourite living musicians, is by no means an inept film composer, however: half the score, when he turns to traditional orchestration, is majestic. "Pran's Theme" and its variations are appropriately elegiac, and "Requim for a City," with its chorus of grieving voices, is a haunting attempt at showing through music the misery of the one million Cambodians forced by the Khmer Rouge to abandon the capital in a forced march to the countryside to work on the Killing Fields. Twenty-seven years later what the movie has to say about the darkness in the human soul, and the determination to overcome it, remains fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's nothing to forgive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    del91
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Joffe's "The Killing Fields" is a nerve-shredding full film of power and emotion. The facts that the film is not based, but an actual true story, coupled with the knowledge that star Haing S Ngor was an actual Khmer Rouge prisoner, makes it impossible to turn away from the screen. Sam Waterston's performance as the determined turned guilt-ridden reporter Sydney Schanberg is good, but the show belongs to Ngor whose compelling performance gives us not only a person we care about but also a realistic, real human being, thrown into horrible circumstances of outside causes. If anything Ngor's terrific performance can be the sole reason of this film's raw power and brutality. But there is more to watch in this human film. Mike Oldfield's great, suitable score which perfectly suits the action without getting too dramatic or too subtle. The stunning cinematography which shows the horrors of war amidst the beauty of Cambodia. Terrific production value showing atmospheric, realistic locations filled with thousands of extras, a feat reminding me of the days of David Lean, only less joyous and much more terrifying given the context. I cannot recommend this brilliant film enough. Actions speak louder than words, so go see this as soon as you can, and prepare to be moved immensely. The use of John Lennon's "Imagine" is perfectly suited. Overall rating: 91/100
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A historical drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bahadrkk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie takes us to 70s of Cambodia, let us know how vulnerable Cambodian government and US against Khmer Rouge, makes us witnesses of violence implemented by Khmer Rouge, we also can see two brave men, one of whom is Cambodian Dith Pran, how they are disciplined and workaholic even under these circumstances. Although Haing Ngor hadn't had acting experience before, he performed intermediate level of acting. All of the other actors performed well and did their business. Although we couldn't see a lot of battle scenes, there are a lot of scenes about the results of war actions; wounded people, dead people, captivated personal, and tortures. I would prefer to see more battle actions and would like to see them more effective in a war movie, but this movie is much a drama, drama of Cambodian people, and drama of a journalist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vale_krtal14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sydney Schanberg is a journalist in The New York Times, who was sent to Cambodia in 1972 as a correspondent of the war that was occurring there. When he arrives, he meets Dith Pran, a Cambodian photojournalist and refugee who survived the Cambodian Genocide. This man becomes Schaberg's guide and translator during the war. When trying to photograph the execution of two Khmer Rouge operatives, they are arrested and later learn that the press had reported a different version of the story. In 1975, people were being evacuated from the capital because of a possible invasion from the Khmer Rouge. Even though Pran's family is able to flee, he decided to stay and help Schanberg cover the story. After going through several situations, in which they get arrested again, Pran is turned over to the Khmer Rouge after they ask for every Cambodian citizen to be turned in. After months of searching for Pran, Schanberg begins to blame himself for Pran's situation. He wouldn't be trapped if it weren't for him. However, after several complications, Pran reaches a Red Cross camp in the border of Thailand. When he returns home to his family, he reunites with Schanberg who apologizes for everything. Pran forgives him and the movie ends. This movie was extraordinary. The acting, camera movements and the realism in the film captured everything necessary for the audience to be caught in the moment. It is credible, touching and it is poetically convincing. It doesn't have a traditional Hollywood structure, but as a human story, it is very well made. It captures a vivid image of how people's lives were during that period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marykate_nyland
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of the most influential films of the 20th century. Its provocative and dangerous subject matter stresses the importance of communication and the freedom to communicate. Based on the Khmer Rouge occupation and genocide of Cambodia in the 1970's, the film tells the story of two men, catapulted into chaos and peril. The movie is first and foremost, a historical account. The events are based off the true story of Dith Pran and Sydney Schanberg. Given that I had not known much about the Cambodian genocide of the 1970's prior to seeing this film, I must herald the piece as a successful feat of cinematography that served as both informational as well as inspirational. The film is believable, realistic, and heart wrenching. I immediately felt for the two main characters as they quickly exchanged trust and fell victim to the powers of political violence. While it is slightly romanticized, The Killing Fields still manages to produce a message with real life implications.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Nixon Doctrine in its purest form..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ironies abound in THE KILLING FIELDS. "Cambodia is the Nixon doctrine in its purest form," boasts one of the twentieth century's greatest war criminals (who himself lived a long and happy life, thereby putting the lie to any and all notions of karma). The Vietnam War, we're told, resulted in 3 million deaths (70-80% of all casualties were civilian). Does that total factor in the Cambodians who were murdered in the war's "aftermath?" (90% of all deaths in Iraq were civilian, by the way. Evidence has now come to light that the U.$. actually AIDED Saddam Hussein when he used chemical weapons against the Kurds in Iraq. That's right: the same government threatening to bomb Syria back into The Stone Age actually had an active part in the mass murder of Kurdish civilians. Or was it IRANIANS, during the Iran-Iraq War? "Six of one, half dozen of the other," U.$. politicos might say, but the distinction DOES matter, especially if you're Iranian or Kurdish... I may be wrong about the Kurdish murders, but I'm not going to change my comments until I see some paperwork showing otherwise. And there are 30,000 drones in the skies over the U.$., even as I write...) Another of the ironies is what happened to Haing S. Ngor (Dith Pran in THE KILLING FIELDS) after he came to the U.$.: having survived genocide in Cambodia, he was murdered here, in the street. Maybe THIS is the true Killing Field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachana Rom
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of those all too rare movies, a movie that challenges you to think about what you have just witnessed on screen, a movie that has the power to make you very aware that human tragedy and persecution are very much with us today. That said, the film concerns one man's triumph over unbelievable tragedy and adversity. The cinematography is first class, and the acting is all too believable. To appreciate the full enormity of this film I would strongly recommend reading up on the events with which the film is concerned. This film is hard to fault, and the ending with John Lennon's "Imagine" in the background is perfect and may well reduce you to tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkness of the soul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richard6
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the former French colony of Indochina, The Killing Fields centres on New York Times correspondent Sydney Schanberg, together with fellow journalistic aid and Cambodian national Dith Pran reporting on the military involvement of the United States in South East Asia in the early 1970s, Significantly, and the films main focal point, commentating on the latter stages of the Cambodian civil war. Due to the close proximity to Vietnam, and the United States wearisome involvement in the on-going communist and democratic conflicts in South East Asia, American foreign policy and public interest paid portentous attentiveness to the affairs of Cambodia. The film is introduced at the time of America's covert aerial bombardment of Eastern Cambodian military targets following the communist guerrillas refusal to adhere to the 1973 Paris Peace Treaty. Zealous journalist Schanberg is eager to and hindered from reporting to the American public the trepidation caused by the American bombing. Succeeding this introduction, the film moves intensely to the 1975 evacuation of foreign nationals from Phnom Penh during the seizing of power by the totalitarian communists Kampuchea before focusing on the consequent killing fields caused through social transformation and the year-zero policy. The film's final act, following a left behind Pran's escape from a national forced labour camp, is the eventual reuniting of the two journalist friends. From one stand point, British director Ronald Joffe does not shy away from exposing the human atrocities caused by armed conflict. Yet, Joffe does not over-embellish the horrors that inhabitant's encounter in a war-torn Country. Particularly, The Killing Fields centrepiece is the acts of humanity both moral, relationship between close friends, and immoral, the killing of innocent civilians and possible to a lesser extent, the unintentional minor selfish betrayal of Schanberg towards Pran. Rather than taking a more dramatic conventional route, the films interesting aspect is to view from a pragmatic everyday journalistic media approach. Also, interestingly The Killing Fields is one of a handful of English language films to call attention the violence, economics and political ideologies of twentieth-century revolutions. The horrors of the Khmer Rouge and the story told in The killing Fields draws parallels with events in the 1930's collectivisation of Ukrainian agriculture, the Nazi Holocaust of World War II and Mao's Great Leap Forward in the 1950's, all of which resulted in systematic extermination. Unfortunately I was unable to view the film in anamorphic widescreen 1.78:1 format. Although not as detailed, viewing the film in standard format did not eradicate the intensity of the film. As well as a story of friendship, The Killing Fields is an exceptional example of a former colonial countries dilemma when faced with dissimilar political ideologies following independence. Furthermore, the indescribable torment citizens' encounter in a brutal civil war and the mass suffering during the course of inhumane social experiments and the forced undemocratic reorganising of a society.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well Made, But Not Particularly Informative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although The Killing Fields has a reputation as the definitive work on the Khmer Rouge genocide, it is actually a rather shallow treatment of the topic. It does not give much insight into the motivations of the Khmer Rouge or of its own characters for that matter. The film follows journalist Sydney Schanberg and his Cambodian translator Dith Pran as they cover the fall of the Cambodian government. In his enthusiasm to cover the story, Schanberg decides to stay behind when the American Embassy evacuates. This results in Pran being stranded in Cambodia for the duration of the Khmer Rouge regime. The film works best when it focuses on the personal drama between Schanberg and Dith Pran. Sam Waterston gives a good performance as Schanberg, making us empathize with the character even when he acts like a self-indulgent jerk. Haing S. Ngor is excellent as Pran, earning his Oscar with a moving performance. However, the film does not give us any insight into the characters, particularly why Pran, who is clearly terrified, decides to stay behind with Schanberg. Their relationship, while compelling portrayed by the actors, is not explored in any depth, leading to unintentional homosexual overtones. More gallingly, the film does not really give any insight into the Khmer Rouge or why they carried out their atrocities. With Nazis and other more familiar historical villains, viewers will generally have a good sense of their ideologies and motivations. This is not necessarily the case with the Khmer Rouge. We do not really get a sense of who the Khmer Rouge are targeting or why? This is a particularly glaring omission as many younger Americans are only familiar with the Cambodian genocide from this movie. Furthermore, the film's general lack of on-screen violence results in a failure to convey the true horror of what took place. This flaw is acknowledged even by some involved in the film. As Haing Ngor reported in his autobiography, both he and Dith Pran thought the film's violence should be more graphic to convey the brutality of the Khmer Rouge. If you want a true sense of who the Khmer Rouge were, see the documentary S21: The Khmer Rouge Killing Machine, which goes into far greater detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Exceptional Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyejacker
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is an important film. It tells the story of two journalists혰one American and one Cambodian혰struggling to stay alive in war-torn Cambodia. Of course, it tells a bigger story too, namely the result of the bombing of Cambodia by the United States and subsequent atrocities committed by the Khmer Rouge: torture, slavery, brainwashing, increasingly indiscriminate murder on a mass scale. All very real and very terrible things. The film manages to tackle all of this heavy material without glossing anything over, (I'm looking at you Hotel Rwanda) and without making it so brutal as to be unwatchable. Unfortunately, the majority of the acting and dialogue in The Killing Fields isn't quite good enough to do the aforementioned atrocities justice. That is not to say these aspects of the film are bad, they're perfectly adequate. I just wish they were as flawless as some enraptured reviewers would have you believe. Ironically, (and perhaps even fittingly) it's the non-actor Cambodian children that give the most convincing, (and touching) performances in the movie. They may just be being themselves, but it lends the film an authenticity which few of the trained actors were able to capture with any consistency. The cinematography is spot on. Brilliantly balanced and flawlessly framed, it's practically symbolic in a few shots. Just beautiful. All of the filming appeared to be shot on site, in Cambodia and elsewhere, a practice that the majority of modern directors seem to have forgotten about, which is a shame since no amount of CGI or special effects are as convincing as the real place. The sets look 100% real, nothing looks staged. The music ranges from moving, to merely fitting, to downright strange and painfully 80's. Fortunately, there's more of the former than of the latter. With the exception of a few crude sound effects, The Killing Fields sounds quite good overall. While important, The Killing Fields is unlikely to ever be a very popular film. While it's technically a "war movie" (in part) it never glorifies violence, or tries to make it look cool. There's plenty of violence, of course, but it's more of the uncensored 6 o' clock news variety. Obviously, the film also draws attention to a very dark page from the United States past, and raises a lot of uncomfortable questions, which is bound to turn some people off. However, for anyone mature enough to handle its subject matter, and empathetic enough to explore the wide range of emotions covered in the film, The Killing Fields should really not be missed. 7.9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Gut-Wrenching History Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1975 the revolutionary group Khmer Rouge took over Cambodia and initiated a regime that reportedly claimed two million lives. At the time the Vietnam War was still going on, Cambodia was a strategic territory for the American army and the country was full of journalists. The basis of the movie's story comes from the lives of two of them: New York Times journalist Sydney Schanberg, and Dith Pran, Cambodian photojournalist and interpreter who coined the term "Killing Fields." Written by Bruce Robinson based on their writings, the movie follows in fact two stories: one is the fall of Phnom Penh, the capital, and the evacuation of the international embassies, as witnessed by Sydney and Pran, and Sydney's return to the USA; and the second, more radical narrative, shows the horrors of the Khmer Rouge as witnessed by Pran after he's captured and sent to work in a Killing Field, and his epic escape to freedom. From Phnom Penh Sydney and Pran report the events of the civil war between the government and the Khmer Rouge, with the revolutionaries clearly gaining control of the country. The international embassies start evacuating their personnel. Sydney and Pran opt to remain, although Pran sends his wife and family away. As the Khmer Rouge revolutionaries enter the city, they're initially received with joy and prospects of peace, everyone tired of the war. Even Pran joins the festivities. However the Khmer Rouge, split in different factions due to internal power struggles, continue to fight in the capital. Sydney and Pran find refuge in the French embassy, until it's also evacuated and all Cambodians hiding there are turned over to the revolutionaries. For the time, the movie was quite revolutionary in casting a non-amateur actor in the role of Dith Pran. They found Haing Somnang Ngor, a doctor living in the USA, to portray Pran. Like Pran, Ngor had also spent four years in the killing fields before escaping. He won the Oscar for Best Supporting Actor in 1985 for this role. He played the role with naturalism and lightness, displaying a restraint in emotions in situations where an actor would typically go into melodramatic mode. The choice of Ngor is ahead of its time for another reason. Anglo-American movies tend to work on the logic that audiences can only care for the plight of foreign countries if the experiences are mediated through a character from their culture; that's why war correspondents are usually the main characters in such movies. Although now thanks to movies like Letters from Iwo Jima and Hotel Rwanda this is changing, casting a Cambodian actor to tell the story of a Cambodian prisoner of the Khmer Rouge was audacious then. Sam Waterston also delivers a powerful performance as Sydney, an authoritarian boss who blames himself for having used Pran to further his career only to abandon him. Back in New York he starts an international campaign to find his friend, always wondering whether he's doing enough for him. The movie is also helped with performances from John Malkovich and Julian Sands as two other journalists, Craig T. Nelson as the US Army officer in charge of the American evacuation, and Spalding Gray as the morally-torn American Consul, wary of abandoning the country to the revolutionaries. The scenes in the Killing Fields still have, decades later and after graphic violence has become generalised, the power to affect because of how the movie shows the psychological roots of the crimes. It's not that the images are excessively violent, it's that the movie depicts a philosophy of inhumanity. Regimes don't just producer horror for its own sake, the violence is just a tool to implement ideas. Rather than just showing the horrors, the movie shows the philosophy which the violence was used to enforce: the viewer is taken into the classrooms where children are being taught to hate the concept of family and any personal relationships that may threaten blind loyalty to the party; children are given power over life and death; intellectuals, teachers, journalists are executed for their skills; people are forbidden from growing crops, because that's a sign of free initiative, even though thousands are starving to death The movie confronts us with those ideas and we can't help but ask, "How the hell did anyone ever think these ideas could work in a society?" Not everything holds up as well in the movie. Many good scenes are ruined by Mike Oldfield's intrusive cacophony of synthesizer noises. Nowadays, when we listen to electronic scores with less patience than our ancestors did back in the '80s, a lot of this music sounds horrible. Oldfield, one of my favourite living musicians, is by no means an inept film composer, however: half the score, when he turns to traditional orchestration, is majestic. "Pran's Theme" and its variations are appropriately elegiac, and "Requim for a City," with its chorus of grieving voices, is a haunting attempt at showing through music the misery of the one million Cambodians forced by the Khmer Rouge to abandon the capital in a forced march to the countryside to work on the Killing Fields. Twenty-seven years later what the movie has to say about the darkness in the human soul, and the determination to overcome it, remains fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's nothing to forgive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    del91
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Joffe's "The Killing Fields" is a nerve-shredding full film of power and emotion. The facts that the film is not based, but an actual true story, coupled with the knowledge that star Haing S Ngor was an actual Khmer Rouge prisoner, makes it impossible to turn away from the screen. Sam Waterston's performance as the determined turned guilt-ridden reporter Sydney Schanberg is good, but the show belongs to Ngor whose compelling performance gives us not only a person we care about but also a realistic, real human being, thrown into horrible circumstances of outside causes. If anything Ngor's terrific performance can be the sole reason of this film's raw power and brutality. But there is more to watch in this human film. Mike Oldfield's great, suitable score which perfectly suits the action without getting too dramatic or too subtle. The stunning cinematography which shows the horrors of war amidst the beauty of Cambodia. Terrific production value showing atmospheric, realistic locations filled with thousands of extras, a feat reminding me of the days of David Lean, only less joyous and much more terrifying given the context. I cannot recommend this brilliant film enough. Actions speak louder than words, so go see this as soon as you can, and prepare to be moved immensely. The use of John Lennon's "Imagine" is perfectly suited. Overall rating: 91/100
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A historical drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bahadrkk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie takes us to 70s of Cambodia, let us know how vulnerable Cambodian government and US against Khmer Rouge, makes us witnesses of violence implemented by Khmer Rouge, we also can see two brave men, one of whom is Cambodian Dith Pran, how they are disciplined and workaholic even under these circumstances. Although Haing Ngor hadn't had acting experience before, he performed intermediate level of acting. All of the other actors performed well and did their business. Although we couldn't see a lot of battle scenes, there are a lot of scenes about the results of war actions; wounded people, dead people, captivated personal, and tortures. I would prefer to see more battle actions and would like to see them more effective in a war movie, but this movie is much a drama, drama of Cambodian people, and drama of a journalist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vale_krtal14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sydney Schanberg is a journalist in The New York Times, who was sent to Cambodia in 1972 as a correspondent of the war that was occurring there. When he arrives, he meets Dith Pran, a Cambodian photojournalist and refugee who survived the Cambodian Genocide. This man becomes Schaberg's guide and translator during the war. When trying to photograph the execution of two Khmer Rouge operatives, they are arrested and later learn that the press had reported a different version of the story. In 1975, people were being evacuated from the capital because of a possible invasion from the Khmer Rouge. Even though Pran's family is able to flee, he decided to stay and help Schanberg cover the story. After going through several situations, in which they get arrested again, Pran is turned over to the Khmer Rouge after they ask for every Cambodian citizen to be turned in. After months of searching for Pran, Schanberg begins to blame himself for Pran's situation. He wouldn't be trapped if it weren't for him. However, after several complications, Pran reaches a Red Cross camp in the border of Thailand. When he returns home to his family, he reunites with Schanberg who apologizes for everything. Pran forgives him and the movie ends. This movie was extraordinary. The acting, camera movements and the realism in the film captured everything necessary for the audience to be caught in the moment. It is credible, touching and it is poetically convincing. It doesn't have a traditional Hollywood structure, but as a human story, it is very well made. It captures a vivid image of how people's lives were during that period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marykate_nyland
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of the most influential films of the 20th century. Its provocative and dangerous subject matter stresses the importance of communication and the freedom to communicate. Based on the Khmer Rouge occupation and genocide of Cambodia in the 1970's, the film tells the story of two men, catapulted into chaos and peril. The movie is first and foremost, a historical account. The events are based off the true story of Dith Pran and Sydney Schanberg. Given that I had not known much about the Cambodian genocide of the 1970's prior to seeing this film, I must herald the piece as a successful feat of cinematography that served as both informational as well as inspirational. The film is believable, realistic, and heart wrenching. I immediately felt for the two main characters as they quickly exchanged trust and fell victim to the powers of political violence. While it is slightly romanticized, The Killing Fields still manages to produce a message with real life implications.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Nixon Doctrine in its purest form..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ironies abound in THE KILLING FIELDS. "Cambodia is the Nixon doctrine in its purest form," boasts one of the twentieth century's greatest war criminals (who himself lived a long and happy life, thereby putting the lie to any and all notions of karma). The Vietnam War, we're told, resulted in 3 million deaths (70-80% of all casualties were civilian). Does that total factor in the Cambodians who were murdered in the war's "aftermath?" (90% of all deaths in Iraq were civilian, by the way. Evidence has now come to light that the U.$. actually AIDED Saddam Hussein when he used chemical weapons against the Kurds in Iraq. That's right: the same government threatening to bomb Syria back into The Stone Age actually had an active part in the mass murder of Kurdish civilians. Or was it IRANIANS, during the Iran-Iraq War? "Six of one, half dozen of the other," U.$. politicos might say, but the distinction DOES matter, especially if you're Iranian or Kurdish... I may be wrong about the Kurdish murders, but I'm not going to change my comments until I see some paperwork showing otherwise. And there are 30,000 drones in the skies over the U.$., even as I write...) Another of the ironies is what happened to Haing S. Ngor (Dith Pran in THE KILLING FIELDS) after he came to the U.$.: having survived genocide in Cambodia, he was murdered here, in the street. Maybe THIS is the true Killing Field.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachana Rom
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of those all too rare movies, a movie that challenges you to think about what you have just witnessed on screen, a movie that has the power to make you very aware that human tragedy and persecution are very much with us today. That said, the film concerns one man's triumph over unbelievable tragedy and adversity. The cinematography is first class, and the acting is all too believable. To appreciate the full enormity of this film I would strongly recommend reading up on the events with which the film is concerned. This film is hard to fault, and the ending with John Lennon's "Imagine" in the background is perfect and may well reduce you to tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darkness of the soul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richard6
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Set in the former French colony of Indochina, The Killing Fields centres on New York Times correspondent Sydney Schanberg, together with fellow journalistic aid and Cambodian national Dith Pran reporting on the military involvement of the United States in South East Asia in the early 1970s, Significantly, and the films main focal point, commentating on the latter stages of the Cambodian civil war. Due to the close proximity to Vietnam, and the United States wearisome involvement in the on-going communist and democratic conflicts in South East Asia, American foreign policy and public interest paid portentous attentiveness to the affairs of Cambodia. The film is introduced at the time of America's covert aerial bombardment of Eastern Cambodian military targets following the communist guerrillas refusal to adhere to the 1973 Paris Peace Treaty. Zealous journalist Schanberg is eager to and hindered from reporting to the American public the trepidation caused by the American bombing. Succeeding this introduction, the film moves intensely to the 1975 evacuation of foreign nationals from Phnom Penh during the seizing of power by the totalitarian communists Kampuchea before focusing on the consequent killing fields caused through social transformation and the year-zero policy. The film's final act, following a left behind Pran's escape from a national forced labour camp, is the eventual reuniting of the two journalist friends. From one stand point, British director Ronald Joffe does not shy away from exposing the human atrocities caused by armed conflict. Yet, Joffe does not over-embellish the horrors that inhabitant's encounter in a war-torn Country. Particularly, The Killing Fields centrepiece is the acts of humanity both moral, relationship between close friends, and immoral, the killing of innocent civilians and possible to a lesser extent, the unintentional minor selfish betrayal of Schanberg towards Pran. Rather than taking a more dramatic conventional route, the films interesting aspect is to view from a pragmatic everyday journalistic media approach. Also, interestingly The Killing Fields is one of a handful of English language films to call attention the violence, economics and political ideologies of twentieth-century revolutions. The horrors of the Khmer Rouge and the story told in The killing Fields draws parallels with events in the 1930's collectivisation of Ukrainian agriculture, the Nazi Holocaust of World War II and Mao's Great Leap Forward in the 1950's, all of which resulted in systematic extermination. Unfortunately I was unable to view the film in anamorphic widescreen 1.78:1 format. Although not as detailed, viewing the film in standard format did not eradicate the intensity of the film. As well as a story of friendship, The Killing Fields is an exceptional example of a former colonial countries dilemma when faced with dissimilar political ideologies following independence. Furthermore, the indescribable torment citizens' encounter in a brutal civil war and the mass suffering during the course of inhumane social experiments and the forced undemocratic reorganising of a society.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well Made, But Not Particularly Informative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheExpatriate700
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although The Killing Fields has a reputation as the definitive work on the Khmer Rouge genocide, it is actually a rather shallow treatment of the topic. It does not give much insight into the motivations of the Khmer Rouge or of its own characters for that matter. The film follows journalist Sydney Schanberg and his Cambodian translator Dith Pran as they cover the fall of the Cambodian government. In his enthusiasm to cover the story, Schanberg decides to stay behind when the American Embassy evacuates. This results in Pran being stranded in Cambodia for the duration of the Khmer Rouge regime. The film works best when it focuses on the personal drama between Schanberg and Dith Pran. Sam Waterston gives a good performance as Schanberg, making us empathize with the character even when he acts like a self-indulgent jerk. Haing S. Ngor is excellent as Pran, earning his Oscar with a moving performance. However, the film does not give us any insight into the characters, particularly why Pran, who is clearly terrified, decides to stay behind with Schanberg. Their relationship, while compelling portrayed by the actors, is not explored in any depth, leading to unintentional homosexual overtones. More gallingly, the film does not really give any insight into the Khmer Rouge or why they carried out their atrocities. With Nazis and other more familiar historical villains, viewers will generally have a good sense of their ideologies and motivations. This is not necessarily the case with the Khmer Rouge. We do not really get a sense of who the Khmer Rouge are targeting or why? This is a particularly glaring omission as many younger Americans are only familiar with the Cambodian genocide from this movie. Furthermore, the film's general lack of on-screen violence results in a failure to convey the true horror of what took place. This flaw is acknowledged even by some involved in the film. As Haing Ngor reported in his autobiography, both he and Dith Pran thought the film's violence should be more graphic to convey the brutality of the Khmer Rouge. If you want a true sense of who the Khmer Rouge were, see the documentary S21: The Khmer Rouge Killing Machine, which goes into far greater detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Exceptional Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyejacker
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is an important film. It tells the story of two journalists혰one American and one Cambodian혰struggling to stay alive in war-torn Cambodia. Of course, it tells a bigger story too, namely the result of the bombing of Cambodia by the United States and subsequent atrocities committed by the Khmer Rouge: torture, slavery, brainwashing, increasingly indiscriminate murder on a mass scale. All very real and very terrible things. The film manages to tackle all of this heavy material without glossing anything over, (I'm looking at you Hotel Rwanda) and without making it so brutal as to be unwatchable. Unfortunately, the majority of the acting and dialogue in The Killing Fields isn't quite good enough to do the aforementioned atrocities justice. That is not to say these aspects of the film are bad, they're perfectly adequate. I just wish they were as flawless as some enraptured reviewers would have you believe. Ironically, (and perhaps even fittingly) it's the non-actor Cambodian children that give the most convincing, (and touching) performances in the movie. They may just be being themselves, but it lends the film an authenticity which few of the trained actors were able to capture with any consistency. The cinematography is spot on. Brilliantly balanced and flawlessly framed, it's practically symbolic in a few shots. Just beautiful. All of the filming appeared to be shot on site, in Cambodia and elsewhere, a practice that the majority of modern directors seem to have forgotten about, which is a shame since no amount of CGI or special effects are as convincing as the real place. The sets look 100% real, nothing looks staged. The music ranges from moving, to merely fitting, to downright strange and painfully 80's. Fortunately, there's more of the former than of the latter. With the exception of a few crude sound effects, The Killing Fields sounds quite good overall. While important, The Killing Fields is unlikely to ever be a very popular film. While it's technically a "war movie" (in part) it never glorifies violence, or tries to make it look cool. There's plenty of violence, of course, but it's more of the uncensored 6 o' clock news variety. Obviously, the film also draws attention to a very dark page from the United States past, and raises a lot of uncomfortable questions, which is bound to turn some people off. However, for anyone mature enough to handle its subject matter, and empathetic enough to explore the wide range of emotions covered in the film, The Killing Fields should really not be missed. 7.9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Gut-Wrenching History Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eumenides_0
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1975 the revolutionary group Khmer Rouge took over Cambodia and initiated a regime that reportedly claimed two million lives. At the time the Vietnam War was still going on, Cambodia was a strategic territory for the American army and the country was full of journalists. The basis of the movie's story comes from the lives of two of them: New York Times journalist Sydney Schanberg, and Dith Pran, Cambodian photojournalist and interpreter who coined the term "Killing Fields." Written by Bruce Robinson based on their writings, the movie follows in fact two stories: one is the fall of Phnom Penh, the capital, and the evacuation of the international embassies, as witnessed by Sydney and Pran, and Sydney's return to the USA; and the second, more radical narrative, shows the horrors of the Khmer Rouge as witnessed by Pran after he's captured and sent to work in a Killing Field, and his epic escape to freedom. From Phnom Penh Sydney and Pran report the events of the civil war between the government and the Khmer Rouge, with the revolutionaries clearly gaining control of the country. The international embassies start evacuating their personnel. Sydney and Pran opt to remain, although Pran sends his wife and family away. As the Khmer Rouge revolutionaries enter the city, they're initially received with joy and prospects of peace, everyone tired of the war. Even Pran joins the festivities. However the Khmer Rouge, split in different factions due to internal power struggles, continue to fight in the capital. Sydney and Pran find refuge in the French embassy, until it's also evacuated and all Cambodians hiding there are turned over to the revolutionaries. For the time, the movie was quite revolutionary in casting a non-amateur actor in the role of Dith Pran. They found Haing Somnang Ngor, a doctor living in the USA, to portray Pran. Like Pran, Ngor had also spent four years in the killing fields before escaping. He won the Oscar for Best Supporting Actor in 1985 for this role. He played the role with naturalism and lightness, displaying a restraint in emotions in situations where an actor would typically go into melodramatic mode. The choice of Ngor is ahead of its time for another reason. Anglo-American movies tend to work on the logic that audiences can only care for the plight of foreign countries if the experiences are mediated through a character from their culture; that's why war correspondents are usually the main characters in such movies. Although now thanks to movies like Letters from Iwo Jima and Hotel Rwanda this is changing, casting a Cambodian actor to tell the story of a Cambodian prisoner of the Khmer Rouge was audacious then. Sam Waterston also delivers a powerful performance as Sydney, an authoritarian boss who blames himself for having used Pran to further his career only to abandon him. Back in New York he starts an international campaign to find his friend, always wondering whether he's doing enough for him. The movie is also helped with performances from John Malkovich and Julian Sands as two other journalists, Craig T. Nelson as the US Army officer in charge of the American evacuation, and Spalding Gray as the morally-torn American Consul, wary of abandoning the country to the revolutionaries. The scenes in the Killing Fields still have, decades later and after graphic violence has become generalised, the power to affect because of how the movie shows the psychological roots of the crimes. It's not that the images are excessively violent, it's that the movie depicts a philosophy of inhumanity. Regimes don't just producer horror for its own sake, the violence is just a tool to implement ideas. Rather than just showing the horrors, the movie shows the philosophy which the violence was used to enforce: the viewer is taken into the classrooms where children are being taught to hate the concept of family and any personal relationships that may threaten blind loyalty to the party; children are given power over life and death; intellectuals, teachers, journalists are executed for their skills; people are forbidden from growing crops, because that's a sign of free initiative, even though thousands are starving to death The movie confronts us with those ideas and we can't help but ask, "How the hell did anyone ever think these ideas could work in a society?" Not everything holds up as well in the movie. Many good scenes are ruined by Mike Oldfield's intrusive cacophony of synthesizer noises. Nowadays, when we listen to electronic scores with less patience than our ancestors did back in the '80s, a lot of this music sounds horrible. Oldfield, one of my favourite living musicians, is by no means an inept film composer, however: half the score, when he turns to traditional orchestration, is majestic. "Pran's Theme" and its variations are appropriately elegiac, and "Requim for a City," with its chorus of grieving voices, is a haunting attempt at showing through music the misery of the one million Cambodians forced by the Khmer Rouge to abandon the capital in a forced march to the countryside to work on the Killing Fields. Twenty-seven years later what the movie has to say about the darkness in the human soul, and the determination to overcome it, remains fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's nothing to forgive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    del91
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Joffe's "The Killing Fields" is a nerve-shredding full film of power and emotion. The facts that the film is not based, but an actual true story, coupled with the knowledge that star Haing S Ngor was an actual Khmer Rouge prisoner, makes it impossible to turn away from the screen. Sam Waterston's performance as the determined turned guilt-ridden reporter Sydney Schanberg is good, but the show belongs to Ngor whose compelling performance gives us not only a person we care about but also a realistic, real human being, thrown into horrible circumstances of outside causes. If anything Ngor's terrific performance can be the sole reason of this film's raw power and brutality. But there is more to watch in this human film. Mike Oldfield's great, suitable score which perfectly suits the action without getting too dramatic or too subtle. The stunning cinematography which shows the horrors of war amidst the beauty of Cambodia. Terrific production value showing atmospheric, realistic locations filled with thousands of extras, a feat reminding me of the days of David Lean, only less joyous and much more terrifying given the context. I cannot recommend this brilliant film enough. Actions speak louder than words, so go see this as soon as you can, and prepare to be moved immensely. The use of John Lennon's "Imagine" is perfectly suited. Overall rating: 91/100
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A historical drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bahadrkk
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie takes us to 70s of Cambodia, let us know how vulnerable Cambodian government and US against Khmer Rouge, makes us witnesses of violence implemented by Khmer Rouge, we also can see two brave men, one of whom is Cambodian Dith Pran, how they are disciplined and workaholic even under these circumstances. Although Haing Ngor hadn't had acting experience before, he performed intermediate level of acting. All of the other actors performed well and did their business. Although we couldn't see a lot of battle scenes, there are a lot of scenes about the results of war actions; wounded people, dead people, captivated personal, and tortures. I would prefer to see more battle actions and would like to see them more effective in a war movie, but this movie is much a drama, drama of Cambodian people, and drama of a journalist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vale_krtal14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sydney Schanberg is a journalist in The New York Times, who was sent to Cambodia in 1972 as a correspondent of the war that was occurring there. When he arrives, he meets Dith Pran, a Cambodian photojournalist and refugee who survived the Cambodian Genocide. This man becomes Schaberg's guide and translator during the war. When trying to photograph the execution of two Khmer Rouge operatives, they are arrested and later learn that the press had reported a different version of the story. In 1975, people were being evacuated from the capital because of a possible invasion from the Khmer Rouge. Even though Pran's family is able to flee, he decided to stay and help Schanberg cover the story. After going through several situations, in which they get arrested again, Pran is turned over to the Khmer Rouge after they ask for every Cambodian citizen to be turned in. After months of searching for Pran, Schanberg begins to blame himself for Pran's situation. He wouldn't be trapped if it weren't for him. However, after several complications, Pran reaches a Red Cross camp in the border of Thailand. When he returns home to his family, he reunites with Schanberg who apologizes for everything. Pran forgives him and the movie ends. This movie was extraordinary. The acting, camera movements and the realism in the film captured everything necessary for the audience to be caught in the moment. It is credible, touching and it is poetically convincing. It doesn't have a traditional Hollywood structure, but as a human story, it is very well made. It captures a vivid image of how people's lives were during that period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marykate_nyland
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Killing Fields is one of the most influential films of the 20th century. Its provocative and dangerous subject matter stresses the importance of communication and the freedom to communicate. Based on the Khmer Rouge occupation and genocide of Cambodia in the 1970's, the film tells the story of two men, catapulted into chaos and peril. The movie is first and foremost, a historical account. The events are based off the true story of Dith Pran and Sydney Schanberg. Given that I had not known much about the Cambodian genocide of the 1970's prior to seeing this film, I must herald the piece as a successful feat of cinematography that served as both informational as well as inspirational. The film is believable, realistic, and heart wrenching. I immediately felt for the two main characters as they quickly exchanged trust and fell victim to the powers of political violence. While it is slightly romanticized, The Killing Fields still manages to produce a message with real life implications.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
