<filme>
 <id>
  533
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116041
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Dia em Nova York
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  When a happily married woman discovers a love letter written by her husband to an unknown party, she enlists her dysfunctional family to discover the truth.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Eliza D'Amico thinks her marriage to Louis is going great, until she finds a mysterious love note to her husband. Concerned, she goes to her mother for advice. Eliza, her parents, her sister Jo and Jo's boyfriend all pile into a station wagon, to go to the city to confront Louis with the letter. On the way, the five explore their relations with each other, and meet many interesting people.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   letter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   party
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   thanksgiving
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   station wagon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dysfunctional family
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Greg Mottola
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Greg Mottola
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Hope Davis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Stanley Tucci
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Parker Posey
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An engaging detour from writer/director Greg Mottola
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxpower03
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An engaging indie reminiscent of both Neil Simon and Woody Allen, The Daytrippers utilizes a strong cast as a family travel down literal avenues to unravel a mystery over fidelity. Eliza (Hope Davis) is happily married to publisher Louis (Stanley Tucci), until she discovers a love letter that may or may not have been sent to him. Determined to find out the truth, she travels into the city to confront him, aided by her domineering mother (Anne Meara), subdued father (Pat McNamara), sister Jo (Parker Posey) and her novelist boyfriend Carl (Liev Schreiber). The Daytrippers works best during moments with the Malone family together, from Eliza and Jo's sisterly bonding to mom Rita's fawning over Carl. The various derailments and subplots along the way are a mixed bag, the best allowing for some neat interludes from Marc Grapey as a sleazy womanizer, Marcia Gay Harden as a drunken party girl and Stephanie Venditto as a over-excited receptionist. In terms of acting, Anne Meara steals the show as the fiery matriarch of the Malone family, while a lot of fun is created from Carl's episodic reciting of his novel, a pretentious story about a man with a dog's head. Parker Posey, as always, is also hilarious with her sarcastic gags and deadpan delivery. Not particularly memorable but a movie that at least entertains throughout its short running time, The Daytrippers is an enjoyable melodrama strengthened by the realistic familial chemistry between the film's leads. Rating: C+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Daytrippers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ametaphysicalshark
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the shockingly good teen comedy "Superbad" and the wistful, sentimental post-collegiate angst of "Adventureland", even before his now famous TV work, director Greg Mottola made this 1996 gem "The Daytrippers". The film, like Mottola's other films, works a familiar and unpromising premise into a genuine, heartfelt, wonderful observation on human behavior. The film, while rougher around the edges technically and as a script than either "Superbad" (written by Seth Rogen and Evan Goldberg) and "Adventureland" (written by Mottola himself, as "The Daytrippers" is), is yet another distinctive and memorable Mottola film. The plot is pretty much covered by the film's tagline: "One station wagon. Two generations. Three couples. Four relationships", but much like Mottola's other films ("Superbad": Two best friends and a nerdy semi-friend attempt to get laid before graduation. "Adventureland": college grad works at amusement park and falls in love) the plot doesn't really give any indication of how good the film is. Great script overall by Mottola with terrific characterization and dialogue which rings true, not to mention mature handling of the relationships as well as a good dose of humor. An excellent cast (at their best too, Mottola's great work with actors on display yet again) including Stanley Tucci, Hope Davis, Liev Schrieber, and Parker Posey bring the script to life well, and Mottola's storytelling skills and comic timing as director are, even this early in his career, excellent. Not as good as his later work, but Mottola shows great promise with this early film. Cannot wait for "Paul", which promises to be absolutely brilliant if his career follows the path it's on (getting better with every film).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a better movie than Little Miss Sunshine...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    saucyvideoguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daytrippers and Little Miss Sunshine have very similar themes of family road trips but 'Daytrippers' was far more sophisticated and understated. I'm pretty disappointed this flick isn't available on the DVD in the U.S. Me and my girlfriend watched this one twice in the theaters during the waining heyday of the indie-film era. Our favorite line: When Parker Posey says, "You know dad, that was basically the worst car chase in history..." HAHAHAHAHAHA! HAHAHAHAHAHA! HAHAHAHAHAHA!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The narrative arch isn't that great but it moves forward with good dialogue and performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eliza D'Amico is in love with her husband Louis and assumes that he feels the same way. However when she finds a note of love poetry in his pocket from someone called Sandy, she worries that he is having an affair. Confiding in her mother, father, sister and her sister's boyfriend, the decision is made for her to take a trip into the city to investigate. After a drive, the group pry into Louis' office and uncover something going on with a colleague called Cassandra. They dig deeper and their trip turns into a full day and night in the city. I can understand those who have problems with the narrative arch of this film because it is a bit unlikely and contrived but it is likely that many viewers will find enjoyment in the dialogue and mood of the film. Never hilarious, the film has a consistently nice comic touch and the dialogue help produce the characters over and above the situations that the plot puts them in. In this way it works reasonably well because it develops the story well enough while using the specific situations to allow for comic dialogue. I wasn't ever laughing and I wasn't ever totally engrossed in the story but it did enough to keep my interest and amuse and interest. Mottola aims for an independent feel and hits it spot on. It has its flaws but it works even if the film stock has dated and looks a bit grainy. The cast work well with the material and Mottola's casting agents have done really well to get such an ensemble together. There is no one clear lead and everyone works well together. Davis is given the least of the characters as she has to carry the plot but she does it well regardless. Posey is more interesting because her character is  plus I always find her easy to enjoy for some reason. Schreiber judges his character well and allows us to spot his annoying characteristics gradually in the same way that Jo would be spotting them with time; often I find him annoying, here it was intentional and his performance is good in that way. Tucci has a minor role and his presence is more about his name that his ability, but he is welcome. Meara and McNarama both work well together and produce the most energy as the parents. All of them work well with the dialogue and the scenarios and do their best with the narrative. Overall this is a light indie film that des have weakness in the narrative but generally makes up for it with good dialogue and a nice air to it. The starry (if you move in that way) cast react well to it and turn in good performances and characters that help the film be better that the narrative arch would suggest it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why this wasn't a box smash I'll never know
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stanton67
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a tone to it that is just perfect. The movie hums like a great song. The movie is never boring. The cast is near perfect. The story yes a little simple but the screenplay has parent/adult children relationships down. This is a story that takes place the day after Thanksgiving. You know that day. Everybody is tired and worn out from the day before. Well on this day a woman finds a note in her husbands pocket, She then shows her parents and sister the note. Before you know it we're on a day road trip with the family to track down Stanley Tuci. To give away more of the story would be a crime. Everybody with a family can relate to this! Don't miss out. Also has a cameo Marcia Gay Harden.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A trip to take
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    graham clarke (grahamclarke@earthling.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Greg Mottola makes a very auspicious debut with "The Daytrippers". He directs a terrific cast in what is something of a rarity; a true ensemble piece. Rather than a road movie, this is a street movie with various stations in lower Manhattan. As the journey progresses so too does the family begin to unravel in a manner which is both funny as well as genuinely moving. All give dead on target performances, with highlights from Ann Meara and Lieve Shrieber (whose unravelling is particularly poignant). Hope Davis is as wistfully wonderful as always with Parker Posey, Stanley Tucci, Pat McNaramra and Campbell Scott rounding out the ensemble. A trip you may want to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, VERY personal movie, a little too close to life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    serious89
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... a believably bickering family, portrayed by skilled actors, w/some wonderful ham stuff by Anne Meara and Parker Posey, and more subtle stuff from Hope Davis and Liev Schreiber. The story had a distinctly voyeuristic feel, as if the screenwriter was exorcising some history and making it more entertaining, often hilarious (and interesting?) than a painful history he may have lived through. A cinema verite re-creation by world class skilled actors. As the family's lives unravel, driving around in a freezing cold NYC winter evening, there is a quiet lingering shot of the World Trade Center that is unintentionally haunting, and gives the film (made in 1996) an unintended resonance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not your ordinary road trip
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Snoopymichele
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Truly one of the funniest, most original films of the mid 90's. The casting is truly inspired-Anne Meara gives a knockout performance as an overbearing, but well-meaning suburban mother; Hope Davis is marvelous (as usual) as an optimistic, sort of numb wife on a mission to see if her husband is indeed cheating on her; Liev Schreiber is wonderful as the superb Parker Posey's aspiring writer boyfriend; Campbell Scott steals the movie as a lusty writer Eddie; and of course Stanley Tucci turns in another great performance as the catalyst character in the film. His screen time is brief, but he shines brightly. Marcia Gay Harden's cameo as a neurotic party guest had me practically on the floor laughing. The story unfolds naturally, taking the viewer on the same emotional journey as the characters. There's never a dull moment, and the film is an indie classic filled with thought-provoking dialogue and terrific character sketches.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly UNsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Daytrippers" is a script-driven open ended comedy about a semifunctional family (an ensemble cast including mom, dad, two adult daughters, and a boyfriend) who drive into Manhattan in search of a one of the daughters' wayward husband. With nonstop pseudointellectual pedantic blathering from beginning to end, this uneventful flick takes you along for the ride where you'll suffer from small talk, an explanation of the boyfriend's work-in-progress novel, a silly conversation about politics, an encounter involving the carrying of a t.v. set, and other such pedestrianisms resulting in a mediocre flick which fails in script. "The Daytrippers" might best be described as some really bad Woody Allen which is almost rescued by a solid cast. (C)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A small film that is easy to miss but should be seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmOtaku (ssampon@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I've been meaning to see this film for years, (I think the trailer was on the Reservoir Dogs VHS that I wore out before I bought it on DVD) it was one of probably hundreds of films that I put on my back burner. So when I recently saw it was on a pay channel I jumped on it, and am very glad that I did finally see this gem. The Daytrippers involves a woman (Davis) whose resolve that she is happily married is tested when she finds an excerpt from a love poem that fell from her husband's (Tucci) clothes. She elects to go to her mother (Meara) for advice and ends up going on a day trip to NYC to ask her husband about it. Along for the ride is her father, (McNamara) her sister, (Posey) and her sister's boyfriend (Schrieber). Of course, if they were able to simply confront her husband it would be easy; unfortunately he is no where to be found, so they willingly engage in amateur sleuthing to put together the story while they drive around the city looking for him. The plot is a fairly simple one, but the character development is the true star of the film. While Parker Posey is known best for playing `quirky yet intelligent' characters, her role seems more of a natural addition in this film rather than a run-of-the-mill portrayal for her. Meara is nearly maddening as a meddling mother, and McNamara, a well established character actor is heartbreakingly sweet as the weary father. Davis and Tucci are both fantastic as usual, and while Tucci's role is a small one, he exhibits his usual passion that makes him an exciting actor. Davis gives her character a palpable fragility that just barely makes room for the modicum of strength that is holding her together. In my opinion, the true breakout star of the film is Schrieber as Carl Petrovic, `the boyfriend'. His character has so many facets to his personality and becomes such a complex study that is so rare in a supporting character. And Schrieber's portrayal is brilliant and both comedic and heart-breaking in it's subtle profundity. Schreiber has been on my radar since I saw him in RKO 281 brilliantly portraying one of my personal heroes, Orson Welles, and after viewing this performance I plan to seek out more of his work. The Daytrippers has been an independent film darling for years now and I can see why. It is an intelligent, emotional and well-written and acted film that will hold an appeal for most who take the time to view it. --Shelly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An engaging detour from writer/director Greg Mottola
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxpower03
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An engaging indie reminiscent of both Neil Simon and Woody Allen, The Daytrippers utilizes a strong cast as a family travel down literal avenues to unravel a mystery over fidelity. Eliza (Hope Davis) is happily married to publisher Louis (Stanley Tucci), until she discovers a love letter that may or may not have been sent to him. Determined to find out the truth, she travels into the city to confront him, aided by her domineering mother (Anne Meara), subdued father (Pat McNamara), sister Jo (Parker Posey) and her novelist boyfriend Carl (Liev Schreiber). The Daytrippers works best during moments with the Malone family together, from Eliza and Jo's sisterly bonding to mom Rita's fawning over Carl. The various derailments and subplots along the way are a mixed bag, the best allowing for some neat interludes from Marc Grapey as a sleazy womanizer, Marcia Gay Harden as a drunken party girl and Stephanie Venditto as a over-excited receptionist. In terms of acting, Anne Meara steals the show as the fiery matriarch of the Malone family, while a lot of fun is created from Carl's episodic reciting of his novel, a pretentious story about a man with a dog's head. Parker Posey, as always, is also hilarious with her sarcastic gags and deadpan delivery. Not particularly memorable but a movie that at least entertains throughout its short running time, The Daytrippers is an enjoyable melodrama strengthened by the realistic familial chemistry between the film's leads. Rating: C+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Daytrippers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ametaphysicalshark
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the shockingly good teen comedy "Superbad" and the wistful, sentimental post-collegiate angst of "Adventureland", even before his now famous TV work, director Greg Mottola made this 1996 gem "The Daytrippers". The film, like Mottola's other films, works a familiar and unpromising premise into a genuine, heartfelt, wonderful observation on human behavior. The film, while rougher around the edges technically and as a script than either "Superbad" (written by Seth Rogen and Evan Goldberg) and "Adventureland" (written by Mottola himself, as "The Daytrippers" is), is yet another distinctive and memorable Mottola film. The plot is pretty much covered by the film's tagline: "One station wagon. Two generations. Three couples. Four relationships", but much like Mottola's other films ("Superbad": Two best friends and a nerdy semi-friend attempt to get laid before graduation. "Adventureland": college grad works at amusement park and falls in love) the plot doesn't really give any indication of how good the film is. Great script overall by Mottola with terrific characterization and dialogue which rings true, not to mention mature handling of the relationships as well as a good dose of humor. An excellent cast (at their best too, Mottola's great work with actors on display yet again) including Stanley Tucci, Hope Davis, Liev Schrieber, and Parker Posey bring the script to life well, and Mottola's storytelling skills and comic timing as director are, even this early in his career, excellent. Not as good as his later work, but Mottola shows great promise with this early film. Cannot wait for "Paul", which promises to be absolutely brilliant if his career follows the path it's on (getting better with every film).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a better movie than Little Miss Sunshine...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    saucyvideoguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daytrippers and Little Miss Sunshine have very similar themes of family road trips but 'Daytrippers' was far more sophisticated and understated. I'm pretty disappointed this flick isn't available on the DVD in the U.S. Me and my girlfriend watched this one twice in the theaters during the waining heyday of the indie-film era. Our favorite line: When Parker Posey says, "You know dad, that was basically the worst car chase in history..." HAHAHAHAHAHA! HAHAHAHAHAHA! HAHAHAHAHAHA!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The narrative arch isn't that great but it moves forward with good dialogue and performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eliza D'Amico is in love with her husband Louis and assumes that he feels the same way. However when she finds a note of love poetry in his pocket from someone called Sandy, she worries that he is having an affair. Confiding in her mother, father, sister and her sister's boyfriend, the decision is made for her to take a trip into the city to investigate. After a drive, the group pry into Louis' office and uncover something going on with a colleague called Cassandra. They dig deeper and their trip turns into a full day and night in the city. I can understand those who have problems with the narrative arch of this film because it is a bit unlikely and contrived but it is likely that many viewers will find enjoyment in the dialogue and mood of the film. Never hilarious, the film has a consistently nice comic touch and the dialogue help produce the characters over and above the situations that the plot puts them in. In this way it works reasonably well because it develops the story well enough while using the specific situations to allow for comic dialogue. I wasn't ever laughing and I wasn't ever totally engrossed in the story but it did enough to keep my interest and amuse and interest. Mottola aims for an independent feel and hits it spot on. It has its flaws but it works even if the film stock has dated and looks a bit grainy. The cast work well with the material and Mottola's casting agents have done really well to get such an ensemble together. There is no one clear lead and everyone works well together. Davis is given the least of the characters as she has to carry the plot but she does it well regardless. Posey is more interesting because her character is  plus I always find her easy to enjoy for some reason. Schreiber judges his character well and allows us to spot his annoying characteristics gradually in the same way that Jo would be spotting them with time; often I find him annoying, here it was intentional and his performance is good in that way. Tucci has a minor role and his presence is more about his name that his ability, but he is welcome. Meara and McNarama both work well together and produce the most energy as the parents. All of them work well with the dialogue and the scenarios and do their best with the narrative. Overall this is a light indie film that des have weakness in the narrative but generally makes up for it with good dialogue and a nice air to it. The starry (if you move in that way) cast react well to it and turn in good performances and characters that help the film be better that the narrative arch would suggest it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why this wasn't a box smash I'll never know
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stanton67
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a tone to it that is just perfect. The movie hums like a great song. The movie is never boring. The cast is near perfect. The story yes a little simple but the screenplay has parent/adult children relationships down. This is a story that takes place the day after Thanksgiving. You know that day. Everybody is tired and worn out from the day before. Well on this day a woman finds a note in her husbands pocket, She then shows her parents and sister the note. Before you know it we're on a day road trip with the family to track down Stanley Tuci. To give away more of the story would be a crime. Everybody with a family can relate to this! Don't miss out. Also has a cameo Marcia Gay Harden.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A trip to take
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    graham clarke (grahamclarke@earthling.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Greg Mottola makes a very auspicious debut with "The Daytrippers". He directs a terrific cast in what is something of a rarity; a true ensemble piece. Rather than a road movie, this is a street movie with various stations in lower Manhattan. As the journey progresses so too does the family begin to unravel in a manner which is both funny as well as genuinely moving. All give dead on target performances, with highlights from Ann Meara and Lieve Shrieber (whose unravelling is particularly poignant). Hope Davis is as wistfully wonderful as always with Parker Posey, Stanley Tucci, Pat McNaramra and Campbell Scott rounding out the ensemble. A trip you may want to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, VERY personal movie, a little too close to life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    serious89
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... a believably bickering family, portrayed by skilled actors, w/some wonderful ham stuff by Anne Meara and Parker Posey, and more subtle stuff from Hope Davis and Liev Schreiber. The story had a distinctly voyeuristic feel, as if the screenwriter was exorcising some history and making it more entertaining, often hilarious (and interesting?) than a painful history he may have lived through. A cinema verite re-creation by world class skilled actors. As the family's lives unravel, driving around in a freezing cold NYC winter evening, there is a quiet lingering shot of the World Trade Center that is unintentionally haunting, and gives the film (made in 1996) an unintended resonance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not your ordinary road trip
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Snoopymichele
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Truly one of the funniest, most original films of the mid 90's. The casting is truly inspired-Anne Meara gives a knockout performance as an overbearing, but well-meaning suburban mother; Hope Davis is marvelous (as usual) as an optimistic, sort of numb wife on a mission to see if her husband is indeed cheating on her; Liev Schreiber is wonderful as the superb Parker Posey's aspiring writer boyfriend; Campbell Scott steals the movie as a lusty writer Eddie; and of course Stanley Tucci turns in another great performance as the catalyst character in the film. His screen time is brief, but he shines brightly. Marcia Gay Harden's cameo as a neurotic party guest had me practically on the floor laughing. The story unfolds naturally, taking the viewer on the same emotional journey as the characters. There's never a dull moment, and the film is an indie classic filled with thought-provoking dialogue and terrific character sketches.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly UNsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Daytrippers" is a script-driven open ended comedy about a semifunctional family (an ensemble cast including mom, dad, two adult daughters, and a boyfriend) who drive into Manhattan in search of a one of the daughters' wayward husband. With nonstop pseudointellectual pedantic blathering from beginning to end, this uneventful flick takes you along for the ride where you'll suffer from small talk, an explanation of the boyfriend's work-in-progress novel, a silly conversation about politics, an encounter involving the carrying of a t.v. set, and other such pedestrianisms resulting in a mediocre flick which fails in script. "The Daytrippers" might best be described as some really bad Woody Allen which is almost rescued by a solid cast. (C)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A small film that is easy to miss but should be seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmOtaku (ssampon@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I've been meaning to see this film for years, (I think the trailer was on the Reservoir Dogs VHS that I wore out before I bought it on DVD) it was one of probably hundreds of films that I put on my back burner. So when I recently saw it was on a pay channel I jumped on it, and am very glad that I did finally see this gem. The Daytrippers involves a woman (Davis) whose resolve that she is happily married is tested when she finds an excerpt from a love poem that fell from her husband's (Tucci) clothes. She elects to go to her mother (Meara) for advice and ends up going on a day trip to NYC to ask her husband about it. Along for the ride is her father, (McNamara) her sister, (Posey) and her sister's boyfriend (Schrieber). Of course, if they were able to simply confront her husband it would be easy; unfortunately he is no where to be found, so they willingly engage in amateur sleuthing to put together the story while they drive around the city looking for him. The plot is a fairly simple one, but the character development is the true star of the film. While Parker Posey is known best for playing `quirky yet intelligent' characters, her role seems more of a natural addition in this film rather than a run-of-the-mill portrayal for her. Meara is nearly maddening as a meddling mother, and McNamara, a well established character actor is heartbreakingly sweet as the weary father. Davis and Tucci are both fantastic as usual, and while Tucci's role is a small one, he exhibits his usual passion that makes him an exciting actor. Davis gives her character a palpable fragility that just barely makes room for the modicum of strength that is holding her together. In my opinion, the true breakout star of the film is Schrieber as Carl Petrovic, `the boyfriend'. His character has so many facets to his personality and becomes such a complex study that is so rare in a supporting character. And Schrieber's portrayal is brilliant and both comedic and heart-breaking in it's subtle profundity. Schreiber has been on my radar since I saw him in RKO 281 brilliantly portraying one of my personal heroes, Orson Welles, and after viewing this performance I plan to seek out more of his work. The Daytrippers has been an independent film darling for years now and I can see why. It is an intelligent, emotional and well-written and acted film that will hold an appeal for most who take the time to view it. --Shelly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An engaging detour from writer/director Greg Mottola
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxpower03
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An engaging indie reminiscent of both Neil Simon and Woody Allen, The Daytrippers utilizes a strong cast as a family travel down literal avenues to unravel a mystery over fidelity. Eliza (Hope Davis) is happily married to publisher Louis (Stanley Tucci), until she discovers a love letter that may or may not have been sent to him. Determined to find out the truth, she travels into the city to confront him, aided by her domineering mother (Anne Meara), subdued father (Pat McNamara), sister Jo (Parker Posey) and her novelist boyfriend Carl (Liev Schreiber). The Daytrippers works best during moments with the Malone family together, from Eliza and Jo's sisterly bonding to mom Rita's fawning over Carl. The various derailments and subplots along the way are a mixed bag, the best allowing for some neat interludes from Marc Grapey as a sleazy womanizer, Marcia Gay Harden as a drunken party girl and Stephanie Venditto as a over-excited receptionist. In terms of acting, Anne Meara steals the show as the fiery matriarch of the Malone family, while a lot of fun is created from Carl's episodic reciting of his novel, a pretentious story about a man with a dog's head. Parker Posey, as always, is also hilarious with her sarcastic gags and deadpan delivery. Not particularly memorable but a movie that at least entertains throughout its short running time, The Daytrippers is an enjoyable melodrama strengthened by the realistic familial chemistry between the film's leads. Rating: C+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Daytrippers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ametaphysicalshark
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the shockingly good teen comedy "Superbad" and the wistful, sentimental post-collegiate angst of "Adventureland", even before his now famous TV work, director Greg Mottola made this 1996 gem "The Daytrippers". The film, like Mottola's other films, works a familiar and unpromising premise into a genuine, heartfelt, wonderful observation on human behavior. The film, while rougher around the edges technically and as a script than either "Superbad" (written by Seth Rogen and Evan Goldberg) and "Adventureland" (written by Mottola himself, as "The Daytrippers" is), is yet another distinctive and memorable Mottola film. The plot is pretty much covered by the film's tagline: "One station wagon. Two generations. Three couples. Four relationships", but much like Mottola's other films ("Superbad": Two best friends and a nerdy semi-friend attempt to get laid before graduation. "Adventureland": college grad works at amusement park and falls in love) the plot doesn't really give any indication of how good the film is. Great script overall by Mottola with terrific characterization and dialogue which rings true, not to mention mature handling of the relationships as well as a good dose of humor. An excellent cast (at their best too, Mottola's great work with actors on display yet again) including Stanley Tucci, Hope Davis, Liev Schrieber, and Parker Posey bring the script to life well, and Mottola's storytelling skills and comic timing as director are, even this early in his career, excellent. Not as good as his later work, but Mottola shows great promise with this early film. Cannot wait for "Paul", which promises to be absolutely brilliant if his career follows the path it's on (getting better with every film).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a better movie than Little Miss Sunshine...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    saucyvideoguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daytrippers and Little Miss Sunshine have very similar themes of family road trips but 'Daytrippers' was far more sophisticated and understated. I'm pretty disappointed this flick isn't available on the DVD in the U.S. Me and my girlfriend watched this one twice in the theaters during the waining heyday of the indie-film era. Our favorite line: When Parker Posey says, "You know dad, that was basically the worst car chase in history..." HAHAHAHAHAHA! HAHAHAHAHAHA! HAHAHAHAHAHA!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The narrative arch isn't that great but it moves forward with good dialogue and performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eliza D'Amico is in love with her husband Louis and assumes that he feels the same way. However when she finds a note of love poetry in his pocket from someone called Sandy, she worries that he is having an affair. Confiding in her mother, father, sister and her sister's boyfriend, the decision is made for her to take a trip into the city to investigate. After a drive, the group pry into Louis' office and uncover something going on with a colleague called Cassandra. They dig deeper and their trip turns into a full day and night in the city. I can understand those who have problems with the narrative arch of this film because it is a bit unlikely and contrived but it is likely that many viewers will find enjoyment in the dialogue and mood of the film. Never hilarious, the film has a consistently nice comic touch and the dialogue help produce the characters over and above the situations that the plot puts them in. In this way it works reasonably well because it develops the story well enough while using the specific situations to allow for comic dialogue. I wasn't ever laughing and I wasn't ever totally engrossed in the story but it did enough to keep my interest and amuse and interest. Mottola aims for an independent feel and hits it spot on. It has its flaws but it works even if the film stock has dated and looks a bit grainy. The cast work well with the material and Mottola's casting agents have done really well to get such an ensemble together. There is no one clear lead and everyone works well together. Davis is given the least of the characters as she has to carry the plot but she does it well regardless. Posey is more interesting because her character is  plus I always find her easy to enjoy for some reason. Schreiber judges his character well and allows us to spot his annoying characteristics gradually in the same way that Jo would be spotting them with time; often I find him annoying, here it was intentional and his performance is good in that way. Tucci has a minor role and his presence is more about his name that his ability, but he is welcome. Meara and McNarama both work well together and produce the most energy as the parents. All of them work well with the dialogue and the scenarios and do their best with the narrative. Overall this is a light indie film that des have weakness in the narrative but generally makes up for it with good dialogue and a nice air to it. The starry (if you move in that way) cast react well to it and turn in good performances and characters that help the film be better that the narrative arch would suggest it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why this wasn't a box smash I'll never know
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stanton67
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a tone to it that is just perfect. The movie hums like a great song. The movie is never boring. The cast is near perfect. The story yes a little simple but the screenplay has parent/adult children relationships down. This is a story that takes place the day after Thanksgiving. You know that day. Everybody is tired and worn out from the day before. Well on this day a woman finds a note in her husbands pocket, She then shows her parents and sister the note. Before you know it we're on a day road trip with the family to track down Stanley Tuci. To give away more of the story would be a crime. Everybody with a family can relate to this! Don't miss out. Also has a cameo Marcia Gay Harden.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A trip to take
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    graham clarke (grahamclarke@earthling.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Greg Mottola makes a very auspicious debut with "The Daytrippers". He directs a terrific cast in what is something of a rarity; a true ensemble piece. Rather than a road movie, this is a street movie with various stations in lower Manhattan. As the journey progresses so too does the family begin to unravel in a manner which is both funny as well as genuinely moving. All give dead on target performances, with highlights from Ann Meara and Lieve Shrieber (whose unravelling is particularly poignant). Hope Davis is as wistfully wonderful as always with Parker Posey, Stanley Tucci, Pat McNaramra and Campbell Scott rounding out the ensemble. A trip you may want to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, VERY personal movie, a little too close to life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    serious89
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... a believably bickering family, portrayed by skilled actors, w/some wonderful ham stuff by Anne Meara and Parker Posey, and more subtle stuff from Hope Davis and Liev Schreiber. The story had a distinctly voyeuristic feel, as if the screenwriter was exorcising some history and making it more entertaining, often hilarious (and interesting?) than a painful history he may have lived through. A cinema verite re-creation by world class skilled actors. As the family's lives unravel, driving around in a freezing cold NYC winter evening, there is a quiet lingering shot of the World Trade Center that is unintentionally haunting, and gives the film (made in 1996) an unintended resonance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not your ordinary road trip
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Snoopymichele
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Truly one of the funniest, most original films of the mid 90's. The casting is truly inspired-Anne Meara gives a knockout performance as an overbearing, but well-meaning suburban mother; Hope Davis is marvelous (as usual) as an optimistic, sort of numb wife on a mission to see if her husband is indeed cheating on her; Liev Schreiber is wonderful as the superb Parker Posey's aspiring writer boyfriend; Campbell Scott steals the movie as a lusty writer Eddie; and of course Stanley Tucci turns in another great performance as the catalyst character in the film. His screen time is brief, but he shines brightly. Marcia Gay Harden's cameo as a neurotic party guest had me practically on the floor laughing. The story unfolds naturally, taking the viewer on the same emotional journey as the characters. There's never a dull moment, and the film is an indie classic filled with thought-provoking dialogue and terrific character sketches.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly UNsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Daytrippers" is a script-driven open ended comedy about a semifunctional family (an ensemble cast including mom, dad, two adult daughters, and a boyfriend) who drive into Manhattan in search of a one of the daughters' wayward husband. With nonstop pseudointellectual pedantic blathering from beginning to end, this uneventful flick takes you along for the ride where you'll suffer from small talk, an explanation of the boyfriend's work-in-progress novel, a silly conversation about politics, an encounter involving the carrying of a t.v. set, and other such pedestrianisms resulting in a mediocre flick which fails in script. "The Daytrippers" might best be described as some really bad Woody Allen which is almost rescued by a solid cast. (C)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A small film that is easy to miss but should be seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmOtaku (ssampon@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I've been meaning to see this film for years, (I think the trailer was on the Reservoir Dogs VHS that I wore out before I bought it on DVD) it was one of probably hundreds of films that I put on my back burner. So when I recently saw it was on a pay channel I jumped on it, and am very glad that I did finally see this gem. The Daytrippers involves a woman (Davis) whose resolve that she is happily married is tested when she finds an excerpt from a love poem that fell from her husband's (Tucci) clothes. She elects to go to her mother (Meara) for advice and ends up going on a day trip to NYC to ask her husband about it. Along for the ride is her father, (McNamara) her sister, (Posey) and her sister's boyfriend (Schrieber). Of course, if they were able to simply confront her husband it would be easy; unfortunately he is no where to be found, so they willingly engage in amateur sleuthing to put together the story while they drive around the city looking for him. The plot is a fairly simple one, but the character development is the true star of the film. While Parker Posey is known best for playing `quirky yet intelligent' characters, her role seems more of a natural addition in this film rather than a run-of-the-mill portrayal for her. Meara is nearly maddening as a meddling mother, and McNamara, a well established character actor is heartbreakingly sweet as the weary father. Davis and Tucci are both fantastic as usual, and while Tucci's role is a small one, he exhibits his usual passion that makes him an exciting actor. Davis gives her character a palpable fragility that just barely makes room for the modicum of strength that is holding her together. In my opinion, the true breakout star of the film is Schrieber as Carl Petrovic, `the boyfriend'. His character has so many facets to his personality and becomes such a complex study that is so rare in a supporting character. And Schrieber's portrayal is brilliant and both comedic and heart-breaking in it's subtle profundity. Schreiber has been on my radar since I saw him in RKO 281 brilliantly portraying one of my personal heroes, Orson Welles, and after viewing this performance I plan to seek out more of his work. The Daytrippers has been an independent film darling for years now and I can see why. It is an intelligent, emotional and well-written and acted film that will hold an appeal for most who take the time to view it. --Shelly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An engaging detour from writer/director Greg Mottola
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maxpower03
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An engaging indie reminiscent of both Neil Simon and Woody Allen, The Daytrippers utilizes a strong cast as a family travel down literal avenues to unravel a mystery over fidelity. Eliza (Hope Davis) is happily married to publisher Louis (Stanley Tucci), until she discovers a love letter that may or may not have been sent to him. Determined to find out the truth, she travels into the city to confront him, aided by her domineering mother (Anne Meara), subdued father (Pat McNamara), sister Jo (Parker Posey) and her novelist boyfriend Carl (Liev Schreiber). The Daytrippers works best during moments with the Malone family together, from Eliza and Jo's sisterly bonding to mom Rita's fawning over Carl. The various derailments and subplots along the way are a mixed bag, the best allowing for some neat interludes from Marc Grapey as a sleazy womanizer, Marcia Gay Harden as a drunken party girl and Stephanie Venditto as a over-excited receptionist. In terms of acting, Anne Meara steals the show as the fiery matriarch of the Malone family, while a lot of fun is created from Carl's episodic reciting of his novel, a pretentious story about a man with a dog's head. Parker Posey, as always, is also hilarious with her sarcastic gags and deadpan delivery. Not particularly memorable but a movie that at least entertains throughout its short running time, The Daytrippers is an enjoyable melodrama strengthened by the realistic familial chemistry between the film's leads. Rating: C+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Daytrippers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ametaphysicalshark
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before the shockingly good teen comedy "Superbad" and the wistful, sentimental post-collegiate angst of "Adventureland", even before his now famous TV work, director Greg Mottola made this 1996 gem "The Daytrippers". The film, like Mottola's other films, works a familiar and unpromising premise into a genuine, heartfelt, wonderful observation on human behavior. The film, while rougher around the edges technically and as a script than either "Superbad" (written by Seth Rogen and Evan Goldberg) and "Adventureland" (written by Mottola himself, as "The Daytrippers" is), is yet another distinctive and memorable Mottola film. The plot is pretty much covered by the film's tagline: "One station wagon. Two generations. Three couples. Four relationships", but much like Mottola's other films ("Superbad": Two best friends and a nerdy semi-friend attempt to get laid before graduation. "Adventureland": college grad works at amusement park and falls in love) the plot doesn't really give any indication of how good the film is. Great script overall by Mottola with terrific characterization and dialogue which rings true, not to mention mature handling of the relationships as well as a good dose of humor. An excellent cast (at their best too, Mottola's great work with actors on display yet again) including Stanley Tucci, Hope Davis, Liev Schrieber, and Parker Posey bring the script to life well, and Mottola's storytelling skills and comic timing as director are, even this early in his career, excellent. Not as good as his later work, but Mottola shows great promise with this early film. Cannot wait for "Paul", which promises to be absolutely brilliant if his career follows the path it's on (getting better with every film).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a better movie than Little Miss Sunshine...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    saucyvideoguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daytrippers and Little Miss Sunshine have very similar themes of family road trips but 'Daytrippers' was far more sophisticated and understated. I'm pretty disappointed this flick isn't available on the DVD in the U.S. Me and my girlfriend watched this one twice in the theaters during the waining heyday of the indie-film era. Our favorite line: When Parker Posey says, "You know dad, that was basically the worst car chase in history..." HAHAHAHAHAHA! HAHAHAHAHAHA! HAHAHAHAHAHA!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The narrative arch isn't that great but it moves forward with good dialogue and performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eliza D'Amico is in love with her husband Louis and assumes that he feels the same way. However when she finds a note of love poetry in his pocket from someone called Sandy, she worries that he is having an affair. Confiding in her mother, father, sister and her sister's boyfriend, the decision is made for her to take a trip into the city to investigate. After a drive, the group pry into Louis' office and uncover something going on with a colleague called Cassandra. They dig deeper and their trip turns into a full day and night in the city. I can understand those who have problems with the narrative arch of this film because it is a bit unlikely and contrived but it is likely that many viewers will find enjoyment in the dialogue and mood of the film. Never hilarious, the film has a consistently nice comic touch and the dialogue help produce the characters over and above the situations that the plot puts them in. In this way it works reasonably well because it develops the story well enough while using the specific situations to allow for comic dialogue. I wasn't ever laughing and I wasn't ever totally engrossed in the story but it did enough to keep my interest and amuse and interest. Mottola aims for an independent feel and hits it spot on. It has its flaws but it works even if the film stock has dated and looks a bit grainy. The cast work well with the material and Mottola's casting agents have done really well to get such an ensemble together. There is no one clear lead and everyone works well together. Davis is given the least of the characters as she has to carry the plot but she does it well regardless. Posey is more interesting because her character is  plus I always find her easy to enjoy for some reason. Schreiber judges his character well and allows us to spot his annoying characteristics gradually in the same way that Jo would be spotting them with time; often I find him annoying, here it was intentional and his performance is good in that way. Tucci has a minor role and his presence is more about his name that his ability, but he is welcome. Meara and McNarama both work well together and produce the most energy as the parents. All of them work well with the dialogue and the scenarios and do their best with the narrative. Overall this is a light indie film that des have weakness in the narrative but generally makes up for it with good dialogue and a nice air to it. The starry (if you move in that way) cast react well to it and turn in good performances and characters that help the film be better that the narrative arch would suggest it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why this wasn't a box smash I'll never know
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stanton67
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a tone to it that is just perfect. The movie hums like a great song. The movie is never boring. The cast is near perfect. The story yes a little simple but the screenplay has parent/adult children relationships down. This is a story that takes place the day after Thanksgiving. You know that day. Everybody is tired and worn out from the day before. Well on this day a woman finds a note in her husbands pocket, She then shows her parents and sister the note. Before you know it we're on a day road trip with the family to track down Stanley Tuci. To give away more of the story would be a crime. Everybody with a family can relate to this! Don't miss out. Also has a cameo Marcia Gay Harden.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A trip to take
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    graham clarke (grahamclarke@earthling.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Greg Mottola makes a very auspicious debut with "The Daytrippers". He directs a terrific cast in what is something of a rarity; a true ensemble piece. Rather than a road movie, this is a street movie with various stations in lower Manhattan. As the journey progresses so too does the family begin to unravel in a manner which is both funny as well as genuinely moving. All give dead on target performances, with highlights from Ann Meara and Lieve Shrieber (whose unravelling is particularly poignant). Hope Davis is as wistfully wonderful as always with Parker Posey, Stanley Tucci, Pat McNaramra and Campbell Scott rounding out the ensemble. A trip you may want to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, VERY personal movie, a little too close to life ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    serious89
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... a believably bickering family, portrayed by skilled actors, w/some wonderful ham stuff by Anne Meara and Parker Posey, and more subtle stuff from Hope Davis and Liev Schreiber. The story had a distinctly voyeuristic feel, as if the screenwriter was exorcising some history and making it more entertaining, often hilarious (and interesting?) than a painful history he may have lived through. A cinema verite re-creation by world class skilled actors. As the family's lives unravel, driving around in a freezing cold NYC winter evening, there is a quiet lingering shot of the World Trade Center that is unintentionally haunting, and gives the film (made in 1996) an unintended resonance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not your ordinary road trip
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Snoopymichele
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Truly one of the funniest, most original films of the mid 90's. The casting is truly inspired-Anne Meara gives a knockout performance as an overbearing, but well-meaning suburban mother; Hope Davis is marvelous (as usual) as an optimistic, sort of numb wife on a mission to see if her husband is indeed cheating on her; Liev Schreiber is wonderful as the superb Parker Posey's aspiring writer boyfriend; Campbell Scott steals the movie as a lusty writer Eddie; and of course Stanley Tucci turns in another great performance as the catalyst character in the film. His screen time is brief, but he shines brightly. Marcia Gay Harden's cameo as a neurotic party guest had me practically on the floor laughing. The story unfolds naturally, taking the viewer on the same emotional journey as the characters. There's never a dull moment, and the film is an indie classic filled with thought-provoking dialogue and terrific character sketches.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly UNsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Daytrippers" is a script-driven open ended comedy about a semifunctional family (an ensemble cast including mom, dad, two adult daughters, and a boyfriend) who drive into Manhattan in search of a one of the daughters' wayward husband. With nonstop pseudointellectual pedantic blathering from beginning to end, this uneventful flick takes you along for the ride where you'll suffer from small talk, an explanation of the boyfriend's work-in-progress novel, a silly conversation about politics, an encounter involving the carrying of a t.v. set, and other such pedestrianisms resulting in a mediocre flick which fails in script. "The Daytrippers" might best be described as some really bad Woody Allen which is almost rescued by a solid cast. (C)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A small film that is easy to miss but should be seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmOtaku (ssampon@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I've been meaning to see this film for years, (I think the trailer was on the Reservoir Dogs VHS that I wore out before I bought it on DVD) it was one of probably hundreds of films that I put on my back burner. So when I recently saw it was on a pay channel I jumped on it, and am very glad that I did finally see this gem. The Daytrippers involves a woman (Davis) whose resolve that she is happily married is tested when she finds an excerpt from a love poem that fell from her husband's (Tucci) clothes. She elects to go to her mother (Meara) for advice and ends up going on a day trip to NYC to ask her husband about it. Along for the ride is her father, (McNamara) her sister, (Posey) and her sister's boyfriend (Schrieber). Of course, if they were able to simply confront her husband it would be easy; unfortunately he is no where to be found, so they willingly engage in amateur sleuthing to put together the story while they drive around the city looking for him. The plot is a fairly simple one, but the character development is the true star of the film. While Parker Posey is known best for playing `quirky yet intelligent' characters, her role seems more of a natural addition in this film rather than a run-of-the-mill portrayal for her. Meara is nearly maddening as a meddling mother, and McNamara, a well established character actor is heartbreakingly sweet as the weary father. Davis and Tucci are both fantastic as usual, and while Tucci's role is a small one, he exhibits his usual passion that makes him an exciting actor. Davis gives her character a palpable fragility that just barely makes room for the modicum of strength that is holding her together. In my opinion, the true breakout star of the film is Schrieber as Carl Petrovic, `the boyfriend'. His character has so many facets to his personality and becomes such a complex study that is so rare in a supporting character. And Schrieber's portrayal is brilliant and both comedic and heart-breaking in it's subtle profundity. Schreiber has been on my radar since I saw him in RKO 281 brilliantly portraying one of my personal heroes, Orson Welles, and after viewing this performance I plan to seek out more of his work. The Daytrippers has been an independent film darling for years now and I can see why. It is an intelligent, emotional and well-written and acted film that will hold an appeal for most who take the time to view it. --Shelly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
