<filme>
 <id>
  537
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0102494
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1991
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Garotos de Programa
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Two best friends living on the streets of Portland as hustlers embark on a journey of self discovery and find their relationship stumbling along the way.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Surreal character study focusing on the friendship between two male hustlers, Mike and Scott, in Portland, Oregon. They live on the streets, do drugs, and sell themselves to men and women. Mike is quiet, gay and suffers from narcolepsy. Abandoned as a child, he is obsessed with finding his long-lost mother. Scott is the rebellious son of a high-ranking family, who lives this life mostly to embarrass his father. Mike is in love with Scott, who still maintains he is straight and insists that his wild lifestyle on the streets is only temporary. Together, they embark on a quest to find Mike's mother, traveling from Portland to Idaho to Italy, with Scott picking up a beautiful girl along the way.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   hustler
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   italy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   male hustler
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   idaho
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friend
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Gus Van Sant
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   William Shakespeare
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Gus Van Sant
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   River Phoenix
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Keanu Reeves
  </ator>
  <ator>
   James Russo
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River Phoenix is excellent, as is the film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indie_Locker
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant has always been an interesting filmmaker. He cares about character and story and through the process, his artistic integrity is able to shine through his work and that is why he's considered a prominent director in independent cinema. My Own Private Idaho is more of is more well known independent features and is often viewed as a triumph of independent cinema from the 1990s. The film follows Mark Waters (River Phoenix) an aimless, misguided young man who hustles on the streets and is yearning to find his way in life. His best friend is Scott Favor (Keanu Reeves), who is also a young man and and a hustler, but who instead is running away from his life in the hope of finding something better. Scott comes from a lot of wealth but chooses not to live that lifestyle because when he's this young and wild, he just doesn't believe that its right for him. However the film is centered around Mark, who is played with such brutal honestly by the late River Phoenix. River is completely dedicated to the character and brings a wonderful vulnerability to a lost soul and it makes him relatable. We watch him go from scene to scene, leaving us as unaware of his future as he is. We watch him make many mistakes and we want him to better himself but such a task is not easy. Because that's the way life is. Mark hustles because its just who he is. We don't know how he got here, but we know that he has fallen into this lifestyle and it has consumed him. He needs the money. All of his friends are hustlers, too. He has dreams but its tough to say if he ever truly wants to leave the lifestyle. It seems that getting clients and often falling asleep during it (due to him being narcoleptic) doesn't seem to take as much of a toll on him as does his thoughts about his mother, or his feelings for his best friend. Gus Van Sant crafts a very fine film here that focuses on such a lifestyle that we're not exposed to in our every day lives and turns it into something we can all relate to. It all comes back to that road, the road that we're all on. Does it really end? Probably not. Much like in the way that Mark is shown standing on that road, staring out into the nothingness. Its really about our lives. We live and we're happy, and we're sad, and we're lonely, and we're lost, and we've found ourselves, all of these things happen on the very same road that never ends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good... and very flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PrometheusTree64
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought the Criterion Collection DVD of this because I loved River Phoenix before it was a clich&eacute;. Nevertheless, I saw this in the theater when it was first released, and my opinion hasn't changed: Phoenix is as good as you've heard and the film absolutely has it's moments --- many wonderful moments. Then there's Keanu. Who tried to marry this guy to Shakespeare? He's way out of his league with this kind of material. And these sections of the film, especially the group exchanges in the broken-down tenement house, seem badly edited, those conversations unclear in terms of point and plot --- and I've seen the movie multiple times. It's a shame Van Sant went down that road (the characters, specifically Keanu, breaking in and out of classical speech, which simply doesn't work), because there are many things about this picture that are really terrific... So view it with this in mind. ...and this: after the first couple of viewings of this hauntingly-odd picture, the flaws just seem to melt away and don't matter so much. And you can almost always tell a (potentially) good flick when it manages to inexplicably capture the zeitgeist of its era; in fact, I'm not sure I've ever seen one that evokes the cusp of the 80s/90s as vividly. (So did "Midnight Cowboy" for ITS era, so maybe male hookers is all that's really required. Go figure.) Even Keanu gives a better performance in the "normal" (non-Shakespearean) scenes than usual. And, as with every single River Phoenix movie ever filmed, this one is chock-full of eerily prescient moments of doom: like River seizing on the road, sidewalk, etc...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest for Security and the Return to the Tranquil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie years ago and I suspect that I knew that it had relations with Henry IV but until recently I had not see the original Shakespeare play. However, having read both parts, watched a BBC version of both parts, and also seen an amalgamation of both plays on stage I can say that I am much more familiar with it so that I can have a different understanding of this film. When I had first seen the film I had liked it, and I must say that I still like it, but the second time around, including being more familiar with Henry IV, I must say that it did not appeal to me as much. In part I think Van Sant has pulled away significantly from the original play with regards to the themes of the play as well as with regards to the character of Scott (played by Keanu Reeves and is Hal from the play). In a way Scott and Hal are both rebellious teenagers, but Scott is much more conscious of his desire to 'come good' when he turns 21 whereas this does not seem to be the case with Hal. In fact Hal has to prove to his father that he desires to become good, whereas it is clear from the film that Scott is in no danger of losing his inheritance. In Henry IV Poins is more of a supporting character who acts not so much as Hal's conscience but rather as a friend. In the film though Mike (River Pheonix, who corresponds with Poins) plays a much more important and central role. In fact the film is actually focused on Mike, as he goes on a fruitless search for his mother. There is tension between Mike and Scott because it is clear that Mike loves Scott but this love is not returned. This is something that we know is never going to happen, particularly when Scott says at the opening that as long as you do it for money then it is okay, but as soon as you begin to do it for free, you grow wings (and with that he then looks up at Mike as if suggesting that Mike has already grown wings). Another difference we see is that Scott readily deserts Scott when he gets his inheritance and finds the woman that he takes as his wife (though there is no indicating that there is any love, and we raise the question as to whether Scott is capable of love). Henry IV is many cases is about the right of passage that Hal takes from being a rebellious teenager to becoming a king, but this is something that we do not necessarily see here. Scott is not going through a rite of passage, nor is he learning, he is just having fun and behaving like a child while he is a child, and when he comes into his inheritance, he rejects his past and moves on. Okay, at the final scene, were the two funerals are contrasted (and one could say that both of Scott's fathers have died and are being buried) we see a part of Scott looking on at the other funeral. In a way the past has died, but one past, that of the wild and chaotic nature of youth, is also being buried to be replaced with the cold, clinical nature of adult life. I actually found Van Sant's attempts at Shakespearian language to be rather contrived. In the two scenes which are clearly taken from the play, that of Scott's rejection of Bob (who is the Falstaff figure) and the scene were he is mocking Bob after the robbery, we see that Van Sant is trying to create the poetic nature of the original play but using modern language in doing so. To me this fails completely. I can sort of see what he is going, and in a way he is using the play to build upon Scott's character, but the thing is that the movie is focused on Mike and not on Scott. Mike is vulnerable in many ways. Not only does he not understand himself, or even his sexuality (he confuses friendship with erotic love, and this is something that is not returned) he suffers from Narcolepsy. As long as Scott is around, Mike is safe, but as soon as Scott leaves we discover that he is more vulnerable than ever. In a way Mike's search for his mother is his search for security, in the same way that his quest for love is also his quest for security. We know that as long as Scott is around, Mike is secure, but when we see him on the street, back in Portland, we know that this is no longer the case. Then there is Idaho. The movie begins in Idaho, ends in Idaho, and visits Idaho in the middle. It is as if it is this tranquil place between the horrors of the world outside. It is the world of the unique, of the quite, and of the peaceful that pushes away the world of the street. We see the street in Seattle, in Portland, and even in Rome. Granted, we leave Rome for the country, but in a way it is not Idaho. Mike feels secure in Idaho, but not in Italy. However, we learn at the end that no even Idaho offers that protection, for when he collapses again, he is robbed. I guess the idea of the title suggests that is the case, one's search for peace, and that part inside of you were you can feel secure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets boring as it progresses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that starts off promising but as it progresses it just gets weird and bizarre but just not in a good way. It had my interest at first with the introduction of the characters but after the introductions and a bit of bonding between two characters it just got boring. I think the part I lost interest is when River Phoenix's character is visiting his dad in a trailer. It's basically a depressing and bitter road movie about two gay or bisexual male prostitutes on a road trip. Because they both have mother and father issues that they have to deal with. I give River Phoenix's character some sympathy but not so much for Keanu's character. Maybe because one is more in a rut than the other. And none of the characters are likable in this movie, which is fine since when it comes to the tragedy. It didn't get all that depressing. But the relationship and bonding between these two characters played by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves seemed authentic. Maybe because they were friends in real life. It's somewhat of a artsy flick and it's watchable but just didn't really entertain me or got my interest. It got weird and some of the characters gets pretty darn bizarre. But I guess it somewhat adds to the realism to a degree. This is the first movie I seen with River Phoenix and he basically owns this character. But maybe that is cause there is quite a lot of himself in this character. And Keanu...Well I never found the guy to be a brilliant actor. But he is somewhat versatile and fits right in usually with the role he is in. Overall, this movie through me off guard but not really in a good way. Plus I couldn't connect with any of the characters at all, although that may seem a bit conceited on my part. 4.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River tunes out, Keanu slums
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho is a bittersweet tale of two rent boys in the Pacific coast are and the contrasts between them. With the help of the greatest writer in the English language ever, William Shakespeare, Gus Van Sant draws two great characterizations in the characters realized by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves. You couldn't find two more opposite types in the world. River is a street kid through and through. Even the circumstances of his birth are a tragedy that I won't reveal. His mother leaves him as a youngster and he can't get over it and go on. He was raised by an older brother in the sparsely populated 'potato state' as he calls Idaho and the and the family dynamic was strained. He's a gay kid in an area where that could be deadly so he takes off for the fleshpots of Seattle and Portland where his youth and beauty will bring him some cash. He has no skills or education to support himself any other way. Sad, but the only hope this kid has of a decent life is to get taken up by some older sugar daddy who might just treat him to an education of some kind. That is if he can decide to just get over a bad home life and lack of a normal family. I've known gay kids who came from as lousy a background as River Phoenix and who never could get over it. River has developed an interesting defense mechanism and a psychologist would have field day with him if he got him on the coach. When the stress gets too much for him he just has a seizure like an epileptic, but in fact all he does is fall asleep. It's called narcilepsy, but he's vulnerable in that state as the film shows as well. River just tunes out the world. Keanu comes from a different world, his father is the Mayor of Portland, but he's dying and hopes to have his son take over the family political dynasty. But Tom Troupe is bitterly disappointed in his 'effeminate' son who like Prince Hal likes to hang out with lowlifes and street trash. Keanu's Falstaff is William Richert, a gay older man of a Falstaffian bloated belly who likes the young stuff and in his world probably treats them well. Gus Van Sant was quite imaginative in seeing the gay subtext that could be drawn from Prince Hal and Falstaff. Indeed Keanu says that Richert is closer to him than his real father. But he also says that he's planning to work a change in him when he comes into his own. And he says it in dialog taken from Shakespeare's Henry IV Parts one and two. The most touching scene is with River and Keanu out in the country at a fire where River basically confesses his love for him. It's love to be sure, but River also sees in Keanu a figure who has confidence and self assurance and those are the qualities that draws him to Reeves. What Phoenix misreads is that self confidence is really a safety net that he knows he has and at the appropriate time uses. Although he's gay for pay as he states, he still allows River to have sex with him. I suspect that Gus Van Sant from his own background knows full well that gay for pay is not always 100% absolute. Reeves goes on to his destiny for which if you know your Shakespeare know what that is. Phoenix's destiny is less clear, more than likely an oblivion that a lot of those kids go to. As a fantasy I'd like to think that as Reeves denies himself, closets himself as he moves on in life, that an older River comes back to remind him of his roots. We all know of the tragedy of River Phoenix who died way too young just like a lot of street kids do ironically. There is a second tragedy in the My Own Private Idaho. Rodney Harvey who played one of River and Keanu's street peers also died way too young in similar circumstances to Phoenix. Not only does Van Sant give us an excellent two person character study, but his other character with less dialog than the leads also are fully formed characters which is the mark that many including me say indicates a great film. My Own Private Idaho is a troubling picture, but a realistic one of the underside of gay life that we cannot ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As current today as it was then....a modern classic perhaps.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho Director: Gus Van Sant Starring: River Phoenix, Keanu Reeves, James Russo. Gus Van Sant essentially takes on Shakespeare's Henry IV; it featured the aesthetically delightful River Phoenix as Mike Waters, a wonderfully apt narcoleptic male whore who we first get a glimpse of tipping down an open stretch of road in Idaho. Mike and the action shifts from the cold Seattle to equally cold Portland. It is here that he makes friends with Scott Favor, a secretly soon to be rich guy who is also on the game played by the often-maligned Keanu Reeves. The future for both is as uncertain as uncertain can be, will Scott take up the inheritance he about to get, will Mike survive the streets with his narcolepsy? ￼ Mike feels real affections for Scott, however Scott refuses to believe men can really love each and it would seem that Scott is only doing the gay whole whore thing to kill time and get back at his family. Mike believes Scott will continue with the grand life on the streets, turning tricks even after he bags the inheritance; such is the allure of the unknown. There are many of fellow working boys who agree with Mike's view. This is an uneasy picture, a colourful and surreal attempt to really take the characters to a different kingdom. At times, it is a wonderful although slightly glossy take on the real street hustlers shagging their way to oblivion or not as the individual case may be. Drug abuse and risky behaviours are commonplace on the streets and in the world of the male hooker and it is a small feature of this sometimes-disturbing film. The character of Mike seems almost apologetically plausible, abandoned as a child and obsessed with finding his real long lost mother. Scott less believable as the rebellious disillusioned spoilt little rich kid gone rebelliously bad. You really would not have put them together by design, but fate disregards those lines and together they embark on a quest to find Mike's mother, from Portland to Idaho to Italy they do travel. There is no argument the cinematic quality and the unbelievably stunning settings help to make this film an intriguingly striking viewing delight. It is exceptionally well thought out in terms of location and setting and a master-class for any would be cinematographer. The characterisation I found to be impressive, even Keanu Reeves played his part with just the right amount of smug pathos and humour, especially with the flippantly arrogant lines afford to him. River Phoenix works pure magic on screen with this performance and I am fairly sure I'm not alone in believing this is the role that set him into the great immortal movie star hall of fame. It is no wonder that he pulled in a number of 'best actor' type awards for this intrinsically faceted role. His campfire scene, in which Mike declares his love for Scott, is much applauded by audiences and critics alike  Newsweek claiming it to be "A marvel of delicacy" it really is a testament to what a wonderful talent River Phoenix was, because he wrote that part of the script himself. Village Voice said, "Phoenix vanishes with reckless triumph into his role". It earned around &pound;5 million at the box office worldwide, which is quite impressive, more than that in video and DVD sales. My Own Private Idaho takes the spirit and passion of Shakespeare, bends, manipulates and shapes it to find form in a more modern setting, which works beyond expectation in the most part. Although the traditionalist in me seems to hold the opinion that you should not mess with old Shaky and if you do, you best be prepared to face the harshest of critics. Adaptations are always open to personal interpretation and modifications, which others may not agree with, like or even accept, yet this one seems to work and seems to be commended as a job well done.Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem in the movie genre - very emotional & moving with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry07
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard of this movie for a while now (since it came out I guess) and never had the chance to watch it. Finally, I got my hand on a DVD and was stunned: how could I have missed this before? I would classify this movie in the Indie genre (if that applied to movies), as its style is unusual. Essentially, the dialogs may go into long theatrical speech (literally) rather than a fluent every day life dialog. You get annoyed at times (did not expect a Shakespeare play but a movie) as some of the scenes within this style are not working out (imagine Keanu Reeves in a play - nope! doesn't work for me either). But if you can pass beyond this problem, you will find a gem. Indeed, the characters! What a treat. River Phoenix (Mike) performance is simply breathtaking and inspired: you immediately feel the character of "Mike", the abandoned and confused child not only reverting to hustling for money but striving for belonging, acceptance and love going in life with the dream and memory of his mother. His friendship with Scott (Keanu Reeves) will bring them into a journey where emotions and classics are all covered: lightness and energy of youth, rebellion of the privileged, loneliness, burning passions, struggles and survival, loss, desire. On second thought, perhaps it works well as a Shakespearian play (yes, I know it was intended) but not only because the dialogs are like so but due to the in-depth drama of this movie the breadth of emotion it covers. The story line is flooded with the view of Mike (also narcoleptic) and appears at times as a dream. As a result, to me, the whole movie is simply a great piece, poetic, breath taking and emotional: you stay watching through the theater scenes wanting to know what's next, you get hooked to the artistic aspects of the movie (music is often blending and you find yourself noticing that many details have significance) and you feel for the characters at a deep and intense level as if the topics treated are archetypal. For sure, you will remember this movie whether you were thrown off by it, liked it or loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    trippy arty homage to Shakespeare's Henry IV. a powerful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every time I see this film, I forget how incredibly amazing it is. Yes I'm a huge fan of of the late, great, River Phoenix, think Keanu Reeves is highly underrated, and love Shakespeare. This is a modern adaptation to Henry IV, based around two hustlers Mike and Scott (River and Keanu) and their relationship, with the added wrinkle that Mikey is a narcoleptic and trying to find his long lost mother. Scott is the rich boy who turns his back on his street life when his inheritance kicks in. River's performance is astounding, tender and powerful, and it's a brave pair of best friends (in real life) that take on roles like this but the affection between them is palpable and somehow makes the story of unrequited love even more heartbreaking. The Shakespeare gets confusing if you aren't familiar, as it washes in and out, and if you haven't seen Gus Van Sant before you might not quite follow the surreal imagery and the trippy nature of the film. It's arty, weird and dark, but has a lot of humour and sensitivity, despite being a little bawdy in places, however for all it's adult subject matter it's quite discrete! River and Keanu are astounding in this, and it's a film that River should be remembered for as the bright star he was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like a super 8
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like a super 8 film from the 70's/80's New York this felt like it was art created for the screen on a setting, the open plan falling down dilapidated building. Beautifully shot with scenes of the hills and fields that seemed to roll on forever. The acting even included San Sant himself as well as Grace Zabriskie who is normally in David Lynch's films. The story was maybe even too weird for me and didn't really get a resonance and stayed very flat, it was not his best but showed how he can make his films. Although it was maybe too weird it still made me want to be there in that building, the place where creativity happens, as spaces like that spark imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much ado about nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A narcoleptic hustler and his 'degenerate' (to his father) pal travel the Pacific Northwest in search ofwhat? Freedom? Affection? Adventure? Gus Van Sant's follow up to his career breakthrough 'Drugstore Cowboy' is full odd stylistic tics and transparent social commentary, all of it adding up to a merely pretentious film even more aimless and unmotivated than its two primary characters. Viewers might be forgiven for wondering where the story is going after the brief detour into Idaho itself (the trailer home reunion is a highlight), when the scene shifts abruptly, and for no good reason, to sunny Rome (yes, in Italy). There's plenty to look at, but all the gorgeous imagery hides a shortage of real ideas, and Van Sant's mock Shakespearean dialogue is an annoying conceit (at least the Bard is acknowledged in the credits). Udo Kier, as 'Hans', steals the film away from its two young stars, and the brief documentary appearance of actual teenage hustlers discussing their 'dates' shows what the film could have aspired to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River Phoenix is excellent, as is the film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indie_Locker
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant has always been an interesting filmmaker. He cares about character and story and through the process, his artistic integrity is able to shine through his work and that is why he's considered a prominent director in independent cinema. My Own Private Idaho is more of is more well known independent features and is often viewed as a triumph of independent cinema from the 1990s. The film follows Mark Waters (River Phoenix) an aimless, misguided young man who hustles on the streets and is yearning to find his way in life. His best friend is Scott Favor (Keanu Reeves), who is also a young man and and a hustler, but who instead is running away from his life in the hope of finding something better. Scott comes from a lot of wealth but chooses not to live that lifestyle because when he's this young and wild, he just doesn't believe that its right for him. However the film is centered around Mark, who is played with such brutal honestly by the late River Phoenix. River is completely dedicated to the character and brings a wonderful vulnerability to a lost soul and it makes him relatable. We watch him go from scene to scene, leaving us as unaware of his future as he is. We watch him make many mistakes and we want him to better himself but such a task is not easy. Because that's the way life is. Mark hustles because its just who he is. We don't know how he got here, but we know that he has fallen into this lifestyle and it has consumed him. He needs the money. All of his friends are hustlers, too. He has dreams but its tough to say if he ever truly wants to leave the lifestyle. It seems that getting clients and often falling asleep during it (due to him being narcoleptic) doesn't seem to take as much of a toll on him as does his thoughts about his mother, or his feelings for his best friend. Gus Van Sant crafts a very fine film here that focuses on such a lifestyle that we're not exposed to in our every day lives and turns it into something we can all relate to. It all comes back to that road, the road that we're all on. Does it really end? Probably not. Much like in the way that Mark is shown standing on that road, staring out into the nothingness. Its really about our lives. We live and we're happy, and we're sad, and we're lonely, and we're lost, and we've found ourselves, all of these things happen on the very same road that never ends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good... and very flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PrometheusTree64
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought the Criterion Collection DVD of this because I loved River Phoenix before it was a clich&eacute;. Nevertheless, I saw this in the theater when it was first released, and my opinion hasn't changed: Phoenix is as good as you've heard and the film absolutely has it's moments --- many wonderful moments. Then there's Keanu. Who tried to marry this guy to Shakespeare? He's way out of his league with this kind of material. And these sections of the film, especially the group exchanges in the broken-down tenement house, seem badly edited, those conversations unclear in terms of point and plot --- and I've seen the movie multiple times. It's a shame Van Sant went down that road (the characters, specifically Keanu, breaking in and out of classical speech, which simply doesn't work), because there are many things about this picture that are really terrific... So view it with this in mind. ...and this: after the first couple of viewings of this hauntingly-odd picture, the flaws just seem to melt away and don't matter so much. And you can almost always tell a (potentially) good flick when it manages to inexplicably capture the zeitgeist of its era; in fact, I'm not sure I've ever seen one that evokes the cusp of the 80s/90s as vividly. (So did "Midnight Cowboy" for ITS era, so maybe male hookers is all that's really required. Go figure.) Even Keanu gives a better performance in the "normal" (non-Shakespearean) scenes than usual. And, as with every single River Phoenix movie ever filmed, this one is chock-full of eerily prescient moments of doom: like River seizing on the road, sidewalk, etc...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest for Security and the Return to the Tranquil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie years ago and I suspect that I knew that it had relations with Henry IV but until recently I had not see the original Shakespeare play. However, having read both parts, watched a BBC version of both parts, and also seen an amalgamation of both plays on stage I can say that I am much more familiar with it so that I can have a different understanding of this film. When I had first seen the film I had liked it, and I must say that I still like it, but the second time around, including being more familiar with Henry IV, I must say that it did not appeal to me as much. In part I think Van Sant has pulled away significantly from the original play with regards to the themes of the play as well as with regards to the character of Scott (played by Keanu Reeves and is Hal from the play). In a way Scott and Hal are both rebellious teenagers, but Scott is much more conscious of his desire to 'come good' when he turns 21 whereas this does not seem to be the case with Hal. In fact Hal has to prove to his father that he desires to become good, whereas it is clear from the film that Scott is in no danger of losing his inheritance. In Henry IV Poins is more of a supporting character who acts not so much as Hal's conscience but rather as a friend. In the film though Mike (River Pheonix, who corresponds with Poins) plays a much more important and central role. In fact the film is actually focused on Mike, as he goes on a fruitless search for his mother. There is tension between Mike and Scott because it is clear that Mike loves Scott but this love is not returned. This is something that we know is never going to happen, particularly when Scott says at the opening that as long as you do it for money then it is okay, but as soon as you begin to do it for free, you grow wings (and with that he then looks up at Mike as if suggesting that Mike has already grown wings). Another difference we see is that Scott readily deserts Scott when he gets his inheritance and finds the woman that he takes as his wife (though there is no indicating that there is any love, and we raise the question as to whether Scott is capable of love). Henry IV is many cases is about the right of passage that Hal takes from being a rebellious teenager to becoming a king, but this is something that we do not necessarily see here. Scott is not going through a rite of passage, nor is he learning, he is just having fun and behaving like a child while he is a child, and when he comes into his inheritance, he rejects his past and moves on. Okay, at the final scene, were the two funerals are contrasted (and one could say that both of Scott's fathers have died and are being buried) we see a part of Scott looking on at the other funeral. In a way the past has died, but one past, that of the wild and chaotic nature of youth, is also being buried to be replaced with the cold, clinical nature of adult life. I actually found Van Sant's attempts at Shakespearian language to be rather contrived. In the two scenes which are clearly taken from the play, that of Scott's rejection of Bob (who is the Falstaff figure) and the scene were he is mocking Bob after the robbery, we see that Van Sant is trying to create the poetic nature of the original play but using modern language in doing so. To me this fails completely. I can sort of see what he is going, and in a way he is using the play to build upon Scott's character, but the thing is that the movie is focused on Mike and not on Scott. Mike is vulnerable in many ways. Not only does he not understand himself, or even his sexuality (he confuses friendship with erotic love, and this is something that is not returned) he suffers from Narcolepsy. As long as Scott is around, Mike is safe, but as soon as Scott leaves we discover that he is more vulnerable than ever. In a way Mike's search for his mother is his search for security, in the same way that his quest for love is also his quest for security. We know that as long as Scott is around, Mike is secure, but when we see him on the street, back in Portland, we know that this is no longer the case. Then there is Idaho. The movie begins in Idaho, ends in Idaho, and visits Idaho in the middle. It is as if it is this tranquil place between the horrors of the world outside. It is the world of the unique, of the quite, and of the peaceful that pushes away the world of the street. We see the street in Seattle, in Portland, and even in Rome. Granted, we leave Rome for the country, but in a way it is not Idaho. Mike feels secure in Idaho, but not in Italy. However, we learn at the end that no even Idaho offers that protection, for when he collapses again, he is robbed. I guess the idea of the title suggests that is the case, one's search for peace, and that part inside of you were you can feel secure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets boring as it progresses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that starts off promising but as it progresses it just gets weird and bizarre but just not in a good way. It had my interest at first with the introduction of the characters but after the introductions and a bit of bonding between two characters it just got boring. I think the part I lost interest is when River Phoenix's character is visiting his dad in a trailer. It's basically a depressing and bitter road movie about two gay or bisexual male prostitutes on a road trip. Because they both have mother and father issues that they have to deal with. I give River Phoenix's character some sympathy but not so much for Keanu's character. Maybe because one is more in a rut than the other. And none of the characters are likable in this movie, which is fine since when it comes to the tragedy. It didn't get all that depressing. But the relationship and bonding between these two characters played by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves seemed authentic. Maybe because they were friends in real life. It's somewhat of a artsy flick and it's watchable but just didn't really entertain me or got my interest. It got weird and some of the characters gets pretty darn bizarre. But I guess it somewhat adds to the realism to a degree. This is the first movie I seen with River Phoenix and he basically owns this character. But maybe that is cause there is quite a lot of himself in this character. And Keanu...Well I never found the guy to be a brilliant actor. But he is somewhat versatile and fits right in usually with the role he is in. Overall, this movie through me off guard but not really in a good way. Plus I couldn't connect with any of the characters at all, although that may seem a bit conceited on my part. 4.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River tunes out, Keanu slums
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho is a bittersweet tale of two rent boys in the Pacific coast are and the contrasts between them. With the help of the greatest writer in the English language ever, William Shakespeare, Gus Van Sant draws two great characterizations in the characters realized by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves. You couldn't find two more opposite types in the world. River is a street kid through and through. Even the circumstances of his birth are a tragedy that I won't reveal. His mother leaves him as a youngster and he can't get over it and go on. He was raised by an older brother in the sparsely populated 'potato state' as he calls Idaho and the and the family dynamic was strained. He's a gay kid in an area where that could be deadly so he takes off for the fleshpots of Seattle and Portland where his youth and beauty will bring him some cash. He has no skills or education to support himself any other way. Sad, but the only hope this kid has of a decent life is to get taken up by some older sugar daddy who might just treat him to an education of some kind. That is if he can decide to just get over a bad home life and lack of a normal family. I've known gay kids who came from as lousy a background as River Phoenix and who never could get over it. River has developed an interesting defense mechanism and a psychologist would have field day with him if he got him on the coach. When the stress gets too much for him he just has a seizure like an epileptic, but in fact all he does is fall asleep. It's called narcilepsy, but he's vulnerable in that state as the film shows as well. River just tunes out the world. Keanu comes from a different world, his father is the Mayor of Portland, but he's dying and hopes to have his son take over the family political dynasty. But Tom Troupe is bitterly disappointed in his 'effeminate' son who like Prince Hal likes to hang out with lowlifes and street trash. Keanu's Falstaff is William Richert, a gay older man of a Falstaffian bloated belly who likes the young stuff and in his world probably treats them well. Gus Van Sant was quite imaginative in seeing the gay subtext that could be drawn from Prince Hal and Falstaff. Indeed Keanu says that Richert is closer to him than his real father. But he also says that he's planning to work a change in him when he comes into his own. And he says it in dialog taken from Shakespeare's Henry IV Parts one and two. The most touching scene is with River and Keanu out in the country at a fire where River basically confesses his love for him. It's love to be sure, but River also sees in Keanu a figure who has confidence and self assurance and those are the qualities that draws him to Reeves. What Phoenix misreads is that self confidence is really a safety net that he knows he has and at the appropriate time uses. Although he's gay for pay as he states, he still allows River to have sex with him. I suspect that Gus Van Sant from his own background knows full well that gay for pay is not always 100% absolute. Reeves goes on to his destiny for which if you know your Shakespeare know what that is. Phoenix's destiny is less clear, more than likely an oblivion that a lot of those kids go to. As a fantasy I'd like to think that as Reeves denies himself, closets himself as he moves on in life, that an older River comes back to remind him of his roots. We all know of the tragedy of River Phoenix who died way too young just like a lot of street kids do ironically. There is a second tragedy in the My Own Private Idaho. Rodney Harvey who played one of River and Keanu's street peers also died way too young in similar circumstances to Phoenix. Not only does Van Sant give us an excellent two person character study, but his other character with less dialog than the leads also are fully formed characters which is the mark that many including me say indicates a great film. My Own Private Idaho is a troubling picture, but a realistic one of the underside of gay life that we cannot ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As current today as it was then....a modern classic perhaps.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho Director: Gus Van Sant Starring: River Phoenix, Keanu Reeves, James Russo. Gus Van Sant essentially takes on Shakespeare's Henry IV; it featured the aesthetically delightful River Phoenix as Mike Waters, a wonderfully apt narcoleptic male whore who we first get a glimpse of tipping down an open stretch of road in Idaho. Mike and the action shifts from the cold Seattle to equally cold Portland. It is here that he makes friends with Scott Favor, a secretly soon to be rich guy who is also on the game played by the often-maligned Keanu Reeves. The future for both is as uncertain as uncertain can be, will Scott take up the inheritance he about to get, will Mike survive the streets with his narcolepsy? ￼ Mike feels real affections for Scott, however Scott refuses to believe men can really love each and it would seem that Scott is only doing the gay whole whore thing to kill time and get back at his family. Mike believes Scott will continue with the grand life on the streets, turning tricks even after he bags the inheritance; such is the allure of the unknown. There are many of fellow working boys who agree with Mike's view. This is an uneasy picture, a colourful and surreal attempt to really take the characters to a different kingdom. At times, it is a wonderful although slightly glossy take on the real street hustlers shagging their way to oblivion or not as the individual case may be. Drug abuse and risky behaviours are commonplace on the streets and in the world of the male hooker and it is a small feature of this sometimes-disturbing film. The character of Mike seems almost apologetically plausible, abandoned as a child and obsessed with finding his real long lost mother. Scott less believable as the rebellious disillusioned spoilt little rich kid gone rebelliously bad. You really would not have put them together by design, but fate disregards those lines and together they embark on a quest to find Mike's mother, from Portland to Idaho to Italy they do travel. There is no argument the cinematic quality and the unbelievably stunning settings help to make this film an intriguingly striking viewing delight. It is exceptionally well thought out in terms of location and setting and a master-class for any would be cinematographer. The characterisation I found to be impressive, even Keanu Reeves played his part with just the right amount of smug pathos and humour, especially with the flippantly arrogant lines afford to him. River Phoenix works pure magic on screen with this performance and I am fairly sure I'm not alone in believing this is the role that set him into the great immortal movie star hall of fame. It is no wonder that he pulled in a number of 'best actor' type awards for this intrinsically faceted role. His campfire scene, in which Mike declares his love for Scott, is much applauded by audiences and critics alike  Newsweek claiming it to be "A marvel of delicacy" it really is a testament to what a wonderful talent River Phoenix was, because he wrote that part of the script himself. Village Voice said, "Phoenix vanishes with reckless triumph into his role". It earned around &pound;5 million at the box office worldwide, which is quite impressive, more than that in video and DVD sales. My Own Private Idaho takes the spirit and passion of Shakespeare, bends, manipulates and shapes it to find form in a more modern setting, which works beyond expectation in the most part. Although the traditionalist in me seems to hold the opinion that you should not mess with old Shaky and if you do, you best be prepared to face the harshest of critics. Adaptations are always open to personal interpretation and modifications, which others may not agree with, like or even accept, yet this one seems to work and seems to be commended as a job well done.Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem in the movie genre - very emotional & moving with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry07
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard of this movie for a while now (since it came out I guess) and never had the chance to watch it. Finally, I got my hand on a DVD and was stunned: how could I have missed this before? I would classify this movie in the Indie genre (if that applied to movies), as its style is unusual. Essentially, the dialogs may go into long theatrical speech (literally) rather than a fluent every day life dialog. You get annoyed at times (did not expect a Shakespeare play but a movie) as some of the scenes within this style are not working out (imagine Keanu Reeves in a play - nope! doesn't work for me either). But if you can pass beyond this problem, you will find a gem. Indeed, the characters! What a treat. River Phoenix (Mike) performance is simply breathtaking and inspired: you immediately feel the character of "Mike", the abandoned and confused child not only reverting to hustling for money but striving for belonging, acceptance and love going in life with the dream and memory of his mother. His friendship with Scott (Keanu Reeves) will bring them into a journey where emotions and classics are all covered: lightness and energy of youth, rebellion of the privileged, loneliness, burning passions, struggles and survival, loss, desire. On second thought, perhaps it works well as a Shakespearian play (yes, I know it was intended) but not only because the dialogs are like so but due to the in-depth drama of this movie the breadth of emotion it covers. The story line is flooded with the view of Mike (also narcoleptic) and appears at times as a dream. As a result, to me, the whole movie is simply a great piece, poetic, breath taking and emotional: you stay watching through the theater scenes wanting to know what's next, you get hooked to the artistic aspects of the movie (music is often blending and you find yourself noticing that many details have significance) and you feel for the characters at a deep and intense level as if the topics treated are archetypal. For sure, you will remember this movie whether you were thrown off by it, liked it or loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    trippy arty homage to Shakespeare's Henry IV. a powerful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every time I see this film, I forget how incredibly amazing it is. Yes I'm a huge fan of of the late, great, River Phoenix, think Keanu Reeves is highly underrated, and love Shakespeare. This is a modern adaptation to Henry IV, based around two hustlers Mike and Scott (River and Keanu) and their relationship, with the added wrinkle that Mikey is a narcoleptic and trying to find his long lost mother. Scott is the rich boy who turns his back on his street life when his inheritance kicks in. River's performance is astounding, tender and powerful, and it's a brave pair of best friends (in real life) that take on roles like this but the affection between them is palpable and somehow makes the story of unrequited love even more heartbreaking. The Shakespeare gets confusing if you aren't familiar, as it washes in and out, and if you haven't seen Gus Van Sant before you might not quite follow the surreal imagery and the trippy nature of the film. It's arty, weird and dark, but has a lot of humour and sensitivity, despite being a little bawdy in places, however for all it's adult subject matter it's quite discrete! River and Keanu are astounding in this, and it's a film that River should be remembered for as the bright star he was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like a super 8
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like a super 8 film from the 70's/80's New York this felt like it was art created for the screen on a setting, the open plan falling down dilapidated building. Beautifully shot with scenes of the hills and fields that seemed to roll on forever. The acting even included San Sant himself as well as Grace Zabriskie who is normally in David Lynch's films. The story was maybe even too weird for me and didn't really get a resonance and stayed very flat, it was not his best but showed how he can make his films. Although it was maybe too weird it still made me want to be there in that building, the place where creativity happens, as spaces like that spark imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much ado about nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A narcoleptic hustler and his 'degenerate' (to his father) pal travel the Pacific Northwest in search ofwhat? Freedom? Affection? Adventure? Gus Van Sant's follow up to his career breakthrough 'Drugstore Cowboy' is full odd stylistic tics and transparent social commentary, all of it adding up to a merely pretentious film even more aimless and unmotivated than its two primary characters. Viewers might be forgiven for wondering where the story is going after the brief detour into Idaho itself (the trailer home reunion is a highlight), when the scene shifts abruptly, and for no good reason, to sunny Rome (yes, in Italy). There's plenty to look at, but all the gorgeous imagery hides a shortage of real ideas, and Van Sant's mock Shakespearean dialogue is an annoying conceit (at least the Bard is acknowledged in the credits). Udo Kier, as 'Hans', steals the film away from its two young stars, and the brief documentary appearance of actual teenage hustlers discussing their 'dates' shows what the film could have aspired to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River Phoenix is excellent, as is the film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indie_Locker
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant has always been an interesting filmmaker. He cares about character and story and through the process, his artistic integrity is able to shine through his work and that is why he's considered a prominent director in independent cinema. My Own Private Idaho is more of is more well known independent features and is often viewed as a triumph of independent cinema from the 1990s. The film follows Mark Waters (River Phoenix) an aimless, misguided young man who hustles on the streets and is yearning to find his way in life. His best friend is Scott Favor (Keanu Reeves), who is also a young man and and a hustler, but who instead is running away from his life in the hope of finding something better. Scott comes from a lot of wealth but chooses not to live that lifestyle because when he's this young and wild, he just doesn't believe that its right for him. However the film is centered around Mark, who is played with such brutal honestly by the late River Phoenix. River is completely dedicated to the character and brings a wonderful vulnerability to a lost soul and it makes him relatable. We watch him go from scene to scene, leaving us as unaware of his future as he is. We watch him make many mistakes and we want him to better himself but such a task is not easy. Because that's the way life is. Mark hustles because its just who he is. We don't know how he got here, but we know that he has fallen into this lifestyle and it has consumed him. He needs the money. All of his friends are hustlers, too. He has dreams but its tough to say if he ever truly wants to leave the lifestyle. It seems that getting clients and often falling asleep during it (due to him being narcoleptic) doesn't seem to take as much of a toll on him as does his thoughts about his mother, or his feelings for his best friend. Gus Van Sant crafts a very fine film here that focuses on such a lifestyle that we're not exposed to in our every day lives and turns it into something we can all relate to. It all comes back to that road, the road that we're all on. Does it really end? Probably not. Much like in the way that Mark is shown standing on that road, staring out into the nothingness. Its really about our lives. We live and we're happy, and we're sad, and we're lonely, and we're lost, and we've found ourselves, all of these things happen on the very same road that never ends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good... and very flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PrometheusTree64
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought the Criterion Collection DVD of this because I loved River Phoenix before it was a clich&eacute;. Nevertheless, I saw this in the theater when it was first released, and my opinion hasn't changed: Phoenix is as good as you've heard and the film absolutely has it's moments --- many wonderful moments. Then there's Keanu. Who tried to marry this guy to Shakespeare? He's way out of his league with this kind of material. And these sections of the film, especially the group exchanges in the broken-down tenement house, seem badly edited, those conversations unclear in terms of point and plot --- and I've seen the movie multiple times. It's a shame Van Sant went down that road (the characters, specifically Keanu, breaking in and out of classical speech, which simply doesn't work), because there are many things about this picture that are really terrific... So view it with this in mind. ...and this: after the first couple of viewings of this hauntingly-odd picture, the flaws just seem to melt away and don't matter so much. And you can almost always tell a (potentially) good flick when it manages to inexplicably capture the zeitgeist of its era; in fact, I'm not sure I've ever seen one that evokes the cusp of the 80s/90s as vividly. (So did "Midnight Cowboy" for ITS era, so maybe male hookers is all that's really required. Go figure.) Even Keanu gives a better performance in the "normal" (non-Shakespearean) scenes than usual. And, as with every single River Phoenix movie ever filmed, this one is chock-full of eerily prescient moments of doom: like River seizing on the road, sidewalk, etc...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest for Security and the Return to the Tranquil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie years ago and I suspect that I knew that it had relations with Henry IV but until recently I had not see the original Shakespeare play. However, having read both parts, watched a BBC version of both parts, and also seen an amalgamation of both plays on stage I can say that I am much more familiar with it so that I can have a different understanding of this film. When I had first seen the film I had liked it, and I must say that I still like it, but the second time around, including being more familiar with Henry IV, I must say that it did not appeal to me as much. In part I think Van Sant has pulled away significantly from the original play with regards to the themes of the play as well as with regards to the character of Scott (played by Keanu Reeves and is Hal from the play). In a way Scott and Hal are both rebellious teenagers, but Scott is much more conscious of his desire to 'come good' when he turns 21 whereas this does not seem to be the case with Hal. In fact Hal has to prove to his father that he desires to become good, whereas it is clear from the film that Scott is in no danger of losing his inheritance. In Henry IV Poins is more of a supporting character who acts not so much as Hal's conscience but rather as a friend. In the film though Mike (River Pheonix, who corresponds with Poins) plays a much more important and central role. In fact the film is actually focused on Mike, as he goes on a fruitless search for his mother. There is tension between Mike and Scott because it is clear that Mike loves Scott but this love is not returned. This is something that we know is never going to happen, particularly when Scott says at the opening that as long as you do it for money then it is okay, but as soon as you begin to do it for free, you grow wings (and with that he then looks up at Mike as if suggesting that Mike has already grown wings). Another difference we see is that Scott readily deserts Scott when he gets his inheritance and finds the woman that he takes as his wife (though there is no indicating that there is any love, and we raise the question as to whether Scott is capable of love). Henry IV is many cases is about the right of passage that Hal takes from being a rebellious teenager to becoming a king, but this is something that we do not necessarily see here. Scott is not going through a rite of passage, nor is he learning, he is just having fun and behaving like a child while he is a child, and when he comes into his inheritance, he rejects his past and moves on. Okay, at the final scene, were the two funerals are contrasted (and one could say that both of Scott's fathers have died and are being buried) we see a part of Scott looking on at the other funeral. In a way the past has died, but one past, that of the wild and chaotic nature of youth, is also being buried to be replaced with the cold, clinical nature of adult life. I actually found Van Sant's attempts at Shakespearian language to be rather contrived. In the two scenes which are clearly taken from the play, that of Scott's rejection of Bob (who is the Falstaff figure) and the scene were he is mocking Bob after the robbery, we see that Van Sant is trying to create the poetic nature of the original play but using modern language in doing so. To me this fails completely. I can sort of see what he is going, and in a way he is using the play to build upon Scott's character, but the thing is that the movie is focused on Mike and not on Scott. Mike is vulnerable in many ways. Not only does he not understand himself, or even his sexuality (he confuses friendship with erotic love, and this is something that is not returned) he suffers from Narcolepsy. As long as Scott is around, Mike is safe, but as soon as Scott leaves we discover that he is more vulnerable than ever. In a way Mike's search for his mother is his search for security, in the same way that his quest for love is also his quest for security. We know that as long as Scott is around, Mike is secure, but when we see him on the street, back in Portland, we know that this is no longer the case. Then there is Idaho. The movie begins in Idaho, ends in Idaho, and visits Idaho in the middle. It is as if it is this tranquil place between the horrors of the world outside. It is the world of the unique, of the quite, and of the peaceful that pushes away the world of the street. We see the street in Seattle, in Portland, and even in Rome. Granted, we leave Rome for the country, but in a way it is not Idaho. Mike feels secure in Idaho, but not in Italy. However, we learn at the end that no even Idaho offers that protection, for when he collapses again, he is robbed. I guess the idea of the title suggests that is the case, one's search for peace, and that part inside of you were you can feel secure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets boring as it progresses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that starts off promising but as it progresses it just gets weird and bizarre but just not in a good way. It had my interest at first with the introduction of the characters but after the introductions and a bit of bonding between two characters it just got boring. I think the part I lost interest is when River Phoenix's character is visiting his dad in a trailer. It's basically a depressing and bitter road movie about two gay or bisexual male prostitutes on a road trip. Because they both have mother and father issues that they have to deal with. I give River Phoenix's character some sympathy but not so much for Keanu's character. Maybe because one is more in a rut than the other. And none of the characters are likable in this movie, which is fine since when it comes to the tragedy. It didn't get all that depressing. But the relationship and bonding between these two characters played by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves seemed authentic. Maybe because they were friends in real life. It's somewhat of a artsy flick and it's watchable but just didn't really entertain me or got my interest. It got weird and some of the characters gets pretty darn bizarre. But I guess it somewhat adds to the realism to a degree. This is the first movie I seen with River Phoenix and he basically owns this character. But maybe that is cause there is quite a lot of himself in this character. And Keanu...Well I never found the guy to be a brilliant actor. But he is somewhat versatile and fits right in usually with the role he is in. Overall, this movie through me off guard but not really in a good way. Plus I couldn't connect with any of the characters at all, although that may seem a bit conceited on my part. 4.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River tunes out, Keanu slums
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho is a bittersweet tale of two rent boys in the Pacific coast are and the contrasts between them. With the help of the greatest writer in the English language ever, William Shakespeare, Gus Van Sant draws two great characterizations in the characters realized by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves. You couldn't find two more opposite types in the world. River is a street kid through and through. Even the circumstances of his birth are a tragedy that I won't reveal. His mother leaves him as a youngster and he can't get over it and go on. He was raised by an older brother in the sparsely populated 'potato state' as he calls Idaho and the and the family dynamic was strained. He's a gay kid in an area where that could be deadly so he takes off for the fleshpots of Seattle and Portland where his youth and beauty will bring him some cash. He has no skills or education to support himself any other way. Sad, but the only hope this kid has of a decent life is to get taken up by some older sugar daddy who might just treat him to an education of some kind. That is if he can decide to just get over a bad home life and lack of a normal family. I've known gay kids who came from as lousy a background as River Phoenix and who never could get over it. River has developed an interesting defense mechanism and a psychologist would have field day with him if he got him on the coach. When the stress gets too much for him he just has a seizure like an epileptic, but in fact all he does is fall asleep. It's called narcilepsy, but he's vulnerable in that state as the film shows as well. River just tunes out the world. Keanu comes from a different world, his father is the Mayor of Portland, but he's dying and hopes to have his son take over the family political dynasty. But Tom Troupe is bitterly disappointed in his 'effeminate' son who like Prince Hal likes to hang out with lowlifes and street trash. Keanu's Falstaff is William Richert, a gay older man of a Falstaffian bloated belly who likes the young stuff and in his world probably treats them well. Gus Van Sant was quite imaginative in seeing the gay subtext that could be drawn from Prince Hal and Falstaff. Indeed Keanu says that Richert is closer to him than his real father. But he also says that he's planning to work a change in him when he comes into his own. And he says it in dialog taken from Shakespeare's Henry IV Parts one and two. The most touching scene is with River and Keanu out in the country at a fire where River basically confesses his love for him. It's love to be sure, but River also sees in Keanu a figure who has confidence and self assurance and those are the qualities that draws him to Reeves. What Phoenix misreads is that self confidence is really a safety net that he knows he has and at the appropriate time uses. Although he's gay for pay as he states, he still allows River to have sex with him. I suspect that Gus Van Sant from his own background knows full well that gay for pay is not always 100% absolute. Reeves goes on to his destiny for which if you know your Shakespeare know what that is. Phoenix's destiny is less clear, more than likely an oblivion that a lot of those kids go to. As a fantasy I'd like to think that as Reeves denies himself, closets himself as he moves on in life, that an older River comes back to remind him of his roots. We all know of the tragedy of River Phoenix who died way too young just like a lot of street kids do ironically. There is a second tragedy in the My Own Private Idaho. Rodney Harvey who played one of River and Keanu's street peers also died way too young in similar circumstances to Phoenix. Not only does Van Sant give us an excellent two person character study, but his other character with less dialog than the leads also are fully formed characters which is the mark that many including me say indicates a great film. My Own Private Idaho is a troubling picture, but a realistic one of the underside of gay life that we cannot ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As current today as it was then....a modern classic perhaps.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho Director: Gus Van Sant Starring: River Phoenix, Keanu Reeves, James Russo. Gus Van Sant essentially takes on Shakespeare's Henry IV; it featured the aesthetically delightful River Phoenix as Mike Waters, a wonderfully apt narcoleptic male whore who we first get a glimpse of tipping down an open stretch of road in Idaho. Mike and the action shifts from the cold Seattle to equally cold Portland. It is here that he makes friends with Scott Favor, a secretly soon to be rich guy who is also on the game played by the often-maligned Keanu Reeves. The future for both is as uncertain as uncertain can be, will Scott take up the inheritance he about to get, will Mike survive the streets with his narcolepsy? ￼ Mike feels real affections for Scott, however Scott refuses to believe men can really love each and it would seem that Scott is only doing the gay whole whore thing to kill time and get back at his family. Mike believes Scott will continue with the grand life on the streets, turning tricks even after he bags the inheritance; such is the allure of the unknown. There are many of fellow working boys who agree with Mike's view. This is an uneasy picture, a colourful and surreal attempt to really take the characters to a different kingdom. At times, it is a wonderful although slightly glossy take on the real street hustlers shagging their way to oblivion or not as the individual case may be. Drug abuse and risky behaviours are commonplace on the streets and in the world of the male hooker and it is a small feature of this sometimes-disturbing film. The character of Mike seems almost apologetically plausible, abandoned as a child and obsessed with finding his real long lost mother. Scott less believable as the rebellious disillusioned spoilt little rich kid gone rebelliously bad. You really would not have put them together by design, but fate disregards those lines and together they embark on a quest to find Mike's mother, from Portland to Idaho to Italy they do travel. There is no argument the cinematic quality and the unbelievably stunning settings help to make this film an intriguingly striking viewing delight. It is exceptionally well thought out in terms of location and setting and a master-class for any would be cinematographer. The characterisation I found to be impressive, even Keanu Reeves played his part with just the right amount of smug pathos and humour, especially with the flippantly arrogant lines afford to him. River Phoenix works pure magic on screen with this performance and I am fairly sure I'm not alone in believing this is the role that set him into the great immortal movie star hall of fame. It is no wonder that he pulled in a number of 'best actor' type awards for this intrinsically faceted role. His campfire scene, in which Mike declares his love for Scott, is much applauded by audiences and critics alike  Newsweek claiming it to be "A marvel of delicacy" it really is a testament to what a wonderful talent River Phoenix was, because he wrote that part of the script himself. Village Voice said, "Phoenix vanishes with reckless triumph into his role". It earned around &pound;5 million at the box office worldwide, which is quite impressive, more than that in video and DVD sales. My Own Private Idaho takes the spirit and passion of Shakespeare, bends, manipulates and shapes it to find form in a more modern setting, which works beyond expectation in the most part. Although the traditionalist in me seems to hold the opinion that you should not mess with old Shaky and if you do, you best be prepared to face the harshest of critics. Adaptations are always open to personal interpretation and modifications, which others may not agree with, like or even accept, yet this one seems to work and seems to be commended as a job well done.Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem in the movie genre - very emotional & moving with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry07
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard of this movie for a while now (since it came out I guess) and never had the chance to watch it. Finally, I got my hand on a DVD and was stunned: how could I have missed this before? I would classify this movie in the Indie genre (if that applied to movies), as its style is unusual. Essentially, the dialogs may go into long theatrical speech (literally) rather than a fluent every day life dialog. You get annoyed at times (did not expect a Shakespeare play but a movie) as some of the scenes within this style are not working out (imagine Keanu Reeves in a play - nope! doesn't work for me either). But if you can pass beyond this problem, you will find a gem. Indeed, the characters! What a treat. River Phoenix (Mike) performance is simply breathtaking and inspired: you immediately feel the character of "Mike", the abandoned and confused child not only reverting to hustling for money but striving for belonging, acceptance and love going in life with the dream and memory of his mother. His friendship with Scott (Keanu Reeves) will bring them into a journey where emotions and classics are all covered: lightness and energy of youth, rebellion of the privileged, loneliness, burning passions, struggles and survival, loss, desire. On second thought, perhaps it works well as a Shakespearian play (yes, I know it was intended) but not only because the dialogs are like so but due to the in-depth drama of this movie the breadth of emotion it covers. The story line is flooded with the view of Mike (also narcoleptic) and appears at times as a dream. As a result, to me, the whole movie is simply a great piece, poetic, breath taking and emotional: you stay watching through the theater scenes wanting to know what's next, you get hooked to the artistic aspects of the movie (music is often blending and you find yourself noticing that many details have significance) and you feel for the characters at a deep and intense level as if the topics treated are archetypal. For sure, you will remember this movie whether you were thrown off by it, liked it or loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    trippy arty homage to Shakespeare's Henry IV. a powerful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every time I see this film, I forget how incredibly amazing it is. Yes I'm a huge fan of of the late, great, River Phoenix, think Keanu Reeves is highly underrated, and love Shakespeare. This is a modern adaptation to Henry IV, based around two hustlers Mike and Scott (River and Keanu) and their relationship, with the added wrinkle that Mikey is a narcoleptic and trying to find his long lost mother. Scott is the rich boy who turns his back on his street life when his inheritance kicks in. River's performance is astounding, tender and powerful, and it's a brave pair of best friends (in real life) that take on roles like this but the affection between them is palpable and somehow makes the story of unrequited love even more heartbreaking. The Shakespeare gets confusing if you aren't familiar, as it washes in and out, and if you haven't seen Gus Van Sant before you might not quite follow the surreal imagery and the trippy nature of the film. It's arty, weird and dark, but has a lot of humour and sensitivity, despite being a little bawdy in places, however for all it's adult subject matter it's quite discrete! River and Keanu are astounding in this, and it's a film that River should be remembered for as the bright star he was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like a super 8
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like a super 8 film from the 70's/80's New York this felt like it was art created for the screen on a setting, the open plan falling down dilapidated building. Beautifully shot with scenes of the hills and fields that seemed to roll on forever. The acting even included San Sant himself as well as Grace Zabriskie who is normally in David Lynch's films. The story was maybe even too weird for me and didn't really get a resonance and stayed very flat, it was not his best but showed how he can make his films. Although it was maybe too weird it still made me want to be there in that building, the place where creativity happens, as spaces like that spark imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much ado about nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A narcoleptic hustler and his 'degenerate' (to his father) pal travel the Pacific Northwest in search ofwhat? Freedom? Affection? Adventure? Gus Van Sant's follow up to his career breakthrough 'Drugstore Cowboy' is full odd stylistic tics and transparent social commentary, all of it adding up to a merely pretentious film even more aimless and unmotivated than its two primary characters. Viewers might be forgiven for wondering where the story is going after the brief detour into Idaho itself (the trailer home reunion is a highlight), when the scene shifts abruptly, and for no good reason, to sunny Rome (yes, in Italy). There's plenty to look at, but all the gorgeous imagery hides a shortage of real ideas, and Van Sant's mock Shakespearean dialogue is an annoying conceit (at least the Bard is acknowledged in the credits). Udo Kier, as 'Hans', steals the film away from its two young stars, and the brief documentary appearance of actual teenage hustlers discussing their 'dates' shows what the film could have aspired to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River Phoenix is excellent, as is the film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indie_Locker
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant has always been an interesting filmmaker. He cares about character and story and through the process, his artistic integrity is able to shine through his work and that is why he's considered a prominent director in independent cinema. My Own Private Idaho is more of is more well known independent features and is often viewed as a triumph of independent cinema from the 1990s. The film follows Mark Waters (River Phoenix) an aimless, misguided young man who hustles on the streets and is yearning to find his way in life. His best friend is Scott Favor (Keanu Reeves), who is also a young man and and a hustler, but who instead is running away from his life in the hope of finding something better. Scott comes from a lot of wealth but chooses not to live that lifestyle because when he's this young and wild, he just doesn't believe that its right for him. However the film is centered around Mark, who is played with such brutal honestly by the late River Phoenix. River is completely dedicated to the character and brings a wonderful vulnerability to a lost soul and it makes him relatable. We watch him go from scene to scene, leaving us as unaware of his future as he is. We watch him make many mistakes and we want him to better himself but such a task is not easy. Because that's the way life is. Mark hustles because its just who he is. We don't know how he got here, but we know that he has fallen into this lifestyle and it has consumed him. He needs the money. All of his friends are hustlers, too. He has dreams but its tough to say if he ever truly wants to leave the lifestyle. It seems that getting clients and often falling asleep during it (due to him being narcoleptic) doesn't seem to take as much of a toll on him as does his thoughts about his mother, or his feelings for his best friend. Gus Van Sant crafts a very fine film here that focuses on such a lifestyle that we're not exposed to in our every day lives and turns it into something we can all relate to. It all comes back to that road, the road that we're all on. Does it really end? Probably not. Much like in the way that Mark is shown standing on that road, staring out into the nothingness. Its really about our lives. We live and we're happy, and we're sad, and we're lonely, and we're lost, and we've found ourselves, all of these things happen on the very same road that never ends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good... and very flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PrometheusTree64
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought the Criterion Collection DVD of this because I loved River Phoenix before it was a clich&eacute;. Nevertheless, I saw this in the theater when it was first released, and my opinion hasn't changed: Phoenix is as good as you've heard and the film absolutely has it's moments --- many wonderful moments. Then there's Keanu. Who tried to marry this guy to Shakespeare? He's way out of his league with this kind of material. And these sections of the film, especially the group exchanges in the broken-down tenement house, seem badly edited, those conversations unclear in terms of point and plot --- and I've seen the movie multiple times. It's a shame Van Sant went down that road (the characters, specifically Keanu, breaking in and out of classical speech, which simply doesn't work), because there are many things about this picture that are really terrific... So view it with this in mind. ...and this: after the first couple of viewings of this hauntingly-odd picture, the flaws just seem to melt away and don't matter so much. And you can almost always tell a (potentially) good flick when it manages to inexplicably capture the zeitgeist of its era; in fact, I'm not sure I've ever seen one that evokes the cusp of the 80s/90s as vividly. (So did "Midnight Cowboy" for ITS era, so maybe male hookers is all that's really required. Go figure.) Even Keanu gives a better performance in the "normal" (non-Shakespearean) scenes than usual. And, as with every single River Phoenix movie ever filmed, this one is chock-full of eerily prescient moments of doom: like River seizing on the road, sidewalk, etc...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest for Security and the Return to the Tranquil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie years ago and I suspect that I knew that it had relations with Henry IV but until recently I had not see the original Shakespeare play. However, having read both parts, watched a BBC version of both parts, and also seen an amalgamation of both plays on stage I can say that I am much more familiar with it so that I can have a different understanding of this film. When I had first seen the film I had liked it, and I must say that I still like it, but the second time around, including being more familiar with Henry IV, I must say that it did not appeal to me as much. In part I think Van Sant has pulled away significantly from the original play with regards to the themes of the play as well as with regards to the character of Scott (played by Keanu Reeves and is Hal from the play). In a way Scott and Hal are both rebellious teenagers, but Scott is much more conscious of his desire to 'come good' when he turns 21 whereas this does not seem to be the case with Hal. In fact Hal has to prove to his father that he desires to become good, whereas it is clear from the film that Scott is in no danger of losing his inheritance. In Henry IV Poins is more of a supporting character who acts not so much as Hal's conscience but rather as a friend. In the film though Mike (River Pheonix, who corresponds with Poins) plays a much more important and central role. In fact the film is actually focused on Mike, as he goes on a fruitless search for his mother. There is tension between Mike and Scott because it is clear that Mike loves Scott but this love is not returned. This is something that we know is never going to happen, particularly when Scott says at the opening that as long as you do it for money then it is okay, but as soon as you begin to do it for free, you grow wings (and with that he then looks up at Mike as if suggesting that Mike has already grown wings). Another difference we see is that Scott readily deserts Scott when he gets his inheritance and finds the woman that he takes as his wife (though there is no indicating that there is any love, and we raise the question as to whether Scott is capable of love). Henry IV is many cases is about the right of passage that Hal takes from being a rebellious teenager to becoming a king, but this is something that we do not necessarily see here. Scott is not going through a rite of passage, nor is he learning, he is just having fun and behaving like a child while he is a child, and when he comes into his inheritance, he rejects his past and moves on. Okay, at the final scene, were the two funerals are contrasted (and one could say that both of Scott's fathers have died and are being buried) we see a part of Scott looking on at the other funeral. In a way the past has died, but one past, that of the wild and chaotic nature of youth, is also being buried to be replaced with the cold, clinical nature of adult life. I actually found Van Sant's attempts at Shakespearian language to be rather contrived. In the two scenes which are clearly taken from the play, that of Scott's rejection of Bob (who is the Falstaff figure) and the scene were he is mocking Bob after the robbery, we see that Van Sant is trying to create the poetic nature of the original play but using modern language in doing so. To me this fails completely. I can sort of see what he is going, and in a way he is using the play to build upon Scott's character, but the thing is that the movie is focused on Mike and not on Scott. Mike is vulnerable in many ways. Not only does he not understand himself, or even his sexuality (he confuses friendship with erotic love, and this is something that is not returned) he suffers from Narcolepsy. As long as Scott is around, Mike is safe, but as soon as Scott leaves we discover that he is more vulnerable than ever. In a way Mike's search for his mother is his search for security, in the same way that his quest for love is also his quest for security. We know that as long as Scott is around, Mike is secure, but when we see him on the street, back in Portland, we know that this is no longer the case. Then there is Idaho. The movie begins in Idaho, ends in Idaho, and visits Idaho in the middle. It is as if it is this tranquil place between the horrors of the world outside. It is the world of the unique, of the quite, and of the peaceful that pushes away the world of the street. We see the street in Seattle, in Portland, and even in Rome. Granted, we leave Rome for the country, but in a way it is not Idaho. Mike feels secure in Idaho, but not in Italy. However, we learn at the end that no even Idaho offers that protection, for when he collapses again, he is robbed. I guess the idea of the title suggests that is the case, one's search for peace, and that part inside of you were you can feel secure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets boring as it progresses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that starts off promising but as it progresses it just gets weird and bizarre but just not in a good way. It had my interest at first with the introduction of the characters but after the introductions and a bit of bonding between two characters it just got boring. I think the part I lost interest is when River Phoenix's character is visiting his dad in a trailer. It's basically a depressing and bitter road movie about two gay or bisexual male prostitutes on a road trip. Because they both have mother and father issues that they have to deal with. I give River Phoenix's character some sympathy but not so much for Keanu's character. Maybe because one is more in a rut than the other. And none of the characters are likable in this movie, which is fine since when it comes to the tragedy. It didn't get all that depressing. But the relationship and bonding between these two characters played by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves seemed authentic. Maybe because they were friends in real life. It's somewhat of a artsy flick and it's watchable but just didn't really entertain me or got my interest. It got weird and some of the characters gets pretty darn bizarre. But I guess it somewhat adds to the realism to a degree. This is the first movie I seen with River Phoenix and he basically owns this character. But maybe that is cause there is quite a lot of himself in this character. And Keanu...Well I never found the guy to be a brilliant actor. But he is somewhat versatile and fits right in usually with the role he is in. Overall, this movie through me off guard but not really in a good way. Plus I couldn't connect with any of the characters at all, although that may seem a bit conceited on my part. 4.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River tunes out, Keanu slums
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho is a bittersweet tale of two rent boys in the Pacific coast are and the contrasts between them. With the help of the greatest writer in the English language ever, William Shakespeare, Gus Van Sant draws two great characterizations in the characters realized by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves. You couldn't find two more opposite types in the world. River is a street kid through and through. Even the circumstances of his birth are a tragedy that I won't reveal. His mother leaves him as a youngster and he can't get over it and go on. He was raised by an older brother in the sparsely populated 'potato state' as he calls Idaho and the and the family dynamic was strained. He's a gay kid in an area where that could be deadly so he takes off for the fleshpots of Seattle and Portland where his youth and beauty will bring him some cash. He has no skills or education to support himself any other way. Sad, but the only hope this kid has of a decent life is to get taken up by some older sugar daddy who might just treat him to an education of some kind. That is if he can decide to just get over a bad home life and lack of a normal family. I've known gay kids who came from as lousy a background as River Phoenix and who never could get over it. River has developed an interesting defense mechanism and a psychologist would have field day with him if he got him on the coach. When the stress gets too much for him he just has a seizure like an epileptic, but in fact all he does is fall asleep. It's called narcilepsy, but he's vulnerable in that state as the film shows as well. River just tunes out the world. Keanu comes from a different world, his father is the Mayor of Portland, but he's dying and hopes to have his son take over the family political dynasty. But Tom Troupe is bitterly disappointed in his 'effeminate' son who like Prince Hal likes to hang out with lowlifes and street trash. Keanu's Falstaff is William Richert, a gay older man of a Falstaffian bloated belly who likes the young stuff and in his world probably treats them well. Gus Van Sant was quite imaginative in seeing the gay subtext that could be drawn from Prince Hal and Falstaff. Indeed Keanu says that Richert is closer to him than his real father. But he also says that he's planning to work a change in him when he comes into his own. And he says it in dialog taken from Shakespeare's Henry IV Parts one and two. The most touching scene is with River and Keanu out in the country at a fire where River basically confesses his love for him. It's love to be sure, but River also sees in Keanu a figure who has confidence and self assurance and those are the qualities that draws him to Reeves. What Phoenix misreads is that self confidence is really a safety net that he knows he has and at the appropriate time uses. Although he's gay for pay as he states, he still allows River to have sex with him. I suspect that Gus Van Sant from his own background knows full well that gay for pay is not always 100% absolute. Reeves goes on to his destiny for which if you know your Shakespeare know what that is. Phoenix's destiny is less clear, more than likely an oblivion that a lot of those kids go to. As a fantasy I'd like to think that as Reeves denies himself, closets himself as he moves on in life, that an older River comes back to remind him of his roots. We all know of the tragedy of River Phoenix who died way too young just like a lot of street kids do ironically. There is a second tragedy in the My Own Private Idaho. Rodney Harvey who played one of River and Keanu's street peers also died way too young in similar circumstances to Phoenix. Not only does Van Sant give us an excellent two person character study, but his other character with less dialog than the leads also are fully formed characters which is the mark that many including me say indicates a great film. My Own Private Idaho is a troubling picture, but a realistic one of the underside of gay life that we cannot ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As current today as it was then....a modern classic perhaps.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho Director: Gus Van Sant Starring: River Phoenix, Keanu Reeves, James Russo. Gus Van Sant essentially takes on Shakespeare's Henry IV; it featured the aesthetically delightful River Phoenix as Mike Waters, a wonderfully apt narcoleptic male whore who we first get a glimpse of tipping down an open stretch of road in Idaho. Mike and the action shifts from the cold Seattle to equally cold Portland. It is here that he makes friends with Scott Favor, a secretly soon to be rich guy who is also on the game played by the often-maligned Keanu Reeves. The future for both is as uncertain as uncertain can be, will Scott take up the inheritance he about to get, will Mike survive the streets with his narcolepsy? ￼ Mike feels real affections for Scott, however Scott refuses to believe men can really love each and it would seem that Scott is only doing the gay whole whore thing to kill time and get back at his family. Mike believes Scott will continue with the grand life on the streets, turning tricks even after he bags the inheritance; such is the allure of the unknown. There are many of fellow working boys who agree with Mike's view. This is an uneasy picture, a colourful and surreal attempt to really take the characters to a different kingdom. At times, it is a wonderful although slightly glossy take on the real street hustlers shagging their way to oblivion or not as the individual case may be. Drug abuse and risky behaviours are commonplace on the streets and in the world of the male hooker and it is a small feature of this sometimes-disturbing film. The character of Mike seems almost apologetically plausible, abandoned as a child and obsessed with finding his real long lost mother. Scott less believable as the rebellious disillusioned spoilt little rich kid gone rebelliously bad. You really would not have put them together by design, but fate disregards those lines and together they embark on a quest to find Mike's mother, from Portland to Idaho to Italy they do travel. There is no argument the cinematic quality and the unbelievably stunning settings help to make this film an intriguingly striking viewing delight. It is exceptionally well thought out in terms of location and setting and a master-class for any would be cinematographer. The characterisation I found to be impressive, even Keanu Reeves played his part with just the right amount of smug pathos and humour, especially with the flippantly arrogant lines afford to him. River Phoenix works pure magic on screen with this performance and I am fairly sure I'm not alone in believing this is the role that set him into the great immortal movie star hall of fame. It is no wonder that he pulled in a number of 'best actor' type awards for this intrinsically faceted role. His campfire scene, in which Mike declares his love for Scott, is much applauded by audiences and critics alike  Newsweek claiming it to be "A marvel of delicacy" it really is a testament to what a wonderful talent River Phoenix was, because he wrote that part of the script himself. Village Voice said, "Phoenix vanishes with reckless triumph into his role". It earned around &pound;5 million at the box office worldwide, which is quite impressive, more than that in video and DVD sales. My Own Private Idaho takes the spirit and passion of Shakespeare, bends, manipulates and shapes it to find form in a more modern setting, which works beyond expectation in the most part. Although the traditionalist in me seems to hold the opinion that you should not mess with old Shaky and if you do, you best be prepared to face the harshest of critics. Adaptations are always open to personal interpretation and modifications, which others may not agree with, like or even accept, yet this one seems to work and seems to be commended as a job well done.Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem in the movie genre - very emotional & moving with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry07
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard of this movie for a while now (since it came out I guess) and never had the chance to watch it. Finally, I got my hand on a DVD and was stunned: how could I have missed this before? I would classify this movie in the Indie genre (if that applied to movies), as its style is unusual. Essentially, the dialogs may go into long theatrical speech (literally) rather than a fluent every day life dialog. You get annoyed at times (did not expect a Shakespeare play but a movie) as some of the scenes within this style are not working out (imagine Keanu Reeves in a play - nope! doesn't work for me either). But if you can pass beyond this problem, you will find a gem. Indeed, the characters! What a treat. River Phoenix (Mike) performance is simply breathtaking and inspired: you immediately feel the character of "Mike", the abandoned and confused child not only reverting to hustling for money but striving for belonging, acceptance and love going in life with the dream and memory of his mother. His friendship with Scott (Keanu Reeves) will bring them into a journey where emotions and classics are all covered: lightness and energy of youth, rebellion of the privileged, loneliness, burning passions, struggles and survival, loss, desire. On second thought, perhaps it works well as a Shakespearian play (yes, I know it was intended) but not only because the dialogs are like so but due to the in-depth drama of this movie the breadth of emotion it covers. The story line is flooded with the view of Mike (also narcoleptic) and appears at times as a dream. As a result, to me, the whole movie is simply a great piece, poetic, breath taking and emotional: you stay watching through the theater scenes wanting to know what's next, you get hooked to the artistic aspects of the movie (music is often blending and you find yourself noticing that many details have significance) and you feel for the characters at a deep and intense level as if the topics treated are archetypal. For sure, you will remember this movie whether you were thrown off by it, liked it or loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    trippy arty homage to Shakespeare's Henry IV. a powerful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every time I see this film, I forget how incredibly amazing it is. Yes I'm a huge fan of of the late, great, River Phoenix, think Keanu Reeves is highly underrated, and love Shakespeare. This is a modern adaptation to Henry IV, based around two hustlers Mike and Scott (River and Keanu) and their relationship, with the added wrinkle that Mikey is a narcoleptic and trying to find his long lost mother. Scott is the rich boy who turns his back on his street life when his inheritance kicks in. River's performance is astounding, tender and powerful, and it's a brave pair of best friends (in real life) that take on roles like this but the affection between them is palpable and somehow makes the story of unrequited love even more heartbreaking. The Shakespeare gets confusing if you aren't familiar, as it washes in and out, and if you haven't seen Gus Van Sant before you might not quite follow the surreal imagery and the trippy nature of the film. It's arty, weird and dark, but has a lot of humour and sensitivity, despite being a little bawdy in places, however for all it's adult subject matter it's quite discrete! River and Keanu are astounding in this, and it's a film that River should be remembered for as the bright star he was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like a super 8
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like a super 8 film from the 70's/80's New York this felt like it was art created for the screen on a setting, the open plan falling down dilapidated building. Beautifully shot with scenes of the hills and fields that seemed to roll on forever. The acting even included San Sant himself as well as Grace Zabriskie who is normally in David Lynch's films. The story was maybe even too weird for me and didn't really get a resonance and stayed very flat, it was not his best but showed how he can make his films. Although it was maybe too weird it still made me want to be there in that building, the place where creativity happens, as spaces like that spark imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much ado about nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A narcoleptic hustler and his 'degenerate' (to his father) pal travel the Pacific Northwest in search ofwhat? Freedom? Affection? Adventure? Gus Van Sant's follow up to his career breakthrough 'Drugstore Cowboy' is full odd stylistic tics and transparent social commentary, all of it adding up to a merely pretentious film even more aimless and unmotivated than its two primary characters. Viewers might be forgiven for wondering where the story is going after the brief detour into Idaho itself (the trailer home reunion is a highlight), when the scene shifts abruptly, and for no good reason, to sunny Rome (yes, in Italy). There's plenty to look at, but all the gorgeous imagery hides a shortage of real ideas, and Van Sant's mock Shakespearean dialogue is an annoying conceit (at least the Bard is acknowledged in the credits). Udo Kier, as 'Hans', steals the film away from its two young stars, and the brief documentary appearance of actual teenage hustlers discussing their 'dates' shows what the film could have aspired to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River Phoenix is excellent, as is the film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indie_Locker
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant has always been an interesting filmmaker. He cares about character and story and through the process, his artistic integrity is able to shine through his work and that is why he's considered a prominent director in independent cinema. My Own Private Idaho is more of is more well known independent features and is often viewed as a triumph of independent cinema from the 1990s. The film follows Mark Waters (River Phoenix) an aimless, misguided young man who hustles on the streets and is yearning to find his way in life. His best friend is Scott Favor (Keanu Reeves), who is also a young man and and a hustler, but who instead is running away from his life in the hope of finding something better. Scott comes from a lot of wealth but chooses not to live that lifestyle because when he's this young and wild, he just doesn't believe that its right for him. However the film is centered around Mark, who is played with such brutal honestly by the late River Phoenix. River is completely dedicated to the character and brings a wonderful vulnerability to a lost soul and it makes him relatable. We watch him go from scene to scene, leaving us as unaware of his future as he is. We watch him make many mistakes and we want him to better himself but such a task is not easy. Because that's the way life is. Mark hustles because its just who he is. We don't know how he got here, but we know that he has fallen into this lifestyle and it has consumed him. He needs the money. All of his friends are hustlers, too. He has dreams but its tough to say if he ever truly wants to leave the lifestyle. It seems that getting clients and often falling asleep during it (due to him being narcoleptic) doesn't seem to take as much of a toll on him as does his thoughts about his mother, or his feelings for his best friend. Gus Van Sant crafts a very fine film here that focuses on such a lifestyle that we're not exposed to in our every day lives and turns it into something we can all relate to. It all comes back to that road, the road that we're all on. Does it really end? Probably not. Much like in the way that Mark is shown standing on that road, staring out into the nothingness. Its really about our lives. We live and we're happy, and we're sad, and we're lonely, and we're lost, and we've found ourselves, all of these things happen on the very same road that never ends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good... and very flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PrometheusTree64
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought the Criterion Collection DVD of this because I loved River Phoenix before it was a clich&eacute;. Nevertheless, I saw this in the theater when it was first released, and my opinion hasn't changed: Phoenix is as good as you've heard and the film absolutely has it's moments --- many wonderful moments. Then there's Keanu. Who tried to marry this guy to Shakespeare? He's way out of his league with this kind of material. And these sections of the film, especially the group exchanges in the broken-down tenement house, seem badly edited, those conversations unclear in terms of point and plot --- and I've seen the movie multiple times. It's a shame Van Sant went down that road (the characters, specifically Keanu, breaking in and out of classical speech, which simply doesn't work), because there are many things about this picture that are really terrific... So view it with this in mind. ...and this: after the first couple of viewings of this hauntingly-odd picture, the flaws just seem to melt away and don't matter so much. And you can almost always tell a (potentially) good flick when it manages to inexplicably capture the zeitgeist of its era; in fact, I'm not sure I've ever seen one that evokes the cusp of the 80s/90s as vividly. (So did "Midnight Cowboy" for ITS era, so maybe male hookers is all that's really required. Go figure.) Even Keanu gives a better performance in the "normal" (non-Shakespearean) scenes than usual. And, as with every single River Phoenix movie ever filmed, this one is chock-full of eerily prescient moments of doom: like River seizing on the road, sidewalk, etc...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest for Security and the Return to the Tranquil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie years ago and I suspect that I knew that it had relations with Henry IV but until recently I had not see the original Shakespeare play. However, having read both parts, watched a BBC version of both parts, and also seen an amalgamation of both plays on stage I can say that I am much more familiar with it so that I can have a different understanding of this film. When I had first seen the film I had liked it, and I must say that I still like it, but the second time around, including being more familiar with Henry IV, I must say that it did not appeal to me as much. In part I think Van Sant has pulled away significantly from the original play with regards to the themes of the play as well as with regards to the character of Scott (played by Keanu Reeves and is Hal from the play). In a way Scott and Hal are both rebellious teenagers, but Scott is much more conscious of his desire to 'come good' when he turns 21 whereas this does not seem to be the case with Hal. In fact Hal has to prove to his father that he desires to become good, whereas it is clear from the film that Scott is in no danger of losing his inheritance. In Henry IV Poins is more of a supporting character who acts not so much as Hal's conscience but rather as a friend. In the film though Mike (River Pheonix, who corresponds with Poins) plays a much more important and central role. In fact the film is actually focused on Mike, as he goes on a fruitless search for his mother. There is tension between Mike and Scott because it is clear that Mike loves Scott but this love is not returned. This is something that we know is never going to happen, particularly when Scott says at the opening that as long as you do it for money then it is okay, but as soon as you begin to do it for free, you grow wings (and with that he then looks up at Mike as if suggesting that Mike has already grown wings). Another difference we see is that Scott readily deserts Scott when he gets his inheritance and finds the woman that he takes as his wife (though there is no indicating that there is any love, and we raise the question as to whether Scott is capable of love). Henry IV is many cases is about the right of passage that Hal takes from being a rebellious teenager to becoming a king, but this is something that we do not necessarily see here. Scott is not going through a rite of passage, nor is he learning, he is just having fun and behaving like a child while he is a child, and when he comes into his inheritance, he rejects his past and moves on. Okay, at the final scene, were the two funerals are contrasted (and one could say that both of Scott's fathers have died and are being buried) we see a part of Scott looking on at the other funeral. In a way the past has died, but one past, that of the wild and chaotic nature of youth, is also being buried to be replaced with the cold, clinical nature of adult life. I actually found Van Sant's attempts at Shakespearian language to be rather contrived. In the two scenes which are clearly taken from the play, that of Scott's rejection of Bob (who is the Falstaff figure) and the scene were he is mocking Bob after the robbery, we see that Van Sant is trying to create the poetic nature of the original play but using modern language in doing so. To me this fails completely. I can sort of see what he is going, and in a way he is using the play to build upon Scott's character, but the thing is that the movie is focused on Mike and not on Scott. Mike is vulnerable in many ways. Not only does he not understand himself, or even his sexuality (he confuses friendship with erotic love, and this is something that is not returned) he suffers from Narcolepsy. As long as Scott is around, Mike is safe, but as soon as Scott leaves we discover that he is more vulnerable than ever. In a way Mike's search for his mother is his search for security, in the same way that his quest for love is also his quest for security. We know that as long as Scott is around, Mike is secure, but when we see him on the street, back in Portland, we know that this is no longer the case. Then there is Idaho. The movie begins in Idaho, ends in Idaho, and visits Idaho in the middle. It is as if it is this tranquil place between the horrors of the world outside. It is the world of the unique, of the quite, and of the peaceful that pushes away the world of the street. We see the street in Seattle, in Portland, and even in Rome. Granted, we leave Rome for the country, but in a way it is not Idaho. Mike feels secure in Idaho, but not in Italy. However, we learn at the end that no even Idaho offers that protection, for when he collapses again, he is robbed. I guess the idea of the title suggests that is the case, one's search for peace, and that part inside of you were you can feel secure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets boring as it progresses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that starts off promising but as it progresses it just gets weird and bizarre but just not in a good way. It had my interest at first with the introduction of the characters but after the introductions and a bit of bonding between two characters it just got boring. I think the part I lost interest is when River Phoenix's character is visiting his dad in a trailer. It's basically a depressing and bitter road movie about two gay or bisexual male prostitutes on a road trip. Because they both have mother and father issues that they have to deal with. I give River Phoenix's character some sympathy but not so much for Keanu's character. Maybe because one is more in a rut than the other. And none of the characters are likable in this movie, which is fine since when it comes to the tragedy. It didn't get all that depressing. But the relationship and bonding between these two characters played by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves seemed authentic. Maybe because they were friends in real life. It's somewhat of a artsy flick and it's watchable but just didn't really entertain me or got my interest. It got weird and some of the characters gets pretty darn bizarre. But I guess it somewhat adds to the realism to a degree. This is the first movie I seen with River Phoenix and he basically owns this character. But maybe that is cause there is quite a lot of himself in this character. And Keanu...Well I never found the guy to be a brilliant actor. But he is somewhat versatile and fits right in usually with the role he is in. Overall, this movie through me off guard but not really in a good way. Plus I couldn't connect with any of the characters at all, although that may seem a bit conceited on my part. 4.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River tunes out, Keanu slums
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho is a bittersweet tale of two rent boys in the Pacific coast are and the contrasts between them. With the help of the greatest writer in the English language ever, William Shakespeare, Gus Van Sant draws two great characterizations in the characters realized by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves. You couldn't find two more opposite types in the world. River is a street kid through and through. Even the circumstances of his birth are a tragedy that I won't reveal. His mother leaves him as a youngster and he can't get over it and go on. He was raised by an older brother in the sparsely populated 'potato state' as he calls Idaho and the and the family dynamic was strained. He's a gay kid in an area where that could be deadly so he takes off for the fleshpots of Seattle and Portland where his youth and beauty will bring him some cash. He has no skills or education to support himself any other way. Sad, but the only hope this kid has of a decent life is to get taken up by some older sugar daddy who might just treat him to an education of some kind. That is if he can decide to just get over a bad home life and lack of a normal family. I've known gay kids who came from as lousy a background as River Phoenix and who never could get over it. River has developed an interesting defense mechanism and a psychologist would have field day with him if he got him on the coach. When the stress gets too much for him he just has a seizure like an epileptic, but in fact all he does is fall asleep. It's called narcilepsy, but he's vulnerable in that state as the film shows as well. River just tunes out the world. Keanu comes from a different world, his father is the Mayor of Portland, but he's dying and hopes to have his son take over the family political dynasty. But Tom Troupe is bitterly disappointed in his 'effeminate' son who like Prince Hal likes to hang out with lowlifes and street trash. Keanu's Falstaff is William Richert, a gay older man of a Falstaffian bloated belly who likes the young stuff and in his world probably treats them well. Gus Van Sant was quite imaginative in seeing the gay subtext that could be drawn from Prince Hal and Falstaff. Indeed Keanu says that Richert is closer to him than his real father. But he also says that he's planning to work a change in him when he comes into his own. And he says it in dialog taken from Shakespeare's Henry IV Parts one and two. The most touching scene is with River and Keanu out in the country at a fire where River basically confesses his love for him. It's love to be sure, but River also sees in Keanu a figure who has confidence and self assurance and those are the qualities that draws him to Reeves. What Phoenix misreads is that self confidence is really a safety net that he knows he has and at the appropriate time uses. Although he's gay for pay as he states, he still allows River to have sex with him. I suspect that Gus Van Sant from his own background knows full well that gay for pay is not always 100% absolute. Reeves goes on to his destiny for which if you know your Shakespeare know what that is. Phoenix's destiny is less clear, more than likely an oblivion that a lot of those kids go to. As a fantasy I'd like to think that as Reeves denies himself, closets himself as he moves on in life, that an older River comes back to remind him of his roots. We all know of the tragedy of River Phoenix who died way too young just like a lot of street kids do ironically. There is a second tragedy in the My Own Private Idaho. Rodney Harvey who played one of River and Keanu's street peers also died way too young in similar circumstances to Phoenix. Not only does Van Sant give us an excellent two person character study, but his other character with less dialog than the leads also are fully formed characters which is the mark that many including me say indicates a great film. My Own Private Idaho is a troubling picture, but a realistic one of the underside of gay life that we cannot ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As current today as it was then....a modern classic perhaps.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho Director: Gus Van Sant Starring: River Phoenix, Keanu Reeves, James Russo. Gus Van Sant essentially takes on Shakespeare's Henry IV; it featured the aesthetically delightful River Phoenix as Mike Waters, a wonderfully apt narcoleptic male whore who we first get a glimpse of tipping down an open stretch of road in Idaho. Mike and the action shifts from the cold Seattle to equally cold Portland. It is here that he makes friends with Scott Favor, a secretly soon to be rich guy who is also on the game played by the often-maligned Keanu Reeves. The future for both is as uncertain as uncertain can be, will Scott take up the inheritance he about to get, will Mike survive the streets with his narcolepsy? ￼ Mike feels real affections for Scott, however Scott refuses to believe men can really love each and it would seem that Scott is only doing the gay whole whore thing to kill time and get back at his family. Mike believes Scott will continue with the grand life on the streets, turning tricks even after he bags the inheritance; such is the allure of the unknown. There are many of fellow working boys who agree with Mike's view. This is an uneasy picture, a colourful and surreal attempt to really take the characters to a different kingdom. At times, it is a wonderful although slightly glossy take on the real street hustlers shagging their way to oblivion or not as the individual case may be. Drug abuse and risky behaviours are commonplace on the streets and in the world of the male hooker and it is a small feature of this sometimes-disturbing film. The character of Mike seems almost apologetically plausible, abandoned as a child and obsessed with finding his real long lost mother. Scott less believable as the rebellious disillusioned spoilt little rich kid gone rebelliously bad. You really would not have put them together by design, but fate disregards those lines and together they embark on a quest to find Mike's mother, from Portland to Idaho to Italy they do travel. There is no argument the cinematic quality and the unbelievably stunning settings help to make this film an intriguingly striking viewing delight. It is exceptionally well thought out in terms of location and setting and a master-class for any would be cinematographer. The characterisation I found to be impressive, even Keanu Reeves played his part with just the right amount of smug pathos and humour, especially with the flippantly arrogant lines afford to him. River Phoenix works pure magic on screen with this performance and I am fairly sure I'm not alone in believing this is the role that set him into the great immortal movie star hall of fame. It is no wonder that he pulled in a number of 'best actor' type awards for this intrinsically faceted role. His campfire scene, in which Mike declares his love for Scott, is much applauded by audiences and critics alike  Newsweek claiming it to be "A marvel of delicacy" it really is a testament to what a wonderful talent River Phoenix was, because he wrote that part of the script himself. Village Voice said, "Phoenix vanishes with reckless triumph into his role". It earned around &pound;5 million at the box office worldwide, which is quite impressive, more than that in video and DVD sales. My Own Private Idaho takes the spirit and passion of Shakespeare, bends, manipulates and shapes it to find form in a more modern setting, which works beyond expectation in the most part. Although the traditionalist in me seems to hold the opinion that you should not mess with old Shaky and if you do, you best be prepared to face the harshest of critics. Adaptations are always open to personal interpretation and modifications, which others may not agree with, like or even accept, yet this one seems to work and seems to be commended as a job well done.Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem in the movie genre - very emotional & moving with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry07
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard of this movie for a while now (since it came out I guess) and never had the chance to watch it. Finally, I got my hand on a DVD and was stunned: how could I have missed this before? I would classify this movie in the Indie genre (if that applied to movies), as its style is unusual. Essentially, the dialogs may go into long theatrical speech (literally) rather than a fluent every day life dialog. You get annoyed at times (did not expect a Shakespeare play but a movie) as some of the scenes within this style are not working out (imagine Keanu Reeves in a play - nope! doesn't work for me either). But if you can pass beyond this problem, you will find a gem. Indeed, the characters! What a treat. River Phoenix (Mike) performance is simply breathtaking and inspired: you immediately feel the character of "Mike", the abandoned and confused child not only reverting to hustling for money but striving for belonging, acceptance and love going in life with the dream and memory of his mother. His friendship with Scott (Keanu Reeves) will bring them into a journey where emotions and classics are all covered: lightness and energy of youth, rebellion of the privileged, loneliness, burning passions, struggles and survival, loss, desire. On second thought, perhaps it works well as a Shakespearian play (yes, I know it was intended) but not only because the dialogs are like so but due to the in-depth drama of this movie the breadth of emotion it covers. The story line is flooded with the view of Mike (also narcoleptic) and appears at times as a dream. As a result, to me, the whole movie is simply a great piece, poetic, breath taking and emotional: you stay watching through the theater scenes wanting to know what's next, you get hooked to the artistic aspects of the movie (music is often blending and you find yourself noticing that many details have significance) and you feel for the characters at a deep and intense level as if the topics treated are archetypal. For sure, you will remember this movie whether you were thrown off by it, liked it or loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    trippy arty homage to Shakespeare's Henry IV. a powerful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every time I see this film, I forget how incredibly amazing it is. Yes I'm a huge fan of of the late, great, River Phoenix, think Keanu Reeves is highly underrated, and love Shakespeare. This is a modern adaptation to Henry IV, based around two hustlers Mike and Scott (River and Keanu) and their relationship, with the added wrinkle that Mikey is a narcoleptic and trying to find his long lost mother. Scott is the rich boy who turns his back on his street life when his inheritance kicks in. River's performance is astounding, tender and powerful, and it's a brave pair of best friends (in real life) that take on roles like this but the affection between them is palpable and somehow makes the story of unrequited love even more heartbreaking. The Shakespeare gets confusing if you aren't familiar, as it washes in and out, and if you haven't seen Gus Van Sant before you might not quite follow the surreal imagery and the trippy nature of the film. It's arty, weird and dark, but has a lot of humour and sensitivity, despite being a little bawdy in places, however for all it's adult subject matter it's quite discrete! River and Keanu are astounding in this, and it's a film that River should be remembered for as the bright star he was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like a super 8
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like a super 8 film from the 70's/80's New York this felt like it was art created for the screen on a setting, the open plan falling down dilapidated building. Beautifully shot with scenes of the hills and fields that seemed to roll on forever. The acting even included San Sant himself as well as Grace Zabriskie who is normally in David Lynch's films. The story was maybe even too weird for me and didn't really get a resonance and stayed very flat, it was not his best but showed how he can make his films. Although it was maybe too weird it still made me want to be there in that building, the place where creativity happens, as spaces like that spark imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much ado about nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A narcoleptic hustler and his 'degenerate' (to his father) pal travel the Pacific Northwest in search ofwhat? Freedom? Affection? Adventure? Gus Van Sant's follow up to his career breakthrough 'Drugstore Cowboy' is full odd stylistic tics and transparent social commentary, all of it adding up to a merely pretentious film even more aimless and unmotivated than its two primary characters. Viewers might be forgiven for wondering where the story is going after the brief detour into Idaho itself (the trailer home reunion is a highlight), when the scene shifts abruptly, and for no good reason, to sunny Rome (yes, in Italy). There's plenty to look at, but all the gorgeous imagery hides a shortage of real ideas, and Van Sant's mock Shakespearean dialogue is an annoying conceit (at least the Bard is acknowledged in the credits). Udo Kier, as 'Hans', steals the film away from its two young stars, and the brief documentary appearance of actual teenage hustlers discussing their 'dates' shows what the film could have aspired to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River Phoenix is excellent, as is the film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indie_Locker
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant has always been an interesting filmmaker. He cares about character and story and through the process, his artistic integrity is able to shine through his work and that is why he's considered a prominent director in independent cinema. My Own Private Idaho is more of is more well known independent features and is often viewed as a triumph of independent cinema from the 1990s. The film follows Mark Waters (River Phoenix) an aimless, misguided young man who hustles on the streets and is yearning to find his way in life. His best friend is Scott Favor (Keanu Reeves), who is also a young man and and a hustler, but who instead is running away from his life in the hope of finding something better. Scott comes from a lot of wealth but chooses not to live that lifestyle because when he's this young and wild, he just doesn't believe that its right for him. However the film is centered around Mark, who is played with such brutal honestly by the late River Phoenix. River is completely dedicated to the character and brings a wonderful vulnerability to a lost soul and it makes him relatable. We watch him go from scene to scene, leaving us as unaware of his future as he is. We watch him make many mistakes and we want him to better himself but such a task is not easy. Because that's the way life is. Mark hustles because its just who he is. We don't know how he got here, but we know that he has fallen into this lifestyle and it has consumed him. He needs the money. All of his friends are hustlers, too. He has dreams but its tough to say if he ever truly wants to leave the lifestyle. It seems that getting clients and often falling asleep during it (due to him being narcoleptic) doesn't seem to take as much of a toll on him as does his thoughts about his mother, or his feelings for his best friend. Gus Van Sant crafts a very fine film here that focuses on such a lifestyle that we're not exposed to in our every day lives and turns it into something we can all relate to. It all comes back to that road, the road that we're all on. Does it really end? Probably not. Much like in the way that Mark is shown standing on that road, staring out into the nothingness. Its really about our lives. We live and we're happy, and we're sad, and we're lonely, and we're lost, and we've found ourselves, all of these things happen on the very same road that never ends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good... and very flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PrometheusTree64
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought the Criterion Collection DVD of this because I loved River Phoenix before it was a clich&eacute;. Nevertheless, I saw this in the theater when it was first released, and my opinion hasn't changed: Phoenix is as good as you've heard and the film absolutely has it's moments --- many wonderful moments. Then there's Keanu. Who tried to marry this guy to Shakespeare? He's way out of his league with this kind of material. And these sections of the film, especially the group exchanges in the broken-down tenement house, seem badly edited, those conversations unclear in terms of point and plot --- and I've seen the movie multiple times. It's a shame Van Sant went down that road (the characters, specifically Keanu, breaking in and out of classical speech, which simply doesn't work), because there are many things about this picture that are really terrific... So view it with this in mind. ...and this: after the first couple of viewings of this hauntingly-odd picture, the flaws just seem to melt away and don't matter so much. And you can almost always tell a (potentially) good flick when it manages to inexplicably capture the zeitgeist of its era; in fact, I'm not sure I've ever seen one that evokes the cusp of the 80s/90s as vividly. (So did "Midnight Cowboy" for ITS era, so maybe male hookers is all that's really required. Go figure.) Even Keanu gives a better performance in the "normal" (non-Shakespearean) scenes than usual. And, as with every single River Phoenix movie ever filmed, this one is chock-full of eerily prescient moments of doom: like River seizing on the road, sidewalk, etc...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest for Security and the Return to the Tranquil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie years ago and I suspect that I knew that it had relations with Henry IV but until recently I had not see the original Shakespeare play. However, having read both parts, watched a BBC version of both parts, and also seen an amalgamation of both plays on stage I can say that I am much more familiar with it so that I can have a different understanding of this film. When I had first seen the film I had liked it, and I must say that I still like it, but the second time around, including being more familiar with Henry IV, I must say that it did not appeal to me as much. In part I think Van Sant has pulled away significantly from the original play with regards to the themes of the play as well as with regards to the character of Scott (played by Keanu Reeves and is Hal from the play). In a way Scott and Hal are both rebellious teenagers, but Scott is much more conscious of his desire to 'come good' when he turns 21 whereas this does not seem to be the case with Hal. In fact Hal has to prove to his father that he desires to become good, whereas it is clear from the film that Scott is in no danger of losing his inheritance. In Henry IV Poins is more of a supporting character who acts not so much as Hal's conscience but rather as a friend. In the film though Mike (River Pheonix, who corresponds with Poins) plays a much more important and central role. In fact the film is actually focused on Mike, as he goes on a fruitless search for his mother. There is tension between Mike and Scott because it is clear that Mike loves Scott but this love is not returned. This is something that we know is never going to happen, particularly when Scott says at the opening that as long as you do it for money then it is okay, but as soon as you begin to do it for free, you grow wings (and with that he then looks up at Mike as if suggesting that Mike has already grown wings). Another difference we see is that Scott readily deserts Scott when he gets his inheritance and finds the woman that he takes as his wife (though there is no indicating that there is any love, and we raise the question as to whether Scott is capable of love). Henry IV is many cases is about the right of passage that Hal takes from being a rebellious teenager to becoming a king, but this is something that we do not necessarily see here. Scott is not going through a rite of passage, nor is he learning, he is just having fun and behaving like a child while he is a child, and when he comes into his inheritance, he rejects his past and moves on. Okay, at the final scene, were the two funerals are contrasted (and one could say that both of Scott's fathers have died and are being buried) we see a part of Scott looking on at the other funeral. In a way the past has died, but one past, that of the wild and chaotic nature of youth, is also being buried to be replaced with the cold, clinical nature of adult life. I actually found Van Sant's attempts at Shakespearian language to be rather contrived. In the two scenes which are clearly taken from the play, that of Scott's rejection of Bob (who is the Falstaff figure) and the scene were he is mocking Bob after the robbery, we see that Van Sant is trying to create the poetic nature of the original play but using modern language in doing so. To me this fails completely. I can sort of see what he is going, and in a way he is using the play to build upon Scott's character, but the thing is that the movie is focused on Mike and not on Scott. Mike is vulnerable in many ways. Not only does he not understand himself, or even his sexuality (he confuses friendship with erotic love, and this is something that is not returned) he suffers from Narcolepsy. As long as Scott is around, Mike is safe, but as soon as Scott leaves we discover that he is more vulnerable than ever. In a way Mike's search for his mother is his search for security, in the same way that his quest for love is also his quest for security. We know that as long as Scott is around, Mike is secure, but when we see him on the street, back in Portland, we know that this is no longer the case. Then there is Idaho. The movie begins in Idaho, ends in Idaho, and visits Idaho in the middle. It is as if it is this tranquil place between the horrors of the world outside. It is the world of the unique, of the quite, and of the peaceful that pushes away the world of the street. We see the street in Seattle, in Portland, and even in Rome. Granted, we leave Rome for the country, but in a way it is not Idaho. Mike feels secure in Idaho, but not in Italy. However, we learn at the end that no even Idaho offers that protection, for when he collapses again, he is robbed. I guess the idea of the title suggests that is the case, one's search for peace, and that part inside of you were you can feel secure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets boring as it progresses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that starts off promising but as it progresses it just gets weird and bizarre but just not in a good way. It had my interest at first with the introduction of the characters but after the introductions and a bit of bonding between two characters it just got boring. I think the part I lost interest is when River Phoenix's character is visiting his dad in a trailer. It's basically a depressing and bitter road movie about two gay or bisexual male prostitutes on a road trip. Because they both have mother and father issues that they have to deal with. I give River Phoenix's character some sympathy but not so much for Keanu's character. Maybe because one is more in a rut than the other. And none of the characters are likable in this movie, which is fine since when it comes to the tragedy. It didn't get all that depressing. But the relationship and bonding between these two characters played by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves seemed authentic. Maybe because they were friends in real life. It's somewhat of a artsy flick and it's watchable but just didn't really entertain me or got my interest. It got weird and some of the characters gets pretty darn bizarre. But I guess it somewhat adds to the realism to a degree. This is the first movie I seen with River Phoenix and he basically owns this character. But maybe that is cause there is quite a lot of himself in this character. And Keanu...Well I never found the guy to be a brilliant actor. But he is somewhat versatile and fits right in usually with the role he is in. Overall, this movie through me off guard but not really in a good way. Plus I couldn't connect with any of the characters at all, although that may seem a bit conceited on my part. 4.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River tunes out, Keanu slums
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho is a bittersweet tale of two rent boys in the Pacific coast are and the contrasts between them. With the help of the greatest writer in the English language ever, William Shakespeare, Gus Van Sant draws two great characterizations in the characters realized by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves. You couldn't find two more opposite types in the world. River is a street kid through and through. Even the circumstances of his birth are a tragedy that I won't reveal. His mother leaves him as a youngster and he can't get over it and go on. He was raised by an older brother in the sparsely populated 'potato state' as he calls Idaho and the and the family dynamic was strained. He's a gay kid in an area where that could be deadly so he takes off for the fleshpots of Seattle and Portland where his youth and beauty will bring him some cash. He has no skills or education to support himself any other way. Sad, but the only hope this kid has of a decent life is to get taken up by some older sugar daddy who might just treat him to an education of some kind. That is if he can decide to just get over a bad home life and lack of a normal family. I've known gay kids who came from as lousy a background as River Phoenix and who never could get over it. River has developed an interesting defense mechanism and a psychologist would have field day with him if he got him on the coach. When the stress gets too much for him he just has a seizure like an epileptic, but in fact all he does is fall asleep. It's called narcilepsy, but he's vulnerable in that state as the film shows as well. River just tunes out the world. Keanu comes from a different world, his father is the Mayor of Portland, but he's dying and hopes to have his son take over the family political dynasty. But Tom Troupe is bitterly disappointed in his 'effeminate' son who like Prince Hal likes to hang out with lowlifes and street trash. Keanu's Falstaff is William Richert, a gay older man of a Falstaffian bloated belly who likes the young stuff and in his world probably treats them well. Gus Van Sant was quite imaginative in seeing the gay subtext that could be drawn from Prince Hal and Falstaff. Indeed Keanu says that Richert is closer to him than his real father. But he also says that he's planning to work a change in him when he comes into his own. And he says it in dialog taken from Shakespeare's Henry IV Parts one and two. The most touching scene is with River and Keanu out in the country at a fire where River basically confesses his love for him. It's love to be sure, but River also sees in Keanu a figure who has confidence and self assurance and those are the qualities that draws him to Reeves. What Phoenix misreads is that self confidence is really a safety net that he knows he has and at the appropriate time uses. Although he's gay for pay as he states, he still allows River to have sex with him. I suspect that Gus Van Sant from his own background knows full well that gay for pay is not always 100% absolute. Reeves goes on to his destiny for which if you know your Shakespeare know what that is. Phoenix's destiny is less clear, more than likely an oblivion that a lot of those kids go to. As a fantasy I'd like to think that as Reeves denies himself, closets himself as he moves on in life, that an older River comes back to remind him of his roots. We all know of the tragedy of River Phoenix who died way too young just like a lot of street kids do ironically. There is a second tragedy in the My Own Private Idaho. Rodney Harvey who played one of River and Keanu's street peers also died way too young in similar circumstances to Phoenix. Not only does Van Sant give us an excellent two person character study, but his other character with less dialog than the leads also are fully formed characters which is the mark that many including me say indicates a great film. My Own Private Idaho is a troubling picture, but a realistic one of the underside of gay life that we cannot ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As current today as it was then....a modern classic perhaps.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho Director: Gus Van Sant Starring: River Phoenix, Keanu Reeves, James Russo. Gus Van Sant essentially takes on Shakespeare's Henry IV; it featured the aesthetically delightful River Phoenix as Mike Waters, a wonderfully apt narcoleptic male whore who we first get a glimpse of tipping down an open stretch of road in Idaho. Mike and the action shifts from the cold Seattle to equally cold Portland. It is here that he makes friends with Scott Favor, a secretly soon to be rich guy who is also on the game played by the often-maligned Keanu Reeves. The future for both is as uncertain as uncertain can be, will Scott take up the inheritance he about to get, will Mike survive the streets with his narcolepsy? ￼ Mike feels real affections for Scott, however Scott refuses to believe men can really love each and it would seem that Scott is only doing the gay whole whore thing to kill time and get back at his family. Mike believes Scott will continue with the grand life on the streets, turning tricks even after he bags the inheritance; such is the allure of the unknown. There are many of fellow working boys who agree with Mike's view. This is an uneasy picture, a colourful and surreal attempt to really take the characters to a different kingdom. At times, it is a wonderful although slightly glossy take on the real street hustlers shagging their way to oblivion or not as the individual case may be. Drug abuse and risky behaviours are commonplace on the streets and in the world of the male hooker and it is a small feature of this sometimes-disturbing film. The character of Mike seems almost apologetically plausible, abandoned as a child and obsessed with finding his real long lost mother. Scott less believable as the rebellious disillusioned spoilt little rich kid gone rebelliously bad. You really would not have put them together by design, but fate disregards those lines and together they embark on a quest to find Mike's mother, from Portland to Idaho to Italy they do travel. There is no argument the cinematic quality and the unbelievably stunning settings help to make this film an intriguingly striking viewing delight. It is exceptionally well thought out in terms of location and setting and a master-class for any would be cinematographer. The characterisation I found to be impressive, even Keanu Reeves played his part with just the right amount of smug pathos and humour, especially with the flippantly arrogant lines afford to him. River Phoenix works pure magic on screen with this performance and I am fairly sure I'm not alone in believing this is the role that set him into the great immortal movie star hall of fame. It is no wonder that he pulled in a number of 'best actor' type awards for this intrinsically faceted role. His campfire scene, in which Mike declares his love for Scott, is much applauded by audiences and critics alike  Newsweek claiming it to be "A marvel of delicacy" it really is a testament to what a wonderful talent River Phoenix was, because he wrote that part of the script himself. Village Voice said, "Phoenix vanishes with reckless triumph into his role". It earned around &pound;5 million at the box office worldwide, which is quite impressive, more than that in video and DVD sales. My Own Private Idaho takes the spirit and passion of Shakespeare, bends, manipulates and shapes it to find form in a more modern setting, which works beyond expectation in the most part. Although the traditionalist in me seems to hold the opinion that you should not mess with old Shaky and if you do, you best be prepared to face the harshest of critics. Adaptations are always open to personal interpretation and modifications, which others may not agree with, like or even accept, yet this one seems to work and seems to be commended as a job well done.Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem in the movie genre - very emotional & moving with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry07
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard of this movie for a while now (since it came out I guess) and never had the chance to watch it. Finally, I got my hand on a DVD and was stunned: how could I have missed this before? I would classify this movie in the Indie genre (if that applied to movies), as its style is unusual. Essentially, the dialogs may go into long theatrical speech (literally) rather than a fluent every day life dialog. You get annoyed at times (did not expect a Shakespeare play but a movie) as some of the scenes within this style are not working out (imagine Keanu Reeves in a play - nope! doesn't work for me either). But if you can pass beyond this problem, you will find a gem. Indeed, the characters! What a treat. River Phoenix (Mike) performance is simply breathtaking and inspired: you immediately feel the character of "Mike", the abandoned and confused child not only reverting to hustling for money but striving for belonging, acceptance and love going in life with the dream and memory of his mother. His friendship with Scott (Keanu Reeves) will bring them into a journey where emotions and classics are all covered: lightness and energy of youth, rebellion of the privileged, loneliness, burning passions, struggles and survival, loss, desire. On second thought, perhaps it works well as a Shakespearian play (yes, I know it was intended) but not only because the dialogs are like so but due to the in-depth drama of this movie the breadth of emotion it covers. The story line is flooded with the view of Mike (also narcoleptic) and appears at times as a dream. As a result, to me, the whole movie is simply a great piece, poetic, breath taking and emotional: you stay watching through the theater scenes wanting to know what's next, you get hooked to the artistic aspects of the movie (music is often blending and you find yourself noticing that many details have significance) and you feel for the characters at a deep and intense level as if the topics treated are archetypal. For sure, you will remember this movie whether you were thrown off by it, liked it or loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    trippy arty homage to Shakespeare's Henry IV. a powerful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every time I see this film, I forget how incredibly amazing it is. Yes I'm a huge fan of of the late, great, River Phoenix, think Keanu Reeves is highly underrated, and love Shakespeare. This is a modern adaptation to Henry IV, based around two hustlers Mike and Scott (River and Keanu) and their relationship, with the added wrinkle that Mikey is a narcoleptic and trying to find his long lost mother. Scott is the rich boy who turns his back on his street life when his inheritance kicks in. River's performance is astounding, tender and powerful, and it's a brave pair of best friends (in real life) that take on roles like this but the affection between them is palpable and somehow makes the story of unrequited love even more heartbreaking. The Shakespeare gets confusing if you aren't familiar, as it washes in and out, and if you haven't seen Gus Van Sant before you might not quite follow the surreal imagery and the trippy nature of the film. It's arty, weird and dark, but has a lot of humour and sensitivity, despite being a little bawdy in places, however for all it's adult subject matter it's quite discrete! River and Keanu are astounding in this, and it's a film that River should be remembered for as the bright star he was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like a super 8
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like a super 8 film from the 70's/80's New York this felt like it was art created for the screen on a setting, the open plan falling down dilapidated building. Beautifully shot with scenes of the hills and fields that seemed to roll on forever. The acting even included San Sant himself as well as Grace Zabriskie who is normally in David Lynch's films. The story was maybe even too weird for me and didn't really get a resonance and stayed very flat, it was not his best but showed how he can make his films. Although it was maybe too weird it still made me want to be there in that building, the place where creativity happens, as spaces like that spark imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much ado about nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A narcoleptic hustler and his 'degenerate' (to his father) pal travel the Pacific Northwest in search ofwhat? Freedom? Affection? Adventure? Gus Van Sant's follow up to his career breakthrough 'Drugstore Cowboy' is full odd stylistic tics and transparent social commentary, all of it adding up to a merely pretentious film even more aimless and unmotivated than its two primary characters. Viewers might be forgiven for wondering where the story is going after the brief detour into Idaho itself (the trailer home reunion is a highlight), when the scene shifts abruptly, and for no good reason, to sunny Rome (yes, in Italy). There's plenty to look at, but all the gorgeous imagery hides a shortage of real ideas, and Van Sant's mock Shakespearean dialogue is an annoying conceit (at least the Bard is acknowledged in the credits). Udo Kier, as 'Hans', steals the film away from its two young stars, and the brief documentary appearance of actual teenage hustlers discussing their 'dates' shows what the film could have aspired to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River Phoenix is excellent, as is the film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indie_Locker
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant has always been an interesting filmmaker. He cares about character and story and through the process, his artistic integrity is able to shine through his work and that is why he's considered a prominent director in independent cinema. My Own Private Idaho is more of is more well known independent features and is often viewed as a triumph of independent cinema from the 1990s. The film follows Mark Waters (River Phoenix) an aimless, misguided young man who hustles on the streets and is yearning to find his way in life. His best friend is Scott Favor (Keanu Reeves), who is also a young man and and a hustler, but who instead is running away from his life in the hope of finding something better. Scott comes from a lot of wealth but chooses not to live that lifestyle because when he's this young and wild, he just doesn't believe that its right for him. However the film is centered around Mark, who is played with such brutal honestly by the late River Phoenix. River is completely dedicated to the character and brings a wonderful vulnerability to a lost soul and it makes him relatable. We watch him go from scene to scene, leaving us as unaware of his future as he is. We watch him make many mistakes and we want him to better himself but such a task is not easy. Because that's the way life is. Mark hustles because its just who he is. We don't know how he got here, but we know that he has fallen into this lifestyle and it has consumed him. He needs the money. All of his friends are hustlers, too. He has dreams but its tough to say if he ever truly wants to leave the lifestyle. It seems that getting clients and often falling asleep during it (due to him being narcoleptic) doesn't seem to take as much of a toll on him as does his thoughts about his mother, or his feelings for his best friend. Gus Van Sant crafts a very fine film here that focuses on such a lifestyle that we're not exposed to in our every day lives and turns it into something we can all relate to. It all comes back to that road, the road that we're all on. Does it really end? Probably not. Much like in the way that Mark is shown standing on that road, staring out into the nothingness. Its really about our lives. We live and we're happy, and we're sad, and we're lonely, and we're lost, and we've found ourselves, all of these things happen on the very same road that never ends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good... and very flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PrometheusTree64
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought the Criterion Collection DVD of this because I loved River Phoenix before it was a clich&eacute;. Nevertheless, I saw this in the theater when it was first released, and my opinion hasn't changed: Phoenix is as good as you've heard and the film absolutely has it's moments --- many wonderful moments. Then there's Keanu. Who tried to marry this guy to Shakespeare? He's way out of his league with this kind of material. And these sections of the film, especially the group exchanges in the broken-down tenement house, seem badly edited, those conversations unclear in terms of point and plot --- and I've seen the movie multiple times. It's a shame Van Sant went down that road (the characters, specifically Keanu, breaking in and out of classical speech, which simply doesn't work), because there are many things about this picture that are really terrific... So view it with this in mind. ...and this: after the first couple of viewings of this hauntingly-odd picture, the flaws just seem to melt away and don't matter so much. And you can almost always tell a (potentially) good flick when it manages to inexplicably capture the zeitgeist of its era; in fact, I'm not sure I've ever seen one that evokes the cusp of the 80s/90s as vividly. (So did "Midnight Cowboy" for ITS era, so maybe male hookers is all that's really required. Go figure.) Even Keanu gives a better performance in the "normal" (non-Shakespearean) scenes than usual. And, as with every single River Phoenix movie ever filmed, this one is chock-full of eerily prescient moments of doom: like River seizing on the road, sidewalk, etc...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest for Security and the Return to the Tranquil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie years ago and I suspect that I knew that it had relations with Henry IV but until recently I had not see the original Shakespeare play. However, having read both parts, watched a BBC version of both parts, and also seen an amalgamation of both plays on stage I can say that I am much more familiar with it so that I can have a different understanding of this film. When I had first seen the film I had liked it, and I must say that I still like it, but the second time around, including being more familiar with Henry IV, I must say that it did not appeal to me as much. In part I think Van Sant has pulled away significantly from the original play with regards to the themes of the play as well as with regards to the character of Scott (played by Keanu Reeves and is Hal from the play). In a way Scott and Hal are both rebellious teenagers, but Scott is much more conscious of his desire to 'come good' when he turns 21 whereas this does not seem to be the case with Hal. In fact Hal has to prove to his father that he desires to become good, whereas it is clear from the film that Scott is in no danger of losing his inheritance. In Henry IV Poins is more of a supporting character who acts not so much as Hal's conscience but rather as a friend. In the film though Mike (River Pheonix, who corresponds with Poins) plays a much more important and central role. In fact the film is actually focused on Mike, as he goes on a fruitless search for his mother. There is tension between Mike and Scott because it is clear that Mike loves Scott but this love is not returned. This is something that we know is never going to happen, particularly when Scott says at the opening that as long as you do it for money then it is okay, but as soon as you begin to do it for free, you grow wings (and with that he then looks up at Mike as if suggesting that Mike has already grown wings). Another difference we see is that Scott readily deserts Scott when he gets his inheritance and finds the woman that he takes as his wife (though there is no indicating that there is any love, and we raise the question as to whether Scott is capable of love). Henry IV is many cases is about the right of passage that Hal takes from being a rebellious teenager to becoming a king, but this is something that we do not necessarily see here. Scott is not going through a rite of passage, nor is he learning, he is just having fun and behaving like a child while he is a child, and when he comes into his inheritance, he rejects his past and moves on. Okay, at the final scene, were the two funerals are contrasted (and one could say that both of Scott's fathers have died and are being buried) we see a part of Scott looking on at the other funeral. In a way the past has died, but one past, that of the wild and chaotic nature of youth, is also being buried to be replaced with the cold, clinical nature of adult life. I actually found Van Sant's attempts at Shakespearian language to be rather contrived. In the two scenes which are clearly taken from the play, that of Scott's rejection of Bob (who is the Falstaff figure) and the scene were he is mocking Bob after the robbery, we see that Van Sant is trying to create the poetic nature of the original play but using modern language in doing so. To me this fails completely. I can sort of see what he is going, and in a way he is using the play to build upon Scott's character, but the thing is that the movie is focused on Mike and not on Scott. Mike is vulnerable in many ways. Not only does he not understand himself, or even his sexuality (he confuses friendship with erotic love, and this is something that is not returned) he suffers from Narcolepsy. As long as Scott is around, Mike is safe, but as soon as Scott leaves we discover that he is more vulnerable than ever. In a way Mike's search for his mother is his search for security, in the same way that his quest for love is also his quest for security. We know that as long as Scott is around, Mike is secure, but when we see him on the street, back in Portland, we know that this is no longer the case. Then there is Idaho. The movie begins in Idaho, ends in Idaho, and visits Idaho in the middle. It is as if it is this tranquil place between the horrors of the world outside. It is the world of the unique, of the quite, and of the peaceful that pushes away the world of the street. We see the street in Seattle, in Portland, and even in Rome. Granted, we leave Rome for the country, but in a way it is not Idaho. Mike feels secure in Idaho, but not in Italy. However, we learn at the end that no even Idaho offers that protection, for when he collapses again, he is robbed. I guess the idea of the title suggests that is the case, one's search for peace, and that part inside of you were you can feel secure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets boring as it progresses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that starts off promising but as it progresses it just gets weird and bizarre but just not in a good way. It had my interest at first with the introduction of the characters but after the introductions and a bit of bonding between two characters it just got boring. I think the part I lost interest is when River Phoenix's character is visiting his dad in a trailer. It's basically a depressing and bitter road movie about two gay or bisexual male prostitutes on a road trip. Because they both have mother and father issues that they have to deal with. I give River Phoenix's character some sympathy but not so much for Keanu's character. Maybe because one is more in a rut than the other. And none of the characters are likable in this movie, which is fine since when it comes to the tragedy. It didn't get all that depressing. But the relationship and bonding between these two characters played by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves seemed authentic. Maybe because they were friends in real life. It's somewhat of a artsy flick and it's watchable but just didn't really entertain me or got my interest. It got weird and some of the characters gets pretty darn bizarre. But I guess it somewhat adds to the realism to a degree. This is the first movie I seen with River Phoenix and he basically owns this character. But maybe that is cause there is quite a lot of himself in this character. And Keanu...Well I never found the guy to be a brilliant actor. But he is somewhat versatile and fits right in usually with the role he is in. Overall, this movie through me off guard but not really in a good way. Plus I couldn't connect with any of the characters at all, although that may seem a bit conceited on my part. 4.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River tunes out, Keanu slums
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho is a bittersweet tale of two rent boys in the Pacific coast are and the contrasts between them. With the help of the greatest writer in the English language ever, William Shakespeare, Gus Van Sant draws two great characterizations in the characters realized by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves. You couldn't find two more opposite types in the world. River is a street kid through and through. Even the circumstances of his birth are a tragedy that I won't reveal. His mother leaves him as a youngster and he can't get over it and go on. He was raised by an older brother in the sparsely populated 'potato state' as he calls Idaho and the and the family dynamic was strained. He's a gay kid in an area where that could be deadly so he takes off for the fleshpots of Seattle and Portland where his youth and beauty will bring him some cash. He has no skills or education to support himself any other way. Sad, but the only hope this kid has of a decent life is to get taken up by some older sugar daddy who might just treat him to an education of some kind. That is if he can decide to just get over a bad home life and lack of a normal family. I've known gay kids who came from as lousy a background as River Phoenix and who never could get over it. River has developed an interesting defense mechanism and a psychologist would have field day with him if he got him on the coach. When the stress gets too much for him he just has a seizure like an epileptic, but in fact all he does is fall asleep. It's called narcilepsy, but he's vulnerable in that state as the film shows as well. River just tunes out the world. Keanu comes from a different world, his father is the Mayor of Portland, but he's dying and hopes to have his son take over the family political dynasty. But Tom Troupe is bitterly disappointed in his 'effeminate' son who like Prince Hal likes to hang out with lowlifes and street trash. Keanu's Falstaff is William Richert, a gay older man of a Falstaffian bloated belly who likes the young stuff and in his world probably treats them well. Gus Van Sant was quite imaginative in seeing the gay subtext that could be drawn from Prince Hal and Falstaff. Indeed Keanu says that Richert is closer to him than his real father. But he also says that he's planning to work a change in him when he comes into his own. And he says it in dialog taken from Shakespeare's Henry IV Parts one and two. The most touching scene is with River and Keanu out in the country at a fire where River basically confesses his love for him. It's love to be sure, but River also sees in Keanu a figure who has confidence and self assurance and those are the qualities that draws him to Reeves. What Phoenix misreads is that self confidence is really a safety net that he knows he has and at the appropriate time uses. Although he's gay for pay as he states, he still allows River to have sex with him. I suspect that Gus Van Sant from his own background knows full well that gay for pay is not always 100% absolute. Reeves goes on to his destiny for which if you know your Shakespeare know what that is. Phoenix's destiny is less clear, more than likely an oblivion that a lot of those kids go to. As a fantasy I'd like to think that as Reeves denies himself, closets himself as he moves on in life, that an older River comes back to remind him of his roots. We all know of the tragedy of River Phoenix who died way too young just like a lot of street kids do ironically. There is a second tragedy in the My Own Private Idaho. Rodney Harvey who played one of River and Keanu's street peers also died way too young in similar circumstances to Phoenix. Not only does Van Sant give us an excellent two person character study, but his other character with less dialog than the leads also are fully formed characters which is the mark that many including me say indicates a great film. My Own Private Idaho is a troubling picture, but a realistic one of the underside of gay life that we cannot ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As current today as it was then....a modern classic perhaps.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho Director: Gus Van Sant Starring: River Phoenix, Keanu Reeves, James Russo. Gus Van Sant essentially takes on Shakespeare's Henry IV; it featured the aesthetically delightful River Phoenix as Mike Waters, a wonderfully apt narcoleptic male whore who we first get a glimpse of tipping down an open stretch of road in Idaho. Mike and the action shifts from the cold Seattle to equally cold Portland. It is here that he makes friends with Scott Favor, a secretly soon to be rich guy who is also on the game played by the often-maligned Keanu Reeves. The future for both is as uncertain as uncertain can be, will Scott take up the inheritance he about to get, will Mike survive the streets with his narcolepsy? ￼ Mike feels real affections for Scott, however Scott refuses to believe men can really love each and it would seem that Scott is only doing the gay whole whore thing to kill time and get back at his family. Mike believes Scott will continue with the grand life on the streets, turning tricks even after he bags the inheritance; such is the allure of the unknown. There are many of fellow working boys who agree with Mike's view. This is an uneasy picture, a colourful and surreal attempt to really take the characters to a different kingdom. At times, it is a wonderful although slightly glossy take on the real street hustlers shagging their way to oblivion or not as the individual case may be. Drug abuse and risky behaviours are commonplace on the streets and in the world of the male hooker and it is a small feature of this sometimes-disturbing film. The character of Mike seems almost apologetically plausible, abandoned as a child and obsessed with finding his real long lost mother. Scott less believable as the rebellious disillusioned spoilt little rich kid gone rebelliously bad. You really would not have put them together by design, but fate disregards those lines and together they embark on a quest to find Mike's mother, from Portland to Idaho to Italy they do travel. There is no argument the cinematic quality and the unbelievably stunning settings help to make this film an intriguingly striking viewing delight. It is exceptionally well thought out in terms of location and setting and a master-class for any would be cinematographer. The characterisation I found to be impressive, even Keanu Reeves played his part with just the right amount of smug pathos and humour, especially with the flippantly arrogant lines afford to him. River Phoenix works pure magic on screen with this performance and I am fairly sure I'm not alone in believing this is the role that set him into the great immortal movie star hall of fame. It is no wonder that he pulled in a number of 'best actor' type awards for this intrinsically faceted role. His campfire scene, in which Mike declares his love for Scott, is much applauded by audiences and critics alike  Newsweek claiming it to be "A marvel of delicacy" it really is a testament to what a wonderful talent River Phoenix was, because he wrote that part of the script himself. Village Voice said, "Phoenix vanishes with reckless triumph into his role". It earned around &pound;5 million at the box office worldwide, which is quite impressive, more than that in video and DVD sales. My Own Private Idaho takes the spirit and passion of Shakespeare, bends, manipulates and shapes it to find form in a more modern setting, which works beyond expectation in the most part. Although the traditionalist in me seems to hold the opinion that you should not mess with old Shaky and if you do, you best be prepared to face the harshest of critics. Adaptations are always open to personal interpretation and modifications, which others may not agree with, like or even accept, yet this one seems to work and seems to be commended as a job well done.Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem in the movie genre - very emotional & moving with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry07
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard of this movie for a while now (since it came out I guess) and never had the chance to watch it. Finally, I got my hand on a DVD and was stunned: how could I have missed this before? I would classify this movie in the Indie genre (if that applied to movies), as its style is unusual. Essentially, the dialogs may go into long theatrical speech (literally) rather than a fluent every day life dialog. You get annoyed at times (did not expect a Shakespeare play but a movie) as some of the scenes within this style are not working out (imagine Keanu Reeves in a play - nope! doesn't work for me either). But if you can pass beyond this problem, you will find a gem. Indeed, the characters! What a treat. River Phoenix (Mike) performance is simply breathtaking and inspired: you immediately feel the character of "Mike", the abandoned and confused child not only reverting to hustling for money but striving for belonging, acceptance and love going in life with the dream and memory of his mother. His friendship with Scott (Keanu Reeves) will bring them into a journey where emotions and classics are all covered: lightness and energy of youth, rebellion of the privileged, loneliness, burning passions, struggles and survival, loss, desire. On second thought, perhaps it works well as a Shakespearian play (yes, I know it was intended) but not only because the dialogs are like so but due to the in-depth drama of this movie the breadth of emotion it covers. The story line is flooded with the view of Mike (also narcoleptic) and appears at times as a dream. As a result, to me, the whole movie is simply a great piece, poetic, breath taking and emotional: you stay watching through the theater scenes wanting to know what's next, you get hooked to the artistic aspects of the movie (music is often blending and you find yourself noticing that many details have significance) and you feel for the characters at a deep and intense level as if the topics treated are archetypal. For sure, you will remember this movie whether you were thrown off by it, liked it or loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    trippy arty homage to Shakespeare's Henry IV. a powerful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every time I see this film, I forget how incredibly amazing it is. Yes I'm a huge fan of of the late, great, River Phoenix, think Keanu Reeves is highly underrated, and love Shakespeare. This is a modern adaptation to Henry IV, based around two hustlers Mike and Scott (River and Keanu) and their relationship, with the added wrinkle that Mikey is a narcoleptic and trying to find his long lost mother. Scott is the rich boy who turns his back on his street life when his inheritance kicks in. River's performance is astounding, tender and powerful, and it's a brave pair of best friends (in real life) that take on roles like this but the affection between them is palpable and somehow makes the story of unrequited love even more heartbreaking. The Shakespeare gets confusing if you aren't familiar, as it washes in and out, and if you haven't seen Gus Van Sant before you might not quite follow the surreal imagery and the trippy nature of the film. It's arty, weird and dark, but has a lot of humour and sensitivity, despite being a little bawdy in places, however for all it's adult subject matter it's quite discrete! River and Keanu are astounding in this, and it's a film that River should be remembered for as the bright star he was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like a super 8
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like a super 8 film from the 70's/80's New York this felt like it was art created for the screen on a setting, the open plan falling down dilapidated building. Beautifully shot with scenes of the hills and fields that seemed to roll on forever. The acting even included San Sant himself as well as Grace Zabriskie who is normally in David Lynch's films. The story was maybe even too weird for me and didn't really get a resonance and stayed very flat, it was not his best but showed how he can make his films. Although it was maybe too weird it still made me want to be there in that building, the place where creativity happens, as spaces like that spark imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much ado about nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A narcoleptic hustler and his 'degenerate' (to his father) pal travel the Pacific Northwest in search ofwhat? Freedom? Affection? Adventure? Gus Van Sant's follow up to his career breakthrough 'Drugstore Cowboy' is full odd stylistic tics and transparent social commentary, all of it adding up to a merely pretentious film even more aimless and unmotivated than its two primary characters. Viewers might be forgiven for wondering where the story is going after the brief detour into Idaho itself (the trailer home reunion is a highlight), when the scene shifts abruptly, and for no good reason, to sunny Rome (yes, in Italy). There's plenty to look at, but all the gorgeous imagery hides a shortage of real ideas, and Van Sant's mock Shakespearean dialogue is an annoying conceit (at least the Bard is acknowledged in the credits). Udo Kier, as 'Hans', steals the film away from its two young stars, and the brief documentary appearance of actual teenage hustlers discussing their 'dates' shows what the film could have aspired to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River Phoenix is excellent, as is the film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indie_Locker
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant has always been an interesting filmmaker. He cares about character and story and through the process, his artistic integrity is able to shine through his work and that is why he's considered a prominent director in independent cinema. My Own Private Idaho is more of is more well known independent features and is often viewed as a triumph of independent cinema from the 1990s. The film follows Mark Waters (River Phoenix) an aimless, misguided young man who hustles on the streets and is yearning to find his way in life. His best friend is Scott Favor (Keanu Reeves), who is also a young man and and a hustler, but who instead is running away from his life in the hope of finding something better. Scott comes from a lot of wealth but chooses not to live that lifestyle because when he's this young and wild, he just doesn't believe that its right for him. However the film is centered around Mark, who is played with such brutal honestly by the late River Phoenix. River is completely dedicated to the character and brings a wonderful vulnerability to a lost soul and it makes him relatable. We watch him go from scene to scene, leaving us as unaware of his future as he is. We watch him make many mistakes and we want him to better himself but such a task is not easy. Because that's the way life is. Mark hustles because its just who he is. We don't know how he got here, but we know that he has fallen into this lifestyle and it has consumed him. He needs the money. All of his friends are hustlers, too. He has dreams but its tough to say if he ever truly wants to leave the lifestyle. It seems that getting clients and often falling asleep during it (due to him being narcoleptic) doesn't seem to take as much of a toll on him as does his thoughts about his mother, or his feelings for his best friend. Gus Van Sant crafts a very fine film here that focuses on such a lifestyle that we're not exposed to in our every day lives and turns it into something we can all relate to. It all comes back to that road, the road that we're all on. Does it really end? Probably not. Much like in the way that Mark is shown standing on that road, staring out into the nothingness. Its really about our lives. We live and we're happy, and we're sad, and we're lonely, and we're lost, and we've found ourselves, all of these things happen on the very same road that never ends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good... and very flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PrometheusTree64
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought the Criterion Collection DVD of this because I loved River Phoenix before it was a clich&eacute;. Nevertheless, I saw this in the theater when it was first released, and my opinion hasn't changed: Phoenix is as good as you've heard and the film absolutely has it's moments --- many wonderful moments. Then there's Keanu. Who tried to marry this guy to Shakespeare? He's way out of his league with this kind of material. And these sections of the film, especially the group exchanges in the broken-down tenement house, seem badly edited, those conversations unclear in terms of point and plot --- and I've seen the movie multiple times. It's a shame Van Sant went down that road (the characters, specifically Keanu, breaking in and out of classical speech, which simply doesn't work), because there are many things about this picture that are really terrific... So view it with this in mind. ...and this: after the first couple of viewings of this hauntingly-odd picture, the flaws just seem to melt away and don't matter so much. And you can almost always tell a (potentially) good flick when it manages to inexplicably capture the zeitgeist of its era; in fact, I'm not sure I've ever seen one that evokes the cusp of the 80s/90s as vividly. (So did "Midnight Cowboy" for ITS era, so maybe male hookers is all that's really required. Go figure.) Even Keanu gives a better performance in the "normal" (non-Shakespearean) scenes than usual. And, as with every single River Phoenix movie ever filmed, this one is chock-full of eerily prescient moments of doom: like River seizing on the road, sidewalk, etc...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest for Security and the Return to the Tranquil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie years ago and I suspect that I knew that it had relations with Henry IV but until recently I had not see the original Shakespeare play. However, having read both parts, watched a BBC version of both parts, and also seen an amalgamation of both plays on stage I can say that I am much more familiar with it so that I can have a different understanding of this film. When I had first seen the film I had liked it, and I must say that I still like it, but the second time around, including being more familiar with Henry IV, I must say that it did not appeal to me as much. In part I think Van Sant has pulled away significantly from the original play with regards to the themes of the play as well as with regards to the character of Scott (played by Keanu Reeves and is Hal from the play). In a way Scott and Hal are both rebellious teenagers, but Scott is much more conscious of his desire to 'come good' when he turns 21 whereas this does not seem to be the case with Hal. In fact Hal has to prove to his father that he desires to become good, whereas it is clear from the film that Scott is in no danger of losing his inheritance. In Henry IV Poins is more of a supporting character who acts not so much as Hal's conscience but rather as a friend. In the film though Mike (River Pheonix, who corresponds with Poins) plays a much more important and central role. In fact the film is actually focused on Mike, as he goes on a fruitless search for his mother. There is tension between Mike and Scott because it is clear that Mike loves Scott but this love is not returned. This is something that we know is never going to happen, particularly when Scott says at the opening that as long as you do it for money then it is okay, but as soon as you begin to do it for free, you grow wings (and with that he then looks up at Mike as if suggesting that Mike has already grown wings). Another difference we see is that Scott readily deserts Scott when he gets his inheritance and finds the woman that he takes as his wife (though there is no indicating that there is any love, and we raise the question as to whether Scott is capable of love). Henry IV is many cases is about the right of passage that Hal takes from being a rebellious teenager to becoming a king, but this is something that we do not necessarily see here. Scott is not going through a rite of passage, nor is he learning, he is just having fun and behaving like a child while he is a child, and when he comes into his inheritance, he rejects his past and moves on. Okay, at the final scene, were the two funerals are contrasted (and one could say that both of Scott's fathers have died and are being buried) we see a part of Scott looking on at the other funeral. In a way the past has died, but one past, that of the wild and chaotic nature of youth, is also being buried to be replaced with the cold, clinical nature of adult life. I actually found Van Sant's attempts at Shakespearian language to be rather contrived. In the two scenes which are clearly taken from the play, that of Scott's rejection of Bob (who is the Falstaff figure) and the scene were he is mocking Bob after the robbery, we see that Van Sant is trying to create the poetic nature of the original play but using modern language in doing so. To me this fails completely. I can sort of see what he is going, and in a way he is using the play to build upon Scott's character, but the thing is that the movie is focused on Mike and not on Scott. Mike is vulnerable in many ways. Not only does he not understand himself, or even his sexuality (he confuses friendship with erotic love, and this is something that is not returned) he suffers from Narcolepsy. As long as Scott is around, Mike is safe, but as soon as Scott leaves we discover that he is more vulnerable than ever. In a way Mike's search for his mother is his search for security, in the same way that his quest for love is also his quest for security. We know that as long as Scott is around, Mike is secure, but when we see him on the street, back in Portland, we know that this is no longer the case. Then there is Idaho. The movie begins in Idaho, ends in Idaho, and visits Idaho in the middle. It is as if it is this tranquil place between the horrors of the world outside. It is the world of the unique, of the quite, and of the peaceful that pushes away the world of the street. We see the street in Seattle, in Portland, and even in Rome. Granted, we leave Rome for the country, but in a way it is not Idaho. Mike feels secure in Idaho, but not in Italy. However, we learn at the end that no even Idaho offers that protection, for when he collapses again, he is robbed. I guess the idea of the title suggests that is the case, one's search for peace, and that part inside of you were you can feel secure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets boring as it progresses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that starts off promising but as it progresses it just gets weird and bizarre but just not in a good way. It had my interest at first with the introduction of the characters but after the introductions and a bit of bonding between two characters it just got boring. I think the part I lost interest is when River Phoenix's character is visiting his dad in a trailer. It's basically a depressing and bitter road movie about two gay or bisexual male prostitutes on a road trip. Because they both have mother and father issues that they have to deal with. I give River Phoenix's character some sympathy but not so much for Keanu's character. Maybe because one is more in a rut than the other. And none of the characters are likable in this movie, which is fine since when it comes to the tragedy. It didn't get all that depressing. But the relationship and bonding between these two characters played by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves seemed authentic. Maybe because they were friends in real life. It's somewhat of a artsy flick and it's watchable but just didn't really entertain me or got my interest. It got weird and some of the characters gets pretty darn bizarre. But I guess it somewhat adds to the realism to a degree. This is the first movie I seen with River Phoenix and he basically owns this character. But maybe that is cause there is quite a lot of himself in this character. And Keanu...Well I never found the guy to be a brilliant actor. But he is somewhat versatile and fits right in usually with the role he is in. Overall, this movie through me off guard but not really in a good way. Plus I couldn't connect with any of the characters at all, although that may seem a bit conceited on my part. 4.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River tunes out, Keanu slums
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho is a bittersweet tale of two rent boys in the Pacific coast are and the contrasts between them. With the help of the greatest writer in the English language ever, William Shakespeare, Gus Van Sant draws two great characterizations in the characters realized by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves. You couldn't find two more opposite types in the world. River is a street kid through and through. Even the circumstances of his birth are a tragedy that I won't reveal. His mother leaves him as a youngster and he can't get over it and go on. He was raised by an older brother in the sparsely populated 'potato state' as he calls Idaho and the and the family dynamic was strained. He's a gay kid in an area where that could be deadly so he takes off for the fleshpots of Seattle and Portland where his youth and beauty will bring him some cash. He has no skills or education to support himself any other way. Sad, but the only hope this kid has of a decent life is to get taken up by some older sugar daddy who might just treat him to an education of some kind. That is if he can decide to just get over a bad home life and lack of a normal family. I've known gay kids who came from as lousy a background as River Phoenix and who never could get over it. River has developed an interesting defense mechanism and a psychologist would have field day with him if he got him on the coach. When the stress gets too much for him he just has a seizure like an epileptic, but in fact all he does is fall asleep. It's called narcilepsy, but he's vulnerable in that state as the film shows as well. River just tunes out the world. Keanu comes from a different world, his father is the Mayor of Portland, but he's dying and hopes to have his son take over the family political dynasty. But Tom Troupe is bitterly disappointed in his 'effeminate' son who like Prince Hal likes to hang out with lowlifes and street trash. Keanu's Falstaff is William Richert, a gay older man of a Falstaffian bloated belly who likes the young stuff and in his world probably treats them well. Gus Van Sant was quite imaginative in seeing the gay subtext that could be drawn from Prince Hal and Falstaff. Indeed Keanu says that Richert is closer to him than his real father. But he also says that he's planning to work a change in him when he comes into his own. And he says it in dialog taken from Shakespeare's Henry IV Parts one and two. The most touching scene is with River and Keanu out in the country at a fire where River basically confesses his love for him. It's love to be sure, but River also sees in Keanu a figure who has confidence and self assurance and those are the qualities that draws him to Reeves. What Phoenix misreads is that self confidence is really a safety net that he knows he has and at the appropriate time uses. Although he's gay for pay as he states, he still allows River to have sex with him. I suspect that Gus Van Sant from his own background knows full well that gay for pay is not always 100% absolute. Reeves goes on to his destiny for which if you know your Shakespeare know what that is. Phoenix's destiny is less clear, more than likely an oblivion that a lot of those kids go to. As a fantasy I'd like to think that as Reeves denies himself, closets himself as he moves on in life, that an older River comes back to remind him of his roots. We all know of the tragedy of River Phoenix who died way too young just like a lot of street kids do ironically. There is a second tragedy in the My Own Private Idaho. Rodney Harvey who played one of River and Keanu's street peers also died way too young in similar circumstances to Phoenix. Not only does Van Sant give us an excellent two person character study, but his other character with less dialog than the leads also are fully formed characters which is the mark that many including me say indicates a great film. My Own Private Idaho is a troubling picture, but a realistic one of the underside of gay life that we cannot ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As current today as it was then....a modern classic perhaps.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho Director: Gus Van Sant Starring: River Phoenix, Keanu Reeves, James Russo. Gus Van Sant essentially takes on Shakespeare's Henry IV; it featured the aesthetically delightful River Phoenix as Mike Waters, a wonderfully apt narcoleptic male whore who we first get a glimpse of tipping down an open stretch of road in Idaho. Mike and the action shifts from the cold Seattle to equally cold Portland. It is here that he makes friends with Scott Favor, a secretly soon to be rich guy who is also on the game played by the often-maligned Keanu Reeves. The future for both is as uncertain as uncertain can be, will Scott take up the inheritance he about to get, will Mike survive the streets with his narcolepsy? ￼ Mike feels real affections for Scott, however Scott refuses to believe men can really love each and it would seem that Scott is only doing the gay whole whore thing to kill time and get back at his family. Mike believes Scott will continue with the grand life on the streets, turning tricks even after he bags the inheritance; such is the allure of the unknown. There are many of fellow working boys who agree with Mike's view. This is an uneasy picture, a colourful and surreal attempt to really take the characters to a different kingdom. At times, it is a wonderful although slightly glossy take on the real street hustlers shagging their way to oblivion or not as the individual case may be. Drug abuse and risky behaviours are commonplace on the streets and in the world of the male hooker and it is a small feature of this sometimes-disturbing film. The character of Mike seems almost apologetically plausible, abandoned as a child and obsessed with finding his real long lost mother. Scott less believable as the rebellious disillusioned spoilt little rich kid gone rebelliously bad. You really would not have put them together by design, but fate disregards those lines and together they embark on a quest to find Mike's mother, from Portland to Idaho to Italy they do travel. There is no argument the cinematic quality and the unbelievably stunning settings help to make this film an intriguingly striking viewing delight. It is exceptionally well thought out in terms of location and setting and a master-class for any would be cinematographer. The characterisation I found to be impressive, even Keanu Reeves played his part with just the right amount of smug pathos and humour, especially with the flippantly arrogant lines afford to him. River Phoenix works pure magic on screen with this performance and I am fairly sure I'm not alone in believing this is the role that set him into the great immortal movie star hall of fame. It is no wonder that he pulled in a number of 'best actor' type awards for this intrinsically faceted role. His campfire scene, in which Mike declares his love for Scott, is much applauded by audiences and critics alike  Newsweek claiming it to be "A marvel of delicacy" it really is a testament to what a wonderful talent River Phoenix was, because he wrote that part of the script himself. Village Voice said, "Phoenix vanishes with reckless triumph into his role". It earned around &pound;5 million at the box office worldwide, which is quite impressive, more than that in video and DVD sales. My Own Private Idaho takes the spirit and passion of Shakespeare, bends, manipulates and shapes it to find form in a more modern setting, which works beyond expectation in the most part. Although the traditionalist in me seems to hold the opinion that you should not mess with old Shaky and if you do, you best be prepared to face the harshest of critics. Adaptations are always open to personal interpretation and modifications, which others may not agree with, like or even accept, yet this one seems to work and seems to be commended as a job well done.Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem in the movie genre - very emotional & moving with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry07
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard of this movie for a while now (since it came out I guess) and never had the chance to watch it. Finally, I got my hand on a DVD and was stunned: how could I have missed this before? I would classify this movie in the Indie genre (if that applied to movies), as its style is unusual. Essentially, the dialogs may go into long theatrical speech (literally) rather than a fluent every day life dialog. You get annoyed at times (did not expect a Shakespeare play but a movie) as some of the scenes within this style are not working out (imagine Keanu Reeves in a play - nope! doesn't work for me either). But if you can pass beyond this problem, you will find a gem. Indeed, the characters! What a treat. River Phoenix (Mike) performance is simply breathtaking and inspired: you immediately feel the character of "Mike", the abandoned and confused child not only reverting to hustling for money but striving for belonging, acceptance and love going in life with the dream and memory of his mother. His friendship with Scott (Keanu Reeves) will bring them into a journey where emotions and classics are all covered: lightness and energy of youth, rebellion of the privileged, loneliness, burning passions, struggles and survival, loss, desire. On second thought, perhaps it works well as a Shakespearian play (yes, I know it was intended) but not only because the dialogs are like so but due to the in-depth drama of this movie the breadth of emotion it covers. The story line is flooded with the view of Mike (also narcoleptic) and appears at times as a dream. As a result, to me, the whole movie is simply a great piece, poetic, breath taking and emotional: you stay watching through the theater scenes wanting to know what's next, you get hooked to the artistic aspects of the movie (music is often blending and you find yourself noticing that many details have significance) and you feel for the characters at a deep and intense level as if the topics treated are archetypal. For sure, you will remember this movie whether you were thrown off by it, liked it or loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    trippy arty homage to Shakespeare's Henry IV. a powerful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every time I see this film, I forget how incredibly amazing it is. Yes I'm a huge fan of of the late, great, River Phoenix, think Keanu Reeves is highly underrated, and love Shakespeare. This is a modern adaptation to Henry IV, based around two hustlers Mike and Scott (River and Keanu) and their relationship, with the added wrinkle that Mikey is a narcoleptic and trying to find his long lost mother. Scott is the rich boy who turns his back on his street life when his inheritance kicks in. River's performance is astounding, tender and powerful, and it's a brave pair of best friends (in real life) that take on roles like this but the affection between them is palpable and somehow makes the story of unrequited love even more heartbreaking. The Shakespeare gets confusing if you aren't familiar, as it washes in and out, and if you haven't seen Gus Van Sant before you might not quite follow the surreal imagery and the trippy nature of the film. It's arty, weird and dark, but has a lot of humour and sensitivity, despite being a little bawdy in places, however for all it's adult subject matter it's quite discrete! River and Keanu are astounding in this, and it's a film that River should be remembered for as the bright star he was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like a super 8
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like a super 8 film from the 70's/80's New York this felt like it was art created for the screen on a setting, the open plan falling down dilapidated building. Beautifully shot with scenes of the hills and fields that seemed to roll on forever. The acting even included San Sant himself as well as Grace Zabriskie who is normally in David Lynch's films. The story was maybe even too weird for me and didn't really get a resonance and stayed very flat, it was not his best but showed how he can make his films. Although it was maybe too weird it still made me want to be there in that building, the place where creativity happens, as spaces like that spark imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much ado about nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A narcoleptic hustler and his 'degenerate' (to his father) pal travel the Pacific Northwest in search ofwhat? Freedom? Affection? Adventure? Gus Van Sant's follow up to his career breakthrough 'Drugstore Cowboy' is full odd stylistic tics and transparent social commentary, all of it adding up to a merely pretentious film even more aimless and unmotivated than its two primary characters. Viewers might be forgiven for wondering where the story is going after the brief detour into Idaho itself (the trailer home reunion is a highlight), when the scene shifts abruptly, and for no good reason, to sunny Rome (yes, in Italy). There's plenty to look at, but all the gorgeous imagery hides a shortage of real ideas, and Van Sant's mock Shakespearean dialogue is an annoying conceit (at least the Bard is acknowledged in the credits). Udo Kier, as 'Hans', steals the film away from its two young stars, and the brief documentary appearance of actual teenage hustlers discussing their 'dates' shows what the film could have aspired to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River Phoenix is excellent, as is the film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indie_Locker
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant has always been an interesting filmmaker. He cares about character and story and through the process, his artistic integrity is able to shine through his work and that is why he's considered a prominent director in independent cinema. My Own Private Idaho is more of is more well known independent features and is often viewed as a triumph of independent cinema from the 1990s. The film follows Mark Waters (River Phoenix) an aimless, misguided young man who hustles on the streets and is yearning to find his way in life. His best friend is Scott Favor (Keanu Reeves), who is also a young man and and a hustler, but who instead is running away from his life in the hope of finding something better. Scott comes from a lot of wealth but chooses not to live that lifestyle because when he's this young and wild, he just doesn't believe that its right for him. However the film is centered around Mark, who is played with such brutal honestly by the late River Phoenix. River is completely dedicated to the character and brings a wonderful vulnerability to a lost soul and it makes him relatable. We watch him go from scene to scene, leaving us as unaware of his future as he is. We watch him make many mistakes and we want him to better himself but such a task is not easy. Because that's the way life is. Mark hustles because its just who he is. We don't know how he got here, but we know that he has fallen into this lifestyle and it has consumed him. He needs the money. All of his friends are hustlers, too. He has dreams but its tough to say if he ever truly wants to leave the lifestyle. It seems that getting clients and often falling asleep during it (due to him being narcoleptic) doesn't seem to take as much of a toll on him as does his thoughts about his mother, or his feelings for his best friend. Gus Van Sant crafts a very fine film here that focuses on such a lifestyle that we're not exposed to in our every day lives and turns it into something we can all relate to. It all comes back to that road, the road that we're all on. Does it really end? Probably not. Much like in the way that Mark is shown standing on that road, staring out into the nothingness. Its really about our lives. We live and we're happy, and we're sad, and we're lonely, and we're lost, and we've found ourselves, all of these things happen on the very same road that never ends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good... and very flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PrometheusTree64
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought the Criterion Collection DVD of this because I loved River Phoenix before it was a clich&eacute;. Nevertheless, I saw this in the theater when it was first released, and my opinion hasn't changed: Phoenix is as good as you've heard and the film absolutely has it's moments --- many wonderful moments. Then there's Keanu. Who tried to marry this guy to Shakespeare? He's way out of his league with this kind of material. And these sections of the film, especially the group exchanges in the broken-down tenement house, seem badly edited, those conversations unclear in terms of point and plot --- and I've seen the movie multiple times. It's a shame Van Sant went down that road (the characters, specifically Keanu, breaking in and out of classical speech, which simply doesn't work), because there are many things about this picture that are really terrific... So view it with this in mind. ...and this: after the first couple of viewings of this hauntingly-odd picture, the flaws just seem to melt away and don't matter so much. And you can almost always tell a (potentially) good flick when it manages to inexplicably capture the zeitgeist of its era; in fact, I'm not sure I've ever seen one that evokes the cusp of the 80s/90s as vividly. (So did "Midnight Cowboy" for ITS era, so maybe male hookers is all that's really required. Go figure.) Even Keanu gives a better performance in the "normal" (non-Shakespearean) scenes than usual. And, as with every single River Phoenix movie ever filmed, this one is chock-full of eerily prescient moments of doom: like River seizing on the road, sidewalk, etc...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest for Security and the Return to the Tranquil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie years ago and I suspect that I knew that it had relations with Henry IV but until recently I had not see the original Shakespeare play. However, having read both parts, watched a BBC version of both parts, and also seen an amalgamation of both plays on stage I can say that I am much more familiar with it so that I can have a different understanding of this film. When I had first seen the film I had liked it, and I must say that I still like it, but the second time around, including being more familiar with Henry IV, I must say that it did not appeal to me as much. In part I think Van Sant has pulled away significantly from the original play with regards to the themes of the play as well as with regards to the character of Scott (played by Keanu Reeves and is Hal from the play). In a way Scott and Hal are both rebellious teenagers, but Scott is much more conscious of his desire to 'come good' when he turns 21 whereas this does not seem to be the case with Hal. In fact Hal has to prove to his father that he desires to become good, whereas it is clear from the film that Scott is in no danger of losing his inheritance. In Henry IV Poins is more of a supporting character who acts not so much as Hal's conscience but rather as a friend. In the film though Mike (River Pheonix, who corresponds with Poins) plays a much more important and central role. In fact the film is actually focused on Mike, as he goes on a fruitless search for his mother. There is tension between Mike and Scott because it is clear that Mike loves Scott but this love is not returned. This is something that we know is never going to happen, particularly when Scott says at the opening that as long as you do it for money then it is okay, but as soon as you begin to do it for free, you grow wings (and with that he then looks up at Mike as if suggesting that Mike has already grown wings). Another difference we see is that Scott readily deserts Scott when he gets his inheritance and finds the woman that he takes as his wife (though there is no indicating that there is any love, and we raise the question as to whether Scott is capable of love). Henry IV is many cases is about the right of passage that Hal takes from being a rebellious teenager to becoming a king, but this is something that we do not necessarily see here. Scott is not going through a rite of passage, nor is he learning, he is just having fun and behaving like a child while he is a child, and when he comes into his inheritance, he rejects his past and moves on. Okay, at the final scene, were the two funerals are contrasted (and one could say that both of Scott's fathers have died and are being buried) we see a part of Scott looking on at the other funeral. In a way the past has died, but one past, that of the wild and chaotic nature of youth, is also being buried to be replaced with the cold, clinical nature of adult life. I actually found Van Sant's attempts at Shakespearian language to be rather contrived. In the two scenes which are clearly taken from the play, that of Scott's rejection of Bob (who is the Falstaff figure) and the scene were he is mocking Bob after the robbery, we see that Van Sant is trying to create the poetic nature of the original play but using modern language in doing so. To me this fails completely. I can sort of see what he is going, and in a way he is using the play to build upon Scott's character, but the thing is that the movie is focused on Mike and not on Scott. Mike is vulnerable in many ways. Not only does he not understand himself, or even his sexuality (he confuses friendship with erotic love, and this is something that is not returned) he suffers from Narcolepsy. As long as Scott is around, Mike is safe, but as soon as Scott leaves we discover that he is more vulnerable than ever. In a way Mike's search for his mother is his search for security, in the same way that his quest for love is also his quest for security. We know that as long as Scott is around, Mike is secure, but when we see him on the street, back in Portland, we know that this is no longer the case. Then there is Idaho. The movie begins in Idaho, ends in Idaho, and visits Idaho in the middle. It is as if it is this tranquil place between the horrors of the world outside. It is the world of the unique, of the quite, and of the peaceful that pushes away the world of the street. We see the street in Seattle, in Portland, and even in Rome. Granted, we leave Rome for the country, but in a way it is not Idaho. Mike feels secure in Idaho, but not in Italy. However, we learn at the end that no even Idaho offers that protection, for when he collapses again, he is robbed. I guess the idea of the title suggests that is the case, one's search for peace, and that part inside of you were you can feel secure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets boring as it progresses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that starts off promising but as it progresses it just gets weird and bizarre but just not in a good way. It had my interest at first with the introduction of the characters but after the introductions and a bit of bonding between two characters it just got boring. I think the part I lost interest is when River Phoenix's character is visiting his dad in a trailer. It's basically a depressing and bitter road movie about two gay or bisexual male prostitutes on a road trip. Because they both have mother and father issues that they have to deal with. I give River Phoenix's character some sympathy but not so much for Keanu's character. Maybe because one is more in a rut than the other. And none of the characters are likable in this movie, which is fine since when it comes to the tragedy. It didn't get all that depressing. But the relationship and bonding between these two characters played by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves seemed authentic. Maybe because they were friends in real life. It's somewhat of a artsy flick and it's watchable but just didn't really entertain me or got my interest. It got weird and some of the characters gets pretty darn bizarre. But I guess it somewhat adds to the realism to a degree. This is the first movie I seen with River Phoenix and he basically owns this character. But maybe that is cause there is quite a lot of himself in this character. And Keanu...Well I never found the guy to be a brilliant actor. But he is somewhat versatile and fits right in usually with the role he is in. Overall, this movie through me off guard but not really in a good way. Plus I couldn't connect with any of the characters at all, although that may seem a bit conceited on my part. 4.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River tunes out, Keanu slums
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho is a bittersweet tale of two rent boys in the Pacific coast are and the contrasts between them. With the help of the greatest writer in the English language ever, William Shakespeare, Gus Van Sant draws two great characterizations in the characters realized by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves. You couldn't find two more opposite types in the world. River is a street kid through and through. Even the circumstances of his birth are a tragedy that I won't reveal. His mother leaves him as a youngster and he can't get over it and go on. He was raised by an older brother in the sparsely populated 'potato state' as he calls Idaho and the and the family dynamic was strained. He's a gay kid in an area where that could be deadly so he takes off for the fleshpots of Seattle and Portland where his youth and beauty will bring him some cash. He has no skills or education to support himself any other way. Sad, but the only hope this kid has of a decent life is to get taken up by some older sugar daddy who might just treat him to an education of some kind. That is if he can decide to just get over a bad home life and lack of a normal family. I've known gay kids who came from as lousy a background as River Phoenix and who never could get over it. River has developed an interesting defense mechanism and a psychologist would have field day with him if he got him on the coach. When the stress gets too much for him he just has a seizure like an epileptic, but in fact all he does is fall asleep. It's called narcilepsy, but he's vulnerable in that state as the film shows as well. River just tunes out the world. Keanu comes from a different world, his father is the Mayor of Portland, but he's dying and hopes to have his son take over the family political dynasty. But Tom Troupe is bitterly disappointed in his 'effeminate' son who like Prince Hal likes to hang out with lowlifes and street trash. Keanu's Falstaff is William Richert, a gay older man of a Falstaffian bloated belly who likes the young stuff and in his world probably treats them well. Gus Van Sant was quite imaginative in seeing the gay subtext that could be drawn from Prince Hal and Falstaff. Indeed Keanu says that Richert is closer to him than his real father. But he also says that he's planning to work a change in him when he comes into his own. And he says it in dialog taken from Shakespeare's Henry IV Parts one and two. The most touching scene is with River and Keanu out in the country at a fire where River basically confesses his love for him. It's love to be sure, but River also sees in Keanu a figure who has confidence and self assurance and those are the qualities that draws him to Reeves. What Phoenix misreads is that self confidence is really a safety net that he knows he has and at the appropriate time uses. Although he's gay for pay as he states, he still allows River to have sex with him. I suspect that Gus Van Sant from his own background knows full well that gay for pay is not always 100% absolute. Reeves goes on to his destiny for which if you know your Shakespeare know what that is. Phoenix's destiny is less clear, more than likely an oblivion that a lot of those kids go to. As a fantasy I'd like to think that as Reeves denies himself, closets himself as he moves on in life, that an older River comes back to remind him of his roots. We all know of the tragedy of River Phoenix who died way too young just like a lot of street kids do ironically. There is a second tragedy in the My Own Private Idaho. Rodney Harvey who played one of River and Keanu's street peers also died way too young in similar circumstances to Phoenix. Not only does Van Sant give us an excellent two person character study, but his other character with less dialog than the leads also are fully formed characters which is the mark that many including me say indicates a great film. My Own Private Idaho is a troubling picture, but a realistic one of the underside of gay life that we cannot ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As current today as it was then....a modern classic perhaps.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho Director: Gus Van Sant Starring: River Phoenix, Keanu Reeves, James Russo. Gus Van Sant essentially takes on Shakespeare's Henry IV; it featured the aesthetically delightful River Phoenix as Mike Waters, a wonderfully apt narcoleptic male whore who we first get a glimpse of tipping down an open stretch of road in Idaho. Mike and the action shifts from the cold Seattle to equally cold Portland. It is here that he makes friends with Scott Favor, a secretly soon to be rich guy who is also on the game played by the often-maligned Keanu Reeves. The future for both is as uncertain as uncertain can be, will Scott take up the inheritance he about to get, will Mike survive the streets with his narcolepsy? ￼ Mike feels real affections for Scott, however Scott refuses to believe men can really love each and it would seem that Scott is only doing the gay whole whore thing to kill time and get back at his family. Mike believes Scott will continue with the grand life on the streets, turning tricks even after he bags the inheritance; such is the allure of the unknown. There are many of fellow working boys who agree with Mike's view. This is an uneasy picture, a colourful and surreal attempt to really take the characters to a different kingdom. At times, it is a wonderful although slightly glossy take on the real street hustlers shagging their way to oblivion or not as the individual case may be. Drug abuse and risky behaviours are commonplace on the streets and in the world of the male hooker and it is a small feature of this sometimes-disturbing film. The character of Mike seems almost apologetically plausible, abandoned as a child and obsessed with finding his real long lost mother. Scott less believable as the rebellious disillusioned spoilt little rich kid gone rebelliously bad. You really would not have put them together by design, but fate disregards those lines and together they embark on a quest to find Mike's mother, from Portland to Idaho to Italy they do travel. There is no argument the cinematic quality and the unbelievably stunning settings help to make this film an intriguingly striking viewing delight. It is exceptionally well thought out in terms of location and setting and a master-class for any would be cinematographer. The characterisation I found to be impressive, even Keanu Reeves played his part with just the right amount of smug pathos and humour, especially with the flippantly arrogant lines afford to him. River Phoenix works pure magic on screen with this performance and I am fairly sure I'm not alone in believing this is the role that set him into the great immortal movie star hall of fame. It is no wonder that he pulled in a number of 'best actor' type awards for this intrinsically faceted role. His campfire scene, in which Mike declares his love for Scott, is much applauded by audiences and critics alike  Newsweek claiming it to be "A marvel of delicacy" it really is a testament to what a wonderful talent River Phoenix was, because he wrote that part of the script himself. Village Voice said, "Phoenix vanishes with reckless triumph into his role". It earned around &pound;5 million at the box office worldwide, which is quite impressive, more than that in video and DVD sales. My Own Private Idaho takes the spirit and passion of Shakespeare, bends, manipulates and shapes it to find form in a more modern setting, which works beyond expectation in the most part. Although the traditionalist in me seems to hold the opinion that you should not mess with old Shaky and if you do, you best be prepared to face the harshest of critics. Adaptations are always open to personal interpretation and modifications, which others may not agree with, like or even accept, yet this one seems to work and seems to be commended as a job well done.Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem in the movie genre - very emotional & moving with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry07
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard of this movie for a while now (since it came out I guess) and never had the chance to watch it. Finally, I got my hand on a DVD and was stunned: how could I have missed this before? I would classify this movie in the Indie genre (if that applied to movies), as its style is unusual. Essentially, the dialogs may go into long theatrical speech (literally) rather than a fluent every day life dialog. You get annoyed at times (did not expect a Shakespeare play but a movie) as some of the scenes within this style are not working out (imagine Keanu Reeves in a play - nope! doesn't work for me either). But if you can pass beyond this problem, you will find a gem. Indeed, the characters! What a treat. River Phoenix (Mike) performance is simply breathtaking and inspired: you immediately feel the character of "Mike", the abandoned and confused child not only reverting to hustling for money but striving for belonging, acceptance and love going in life with the dream and memory of his mother. His friendship with Scott (Keanu Reeves) will bring them into a journey where emotions and classics are all covered: lightness and energy of youth, rebellion of the privileged, loneliness, burning passions, struggles and survival, loss, desire. On second thought, perhaps it works well as a Shakespearian play (yes, I know it was intended) but not only because the dialogs are like so but due to the in-depth drama of this movie the breadth of emotion it covers. The story line is flooded with the view of Mike (also narcoleptic) and appears at times as a dream. As a result, to me, the whole movie is simply a great piece, poetic, breath taking and emotional: you stay watching through the theater scenes wanting to know what's next, you get hooked to the artistic aspects of the movie (music is often blending and you find yourself noticing that many details have significance) and you feel for the characters at a deep and intense level as if the topics treated are archetypal. For sure, you will remember this movie whether you were thrown off by it, liked it or loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    trippy arty homage to Shakespeare's Henry IV. a powerful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every time I see this film, I forget how incredibly amazing it is. Yes I'm a huge fan of of the late, great, River Phoenix, think Keanu Reeves is highly underrated, and love Shakespeare. This is a modern adaptation to Henry IV, based around two hustlers Mike and Scott (River and Keanu) and their relationship, with the added wrinkle that Mikey is a narcoleptic and trying to find his long lost mother. Scott is the rich boy who turns his back on his street life when his inheritance kicks in. River's performance is astounding, tender and powerful, and it's a brave pair of best friends (in real life) that take on roles like this but the affection between them is palpable and somehow makes the story of unrequited love even more heartbreaking. The Shakespeare gets confusing if you aren't familiar, as it washes in and out, and if you haven't seen Gus Van Sant before you might not quite follow the surreal imagery and the trippy nature of the film. It's arty, weird and dark, but has a lot of humour and sensitivity, despite being a little bawdy in places, however for all it's adult subject matter it's quite discrete! River and Keanu are astounding in this, and it's a film that River should be remembered for as the bright star he was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like a super 8
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like a super 8 film from the 70's/80's New York this felt like it was art created for the screen on a setting, the open plan falling down dilapidated building. Beautifully shot with scenes of the hills and fields that seemed to roll on forever. The acting even included San Sant himself as well as Grace Zabriskie who is normally in David Lynch's films. The story was maybe even too weird for me and didn't really get a resonance and stayed very flat, it was not his best but showed how he can make his films. Although it was maybe too weird it still made me want to be there in that building, the place where creativity happens, as spaces like that spark imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much ado about nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A narcoleptic hustler and his 'degenerate' (to his father) pal travel the Pacific Northwest in search ofwhat? Freedom? Affection? Adventure? Gus Van Sant's follow up to his career breakthrough 'Drugstore Cowboy' is full odd stylistic tics and transparent social commentary, all of it adding up to a merely pretentious film even more aimless and unmotivated than its two primary characters. Viewers might be forgiven for wondering where the story is going after the brief detour into Idaho itself (the trailer home reunion is a highlight), when the scene shifts abruptly, and for no good reason, to sunny Rome (yes, in Italy). There's plenty to look at, but all the gorgeous imagery hides a shortage of real ideas, and Van Sant's mock Shakespearean dialogue is an annoying conceit (at least the Bard is acknowledged in the credits). Udo Kier, as 'Hans', steals the film away from its two young stars, and the brief documentary appearance of actual teenage hustlers discussing their 'dates' shows what the film could have aspired to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River Phoenix is excellent, as is the film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Indie_Locker
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant has always been an interesting filmmaker. He cares about character and story and through the process, his artistic integrity is able to shine through his work and that is why he's considered a prominent director in independent cinema. My Own Private Idaho is more of is more well known independent features and is often viewed as a triumph of independent cinema from the 1990s. The film follows Mark Waters (River Phoenix) an aimless, misguided young man who hustles on the streets and is yearning to find his way in life. His best friend is Scott Favor (Keanu Reeves), who is also a young man and and a hustler, but who instead is running away from his life in the hope of finding something better. Scott comes from a lot of wealth but chooses not to live that lifestyle because when he's this young and wild, he just doesn't believe that its right for him. However the film is centered around Mark, who is played with such brutal honestly by the late River Phoenix. River is completely dedicated to the character and brings a wonderful vulnerability to a lost soul and it makes him relatable. We watch him go from scene to scene, leaving us as unaware of his future as he is. We watch him make many mistakes and we want him to better himself but such a task is not easy. Because that's the way life is. Mark hustles because its just who he is. We don't know how he got here, but we know that he has fallen into this lifestyle and it has consumed him. He needs the money. All of his friends are hustlers, too. He has dreams but its tough to say if he ever truly wants to leave the lifestyle. It seems that getting clients and often falling asleep during it (due to him being narcoleptic) doesn't seem to take as much of a toll on him as does his thoughts about his mother, or his feelings for his best friend. Gus Van Sant crafts a very fine film here that focuses on such a lifestyle that we're not exposed to in our every day lives and turns it into something we can all relate to. It all comes back to that road, the road that we're all on. Does it really end? Probably not. Much like in the way that Mark is shown standing on that road, staring out into the nothingness. Its really about our lives. We live and we're happy, and we're sad, and we're lonely, and we're lost, and we've found ourselves, all of these things happen on the very same road that never ends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good... and very flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PrometheusTree64
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I bought the Criterion Collection DVD of this because I loved River Phoenix before it was a clich&eacute;. Nevertheless, I saw this in the theater when it was first released, and my opinion hasn't changed: Phoenix is as good as you've heard and the film absolutely has it's moments --- many wonderful moments. Then there's Keanu. Who tried to marry this guy to Shakespeare? He's way out of his league with this kind of material. And these sections of the film, especially the group exchanges in the broken-down tenement house, seem badly edited, those conversations unclear in terms of point and plot --- and I've seen the movie multiple times. It's a shame Van Sant went down that road (the characters, specifically Keanu, breaking in and out of classical speech, which simply doesn't work), because there are many things about this picture that are really terrific... So view it with this in mind. ...and this: after the first couple of viewings of this hauntingly-odd picture, the flaws just seem to melt away and don't matter so much. And you can almost always tell a (potentially) good flick when it manages to inexplicably capture the zeitgeist of its era; in fact, I'm not sure I've ever seen one that evokes the cusp of the 80s/90s as vividly. (So did "Midnight Cowboy" for ITS era, so maybe male hookers is all that's really required. Go figure.) Even Keanu gives a better performance in the "normal" (non-Shakespearean) scenes than usual. And, as with every single River Phoenix movie ever filmed, this one is chock-full of eerily prescient moments of doom: like River seizing on the road, sidewalk, etc...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Quest for Security and the Return to the Tranquil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie years ago and I suspect that I knew that it had relations with Henry IV but until recently I had not see the original Shakespeare play. However, having read both parts, watched a BBC version of both parts, and also seen an amalgamation of both plays on stage I can say that I am much more familiar with it so that I can have a different understanding of this film. When I had first seen the film I had liked it, and I must say that I still like it, but the second time around, including being more familiar with Henry IV, I must say that it did not appeal to me as much. In part I think Van Sant has pulled away significantly from the original play with regards to the themes of the play as well as with regards to the character of Scott (played by Keanu Reeves and is Hal from the play). In a way Scott and Hal are both rebellious teenagers, but Scott is much more conscious of his desire to 'come good' when he turns 21 whereas this does not seem to be the case with Hal. In fact Hal has to prove to his father that he desires to become good, whereas it is clear from the film that Scott is in no danger of losing his inheritance. In Henry IV Poins is more of a supporting character who acts not so much as Hal's conscience but rather as a friend. In the film though Mike (River Pheonix, who corresponds with Poins) plays a much more important and central role. In fact the film is actually focused on Mike, as he goes on a fruitless search for his mother. There is tension between Mike and Scott because it is clear that Mike loves Scott but this love is not returned. This is something that we know is never going to happen, particularly when Scott says at the opening that as long as you do it for money then it is okay, but as soon as you begin to do it for free, you grow wings (and with that he then looks up at Mike as if suggesting that Mike has already grown wings). Another difference we see is that Scott readily deserts Scott when he gets his inheritance and finds the woman that he takes as his wife (though there is no indicating that there is any love, and we raise the question as to whether Scott is capable of love). Henry IV is many cases is about the right of passage that Hal takes from being a rebellious teenager to becoming a king, but this is something that we do not necessarily see here. Scott is not going through a rite of passage, nor is he learning, he is just having fun and behaving like a child while he is a child, and when he comes into his inheritance, he rejects his past and moves on. Okay, at the final scene, were the two funerals are contrasted (and one could say that both of Scott's fathers have died and are being buried) we see a part of Scott looking on at the other funeral. In a way the past has died, but one past, that of the wild and chaotic nature of youth, is also being buried to be replaced with the cold, clinical nature of adult life. I actually found Van Sant's attempts at Shakespearian language to be rather contrived. In the two scenes which are clearly taken from the play, that of Scott's rejection of Bob (who is the Falstaff figure) and the scene were he is mocking Bob after the robbery, we see that Van Sant is trying to create the poetic nature of the original play but using modern language in doing so. To me this fails completely. I can sort of see what he is going, and in a way he is using the play to build upon Scott's character, but the thing is that the movie is focused on Mike and not on Scott. Mike is vulnerable in many ways. Not only does he not understand himself, or even his sexuality (he confuses friendship with erotic love, and this is something that is not returned) he suffers from Narcolepsy. As long as Scott is around, Mike is safe, but as soon as Scott leaves we discover that he is more vulnerable than ever. In a way Mike's search for his mother is his search for security, in the same way that his quest for love is also his quest for security. We know that as long as Scott is around, Mike is secure, but when we see him on the street, back in Portland, we know that this is no longer the case. Then there is Idaho. The movie begins in Idaho, ends in Idaho, and visits Idaho in the middle. It is as if it is this tranquil place between the horrors of the world outside. It is the world of the unique, of the quite, and of the peaceful that pushes away the world of the street. We see the street in Seattle, in Portland, and even in Rome. Granted, we leave Rome for the country, but in a way it is not Idaho. Mike feels secure in Idaho, but not in Italy. However, we learn at the end that no even Idaho offers that protection, for when he collapses again, he is robbed. I guess the idea of the title suggests that is the case, one's search for peace, and that part inside of you were you can feel secure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets boring as it progresses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KineticSeoul
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that starts off promising but as it progresses it just gets weird and bizarre but just not in a good way. It had my interest at first with the introduction of the characters but after the introductions and a bit of bonding between two characters it just got boring. I think the part I lost interest is when River Phoenix's character is visiting his dad in a trailer. It's basically a depressing and bitter road movie about two gay or bisexual male prostitutes on a road trip. Because they both have mother and father issues that they have to deal with. I give River Phoenix's character some sympathy but not so much for Keanu's character. Maybe because one is more in a rut than the other. And none of the characters are likable in this movie, which is fine since when it comes to the tragedy. It didn't get all that depressing. But the relationship and bonding between these two characters played by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves seemed authentic. Maybe because they were friends in real life. It's somewhat of a artsy flick and it's watchable but just didn't really entertain me or got my interest. It got weird and some of the characters gets pretty darn bizarre. But I guess it somewhat adds to the realism to a degree. This is the first movie I seen with River Phoenix and he basically owns this character. But maybe that is cause there is quite a lot of himself in this character. And Keanu...Well I never found the guy to be a brilliant actor. But he is somewhat versatile and fits right in usually with the role he is in. Overall, this movie through me off guard but not really in a good way. Plus I couldn't connect with any of the characters at all, although that may seem a bit conceited on my part. 4.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    River tunes out, Keanu slums
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho is a bittersweet tale of two rent boys in the Pacific coast are and the contrasts between them. With the help of the greatest writer in the English language ever, William Shakespeare, Gus Van Sant draws two great characterizations in the characters realized by River Phoenix and Keanu Reeves. You couldn't find two more opposite types in the world. River is a street kid through and through. Even the circumstances of his birth are a tragedy that I won't reveal. His mother leaves him as a youngster and he can't get over it and go on. He was raised by an older brother in the sparsely populated 'potato state' as he calls Idaho and the and the family dynamic was strained. He's a gay kid in an area where that could be deadly so he takes off for the fleshpots of Seattle and Portland where his youth and beauty will bring him some cash. He has no skills or education to support himself any other way. Sad, but the only hope this kid has of a decent life is to get taken up by some older sugar daddy who might just treat him to an education of some kind. That is if he can decide to just get over a bad home life and lack of a normal family. I've known gay kids who came from as lousy a background as River Phoenix and who never could get over it. River has developed an interesting defense mechanism and a psychologist would have field day with him if he got him on the coach. When the stress gets too much for him he just has a seizure like an epileptic, but in fact all he does is fall asleep. It's called narcilepsy, but he's vulnerable in that state as the film shows as well. River just tunes out the world. Keanu comes from a different world, his father is the Mayor of Portland, but he's dying and hopes to have his son take over the family political dynasty. But Tom Troupe is bitterly disappointed in his 'effeminate' son who like Prince Hal likes to hang out with lowlifes and street trash. Keanu's Falstaff is William Richert, a gay older man of a Falstaffian bloated belly who likes the young stuff and in his world probably treats them well. Gus Van Sant was quite imaginative in seeing the gay subtext that could be drawn from Prince Hal and Falstaff. Indeed Keanu says that Richert is closer to him than his real father. But he also says that he's planning to work a change in him when he comes into his own. And he says it in dialog taken from Shakespeare's Henry IV Parts one and two. The most touching scene is with River and Keanu out in the country at a fire where River basically confesses his love for him. It's love to be sure, but River also sees in Keanu a figure who has confidence and self assurance and those are the qualities that draws him to Reeves. What Phoenix misreads is that self confidence is really a safety net that he knows he has and at the appropriate time uses. Although he's gay for pay as he states, he still allows River to have sex with him. I suspect that Gus Van Sant from his own background knows full well that gay for pay is not always 100% absolute. Reeves goes on to his destiny for which if you know your Shakespeare know what that is. Phoenix's destiny is less clear, more than likely an oblivion that a lot of those kids go to. As a fantasy I'd like to think that as Reeves denies himself, closets himself as he moves on in life, that an older River comes back to remind him of his roots. We all know of the tragedy of River Phoenix who died way too young just like a lot of street kids do ironically. There is a second tragedy in the My Own Private Idaho. Rodney Harvey who played one of River and Keanu's street peers also died way too young in similar circumstances to Phoenix. Not only does Van Sant give us an excellent two person character study, but his other character with less dialog than the leads also are fully formed characters which is the mark that many including me say indicates a great film. My Own Private Idaho is a troubling picture, but a realistic one of the underside of gay life that we cannot ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As current today as it was then....a modern classic perhaps.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Own Private Idaho Director: Gus Van Sant Starring: River Phoenix, Keanu Reeves, James Russo. Gus Van Sant essentially takes on Shakespeare's Henry IV; it featured the aesthetically delightful River Phoenix as Mike Waters, a wonderfully apt narcoleptic male whore who we first get a glimpse of tipping down an open stretch of road in Idaho. Mike and the action shifts from the cold Seattle to equally cold Portland. It is here that he makes friends with Scott Favor, a secretly soon to be rich guy who is also on the game played by the often-maligned Keanu Reeves. The future for both is as uncertain as uncertain can be, will Scott take up the inheritance he about to get, will Mike survive the streets with his narcolepsy? ￼ Mike feels real affections for Scott, however Scott refuses to believe men can really love each and it would seem that Scott is only doing the gay whole whore thing to kill time and get back at his family. Mike believes Scott will continue with the grand life on the streets, turning tricks even after he bags the inheritance; such is the allure of the unknown. There are many of fellow working boys who agree with Mike's view. This is an uneasy picture, a colourful and surreal attempt to really take the characters to a different kingdom. At times, it is a wonderful although slightly glossy take on the real street hustlers shagging their way to oblivion or not as the individual case may be. Drug abuse and risky behaviours are commonplace on the streets and in the world of the male hooker and it is a small feature of this sometimes-disturbing film. The character of Mike seems almost apologetically plausible, abandoned as a child and obsessed with finding his real long lost mother. Scott less believable as the rebellious disillusioned spoilt little rich kid gone rebelliously bad. You really would not have put them together by design, but fate disregards those lines and together they embark on a quest to find Mike's mother, from Portland to Idaho to Italy they do travel. There is no argument the cinematic quality and the unbelievably stunning settings help to make this film an intriguingly striking viewing delight. It is exceptionally well thought out in terms of location and setting and a master-class for any would be cinematographer. The characterisation I found to be impressive, even Keanu Reeves played his part with just the right amount of smug pathos and humour, especially with the flippantly arrogant lines afford to him. River Phoenix works pure magic on screen with this performance and I am fairly sure I'm not alone in believing this is the role that set him into the great immortal movie star hall of fame. It is no wonder that he pulled in a number of 'best actor' type awards for this intrinsically faceted role. His campfire scene, in which Mike declares his love for Scott, is much applauded by audiences and critics alike  Newsweek claiming it to be "A marvel of delicacy" it really is a testament to what a wonderful talent River Phoenix was, because he wrote that part of the script himself. Village Voice said, "Phoenix vanishes with reckless triumph into his role". It earned around &pound;5 million at the box office worldwide, which is quite impressive, more than that in video and DVD sales. My Own Private Idaho takes the spirit and passion of Shakespeare, bends, manipulates and shapes it to find form in a more modern setting, which works beyond expectation in the most part. Although the traditionalist in me seems to hold the opinion that you should not mess with old Shaky and if you do, you best be prepared to face the harshest of critics. Adaptations are always open to personal interpretation and modifications, which others may not agree with, like or even accept, yet this one seems to work and seems to be commended as a job well done.Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem in the movie genre - very emotional & moving with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry07
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard of this movie for a while now (since it came out I guess) and never had the chance to watch it. Finally, I got my hand on a DVD and was stunned: how could I have missed this before? I would classify this movie in the Indie genre (if that applied to movies), as its style is unusual. Essentially, the dialogs may go into long theatrical speech (literally) rather than a fluent every day life dialog. You get annoyed at times (did not expect a Shakespeare play but a movie) as some of the scenes within this style are not working out (imagine Keanu Reeves in a play - nope! doesn't work for me either). But if you can pass beyond this problem, you will find a gem. Indeed, the characters! What a treat. River Phoenix (Mike) performance is simply breathtaking and inspired: you immediately feel the character of "Mike", the abandoned and confused child not only reverting to hustling for money but striving for belonging, acceptance and love going in life with the dream and memory of his mother. His friendship with Scott (Keanu Reeves) will bring them into a journey where emotions and classics are all covered: lightness and energy of youth, rebellion of the privileged, loneliness, burning passions, struggles and survival, loss, desire. On second thought, perhaps it works well as a Shakespearian play (yes, I know it was intended) but not only because the dialogs are like so but due to the in-depth drama of this movie the breadth of emotion it covers. The story line is flooded with the view of Mike (also narcoleptic) and appears at times as a dream. As a result, to me, the whole movie is simply a great piece, poetic, breath taking and emotional: you stay watching through the theater scenes wanting to know what's next, you get hooked to the artistic aspects of the movie (music is often blending and you find yourself noticing that many details have significance) and you feel for the characters at a deep and intense level as if the topics treated are archetypal. For sure, you will remember this movie whether you were thrown off by it, liked it or loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    trippy arty homage to Shakespeare's Henry IV. a powerful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every time I see this film, I forget how incredibly amazing it is. Yes I'm a huge fan of of the late, great, River Phoenix, think Keanu Reeves is highly underrated, and love Shakespeare. This is a modern adaptation to Henry IV, based around two hustlers Mike and Scott (River and Keanu) and their relationship, with the added wrinkle that Mikey is a narcoleptic and trying to find his long lost mother. Scott is the rich boy who turns his back on his street life when his inheritance kicks in. River's performance is astounding, tender and powerful, and it's a brave pair of best friends (in real life) that take on roles like this but the affection between them is palpable and somehow makes the story of unrequited love even more heartbreaking. The Shakespeare gets confusing if you aren't familiar, as it washes in and out, and if you haven't seen Gus Van Sant before you might not quite follow the surreal imagery and the trippy nature of the film. It's arty, weird and dark, but has a lot of humour and sensitivity, despite being a little bawdy in places, however for all it's adult subject matter it's quite discrete! River and Keanu are astounding in this, and it's a film that River should be remembered for as the bright star he was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like a super 8
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom van de Bospoort
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like a super 8 film from the 70's/80's New York this felt like it was art created for the screen on a setting, the open plan falling down dilapidated building. Beautifully shot with scenes of the hills and fields that seemed to roll on forever. The acting even included San Sant himself as well as Grace Zabriskie who is normally in David Lynch's films. The story was maybe even too weird for me and didn't really get a resonance and stayed very flat, it was not his best but showed how he can make his films. Although it was maybe too weird it still made me want to be there in that building, the place where creativity happens, as spaces like that spark imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    much ado about nothing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A narcoleptic hustler and his 'degenerate' (to his father) pal travel the Pacific Northwest in search ofwhat? Freedom? Affection? Adventure? Gus Van Sant's follow up to his career breakthrough 'Drugstore Cowboy' is full odd stylistic tics and transparent social commentary, all of it adding up to a merely pretentious film even more aimless and unmotivated than its two primary characters. Viewers might be forgiven for wondering where the story is going after the brief detour into Idaho itself (the trailer home reunion is a highlight), when the scene shifts abruptly, and for no good reason, to sunny Rome (yes, in Italy). There's plenty to look at, but all the gorgeous imagery hides a shortage of real ideas, and Van Sant's mock Shakespearean dialogue is an annoying conceit (at least the Bard is acknowledged in the credits). Udo Kier, as 'Hans', steals the film away from its two young stars, and the brief documentary appearance of actual teenage hustlers discussing their 'dates' shows what the film could have aspired to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
